Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
Question,
I'm a cybernetic organism living tissue.
This episode is brought to you by audible,
which I've used for years.
I love audiobooks and I've two
to recommend right off the bat.
Number one is pressed my
favorite audio book of all time,
and that is the graveyard
book by Neil Gaiman.
The only audiobook I've wanted to
immediately listen to a second time.
As soon as I finished. It's amazing.
You will thank me. The graveyard book.
The second is vagabonding by Rolf Potts,
which had a huge impact on my life and
formed the basis for a lot of what became
the four hour work week.
So all you need to do to get your free
audio book and a Free 30 Day trial is go
to audible.com forward slash Tim and
you can choose one of those two books,
the graveyard book bag of bonding
or more than 180,000 audio programs.
So that could be a book. That could be
a magazine, that could be a newspaper,
it could be a class. It's that easy.
Go to audible.com forward slash Tim,
that's audible.com forward slash
Tim and grab a book. Enjoy.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is a great partner for
creating and growing your business.
It's a one stop shop for
all of your graphic design
needs, whether that's a logo,
website, business card, or anything else.
I used 99 designs to get book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to become a number
one New York Times bestseller.
I also use them for banner
ads, illustrations, and other
things. With 99 designs,
designers around the world compete
to create the best design for you.
You give feedback and
then pick your favorite.
You end up happy or you get your
money back. It's very simple.
You can check out a few of my
own designs and those of yours,
meaning Tim Ferriss,
show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and right now my
listeners, you guys will get a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
That's 99 designs.com forward
slash. Tim, check it out.
Hello Ladies and germs.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job to deconstruct world class
performers, whether they are from chess,
sports, military,
entertainment or otherwise.
I tease out the routines, the
habits, the favorite books,
etc. That you can use.
At least that's the goal and this
episode was a massive success because the
guest Seth Goden 10 x to my expectations
and I already expected him to be
incredible,
which of course he was.
Seth Goden is probably the best
known marketing mind in the world.
The author of 17 bestselling books that
have been translated into more than 35
languages. He writes about the way
ideas spread, marketing of course,
strategic quitting leadership,
and most of all challenging the status
quo in all areas and he does this
personally in his own life
in many different ways.
His books include linchpin,
tribes, the dip, purple cow,
your turn and many others.
He's also founded several companies
including Yoyodyne and Squidoo, his blog,
which is easy to find.
Just type Seth into Google is one
of the most popular in the world.
He's been inducted into the
direct marketing hall of fame.
He's done all sorts of amazing
things and generally speaking,
Seth doesn't get into his personal life,
his personal habits.
This interview is an exception. He tells
a lot of stories he's never told before.
We get into a lot of details that he has
never disclosed or shared before and we
cover a ton and we had a blast.
His favorite list of audio books
that he listens to repeatedly,
some of them once per month, his morning
routine, breakfast, dietary habits,
how he processes email
meditative practices,
why he's fixated on among other things,
coffee and vodka,
despite the fact that he
consumes neither of them,
how to go from wantrepreneur to
entrepreneur and it goes on and on.
We really had a great time.
I hope that you also have a great time
listening to it. So without further ado,
please enjoy my conversation
with none other than Seth Godin.
Seth,
welcome to the show,
Tim. It's a pleasure. What
a thrill at the talk to you.
I have over the years just become more
and more fascinated by your entire life.
And I really admire not only the work
you've put out but the entire life you've
crafted for yourself.
And since day one I think my fans
have been asking me to not will I,
but when will you have Seth on the
podcast? So it's really fun to,
to set aside the time and
I really appreciate it.
And we've also ended up having quite a
few mutual friends and I thought perhaps
a fun place to start would be with
something I only learned recently. And uh,
I guess the best way to approach this
would be to just ask you to talk about
maybe your,
how do you prepare coffee or vodka.
Okay. Um, the coffee thing,
we'll start there. I don't drink
coffee. I wish I did. I need a vice.
But I like making it, I like the, uh,
act of trying without being one of those
people who's like measuring everything
because that's not my shtick.
To have an intuitive sense of what
makes a good pool of espresso.
And I used to have a fancy slayer machine,
which is this super digital hunk of a
device that did not belong in anyone's
kitchen, particularly mine.
So when it started acting up,
I was able to sell it for a fair price
and switched in the completely opposite
direction to a Swiss made 17 year old,
totally manual machine.
Like you got to pull a handle and um,
I roast my own beans,
which is key.
Marco Arment taught me that roasting
your own beans is more important than any
other thing you can do if
you want to make coffee.
And I think there's a metaphor there.
I know there's a metaphor there,
which is you can spend a lot of
time trying to fix stuff later,
but starting with the right raw
materials makes a huge difference.
Garbage in, garbage out. There you
go, Marco. Just for context for folks,
that's Marco and I don't know why I'm
having this mental blank right now.
Of course,
the Tumbler and now overcast,
which is a great podcast
player that I use myself,
really fascinating guy in his own right.
Uh,
why don't you drink coffee and
it hurts my stomach. Uh, and
some people, here's the thing,
some people are gluten intolerant.
I'm just intolerant,
intolerant of, we're talking about
food products, food, not humans.
Good with humans. And if you have to pick
one, it's better to be tolerant of you
and the, the, the vodka. Can
we dig into that for a second?
So there's a place near my house called
stone barns that is actually used to be
the Rockefeller his summer house
and it's a nice restaurant.
And at the bar, I don't
drink either, but uh,
I'm told that at the bar they
serve honey oatmeal vodka.
And I reverse engineered the
recipe and have, it sounds still,
but I make it in my basement.
The recipe for those who are interested
is you take a bottle of vodka,
you don't want the super cheap stuff,
but you don't want the expensive stuff
cause that's a little bit of a rip off
and you pour it over,
uh,
like a pound of just plain old oatmeal,
uncooked and half a jar of honey.
And you let it sit in the fridge for
two weeks during it now and then,
and then you strain it out back into
the original bottle and you're done.
The, the, the feedback and the feedback,
it sounds so odd like an
employee interview or something,
but when I was chatting with a couple
of mutual friends, they said what,
what impresses me most,
or one of the things that impresses me
most about Seth is how well thought out
and meticulous all of these
various activities are,
is that something that started very,
very early?
Have you had that attention to detail
for as long as you can remember or did
some experience or collection
of people instill that in you?
Well, I think it's really important
that we get the scale properly here.
Um,
I am meticulous compared to
an amateur house painter.
I am a slob compared to you.
I, if they're not, it's right.
There is nothing about any of these tasks
that could be described as meticulous.
The, for example, the amount of
oatmeal, honey varies wildly.
Every single time there's,
uh, you know, the coffee,
probably a coffee snob,
just turn up his nose at what I'm trying
to do. I don't enjoy being meticulous.
I enjoy,
um,
sort of running roughshod
over the status quo,
learning what I can learn as I go.
But no one has ever accused.
All right. So putting that that,
uh, so derisive term aside,
I think maybe the word that it would
be more appropriate in my mind is
thoughtful. Uh, yes, I'm very thoughtful.
That's what I do because
I'm not good at sports
and uh, I just have to,
I have, because these,
these are things I just
only recently learned.
So I heard from a chef friend of ours,
then you have the most impressive
cookbook collection he has ever seen.
How and why?
Well, okay. So before Amazon,
I was a book packager and what book
packagers do for a living is come up with
ideas for books and then make them,
and I made 120 books in 10 years,
a book a month. I made bestsellers.
I made books that sold no copies.
I made books on gardening
and I did trivia projects.
I made a books all over the map.
And the way you do that is a,
you work with an expert.
So my second book was professor
heard Barns on the spot,
spot and stain removal guide and herb
was the world's expert on spot and stain
removal. And the deal was I got his
notebook, he got half the money,
I did all the work. Um, and, but sometimes
you don't have an expert with you.
So what you do is you go to the bookstore
and buy every book on the topic.
And that's how my book collection grew
to many thousands of books because a book
is a bargain,
still a screaming bargain.
You pay 1520 bucks and you have
something that might change your life.
You have something that reminds you 20
years later sitting on the shelf where
you were when you read it.
I love buying books.
And so the cookbook thing started with
my mom's copy of the joy of cooking.
And every time I saw a
cookbook that seemed like I
would get three good insights
out of it,
I bought it because it was a screaming
bargain and then it grew and it grew.
And then Amazon showed up and one click
shopping and maybe you should buy this
one next. And every once, you know,
growing up there,
you know,
people were in my house with the
doorbell would ring and everyone go,
Amazon's here because every
night the doorbell would ring.
So there,
that's where the cookbooks,
if you were, if you had someone
over for dinner, and I've,
I've heard you're an incredible cook and
they said they wanted to learn how to
cook.
Are there any particular books that you
would recommend to them or approaches
for that matter?
Okay, so for just about anybody, the
right answer is the four hour chef.
Well that wasn't, I intended to be
a softball. I wasn't trying to set
that up because before that
book you had a weave together,
you know, a 30 minute narrative to help
somebody think about what cooking meant.
Uh,
my wife got me a Chris Schlesinger
cooking class and it was the only cooking
class I'd ever taken.
And in 20 minutes I learned more about
cooking than I think I've learned before
or since,
because Chris Basically taught me how to
think about what you were trying to do
and basically said a,
you should taste the food as you go,
which is surprisingly small
number of people do. And B,
he said salt and olive oil actually are
cheating and their secret weapons and
they always work. You can even add them
to ice cream. They just always work.
So for me,
part of the thoughtfulness is I don't
use a lot of salts and I don't use it a
lot of oil because I know I
could, but it's cheating. And uh,
I like to think about cooking again as
a metaphor for most of what you are,
have been teaching the real lesson
that you have been teaching,
not the detailed stuff,
which is that it costs
very little to find out.
And yeah,
exactly.
Lots of people are afraid to find out
and that's why they're bad at cooking.
And there are thing I love about
cooking because my projects like yours
sometimes last for years is
that cooking lasts for an hour.
And at the end you have success
or failure. And that cycle of,
I have an idea at four and we're sitting
down at six is one that I liked very
much. And I'll tell you a story that
I don't think I've ever told out loud.
Um, I used to go shopping
every single night cause I,
I cooked for the family
for many, many years, every
single night, still mostly do.
And um, I would stop at the
Korean Deli near my house. Um,
and it was a fish store.
It was a flower shop and it was
a nice fresh vegetable place.
And the man who owned
it was a friend of mine.
I used to bring him my books when
they were translated into Korean,
which was fun. And, um,
every single night I would go to
get the freshest stuff. Anyway,
a giant evil drugstore chain bought the
place and tore it down and put up an
evil drugstore. And, uh,
so I didn't know how to
commemorate this loss.
I ended up going online to one of
those places that sell those brass
architectural plaques and I had a brass
architectural plaque made honoring the
place and I fixed it to the side
of the drug store where it has,
where it has been for the last five years.
Unmolested it's amazing,
the tangible aspect of
cooking and is something I,
I completely agree with you on compared
to say some of the more abstract or
longer term projects.
When you have something to show for your
effort at the end that is very tangible
and tactile, uh, is,
is that part of the reason that you are
as interested in audio equipment as you
are of our peer to be?
I've never been to your house,
but so I hear that you have the
most incredible sound system
many people have ever seen is,
is it's, I mean, is there a, uh,
I don't know what, what, what the
details are, but is, is there a,
an analog of tactile drive behind
that or what is the, what is the,
or the reason behind that?
Well. Okay, so here's the, you
know, the arc for me for many,
many years has been railing against,
uh,
various industrial complexes,
the TV industrial complex,
the educational industrial complex,
and this corporatization
of just about everything.
Uh, there is, I was in China eight weeks
ago. There's a village outside of, uh,
Shen Zen called Dolphin where they paint
one third of all the oil paintings in
the world over and over as fast as
they can. These paintings are art.
They're merely paintings.
They are what happens if a giant big
box store needs 10,000 oil paintings?
This is how they get them.
Uh, what I discovered,
I was at my friend Steve's house 20
years ago and he had a big pile of this
magazine called stereophile.
Stereophile is handmade magazine about
handmade audio equipment with people
arguing with each other about this, that,
and the other thing, a lot of arguing.
And it was really fun
to read. And, you know,
I have no interest in baseball whatsoever,
but this was like baseball and that you
could track the careers of the various,
uh, artisans and you could be on one
side or the other of these discussions.
So for me, uh, you know,
I started by buying inexpensive used
stuff and there's a marketplace online
called audio gone with no e at the end
where you can find people who buy things
new and sell them six months
later in perfect condition. Uh,
and I found that
connecting to the artisan,
understanding their point of
view of finding the guy in,
I think he's in Cleveland who
makes speaker wires by hand,
finding the, uh, Paul McGowan in Boulder,
Colorado who is at the cutting edge
of certain parts of the stereo,
but not other ones. Making them in
boulder with a team of people. Uh,
it gives me pleasure and that pleasure
is a placebo that makes the music sound
better.
Um,
and the act of carefully choosing what
you're going to listen to and knowing
that the heritage and the
terroir of the thing behind it,
it feels to me, uh, like a productive
hobby that doesn't hurt anybody.
So it's something I spent some time on.
How do you consume media or if or what
type of media do you consume as it is,
is the bulk of it's still in
book form that is a hard copy or,
uh,
how do you consume media?
Well,
I'll start with,
I don't watch any television that's live
and I feel strongly that most people
shouldn't. Um, I think that one
of the single best hacks, uh,
is that after Seinfeld lawn off the air,
that was it.
And we ripped it out and it frees up
hours and hours every day to explore media
or content that's up to you as
opposed to somebody else. Um,
so, and I don't watch any TV at
home recorded or otherwise, but,
so that leaves me with books
and kindle and music mostly. Uh,
the thing with books is,
uh,
I really don't have the
patients for literature.
I didn't grow up with literature.
I was an engineering college. Uh,
and I just never got the knack
for decoding really dense fiction.
Um,
and so on the other hand,
like you every day the mailman
brings unsolicited books in the mail.
So there's a,
a very high throughput of reading books
before most good people get to see them.
And once you do enough, you don't have
to read the whole thing to get the joke.
And every once in a while it's good enough
that you keep going. Uh, if I blurb it,
it means I went all the
way to the end. But, um,
I love reading books on paper.
It's harder for me to read books on the
kindle when I'm not traveling because it
doesn't have that Proust.
Ian,
a reminder to me of what
a book actually means.
So one of the things
people in my generation are
discovering is that people who
are 20 or 30 are coming up viewing
books as nothing but a reminder of to
drudgery of high school.
And if a book is on an electronic device,
it's one click away from email.
And email is always better than
reading a book if you're 25. Um,
and so I fear for the future
of our medium because it's not,
it doesn't have the,
the place in our culture that he,
he's too.
How do you
determine,
and if the book blurb of particular
example is going to just create a delusion
that you don't want, we don't have
to address that one, but I've,
I've been very impressed in some of our
conversations by the rules that you've
established for yourself for saying
yes or no to certain things. Uh,
and perhaps we could start if you're
willing to talk about it with speaking
engagements,
like how do you speaking engagements
as you've experienced it if you have a
successful book.
I went from kind of zero to 60,
very quickly unexpectedly and said yes
to everything and it just turned into a
parody of up in the air.
I mean,
I felt like a traveling salesman or
Jack Lemmon and Glengarry Glen Ross was,
it was horrible. How do you,
what are your rules for,
for instance,
speaking engagements,
it for whatever your to whatever extent
you're comfortable talking about them.
Oh, I'd be happy to. And then I'll scroll
back a little bit and tell you why.
I have to have rules for things like that.
Um,
for speaking engagements,
I don't want to do more than
30 a year because they are,
at least for me,
uh,
not additive to the joy of my day
except for the hour I'm on stage.
So I am prepared to do an unlimited
number of speaking engagements in Zip Code
One oh seven Oh six, um, you know,
Monday I'm going to Carnegie Hall to talk,
uh,
for free to 25 music students who have
devoted their lives to doing what they
do. And it's a privilege to
do something like that. Um,
if I have to get on an airplane,
it's a whole other project.
So I think really hard about what
impact am I trying to make. Um,
and will this help me,
uh, move things forward,
which is the, where this nests into. Uh,
my mentor and late friend Zig
Ziglar used to talk about, uh,
the idea he used to say,
I've never changed anyone's
life with a speaking Gig,
but sometimes I do a speaking gig and
they buy my cassettes and if they buy my
cassettes, I got a shot at
changing their life. And for me,
my mission and has been for a long time
is to make a certain kind of change
happen. I want to help people
see the world differently.
And if they choose to make a different
choice after they see the world
differently,
I want to help people connect to each
other and to use that connection to make
things better.
And I don't want to be a TV personality.
So the question is how do I
bring that teaching to people?
And what I've found is it's a very unique
situation when you have 500 or 5,000
high powered people in a room who didn't
expect that you were going to be there.
But now that you're there are
eager to hear what you have to say.
And they set aside their Twitter account
and they set aside their preconceptions.
And for 45 minutes or an hour,
you have a screen that's 30 feet by 20
feet and you have a microphone that's
amplified. And maybe just maybe
you can get under their skin.
And if you do, maybe just, maybe they
go back to their office and you know,
get 10 copies of your turn and
hand them out to their team.
And then I can, you know, do
that practice that I seek,
which is to change the conversation.
So that's why I do it at all.
And the,
uh, and the further away it is, the less
likely you are to say yes. Does that act,
is that fair?
Oh yeah. Well, yeah. What I did was, uh,
having studied a little bit of economics
is I changed, I changed the price.
Uh, Los Angeles costs three
times as much as New York.
And if you don't think that's fair,
then don't make me go to Los Angeles.
And you said, um, you're going to
elaborate on why you need rules.
And maybe you just did.
Maybe that was
the, the, the answer. But you
know, the phone rings, right?
And lots of people want a thing and if
it doesn't align with the thing that is
your mission and you say yes,
then now it's their mission.
And there's nothing wrong with being
a wandering generality instead of a
meaningful specific but don't expect
to make the change you seek to make if
that's what you do. That did you
know the thing is, and Derrick,
I thought your interview with Derek was
one of the best ones you've ever done.
Thanks Derek. Makes it quite
easy. Derek Sivers is awesome.
I adore him.
And he talked about offense versus
defense and if you think hard about one's
life,
most people spend most of their
time on defense in reactive mode,
definitely in playing with the cards
they got instead of moving to a different
table with different cards instead
of seeking to change other people,
they are willing to be changed.
And part of the arc of what I'm trying
to teach is everyone who can hear this
has more power than they think they do.
And the question is,
what are you going to do with that power?
Because it comes with a
responsibility right out of Spiderman.
But that responsibility is you're going
to make change happen or you're going to
ignore it. And if you make
change happen and that's on you.
Yeah,
it does.
Just pausing as I was thinking of how
well anyone who's listening to this
podcast relative to the vast
majority of people on the planet,
uh, how well they are
doing for whatever reason.
I was just bridging the gap between
our little text exchange, uh,
before the call where I asked you if
you are ready and you said born ready.
Not Actually, I was born naked
and afraid and unable to read,
unable to type in SAP.
If you look at that progression,
making it from there to
where we are collectively,
everyone listening to this podcast
or being on it, it's, it's,
it's pretty astonishing. Uh, the,
can I just interrupt you
for a second? Yes, sir.
I think that's part of the
secret plan of Tim Ferriss,
which is that when you
came out of the gate,
it was or felt like here
are some techniques and some
shortcuts and it was seen
as a, uh, you know, an early
version of the life hacking thing.
But I don't think that's
what you're really doing.
I think what you are really doing
is saying to people, all right,
now that you are so much
more fit in every area,
mentally, physically,
emotionally, spiritually, what
are you going to do with it?
And when you think about the
Seneca stuff and the podcast,
that's where you've been going
for a long time. And I, for one,
just wanting to call you out and applaud
you on it because it's not the easy
path.
It's the path that's important and you
have been consistent and shown up and
done the work.
Thank you. Uh, that means,
uh, that means a lot to me.
And you're correct.
I,
the tactics get people
in the door so to speak.
But then the question is,
all right,
once you have more of this finite resource
called time and you've sharpen the ax
in these various areas, where do you
apply your effort? Uh, and you know,
I would, this is, this is maybe going to
turn into a therapy session for myself,
but I've found myself,
I mean,
we're just talking about books
and their place in culture,
feeling like I'm in a transition point
and you've been so consistent and so
present for so many people for
so long, your readers, et cetera.
Uh, how do you navigate big
transitions in your own life?
And that's a very general question.
But for instance, I find my,
the reason the podcast started
as cause burned out on books,
it was after the four hour chef,
670 some odd pages.
I just felt so battle weary and,
and run down by publishing
that I wanted to take a break.
And the podcast was a side project
that then became its own entire thing
altogether.
But when you find yourself wondering
maybe what to do next, I mean,
how do you navigate some of those
larger transitions? And I mean,
if you have any examples
that come to mind,
I, well, the good news is you did
exactly the right thing and I applaud it.
It's not easy to do that because it
means going from a place where by outside
measures you are about to succeed again
to a place where by outside measures you
might not. And hence the
model of this might not work.
And so on a good day,
my story to myself is this might not work.
That's my job to do something
that might not work.
And the number of projects I've done a
big and small exceeds most people's and
the number of failures I have
dramatically exceeds most people's.
And I'm super proud of that.
More proud of the failures
than the successes because
it's about this mantra of
Wa is this generous?
Is this going to connect?
Is this going to change people for
the better? Is it worth trying?
If it meets those criteria and I
can control myself into doing it,
then I ought to write.
And the transitions aren't easy.
I regularly spend months telling people
that I'm unemployed and in between
projects. And, um,
I regularly publicly quit
the book business, uh,
which I did maybe for the last
time a year, two years ago,
more than two years ago. Uh,
your turn came out a year ago,
November. So what is that, 15 months ago?
And I haven't written one
word of a book since then.
What was the word I'm smelling? I
haven't written. Oh, I basically,
I've written one word of
a book, sorry. And uh,
and the reason is the people who I seek
to serve don't want me to write another
book. They want me to do
something else instead. And uh,
they people come up to me as they
might come up to you and say,
you should be really proud of me.
I finished your book. You don't,
no one goes up to Steven Spielberg and
says, you should be pretty proud of me.
I finished all of Vt. I made
it. Did he ended the VP. Right.
And so, you know, with your turn, I
designed it. I illustrated it myself.
I made it so that people would
happily share it with each other.
Because when you share a book,
sometimes you feel a little guilty
cause someone might feel guilty for not
finishing all 600 pages.
But when you share maybe a podcast or
a blog poster and illustrated book,
it makes you feel closer to that person
in the sense that you're both going to
enjoy this journey.
And just,
just to peek behind the curtain a
little bit with some of your decisions,
how did you decide or what is the
thinking behind a daily blog versus,
say,
a longer blog post once a week
or at some other frequency?
So the daily blog,
uh,
evolved and it's one of the
top five career decisions
I've ever made in terms of
having a practice that resonates with
the people who I needed to resonate with,
that I can do forever and have been
doing for more than eight years now.
Um, and that leaves a trail behind.
I don't need anyone's permission.
I don't need to go out and promote it.
I don't use any analytics.
I don't have comments.
It's just this is what I noticed today
and I thought I'd share it with you.
And for awhile,
uh,
it was an intermittent blog and then it
was a five times a day blog and that,
you know, I do write five posts a day.
I just don't publish five posts a day.
Uh,
but it became clear that I could get
the appropriate amount of mind space in
that period of time. Now
I'll tell you, I got,
I've gotten this note maybe eight
times in the last couple of years.
It's enraging and the note says,
I wish you wouldn't post every day.
I can't read that fast.
Please post fewer.
And the thing is,
it's so selfish because all you
gotta do is just skip some of them.
These people don't want other people
that we reading the posts if they can't
read it.
Oh Man.
And the uh,
when you say you wrote where you write
five posts today, just don't publish five.
Is that because you are writing them in
advance to publish all of them later or
you write five and discard four and
keep the best one or something else?
There is no ritual. They're just, I
just notice things. I write them down.
I look at them,
I look at the post before
is next in the queue. I say,
could I do better than that? I tried
different one. So it just averages out.
I mean it's not like there's this method,
I have no method.
Do you draft by hand in word
in a particular program?
I typewrite into typepad
right when I'm in tech.
So I learned this from chip Conley. Have
you had chip on the show? I haven't,
but I'd love, chip is
a great guy. Great Guy.
So chip and I went to business
school together and um,
he was the,
uh,
third youngest person in the class and
I was the second youngest person in the
class. So he, he got five of us together.
And every Tuesday night we met in the
anthropology department for four hours and
we brainstormed more than 5,000 business
ideas over the course of the first year
of business school who was magnificent.
It wasn't official, it wasn't sanctioned.
It was just chip said,
let's do this. And we did.
And he picked the anthropology department
cause he knew someone there and could
get the conference room. And he said, this
is the only place we will ever do this.
And the reason is when
you walk into this room,
you will associate this room
with what we do here. That's all.
And I feel the same way about my blog.
If I am in the typepad editor,
I know exactly what my
brain needs to feel like.
And then the writing happens.
Do you,
uh,
what is your writing warmup look like?
And when do you typically write a, one of
my fans said that you'd, at some point,
this could be a misquote,
but said that you had an elaborate or
extreme sort of mental warmup for writing.
But what, what is, what
is the f what is your,
do you write in the mornings or
what time do you typically write?
Okay, so now I needed to tell you about
Stephen King's pencil. Yes, please.
Cause I feel very strongly about this.
Um,
Stephen King often goes to writer's
conferences and there'll be this question
and that question.
The next question.
And inevitably someone raises
their hand and says, Steven King,
you're one of the most successful,
revered writers of your generation.
What kind of pencil do you use
and I won't go there. It doesn't
matter. It's a way to hide.
It's not interesting to me to talk
about how I do it because there's no
correlation that I have ever encountered
between how writers write and how good
their work is. So you should just
move on because it doesn't matter.
All right. So I will, let me, I'll
make a confession then, which is,
uh, I've been given certain
types, what I feel blocked,
which does happen with writing.
I take a long time to get to the point
where I feel like I have the balls in the
air well enough to put pieces together.
It's just takes me a long
time to synthesize, but not
unlike some coders I guess.
But the point I was going to make is
that I went to a conversation between Po
Bronson or writer and,
and another gent.
I'm blanking on his name and
I asked Po during the Q and a,
what he did when he felt blocked or
couldn't figure out what to do next in
writing. And he said, right,
what makes you angry? Write
about what makes you angry.
And I,
I found that very helpful.
It was a very helpful way to at least
get the hand or the brain moving to break
the ice. Uh, I totally agree. Yeah.
That's not the question. But if
you, if you said to Po Bronson,
how do you write these books that are
remarkable and thoughtful and generous?
I don't think his answer is every morning
I get as angry as I can and no. Agreed.
Agreed.
I agree.
So you and I could list 25 tricks that
help us get past the resistance and stark
the flow of writing.
But that's different than saying I need
to do it like those other people do it.
Agreed. Agreed. I guess, uh, the,
in the buffet of things that have
been helpful along those lines, if,
if for whatever reason didn't get
a good night's sleep feeling off,
you sit down to write
right? This I got, this is
easy. All right. The answer
to this question is right.
Write poorly,
continue writing poorly.
Write poorly until it's not bad anymore
and that you will have something you can
use that people who have trouble
coming up with good ideas.
If they're telling you the truth will
tell you they don't have very many bad
ideas.
But people have plenty of good ideas.
If they're telling you the truth will
say they have even more bad ideas.
So the goal isn't to get good ideas.
The goal is to get bad ideas because
once you get enough bad ideas,
then some good ones have to show up.
Yeah, that's, I remember this brings to
mind a, I have a photo of it somewhere,
but all of the title that all of the
brainstorm titles for the four hour work
week,
that we're not the four hour work week.
I mean for those people who think the
four hour work week sounds like a bad
infomercial product. I mean you should
have seen some of the, some of the, uh,
the outcast on this page. They
were horrible. I mean I can't even,
I atrocious just
to even look back at some of them,
but the, the blog and the daily,
Blake said it was one of your
top five business decisions. Uh,
what are some of the other top
business decisions that you've made?
Uh,
okay.
So we'll go way back and I would say the
first one which is useful to everybody
is sell something that people want to buy.
A,
my friend Lynn is a brilliant,
brilliant thinker and designer.
And for years she was in the business
of designing toys and a soft goods for
moms with toddlers.
And every toy company in America
was mean to her, rejected her,
had nothing to do with her.
And I said, Lynn, it's simple.
Toy companies don't like toy designers.
They're not organized to do
business with toy designers.
They're not hoping toy designers
will come to them. I said,
come with me into the book
business because every day
there are underpaid really
smart people in the book business who
wake up waiting for the next great idea to
come across their desk. They're
eager to buy what you have to sell.
And within two months she
did the decks of cards,
the 52 decks and so more than
5 million decks of cards.
Um,
and that's because they appreciated her.
So if you think about how hard
it is to push a business uphill,
particularly when you're just getting
started, one answer is to say,
why don't you just start a
different business? A business
you can push down hill.
This is a, this is a good lesson. Yeah.
Sometimes I, there's a fetishizing of the,
the sort of rolling of the stone like
sis, is that, am I getting that right?
[inaudible] and uh,
you know,
in Silicon Valley and it's just like
fetishizing of its, uh, of the pain.
And I'm like,
maybe your model is just too difficult.
Amazing. She's a different business.
Uh, okay. That is a good lesson. Uh,
any other,
well, so then the, the other
lesson happens all the time,
which is knowing when I'm
wrong is a useful skill.
And lots of people who do good work have
trouble knowing when they haven't done
good work and they think
they should stick with it.
Other people have done good work. Don't
think they have and they pivot too soon.
So figuring that moment out,
1994,
I'm running one of the
first Internet companies.
We invented commercial email and Mark
Hurst shows me this thing called the world
wide web. And I say, that's stupid.
It's just like prodigy except it's
slower and there's nobody to pass money.
And for six months I persisted in pointing
out that the worldwide web make no
sense whatsoever.
And I then one day just woke up and said,
wait a minute,
let me look at that again.
And we completely changed how we decided
we were going to do our business.
Uh,
the same thing is true with the cover
of all marketers are liars because the
cover and the title was
super clever and wrong.
It was not a matter of me persisting in
persuading people that they needed to
get the joke. It was merely a
matter of persuading the publisher.
We should make the paperback have a
different cover and a different title, uh,
that if you're going to try a lot of
things, you're going to fail a lot.
And figuring out the difference between
the failures of your judgment versus the
failures of not persisting long
enough, uh, is a useful skill.
And I'm still not great at it,
but I'm better at it than I was.
You've interacted with, uh, many
more entrepreneurs than I have.
I would say at this point,
and one of the questions that I get
constantly that you might have a better
answer for it because I don't have
a great answer for it right now, is
when do I know,
how do I discern between an idea that
I should keep persisting with despite
many, many, many,
many rejections versus a bad idea that I
should abandon that is getting the same
type of rejection but that I'm equally
enthusiastic about [inaudible] that's a
very wordy way to put it.
But I get some question.
I get some version of that
question all the time. How do you,
how would you answer that?
Well,
first we have to scroll back.
There's a difference between
freelancers and entrepreneurs.
Most people who are independent are
freelancers. They get paid when they work.
They do good work and get paid for a
few people are entrepreneurs building a
business bigger than themselves,
a business that makes them money when
they sleep a business where they don't
actually do the work that the customer
is buying and a business that they can
sell one day. So, uh, you
know, we, we look at, uh,
Larry Ellison,
Larry Ellison doesn't code at Oracle.
Larry Ellison doesn't make most of the
sales calls. What does Larry Ellison do?
Actually,
his job is to think about something that
needs to be done and hire someone else
to do it over and over again,
building something bigger than himself.
So the first thing I would say to
the person who's confused as well,
are you an entrepreneur or a freelancer?
If you're an entrepreneur,
then you have signed up for a
series of choices and challenges.
And again, start with selling
something people want to buy.
There's no reason to try to invent a need
when there are so many needs and wants
that are unfilled,
right?
So people didn't wake up 10 years
ago and say, I need an Uber.
But they did up 10 years ago and say,
I need an easy,
inexpensive way to get from a to B.
Correct.
Once you could go to someone and say, I
have that. People would say I want that.
But if you're just saying, I'm really
clever, I know what you should want.
And when you tell people what it is,
they don't want it.
You're either talking to the wrong
people or you made the wrong thing.
So the blog post,
I point people to the most is called
first 10 and it is a simple theory of
marketing that says, tell 10 people,
show 10 people, share it with 10 people,
10 people who already trust
you and already like you.
If they don't tell anybody else it's
not that good and you should start over.
And if they do tell other
people you're on your way.
And for those people who hear your
description of entrepreneur and they say,
that's what I want, that is what I
want. I want it to be an entrepreneur.
They currently have nine
to five job or maybe more,
maybe 80 to a hundred hours a week
management consultant job. Who knows,
uh, this is also a fan
question and they, they,
they desperately want to go from
wantrepreneur to entrepreneur. Uh,
the specific question was,
if I had a sticky note to put on my
computer to help me make that jump,
what would it say? Do you have any
thoughts? And you can, you can,
you can rephrase the question if you'd
like or rip to shreds. Well, let's pick,
pick
two different kinds of entrepreneurs.
One kind of entrepreneur. You say,
uh,
whose need am I satisfying today?
And can I assemble assets who I satisfy
it in a defensible way so I don't have
to be the cheapest? And
by that I mean, uh, I,
and I've, I've written about
this snow shuffling, right?
We know that there's a
need for snow shuffling.
We know that if you spend time and effort,
you can arrange a team of
10 snow shovelers who don't
have the initiative you
have.
And you can use existing
almost free technology to, uh,
assign the snow shovelers
to where they need to go.
And you're not going to win because
you're the cheapest snow shoveling company
you're going to win.
Because you can get to customers
faster and better and more efficiently.
That's a very straightforward
form of entrepreneurship.
It is available to everyone without an
enormous amount of talent or artistic
creativity required because you just
make a list of the thousand things around
you that people need and want.
You make a list of the kinds of assets
and connections you can build and you go
do it and you do it and you do it and
you do it until you're big enough.
The other kind to quote Michael Schrage
here is to say the purpose of my
business is to change people, to change
them from something into something else.
And this is the kind of business
that we remember generations later.
So Harley Davidson, my favorite
example, changed. Disrespected,
disconnected outsiders into
respected family members,
insiders. That's what you get when
you pay $12,000 for a motorcycle.
Because if you, all you want is
transport bias, the Zucchini,
and the way to think about it
is no one gets a Suzuki Tattoo.
You can decide that you
want to be tattoo worthy,
that you want to change a population
in a way that makes you indispensable.
That kind of entrepreneurship
requires insight at a different level.
There's nothing, uh,
unattainable about it.
I encourage people to go do it,
but know that it is a higher stakes game.
Then being the person who apply systems
thinking to an existing clear need.
This is,
this is going to seem big posted by them
big posted or, or maybe, uh,
are there any check boxes that people
could use to determine if they should not
become an entrepreneur or the,
because if you, if you look at the,
let's just say the narrative on
the covers of business magazines,
it seems like,
uh,
to the untrained eye perhaps of that
or the train die for that matter,
that everyone is being encouraged to
become an entrepreneur and start their own
company.
Um,
and I'm curious to hear if,
if you,
in what cases do you actively discourage
people from starting their own company?
The first thing I would say is the uh,
discerning reader of business magazines
differentiates between the articles were
written for people who are voyeurs and
the articles that are written for you and
98% of the covers aren't written for you.
You should skip those.
You should skip the,
uh,
articles that lie and eyes people without
actually explaining anything about
them other than they are
different than better than you.
Um, that said, uh, you know, we,
we've gotten this far without
talking about Steve Pressfield.
The resistance runs deep and the same
thing that causes writer's block is what
Causes Entrepreneurial Block.
And just for people listening,
Steven Pressfield,
the war of art and among other
books, very, very worth reading,
right? The war of art is one of
those books, at least for me.
When I finally was exposed to it,
I said, why wasn't I informed?
Why did it take this long for
this book to land on my desk?
There aren't very many
books I could say like that.
Most of my books don't
fall into that category.
You're a book stuff like there are
there in the world. You find our books.
Steve's book was hidden in some little
corner and I'm super glad I found it.
I tracked him down. I published
the sequel called do the work. Um,
and now he's the publisher of that book.
But reading the war of artists is
really essential, painful and essential.
Anyway. People get entrepreneurial
block for only one reason.
It is not because they are not qualified.
It is not because they are not passionate.
It is because they are afraid.
And you need to be clear with
yourself about what you are afraid of,
why you are afraid,
and whether you care enough to dance
with that fear because it will never go
away.
Sounds a lot like,
uh,
I mean there's so many parallels of
course with the stoicism meditation,
you know,
not trying to suffocate these so called
negative emotions because they're going
to be constant companions.
So you have to learn how to navigate and
be friend them or at least accept them
in a way. But if we look
at fear, uh, I remember,
I think it was the four hour
body, I said that, uh, you know,
the fears of modern man can
be boiled down to two things,
getting fat and too much email.
If we look at email,
uh,
you are very well known for
responding extremely quickly to many,
many people who pin you.
And this we can,
I can get more specific if it's helpful,
but how do you process email?
Right.
Let's also point out for those of you
who are considering sending me an email,
that according to the surgeon general,
one out of every 300 people who send me
an email spontaneously burst into flame.
This is all you have to decide.
Is it worth the risk?
Okay. So, um,
it's the email thing is a real problem
for me and I don't have a way out and I'm
not sure I want the way out because if
I wanted one I would probably find one.
I decided a very long time ago,
um,
as the author of permission marketing
a book about anticipated personal and
relevant messages to
people want to get them,
that this medium was going to be a place
I was going to spend a lot of time in.
And if someone cared enough to
send me a generous non anonymous,
uh, email, I could certainly try
to spend the time to write back.
And it worked for a really long time.
And for someone with add like mine,
it's a thrill because every time you
look over on your computer there's
something that looks like productive
work, just waiting to be done. But
at the end of the day,
if all you've done is answer email,
unless you work in help scout or
some tech support job, it's probable.
You haven't created any
enormous amount of value.
And I need to work ever
harder at disciplining myself
to not live in my email
box because I'm really good at it.
It makes people happy,
but it's not part of the
change I'm trying to make.
I don't want to say to people,
oh, you were the last one.
The person after you
doesn't get a response.
I don't want to hire someone to answer
my email cause every word I have ever
written has been written by me.
Um,
and so I soldier on. But I say to
people like you who have a platform,
please ask people to do the world a
favor and write to Tim instead of,
well, I've been, uh, I've, I've
thrown myself to the wolves in a way,
uh, with, with email just because
I tend not to respond to many,
but it's in the,
in a world where many,
many folks in, it'd be curious to hear
how you handle this particular instance.
Make unsolicited introduction.
So people you know,
who should probably know better and
maybe you've only met them three or four
times, but somehow they have your
email address, email you and say,
uh, Hi Seth, I'd love for
you to meet Doug So-and-so,
CEO of such and such who's
Blahblahblahblahblah and he
wanted to connect because
of this, this, and this. I'm
sure you guys will get along. Uh,
do you have a coping mechanism for,
for that if you experience it?
Wow. Okay. So this is a problem you
have created largely for yourself?
Like most of my problems,
I'm sure
I don't invest in any companies.
I don't take pitches for my
blog and I don't go to meetings.
So it's easy for me to generously right
back to someone and say, I don't invest,
I don't take pitches and I don't
go to meetings. How can I help you?
Because most of the time they
want one of those three things.
And so if they're being honest,
we're now done.
Uh, and if, if you get,
do you then therefore something like,
I mean Rick Rubin is very similar
in this way. The music producer.
Do you have people always come to you
if you want to meet them or it is deemed
worth your time or are
there exceptions and if so,
how do you decide what makes the cut?
So going to La to have lunch
with Rick is on my list.
I haven't even begun to
schedule it because the
thought of flying somewhere not
to do my speaking work is really
an Fmla. But one day, hi Rick,
I'm going to come have lunch with you.
One of the things that happens if you
live 40 minutes from the world's greatest
city is that people in New York don't
want to make the last 40 minutes.
So I end up, if I'm meeting
someone, but I don't go to meetings,
I usually ended up in New York City.
Got It. What other, what other
things do you categorically,
and I'm not quite done with the email,
we're going to maybe come back to that,
but what other activities do
you categorically say no to
and so on?
It
tastes like soap to you is that is
well known.
The,
the gastropod podcasted an episode
about me and my Salon trow aversion.
All right, so no Cilantro. So
there, there a couple of cuisines.
It'd be very challenging to navigate.
Uh, I mean a Vietnamese noodles,
very tough.
Uh,
but the part of the reason
I ask is that you see,
you have had just tremendous longevity
as a writer and as a thinker,
as a speaker.
There are many people who have
one or two successful books get,
gets inundated with various
opportunities, good, bad in between,
say yes,
become very scattered,
flameout become irrelevant somehow and
the wider world never hears from them or
sees their gifts again.
And I think in part it's because as I
did with speaking engagements early on,
I was so flattered that anyone would pay
me anything to speak and just amazed at
these sums.
It seemed just insane at the time that
I said yes to everything and it made my
life quite miserable. And people do that
with many, many different things. Right.
The investing,
which is why I'm not taking any investing
meetings or investing in any startups
anymore at this point. Uh, I just
realized I had to say no to all of it.
I couldn't say yes to just the top 1%
because that's still meant that I had to
filter the other 99%.
No. Yes, exactly. Why this is about
cognitive load and it's about,
um,
the dip and it's about
seeking to be a crafts person.
So the reason I don't use
Twitter is I saw Twitter early,
which is unusual for me, and I said, wow,
I could do this and have a lot of
followers. And then I said, well,
what would that mean?
A,
it would mean less time spent writing
my blog be it would mean exposing myself
to anonymous comments from people
who want me to pay attention to them.
We'll either of those two things make me
better at the things I want to be good
at.
No.
Will it be a thrill in the sense that
there'll be a little fearful edge to it
every time I interact,
yes,
but I have conservation of fear and I
have to be really careful because if I'm
busy sorting through more stuff,
the cognitive load goes up and I
can't do what Neil Gaiman does.
Like Neal famously has said that the
way he writes a book is he makes himself
extremely bored.
And if he's bored enough of book's
going to come out because it's it.
He needs to entertain himself.
Well,
the problem with most people don't
understand about social media.
Social media wasn't
invented to make you better.
It was invented to make
the company's money.
And you are an employee of the company
and you are the product that they sell
and they have put you in a little hamster
wheel and they throw a little treats
and now and then.
But you got to decide what's the
impact you're trying to make.
And this still comes back to the
fear thing and one of the biggest
misunderstandings of the people who are
into that whole quantified self thing is
they are confusing quantifying the
self with dancing with the fear.
And they're completely different
things to do in a given day.
That one is Taylorism.
It's scientific management,
it's productivity. It's we need to move
these widgets from one place to another.
What's the most efficient way?
And I'm glad we got good at industry
because it makes our lives way more rich,
right?
But our economy,
our world and our soul
aren't fulfilled by that.
They're fulfilled by people who do
something that has never been done before.
And if it's never been done before,
you can't quantify it because
it's never been done before.
And so to be good at it doesn't mean
you quantify your weight into it.
To be good at it means
you're clear the decks.
So that all that's left
is you and the Muse,
you and the fear you and the change
you want to make in the world.
I can't think of something that's more
productive for the kind of people who are
lucky enough and blessed enough to be
rich enough to be listening to this,
to focus their energy on.
We don't need folks like that to be,
to go from 90 words per minute to
105 words per minute when they type,
it's not a factor.
What we need is for them to type
something that's worth reading.
I'm so glad you brought up Neil Gaiman
and he's one of my favorite writers.
Favorite people out there.
Someday I'll get him on the podcast.
It will happen eventually. Uh, but the,
I guess it's make good art is that his
commencement speech of this is just such
an incredible message.
I needed that at a particular point.
It just happened to cross, you
know, come across the transom. Uh,
I encourage everybody to listen to.
Do you think if you were coming off of,
let's just say your first bestseller
and you were thrust into the limelight,
would you choose to,
would you choose again to do the blog and
to do it the way you're doing it or do
you think you would
choose different tools?
Well,
the first thing I would say is everyone
should blog even if it's not under their
own name every single day.
If you are in public making
predictions and noticing things,
your life gets better because you will
find a discipline that can't help but
benefit you. If you want to
do it in a diary, that's fine,
but the problem with diaries
is because they're private.
You can start hiding in public in
this blog, there it is. Six weeks ago,
you said this,
12 weeks ago you said that,
are you able every day to say thing
that's new that you're willing to stand
behind? I think that's just
a huge, wonderful practice,
but that wasn't your question.
Your question was trust and attention
because those are the two things that are
scarce. In an economy where
things that used to be scarce,
not so much anymore,
and attention is as you have built your
arc around is scarce because we're not
making any more of it and there are
ever more tools to interrupt evermore
people.
But interrupting people well is not
easy and it doesn't really scale.
So first thing we have
to do is earn attention.
And if we earn attention over time,
we gain trust.
So if someone says, Tim Ferriss is
coming to give a speech tomorrow,
the other person doesn't say,
tell me exactly what he's going to say.
And then I'll decide if I want to come.
They say, oh, Tim Ferriss, I trust him,
I'll come.
That's what we seek to build.
So the book industry is magical because
the book industry 500 Years of the book
industry is someone at a publisher picked,
you said to their readers,
I care enough about this idea that I'll
spend x number of dollars to bring it to
you.
The bookstore said,
this is before there was
an infinite shelf space.
There are a lot of
books we could sell you,
but we picked this one
because the publisher is so
excited and then when by the
time the reader touches it,
it's a trustworthy object.
Now that's being hacked and
hacked and hacked some more.
You can buy your way into the New York
Times bestseller list for not much money.
You can self publish a book that
looks like a real book. You can put,
anyone can publish for the kindle,
therefore anyone does.
So we're stripping away the trust
building element of the book industry.
But if your book did work and people
encountered it and now they trust you,
then the job is to find
a social media platform.
There isn't one right answer
where you can continue to connect.
People continue to tell stories and so
you earn more trust, more permission,
which gets you more attention,
which gets more trust,
which lets you make the change
you want to make in the universe.
What opportunities were you offered?
Doesn't have to be specific that
you're glad you turned down. Are there,
are there any, are there any particular
examples that come to mind? And if not,
I can,
I can move on.
But I'm just curious if there are any
opportunities that you've turned down for
me.
For instance,
one of them would be like every
reality TV show invite I've ever had.
I'm thrilled. And I was singing, I
was extremely tempted early on. Uh,
but in retrospect, extremely happy.
I said no to all of that. Uh,
yes, that's, these does a great
point. TV runs deep in our culture,
so they wanted me to be on that super
famous one and then that other one.
And I never hesitated in saying no,
because that's the moment when you
decide who you want to be. Right.
And so I paid extra careful attention
to the question and after careful
attention to my answer,
and it resonated.
I would say the biggest
shift, uh, which is, uh,
for Silicon Valley people hard to get
your arms around because there's a game
being played there.
And it's just a game I've opted out
of is when I was at Yahoo during the
renaissance in 1999. Uh, uh, Bill Gross,
who's a super nice guy,
came to me and asked me to be a
head of marketing for the company.
He was building a,
it had Steven Spielberg on the board.
It was teed up to be,
you know,
the seventh next IPO and there were $1
billion in stock options on the table.
And I said to myself,
well, if I say yes to this,
I've decided what I do
for the rest of my life,
which is say yes to the next one because
I don't need to say yes to anise to buy
Cilantro and vodka.
Why would I say yes?
It's because I liked the
game and I didn't say yes.
And even though the billion dollars
in stock options never came around,
I think I'd be even more
proud of it if they had,
because the money is a story.
Once you have enough for beans and rice
and taking care of your family and a few
other things,
money is a story and you can tell yourself
any story you want about money and
it's better to tell yourself a story about
money then you can happily live with.
Could you, could you elaborate
on that a little bit? What is,
what is your story about money?
Is that what you just said? Uh,
because this is a really important point.
It's something I've been trying to
mull over and in the last year or so in
particular, well let me start with the
marketing story about money, which is,
uh,
take uh,
a $10 bill and go to the bus station
and walk up to someone and say,
I'll sell you this $10 bill for a
dollar and you should actually do this.
Uh, no one will buy it from you. And,
and there are a few reasons for this.
The first reason is no one goes to the
bus station hoping to do a financial
transaction.
The second one is only an insane person
would try to sell you a real $10 bill
for a dollar.
And dealing with insane people is tricky.
So it must not be a real $10 bill.
You should just walk away.
Now let's try a different thing.
Put a $10 bill in your neighbor's
mailbox when he's not home and runaway.
Do it the next day.
Do it the third day on the fourth day.
Ring your neighbor's
tent a doorbell and say,
I'm the guy who left three
$10 bills in your mailbox.
Here is another one.
You want to buy it for a dollar,
you'll sell it because
your knows you're crazy,
but you're crazy in a very particular
way and you've earned the trust that it's
a real $10 bill,
right?
So we assume that $10
bills are worth $10 but no,
it's a, it's a mutual belief.
And if the belief isn't present,
they're worth nothing.
Now we get to our internal
narrative about money.
Is money that number,
it's not even pieces of paper anymore.
It's a number on a screen. Is that a
reflection of your worth as a human?
Right.
One of the things that Derek said on
your podcast that I sort of disagree with
is that being rich is a signal,
a symbol that you've created a lot
of value for a lot of people. Uh,
I think lots of times
that's actually not true.
And there are lots of ways to create
value for people and most of them do not
involve money.
So what we have to decide once we're okay,
once we're not living on $3 a day, once
we have a roof, once we have healthcare,
is we have to decide how much more money
and what am I going to trade for it
because we always trade something for it.
Unless we're fortunate enough that the
very thing we want to do is the thing
that also gives us our maximum income.
And I don't think that merely because
some blog decides that people with big
valuations are doing better. That
doesn't mean you should listen to them.
So when you think of the word,
if you even think of this word,
but when you hear the word successful,
who's the first person who
comes to mind for you and why?
MMM.
You know,
my parents were successful because of
how many people they mattered to. Uh,
my friend Jacqueline Novogratz,
who I think should win the Nobel prize,
who runs the Acumen Fund
is insanely successful.
She is changing whole continents of the
earth by bringing an idea to the fore
and doing it relentlessly for
year after year after year. Um,
and then I think about, you know, uh,
people in my neighborhood
who are successful because
they get to shovel their
neighbor's walk whose elderly
and it's snowed last night.
And that privilege and that trust,
that's some live a successful life.
Is there anything you've changed your
mind about in the last few years?
Other than the web being dumb, other
than the web being dumb? Yeah, there are,
there are, there are bunch of
things. Um, you know, I have, uh,
changed my mind in each direction
about the book industry,
about it not mattering
that about it mattering.
And now at about it being in
a sad but slow decline. Uh,
I've changed my mind about
the big companies in the,
of our Internet.
I think that they changed around the
same time I changed my mind maybe before
that.
Uh,
they went from being
really profoundly useful,
important public goods that created
enormous value to being public companies
where there's so much pressure
on management by everyone
who works there to make
the stock price go up,
that they don't often make decisions
in the public good and a more,
and I was probably naive to think
that they would keep doing it,
but they are stopping.
Uh,
what is something that you believe that
other people think is crazy or insane?
And this is a bastardization of Peter
Teal question that he's as an interview
sometimes, but, um, I think,
I think that deep down I am certain
that people are plastic in the positive
sense, flexible and able to grow. Uh,
I think almost everything is made not
born and that makes people uncomfortable
because it puts them on the hook.
But I truly believe it.
What is the book or the books that
you've given most as a gift or as gifts
besides your own,
if you've given your own?
Well, I want to talk about my own
because, yeah. Well let you know,
definitely we can talk to your spouse.
You're talking about your
movie if you're an actor,
but you're not supposed to talk about
your book. If you're an author. I wrote,
I wrote your turn so I could give it away.
And so I spoke at a high
school two weeks ago.
I gave every student to copy
a month before I got there.
And there are very few books that are
written to be given away in the sense
that,
uh,
most books are purchased by the person
in 10 done reading them and you write a
book differently if you think
it's going to be given away. Um,
but I've also given away many copies of
Cory Doctorow is books if you're into
three d printing and stuff makers,
if you're into a security
and privacy little brother,
uh,
I've given away tons of copies of
the right kind of science fiction.
Uh, let me distinguish
between a couple of kinds.
The movies have ruined science fiction
because they have created this sort of
violent Dystopian,
uh,
we all ought to become survivalists,
Zombie fueled science fiction.
That isn't what science fiction was for.
Uh,
the other kind of science fiction is
the science fiction that fundamentally
rewires your brain.
And this is one reason why,
uh, live tweeting a speech
is it makes no sense.
And why taking tons of notes on
certain kinds of books make no sense.
Because as a Scott McCloud
pointed in his brilliant book,
understanding comics,
which I have given away many,
many copies of all the action in comics
happens in between the panels that
that's why comics are an art form.
Because in panel a,
something happened in panel B,
something happened,
but it's what happened between a and B.
The changed your mind about anything,
the actions in your head.
Well,
the same thing is true in a
great science fiction book.
If you read snow crash c for
sure. Good Book. Such a good book.
It's such a good book, but you can't
give it to someone. Now I've tried,
it doesn't work. You have to read it
before you've been on the Internet. Uh,
and then then it changes your mind.
Right?
Or if you read diamond age before you've
thought about molecular anything or
three d printing, then it changes
your mind. You know, he, he,
he wrote that book before the Ipad,
before the kindle.
It's just that shift is now I tell you
this shift and now the book doesn't work
the way it would have if I
hadn't told you that the shift,
cause it's when it shifts in your head.
So if you,
if you read Dune and you don't read
it for the plot but you read it for
understanding geopolitics,
suddenly something clicks in your head.
If you read pattern
recognition by William Gibson,
you don't even have to finish it.
Just read the first five chapters and
suddenly you will now understand what a
brand is.
And it's just,
those are the kinds of books that I
give away a lot separate from the books
in audio that I give away,
which I had been saving for you to ask
me about because audio is my focus for
today.
Oh, let's get into it. No, I mean I, I've,
I'm a by virtue of doing this podcast
and a also becoming involved with audio
books. I'm all about audio
right now, so please just, I'll,
I'll let you take them up.
Here we go.
So what we explained,
I explained was certain kinds of books
work cause they cause something to flip
in your head.
They cannot be digested.
They set you up and they
take it to the next step.
Audio is different because you can listen
to it again and again and again and
you listen to it when you don't think you
are paying attention and it's working.
And when I make a list of books
that have profoundly influenced me,
they tend to be books that I have listened
to. Well, in the case of the first one,
I'll start with so many times
that I wore out 72 cassettes.
They could not be played anymore.
And I had to buy another $500 set.
That's when I didn't have
$500 to spend on 72 cassettes.
And that Zig Ziglar,
zig is your grandfather
and my grandfather, he's
Tony Robbins grandfather.
None of us would be here if
it weren't for zig. And uh,
some of his politics and some of his
outlook on life are extremely dated.
And I disagreed with them.
But the fundamental principles of goal
setting and motivation and the fear
people have of saying yes
when you sell to them.
Those were the three sections
of the stuff just kept me going.
And again and again and again.
And I told him the one time
we worked together, I said,
anytime you need me to stand in for you,
I, you can even do it with the accent
because that's how many times I listened.
So that's the first one.
Is there a particular name to the series
or is there just one audio set by zig?
Well now there's, so there's one series,
I guess it's a collection, right? Right.
Three series,
one series on goal setting.
One series called how to stay motivated
and one series called secrets of closing
the sale. Yeah. On secrets
of closing the sale.
Zig tells a 17 minute story about a
guy in St Louis shining his shoes.
So just if you just listen to one story,
if you're into selling,
you're just listening to that story.
10 Times can listen once 10 times you'll
become a different kind of salesperson.
And if you, if you listen to this
story about his friend in Canada,
you will understand what motivation is.
If you listen to him talking about how
we rewire our brains with goal setting.
I mean you, Tim, I've
talked about it so much,
but it's a really fascinating
glimpse at 1960 and I encourage it.
Number two, almost the flip side, uh,
the recorded works of Pema
Chodron, c h. O, d r. O. N.
And I'm guessing you've talked about
her in the past. She has come up. Yeah.
She is a Buddhist nun who has
a monastery in Nova Scotia.
And, uh, Pema, uh,
we'll also get under your skin
in a totally different way.
She is a disciple of Chung Trump.
RMP Shea, who was the first, uh,
full Buddhist monk in the u s uh,
the way to understand his teaching
is in one tiny little parable,
which is this,
we are falling,
falling with nothing to hold on
to and nothing to slow us down.
The good news is there
is no ground to land on.
So those are two then, uh, inspired by
the two of them and some work I did,
I did it something for
charity called leap first.
That's a short audio book that captures
some of the things I was trying to teach
people, uh, about this. And you
can get that at sounds true.
I have four more,
uh,
working our way from the
nonfiction to more lyrical,
uh,
the art of possibility,
which is very hard to find on audio
and is totally worth seeking out.
It's by Roz Zander and her
husband Ben Friends of mine. Uh,
Ben is the a symphony conductor in Boston
and Roz is a social worker and the two
of them will completely change the
way you think about possibility,
about enrollment, about
leadership. And again,
I listened to it probably
once a month in the car.
Just put it on in the middle.
It doesn't matter where you start.
The next one is the war of art.
Also hard to find that audio.
I find Steve's voice to be fascinating.
And um,
even before I knew him, I was fascinated
by listening to him speak his own work,
uh, to left, uh, just kids,
which is the single best audio
book ever recorded by Patti Smith.
It is not going to change
the way you do business,
but it might change the way you live.
It's about love and loss and art.
It's about non confidence and confidence.
Uh,
and it's mostly about having
a best friend. It's magic.
And I can just hear her quoting Robert.
Patty.
So curt and then the last one I'm going
to tell you outta left field is a book
called debt by David Graber.
Uh,
I recommended an audio because David
is sometimes repetitive and a little
elliptical, but in audio it's all okay
because you can just listen to it again.
Debt is a,
David was on tenure track at Yale.
Then he cofounded the occupy movement and
sort of looks like they threw him out.
Um,
he's an anthropologist and he studies
lots of things in our ancient history.
His theory about where did
money come from is mind blowing.
And I'll give you the short
version, which is, uh,
every economics textbook and he quotes
seven of them teaches that people got
tired of carrying around a
goat to trade for a sheep.
And it's hard to cut it up to trade
for some butter and some bread.
So with all that trading in the little
village square that looks something like
Salem, Massachusetts, one day someone
said, let's have money instead.
And everyone was happy.
It turns out there's no evidence
that this ever happened once,
anywhere in the universe
never,
never stops the writing though.
And instead he argues very
persuasively that, um,
money was invented to keep track of debt.
And that debt predates money.
And this is a book about simple
debt and then the debt that leads to
prostitution and then the debt that
leads to marriage debt and then the debt
that leads to developing nations being
billions of dollars in debt to the rich
world merely because a
dictator stolen a lot of money.
And I found it completely rewired the
way I thought our world actually worked.
Uh, I'm not ready to go stand on the
battle lines of the next occupy movement,
but I really have far more color and
insight now as to what money is and how it
changed everything because
it's all about debt.
Which of these going from Zig to Pema
and onward down to debt with David,
which of these do you
think I should start with?
Or which one would you
suggest I start with? Well,
I think it's important to realize that
audio books are a practice that real
books are not. You can, uh, read
real books the way you and I do,
which is read a chapter and then decide
if chapter two has earned it or not. Um,
but I find that like dieting,
you're not going to get any benefit
if you just start and see how it goes.
So for me,
if you're feeling stuck,
it's all about the war of art
and the art of possibility.
If you are feeling stressed,
it's about Pema.
If you need to see a path that is more
colored than the one you're already on,
which is pretty technicolor,
then it zig.
And if you just want to cry a little,
it's just kids.
And then debt is the one that's
as closest to reading a book.
I don't think many people
should listen to debt 10 times.
And uh, this is not exactly debt,
but just on a, on a money theme,
uh,
can you think of any $100 or less purchase
that has heavily impacted your life
in the last six months or recent memory?
So,
you know,
once the Stereo is working,
it doesn't make sense to buy more stereo
equipment because that's just silly and
you can do better than that.
Um,
but where you could do is
become obsessed with our teas.
Anol bean to bar chocolate. Okay. I'm,
I'm saying one could not that one should,
but one could.
So I did and I worked my
way up the ladder, uh,
about a year ago I was about to start my
own chocolate company because it's not
that hard.
Um,
and then I bumped into a few brands that
were doing it better than I ever could.
And so there is a company in
western Massachusetts called
rogue chocolate, r, O, g,
u e, and you can only buy
their stuff preorder by mail,
12 bucks for a chocolate bar.
And I'd pay 20 happily because
a party happens in your mouth.
That's like a whole new ball game.
So every day there's,
I have a huge pile of
artisinal chocolates here,
only dark chocolate please.
And um,
I'm actually an advisor to a new
acumen company called Krakow hunters in
Colombia. But there are two chocolate
companies I want to highlight rogue,
which mentioned and ask a nosy rogue
because I don't believe it's possible to
make better chocolate than they are.
I think Satan works with them.
And the second one Aszkenazy because
Shawn who used to be a lawyer is living a
life that is worth noting
and possibly emulating.
He not only buys his beans from farmers
in the Philippines and other countries
who he meets,
but he puts their
children to school and uh,
he has built a practice of
creating a worthwhile luxury.
Good.
That directly benefits people.
Not sort of, not a little but directly.
Nice. How'd you spell ask? A nosy.
I want to write Ashkenazi, but
that's not the same thing. Right?
That's what I say in my head every time.
It's a S.
K. I. N. O. S. I. E.
I don't do the marketing for them
cause if I did it probably would have a
different name. I'm
just saying. So anyway,
this chocolate habit is finally the vice
I had been looking for my whole life.
I can, I can tell the difference
between a one continent, another.
I can tell how long they conked it for.
I can talk about [inaudible] Compton.
I don't know what that means.
I know what I've like a cock, this,
the, this a marine mammal on mammal.
I'm Moelis is, but so what is conk?
Okay, what does her hands chuck?
Here's how you make chocolate.
Cocoa Pod is like a nerf football and
you throw them on a net for a while and
they ferment and then your crack them
open and you're driving in the sun and
inside each one or something about
three times the size of a coffee bean,
the shell, uh, you can't eat.
That means that there's
about to be a lot of labor.
But before you can take the shell off,
you roast them and then
after they're roasted,
you have to one by one take the shell off.
And that's really hard. And people have
made these really cool machines to do it,
but it's still hard.
Then you're left with nibs.
These nibs are unsweetened
and but if you eat one,
they taste a little like dark chocolate,
then you take it and you put it in this
machine that grinds them and grinds them
and grinds them.
And as they are being ground Davey,
lease a little bit in the oil and the
liquor and it became smoother and smoother
and smoother. Interesting. Side note,
it turns out that the machine that
you can use to do this at home is also
capable of making Italy out of rice,
which are those delectable
little Indian Kreps.
So a guy from India who loves chocolate
figure this out and he imports Italy
makers puts a new sticker on them and
sells them as sharklet conking machines.
So you put,
it's to granite stones,
the they're in there and you
can do it for up to six hours.
And what happens is soon after
40 50 hours in the machine,
it's at a micron size that your tongue
can no longer tell when you make it even
smaller,
you then take that liquid,
you'll put it if you're adding
sugar in a tempering machine.
Tempering is another really cool device
that causes all of the molecules in the
chocolate to line up in a
certain direction by taking
the chocolate to a cool
but not too cool temperatures. So it's
still liquid, not too hot, not too cold.
And by spinning it around,
all the molecules line up.
And that is why chocolate
bars snap when you break them.
And why they don't turn gray in the air.
If you don't temper it,
you don't get either of those effects.
It's like a, it's like an MRI
machine for Coachella molecules. Uh,
that, you know, I did some,
I actually did a little bit of tempering
back in the day making truffles ages
ago and Saratoga,
Saratoga. It was a blast.
I recommend everybody take
a take a chocolate making
class if you can. So this,
this is great. Rogue chocolate.
And where's Rowe chocolate based?
Just because there's more than one.
The one that you're referring to.
Hold on.
I just ate up all of my last batch
so I can't look at the label,
but I can tell you that
they are in three rivers,
Massachusetts. Three rivers
mess. Okay. And, uh, on,
on the, uh, subject of eating, what
do your eating habits look like?
What does your diet look like? Yeah,
it's really not good. It's not good.
Not good cause I'm bored by it.
But people are fascinated when we
go out to dinner because there's so,
I don't eat wheat. I don't eat dairy. I
don't eat Cilantro. I don't eat meat. Um,
because each time I sort of
adjust what I eat, I feel better.
And so I feel like I am in a happy
place where I can make fascinating,
interesting food and mostly eat happily
in restaurants without being obsessive
about it.
What is the first say, two hours of
your day look like? And what is Breck,
what is your,
what does a typical breakfast?
Uh, breakfast is one more decision I
don't make. So it's a frozen banana,
hemp powder,
almond milk.
I dried plum and some walnuts in,
uh,
the blender. And, um,
then I make coffee for whoever comes
over that morning and for my lovely wife,
uh,
meanwhile I've probably done an hour and
a half of stuff online before seven 30.
Um, so then I know the world didn't break
when I was asleep and then I can get to
work.
What is the half hour of triage,
Internet triage or computer
triage look like? What do you,
what types of things are
you doing in that half hour?
Well, the most important thing is, uh,
did the blog work because if it didn't,
I have to take evasive action.
But I love the guys at typepad.
It's the best 29 bucks a month I spend
because it doesn't crash and it works.
Um,
and then I tried to clear the email box.
Uh, I live, I've lived
in inbox zero since, uh,
before it was coined and um,
now my brain is free.
And so then I try not to be an email
hound until I've done actual productive
work. And then I come to the apartment
where I work and other people join me here
sometimes. And we work on the Alt
Mba, which is a school I am building.
And um,
that's what I do for work.
And, uh, when was the last time
you worked at home if you ever did?
Well, if there's a laptop
or I'm not unconscious,
I'm at work in the sense that what
I do for a living is notice things.
Right, right. I guess the
reason I ask is I've, I've,
I've long considered getting an office
as opposed to operating out of coffee
shops and miscellaneous locations.
Uh,
and that is the,
the context behind the,
yeah, it's, I do much better in this room.
This room is, I couldn't recreate
this room for $10 million.
It's got so much Patina,
it's got Patina on the Patina.
And that sets a bar for me about the
fact that I don't want to compromise just
to do the next thing. Because I look at
the last thing or the thing before that.
And I said, damn, I'm proud of that. Don't
do something you're not proud of. So,
you know, the alt Mba w I
wouldn't be running. It's still,
if it wasn't the single most important
educational thing I've ever done,
and that's what I keep trying to do is
the next thing's gotta be worthy of it or
else I might as well just take a break.
Could you elaborate?
Because a lot of the questions from my
fans on Twitter and Facebook were related
to education and they, they
generally came in the form of, uh,
in a number of themes. One was, you know,
could you have him elaborate on his
education manifesto on the other was,
hey,
I have a kid who's in fourth grade.
I have a kid who's just
going to be entering school.
What would Seth do in my shoes?
Um,
and you don't have to tackle
those right off the bat,
but as that is context,
could you,
could you tell us more
about what you're up to?
All right, so this is a rant
and is not about what I'm up to.
It's about what I was up
to and the rant is this,
sooner or later parents have to take
responsibility for putting their kids into
a system that is indebting them
and teaching them to be cogs in a,
in a economy that doesn't
want cogs anymore.
And parents get to decide,
uh,
I'm a huge fan of public school,
send my kids to public school.
I think everyone should go
to public school cause it's
a great mix master of our
world.
But from three o'clock to 10 o'clock,
those kids are getting homeschooled and
they're either getting homeschooled and
watching the Flintstones or are they
getting homeschooled in learning something
useful. And I think we need
to teach kids two things.
One, how to lead and to how
to solve interesting problems.
Because the fact is there are plenty
of countries on earth where there are
people who are willing to be obedient
and work harder for less money than us.
So we cannot out
obedience the competition.
Therefore we have to out lead
or out solve the other people.
I don't care what country they live in,
Wyoming or across the world who want that.
Whatever is scarce.
The way you teach your kids to solve
interesting problems is to give them
interesting problems to solve and then
don't criticize them when they
fail because kids aren't stupid.
If they get in trouble every time they
tried to solve an interesting problem,
they'll just go back to getting an a by
memorizing what's in the textbook that
it's so important here. And I spend
an enormous amount of time with kids.
Uh, I produced the wizard of
Oz, the musical in fourth grade.
I used to help run a summer camp.
Uh,
I think that it's a privilege
to be able to look a trusting,
energetic,
smart,
11 year old in the eye and tell him the
truth and what we can say to that 11
year old is,
I really don't care how you
did on your vocabulary test.
I care about whether you have something
to say and we can teach our kids from a
young age to be the kind of people we
want them to be and anything that's worth
memorizing is worth looking up now.
So we don't need to have them spend a
lot of time getting good grades so they
can go into a famous college because
famous colleges don't work anymore.
Famous college isn't the point anymore.
The point is,
is there an entity that will have trouble
living without you when you seek to
earn a living? Because if there is,
you'll be able to make a living.
If on the other hand,
you're waiting in the placement
office for someone to pick you,
you will be persistently undervalued.
You talked earlier about
writing daily as a practice,
listening to the audio
books as a practice.
Are there any practices that you would
suggest to the kind of overwhelmed,
busy parent who wants to start to be
more proactive in this department?
They have an 11 year old. Are there
any practices or exercises that they,
that you would suggest?
Well,
you know super well that busy
is a trap and the is a myth.
So what could possibly be
more important than your kid?
Please don't play the busy card.
If you spend two hours a day without an
electronic device looking your kid in
the eye, talking to them and
solving interesting problems,
you will raise a different kid
than someone who doesn't do that.
And that's one of the reasons why I
cook dinner every night because what a
wonderful semi distracted environment
for the kid to tell you the truth for you
to have low stakes,
but super important conversations
with someone who's important to you.
Right? That this idea, get home from work,
put on your sneakers and go
for a walk with your kid.
You know my friend Brian walks
his daughter to school every day.
That's priceless. Well, how
can you be too busy to do that?
And the work you're doing now.
So I did a couple of courses for
skillshare. They worked really well.
They were very highly rated and
they had an 80% dropout rate,
which is way better than anybody else
because other online courses that have a
97% dropout rate than I did,
of course for you to me.
And the same thing
happened and I'm thinking,
I loved making these courses and you know,
there I am on screen,
it sounds like me.
But why are people dropping out
of my courses and everyone else's?
And the reason is because when it gets
hard and there's no social pressure,
you leave.
So what I said was how do I make
the opposite of an online course?
And that meant instead of a million
people a hundred it meant instead of being
free, it's expensive. Instead
of letting everyone in,
you have to apply instead of being easy.
It's hard.
And instead of being on your own,
it's a group thing where there are
coaches watching you all the time.
And instead of lectures,
it's 100% projects.
So I built it to see what would happen.
And so the Alt Mba is for
people at big companies.
We've got people from whole foods and
Microsoft and it's for people that tiny
companies,
and it's not for everybody,
but we get this cohort of people and uh,
there's a coach for every 10. We put
them in slack, we put them in wordpress,
we give him 14 assignments
over a 28 day period of time.
And we sprint as fast as we can.
And it's unbelievable.
Tim, I just gotta tell you
it's an unbelievable, cause
I'm not actively involved.
I just watch and because eventually the
goal is to have more of these sessions.
I can't be in them if they have more of
them and people change because we don't
give them any other choice.
Could you, could you expand
on the social pressure piece?
I think this is such an important
point and I was asked recently,
I get asked all the time,
maybe you get asked this too,
but like how do you maintain
the discipline or how do
you change this habit?
How do you do this?
And my answer is almost always the sound.
Like you have to have a punishment or a
reward for following or not following it
for doing it or not
doing it. And it's, it's,
it's just incredible to see how people
who have never been able to lose weight
before,
as soon as they have $100 of their own
money on the line and it's a betting pool,
five other people who will be
able to heckle them at the office,
all of a sudden they figure it out really
quickly in the how to isn't as hard.
But uh, in, in, in this
particular example,
could you expand on the, uh, the social
aspect because I think it's really,
really important and transfers and
applies to a lot of other areas.
There are some people in some areas who
have this self discipline necessary to
get the work done that needs to get
done. You know, those people and I need,
I know those people and
when we find one of them,
it's fabulous.
Like I think I am like that with certain
parts of my craft in that no one would
notice if I didn't do it the way I do it.
I just choose to do it.
When it comes to education though,
all of us have 12 to 20
years of brainwashing going
on with which is epitomized
by one sentence.
I hate with a passion,
which is will this be on the test?
Right? So as soon as you say
will this beyond the test,
you've instantly defined
why you are doing something.
And then when we invite you to an
online course for free on artificial
intelligence in which
there is no certificate,
which there is no accreditation and
you get to problem number four and it's
really hard and you ask yourself,
will this be on the test?
And then you realize there is no test
and no one even knows you're taking the
course. Then you stop and you go eat
some m and m's and you turn on the TV.
And so the goal here was,
um,
if you need,
if you benefit,
if you thrive from being in an environment
where you will push yourself to get
what you wanted all along,
I'll give you people who will push you,
your fellow students and your
coaches and there won't be a test.
And there won't be great.
It's this is better than that.
This is teaching you to internalize
the narrative of my mom's not here,
my mom's not watching,
but I should act like she was,
who do you in, in, in your life,
who helps tell you you're wrong or point
out when your work isn't good or uh,
otherwise, you know, talk
to the emperor so to speak,
because you've had so much success.
There's,
there's always the risk that people will
tell you what you want to hear or just
give you, uh, give you praise in,
in all circumstances.
Who Do you lean on for the,
the truth,
when you,
when you need bitter truth sometimes.
Okay.
So I would break this
into two kinds of people.
I have been blessed by being surrounded
by very skeptical people and,
um, you know, people who
turned to me and 1991 and said,
this internet thing's never going to
amount to anything or an English teacher
who wrote in my yearbook, uh,
you are the bane of my existence.
You will never write
anything worth reading.
Well, hold on, let me just
pause there for a second.
What did you do to this guy or the woman?
I dedicated one of my books to her.
Did you send it to her?
Yes, I did. How did, how did she take
that? She was, she was, she had a tongue
in cheek. How long? She was fine. Um,
but so that they're sort of uninformed.
Skepticism is easy,
at least for me to find partly
cause I don't live in San Francisco,
not fully in the echo chamber,
drinking the Koolaid.
Um, but the other kind
is so rare, so scarce,
so precious. I only get little
dribs of it now. And then,
which is someone who gets you,
someone who can see right
through to your soul,
who with generosity and care can
look you in the eye, hand you back,
something that you say, I think this
would be better if you did it again.
And um, I had a business partner, Steve,
who was like that in
1979 and 81 80 and 81.
And finding that again in a consistent
way is really precious and really hard.
Yeah. That is difficult. Um,
what advice would you give your 30 year
old self and if you could place us for
you, like where you
are, what you're doing.
Um, I'm going to cheat because I've
been asked this question before.
Cheating's allowed. So first, do you know
about the science fiction book replay?
Uh, no, I don't really hunt. Brilliant
game changer replay. All right.
Is, uh, I will tell you it's a,
it's the best time travel
book ever written anyway.
I had so many bumps starting
when I was 30 years old.
They lasted for nine years and I wouldn't
tell my 30 year old self anything
because if I hadn't had those bumps I
wouldn't be me. And I'm glad I'm me.
What was the, if you're
comfortable telling us, I mean,
what was the hardest or one of the
hardest bumps in that period of time?
Um,
you know,
I was trying to shift my dream of
what I wanted to do for a living.
I was growing up, I was
failing at business. Uh,
I had some quiet,
relentless,
repeated failures of no,
I had failures of sloppiness
where if I knew what I knew now,
I wouldn't have done something and they
would have saved me a year of my life.
Um,
there were failures of how big does
something need to be and all sorts of
visible scarring that,
um,
was hard.
But it was part of the deal when you have
a protracted difficult
period of time like that is,
is there any particular activity or
technique or self talk that you use to try
to get back on your feet
more quickly?
While now I'm so much better at it because
of Pema and because of meditation and
because of,
um,
knowing how to sit with it and not
insist that the tension go away.
The other thing that's important here,
uh,
as long as we're getting personal
is I had to make a decision, uh,
after I sold my company about whether I
wanted to continue facing professional
existential crises because
Yoyodyne and the projects before that
we're right on the edge for a really long
time. One more mistake. You're out
of the game. And I like the game.
I didn't want to be out of the gate.
There's a thrill to dancing
with existential crises.
And I know plenty of people who
have been lucky, like I was,
who got right back in.
So they get more existential crises.
And I made the decision that I liked
the game too much to bet all the chips.
So I never do
meaning that it could, could you
rephrase that? Yeah, I'm well,
I'm not sure I know what you mean.
Sure.
So if I understand what you mean about
the existential crises 100% because I
know so many people who just, they're
addicted to that roller coaster. Uh,
but when you said not betting all
the chips, right, so let's say I took
100% of the trust I have in my brand and
put it behind something really daring
and huge, that might not work. And
so if at the end it doesn't work,
and now no one ever trusts me again,
uh,
that's an existential crisis that's going
to get you out of bed in the morning,
isn't it? Um, I don't
want to do that. Right.
I don't want to violate the trust
I've earned with people or risk risk,
violating that trust risk,
violating that trust.
So that keeps me from doing certain
things that people with resources could
choose to do.
But I don't want to play that game.
What is your meditation
practice look like?
It's sloppy. It works. It's
nothing worth writing home about.
That's okay. Maybe it's worth mentioning
briefly. I just, even if sloppy, I,
I, I mean, I, and look in, in
full disclosure when people, I've,
journalists asked me, you know, can I,
but we want to follow you for a day.
And I'm like, no, you don't. You
really don't. It, it's going.
It'll be like watching a adaptation
with nic cage and was like,
it's going to be so boring
for you. Uh, but what,
what does the sloppy
meditative practice look like?
My friend Susan Piver runs the largest
online meditation center in the world,
and so every once in a while
I dropped in on her thing. Uh,
I go to the Shambala Center on Sundays
in New York sometimes and sit for half an
hour. But usually, uh, I'm pretty
good at getting into this data.
I need to pretty quickly.
So I'll just sit and I'll
close my eyes and I'll breathe.
And when I've had enough of that,
I'll go back to what I was doing.
Do you have a set time for that? Do you
tend to do it in the morning? So, no,
I don't quantify that stuff.
I quantify almost nothing in my life,
which I'm okay with the, not that you
care, but the work should care. But the,
the, is there a state that triggers
you to sit down and meditate?
Well, yeah. If the narrative is getting
in the way of what's actually happening,
you need to make it so that the narrative
gently backs off and it's really hard
to yell at the narrative and make it back
off right away because that just makes
the narrative louder.
So instead I will undermine it by making
it surrounded by nothing until it sort
of melts away.
I took a, uh, an acting club,
my first ever acting class.
I have no plans to act. Uh,
with this, uh, incredible
guy named Josh Paice,
very successful actor classes
called committed impulse. And when,
when people's mind mind's wandered,
we were instructed to say, you know,
I'm back and there were a
bunch of exercises intended
to make us fully present
to our bottle,
a bodily sensations and whatnot.
And it struck me how applicable all
of that was to exactly what you're
describing,
which is not trying to fight
the riptide of this narrative,
but to just be acutely aware of it.
And I never really thought
of it as meditation,
but I started doing this thing and
I don't know how I started doing it,
but just a three breath break,
like literally just cause I
was always told I count to 10,
do 10 breaths and for whatever he says,
too impatient for that. I was like,
all right, it's just three breaths.
And uh, it found it incredibly,
incredibly helpful as someone who has
some extremely self defeating narratives,
attend to surface all the time.
Uh,
if you could have one billboard anywhere
with anything on it, what would it say?
Uh, Jay Levenson, another old
friend who passed away recently.
I look guerrilla marketing and he liked
to say the best billboard in history
said, free coffee. Next exit
free coffee. Next exit. Uh,
have you given commencement speeches?
Seth,
I have been asked.
Let's go over this.
A whole bunch of people who
don't want to hear from you
waiting for you to be done.
I suppose that's one way to look at it.
So that's the reason why you have
not done commencement speeches.
Ding, Ding, Ding. Let's,
all right, so let's say,
uh, with, with your class,
right, with, with uh,
with your MBA you have, you are giving
the commencement speech to them.
They're motivated.
They do want to hear from you.
They're not waiting to get shit faced
two hours later, or maybe they are,
but not all of them. Uh, what would, what
would you, what would you say to them?
Well, I would like to believe
that one out of every three days,
my blog is a commencement speech,
right?
When it's not talking about
technology or marketing,
I'm talking about respect
and talking about choice.
I'm talking about the impact we can make.
And you know the,
the problem with commencement speeches
is the only ones we hear are the ones
that were transcribed and
written for people like us,
not for actual graduate.
Right.
Because what we really want to say to
actual graduate is just a reminder of what
they should have heard at
least three times a day and
every one of their classes.
And that is you are more
powerful than you think you are.
Act accordingly.
I like that. Just if, just a few
more questions. This has been,
you're doing great. It feels like
we've only been talking for 50.
Oh yeah, no, this is super fun.
I just love every opportunity that,
that I have to chat with you.
Just a few more.
Do you have any ask or
request for my audience?
And the next question is just going
to be where people can find you.
So this is effectively the last question,
but do you have any ask or request for
my audience suggestion for the people
listening? Anything at all? You'd
just like to transmit to them.
Uh,
send someone a thank you note tomorrow.
Do you have any particular way that
you like to send thank you notes?
No, that's, I'm, I'm giving
people a lots of freedom here.
Well freedom. I think that's a great place
to actually wrap up. I think your work,
you're thinking, uh, the,
the daily contact that people
can have with your blog,
even if they get some type of anx by,
by,
by skipping one or two a week instead
of sending you an angry note, uh, is,
is really significant. So, uh,
I would just want to thank you for putting
it all out into the world and I think
are able to create greater freedom for
themselves and the people they care about
as a result of it. So I'd say it's
a meaningful thing that you do.
And where can people were,
where can people find you online?
The basics, where would you like them
to learn more about what you're up to?
And of course for everybody listening,
we will put a tons of links in the show
notes and I'll give out that URL when we
wrap up. But Seth, where can,
where can people find you on
the interwebs were elsewhere?
My mother's plan was to name me
Scott and my grandfather said to her,
don't do that.
That's a brand of toilet paper.
And so she named me Seth instead.
And if you type Seth into
the Google there, I will be
well that it would not have worked if
my name was Scott. That's very true.
Well that keeps it simple. Seth.
Thank you so much for the time. Uh,
and you know what,
we should,
we should maybe I really want to recommend
this because I almost ate an entire
box. Can we talk? Can we touch on
the almond cookies for one second?
Let's talk about, all right, so you
want to take it from here. I just,
my wife was a gluten free or not.
My wife was a workaholic lawyer for 25
years and then she quit and she decided
to open a bakery, but our little town
probably wouldn't attract enough people.
So it became a gluten
free dairy free bakery.
And now there's three of them,
two in Manhattan,
one in Hastings on Hudson called
by the way, they don't ship.
So you're going to have to get yourself
on an airplane and go to the, by the way,
bakery,
don't bother telling them that I sent
you because you will not get a discount.
And why is why the name,
by the way.
So, uh, the idea, I was, uh,
teaching naming one of the long form
free seminars I ran years ago and the
bakery was just getting started.
So we used it as a case study and one
of the students understood that you
shouldn't call it the gluten
free dairy free bakery in town.
You should come up with a name that
carries value. And the value here is,
by the way, it's gluten
free. Who would have known?
And the,
the question that I asked your wife
that I will give the answer to was,
if I could only have one thing
at the bakery, what should I try?
And the almond cookies were
the first answer. I'm Sh and
I've heard, uh, we have a,
we with a mutual friend,
Jeff Jeffery Zurawski.
Jay Z and the four hour chef for those
of you have read it, uh, who's named,
named off a whole list of
others that I need to try.
But the Allmond cookies are amazing.
You just have to try them. And, uh, I can
tolerate dairy, I can tolerate gluten.
These are just a home
run. And I remember, uh,
having a box in the,
uh,
in a hotel in New York City and I sat
down and I opened it and I knew it was
trouble as soon as I saw the cookies
and I had one and I was like, okay,
that's enough. Put it away. It wasn't
one of my cheat days. And you know,
three quarters of a box
later, I'm like, all right,
I have to give these to the staff or
I'm going to eat this entire box. But,
uh, the, uh, yeah, I will,
I will leave it at that.
And for those of you who
follow my, my, my stuff,
you know that I love pastries and I have
a high bar. So, uh, on that note said,
thank you so much for all the time.
Hopefully get to see you again soon.
And to everybody listening,
you can find the show notes with
links to everything that Seth has
mentioned@fourhourworkweek.com
forward slash podcast and a Seth.
Any other parting words? You know, I
usually end by saying go make a Ruckus,
but in your case I don't need
to because you always do.
Thank you for leading us
this. Ferris. Thank you. So,
until next time guys,
thank you for listening.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short
email from me every Friday?
That provides a little more soul of
fun before the weekend and five bullet
Friday is a very short email where I share
the coolest things I've found or that
I've been pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends for instance,
and it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend,
so if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour workweek.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled out
and just drop in your email and you'll
get the very next one and if you sign up,
I hope you enjoy it.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is a great partner for
creating and growing your business.
It's a one stop shop for
all of your graphic design
needs, whether that's a logo,
website,
business card or anything else.
I used 99 designs to get book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to become a number one New
York Times best seller and I also use
them for banner ads, illustrations
and other things with 99 designs,
designers around the world compete
to create the best design for you.
You give feedback and
then pick your favorite.
You end up happy or you get your
money back, it's very simple.
You can check out a few of my own designs
and those of yours meaning Tim Ferriss,
show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and right now my
listeners, you guys will get a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
That's 99 designs.com forward slash Tim
this episode is
brought to you by audible,
which I've used for years.
I love audiobooks and I've two
to recommend right off the bat.
Number one is perhaps my favorite
audio book of all time and that is the
graveyard book by Neil Gaiman.
The only audiobook I've wanted to
immediately listen to a second time.
As soon as I finished. It's amazing.
You will thank me the graveyard book.
The second is vagabonding by Rolf Potts,
which had a huge impact on my life and
formed the basis for a lot of what became
the four hour workweek.
So all you need to do to get your free
audio book and a Free 30 Day trial is go
to audible.com forward slash 10 and
you can choose one of those two books,
the graveyard book vagabonding or
more than 180,000 audio programs.
So that could be a book. That could be
a magazine, that could be a newspaper,
could be a class. It's that easy.
Go to audible.com forward slash Tim,
that's audible.com forward slash Tim
and grab a book. And until next time,
thank you for listening.