All right. What's up guys and Shay?
Carl, thanks for the inspiration.
A number of you reminded me that I was
supposed to do my first vlog no later
than today as a start to my 30
days of continuous with logging.
I'm on book deadline and it just so
happens the next 30 days exactly coincides
with when I'm supposed to finish the book.
So maybe that'll make it exciting. Uh,
and certainly anybody who is not watching
this can ask me questions and I will
answer for a bit. I'm not going
to do it too, too, too long. Um,
but today was exciting.
Had A,
someone land here as a researcher to
help me for the next 30 days with putting
things together and didn't get very
much done today. To be quite frank,
got to about 3:00 PM and realized
I hadn't done much at all.
I was just one of those
days and I forget the quote,
but I believe that somebody said at
some point you could find the quote that
courage isn't always some grant thing.
It's just going to bed
and saying to yourself,
I will try harder tomorrow.
Along those lines.
So ask me some questions guys,
and then I'm going to hop off.
I see they removed the
timer from Facebook.
So I'll just do a couple of minutes
and then I'm going to get to bedtime.
Jim Jacobs, how do you
monetize your podcasts? Well,
there's direct and indirect income.
Direct income would be sponsorship.
Indirect would be all the relationships
and so on that I develop in terms of
network through the podcast. My Favorite
Mall Beck, I like close into the CFA.
I like, uh, here's one she
goes through. CFA is one of
my favorite mall backs. Uh,
thoughts on feeding dogs a raw diet.
Uh,
I think that uh,
feeding some raw food is
probably a good idea. Uh,
I feed my dog some freeze dried
and then reconstituted raw rabbit,
lamb,
things along those lines.
But modern dogs are scavengers,
so I think that they're pretty well
adapted to eat just about everything. Uh,
I do think they are omnivores,
which means including a carnivorous fair.
Uh, let's see. One of my drinking
and not drinking any wine right now.
Uh, how's my compound bow coming
along? It's coming along well.
I'll show you what it looks like and
actually have some tweaks that I'll be
making tomorrow to it.
You can make that out
is currently what I'm experimenting
with and training with.
So I am very much looking forward to a
two hour training session tomorrow with a
coach. All right, well
let's keep scanning.
Uh, all right. Why haven't I had Neil
Gaiman all the podcast yet? Well,
I've tried deal is a good guy, but
when he's on deadline, unlike me,
perhaps he doesn't get caught up in
using social media to push it off.
Although I made a commitment to Shay
that I would do this and to you guys.
So here we are.
A best advice for marriage.
Uh, listen more than
you talk probably. Uh,
let's see.
Thoughts on going from Quito to slow carb.
It's a lot easier than
going from slow carb Kido,
so it shouldn't be too terribly difficult.
Uh,
row the hair hat. Nah, I think, uh,
I think this is my default
these days guys. Uh,
Josh says your dog eats
better than my wife. Well,
you know, I do what I
can. From my pooch, uh,
thoughts on jumping in
the last five pounds.
This from Ashley's see the last
mile in the four hour body.
Uh,
let's see.
Okay.
All right. A lot of people
are asking about interviews,
not doing interviews right now
because I'm on book deadline.
So that's one of my rules.
I'm not doing any media interviews and uh,
alas that is non negotiable cause I
have a lot to do in the next four weeks.
Uh,
uh, what is the scariest part
about stepping into success? Uh,
losing privacy I would say in the privacy
of your family and people you care
about that can be very dangerous.
What is most rewarding you
have in Archimedes lever
for doing a lot of positive
good in the world. And uh, and,
and I suppose I'm answering this from
the perspective of someone who's in the
public eye and that's not always the
case for everyone who achieved success as
they may define it. Of
course. Uh, but that is my,
my current answer.
Best piece of advice to youth.
Take risks when you're young
and you are the average of,
actually we were reverse it.
You are the average of the five people
you associate with most and in terms of
entrepreneurial risks,
uh,
ideal to take those when you don't have
any dependence. No Morgan should, etc.
Uh,
all right. Landon. Yes,
please. Please keep doing this.
Yeah. If you guys like this,
let me know. I will
continue to do these. Uh,
okay.
And this is from Brent,
which is related to the earlier answer
in my pit bulls on the raw freeze dried
and raw freeze dried vegetables. Their
health is amazing. Yeah. Molly's health.
My dog is just a fantastic,
uh,
okay.
Why the goatee?
Oh yeah.
You know,
when I shave I usually use clippers and
if I'm like running out to dinner and I
just don't want to look like a homeless
person, I'll take this stuff off.
But this is delicate work here.
Now you can really like
Nicco lip or Nicole,
nick a nostril. So this is just
laziness. It's not a stylistic thing.
I'll take it off eventually. I don't
actually like having it. Uh, all right.
I look tired. I am tired. I'm on book
deadline and I have a month left.
So, uh, no huge surprise
there. But yeah, I am tired.
That's why I liked hired a business coach.
Would I hire,
I don't know how to hire a business coach.
I'm afraid. Uh, would I interview Trent?
Reznor absolutely. Uh, big booty,
Asian woman.
Where are they and how do I find them?
Not sure I can help you there. Maybe you
go to Brazil and find some mixed blood,
I suppose. Uh, let's see.
How do you get rid of bags
under your eyes? Sleep less.
Coffee and coconut oil topically
coffee is usually the culprit for me.
That's what gives me bags
under my eyes. Uh, alright.
Longest time of held my breath is actually
over seven minutes with hyperbaric
oxygen treatment and Wim Hoff
method and a few other things.
But under normal circumstances
with some breath training,
I've done more than four
minutes with David Blaine.
I did three minutes and I want to
say 33 seconds. But in general,
my breath hold times are very, very bad.
So if I were to hold my breath right now,
I'd probably be 45 seconds. Something
like that. You can do a lot with training,
but you don't want to do any type of,
um,
very rarely want to do any kind of breath
work related to extending breath hold
time because you're blowing off CO2, uh,
around water. I highly advise against it.
Um, I know a number of people who've
had horrifyingly dangerous shallow water
blackouts from that. Uh, let's see,
best sales book out there for beginner.
I would get persuasion by cal Deni.
Alton Brown, the podcast. Yeah, I'd
love to have them on a low volume.
Okay.
Why Paris for the trip?
Because it's a beautiful city and I never,
I'd never spent any real time there.
Last time I was in Paris I
couldn't afford a real meal,
so I was staying in hostels where people
were farming and having sex and so on,
which is fun I suppose. But I was nice
to have a change of pace and do Paris,
uh,
without any real constraints.
Alright. Tried oil pulling and sardine.
It's worked for whitening teeth.
Congratulations. Rigor. I believe it. Uh,
am I still on Kido? Uh, Stephanie?
No, I'm not in Quito right now,
although I am consuming powdered
oil from quest nutrition.
Uh,
Kido is very boring and um,
it was the choir's a level of adherence
and I'm not willing to follow right now
with, uh, with the book stuff. All right.
I'm just going to take a few more guys
and then I'm going to bed because I'm
tired. Look at me. Uh,
all right. A wash wash. She,
Robert, you're welcome. Good
Day from Melbourne Cup Day.
Uh, let's see. What would you,
what would you set as an average
budget for a year of vagabonding? Well,
that varies tremendously and it also,
um,
I think implies that you need to
make all that money in advance,
which I'm not sure is the case.
I know it's not the case. Um,
so I would actually just refer to
the book vagabonding pick it up.
That'll help you with
that question. Uh, right.
I haven't read Ray Pete's work.
Uh,
two to three actions.
Would I take move to the bay area with
the goal of starting a tech business?
Mark,
I would volunteer at events where you
can interact with people above your pay
grade. So find organizations handling
events, nonprofits and whatnot,
and volunteer and do a great job.
Even if takes you a while to meet any of
the higher ups or people you'd like to
meet. Uh, best book to
learn about stoicism.
There are quite a few.
I think that Ryan holiday does good work
with the obstacle's the way ego is the
enemy. Uh, I,
I really think you can dive right
into the deep end of the pool and get
something like the Tao of
Seneca. Um, those, those,
that's the audio version of the moral
letters to local leaders and you can get a
paperback version of that
called letters from a Stoic,
uh, which is also very, very good. Okay.
Can't do too many along ones here.
Metallica eighties or after,
I would say master of
puppets and justice for all.
That's it. For me, a handstand work has,
has a stalled a bit,
a damaged a ligament in my
right wrist doing ring work.
I thought I actually broke my wrist.
So unfortunately my wrist and goes
back about that far right now.
So I'm not doing any handstand word.
All right.
Who are you and why are you in my
newsfeed? I Dunno. I know who I am.
I don't know why in your newsfeed if
you don't have any interest in me,
any book on how to not
get offended easily. Yes.
And this will be where I
stopped this particular evening.
Um, this blog as it were. Um,
the book is radical
acceptance by Tara Brock.
If you have issues with getting offended
easily, if you have issues with anger,
a few issues with any, a runaway
emotions, reactive emotions.
It's a fantastic book. I loved it so
much that I had her on the podcast.
She's an incredible, incredible woman.
So it also encouraged checking out the,
uh,
checking out the podcast with Tara Brock.
Obra c h. All right guys,
I'm going to get out of here,
but if you enjoyed that,
then please let me know and I
will do more. This is, I suppose,
uh, the first of a hypothetical
30 days of blogging.
Thanks so much for watching guys and be
sure to consider signing up for my email
newsletter by clicking on
email and newsletter because
I share private Q and A's
exclusive content.
Awesome things like five bullet Fridays,
which is the five coolest things I've
discovered in a given week exclusively via
email.
And that's for the die hard.
That's for the people who really want
the main line of usefulness and how to,
and to really ride along with me as I
learn and discover the most useful things
that I find. So check it out,
email newsletter, click on it,
and please let me know what you
would like more of in terms of video,
in terms of audio.
I will try to make it for you.
So let me know in the comments
and thank you again for watching.