Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
You posted a question.
I'm a cybernetic organism,
living tissue.
This episode is brought to
you by Wealthfront and this
is a very unique sponsor.
Wealthfront is a massively disruptive
in a good way, set it and forget it.
Investing service led by technologists
from places like apple and world famous
investors.
It has exploded in popularity in the last
two years and they now have more than
two and a half billion dollars
under management. In fact,
some of my very good friends,
investors in silicon valley have millions
of their own money in Wealthfront.
So the question is why? Why is
it so popular? Why is it unique?
Because you can get services previously
reserved for the ultra wealthy but only
pay pennies on the dollar for them.
And this is because they use smarter
software instead of retail locations,
bloated sales teams, et cetera. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
I suggest you check out wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim take the risk
assessment quiz which only takes two to
five minutes and they'll show you for
free exactly the portfolio they'd put
you in and if you just want to take their
advice, run with it, do it yourself.
You can do that or as I would,
you can set it and
forget it and here's why.
The value of Wealthfront is in the
automation of habits and strategies that
investors should be using on a regular
basis but normally aren't great investing
is a marathon,
not a sprint,
and little things that you may or may
not be familiar with like automatic tax
loss harvesting,
rebalancing your portfolio,
cross more than 10 asset classes and
dividend reinvestment add up to very large
amounts of money over longer periods
of time. Wealthfront, as I mentioned,
since it's using software
instead of retail locations,
etc. Can offer all of this at low
costs that were previously completely
impossible right off the bat,
you never pay commissions or
account fees for everything.
They charge 0.25% per year on assets above
the first 15,000 which is managed for
free. If you use my link,
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim,
that is less than $5 a month to invest
a $30,000 account for instance. Now,
normally when I have a
sponsor on this show,
it's because I use them and
recommend them. In this case,
it's a little different.
I don't use Wealthfront yet because
I'm not allowed to. Here's the deal.
They wanted to sponsor this podcast,
but because of sec regulations,
companies that invest your money are
not allowed to use client testimonials.
So I couldn't be a user end
have them on the podcast,
but I've been so impressed by Wealthfront
that I've invested a significant
amount of my own money, at least for me,
uh, in the team and the company itself.
So I am an investor and hope
to soon use it as a client.
Now back to the recommendation
as a Tim Ferriss show listener,
you'll get $15,000 managed for free
if you decide to open an account.
But just start with seeing the portfolio
that they would suggest for you.
Take two minutes, fill out their
questionnaire@wealthfront.com
forward slash. Tim,
it's fast,
it's free.
There's no downside that I can think of.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is a great partner for
creating and growing your business.
It's a one stop shop for
all of your graphic design
needs, whether that's a logo,
website, business card, or anything else.
I used 99 designs to get book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to become a number one New
York Times bestseller and they also use
them for banner ads, illustrations,
and other things. With 99 designs,
designers around the world compete
to create the best design for you.
You give feedback and
then pick your favorite.
You end up happy or you get your
money back. It's very simple.
You can check out a few of my
own designs and those of yours,
meaning Tim Ferriss,
show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and right now my
listeners, you guys will get a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
That's 99 designs.com forward
slash. Tim, check it out.
Oh
he, she booties on the, uh, my friends.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job to deconstruct
world class performers,
whether they be from the world
of chess, entertainment, sports,
military,
or in this case,
generalized Human Guinea pig.
And that means my guest is a comrade
in arms of sorts in this wacky world of
self experimentation.
Aga Jacobs,
one of my favorite people out there at
Aga Jacobs on Twitter and elsewhere is
the author of four New
York Times bestsellers.
And he chronicles all
sorts of Shenanigans.
His books include the know it all,
which was about his quest to read the
entire Encyclopedia Britannica and learn
everything in the world. And, uh, in
case you haven't picked this up yet.
He is a hilarious,
hilarious human being.
The year of living biblically about his
quest to follow all of the rules of the
Bible as literally as possible.
Fantastic,
fantastic book drop dead healthy about
his quest to become the healthiest person
alive, uh, in which, uh,
with many a ill advised and
sometimes well advised experiments.
I was involved as one of said advisers,
the Guinea pig diaries collection of
various mishaps but also insightful quests
like outsourcing his entire life and
radical honesty. It's all relative.
We're just coming out in 2017.
So that has to be read about a quest to
connect all of humanity in one family
tree. He is also the host of the new
podcast twice removed by gimlet media.
Of course,
they are the blockbuster factory.
The podcast that is twice removed
is about finding connections.
Aja takes a celebrity guests and at the
end of each episode of introduces them
to a surprise cousin they
didn't know they had.
So it could be one of their heroes and old
friend, a teacher, et Cetera, et cetera.
AJ and I talk about a lot in this episode.
We talk about some of his habits,
what he's learned from many of these
experiments we talk about his creative
process has writing certain
tipping points in his life. Uh,
how he learned to love marketing as an
author who distinct it for very, very,
very long time and a lot more.
We cover a lot of ground and I think
you will have a blast. That's my hope.
I hope you enjoy listening to it as
much as I enjoyed chatting with Aja.
So without further ado,
as I always say,
please enjoy my wide ranging
conversation with a Jay Jacobs.
Aja? Good sir. Welcome to the show.
Thank you Tim.
Delighted to be here
and I thought we could start
maybe at the beginning.
How did we meet? I remember
specifically where I was sitting.
We had our first conversation,
but how did I reach out to you
or was it through the website?
It was great.
Yes,
it was either an email but then we talked
on the phone soon after and you said,
I'm a first time writer.
I'm writing a book.
At that point it was called
drug dealing for fun and profit.
And you said you had read an article I
had written where I outsourced my life to
India, so hired a team of people in
Bangalore to do everything for me,
like answer my email
and argue with my wife.
And you said that you were writing a
book about a similar topic of trying to
find ways to hack work and could you
talk to me about it and could you reprint
that in your book? And I
was like, well this guy,
like he's writing a book about drug
dealing, I don't know, should I trust him?
And I'm like, you know
what the hell. So it,
it came out and then the
vast part was a year later,
like I had forgotten about it and I
got a call from you and you're like,
my book's coming out in case
you want to check it out.
And it's number one on Amazon.
And I'm like,
you mean number one in like 20
something career advice. You're like,
no number one on Amazon,
you are a genius.
How the hell did you do that? The
first time writer. So now I'm like,
uh, yeah, and now you are
my mentor in publishing.
Like you called me for advice
and now like I need to,
a year later I needed
to call you for advice.
This is my chance to ask for more advice.
Aha.
Because I realized that we talked about
your writing at the time and we're going
to get into all sorts of experiments.
But since,
since we were talking about writing,
a number of people in my fan base asked
about your writing process and so we've
talked about your writing,
the subject matter of your writing,
but I don't know if we've ever
talked about your writing process.
Yeah, I'm happy to talk about it. I think
we actually did because when you were,
you were researching how to write a book.
That's true. I asked him, I asked you a
little bit about structure. Yeah. And uh,
but I don't know at the time
I remember I was in Argentina,
I was in Buenos Aires.
So sitting in a coffee shop,
drinking a Cappuccino,
which was a double espresso.
This must have been around,
uh,
late 2005 or early 2006 near this place.
Well, it's a large cemetery
and in near plus a fancy,
I remember exactly where I was
sitting when we had the conversation.
Could you describe for folks,
like I said,
there are two questions
about writing process.
One is micro on say a daily basis
when you are writing a book,
what that day looks like.
And then there's the how do you
decide what to write about. So,
which do you want to tackle
first? Whichever you would
like to tackle first. Well,
let me take, tackle the micro
really quickly, which would be,
mmm. One thing I like to
do first a little, uh,
mental calisthenics before
I start writing. So, uh,
just to warm up my brain,
so I'll, I'll brainstorm.
Maybe it's about the book
event itself or an article,
but it could just be random stuff. Like it
could be like, you know, ah, I saw snow,
man, what can we do with that? Maybe
we could do a, uh, uh, Snow Tran,
ginger person or us know neanderthal like,
and 99% of the ideas suck as you can tell.
But the idea is just to get
your creative juices flowing.
You get writing those down or are
you just doing them and said, yes,
I'm typing them down. And you
know, as I say, none of them,
very few of them are ever
see the light of day.
But that's just to get my
fingers typing is another thing.
I feel just the movement of my fingers
on the key gets me revved up and gets me,
uh, so that uh, I'm,
I'm more comfortable typing.
The other thing I like to think about
is I know that the first half hour of of
actual writing my book that
that is probably going to suck.
And so I just have to accept that
and be okay with throwing it out.
But you got to do that half hour
before a year, your brain clicks in.
So, so that's what I do. I do need,
I do need like three solid hours.
I am not one.
Some people can do it where they
can write in spurts of 20 minutes.
I am not one of those.
I can't do it either.
Yeah.
And I remember I got some very good advice
a few years ago because I was getting
very frustrated by the,
in my mind wasted half hour that
you mentioned. Uh, and someone said,
well you have to realize that if you
write 10 pages and you only get one really
good page at the very end,
those nine pages are not a waste of time.
You needed those nine pages to get to
the 10th page. Yeah, exactly. Okay.
I prefer to have a better ratio.
I'll take it.
No. Yeah, there is some warm up. Uh, yeah.
I wish it could be more
like high intensity interval
training. You're Indian,
you're out. But it is
more like stretching. And
do you tend to do it first thing
in the morning or when do you I do,
well, I have kids so that, that
makes my life a pain in the ass.
So I have had to train myself
to tie it to write at all hours.
So sometimes in the morning, sometimes
at night. And uh, do you drink coffee?
Do you drink coffee? Um, I also,
I have to say I enjoy my white wine.
Uh,
mostly mornings I am a day drinker.
I actually prefer drinking during
the day. Um, but yeah, you know,
there are studies that show that you're
slightly more creative after like I
think after one glass,
like after two or three glasses,
then it all goes to hell. But one
glass, it sort of loosens up the, uh,
the frontal cortex allows
you to make more connections
or it convinces you that you should be
more loosened up and you have the placebo
effect benefit there.
You Guy, and you said,
you sent me over a quote and I don't know
if this is a quote of yours or if it's
tributed to someone else,
but I really enjoyed this and I think
it applies to a lot of what you do,
not just your writing, but
it, here's the quote quote,
it's easier to act your way into a new
way of thinking than to think your way
into a new way of acting.
Can you elaborate on that or provide
us some more context for that?
Yeah, I love that quote and I
think it applies to both of us.
Definitely applies to both of us. Yeah.
I think a lot of what your work and yeah,
I wish I could say I made it up.
It was the founder of habitat for
humanity whose name escapes me right now,
but it was a wonderful, and
the idea is just, you know, uh,
when you is, it's basic
cognitive behavioral psychology.
When you act in a certain way,
then your brain will catch up.
But that's a lot of insight in terms
of change. I find that much easier.
Like I wrote a book about the Bible
and living by the Bible and one of the
things was you had to be
more compassionate and a,
so I had a friend in the hospital, I
hate hospitals, hate them. So I was like,
I'm not going to visit that guy.
But then I thought,
what would a compassionate person do?
And I acted as if I were
a compassionate person.
I forced myself to go to
the hospital and visit him.
And then in my brain I'm like, oh, you
know what, I am kind of compassionate.
You sort of trick your brain,
your brain catches up. Uh, and,
and I've done that and especially with
optimism and confidence, you know,
I don't think I'm a
naturally confident person,
but I act as if I'm confident and
eventually you become more confident.
So what
in the realm of confidence would
embodies confidence for you?
It's like what are the
ways in which you act?
Well, for instance, when I
wrote a book about health,
it was a sort of my um,
my uh,
attempt at the four hour body, uh, and uh,
Aye I was so overwhelmed because it's
such a huge topic and I was trying to be
the healthiest person alive
aside from Tim Ferris. Uh,
and so there was such a,
it's such an undertaking because there's
so much their sleep and their sacks and
there's food and exercise.
So I was all stressed out,
but then I acted every morning
I would wake up full of despair,
but then I would act as if
I was confident. So I would
call my publisher and say,
okay,
when we have the release party,
let's have a Kale Martinis.
What do you think of that? Uh,
so I was acting all cocky as if you know,
this is going to come
out and be a big hit.
And after two or three hours your brain
catches up and I actually felt more
confident and I really find it so helpful.
So I've, I've been thinking
about this a lot recently, uh,
because there's so much talk of,
of mind over body.
And so this is I guess a
corollary to this quote,
but I've been thinking a lot
about, uh, body over mind.
And this is something Tony
Robbins talks a lot about.
If you want to change your psychology,
changing your physiology first,
and it's a lot easier also in the sense
that if you haven't reasoned yourself
into a position of say,
lack of confidence,
or at least you haven't
done it consciously,
it's very hard to reason your way out of
it. Uh, so you just have to act as if,
oh yeah, I absolutely, I agree.
And it's in every part of my life.
Like I did one experiment where I, I
tried to be the best husband ever, and,
uh,
I forced myself to buy a
present for my wife every day,
like just a little trinket.
Uh,
even if I was totally pissed at her and
like you want to, nothing to do with her,
but just that act of giving it to her, it
was like, oh, I'm giving her a present.
I must love her.
And it really changed my view.
So I am a big fan and there, and
we're not the only ones. You know, I,
I read about Teddy Roosevelt
when he was a, he for a while,
he was trying to be a cowboy.
He was actually in,
I think it was Montana and someone asked
him, aren't you terrified? And he's like,
of course I'm terrified when
the bullets is coming at me,
but I just act as if I'm courageous
and they become a little more correct.
Yes. So it sounds like, and I read
this comparison on I think 99 you,
uh, one piece, maybe method acting,
although I know nothing about it.
I'm just using the label. Uh, and
then there's the second component,
which is something that,
uh, I, I didn't, I,
I like this phrase and it's capital
d capital owed delusional optimism.
Uh, can you, can you elaborate
on that? Cause it seems
like there they go together.
Yes. I am a, I am a fan
of delusional optimism,
which is very similar to what
we've been talking about. Uh,
I think it's nothing would get
done without delusional optimism.
And I actually,
one example as I interviewed
George Clooney once for a Esquire,
who by the way is as charming
as you expect George Clooney to.
He gave me a, a
unsolicited, a shoulder rub,
shoulder massage, so that like,
I'll always have that. Uh,
but anyways,
so I asked him about his,
whether his secret to success and
he said one philosophy he has his,
uh,
he used to be a baseball player in high
school and when he got up to the plate,
he would, he wouldn't just say to
himself, am I going to hit a home run?
He would say,
not only am I going to hit a home run,
but the only question is am I going to
hit it over the left wall or the right
wall? And I loved that just like, and
of course, most of the time he did it,
most of the time he struck out,
but it raised the percentage of times
that he did hit a home run because he had
that delusional optimism. Uh, and I love
that. And you have to be careful. I mean,
you don't want, it can lead to terrible
things. So you have to have some,
especially if you're in an organization,
you want the CEO to be delusional,
he off to a optimistic and then you
want someone else to be sort of the bean
counter and be like, I don't
know about this, a balance.
But you really do, I think,
need that delusional
optimism to get things done.
And if we're then rewinding a little bit
and going from the micro book process,
book writing process,
uh,
actually before we leave
the daily writing process,
I've talked to a lot of my friends
who are typically journalists that in
newspapers and they drive me crazy and
they make me very envious because they
talk about how writing or writer's block
doesn't exist and they can kick out
1500 beautiful words every few hours
and they seem to be able to do it.
A lot of my friends who've worked
at different papers do you have,
do you experience blocks
or extended periods where
you're just stuck on projects
and if so, what do you do to help get
yourself out of those folks? Yep. Yeah,
blocked
all the time. I actually
wrote an article once on, uh,
on writer's block and the way that
great writers have overcome it.
I remember, uh, I think Ben
Franklin wrote in the nude,
a lot of writers wrote standing
up like a Nabokov wrote,
standing up. There is a philosopher
and German philosopher named Schiller,
who he needed rotten apples to
inspire him. So I tried them.
I've went, like Tim Ferriss, I, I
tried them all like at the same time,
like standing up naked
with rotten rotten apples.
I don't know if that was successful,
but I will say one of them is similar to
what I said before where you just start
writing and it doesn't have to be,
as long as you accept that it's going
to suck, uh, it lowers the pressure.
So I'll, a lot of times
if I, uh, if I'm stuck,
I'll just start writing,
you know, about the, the,
the Coffee Cup or the
on the window sill are,
you know, how, um, my
elbow itches and just,
just the fact of moving your fingers,
like we talked about how much
your body affects your mind,
moving the fingers gets you
going, uh, and helps. But yeah,
I, it's a problem. It is a certainly, uh,
people who say they don't have writer's
block, they, they drive me crazy.
And uh,
you mentioned this is going to jump
around because it's the style of my mental
like brain.
But you mentioned,
and this is a question that
came up from quite a few, uh,
listeners to the podcast, the year
of living biblically, which was, uh,
one of my favorite books. Yours. I really,
really enjoyed it and
I've told you this before,
but I learned more about
as someone who developed a,
an allergy to organized religion pretty
early on and therefore it never learned
much about it.
It was a fantastic Trojan horse for me
through the entertainment value in the
humor of the book to actually learn a
lot about a number of different religious
traditions. Well bless you. Bless
you Tim. Thanks. So while that,
bless you, that leads me to
the question, which is, uh,
what are the things that
have stuck with you?
Yeah,
that and
because there's one that stuck with me,
which railings a while you talked
about wearing white. Ah, yeah.
And so maybe you could, you could,
you could explain what that means,
but it's actually something that I've
ended up doing on a fairly regular basis
since I run me.
Although you're wearing dark blue and
wearing dark blue right now cause all my
wife's stuff is,
imagine how much better this interview
would be. And, and I was wearing light.
I'm wearing white socks.
Uh, yeah. Well this book,
just to give a very quick background
for those who don't know it was, um,
I grew up with no religion at all.
Uh, as I say in the book, I'm Jewish,
but I'm Jewish in the same way. The
olive garden is Italian, so not very,
no offense,
but I thought one way to learn about
religion would be to dive in and actually
follow every rule in the Bible. So the
famous ones like the 10 Commandments,
uh, and, but also the last famous ones,
like it says you can't shave
the corners of your beard.
I didn't know where the corners were,
so I just let the whole thing grow.
And I had this huge topiary and I got
stopped at airport security. So it was,
hey, uh, it was a, it was a
crazy year, but one of the rules,
the robes probably didn't help it.
Airports
and the sandals and the walking
stick. Yeah. Has He say, you know,
getting into it physically
really makes a difference.
And one of the rules in the Bible,
and I think it's Ecclesiastes,
he says that your garments should always
be white. So I took that literally,
and I only wore white pants,
white shirts and white robes.
And it was weird how it affected my,
uh,
my mind as, you know, like,
it made me feel lighter or more energetic,
uh, and I felt like, you know, it's,
there's just something wearing white,
like I'm going to, you know, uh,
p Diddy's Hamptons party or I'm gonna
play Wimbledon, you know, it's, it's,
it's got positive associations.
So I fell.
And here in New York, people wear dark
clothes all the time. And I think door,
yeah, it affects your,
your mind have, you can,
is that continued to be a piece or what
have continued to play a part in your
life from that book, from that experience?
I do like the little brighter clothes,
more than I used to. I, I would
say, you know, a lot of it I,
I gave, I did shave the beard,
um, because my wife would not,
she wouldn't touch me with that thing.
Uh, even though I kept very clean,
I like moisturized,
conditioned it.
Shampooed but in terms of stuff
that I have actually kept,
uh,
I would say one thing that,
that really has stuck with me is that
the Bible talks about that you should be
grateful all the time. He says he should
be thankful, say prayers of thanksgiving.
So I, when I was doing
the, the book, I would, I,
I took that literally,
so I would be thankful for everything.
So I would press the elevator button,
I'd get in the elevator,
I'd be thankful it didn't plummet to
the basement. Uh, I, uh, it, you know,
I get it,
press the elevator button and I'd be
thankful the doors opened and I got to my
floor. So it was like hundreds
of little tiny things a day.
And it was a weird way to live, very
time consuming, but it was also,
there was something wonderful about
it because it made you realize very
concretely,
there are hundreds of things that go
right every day that you totally take for
granted.
And at least I used to focus on the three
or four that went wrong and just stew
on them.
So I've tried to keep that radical shift
in perspective of being thankful for
all the tiny little things that go
right. And it has made me happier. It,
it's definitely had an impact.
So I want each of you,
if you wouldn't mind,
describe for people, uh,
one of my favorite stories in the book,
uh, stoning adulterers. Well, yes,
I was doing a lot with the Old Testament,
the Hebrew scriptures,
and it says over and over again you
have to stone adulterers. So I thought,
all right, let me try to get this, check
this off the list. So I was, uh, uh,
one day I was in central park and
I was wearing my whole, I had my,
I had to get up the sandals and
a man came up to me and he said,
why are you dressed like
that? And I said, well,
I'm trying to follow all the rules of
the Bible from the 10 commandments to
stoning adulterers. And he
said, well, I'm an adulterer.
I ain't going to stone me. And I
said, well, that would be fantastic.
Thank you for the offer.
So kind. So I took a, uh,
a handful of stones out of my robe pocket
because I had been carrying around for
weeks. Hoecakes because
there was no specification
in terms of the size of the,
exactly. That was the key. I showed
it to him and I'm like, you know,
there's small stones and you know,
I can check it off the list
even if they're small stones.
And he was very aggressive adulterer.
He grabbed the stones out out of
my hand and threw them at my face.
So I thought an eye for an eye,
I can chuck one back at him.
So that's how I chucked it off.
I checked it off the list and yeah,
I didn't continue that.
There were quite a few.
Uh,
I did not continue including if you
follow Leviticus really strictly,
you can't touch a woman when she's
menstruating cause she's impure.
But if you take it really literally
a woman, if she's meant joining,
if she sits on something, a
chair, that chair becomes impure.
And my wife found that offensive so she
sat in every chair in our apartment and
I had to stand for most of the year. Which
as you know, is probably good for you.
Good for your health. Well
you had a travel stool, right?
It was one of those exact sporting
event. Yeah, those are great. Yeah,
they were, um, you know,
they're usually used by people
who are either 83 or 600 pounds,
but I found it very useful,
suited a number of folks.
And then we're not going to get too deep
into the audience questions right now,
but we quite a few questions about
your wife and how you manage your
relationship with your wife,
given all of these odd experiments.
And do you, did you,
did you in some indirect or subconscious
way select someone who have a high
tolerance for all of this?
Great question. How do you,
how do you repair damage
when damage is done?
It is, it is interesting. I mean there
are, first of all, she has veto power.
So there are like,
I'm sure you get this all the time,
readers suggesting
ideas. One suggested, uh,
become the greatest lover in the world
and do all the positions in the Kama
Sutra, which you kind of did in the
four hour body. Uh, but you know,
I've been married for 12 years, so
that was not going to happen. Um,
I did pitch it to her and she,
and she's like, no, that is,
and I have to say I was a
little relieved because I,
I don't think I can bend my
back like that anymore. Uh,
so, so she has veto power.
That's rule number one. Um,
and to I think she does get,
she gets a lot of reader feedback
about how she's so patient that helps.
So please keep sending those
in positive reinforcement. Um,
I will say probably the worst
one for our marriage was,
uh, you know, the, the lifelogging
movement where you, you,
you take keep track. It's like,
yeah, and record everything.
It's like the self tracking, quantified
self taken to the extreme. So you,
I wore,
I had a little tiny camera like smaller
than a Gopro on my ear and I recorded
every moment of my life for about
three months. And it was fascinating.
It really, you know, and I think
it's a glimpse of the future.
I think we are all going towards
that for better or worse.
But one of the things was I was like,
you know,
70% of my arguments with my
wife are about where she says,
you didn't tell me that. And I'm like,
yeah, I did. I did tell you that.
So now I'm like,
you know what?
Now we can rewind and we can
see what we actually said.
So we had a huge argument about something,
whether I had,
she had asked me to order Mexican food,
something ridiculously small and trivial,
but it blew up and I was able to, I
was like, the next day I'm like, okay,
let's rewind and watch the argument.
Um,
and it was so terrible for our
marriage because it's like,
I can't remember.
I think I might've been 60% right,
but the net was that I was 0%
right because she was so upset.
And you don't want to show
someone yelling or angry.
It just is not,
I don't recommend that as a,
a way to navigate a marriage. In fact,
there was a black, you ever go see black?
There's a great episode, I think it
was in the first or second season,
the UK edition of Black
Mirror tastic episode.
It was the same exact premise,
very similar premise,
but you record through your eye.
It was great. I loved that show.
And that was an in the episode,
you know,
things go horribly awry with his marriage,
I think is probably also likely to happen.
Exactly.
It becomes ubiquitous technology.
What did you learn from that experience
aside from not to replay the Mexican
takeout debate?
I think,
well one thing I learned is to,
um,
I of course I have hundreds
of hours of material,
so, uh, I'll, I'll never be able
to watch it because, you know,
it's just an infinite loop.
But I think one is to enjoy
the small moments. You, you
know, if you do watch it,
he just realized that 90% of your day,
as you know,
when I'm getting my kids ready for school,
if you are annoyed during those half
hour because it's a pain in the ass,
that's a half hour of your way,
a life wasted.
Like you have to realize this is it.
Like this is what most of life is.
So try to enjoy that as well as the,
when you know you're playing
laser tag or whatever,
cause that's very rich serving
kill Martinis at your launch party.
That never happened. Uh, so that was one,
I mean also the implications for
the future of fascinating, you know,
how's it gonna Affect Crime?
Like,
how will anyone mug someone when it's
all being uploaded immediately to the
cloud? So it will, I think help crime,
but it'll be terrible for
marriages. And you know, I,
I feel for a future adulterers,
my heart goes out to them because I can't
imagine how you're going to get away
with sneaking around when
everything is fully recorded. Uh,
well,
I mean it will also on the flip side
and it will clarify a lot of crimes that
are not committed where people
are wrongly accused. Well,
you have the flip side also
true. Yeah. It'll be, um,
and I think it'll also,
it might make us more tolerant of people's
mistakes because we all do something,
you know, every, the youtube
video of people melting down and,
and acting like idiots. Everyone
will have one of those. Yeah.
So we're all going to
have no one's purple.
We're all going to have our
flaws right out there on display.
So we have to accept
those and ourselves and,
and be a little more tolerant of others.
So it'll be,
it's going to be a weird future, I
really believe. Fascinating but weird.
Yeah, it's a, I mean, the question for me
is who in all these cases, you know who,
who are going to be the dominant owners
of this information and controllers of
the bits and bites right there
represent all of these videos. Yeah. Uh,
but I want to come back
to tolerance and I'm not,
I'm not sure this is a perfect segue,
but I'm going to force it a radical
honesty. So you wrote a piece,
believe it was titled,
I think you're fat. Uh,
that is about radical honesty.
Could you describe for people,
and then I want to come back and I'm
going to ask you about your thoughts on
marriage and parenting, but I
want to talk this, this ties in,
I think on some level, so radical on
safety. Could you describe absolutely the,
the origins of this experiment and what
you did and, and where you ended up,
which I don't think we've really talked
no. Well, and to be
radically honest, thank you.
You tweeted about it a few
weeks ago and as per usual,
like your endorsement class,
mentor readers,
one tweet. Then I get like, you know,
from months trying to publish they space.
I love the piece smiling.
Thank you. Uh, yeah. This
piece came about because I was,
I read about this guy in Virginia,
a psychologist named Brad Blanton.
Fantastic character,
one of the greatest interviews in my life.
And he believes that you should never
lie, but he goes further. He says,
whatever's on your brain
should come out of your mouth.
No filter like Jim Carrey and liar liar.
So it is insane.
And I was like, well, let me
try this and see what happens.
How maybe he's right. Maybe it
will make my life better. Uh,
despite the challenges.
So I did it and all my God,
it was the worst month
of my life in many ways.
In some ways it was wonderful,
liberating, terrific. In other ways,
it was just dreadful. And to give you
one of the dreadful ones, there was like,
we would go to a restaurant
and we would see my wife,
friends of my wife's that she hadn't
seen since, since college and they'd be,
they said, oh, we should all get together
and have a play date with our kids.
And I had to say what was on my brain,
which was,
you guys seem nice but I have no
interest in ever seen you again.
Cause I don't have time
to see my own friend.
And they were just looked at me aghast.
And my wife of course was furious.
And I mean the one thing is
we never did see them again.
So in that way it was the fact that
I felt terrible and I still feel,
you know, it was totally terrible
thing to say. So there was that. Um,
uh,
but it did affect me in that I still,
I'm not radically honest, like, cause
he's crazy. He's like also, you know,
if you see a beautiful woman
on the street, you say, hello,
I'm very attracted to you. I
would like to sleep with you. Uh,
which I got weirdly a lot
of people and you know,
20 something guys saying they were
using that as a through masterful pickup
line. Exactly. And they said, you
know, the rejection rate was like 95%,
but if you're okay with that, then 5% of
the women were like, hmm. Interesting.
Just in preposition,
I was like the confidence
slash Asperger's.
But uh,
so what I have kept from that is I,
I tried to do what I call a
radical sustainable honesty or,
or positive radical honesty because I
don't need to tell people, you know, uh,
I'm staring at your mole. Like that
just doesn't help the world I think.
But for instance, one of the things
I did was when I was doing that,
I would be thinking,
you know what,
I really liked that boss of mine
when I was 22 at the small newspaper.
He had a very nice influence on me.
Let me call him up and thank him.
So I would call them out of the blue.
And it was very awkward because men are
not supposed to express emotions like
that.
But I would tell him how much he meant
to me and it made me feel so much better
and I hope,
I think it made him feel better.
And so I feel that that's
something I've tried to keep.
If I have a positive thought,
then even if it's embarrassing or weird,
then I will, I will say like, I love
you man. That kind of thing. Uh,
and I think that has made my life better.
So I was given a similar assignment
by an ex girlfriend a number of years ago.
I was having trouble,
and this is no secret to people who've
read certainly a few of the chapters in
tools of titans or in other places that
I've had had my ups and downs in my
managing of depressive periods
and whatnot. And she said, well,
if you're having trouble
making yourself happy,
maybe you should identify
one person every day.
You can send a short thank you
to or call to give a thank you.
And specifically people from long ago
or people you used to be close to or who
had a huge influence on you
that you are no longer close to.
And so I started doing this and calling
teachers I had in high school or
childhood friends and it was a,
it had a hugely uplifting impact on me.
I did it ever go wrong? Did ever
thumb, no, it never went wrong.
And sometimes it wasn't even
about speaking in person.
So if I got a voicemail,
just leave a heartfelt voicemail. It
never went sideways for me. Uh, and uh,
in fact it re re invigorated
I guess are resurrected.
A few childhood friendships and now I'm
back in close contact with a number of
these guys I went to grade school with
and used to play with on a daily basis on
BMX bikes or whenever the hell throwing,
throwing dirt clods into each other's
eyes in the middle of the forest or
whatever we were doing at the time.
So it's been great. It's been really,
really great. I love that.
Uh, how do you, if, if you're,
if you've dismissed the option
of being able to say to someone,
you seem very lovely, but I don't want to
ever see you again, which in a sense is,
is fantastic because you're
able to cut down on all of this.
There's all these social
expectations and commitments.
I think a lot of people are just
drowning and coffee, invitations,
cocktail invitations. Let's do
this. Let's do that. If you're,
if you're trying to practice this
more, a moderate honesty, uh,
how do you think of handling in a
place like New York City in particular,
where you have endless options?
I need your advice on that. I am,
I am terrible at it. I mean, I will tell
people the truth, which is right now,
I am so overwhelmed that I don't have
time for basic hygiene and that they
wouldn't want to hang out with me anyway
because I smell and I've got yellow
teeth. So that the, and that
is the truth. So maybe that's,
that's my best answer. But
yeah, it's a tough one.
The Best I've been able to figure out.
This was actually
something I borrowed from,
I'm not going to mention him by name
because I don't know if you'd want this to
be public,
but a very well known a tech investor,
billionaire tech investor in
Silicon Valley who's always
been very generous with
his time.
And we'd met up a number of times and
I asked him if he'd be open to grabbing
dinner. No, I wasn't vague about it
because I think at this point in my life,
I've learned like let's hang out isn't
good enough for someone who has that so
many demands on their time.
So it was like,
I'd love to meet up to chat about this,
this, and this only if you have time.
But we'd had dinner a number of times in
the past and he said, I would love to,
but I'm on, uh, uh, I'm
taking a meeting vacation.
And so I started applying this
to everything. I was like, oh,
that's brilliant because it's not
personalized. It's not, I can't do it.
Tim Ferris, because I don't like you. It's
no, I'm not doing any meetings. He said,
I'm not doing any meetings.
I'm actually doing no phone calls.
I'm just responding to things via email
because that's the only way I can manage
my schedule right now.
And it was so generalized that
I felt totally fine with that.
So I started applying that to
anything I didn't want to do.
I'm taking a conference called vacation,
I'm taking the meeting vacation,
I'm taking a fill in the blank vacation
and also began putting that in my
autoresponders so that
I didn't feel obligated.
A couple of those you've most certainly,
everyone gets a lot from me.
I love that. Uh, angry when you're taking
a vacation. Everyone needs a vacation,
a vacation. Well, and it
is interesting. I, um,
uh, yeah, another thing
that I do is a, and,
and some people don't improve
this. You may not, but okay.
If I'm totally swamped and someone
asks me out to lunch, then I say,
uh,
what would you think about a Skype lunch
where we both order in food and we have
lunch and we get to talk to each other.
We get to see each other,
but we don't have to Schlep,
we don't have to like waste time.
We don't have to get, you know,
ask the waiter like for the,
for the check and you know,
I'd say 30% of people are offended,
but 70% are willing to try.
And I found it very useful.
Skype loads, type lunch, dinner,
Skype, breakfast, whatever you want.
And I did it once with this guy who was
tech savvy and he like had a background
of us in a cafe like in Paris.
So it was very nice.
A CID or on a lady in the trip moment
virtually. That's fair. That sounds very,
I don't know whether I was lady or
the tramp or both. You can be both.
She's, there were a couple of bullets
we in preparation for this because I've,
I've, so I'm very familiar with
a lot of your work. I've read,
I think all of your books up to
this point and just, yeah, it's,
so you set a number of
bullets that I, I didn't, uh,
expect or I wasn't familiar with.
So I wanted to talk about a few. I,
and I feel like some of these, uh,
we have maybe touched on briefly,
but I wanted to revisit being
kind to your older self.
Can you explain what this means?
This was,
uh,
I learned this while doing the
health book and the idea was,
um, I think it was, it
was a Yale professor. Uh,
I forget his name, but ego nomics
I think is the, what he called it.
And the idea was when they do experiments
and they remind people of that,
that they are going to
be around in 20 years,
people make more responsible decisions.
Like financially they invest more in
their four zero oneK and also health wise
they act more responsibly.
So I thought this was fascinating.
So I took it and I took a,
uh, just a selfie of an,
I digitally aged it on one of those apps.
And so I now look,
I've got this weird,
I looked like I have a skin disease,
but it's me at like 82.
And I put printed it out
and put it over my desk.
And that older age a is always
looking down and saying, you know,
treat me well treatment,
remember,
treat me like you would
treat a friend and you know,
just don't eat that fourth oatmeal cookie,
you know,
just get on that treadmill.
So I find that,
I find that very inspiring and motivating.
And does it something that you're able
to continually notice or do you tune it
out after a while? This is a challenge
that I've had with certain reminders.
So I have a quote for instance from,
uh,
Marcus really is on my refrigerator in
San Francisco and it's about not being,
trying to regain the harmony as quickly
as possible, et Cetera, et cetera.
It's one of these very Marcus
Aurelius type quotes. Uh, there,
there are a number of
them around my house,
but I will occasionally schedule rotating
of the quote or even location because
otherwise it just becomes part of
the scenery and I don't notice it. So
that, and I was, I have
the exact same thing.
Like if you leave it in the same
place you're going to forget about.
What I do is I make it part of
my rotating screen saver so that,
okay, this makes sense. So that
it pops up every, you know,
couple of days and then, oh yeah,
I should, but you're totally right.
We are so good at tuning
things out that have been there
necessarily. Right. But I mean, it's
evolutionarily, it's like, all right,
if there's a piece of furniture,
I don't need to have some type of
acute fighter flight intensity level
observation of it.
Right.
Because it's clearly not having a
direct impact of my survival. Uh,
and, and I had that same
experience with photos.
I had a screensaver that
was a photo of my family,
totally tuned it out after three days.
So I started rotating photos
to remind myself. Oh yeah,
we did do a fun thing there.
And you know, it's not all, uh,
tantrums, tantrums and debates
over Mexican food. Exactly.
What, uh, what else have you continued
to do from drop dead healthy?
I still do love, uh, treadmill desks.
I made my own,
I didn't buy the fancy one,
but I do find it
energizing, you know, and I,
I only walked like one and a half,
two miles per hour when I'm writing
a or answering emails. But, uh,
I find it if I'm sitting
in front of a computer,
I am tempted to just like rest my
head on the space bar and fall asleep.
So I you can't do that when you're
on a treadmill. So I do like that.
And I also still like, uh, the,
the competition.
Some people are not motivated by this,
but I am like getting friends,
uh,
making sure that I get to 10,000
steps or my friends can mock me,
that they can see there's like a
leaderboard and that they can, would,
would you use for that right now
in terms of sharing that with them?
I have been a use,
I like hooked up my
fitbit to my apple health.
It was complicated. It
took, it took a while. Yeah.
And how do you encourage your friends
to mock you if you don't get 10,000?
Are they the type of friends who don't
need much instruction in the market
apartment? Yeah, I'm trying to think. I
used to, it's been awhile, but, um, the,
this great writer who
wrote the, uh, the seek,
the Henrietta lacks book. Uh Oh,
right, sure, sure, sure. Anyway,
she is,
she is great and also very,
so I think he just got to
find the people who, uh,
are most adept at mockery. I
am motivated by mockery. Uh,
some people are not.
So there's a,
there's a story that I've told quite
a bit because I think that it's very
practical in a lot of ways and
that there are variations of this.
But I'd like you to tell probably the
more accurate version because I feel like
I get details of this wrong when I
retell it. Blackmailing yourself. Yeah.
Sly with cell on it.
I went to,
let's talk about the cake that's
talking about the gay, Gay, Gay, uh,
which I do not support just to get
that out there right up front. Uh,
but I launched,
I've watched many of your talks and and
in a couple of them you mentioned that
very flattering. Thank you. Uh,
this is an idea by that
same Yale professor and the,
his idea was if you want to quit something
or you want to stop doing a terrible
behavior,
then you can blackmail yourself.
Is this the same Yale professor ended up
leader or currently being involved with
stick.com? Yes, that's
right. S T I C K k.com.
Where this is built into sort of the
mechanics of how the site works. Exactly.
Okay. This is where you choose the
anti charity. It's the anti charity.
It's sort of motivated. You took
it to the next level. Well I was,
excuse me,
I was and I'm doing the health book and
I was eating all of these dried mangoes
cause they sort of have the
veneer of health cause they're,
they're fruit but, but really they're
just sugar. I just so much sugar.
So I knew I had to quit. So I
arranged it. I said to my wife,
if I eat another dried mango,
then I'm instructing you.
Now you have to do this,
you have to send a $100 check to the KKK.
And I,
it was so effective.
It was crazy because just the thought of
that check going out made me physically
ill and I was able to quit cold Turkey.
So,
and he talks about people
smoking use this, uh,
strategy and yeah.
Have you ever tried it?
I have tried the anti
charity and it's incredible.
I've also done this with bedding
because I think that for instance,
if you have a betting pool with
five people who have a certain goal,
let's just say that's body re composition.
So they're each getting,
this is actually a real example from a
friend of mine who recently lost 40 or 50
pounds. They're each getting
dexa scans. So these scans,
it'll indicate body fat percentage
and muscle mass. And so on, every,
let's just call it two weeks
or something like that,
which is actually surprisingly
inexpensive. It's a big
30, 40 bucks. Hmm. And uh,
whoever has the most successful
recomposition of their
body by the end would get
the pot and each person, I think it was
putting in $100 and so it was $500 total,
but people will,
I don't think it's the $500 that gets
people to lose the weight in this case
lose fat.
I think that it is the two things,
the the social mockery and a at grab
asking and ball busting in this case is
five guys and it is the losing of $100.
It's the loss aversion I think
more than the prospect of gain.
And so this is one of the many
issues that I suppose I take with the
43rd place gets a gold star ever.
Everyone's a winner.
We should only focus on
positive reinforcement,
a sort of fetishizing of the patting
on the head in the u s at least where I
think the,
the s the stick instead of the carrot and
the like the shame and humiliation and
all of these, all of these
things that are thought of as,
as negative actually really,
really useful tools if you recognize how,
uh,
how ingrained they are as
incentives in human beings.
I find that very useful.
I mean,
you've got to be careful not to crush
someone's ego so they curl up in a fetal
position. So it's a fine line.
But, uh, but good natured,
uh, sticks, I think, you know,
like a soft maybe, uh, you know,
nerf sticks I think are,
are incredibly helpful. Uh,
so this is one that I may have read
about. It didn't ring a bell. Uh,
the, uh, trip to Jerry
Falwell's church. Oh yeah. Yes.
This is when I was writing the Bible and
I sent you this in the context of just
the joy of being a mentor.
Uh,
and I can say that because this guy,
my mentee,
my protege has far
surpassed me in success.
His name is Kevin Reus and he was a
writer for the New York Times in New York
magazine. Now he's at fusion and he's
written a couple great books, but he,
I met him because I was
writing my book on the Bible.
He was a freshman at my
Alma Mater Brown University.
And he wrote me a very funny letter
saying he wanted it to be a writer.
So immediately that's a good lesson.
Like just the Chutzpah,
I call it a strategic Chutzpah,
just writing out of the blue instead
of going through alumni relations,
he just wrote me out of the blue,
I want to be a writer,
I'll work for you for free
while I reason for it.
So that I was like,
you know,
I was already impressed and at the time
I was trying to follow all the rules of
the Bible and the Bible
actually in the Old Testament,
slavery is,
is fine.
So I was really struggling with how
do I deal with that in my life because
obviously slavery not so
fine, not so legal. Thank God.
Uh, so I said the closest
thing to slavery, uh, in,
in my life isn't an into an internship.
So if you can come and
be my intern and uh,
and let me call you my biblical
slave, then let's do it. So He's like,
I'm in and he was great.
So proactive.
And then as a thank you,
I took him on one of the trips I made
for that book where I was going around
trying to see how different people
interpreted the Bible. Literally.
And I took him to Jerry
Falwell's church and he was,
he was fascinated. He was
like, this is amazing.
This is like an alternate universe.
I live in a bubble. I want to,
what if I transferred from Brown,
the most liberal college, uh,
in the United States to Liberty College,
which is one of the most conservative
where you can't watch an r rated movie.
You get in trouble for,
you can't like holding hands with
someone of the opposite sex is like,
you know, that's for
voting. So, uh, I was like,
that's an interesting idea.
And I said,
encouraged them to write a proposal and
I helped him a bit and hooked him up
with an agent and he did it and
he went and got the book contract,
wrote a great book, which is Great.
Not just because it's interesting,
but because it's very nuanced and he's,
he shows that these are people and that
there are benefits to this way of life.
And, uh, so it's not, he
didn't villainize him. Uh,
and anyway,
uh,
I thought that that was a fantastic,
so just this idea of like
being a mentor gives,
gives so much pleasure. I
think it's, uh, you know,
in one way it's a waste of time,
but in another way it's just,
and it's also from a very practical
point of view, it's paid off.
Like now he's so much smarter than me
and more connected with the Internet that
he can help me.
What if we look at,
uh,
your toolkit and set rules that you have
done a lot of experiments for
many, many different things. If,
if you were trying to
give someone who is saying
about to get married,
recommendations for
marriage and parenting,
if you, if you had to be as not summer,
but as, as, as serious as possible, what,
what, what, what would, what would,
what would the real advice be?
Well, a couple of things come to
mind. One is, you know, the Cliche,
don't go to bed angry.
I fully disagree with that.
I go to bed angry all the time and I
find it so helpful because my wife gets
cranky at night.
If I tried to argue it out with her,
she would be furious and neither of us
would get sleep. It would be a disaster.
He go to sleep, you wake up in the
morning, you have a fresh perspective,
you can talk about it rationally.
And I do that with my kids too.
Like we start to get an argument. I
say, you know what? Let's cool down.
Let's think about this.
I'm not forgetting about this argument,
but let's reconvene in in a few hours.
So I actually, I do like that.
So don't go do, go to bed.
Angry is my first,
uh,
another one is from my wife's
a Stepdad who died recently,
but he said when we were getting married,
I thought he gave very good advice.
He said,
you both think Europe,
both gonna think that you're doing like
70% of the work in the marriage and
you're both wrong,
you know,
so just be aware of how much the other
person is doing and you're taking for
granted. Uh, and, and for
one of my experiments,
the one I said where I tried
to be the best husband,
I was one of the,
one of the things we did was we wrote a
list of everything she does in our lives
around the house and everything I do.
I honestly thought it was
going to be about 50, 50,
and it was like 80 her and 20 me.
So it was very humbling experience.
It was in one sense,
terrible because now she
realizes too how little I did.
So it's made my life worse in one sense,
but it's also,
it was very revolutionary and I
got to see, you know, like the,
the little um, liquid soap thing. I,
I just figured they refilled themselves.
It was like a self cleaning oven or
something, but I was like, oh yeah,
someone has to do that.
So be aware of how much the other person
is doing. Even if you, you don't see it,
you know, it's the, it's the conference,
you know, what the whatever biases,
you're not seeing it so
you're not aware of it. Well,
can I just pop that back
at you and ask you what,
what you would suggest to someone
going into a relationship? Ah, I think
this is probably above my pay grade.
I have not yet decided how I feel about
marriage or gained much clarity related
to, uh, to marriage. But
you know, I think I would,
I would give the advice
that Amanda Palmer,
the musician received from a mentor
furs and for any type of conflict
resolution, say less. I think
that would be the starting point.
Just say less like that because my
inclination and I think that my entire
families are much of my family is this
way. Certainly my brother's this way.
The desire to be right sometimes
overrides the pragmatic
road to being effective,
at least with uh,
my brother and I can both get kind of
righteously indignant and that does not
help with conflict resolution. It
turns out. So I would say say less.
I've become better at it.
I love, and that there are a
couple of things that come to mind.
Phrases like I've heard you can be right
or you can be married but not both,
which I think is a good one.
And then I asked some 80 year old guy
who would have been married for 50 years,
what his secret is and he said,
okay, tooth marks on the tongue.
That's the secret to a happy marriage.
Just bite your tongue,
bite it by the bite it.
It's funny,
there's some,
there's some funny bits of advice
that I've heard thrown around.
I'm not saying this is the advice I
would give. I also talked to a friend,
he's soon to be, who was it?
It was not as father in law.
It was not as direct father in law.
It,
he was about to get married
literally the day of the wedding.
And I think it was the
grandfather from the old country,
like Poland or somewhere grabbed him
and he's like, let's take a walk.
Took him for a walk and he said, this
is all you need to know. He goes,
only professionals only on the road.
So I'll let people figure that out
for themselves. But yeah, some,
some credit relationship advice out there.
Other advice I would give would be
no.
What you need to work on and ideally find
someone who's really good at what you
need to work on. Um,
because I, I do think,
at least for me,
the,
there's a complimentary polarity that
needs to exist for a relationship to have
any longevity. And uh, it's, uh,
it's a complementary set of skills,
but those could overlap
very much with attributes,
just God given or nature
given predispositions.
Uh, and then the, you know, something that
I don't know if I've ever written about,
but I've noticed for a
lot of relationships,
and this goes for Hetero normative or
homosexual goes for anything sexual as far
as I can tell, uh, at least in,
in many cases that if you were to imagine
a sliding scale and you have 100%,
and this, this is going to get people
up in a tizzy, no matter I phrase it.
So I'm going to try to state it simply,
uh,
100% what we would consider feminine
attributes on one end of the scale,
and then 100% masculine attributes
at the other end of the scale.
And in the middle you have perfect
Androgyny, just a complete perfect 50,
50 androgyny in all respects,
physical, mental, emotional,
and otherwise that wherever
you are on the slider,
you will be most attracted to and
have the most longevity. Well,
actually I should not say longevity.
You'll be most attracted to and perhaps
most compatible with someone who is the
opposite.
So if you are,
say 70% male attributes
or a masculine attributes,
30% feminine attributes,
then you will be most rejected someone
who is 70% feminine attributes,
30% masculine attributes,
and that that sort of equal polarity from
the center 50 50 proof androgyny seems
to work pretty well.
And that when you find someone who
generally,
and this is just very abstract
speculation on my part,
but it seems to be the case when you see
if people who are say overlap too much
in on one side of that spectrum,
very rarely works. And from what
I've observed, very, very rarely, uh,
so that,
that's not so much advice,
but maybe I conceptual framework for
thinking about, yeah, that's interesting.
I was trying to apply it to
my own merits to theater. Uh,
and if I lined up and I
think actually 70 30 is,
is about where I am. Salmon maybe. Yeah,
maybe 65 35 and
I don't know if different people would
say lower. So those are, those are the,
some of my passing thoughts. Um,
Bilin ones working on it. Yeah.
This is something I'm working on a lot.
I'm hoping to have a number of people
on the podcast to discuss these types of
questions as the Perella would
be one there a handful of others.
Have you had Dan savage on the, I haven't,
you know, he would be another, he'd be,
he'd be another mind to pick on this.
And uh, he's been recommended to,
to quite a few, uh, by quite a
few listeners of mine as well.
Uh, so it's, it's, uh, so I was
chatting with a friend of mine,
I don't know if you've spent any time
with Neil Strauss before. All right,
so back, so Neil, eight time New
York Times bestselling author,
he's one of those guys who never gets
writer's block. It makes me crazy.
But he wrote a piece recently,
I think it was for rolling stone and
just like the age of fear. But the point,
I might be getting the headline wrong,
but it,
the basic premise was that we've never
lived in safer times and yet everyone is
more afraid than they've ever more
fearful than they've ever been.
So for a while you wrote a column for,
I guess it was mental floss.
Yes.
Can I just say one thing about Neil
Strauss that I love is that he is so
generous with his ideas.
And this is something
I've come around to
like, uh, you know, he,
he gave me two or three book ideas.
I never pursued them,
but they're good book ideas. Like he
had one where he said, you should just,
you know what, it's kind of similar to
your podcast. You should find the best,
the Michael Jordan of everything and
learn their secrets and then write a book.
It's kind of tools for titans kind of
exactly what I did. That's hilarious.
I didn't realize that.
But I love the idea of being
generous with your ideas.
Cause when I first started my career, I
was so paranoid. I wouldn't, people say,
what are you working on? Oh, I can't tell
you. Even though it was like, you know,
it was probably some lean thing
that no one's going to steal.
And if they did steal it. So what?
It's all about execution. Uh,
so I, this is a crazy story.
This is, I'm much older than you.
So when I very first started,
I got out of college,
they were still libraries and that's
where you would go to research things.
And I was doing a book on,
it was like a joke book on the eerie,
similarities between Jesus and Elvis
because Elvis had said that he was,
he believed he was the second coming.
And I was so paranoid that I
went to two different libraries.
So I went to one to get books about
Elvis and wanting to get books.
Anybody to put two and two together.
Yeah. Is that an insane level of delusion?
They're like,
who cares?
And then now I feel telling people my
ideas at the positives outweigh the
negatives that you've,
you meet people who are interesting,
who can help you or expand the idea.
Um,
I dunno if you know Adam Mansbach,
uh, who wrote go the, I don't know.
Are you loud? Do you want the e on this
or no? Go the F to sleep. Oh No, you.
Oh yeah, yeah, absolutely. You
don't know. We have lots of cursing,
so deliberately not,
uh, Falwell compliant.
So yes, go the fuck to sleep. Really.
Yeah. And he really, it's brilliant,
which became a huge bestseller because
it got leaked as far as I can tell as a
pdf among people in the publishing
world. Oh, that's so interesting.
Part of how it became a huge bestseller.
Well that's similar to because he had put
it up as a Facebook update and like as
a joke, he said, I'm going to write
a book called go after sleep and,
and people are like,
you should do that.
So the idea of sharing and being out
there with your ideas, um, that's,
I've been a big change in my career.
So just to touch on that because I
think it's really important ideas. Uh,
Neil Strauss does this all though,
when he is working on something,
he is tremendously paranoid about it.
And when he's already
committed to writing something,
I've known Neil forever
and he's still will not,
he's afraid of letting out the meme now.
But I do think these are
two different things.
Once you fully committed
to doing something and when
you're testing the waters I
think are two distinct phases. But I
remember when I was proofreading his book,
emergency number one,
the only reason he let me write about
it or rather a read it was because he
wouldn't tell what he was writing about.
He wouldn't tell me, he wouldn't tell me.
And I just threw out this hail Mary and I
said, what is it? Some five flags stuff,
which is very sort of insider terminology
for all sorts of kind of prepper
survivalist,
multiple passport communities.
And his eyes got about the
size of, of, of, of uh,
of a dinner plate. And he
said, what have you heard,
what have you heard?
And then he would give me printed
out like 15 to 20 pages at a time to
proofread.
And then I would have to give those
back before I could have the next set.
I love it. Where are they color
coded? I color coded, although the,
I'm sure knowing the,
Oh,
there's probably some type
of identification like serial
numbers on them, but uh,
but he,
he is very generous as ideas.
Until he decides where he's going
to go all in. And Kevin Rose,
very close friend of
Mine, serial entrepreneur,
extremely successful investor,
does the same thing. And the Kevin
Kelly founding editor of wired,
one of my favorite people out there, I
think he's, he's probably the real world,
most interesting man in
the world. Uh, you know,
a technology futurist who spends time
with the Amish almost every year to
determine how they, how they
accept and vet technology. I mean,
fascinating guy.
He also tries to give away or kill as
many of his own ideas as possible and if
he can't give them away,
he can't kill them and they
stick with him and uh, he,
you know, he alone then those are the
ideas he conceived, he considers pursuing.
So in a way,
giving ideas away is one of his filters
for determining what he should work on
because he is, he's a man
of a lot of ideas. He might
have 20 different projects,
right? The ones he can't
give a give away. Uh,
when that group overlaps
with, or I should say, rather,
when you combine the ones he can't
give away with the ones that, uh,
he can't kill because he can't find
flaws in them, some fatal flaw.
Those are the projects ends up.
That's so interesting. I love that. Yeah.
So we were, but we were, uh, we were,
we were talking about earlier on
being grateful for the little things.
And then Neil came up because he
wrote this rolling stone piece on the,
the age of fear and how
everyone's terrified and
thinks that the world's going
to hell in a hand basket and every
possible respect. But objectively,
things seem pretty good.
Oh yeah. I totally believe that. And, and
there's that great Steven pinker book,
the better angels of our nature,
which traces the history of violence
and how we are in the safest time ever,
even with the horrors of the 20 20th
century wars. And, um, yeah, and I,
uh, there was a great magazine called
mental floss that just folded a month ago,
but they still have a web presence.
And I wrote a monthly column. Uh,
I can't remember. I want it to
call it the good old days sucked.
But I don't think it ended up being called
that, but, but the premise was we all,
we have this powder and problems. Oh yeah,
exactly. Modern problem. There we go.
You are, let me see.
You're better than me. Uh,
I just happened to read your Wikipedia
more, more recently than you.
Uh,
yeah,
so the idea was every month I would
take a different topic and shell how
horrible life used to be and, and
how grateful we should be. You know,
not all of us,
there are still people in other countries
and even in our country living in
horrible conditions. But
uh, if you're lucky enough,
we live in by far the best times.
And there are so many examples I did.
The first one I think was on
medicine and the one that came, uh,
the one I talked about in the first
paragraph I believe was the, uh,
the smoke enema, left tobacco,
Anima, which is, you know,
the phrase blow smoke up your ass.
Like that was a literal thing.
It came because they would have a hose
and a and a pump and they would shoot
tobacco up your butt,
uh,
because they believed that it was good
for your stomach and good for your health
kid. This might explain something that
I've been trying to figure out for
years now.
So a friend of mine sent me a photograph
of the menu of a whorehouse in like the
early 18 hundreds and it was
like blow job, $2, you know,
whatever. This type of sex,
$3, this type of sex, $1.
And then it had smoke up the ass
$30. And I was like, wait a second,
I want to know what the
smoke up the ass is about.
I was very curious because
it's like what was the,
but maybe this was actually like the
medicinal option of the venue. Exactly.
It was like,
that is fascinating.
How did something not so highly prized
come to be associated with a deceitful
flattery? Blowing smoke up your ass.
It is, it's a weird, a weird segue.
Uh, I don't know. Let to make, all right,
so the tobacco enema back in the day.
So yeah. Uh, I'm sure you can still find
it. I'm sure there's someone out there.
If you Google it, uh, oh, you
know what else to be thankful.
If you era for feeling down,
uh,
I would Google the words surgery
without anesthesia and uh,
and read the first person accounts of
people who had surgery and it is just,
Oh my God,
it is just,
does not sound appealing or pleasant
in the least? No, it was cray. Yeah.
This one woman wrote one and it was just,
you know, I couldn't sleep for days,
so even when I'm going to the
hospital for a procedure, I'm like,
all right, at least we got anesthesia
so it has made my life better.
This idea and, uh, people out there.
You can definitely find
Neil's piece on this as well,
which I think is a good two
good recalibration. Yeah.
I remember something was
really bothering me. Uh,
I was maybe I ran across
something about isis,
drowning people in cages or,
or burning people alive, both of which
are of course, horrible, horrible,
horrible things. And I was having a
conversation with someone I won't mention,
but very, very famous and successful
technologists. And he said, well,
he's like all terrible, but thank God
we're not in the Middle Ages. He's like,
broadly speaking, humanity would be much
worse off than we are right now with,
with these edge cases.
Absolutely.
And on that theme you can also
Google Louis C K on Conan.
I think it's something like everything
is great and everyone's miserable.
Yes. All right. So as far as long as
you're doing stand up, I was, I was,
I was not going to mention this,
but I will because I think it's so
hilarious living in San Francisco.
I get a overdosed on San
Francisco sometimes and there
may be a place for this.
So people out there who are aficionados
try not to freak out and just laugh at,
uh, yourselves or laugh at this because
I think it's pretty funny. Patton Oswald.
So one of my favorite
comedians has this piece, uh,
where he opens in effect
saying, you know, if,
if one of my whole foods friends
lectures me one more time on home birth,
so I'm going to punch all the soy and
the planet and he goes on to talk about,
and I'm not going to do it justice,
but he's like,
you know what women were dreaming about
on the frontier when there were like
squatting on the mud in a shack,
giving birth hospitals,
these amazing sterile environments
where you didn't have to worry about the
wolverines sneaking in and
stealing the afterbirth. And He, I,
I want people to listen to it cause I
think it's so good. I love that. Uh, yeah,
it's easy to Romanticize it itself and
the good old days when in fact the good
old days are very frequently terrible,
terrible. The terrible old is
fat. And actually that brings to mind
when I was researching the Bible, uh,
there is a line in the
Bible where God says,
because of Eve eating the apple,
uh,
women shell have pain in childbirth and
when anesthesia for childbirth was first
introduced, there were some, uh, super
religious people who are like, oh no,
we can't have that. Women
have to suffer. And a,
so thank God I and my wife,
she was like,
gimme that drug Kimmy,
give it to me now.
It was no chance she was going to
do it naturally. How did you choose,
use your [inaudible] projects?
I mean these,
these are big projects, book projects,
very time consuming. What are,
what are some of the, and maybe
this is a way to to edge into it.
What are some of the ideas you came close
to doing that you ended up not doing
it?
Uh, yeah. Well, there
was the, the Kama Sutra,
which my life up vetoing the
Bosch on. Uh, I think, uh,
the answer and maybe
not the most surprising,
but I have to be totally
passionate about it because, uh,
it can't just be something that I think
will be popular and has to be something
that I am super excited about.
Cause like you, uh, you know,
I commit to these things and maybe
not to the level of Tim Ferriss,
but I do, I go in, I go in hard and I try,
I try to be Tim Ferris, he or
my, I am the less successful,
less famous Paris.
Uh,
but how many best sellers should bad for
you're ahead of me bow not in tonight
in terms of quantity. Uh, but
yeah, I would say there's that.
And
if it makes me laugh,
I once talked to a daily show writer,
uh,
about his writing process and he said
one of the most important things to him
was that he could surprise
himself while he was writing.
And I love that idea.
Just being able to surprise yourself.
And I feel that same way about big ideas.
You have to the like when you come
up with the idea, you'd be like,
Oh man, I love that idea. I like you.
You amuse yourself or just going
like, hmm, when that happens,
I've tried to become better at that
because I've noticed a Bj Novak who's a
fantastic writer and a excellent of
course actor and everything else,
producer, well known for the office
and many other things. But uh, he,
Scott Adams as well,
creator of Dilbert really pay a lot of
attention to the kinesthetic sort of body
response to what they're writing.
And so I've tried to really,
really hone in on paying more attention
to that as I'm writing or drafting or
brainstorming or anything that's
only making a note here that,
cause I've never talked about this,
but when I'm writing and I write
something that I, I think might be funny,
I can tell there's sort of a
little ping in the back of my head,
like a little dopamine rush and yeah,
I do try to pay attention to that.
That's so interesting. I never,
never verbalized it. Um, and
then just the idea I do love,
like I think you do is taking,
uh,
an idea and just pushing it to its logical
extreme just to reductio ad absurdum.
So like, you know, when I first read
about outsourcing and I was like,
well this is cool,
how can I push this to the extreme?
How can I outsource every
single thing in the world? Uh,
and that's how I came up with
the idea for, for those folks,
beauty of Reductio ad absurdum
also underestimated and
I think its power and its
humor. Uh, why so you were saying I
have to be really excited about it.
I have to on some level maybe
find a funny why genealogy.
Well then not something that people
generally think of as the slapping.
It's true. Well genealogy is a dean.
Yeah. I try not to use that word.
I say a family history that sounds, but
there we go. Really connections or, uh,
but this came about because a
couple of years ago I was, uh,
at my desk and I got an
email from a guy and he said,
you don't know me but your 12th
cousin. And I thought, okay,
next comes,
he's going to say please,
why are $10,000 to my name Nigerian
bank account? But he didn't.
And I looked into it more.
And he's one of this group people,
they're researchers and scientists,
uh,
and geneticists who are building a family
tree, the biggest family tree ever,
the biggest possible family tree ever
of every human on earth connecting
everyone on earth in one family
tree. And I was like, that is a bold,
crazy idea. I love it. So
that's how I dove into it. And,
and it's crazy. You know, as I say,
there are two ways you do it with DNA,
but one way is on the Internet where
you almost a Wikipedia like model where
thousands, millions of people are
working on the same big family tree.
So I'm on this tree,
which now has 100 million people.
And one of the fun things that will take
up like a week of your life as he can
figure out how you're related
to almost anyone else.
Like Barack Obama for instance.
This is true is my fifth grade aunt's
husband's brother's wife's seventh great
nephew. So, uh, so we're pretty close.
I'm sure when he's out of office
soon he'll be hang in with me.
So I loved this idea.
It's like six degrees of Kevin Bacon,
but everyone is Kevin Bacon. Uh, and,
and I became entranced and I
decided this is my next book.
And for your listeners,
actually it has very practical
implications because you
were article here on the
Tim Ferriss show. Yeah.
This is, uh, this is a,
this is a tool I believe four titans or,
or non titans. But it is, it's like
the greatest social network ever.
It's like linkedin on
steroids because I was trying,
I threw an event of trying to hold the
biggest family reunion ever and I needed
publicity. So I would find
a reporter or a TV producer.
I would figure out how I was related to
them. I would send them an email and say,
listen, this may sound weird, but
you are my, uh, seventh cousin,
three times removed, husband's son. Uh,
so we're,
we're family.
Would you do a favor for a cousin
and write about my project?
And I'd say, you know, 20% of the time
they were freaked out and like, you know,
stop stalking me. But 80% of the time
they were intrigued. They're like, really?
We're cousin. Oh, that's
so interesting. And,
and I got more publicity that way than
anything. So what was the subject line?
Do you remember what the subject
line it might've been? Uh,
I think it was from Asia. Your relative?
Yeah, from Adj, your distant cousin.
I wanted to,
for my book about it,
I wanted to interview George h w Bush.
So, you know, cause he's
like, got this huge family.
So I emailed his chief of staff and
is like, you know, uh, and she said,
oh, we're where he's not doing interviews.
And I said, well, but I am a cousin.
She's like, oh, well your cousin,
I guess we can make an exception,
probably go down and interview them.
So until for,
for another like three years, this will
work and then everyone will realize,
oh wait, everyone's cousins. So, uh,
but I highly recommend
it as a strategy for now.
Gotta make it gotta make it
count while you can. Right. Uh,
why did you decide to do a podcast?
Yes. I am now a number of fans,
uh,
of yours and mine said they'd
love to your audio books.
Ah, that's nice. And have you,
God,
you know,
this went in a need to edit this out
if this is not the right anecdote,
but I could swear that you told me at
some point that you went into record your
audio book and the People at the studio,
I want to say this was you. They
said, well, you seem to have a cold,
so why don't you come back when
you don't have a cold? Is this,
is this the right story? Oh, that's
hilarious. But I, you know what,
it might well have been, I don't
trust my memory. So I have a,
one of my friends at least who, who has
gone on Abe's, you or somebody else.
And he, he went into record his
audio book and he was so excited
when they went on to be hugely successful.
And the Andy,
he recorded for a 10 minutes and
the producer and the students like,
you know what, let's, let's take a
break. And, uh, when, uh, what we have,
you come in in a few days when you're
cold is over. And he's like, no,
I don't have a goal. This is
just what I sound like. Love it.
I know I have an odd voice. I
have an invoice. It hasn't, uh,
it hasn't hindered me to my own.
I'm not saying you have an odd voice.
I was bringing it up because I thought
that it was from you, but I love that.
Well, I will tell you when I had
recorded my audio book, I, um,
I apparently had a very active stomach.
I, and so it was growing a lot.
Uh,
so I had to do a lot of rethinks and I
was apologize and the producers and they
said, no, no to everyone
that have with everyone.
And they in fact had a file of all these
famous authors like body sounds like,
like Susan Sontag's farts or
whatever. Uh, and I was like,
you got to put that out.
Like that would be the most awesome album,
famous people's bodily functions.
Uh, but I don't think they did.
So anyway, the podcast, so I took us off
the rails podcast. I'm very excited about.
It's a,
it's called twice removed and it's sort
of an interview show mixed with hardcore
history mixed with a game show.
So it's an odd mix.
And the idea is we take a notable person
and then we go through their family
history and find the most interesting
inspirational stories and then talk about
those.
And then at the end we introduced them
to a cousin they didn't know they had.
So it's sort of this like surprise ending.
And it could be someone
like that bear their hero,
maybe their mentor. It could be a, you
know, an ex girlfriend. It could be.
It could be anyone. And we don't,
we haven't done that yet, but,
uh, but yeah,
exactly. You, our wives, we all
our cousins with your spouse. Uh,
but yeah, no, I,
and it's being produced
by Gimlet who start up,
uh, which I'm sure because you're
friends with Chris Saka and so,
uh, yeah, uh, startup,
which is, as you might know,
your listeners might know. It's like, uh,
it was a podcast about starting
a podcast company, very metta.
Um,
so they are doing it and they
are amazing because they are,
they're all like this
American life, uh, alumns.
And so they are just so good at editing
and crafting the story and music.
And I,
I know nothing about it.
So it's been a fascinating learning
experience and learning also how to tell
stories in an audio way, which
is just different. And, uh,
so I've, I've found it, uh,
it's fascinating. Uh, it's been,
uh, uh, we'll see. We'll see how it
does, but I'm, I'm excited. Yeah.
They have a really good team. I
mean, Alex Bloomberg, he's actually,
he's also in tools of titans.
Really,
really good at asking
questions because he's, he's,
he records really long tape and is
good at eliciting emotion and stories
specifically like you said, from interview
subjects. And he, uh, he gives me,
I'm sure I, since you interviewed
him, like, yeah, the silence.
He's like brilliant at using the silence.
Just like waiting on,
getting the silence, do the work.
Oh yeah. He's really, really good.
And they've had a whole string of
really successful shows me and reply all
mystery show. They've had a very,
very consistent hit rate. So, uh,
cost. I will be certainly
checking that out. And uh,
and we actually had one that's sort of
related to some of the stuff you do.
We had, um, Abby Jacobson
who's on broad city,
she's a hilarious comedian, but one of
her ancestors was this entrepreneur,
a woman entrepreneur.
So we did like a whole segment on female
entrepreneurs through history, uh,
including Betsy Ross. Like we all
think of her dislike, so in the flag.
But apparently she's like, she had
like a team. She was, cause she was,
she was a kitten. Yeah.
Uh, and same with, um,
JFK is great.
Grandma came over and opened
a like a button shop and it's,
the Kennedys would not have existed
if she hadn't been an entrepreneur and
funded her kids' education and then they
whatever got into liquor and then that
spawned the political dynasty,
the gateway to all good things.
Is it
to you or of course going
to be promoting the podcast?
You've promoted books in the past,
done various types of PR and marketing.
Uh,
one of the bullets that I
wanted to talk about was,
and this is in your voice, but how I
learned to love marketing these, a lot of,
a lot of authors,
a lot of artists certainly
think of marketing as a
sullying their hands with the
dirty work of commercialism or, uh, a,
an evil to be avoided.
So how did you learn to
I didn't, well, you know, partly
inspired by Tim Ferris. Uh,
but partly it was,
I reframed marketing,
I'm trying to think of it, not as the
sullying, uh, that selling my art,
but as something that could
be creative in its own right.
And part of this was I interviewed
the artist Christo, you know,
the guy who raps islands and uh,
the, the gates in central park,
a really interesting guy.
And he was working on this
one project for 24 years.
He was trying to put up
these gates in central park,
these like flat, uh, these curtains
and arches in central park,
like 10,000 orange, uh, arches.
And he had to deal with city
bureaucracy for 24 years.
So I asked him, you know,
God, that must have been so
frustrating. And he said, well,
yes and no.
He said,
I actually see dealing
with the bureaucracy and as
part of my art is like all
part of one big art project.
Uh,
so I don't separate it from the
actual designing of the, uh,
of the pieces. And I was like, that's
an interesting way to look at it.
So I tried to apply that to marketing
and instead of seeing it as this horrible
pain in the ass, like, what can
I do that's creative with it?
And one of the things when I was
doing the year of living biblically,
for instance,
I was like,
how can I a section this off so it,
uh,
I can appeal to like
50 different audiences.
So I wrote a piece for a music
magazine about music in the Bible.
Uh,
I did for Glamour magazine.
I wrote sex advice in
the Bible cause there's,
there's a good amount of sex
in the Bible. Um, and uh,
and it was actually, it
was very interesting. I've,
I became a fan of this way of
thinking as opposed to being an end.
The same thing with speeches.
I used to hate giving speeches,
but like we said before, the whole
fake it till you make it. Uh, I,
I forced myself to do every speech I
could and now I just, you know, I love,
I actually,
I, I'm not a fan of sitting down
in front of the keyboard, but I,
I'd much rather be on stage talking.
Well that's part of the, uh,
the dangerous Siren Song of marketing.
So when I was working on tools of titans,
I uses a program called scrivener to put
together my books that I've done that
for the last three books. And
there is a, I had a working file,
which was marketing ideas and I found it
was very dangerous to have that within
a stone's throw of my writing because it
was always easier to or more enjoyable
for me to work on the marketing ideas
and put off the actual work of writing.
So it had marketing ideas
and I modified the file name.
So it was marketing ideas,
Ha Dash,
focus on writing in all caps,
exclamation points.
Uh,
that's it.
But now if you had to rank the different
parts of your job in terms of enjoyment
and enjoyment that they give you,
what would you say? Well, it's a,
funny enough,
this past this,
this last book was the first one
that I've enjoyed writing. I enjoy,
I love doing what I'm doing right now,
which is my favorite part of
writing without the writing,
right? The interviewing,
I love the interviewing and
the researching. Do. I do
enjoy the experimentation,
but there's sometimes go
sideways as you and I both know.
So there's a always turn out
as intended or hoped. Uh,
and then the probably historically
would have been marketing and then the
writing, but the writing
was right there. I would say
yes. Not at par with the marketing, maybe
even ahead of it this time around, which,
what do you think that was?
Was it the,
the topic or what did you discover
some who enjoy their work?
There were a few things.
I think that primarily it was the
enjoyment and assimilation of,
this is kind of Meta,
but absorbing the lessons
and recommendations of the
people I interviewed as I
was editing and reviewing and taking
multiple passes on these chapters.
Interesting. So I was, I was
actually incorporating a lot of the,
what's an example? Do you remember
one? Sure. Oh yeah, I was,
I ended up having a routine
where, for instance, I did a,
used a barrel sauna,
which with the exact same specs as Rick
Ruben who recommended it to me, uh,
and alternated that with cold
exposure at specific times of the day.
Just like Wim Hoff Wood.
And in the mornings I would listen to
say a guided meditation from Tara Brock,
specifically the 2010
summer smile meditation,
which Ray proposal recommended to me.
So I started incorporating,
and then I would take say exogenous
ketones, which of these powders,
synthetic ketones, which Dominic
D'Agostino had recommended to me.
So all of these bits and
pieces from the actual
became part of my daily routine
for working on the chapters,
which is kind of wild. And then there's
the deeper kind of philosophical stuff.
I was writing this mostly over the summer
and early fall and there were a few
people in the book,
like Bj Miller who is a palliative
care physician who's helped more than
thousand people die. Ed Cooke,
memory champion who taught,
you might remember a book
called moonwalking with
Einstein. Yeah. So Ed Cooke is,
who is the the memory champion
slash coach who taught in this case?
I think it was Joshua Four.
Yeah, there's four brothers.
Both amazing writers. Uh, three of
you now there are three. That's right.
So to become national membrane champion
in the U S in one year. So Ed Cooke,
NBJ Miller,
both use stargazing is a way to reduce
anxiety and they both have particular
ways that they go about it.
So,
so I did that every night before going
to bed and it just went on and on and on.
So I think that the subject matter itself
had a huge impact on the writing of
the book,
which was unexpected in a
way that is the mark helpful.
Yeah.
And the marketing at this point for me
is fun because I try to make it fun in
the sense that I very often ask myself,
how can I make the
launch itself PR worthy,
if that makes sense. And that forces
me to do sometimes absurd things.
And even if some of the
absurd things are, uh, what,
what I might consider or people
might consider a waste of money,
like doing billboards in New York City
right now I have 80 plus billboards in
New York City with the answers
from guests to the question,
what would you put on a billboard if
you could put anything on a billboard to
get a message out to millions of people.
So we've got all these answers and took
some of my favorites and now they're on
actual physical billboards all throughout
New York City that probably doesn't
sell a lot of books.
But that gives me such childlike joy
to do something that absurd and to make
guests happy themselves,
that even if it is a waste of money,
it's probably not a waste of money,
meaning an isolation.
Maybe it's a waste of money,
but because of the infusion of enthusiasm
that it's given me an excitement,
it's created in a,
among many of the of the guests and
people who ended up in the book.
It's acted as fuel for a lot of other
things that actually do have a good
financial return or at
least a clear financial.
I love that. Funny. Yeah. I had a
similar experience. I actually have,
I'm finishing my book on the family now,
but as part of it last
summer, I through, uh,
the biggest worldwide
family reunion, uh, ever,
and that was like financially not a great,
but it was,
uh,
it was so fun and so interesting. Uh, and,
and I hope raised the profile enough
that it will pay off in the end.
But, um, yeah, cause it was
like 4,000 people in New York.
But then there were 40
simultaneous reunions around
the world and sister sledge
came and saying, we are a
family. One thing, this was a,
this was a revelation. You know, I was
sister sledge, we are family. I'm like,
this is the perfect. So this is, uh,
but it turns out like one of the sisters,
like he's not talking
to the other lawsuit.
So their family in the sense that
every family is dysfunctional.
Uh,
let's grab a couple of the end questions
and then we'll jump into some rapid
fire questions. Yeah. This is a
question you probably get a lot.
I certainly get it a lot,
but I'm curious how you would answer.
This is from Constantine.
He knows them stiffs of, as,
I can't pronounce it, but
it's a I. N o z. E m t.
S. E. V. Which experiment or approached
turned out to be a total dud.
Something that you had extremely high
hopes for? The completely flopped.
I did star, uh, and you probably will
remember this guy's name, but, uh,
the man who invented a,
the idea of micro expressions where you,
right Paul? I come in, yes,
there we go. And it was,
his idea was he was like the
show about the lie catcher,
you know, the people you can tell who's
lying based on their facial expressions.
So I interviewed him, great interview,
and I tried it and I just couldn't do it.
I don't know.
I don't know whether it's because
it's a pseudoscience or whether,
because it's my failure probably
the ladder, but I, it just,
uh,
and it's fun to write about failures,
but not when there's just nothing but
can eat a little know lesson learned.
Just couldn't do. Exactly. Uh, all right.
This is from Miguel flea
gear, I think it is, uh,
book outtakes from your
year of living biblically.
Is there anything that didn't make it in
that interesting? I did, yes. There was,
in Orlando, there's a theme park
called the Holy Land Experience,
which is the Disney version of,
uh,
ancient Jerusalem. And so
you've got, and you know,
instead of mascots like Disneyworld,
you've got, you know, Jesus,
you got this guy with robes and the
beard and he's got a little Madonna,
Ted face, Mike. And he's, you know,
talk and you've got
these guys like lepers.
That was my feet like a blind leper
begging on the street with his little
microphone. Uh, so, and then
they read it. But, but anyway,
I went there and it could have been
a funny chapter in that it was,
I found it very ridiculous, but it was
also like shooting fish in a barrel.
It was like, or I think PJ
O'rourke said, uh, you know,
shooting cows with a sawed off
shotgun. It was just too easy. And um,
and there, and there are people,
I'm sure that it was meaningful too.
So why, why ruin their lives
just for a cheap laugh?
So that didn't make it,
so this is, I mean, these
are all related, I suppose.
This is from Anna Lamont and I'll,
I'll try to simplify this a little bit,
but that,
or I might rephrase that for I read,
it would be great to hear you take on
whether it's possible to completely rewire
our subconscious to ignore the norms
and expectations instilled by society,
family, environment, et Cetera, or
is it a never any work in progress,
something that you need to become
aware of and focus on every single day?
So I think part,
if I could read into this,
maybe what is being asked is or implied,
is that we both do all
these crazy experiments.
How have you trained yourself to ignore
the norms and conventions? But, uh,
and this was directed at both of us.
For me,
I would say the writing is
just the ultimate excuse.
It's the,
it's the perfect alibi to do any absurd
thing you could possibly conceive of.
And then just say, I'm doing
it and writing it out. And
people are like, oh, okay.
Then, I mean, but if you were
doing it seriously, right, if you,
if you didn't have the pretext of
writing about it for the year of living
biblically, like I'm sure plenty of
people thought you were crazy anyway,
but there are people who would have
assumed you were completely insane who
otherwise were like, oh, that's
so genius. Oh, what a great idea.
Yeah, absolutely. I
think that's it. I mean,
I think if you on a fee yourself as a
method writer or instead of a method actor
and just get into character, um,
I, I often do that. I'm like,
I'm going to get into character now. I,
you know, this is not me. This is me.
And I think that you don't have to
be a writer to do that. Actually,
I think the idea of
experimenting on your own life,
even if you're not writing a book, is
I think it's great to just, you know,
try eight different toothpastes
and see which works.
But there is a sense where
you have to commit and you're
like, you know what, I'm,
I'm going to force myself to do this.
I'm going to take on a character
and I'm going to do it. Uh,
so that I find very helpful.
And I think
also I would say this to Anne or
anyone is that if you frame something,
even if you're not writing
about it as an experiment,
I'm doing x for y number of months.
You also can kind of get away with murder
in the sense that if you're worried
about trying something unusual
or uncommon and you can get to,
what should I test by the extension to
reductio ad absurdum, right. Like, okay,
if people are outsourcing like you did,
what is the most absurd,
exaggerated place where, where's
the most absurd, exaggerated place?
I can take this. Yeah,
right. Like, all right.
Passive aggressive bickering with my wife.
Like I'm going to have someone that on
my behalf or an uh, or having eaten,
I actually, ah, you know, this
might be another misattribution
but had no, it's not,
it's not this one. I think
I'm getting right. Were you,
you hired someone to be worried
on your behalf? I saw an extreme.
I thought that was, you found it really
helpful and that sounded so absurd.
But I remember,
I think it was a four hour body.
I was really stressed
out about the deadline.
And so I paid her a virtual assistant
to worry about my deadline for me.
And it was just, it was
such a weird, uh, form of,
not necessarily self deception,
but like taking advantage of a quirk of
human psychology to know that someone
else was on the job. So then I, I
then, who is your virtual assistant?
Was it like an Indian or, uh, in from
Philippines. The Philippines. Yeah.
Good Warriors. Yeah. And
that is awesome. Well, I,
and I also think calling it an
experiment gives you permission to fail
because it's an experiment.
Sometimes experiments fail.
So if you do a change in your life
and say, I'm experimenting with this,
it makes it, and it reminds me of, uh, uh,
I'm probably gonna get this wrong,
but I think it was a French writer named
Montonya who came up with a little word
essay,
which means to try.
So that's what I find that so freeing.
Like when you write something,
it's you're just trying it,
let's try and may work, may not.
And the more that at least
has been true for me,
the more experiments you attempt and
the more you try to push the absurd,
uh,
in certain respects,
the easier it gets because you realize
the penalties are generally not that
severe with some of the
stupid stuff that I do at,
they end up physically being pretty
severe and you can get very injured.
Like don't try to learn park where in a
week it turns out to be a bad idea for
your knees. I saw you recently after
that you had done that and you were,
I was good. I was not in good shape.
He's still have injuries from that.
But generally if you're doing these,
these experiments that you think you're
going to be judged very harshly for,
if you're presenting them in,
in the right way,
if you feel compelled to explain them,
uh,
generally they're very few repercussions
and people were actually more
supportive and interested
in then you would expect.
And also if you get something good
out of it, uh, for your own life,
then it's probably worth it.
Unless you inflict massive pain on others.
Like with radical honesty.
Yes. Radical honesty.
That's the other one I
want to explore a bit.
There's a great book called
lying by Sam Harris. I read that.
I think it's a great, great
book. Very complimentary to the,
I think you're fat as a, uh, okay.
So here's,
this is from Charlotte Chapman,
most embarrassing
failure at an experiment.
So aside from the micro
expressions, right? Uh,
most embarrassing failure and experiment,
did he give up or refine his approach?
Interesting. Yeah. Well, I mean,
I think my life been a series of
embarrassments and humiliations.
So in a way you engineer your,
that's true. I experiments to
be embarrassing. Yes, exactly.
Because I'd also think that makes me
better, a better copy is, you know,
and that is actually one thing I was
thinking about that I learned doing this
podcast is that I'm being humiliated on
radio is actually sometimes makes for
better radio. So, uh,
when I'm doing interviews and I ask a
question and the person is like, God,
that's a dumb question. That is beautiful.
That makes the cut. That's gold.
Yeah. So I, I may not look that sound,
that good on the podcast, but I
think it's entertaining. So, um,
but yeah, I would say many humiliations
I, I don't know if this counts,
but this is the first one
that comes to mind is, uh,
I was working at Esquire magazine
and we asked the actress,
Mary Louise Parker to pose
nude. And I was, uh, uh, uh,
tasked with asking her and she
said, well, I will pose nude,
but only if the editor of the piece
also poses nude. And I was the editor.
So, uh, I went to my editor in chief
and he was like, all right, well do it.
Take off your pants. That's your job. Uh,
so I had to pose nude for a very
well known celebrity photographer.
And it was, it was quite humiliating
and, and, uh, vulnerable and,
and also highly insulting
because I was, you know, he was,
he's a big photographer, so you'd
like 10 assistants, like Gorgeous,
20 something female assistance. And I was
like, oh my God, this is so embarrassing.
But they could not care less.
They were like, you were like,
no interest in my nude form.
So that was like,
that was tough for my ego.
And then they came out and they actually
published the picture and we got some
subscription cancellations, I
believe. So it was a, overall,
I was a, it was a dark
time. All right, let's,
let's do some rapid fire questions, which
may in fact be misnamed. Uh, but there,
there's short questions.
The answers don't need to be short.
When you hear the word successful,
who's the first person who comes
to mind or who comes to mind?
Uh, well, this is a little schmaltzy
even answer, but I would say my dad, uh,
he is a lawyer who loves his job.
Like,
he literally has no hobbies because only
loves is spending time with his family
and his job. So if you can derive
that much pleasure from your job,
uh, I think that's a success. I mean,
to me they're two criterion for success.
One is that you're happy and the other
is that you're making the world a better
place. So, um, and I think he does both.
And he's also like,
he is definitely in,
in our genre of like taking
things to the ridiculous extreme.
He, he writes law books and he holds
the world record for the most number of
footnotes in a law article.
4,280.
Yeah.
So he finds something
and he just goes with it.
Wow. Apple does not fall too far
from the tree on that one. Uh,
what is, I don't ask this with
everyone, but I'll, I'll ask you,
what is something you believe that other
people think is insane or that very few
people who would agree with you on?
Yeah, I love this question. And there,
there are many, many things. Uh,
so let me just go over a
couple of them quickly. Uh,
without trying to alienate too many of
your listeners are so alienated away.
Yeah, they're tough. All right.
One is a cannibalism. Uh,
what about it? You're
up. You're a proponent.
I am a proponent of ethical
camel cannibalism. Okay.
I'm very interested in excited
about in vitro meat, lab grown meat.
Like you take a little cell from
a chicken and grow, uh, you know,
a chicken breast or,
um,
so I'm very excited that I think in 10
or 20 years it's going to be reality and
it's going to open up. You don't have
to just eat cows or chickens, you know,
you get a human burger. Yeah. Human
burial. Well, I was thinking like, yeah,
giraffe are endangered animals, but
yeah, take it to the extreme. You get,
what is the harm in eating another human,
a human burger.
And this is my idea for a startup.
I know.
I think you've pulled back on
angel investing, so yeah. But um,
and maybe some money. Plenty
of them listening. All
right. This may have already,
someone may already be doing this,
but my idea is a celebrity meat.
So like you can eat a Brad Pitt
Burger. Yeah. Either Ebita,
Clooney Burger or eat a, you know, a
j Lo Burger or, and it could even be
specific body parts like that.
Little creepy.
But I wonder what will end up
being the Kobe beef of humans.
So it's like if you can, if you
can choose gender, race and so on,
like where do we end up? Right, right.
Yeah. That's interesting. I Dunno,
I dunno for that. You have questions just
begging to be answered. So cannibalism.
Okay,
that's one.
Um, another one I like Sam Harris.
I don't believe in free will,
which I think,
uh,
is some people see that as depressing,
but I actually find it
liberating and when,
because it's so much easier to forgive
yourself for doing stupid things if he
realize that you really didn't have,
there was no other die has been
cast the die as we can endure.
And I think you're more forgiving of other
people and the stupid things they do.
No, no. Conversely though wouldn't,
couldn't you also be more uh,
forgiving or accepting of things that
should not be condoned or is that that
just come back to the lack of
free will and your, your sort of,
my feeling is there's a difference
between a fatalism and determinism.
So you can believe that
you don't have freewill.
But of course our decisions
make a difference.
Like if I just for the rest of the month
old lay here on this couch, you know,
my life would, would fall
apart. I realize that.
So I'm not saying our
decisions make a difference.
It's just those decisions are
predetermined. That's a big subject.
Uh Oh and I did have, wait, what was
the other one that I wanted to bring up?
Shoot, it'll come back to it and go
back to it. Oh well the last one,
which is multi versus a,
I know a lot of physicists
believe in multi verses and,
but it really hit me with this election
cycle because it is so like I can see at
the convention of of universes
all of the multiverse is an ICC.
Our Universe is going to be like
getting just ton of crap. Like guys,
this is the universe where
Donald Trump is president.
Like can you believe that we'd be like,
if the multiverse is actually
collection of kids in school,
you're saying that we're
going to be taunted? I think
so. I do believe that. Uh,
so yeah, that's what I've been
thinking about recently. What books,
what book or books have you gifted the
most to other people besides your own? Uh,
I would say, I can't remember whether you
had them on as a gas, but Jonathan Heit,
I have not heard him on as a guest.
He's a great writer.
How do you spell his last
name? H. A. I. D. T and I,
maybe he's come up a few times
in conversation with friends.
Recently did a great ted talk.
He wrote a book called the righteous
mind and it's all about trying to figure
out the,
the gap between the red and blue states,
Republican and Democrat.
And it's really interesting.
And he likens it to almost taste buds.
Like Republicans have different moral
tastes buds than Democrats. And,
uh,
I think the righteous mind may have been
recommended to me by a neuroscientist
about a year ago,
a phd in neuroscience.
So the righteous mind,
uh,
what purchase of $100 or less has most
positively impacted your life in recent
memory? Is a good question. Uh,
well one thing I do love the, my
elastic shoe laces and my, uh,
do you use those? No, I
like this idea though.
I was just fussing with
shoelaces yesterday and got
so fed up that I went and
found a different pair of shoes that
I had packed, uh, which you know,
if she likes it. So elastic shoe
laces. Yeah. So you just replace the,
the cloth shoe laces with these,
alas,
I think it's called lace
lock is of the brand I use.
And yet lay shoe laces
seem like such like 19th,
18th century technology. It's
so crazy. We still use them.
And these ones you just slip them
on and they, they, for me at least,
they're just as tight and uh,
and secure.
And also they're also not as sort of
mental institution is like velcro shoes.
You don't have to make the jump to Velcro,
you can go in between with the
right. Yeah, the velcro. If you're
under seven or like over 80,
you can get away with velcro.
But in between it's hard.
Uh, do you have any
particular morning rituals?
Anything that is particularly
important to you that is not obvious?
Like,
yes,
you want to keep your kids alive and
I'm imagining feed them in some form and
fashion,
but as a,
are there any other morning routines
or rituals that are important for you?
Well, one we talked about is sort
of the, the mental calisthenics.
I find that helpful.
Another you talk about in your books,
which is the sort of restricting
information, information diets.
And I have tried sometimes successfully
to stop reading the newspaper or any
news in the morning because,
you know,
then I just get depressed and spiral.
Uh,
I find it good to read news right before
I go to bed cause then I get depressed
and I'm able to fall
asleep. So, uh, that for me,
keeping your mind clear away from
news in the morning is, is crucial.
Uh, if you were to give a Ted talk
on something you are not known for,
so you've given a lot of talks,
but something that you are not
associated with or known for whatsoever,
what would it be on? Oh,
that's a good one. That's a
good one. I, um, let me think.
Uh,
I don't know if this might be repetitive,
but just talking about all
of the horrible, the ways
that the past is horrible.
I think I could go on for like, I know you
only have 20 minutes of, or a Ted talk,
but I could go on for like four hours.
Uh, do you have any, anything,
is there anything that you, uh,
obsess on or over on the
evenings or weekends?
It's just something I got a
pet obsession of yours that is,
that you have not talked about.
Let's see. I mean, yes,
I'm sure I'm, I'm a,
a slightly obsessive
person as are you. So, um,
yeah, slightly, it's slightly, is
very generous in my case at least.
Uh, I, I'm trying to think.
I would say, I guess,
uh, that I'm, I do have
the fear of missing out,
not on parties, but on ideas. Like I am,
I'm always nervous like that.
I haven't read enough and that there's
great ideas and I'm just willfully
ignorant. Uh, so, so
that's, I guess something.
You read the newspaper before you go to
bed, exit breast and Wallah that then, uh,
if you think about bad advice, what is,
what is some bad advice that you
hear given out often in your world?
And you can define that any way you
want. It could be writing, could be,
I do have one, I have one that's like a
pet peeve of mine, which is be yourself,
uh, because you know what,
if yourself is an asshole,
like Stalin, he was being himself
just lets down would be stolen.
That guy was really being
himself. So I think, uh,
if you think about this a little more,
a little less flippantly,
I think there are things that are very
deep in us. You know, if you're gay,
you're gay, don't try to
change that. But there are, uh,
aspects of our personality
that we think are ingrained,
but that can be changed.
Like I don't think I'm a very
outgoing person. Naturally.
I think I,
I would spend most days
just indoors reading,
but I forced myself to be social,
uh,
sort of force myself to be a, um, uh,
to get out there and it's made my life
better because you interact with people,
you're happier. So don't
just be yourself, try to,
you know,
be the best parts of yourself,
but then take the worst parts of
yourself and try to change those,
which I think you do.
No, no, I agree with that.
I agree with that bias.
And I think there's also be
yourself implies that you're
a finished product in a
sense to, which is where I take
issue with the [inaudible],
the obsession with discover yourself,
where
maybe as a compliment to that at
least maybe even at an alternative,
the create yourself maybe
in some ways more accurate.
Even though we think of this
persistent, I, this persistent Tim,
this persistent Aaj, uh, I mean from,
from the cells in our body to just
about every other aspect of our being.
We were constantly in
flux. I love that, uh,
works in progress.
So I may not have time to put
this up in the next few weeks,
but if you get,
have one gigantic billboard anywhere to
get a message out to millions of people,
they could not be an advertisement.
Uh, any short message,
I was thinking about this
cause I know you ask it.
I mean one thought that occurred to
me is it's something like, you know,
life is too complicated and subtle and
filled with grace to be summed up on a
billboard. So don't pay attention to
billboards, something metta like that.
Um, I did a piece on, on effective
altruism. I know you introduced,
interviewed McCaskill. Yeah, I
am a fan of that way of thinking.
Just, you know, how lucky we
are and trying to give back.
So maybe like, you know,
I is that,
but that would be an advertisement.
No, not necessarily. I mean
you could have a, you know,
if you make more than 68 k per year,
you're in the global 1%.
Yeah. Something like that. Yeah.
It was interesting cause like
you got to use guilt, um,
very guilt will only get you so far like
that that might get you in the door.
But then this feeling of,
of empowerment of helping others I think
is a better motivator for altruism.
Yeah.
Well I think it's more if you're looking
to optimize the lifetime value of a
donor as opposed to a single transaction
that the then resent then yeah.
Guilt is not the primary tool.
Right. At least it seems that way.
Just working with a number of nonprofits,
um,
myself we'll say in educational stuff.
So I sometimes ask people what advice
they would give their younger self.
I'm going to pose it a different
way because you have this,
this aged photo of yourself,
your,
your 82 year old self in your house.
What,
what advice do you think your 82 year
old self would give your current self?
That is a good one. I
like that twist. I think,
um,
and I tried to do this.
I think my 82 year old self
hopefully will be wiser and happier.
I do think overall my level
of happiness has arisen, uh,
which is nice. Um, so hopefully
trending in the right direction,
hopefully fingers crossed
that continues. Uh, and I,
I guess I battled this to
even today is um, uh, don't,
uh,
don't be so opinionated,
don't have such strongly held beliefs
that they can't be changed with evidence.
Uh, you know, I think that
this society is a weird,
as a weird fetish with a
strongly held beliefs and like,
you know, these are my deep seated
beliefs and if you change him,
you're a flip flopper and I, you know,
I think we should got to rebrand.
Flip flopping is great as long as you're
doing it based on evidence and not on
whims like you are,
you have the ability to,
uh, you know, the courage
to change your conviction.
It's not just the courage
of your convictions, but
the courage to change them.
So maybe I would tell myself, you know,
work on that part of your personality.
That's what makes a good scientist
as well now. Exactly right.
What is [inaudible]
one of your favorite personal failures?
What I mean by that is
specifically a failure that
led in some way to a later success or
set the stage for the later success.
Well, I have had many, many failures,
have ways as we've discussed.
And I am a big fan of them. I, uh,
you know, and rejection. I try,
that's one of the things I try to teach
my kids all the time. Like, you know,
you're going to get rejected 98% of the
time. He just got to keep going. One,
I don't know if this falls into
the right category, but I, uh,
NBC a couple of years ago options my life,
one of my books and that it
was going to be a comedy, uh,
where every week it was this writer
did another wacky experiment and chaos
ensued. Uh, and it was a total
failure. It didn't get picked up.
What the lesson I learned was I
actually made a conscious effort.
I was like, you know what, this
may or may not get picked up,
but I am going to consciously enjoy this
experience and get everything I can out
of it. Uh, you know, I got to meet Donald
Sutherland, played my father in law.
Um, my wife was played by this woman
who had much bigger boobs than she did,
so she loved it
and it was just a blast.
And I would go into meetings and I would
see, he'd be like, you know what if,
what if the main character who is
named Aja, what if he did this?
And they're like, oh, a Jay would never do
that. I'd be like, ah, well I am. I don't,
maybe he would.
But it was just so much fun.
And there's one producer who I read
a book of hers and she's like, yeah,
if you cannot enjoy the process,
then you're screwed because the chances
of getting a movie actually made are so
infinitesimal. So enjoy the process,
enjoy the walk up the mountain,
not just the summit. That
was a, that was a big lesson.
What's a, if you think
back, can you think of
the best or one of the best investments
you've ever made? And that could be time,
energy, money. I'll give you an example.
So a Amelia Boone three time
world's toughest mudder champion,
most decorated obstacle course racer
in the world, full time attorney,
also at Apple.
But it was her first entrance
fee for one of these races,
which was I think at the time,
$400, $450, which was a stretch.
I mean it was a,
a real expenditure for,
but it opened up this entirely new
career and she not taken that. Who knows?
Uh, can you kidding? It doesn't have
to be analogous to that, but, uh, he,
can I go the other way? I have two
ideas. One is about a month ago,
I wrote an article for Esquire where I
got the most expensive haircut in the
world in New York City and $800 haircut.
And it was crazy cause, uh,
you know, as this guy, uh,
it was on Park Avenue, his name is
Julien Farel and he was very friendly.
She said, Eric got. Um, and I was like,
and it was a fascinating
learning experience because
of course it's not worth
$800. It's like, that's
insane. It's like, you know,
20% better than my super cuts,
which cost 20 bucks.
But just learning,
he gets clients,
he is booked all the time. Like
how does he do this? And you know,
he's got Goldman Sachs guys who've come
in every week for an $800 haircut and
it's, it's all about the experience
because the actual cutting,
it's not that different.
Right.
But the experience of the Cappuccino
and the music and you know,
he'll talk to you,
stare,
you deepen the eyes and talk to you about
what your hair means to you and how it
can change your life and tough
task ahead of them with me if I go
maybe,
although there the lot small remaining
parts I have. Do you mean a lot to them?
Yeah. So yeah, it was fascinating.
I mean that's how he does it. It's,
and he'll look at your
skull for like five minutes,
like an artist like
knowledgist for knowledge.
So he's able to get clients
by making the experience,
even though the price
is just so ridiculous.
Maybe it's because the prices
are ridiculous. That's a
good part of it. Exactly.
He has just Jack. So anyway,
I thought that was an eye.
I did not pay for it,
luckily ask why are paid for it.
So I guess one of my first books was
about reading the Encyclopedia Britannica
when they still actually printed that
till they were like 40, 33 volumes.
And uh,
I read them all and that costs,
that costs $1,500 to buy that set,
which is an absurd amount for a,
a book,
but it turned out it paid off.
So would you say,
was that book
one of the biggest inflection points
for you as a writer? I mean, did that,
would you, would, if something
put you on the map as a writer,
was it that book or was it
an earlier piece where you,
Saffron Atlee that took it to
a different level. And, uh,
I had written a couple
of other books before,
but they were sort of novelty
short books like, you know,
one was called America offline about
this wonderful world outside of the
Internet where you can actually meet
people face to face and it's all like four
copies. I it came out, I think it
was, uh, it, it would probably suck,
but it's also ahead of its time.
So that probably both play.
But that I think the key was that that
was the first one with real emotion.
Uh, and, and, and it's sort
of an emotional arc. And
I talked about my father,
I talked about the meaning of life and,
and you know,
little lane way I, I tried but it,
and that connected with people.
I think emotion really does that.
And that's one of the big lessons of this
podcast that I'm doing with gimlet is
like getting those emotional
moments really makes a difference.
So let's, let's wrap up on
a question directed at you,
but for the audience of, for
people listening and I'll
certainly tell them, uh,
we'll have two questions,
but the first one is,
is not related to where
they can find you and so on,
which is going to be the last question.
This one is really,
do you have any suggestions,
recommendations,
parting thoughts for people listening,
something they could try or something
that they can just carry with them that
might be helpful or useful in some,
ah,
aside from all the brilliant stuff we
talked about for the last two hours, uh,
it could be one that you want to
underscore. Well, I definitely,
I think we've both talked about this.
The idea of experimenting with your life
is so important because I think if you
do the same, routines are good in some
ways because they automate things.
So some parts of your
life should be automated,
but sometimes the routines caused
you to get in a Rut, like the,
the neurons actually get in a neural rut.
Uh,
so doing simple tricks to
just shake up your life.
I've found it incredibly
enriching. I think you have
for sure. Uh, and it can be,
as I said, it could be just
trying a different toothpaste
every month. You know,
there's millions of to,
I used crest for like 28 years because
some kid at my camp use crest and I
thought he was cool. So I kept
buying it and like, you know,
I actually don't like it. I don't like
what it took me 28 years. I mean like,
you know what, let me
try some other stuff. And
you said also, I think this is worth
repeating and I'm paraphrasing here,
but it's often easier to act your way
into thinking differently as opposed to
thinking your way into acting differently.
Totally. Yeah. And the, yeah, the
quote is, which is not mine, but yeah,
it's easier to act your way into a new
way of thinking than to think your way
into a new way of acting.
It. I, I do love that.
Hey Jay, always fun to
hang out. We've had a,
we've seen each other a little
bit this trip in New York City,
which has been fun and great.
And where can people find you,
learn more about you, uh,
on the Internet, podcasts,
et Cetera.
Where can people check you out and say hi.
The podcast is called twice
removed and it is on Itunes,
a gimlet media and my website is
[inaudible] dot com add a day,
Jacobson, Twitter and um, and,
and my book about family, uh,
not genealogy is coming
out in the fall of 2017.
Very, very cool. A Jay, thanks so much
for taking the time. Thanks. I loved it.
And to everybody listening, as
always, you can find the show notes,
links to everything that we discussed
at four hour workweek Dotcom,
forward slash podcast,
all spelled out for our
work week.com forward slash
podcast. And until next time,
thank you for listening.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short
email from me every Friday?
That provides a little more soul of
fun before the weekend and five bullet
Fridays,
a very short email where
I share the coolest things
I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the uh,
the world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work week.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled
out and just drop in your email
and you will get the very next one.
And if you sign up,
I hope you enjoy it.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is a great partner for
creating and growing your business.
It's a one stop shop for
all of your graphic design
needs, whether that's a logo,
website, business card, or anything else.
I used 99 designs to get book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to become a number
one New York Times bestseller.
I also use them for banner
ads, illustrations, and other
things. With 99 designs,
designers around the world compete
to create the best design for you.
You give feedback and
then pick your favorite.
You end up happy or you get your
money back. It's very simple.
You can check out a few of my
own designs and those of yours,
meaning Tim Ferriss,
show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and right now my
listeners, you guys will get a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
That's 99 designs.com forward
slash. Tim, check it out.
This episode is brought to
you by Wealthfront and this
is a very unique sponsor.
Wealthfront is a massively disruptive
in a good way, set it and forget it.
Investing service led by technologists
from places like apple and world famous
investors.
It has exploded in popularity in the last
two years and they now have more than
two and a half billion dollars
under management. In fact,
some of my very good friends,
investors in silicon valley have millions
of their own money in Wealthfront.
So the question is why? Why is
it so popular? Why is it unique?
Because you can get services previously
reserved for the ultra wealthy but only
pay pennies on the dollar for them.
And this is because they use smarter
software instead of retail locations,
bloated sales teams, et cetera. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
I suggest you check out wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim take the risk
assessment quiz,
which only takes two to five minutes and
they'll show you for free exactly the
portfolio they'd put you in.
And if you just want to take their advice,
run with it, do it yourself.
You can do that or as I would,
you can set it and forget it.
And here's why.
The value of Wealthfront is in the
automation of habits and strategies that
investors should be using on a
regular basis but normally aren't.
Great investing is a marathon,
not a sprint,
and little things that you may or may
not be familiar with like automatic tax
loss harvesting,
rebalancing your portfolio,
cross more than 10 asset classes and
dividend reinvestment add up to very large
amounts of money over longer periods
of time. Wealthfront, as I mentioned,
since it's using software
instead of retail locations,
etc. Can offer all of this at low
costs that were previously completely
impossible right off the bat,
you never pay commissions or
account fees for everything.
They charge 0.25% per year on assets above
the first 15,000 which is managed for
free.
If you use my link,
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim that
is less than $5 a month to invest a
$30,000 account for instance.
Now,
normally when I have a sponsor on this
show is because I use them and recommend
them. In this case,
it's a little different.
I don't use wealth front yet because
I'm not allowed to. Here's the deal.
They wanted to sponsor this podcast,
but because of sec regulations,
companies that invest your money are
not allowed to use client testimonials.
So I couldn't be a user end
have them on the podcast,
but I've been so impressed by Wealthfront
that I've invested a significant
amount of my own money, at least for me,
uh, in the team and the company itself.
So I am an investor and hope
to soon use it as a client.
Now back to the recommendation
as a Tim Ferriss show listener,
you'll get $15,000 managed for free
if you decide to open an account.
But just start with seeing the portfolio
that they would suggest for you.
Take two minutes,
fill out their
questionnaire@wealthfront.com
slash Tim it's fast, it's free.
There's no downside that I can think of.