Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism.
This episode is brought
to you by four sigmatic.
You might remember four sigmatic
for their mushroom coffee,
which was created by those clever finished
founders and when I first mentioned
that coffee on this podcast,
the product sold out in less than a week.
It lights you up like a Christmas tree,
which can be really useful. However,
recently I've been testing the opposite
side of the spectrum and new product and
that is their Reishi mushroom elixir
to help me end my day to get to sleep.
As you guys may know,
longtime listeners,
at least I struggled with insomnia for
decades. I have a largely fixed that,
but still shutting off my monkey
brain has never been easy,
still isn't easy very
often and I found Reishi,
which I've been fascinated by for
a few years now, has been very,
very effective and calming
their old formula. However,
four sigmatic old formula included
Stevia and I like to avoid sweeteners,
all sweeteners for a host of reasons,
and I then just ping them and asked,
hey guys,
I would love to experiment with
this and maybe actually suggested,
but I'd like a version without
sweeteners if you'd be open to it,
if too much of a headache,
don't worry.
And they are always game
for experimentation.
And so they created a special
custom version without the Stevia,
without sweeteners.
Now it is part of my nightly routine.
Their ratio elixir comes
in single serving packets,
which are perfect for travel and in fact
I'm about to leave the country right
now and I have a packet in front of me.
This just going to sit in
the end of my carry on bag.
You only need hot water and it mixes very,
very easily.
Here's some recommended copy
that they put in the read,
so I'm going to read it and then I'll
give you my take quote, a warning.
For those in the experimental mindset,
Reishi is strong and bitter in
parentheses like any great medicine.
So if the bitterness is too much,
I recommend trying it with honey and or
nut milk such as almond milk and quote.
So I'm going to say no,
you should suck it up and you should drink
the tea because it's not that bitter.
And maybe you should take the advice
of all Chinese people when they're
criticizing young ins.
When they say Boone should a cool,
which means you're not
able to eat bitterness.
Bitter is in many cases and indication
of things that help liver detoxification
and so on.
Not saying that's the case here,
but I've tested this ratio
lecture on family members,
on friends, everybody has liked
it. It's a little bit, or if the,
it's not that hard.
So I would just say suck it up and no,
don't put in honey or not milk or any of
that shit. Just drink the goddamn tea.
It's delicious I think. Right? If
you like poo air, that kind of stuff,
that type of tea, you're going
to dig it. So just try it. Okay.
Back to then my read. If you'd like
to naturally improve your sleep,
both onset and quality,
I think naturally you might just
enjoy this ratio lecture without any
sweeteners. It has organic, Reishi
extract, organic fueled, mint extract,
organic rose hips extract, organic
Tulsi extract, and that's it.
No fancy stuff, no artificial watching
McCall at anything. So check it out.
Go to foursigmatic.com forward slash
Ferris and get 20% off this special batch.
I don't know if they're gonna
be making much more of this, uh,
it since it was made specifically for
you guys to do me a favor and try it out
so that they continue to be
open to experimenting with
me to create products for
you guys. Specifically, check it
out for Sigmadek. That's Flur,
s I g M, a t, I c.com
forward slash Ferris, F, e R,
r, I s, s and get 20% off
this special batch and a,
you must use the code of Ferris to
receive a discount. F, e R, R, I s.
S.
So again,
going to foursigmatic.com forward slash
Ferris and then use code Ferris for 20%
off of this rare exclusive,
limited run of Reishi mushroom elixir
for nighttime routines with out any
sweeteners.
Enjoy.
This episode is brought to
you by five bullet Friday,
my very own email newsletter.
It's become one of the most popular email
newsletters in the world with millions
of subscribers and it's super,
super simple.
It does not clog up your inbox every
Friday. I send out five bullet points.
Super short of the coolest
things I've found that week,
which sometimes includes apps, books,
documentaries, supplements, gadgets,
new self experiments, hacks, tricks,
and all sorts of weird stuff that I
dig up from around the world. You guys,
podcast listeners and book readers have
asked me for something short and action
packed for a very long time because
after all of the podcasts, the books,
they can be quite long and that's
why I created five bullet Friday.
It's become one of my favorite
things I do every week. It's free.
It's always going to be free and
you can learn more at Tim. Dot.
Blog forward slash Friday. That's
Tim. Dot. Blog forward slash Friday.
I get asked a lot how I
meet guests for the podcast.
Some of the most amazing people I've ever
interacted with, and little known fact,
I've met probably 25% of them because
they first subscribed to five.
We'll have Friday, so you'll be in
good company. It's a lot of fun.
Five bullet Friday is only available
if you subscribe via email.
I do not publish the content on
the blog or anywhere else. Also,
if I'm doing small in person meetups,
offering early access to startups,
Beta testing, special deals, or
anything else that's very limited,
I share it first with five bullet Friday
subscribers, so check it out, Tim. Dot.
Blog forward slash Friday.
If you listen to this podcast,
it's very likely that you'd dig it a lot
and you can of course easily subscribe
any time. So easy peasy. Again,
that's tim.blog forward slash Friday
and thanks for checking it out if the
spirit moves you.
Hello,
boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to
another episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
Longtime. No, see, long time no hear.
How'd you cope with gin or should I say,
how'd you owe me a [inaudible]?
Something along those lines.
Little rusty, but I digress.
The Tim Ferriss show is typically where
I share the habits and routines of world
class performers as well as try to spot
and discuss the patterns amongst them.
This episode is going to be a role
reversal and since I am a professional
dilutant professional amateur of sorts,
a little self conscious about this.
However,
recently cal Fussman at Cal
Fussman, F, U, s s, m, a,
n the man who's transformed oral history
into an art form. That's not my quote.
And it's not his,
that's what people say about him because
he's interviewed everyone from Clooney
to Gorbachev to Reagan to you name it.
He's a big deal.
And uh,
he is also one of the principle writers
or was one of the senior writers behind
the, what I learned column
for Esquire magazine forever.
Just how he got to kick the tires and
meet many of these folks interviewed me
for his podcast.
He interviewed me in two separate
interviews and in true cal fashion,
he took the conversation to places
I never could have expected.
He really is a master of the
craft of asking questions,
and I love speaking with him as a friend,
but I also love studying
him as an interviewer.
Cal said this interview was one of his
favorites he's ever heard from me because
the way he put it was quote, we get
to learn what made Tim Tim and quote.
We dug into some of the childhood
stories that I typically hold back.
I don't like to talk about some of
the early days and childhood stuff.
Uh,
but cal can pry it out of me.
Cal said he wanted to build a story to
understand what happened to me on my
journey, how it explains where
I am now, what makes me tick,
and where I still hope
to improve and grow.
And I think he was able
to unearth all of that.
So if you're looking for a
true world class performer,
someone who's the best at what they do,
then you should probably look for
one of my other episodes, Tim. Dot.
Blog forward slash, podcast, there are
300 other people you can find Jamie Foxx,
you can find Arnold Schwarzenegger,
you can find chess prodigies
like Josh Waitzkin.
But if you want to hear
about my somewhat odd,
maybe quirky path that took me from my
days as a wee lad to where I am now,
then this may be an episode of interest.
Cal is really,
really a fascinating specimen,
and I've interviewed him twice.
If you want to hear cal side of the story,
his entire insane meandering
adventure of life,
which includes taking shots with hunter
s Thompson and working alongside hunter,
uh, for a period of time, you
can hear that at Tim. Dot.
Blog forward slash cow and you should
absolutely listen to more of cows
interviews. So check out his new
podcast for which I was interviewed.
Big questions with cal Fussman.
So does Google big questions with
cal Fussman, F, U, s, s, m, a, n,
where he interviews all sorts of folks
like Coby Bryant and Daymond John and
Seth Goden and on and on and on.
And then there's me odd man out.
So without further ado and preamble,
I'm kind of stalling with this intro.
I apologize guys.
Here is my interview,
Aka being interviewed by Cal Fussman.
Just went off to spring board
rather just one off the springboard.
So I've been thinking about
this conversation for a
long time and I basically
had two ways to prepare.
I thought I won.
I know you, uh, we been
in the sauna together.
We have met your mom.
That's right. Met Your Dad.
They've gone out to eat.
You won't let me pick up the cheque.
Listen to your podcasts,
read your books.
So I do in some ways,
no,
you and I thought,
well I could do even more research or I
could try to just wipe my memory clean
and approach this in a way
that I really don't know Tim.
And I'm going to try and forget a little
about what I know and just act like I
bumped him to Tim Ferriss on the
train. Holy Shit. This is Tim Ferriss.
How are you doing?
You're pretty good at trains for my term,
my memory here. There you go. I'm good
trains. So, and it's funny, when I
went out to see you, I went on a train.
And so I thought that would
be an interesting way to go.
And the more I think about it,
that thing that really hits me about you
goes to a story
about Brian Grazer and Ron Howard.
Okay.
So one is a producer and
the other's a filmmaker,
their partners,
and I'm interviewing them and
the Claridge Hotel in London,
and we're talking,
we're having a great conversation.
And in the middle of this interview,
a fire alarm goes off and waters.