Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
No one else would pose a question.
I'm a cybernetic organism living.
This episode is brought to you by Peloton,
which I've been using
probably for about a year now.
Peloton is a cutting edge indoor cycling
bike that brings live studio classes
right into your home. You can also
do on demand, which is what I do.
We'll come back to that so you don't have
to worry about fitting classes into a
busy schedule or making it to a studio
or gym with a hectic or unpredictable
commute. I, for instance,
have a Peloton bike right in my master
bedroom at home and it's one of the first
things I do. Many mornings I
wake up and meditate for a bit.
Then I knock out a short 20 minute ride
in my undies. Hard to do that at the gym,
take a shower and I'm in higher
gear for the rest of the day.
It's really convenient and has become
something that I look forward to.
So you have a lot of options
for one if you'd like,
you can ride live with thousands of
other writers across the country on an
interactive leaderboard
to keep you motivated.
There are also up to 14 new classes added
everyday with more than 8,000 classes
on demand and you can pick
based on length, 45 minutes,
20 minutes, whatever music,
hip hop, rock and roll or say low impact
versus high intensity or interval.
You can pick the class structure and
style that works for you and in my case I
quite like Matt Wilbur's and I tend to
do on demand and listened to a lot of and
watch many of the same
classes over and over,
but I'm kind of promiscuous and also
enjoy classes from a lot of the other
instructors.
They have Peloton and amazing roster of
incredible instructors in New York City
with a whole range of styles
and personalities so you
can find what you're in
the mood for.
You also get real time metrics that you
can use to track your performance over
time and that will help, I would say
catalyze you to beat your personal best.
Now that all sounds good, right?
Gamification, Yada, Yada, Yada.
I didn't think that it would work
for me or in any way incentivize me,
but they really 100% hit the
nail on the head. I was very,
very impressed with how motivating it was.
I know worked tremendously
to keep me pushing a,
which quite honestly takes a fair amount.
I can get quite lazy,
particularly with anything
that edges on endurance,
which is kind of more than five reps
of anything for me. So check it out.
Discover this cutting edge indoor cycling
bike that brings a studio experience
right to your home Peloton is
offering listeners to this podcast,
a limited time offer.
Go to one peloton.com that's o n e Peloton
p e l o t o n.com and enter the code
Tim,
all caps at checkout and get $100 off
of accessories with your policy on bike
purchase. So get a great workout at
home. Anytime you want. Check it out.
Go to one peloton.com and use
the code Tim to get started.
This episode is brought to you by
wordpress.com I love wordpress.
I have used it for so many years.
It's my goto platform for
blogging and creating websites.
I use wordpress.com for
everything every day. My site,
tim.blog is built on it. The websites
for my books, including tools of titans,
tribe of mentors. It's all
in wordpress.com and the
founder Matt Mullenweg.
One of my close friends has
appeared on the show many times.
Just search Matt Mullenweg,
Tequila Ferris for quite an exciting time.
Whether you're looking to create a
personal blog, a business site or both,
you can make a really big impact
right out of the box when you build on
wordpress.com and you'll be
in good company. It's used
by the New Yorker, Jay Z,
Beyonce, five 38 tech crunch, Ted, CNN,
and time just to name a handful,
and one
of my
friends@googlewhoshallremainnamelesshastoldmethatwordpress.com
offers the best out of the
box SEO imaginable end quote,
and it's one of the many reasons that
nearly 30% of the Internet is run on
wordpress.
You do not need experience or to hire
someone that's perhaps the best part.
wordpress.com guide you
through the entire experience.
They have hundreds of
designs and templates that
you can use and it's easy to
get started. There's no need to
worry about security upgrades,
hosting any of that. They for 24
seven support and they're very,
very responsive. If you have
questions, they get right back to you.
And this allows you to create the
highest quality with the least amount of
headache and friction. So if
you're building a website, period,
when my friends come to me and ask
what I use, what I recommend they use,
the answer is wordpress.com
so check it out.
If you want to get started today,
learn more with a 15%
discount off any new plan.
Go to wordpress.com forward slash Tim
to create your website and find the plan
that's right for you. So
learn more. Take a look,
wordpress.com forward slash Tim
for 15% off a brand new website.
Check it out.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to
another episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
This episode is not going to be a long
form interview where I distill and
deconstruct world class performers.
In fact,
it is going to be nothing of the sort.
It is a Q and a episode.
This is tea time with Tim or
Timmy or Timbo if your prefer,
where I solicited phone numbers from all
of you and called a handful of you to
field any questions that you might
have and I've done these before.
They're always a lot of fun for me to do.
And among other topics covered in the
various phone calls that you will hear in
this episode, how to find mentors.
How do I think about finding mentors?
How have I found mentors in the past?
Discussions of meaning
Viktor Frankl and so on.
How to get rid of anxiety
or train into confidence.
We talk about that as it relates
to a handful of things. Uh,
cocktails, relationship advice.
If we go all over the place.
And I hope you enjoy this as
much as I enjoyed recording it.
So without further ado,
here is tea time with Tim.
Hello,
is this Edwin?
Yes it is.
Edwin, this is Tim Ferriss
calling. Good afternoon.
Hey Tim, how you doing? Oh man, I
can't, I can't believe this is real.
It's real.
I'm afraid I have,
I have called up and I made my
daycare. Well, me too. Me Too.
So let's jump right into it.
How can I help any a, and I
can't promise I can help,
but I'll try to answer whatever
questions you might have.
I appreciate that.
So my question is about mentors.
So what guidance do you have for
finding a mentor to kind of help,
maybe gain a better understanding
about an industry? Um,
and I think more importantly,
how would you or what guidance do you
have for asking someone to be a mentor?
How do you approach them?
How do you kind of break that
or make that initial contact?
I can, I can actually
answer this one. So the,
the first rule of thumb is that I
would highly advise against ever asking
someone directly to be a mentor in
using those words because the people you
generally will want as a mentor,
unless they're retired,
are probably quite busy and we'll hear
mentor is unpaid part time or full time
job before ever and therefore you want
to approach it somewhat indirectly.
And there are a few
different ways to do that.
There's also a resource I can recommend,
which is a book called the third door,
which I think does a very good job of
exploring real life case studies of
communication that works in communication
that doesn't work when you're reaching
out to people who are where you'd like
to be or who could be possible mentors
even remotely by what
their rights and so on.
So I would suggest
checking out that point.
I'm actually,
I have it in my hand.
I heard your interview with Alex
Benign on your podcast and men,
I have to say,
I am understand it's gotten me through
some hard times and that's where I
initially came across this book and I'm,
I'm right around that chapter.
I'm a maybe like the 60 70 pages in and
I just read the part where it kind of
goes into the intro,
how we've kind of talked to you.
And so I think that's where
that question came from.
Perfect.
Great.
Yeah,
so I'm just trying to break into this and
I'm trying to kind of not repeat those
mistakes that he highlights.
So let me,
let me,
let me take a stab at saving
you from some pitfalls.
The way,
way that I first connected with people
who later became mentors in a sense when
I landed in Silicon Valley in
2000 was through volunteering.
So I highly recommend volunteering.
And the reason for that is that many
organizations including entrepreneurial or
entrepreneurship focused organizations,
that could be the Eo,
the entrepreneurs' organization, it
could be young presidents, organization,
Ypo, it could be any number of others.
There are many of them in Silicon Valley.
I've volunteered at PTI,
which is the Indus Entrepreneur,
even though I'm clearly not Indian,
uh,
and volunteered at a [inaudible],
which at the time was the
silicon valley associate, uh,
association of startup entrepreneurs.
And they given their location
and given their focus,
were able to get media to attend,
to cover speakers,
meaning to feature speakers in articles
and so on for Forbes or fortune and we'd
ever might be.
And that meant if I were to volunteer,
even if I were simply taking
tickets or refilling water glasses,
both of which I did,
I would have an opportunity if
I overperformed, which is easy,
in fact in most volunteer capacities
because the people who show up very often
have the attitude,
I'm not getting paid for this.
So I will do the bare
minimum that they ask of me.
So if you are proactive and asking for
additional responsibility or is there
anything else I can help with, I finished
x, can I help with anything else?
If you are proactive and really
responsible and get things done on time,
you'll very often find that they would
be more than happy to give you additional
responsibility.
And that is how I ended up ultimately
sitting in on planning meetings and
volunteering to uh,
act as a speaker liaison for an event,
which allowed me to reach out to
people I wanted to get to know,
like Jack Canfield,
who is the cocreator is the cocreator
of chicken soup for the soul,
which has sold hundreds
of millions of copies.
The person who commercialized Creatine,
first creatine monohydrate that is,
uh, the creator of the
pet rock. I had ida,
very motley crew of folks that wanted to
assemble and there had to be something
in it for them.
And what was in it for them was
speaking in front of an audience of
entrepreneurs with media in
attendance to cover them.
So I was not asking them for any
favors. In fact, I was asking them,
uh,
if they'd be willing to sort of receive
media coverage in effect and also
interact with other people at
their level. And it was, it was,
uh, during that event I want it to do one
thing and it was not asked them if they
could be a mentor.
It was to demonstrate to them I was very,
very good at doing my job.
So I wanted it to be the smoothest
speaking experience they've ever had.
I wanted it to be an event to remember.
I wanted to assure that
they had the media contacts.
They want it to have interactions that is,
and following that event,
I later,
much later, maybe a month
or two later, you know,
reached out after thanking the speakers,
each speaker separately
and as a group to uh,
Say Ping,
I think it was Jack Canfield at the time.
And I used an approach that was similar
to what I outlined in the four hour work
week when reaching out to experts
who are above your pay grade.
And in effect said, you know, Jack,
I really enjoyed our interactions.
I hope we get to meet again.
And if it's okay with you, I'd,
I'd love to, very rarely, but
if the occasion calls for it,
send you a question that overlaps
with your deep experience.
Uh,
if I'm totally stuck after
trying to figure something
out and it was along those
lines and Jack then,
uh,
I kept in touch with, now it's important
for me to qualify what that means.
Keep in touch with does not mean pastor
does not say it does not mean send him
quarterly updates.
It does not mean clog has inbox.
It means that maybe once
every six to 12 months,
I would send him a legitimate question
and I would indicate what I'd already
tried to do to answer the question.
This is really important.
So if you reach out to a potential
mentor or someone who has more life
experience and you say, hi,
Tim, I was just wondering,
I'm studying this in school,
what should I do?
That's a terrible question because it
doesn't reflect if you've actually tried
to figure it out on your own or if
you're using me for your personal Google.
It also does not lend
itself to a specific answer.
So you have to ask yourself,
is this a question that this person
could answer in four lines or less?
And if you're,
if you look at the question and realize
it's gonna take them a half hour to
answer it because you're asking them
for the meaning of life and to explain
their trajectory and how
they grew their career,
then it's a bad question because
you have more time than they do.
And you should be aware of that from
the outset. So generally the question,
I guess the question I'd
love to ask you is x,
here are the things I've already tried.
My tentative plan is this.
If you have any other thoughts,
I would really appreciate them.
And if you're too busy to respond,
I totally understand.
So give them an out so
that they feel comfortable,
not responding and completely unpressured.
This is very important and perhaps
counterintuitively that'll get you more
answers because what many younger go
getters will do is they'll send an email
and they'll finish it with
looking forward to your reply.
Or I have Tuesday at 2:00 PM and
Thursday at 1:00 PM central open,
which one works for you.
And it's so presumptive and aggressive
that the no matter what the content of
that email, the person receiving it
will be likely to think to themselves,
well shit,
if I,
if I reward this person with
a response to this email,
I am encouraging them to send me 20 more
of these emails and I don't want to do
that, so I'm not going to respond.
So that's, that's one, uh,
one approach.
And I would also encourage you to look
for a south by southwest talk that I
gave,
which funny enough coincides with
south by southwest starting right now,
today and tomorrow and uh,
Austin, Texas in early March.
But the talk is titled how to build a
world class network in record time or
something equally hyperbolic.
In any case,
it is though an accurate reflection of
the talk and you may be able to find it
on the podcast. So there's a chance
that I took the audio and put it on the,
on the podcast.
But if you,
if you Google how to build a world class
network in record time and Tim Ferris,
something will pop up,
whether it is a video recording of the
presentation at south by or it is audio
on the podcast itself,
which I do think, uh,
I had repurposed the audio for.
So those are my thoughts.
If you're reading the third door,
I think that will also compliment
a lot of what we're talking about.
So I hope that helps.
Does that fill in some gaps
hopefully or give you some direction?
Yes, definitely. And, I mean,
I must say it's one thing they're
reading in a book or to hear it on your
podcasts,
but kind of to hear it straight from you,
it just adds a little more weight to it
and it definitely just makes it sound
doable. So I really
appreciate it and I, uh,
I think you for your time and
I just, uh, you know, your,
your show's definitely has
been a game changer for me,
so thank you for that and keep doing
what you're doing and I really appreciate
it.
So thank you so much.
Thanks so much. My pleasure. Of course.
And I should point out one other thing,
which is when I mentioned
Jack Canfield for instance,
I said it once every six to 12 months.
That's a long time.
So that as an indicator that
I'm playing the long game,
right? The question you shouldn't be
asking, and I don't think you are,
but the question you shouldn't be asking
is how can I find a mentor for the next
12 months?
If you're looking for something like that,
it's going to end up being somewhat
transactional and you're going to have to
force something within a context of a
group like the entrepreneurs organization
where people are going there explicitly
for that purpose to learn from one
another to teach and so on.
Otherwise,
I would encourage you to
reframe the question your head.
So the question isn't
how do I get a mentor?
The question is how can I encourage
people I aspire to be like,
who are 10,
20,
30 years ahead of me to respect
me and want me to succeed?
That's a better question. How
do I get people say five, 10,
20 years ahead of me whose
paths I might want to emulate?
How do I get those people to
respect me and want me to succeed?
And if you do that,
that's a precursor to them helping you
in ways that resemble those of a mentor.
But the word mentor is,
uh,
probably a word that will never come up,
even though in practice that's
what they will be doing for you.
Does that make sense?
Yes it does. It's one of those,
the Tim Ferriss hidden gems.
And I think that's the exact
answer I was hoping for.
That's the exact type of
answer I was hoping. Yeah,
I think you answered it perfectly.
Handwritten Followup notes,
handwritten thank you notes or even
just, you know, asking these questions,
you know,
a handwritten letter or what have you.
Do you have any thoughts on if
one is better than the other?
I don't think a handwritten
letter is necessary.
And a lot of people,
myself included,
do not want to give out their mailing
addresses, even if it's a Po box.
So I would say it's unnecessary.
Giving someone a handwritten note at
an event is a different story and I do
recommend that,
uh,
but you can listen to the talk that I
gave on that topic at south by southwest
and on the podcast,
which I mentioned earlier and that we'll
get into details on that. All right,
my man, uh, I will leave you to it.
Good luck and a nice chatting with you.
Thank you. You too. Have a great day.
All right. Bye. Bye.
Steve, this is Tim Ferriss
calling. Good afternoon.
Oh my gosh,
I'm doing great.
I am doing fantastic.
It's a beautiful day and I am excited
to attempt to answer any question you
might have. So I am happy to
let you take it from here.
Well there's
two different questions.
I would say pick if if you could
only get one of them answered,
pick that one because that may be the
case because I want to make sure that I am
able to call more than a few people.
So I would say pick,
pick the one you would most like to
answered if you had to choose one.
And then if it goes quickly then we
can consider a second one. But we'll,
we'll try one.
Okay, great. Well I've read
that it was just a great book and it
really made a big impact on me and it made
me think a lot about purpose
and finding meaning in life.
And I guess my question for you is you've,
you've reached such a high
level of success being able
to affect so many people.
And so I guess my question for you is,
once you've reached that level,
how do you continue to find
purpose in your life? Um,
has it evolved? You know, what, what
would you say purposes right now?
This is a good question.
Big Question as well.
I would say that I'll try to tackle
that in a somewhat meandering fashion.
Uh,
the,
the first thing I would say is
my approach to book writing,
my approach to the podcast,
my approach to the television shows
had been involved with has had a common
thread that is very,
very simple.
People might even consider it simplistic
and that is if I have a pain or a
problem or if I have a desire or goal,
I assume it is very likely that many
other people have the same pains or
problems or desires or goals.
So most of what I do is scratching my
own itch with the expectation that if I
can figure out how to,
how to navigate any of those things well
and take good notes and test a lot so
that I can try the hundred things to
filter down to the one or two that truly
have a disproportionate,
disproportionately good outcome,
that that is a straight forward way of,
of adding value to the world and not just
consuming oxygen and eating resources.
So that's,
that is my general process,
which is a way of backing into your
question about, you know, what,
what is giving me meaning right now?
What is giving me meaning right now
is looking at some of the traumatic
experiences I had as a child.
Looking at the repercussions of that and
the behaviors or thought patterns that
are impossible to explain that
I still have in some cases,
uh,
without looking in the rear view mirror
and somehow metabolizing or integrating
what happened to me that
never had a sense of closure.
And that then ties into a lot of the
research I'm supporting related to
treatment resistant depression,
uh,
related to longterm
demoralization and say, uh,
AIDS survivors at UCF.
And a lot of what I'm hoping to do with
universities and other groups including
a Johns Hopkins at the top
of the list. Uh, and uh,
for me then it's,
it's,
it's assuming that right now for me that
everyone is fighting battles we know
nothing about.
Like literally everyone,
there is some degree of suffering,
whether it's minor or major,
chronic or acute that
everyone walking around Uc,
I mean I'm looking out a,
a,
a high rise right now down at the ground.
So I see these hundreds of ants,
which will soon be thousands and tens
of thousands with south by southwest.
And assuming that every one of those
people has some type of suffering past or
present tense that is affecting how
they make decisions, how they interact,
how they view themselves.
And if I can provide any tools whatsoever
to decrease that suffering and to
allow them to help other
people who are suffering,
then I view that as time very,
very well spent.
So that's how I'm thinking
about it right now,
but I'm not wedded to that
and I think it can fluctuate.
Um,
I do think the filling the void
chapter in the four hour workweek,
which is probably the most neglected yet
most important chapter in some respects
and the entire book towards the tail end,
uh,
ties into a lot of the observations that
you would read in Victor Frankel's book
and books for that matter.
And so there are certainly complimentary
chapters and books that you could
digest, but when in doubt, uh,
I would say instead of
trying to save the world,
look at how you can save yourself
or help yourself in some fashion.
And by doing something that seems
very selfish on the surface,
you're actually being very
practical because you are
scratching your own itch in
such a fashion that you're
not purely speculating,
you are dealing with the real world.
Even if it is limited to you,
which I can pretty much guarantee
you if it's any type of suffering,
if it's any type of desire, there's
a very, very high likelihood,
probably 100%,
but let's just call it very high
likelihood that there are thousands at a
minimum and probably millions of people
in the world with some close cousin,
uh,
of that,
if not the exact same thing in
their deli experience. So that's,
that's how I currently am
and thinking about it. Um,
but I should also say that there's no,
there's no one right answer here.
And it said that your meaning could be
playing music and brightening people's
days for 60 minutes or 30 minutes when
you get on stage to play your set because
you've carefully crafted this art to
change the emotional state of people who
are sitting within 50 feet of you.
That and if that gave you meaning. Uh,
and certainly I think that's,
uh, I think that is meaningful.
I think that's very meaningful. Uh,
even though other people who, uh,
might sit on the sidelines and judge,
which is usually the people
who judged by the way,
it's not the people in the arena who
are actually scraping their knees and
getting things done,
but the peanut gallery on the Internet
and on the side criticizing you saying
that you should be spending your time
a different way if there is no should.
This is that we're not dealing
with the natural laws or physical,
uh,
hard scientific laws that are sort of in,
I mean, we can get into a
conversation of objectivity,
but let's just call them
objective truths, uh, for,
for the sake of this thought exercise,
we're dealing with your perception of
what matters and your perception of what
matters. I think, uh,
though you should listen to other
people and I encourage you to,
to talk to other people about
how they think about it.
Your perception of what matters is
your perception of what matters.
And you can own that and you
can consider it a valid. Uh,
I would say that it's helpful as
your walking around in the world is a
proceeding machine to perhaps read or
listen to certain books like awareness by
Anthony Demello would be,
uh,
a a one recommendation that I would have.
Uh,
but I'll stop talking in a second
because this is a long answer,
but I can't give the meaning of life.
But I can tell you where I think my
most leveraged point of focus is for
creating meaning as I feel it today.
And it's not a purely cognitive
exercise I should say.
It's not that I think about it
and sit down with a spreadsheet,
although with some of the investments
and donations I make in science,
I do think about,
uh,
the downstream effects of
certain landmark studies,
for instance. So I do use an
analytical side to it, but the,
the analytical is more,
in my case these days for the execution.
So I really try to feel with what,
what do I get a whole body yes to that
makes me and other people feel better or
that uh,
in some fashion solves a problem or
helps me or others to get what they're
hoping to have or it gives people hope
then enables them in some fashion.
You know, what, what is the
feeling that I want? Right?
So instead of saying
how do I find meaning,
say like what is the feeling I hope to
have when I find meaning when a sort of
an antecedent or,
uh,
if you can kind of diagnose
what you need by looking at the,
the symptoms,
the side effects,
which would be how you would feel like
if you were doing something really
meaningful, what would that give
you that you don't currently have?
And then try to map that as you're
talking about different ideas,
different topics,
different ways you could spend your time.
Like when does that feeling come up?
And then if you use that as
as one criteria for deciding
where you might want to
focus to create meaning a,
then you can use the analytical to build
a plan for executing on everything we
just described.
But that's long answer
to a short question.
Hopefully that wasn't
completely a word salad. Uh,
did any of that make any sense whatsoever?
That was incredible.
Thank you so much.
That's extremely helpful
and in my situation, um,
I just really appreciate you taking
the time to answer my question and it's
super helpful and I just feel like I
need to say thank you for everything that
you, that you do and that you've done.
Um, I know you hear this all the time,
but you know, I've been following your
work for a very, very long time and uh,
you know,
it's,
you've made so many impacts on my own
life and I know you've made impacts on so
many people. So I just want to say
thank you for being you and I really,
really appreciate you.
Thank you Steve.
I appreciate you as well.
Honestly,
it's like I wouldn't be here able to
do this if I didn't have listeners and
readers who've been so incredibly
supportive of this accidental career I've
ended up having.
So it's a real blessing to be able to do
this in any way and it means a lot that
you would even fill out the
form to allow me to call.
So it's of course my pleasure in
it and I should emphasize too,
I'm still figuring this out.
I'm still making it up as I go along and
testing and at the end of the day for
me,
whether it's looking for meaning
or trying to create meaning,
which I think are two different
approaches that can be very complimentary.
Trying to figure out early stage
investing or any number of dozens of other
things I might get my hands into a rather
than trying to debate in your own head
or with other people what
the best approach might be,
what the best next step might be out of
say three or four or even more things.
I just try to test them.
So I look for low cost tests with limited
downside that I can throw out into the
world to see what happens,
to see what sticks and what doesn't.
So that's all I'm doing and I'm certainly
learning from lots and lots of people
around me, including people like
yourself. Uh, so I'll let you,
I'll let you get back to your day,
but thanks very much for
taking the time yourself.
Thank you so much Jim.
I really appreciate it.
All right man. Take it easy. Bye.
Hello,
I speaking.
Hello, Heather speaking. This is
Tim Ferriss speaking. Good day.
No, it's not. It is. I'm
afraid so. Well, hello.
Why hello, how's, how's, how's the
other, the, the weather, I said Heather,
how's the Heather I guess was
we could speak that way as well.
How has the Heather and how is the
weather surrounding Heather at the moment?
That's how kids get to learn my name and
indeed,
whether it's very cold.
I was going to say,
it looked like you were calling or I
should say I was calling a Toronto number.
Find City.
It is some fantastic friends
and fantastic startups also.
And that lovely city of yours
that does get a little chilly.
What might I be able to attempt
to answer for you, Heather?
So I don't have a pillar and I am,
I have started taking karate.
I've been invited to take my
black belt test in the spring.
Congratulations.
Gotcha. Thank you. But I'm so nervous.
Just like I live now and
I'm a bit of a choker. Uh,
there's no rush.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm just sitting here
with TV and a computer.
Thank you. Um, so I'm,
I know that you do all kinds of fees and
I'm just wondering what your method is
for staying focused and calm.
So the short answer is that I like to
simulate the test environment as much as
possible beforehand. Uh, that can
include many different factors. So,
for instance, if I'm going to be
speaking on stage somewhere, uh,
whether that's Ted or different venue,
I will go,
I will always make sure that I have
a chance, ideally the day before,
maybe the day of to go spend time on
the stage and to test all the technical
equipment and to know exactly where I'm
going to have breakfast the next day.
If it's a large conference that I don't
have to worry about there being any
hiccup in the logistics,
right?
So I would map out the day that you
anticipate or versions of the day that you
anticipate on your test day and look at
all of the things that can stress you
out,
potentially look at all the things the
night before that could stress you out or
cause issues. And then, uh, do two things.
Number one is try to set up a system so
that you run into the fewest number of
those things as possible.
And then secondly,
practice the screw ups beforehand
so that if they do happen,
you aren't going to be as
reactive and thrown off,
if that makes sense. Right. So,
so that could include going to end
using visualization is fine for a lot of
this, but let's just say that there's a
possibility I'm making up this example,
right?
But if there's a possibility that it at
a specific speaking location of do a lot
of speaking anymore,
but let's just say hypothetically,
I'm going to go want to get a
coffee and I think the coffee,
the coffee shop might be
completely overrun with people.
And I don't like crowds,
even though I can speak
in front of crowds,
I don't actually like being in
crowds. Uh, so two things. Number one,
I'm going to come up with
contingency plans, right?
So maybe I buy my own coffee machine and
a target that I can replace or returned
two days later. Maybe I get some
instant coffee from Starbucks.
Maybe I decide to use room service,
uh,
and have backup plants that
I don't have to do that.
And then I could also go in a
number of times when it's really,
really busy and,
uh,
visualize that it is the day of my
speaking gig or the black belt test and
practice calming yourself
down. I think part of, uh,
part of the mistakes or one
of the mistakes, excuse me,
that that folks make is they practice
skills like meditation and mindfulness in
a vacuum, if that, if that makes sense.
So that's exactly right.
So they will meditate in the morning when
it's completely quiet before anyone's
gotten up on their special
cushion in their special room.
And then they go to the DMV and they
completely lose their shit because they
haven't practiced the skill
in the environment that
most demands it or the type
of environments. Uh, so for instance, uh,
a few years ago I went on my first,
uh,
well it was not my first Caribou hunt
in this case was an el Concen. I don't,
I don't hunt very much,
consume everything that I hunt,
but I do hunt occasionally and I went
an El con did not end up harvesting any
elk. Uh, but in preparation for that,
because it was going to be a
bow hunt, I practicing, uh,
in upstate New York, uh, with
archery and I hired a coach.
I was doing all sorts of technical
training, which you've done already.
If you're a black belt test, right?
You've done the technical practice. Yeah,
because doing technical practice,
uh,
but then I realized a few things when
I travel. In this case to Colorado,
I'm going to be going from sea
level to something like s between,
uh, between seven and
11,000 feet of elevation.
So my heart is automatically going to
be beating a lot faster just to make a,
to oxygenate my blood properly or
oxygenating my tissues, I suppose, uh,
more effectively.
Second,
I am almost certainly going to be
extremely nervous at that point.
Had never even seen a bull
elk and they're gigantic.
They're like horse with these enormous
antlers and they make these really
incredible shrieking sound.
Sounds like a woman like being
thrown off a cliff or something.
They make these incredible sounds.
So I assumed if I run into an elk,
which is the objective,
and I have, uh, uh,
a whatever the draw is on the bow pulled
back and my muscles are super tense and
I've been wondering if I'll
screw it up all day long. Uh,
I'm probably going to feel like I've had,
you know, three double espressos. Okay.
If, if that's the case,
I should practice, uh,
under those physiological conditions.
So what I did is I did a number of things.
I would do say 20 or 30 burpees
or 40 or 50 kettlebell swings.
And then I would pick up
the bow and take one shot.
And I did this when I was
practicing in New York,
maybe cause I wanted to get my heart
rate, uh, wellover say like one 80.
So I would do whatever necessary
to get very physiologically,
uh, what I would consider off baseline
and then to attempt the skill,
right? And you want, you
want to be safe with it, of
course. But I would mimic that.
And I also did that when I was
preparing for my ted talk. I would,
uh,
I would down a bunch of double espressos
and then go in to give the presentation
because I'm giving a presentation as a
rehearsal in front of a familiar crowd.
Ultimately when I'm blinded by the
houselights or the stage lights rather and
unable to see people in the crowd,
my body's going to react very differently.
So I want to mimic that. Uh, how far
out is your black belt test right now?
They haven't set the date,
but I believe first evaluations in May.
Okay. So you have, you have something
like two months. Uh, so, uh,
do you do,
uh,
do you do any type of performance
in front of crowds? Do you,
have you done any public
speaking or sports competitions,
things of that nature?
In the past,
many moons ago I, I
perform in front of, um,
it's been a few decades. So, uh,
they just find that I'm
overwhelmed at the idea. Yup.
What does, what does, uh,
what is the format of the black belt test?
Is it going to be the class watching you?
Is it going to be in a familiar location,
a new location? What does it look like?
I,
from what I understand,
there are two main testing locations
and they're sort of more of a formality,
uh, gathering, but none of them are
in and location that I typically,
that I would get to practice that on the
norm. Like they're not at the Dojo. Um,
and I think they're far out and
big. That's fair. Quite a number.
What are, what are your concerns?
What are you worried could happen?
Uh,
I'm read that I will blank
there.
There was a time where I was in a
another competition and when it,
when it came game day,
I just got so nervous I couldn't find
my feet with nothing to do with martial
arts, but still in, so I have that fear
that it's going to happen again and uh,
it's ridiculous.
No, it's not ridiculous. I don't
think it's ridiculous at all.
I really don't think it's your data.
This is,
it's a response that your body and
psyche or having to a past experience to
protect you, right? So you're
sort of subconsciously,
you're trying to protect
yourself to prevent what
happened from happening again.
That makes perfect sense. So the way
you overcome that is in my experience,
not by expecting that on game day you're
going to be able to summon the self
talk that is going to be a hundred times
more effective than any of your self
talk in the past.
It's by rehearsing what you fear.
So you have two months,
which is great news.
So I would think about other
things that make you nervous,
that would make you a specifically
nervous about blanking right?
Whether that's getting up on stage
and talking in front of people.
If that's an example, then find a
local toastmasters for instance,
and get up on stage and start
doing that because you will,
you will then be begin to develop more
confidence in your ability to either not
blank or to blank and
recover from blanking.
Does that make sense?
So I would look for other circumstances
that would provoke the same fear and
practices as much as possible.
I would also find out ahead of time
what the locations are and I would spend
time at those locations because the fewer
new variables you can have on the day
of testing, the better off you'll
be. Uh, I would never, for instance,
when I was competing a thousand years ago,
I would never ever set foot into a
competitive arena or on a mat or anything
like that.
For the first time when I was about
to compete or do some type of testing,
I would always do recon ahead
of time and I would not,
I would know where the
bathrooms are. I would know, uh,
where the main entrance is.
I would know,
I would have an idea of what the
process is going to be. For instance,
when I did my black belt test at
the Kodokan in Tokyo, in Japan,
when I lived there from
15 to 16, uh, four,
it's when I was in Japan,
I was part of the judo club, which is the
judo team. I mean though, they're really,
but yeah,
it doesn't translate particularly well
in English but judo team and that's where
we did our black belt test.
So I did reconn even then to know
exactly what the process would look like,
what the format would look like and uh,
to actually attend a few practices in
that facility just so that I would have,
uh, a familiarity with say, the
temperature of the mats, right? Which is,
which it can vary tremendously in
judo from location to location,
I'm sure for other things as well.
But the kind of plastic rubbery to Tommy
mats that they use in judo could be
freezing cold, uh, in
one place and really,
really warm and another which affects
the hardness or the s the relative
hardness or softness.
Right?
So all of these things I would want
to be exposed to before it matters,
before it counts.
Uh,
there's also a very good
book I can recommend that,
uh, has helped me a lot. I've
read it over and over again.
It has a rather cheesy title,
but the content is exceptional and a very,
very practical.
It's by Dale Carnegie and it's called
how to stop worrying and start living.
And it may seem like a
dramatic recommendation for
this particular example that
you've brought up,
but the fear of blanking,
uh, and how that can be self
reinforcing, if that makes sense. Right?
Like the fear of blanking makes it more
likely that you are going to blank. Uh,
so that is a psychological, uh, it's,
it's a question of psychology and mindset,
uh,
as well as skill set.
And this is,
I think the neglected component that
I've been alluding to since I started
rambling in response to this is
that, uh, if someone asks me,
and I do get asked this pretty frequently,
like how do I build my confidence?
Like what should my self talk look like?
How can I develop confidence in my answer
is you don't develop it in a vacuum.
You develop confidence by systematically
exposing yourself to discomfort and
things that you think are just outside
of your capabilities are just outside of
your comfort zone. And
as you do that, you can,
you condition yourself to better tolerate
stress and to take what you previously
would have considered risks even
though now you recognize them as very
achievable,
trainable objectives and that's
how you build confidence.
You build confidence by doing these
things because at the end of the day,
like your inner critic,
your inner voice is going to know
the truth, right? You can do all,
you can listen to all of the
motivational audio that you want,
but if you've,
if you haven't put in the work and
you haven't set foot in this arena,
if you haven't subjected yourself to a
similar situations that would provoke
this fear of blanking you are
going to know on on a deep level.
On the flip side, this is the good
news. If you've done those things,
you show up and you know you've
done everything you could have done.
And the self talk is,
I've done all of the preparation,
like I have prepared more methodically
than anyone else who was taking this test.
And therefore all I need to do now
is simply let come out what I've been
technically practicing for x number of
months, x number of years. All right.
Like I have, I have turned over every
stone I could to prepare for this.
And that is what makes it far less likely
that you're going to blank or I should
say end gives you the
confidence that if you plank,
which has happened to me dozens of
times on stage in front of big audiences
while I'm speaking, like
literally like just poof, gone,
do not know what the hell comes next.
And once you've learned kind of how
to tap dance with that, uh, you,
you develop confidence,
not just your,
in your ability to execute on a plan,
but your ability to improvise.
And, uh, those would
be, those would be some,
some of my thoughts. But really it's
remove as many unknowns as possible.
If you have, what if this, what if
that go practice, go practice that.
What if in some capacity,
and you know,
maybe that's asking to go to a different
karate school with people you don't
know to participate in
a class or to do a demo.
Like would you mind? And you could
explain to the teacher, like,
I'm not coming in here
with a lot of swagger.
I'm trying to prepare for my black
belt test. I'm really nervous.
I'm going to blank.
I'm working with my teacher.
But one thing that was recommended to me
is getting into unfamiliar environments
because that's what the
testing environment is going
to be to actually perform.
So that I have less fear of
blanking when it matters.
And I'm sure that you could find,
you could even ask your instructor if
there's another instructor he or she can
recommend who would be open
to hosting you in a way.
Right. So there, there are
ways to practice this stuff.
That's a great idea.
Yeah. So that's uh, which,
which was taught to me, right?
This is all stuff that I picked up
from other people who are really,
really seasoned competitors in
the, in the, in, in most instances.
Uh, yeah. Yeah. So this is this,
these are just little bits and pieces
that I've picked up over time for, uh,
inoculating yourself against
sort of a nebulous fear.
Uh, and, uh, there's, there's
another exercise that I would very,
very strongly recommend you go through
because you may realize even if I blank
and this doesn't work,
it doesn't happen.
I can retest three months
later or six months later,
right then.
And there is a thought exercise that
you can go through which involves some
writing. So I guess it's more than just
a thought exercise called fear setting,
which if, uh, do you have, if you
haven't seen it or even if you have,
it may be an opportune time to revisit.
This is something I do very regularly,
probably at least once a quarter,
maybe even once a month. Uh,
and you can find that at Tim dot.
Blog forward slash ted since I
also discussed the process in,
in my last year past that time
and listen to your podcasts.
Right.
Wait where I think it's
comparable to other people.
Okay.
You mentioned it.
Why don't we try it?
Yeah.
So I would,
I would go and print out that blog post
and just run through the exercise even
if it's seems,
uh,
in some way academic,
I think that it will also alleviate a
lot of unnecessary pressure or fear that
you're probably imposing on yourself,
uh,
that may not be extremely
well defined and to that book,
how to stop worrying and start living
will also chip away at that with different
tools and recommendations.
Okay.
And that was Dale Carnegie?
That's right.
Okay. Okay. Thank you.
Um, when smart question,
I hear rigorous more so than our regular
training and I don't know if I should
leading up with have more rest
time or more like go at it.
The giver leading up to it
too to practice. What do you,
what do you recommend that I just am
not, athletics is not my, my background.
Nobody tell it this early. And, um,
I'm looking to get through right and,
and try to do so as gracefully as I can,
but I hear that it's quite a long day.
And by design it's a exciting,
yeah, I would, uh,
I would rest quite a bit in the
week before the actual test,
uh, particularly in the
few days beforehand. Uh,
but since you have two months,
I would strive to make your
training harder than the test day
by design.
And if you've gone through things
that are harder than the actual fight,
so to speak,
you will come in with a very,
very well earned high level of confidence
that you are physically capable
because you've already stressed,
tested those circumstances. So I would,
I would absolutely, you know,
within safe boundaries of course,
uh,
make your training harder than your
competition slash certification for sure.
100%. And, uh, I think of this arc,
you locus,
one of my favorite quotes is we do not
rise to the level of our expectations.
We fall to the level of our training,
right?
So hope and,
uh,
since I'm a high on tea right
now and want to use quartz,
I'll also say, you know, there's,
there's a longer quote by James Cameron,
the director, uh, terminate
her Avatar, et Cetera.
Titanic,
which begins with hope is not a strategy.
Hope is not a strategy.
So conditioned yourself by making
your training at least at a few points
beforehand,
physically more demanding than the test
day and figuring out ways to do that.
And it doesn't necessarily
have to be karate,
but it should be something
that is physically more
demanding than the test day.
I would simulate it as
closely as humanly possible.
You're welcome.
You should. It's the best. Uh,
best, best of luck with your,
with your black belt test. Very
exciting. Yeah. Congratulations.
You too.
Bye Bye.
Justin,
how was it in California or at
least on a California telephone?
This is Tim Ferriss.
I was expecting your call.
Well, here I am not, not, not
to, not to leave you hanging.
I appreciate that.
Los Angeles.
How's Austin tech is presumably,
it's fantastic.
It decided to brighten up and offer
the son just as people are arriving for
south by southwest,
which it always does to seduce everyone.
But the weather is actually
generally very nice, but it's,
it's been cold for the last week or so.
Uh,
how can I be of assistance?
What to question?
Might I be able to answer
or attempt to answer?
Well, you know, this is more of a
personal question and I read the
interesting questions and
I thought if Kim, Tim,
if you had to identify as a type of car,
what would that cost Kelby and
why would you identify as it?
I had to be a cocktail.
You know,
the first thing that came to
mind was an old fashioned,
uh,
just because I feel like for me there
should be certain constants in life.
You should have,
for instance,
consistency with values and how you
make decisions with your values as,
as an operating system
effectively for the go.
No go decisions do not do spend time
with this person versus avoid this person
type of decisions.
Uh,
on the other hand passed the basic
ingredients with say an old fashioned,
you then have as a,
as a bartender,
quite a bit of room to improvise and
add your own flair and it can vary
tremendously from, from
place to place. Uh,
so I think that then offers
the flexibility to reinvent
yourself with respect to
projects with respect to career,
with respect to how you manifest those
values in priorities that guide you a day
to day on a more operational,
uh,
on a more operational level.
So that is the first thing that comes
to mind when you ask about cocktail.
There was like some,
some consistency and a,
a bedrock foundation that
you can rely on and expect.
And then you have the room to improvise
and be creative and reinvent as needed
with all sorts of other
types of adornments and
highlights subtle or over the
top as you see fit.
That was a fantastic answer,
that
glad you liked it. And that was a
pretty quick one. Is there as a,
do you have any other questions or would
you like to leave it at the cocktail?
Sure
we'll be able to get you on a
phone call is I'm 27 years old.
I'm a gentleman.
I consider myself a,
I'm constantly trying
to learn and you know,
I'm a huge fan of podcasts and I can
express my gratitude enough for everything
that you do for myself and
everybody else. Um, um,
somebody who generally struggles with
finding my purpose and I don't want to go
square peg round hole as far as trying
to force myself down a walk of life that,
you know,
maybe it didn't exactly fit for me.
Was there a time that you felt that you
were particularly stagnant and maybe you
weren't fitting in where you thought you
should have and it was just something
that maybe helped you get over that?
I've had that at many points in my life.
So the first thing I would say is that
it is a normal experience and in fact at
your exact age, I was
having that feeling, uh,
27 I would have been
in the process of traveling,
trying to figure out what
I was going to do next.
So I would have been bouncing from
place to place, uh, living on the cheap,
whether it was Ireland or Berlin
or any number of other places,
wondering what the hell am
I going to do with my life?
So I was at the exact same point
in some respects that you are,
it sounds like from
what you're describing,
it's the first thing I would
say is don't panic. Don't,
uh, don't view it as a
personal flaw, a defect. Uh,
don't,
don't think that you are somehow uniquely
unfocused and that the universe of 27
year olds outside of yourself has this
figured out because that's generally not
the case. And, uh,
I've had that feeling at multiple
points and I expect it to come up and I,
I don't dread it because I've learned to
view it as an indicator that something
is not working right.
There is something that I
need or something that I
want or something that I want
to give to others and to the world that
is not being accomplished right now.
So I try to view it as a simple indicator
to zoom out to 30,000 feet. And,
and try to reassess where things are in
terms of what you do after reassessing
a, and one way to reassess by the
way is to get a book like the 80,
20 principle, uh, and uh,
the last name, it's Richard Koch.
It may actually be pronounced cock.
I have no idea. K O c h a, I
never know how to pronounce it.
I'm going to go with coke. Uh,
the 80, 20 principle, the 80,
20 way, I think living the 80, 20 way,
there are a number of books that he has
written which focus exclusively in the
80, 20 principle. Uh, which, uh,
I view is very helpful from
a diagnostic perspective.
If you're just looking at first
establishing a baseline, right?
Where are you expending energy,
where are you allocating your time?
What are the results that are coming
from the various categories of activities
and,
uh,
what type of emotional pay off are you
getting or not getting from those things?
What are the things you want to
get rid of? It's another way to,
from a sideways angle,
get to what you want is
to also identify what you,
what you would like to subtract,
what are the things you're doing,
the people you're spending time with,
uh, the things you're committing to,
et Cetera,
that you would like to remove that are
causing negative stress as opposed to
positive adaptive stress in your life.
So I would suggest those books or
one of them for diagnostic purposes.
And then after that, the natural question
that comes up is, well, what then what,
what do you do?
Uh,
hopefully through that assessment process
you'll have some indication of tests
that you can run.
And I say tests or experiments because
it is a very low pressure labeling to
use.
You're not at 27 making a decision
for the rest of your life,
right?
And it's important to frame it that way
because if you view a decision as a five
or 10 year commitment and there are paths
where that is it that that can be the
case, saint medicine, but
outside of a handful of areas,
uh, you can look at, in even
in the case of medicine,
there are experiments that you could run.
So for instance,
would it be possible if you
are considering traveling
a medical path and thought
that might be something
you'd want to pursue,
that you could sit in at a medical school
and audit a class and ask a professor
who has a great reputation among students
and that's easy to figure out with
online course rankings and so on.
Uh,
who's one specific teaching awards?
Could you sit in and audit a class because
you are considering pursuing medical
school and a career in medicine?
Is that something that you could use it
as an experiment for two weeks to sit in
on these classes to give
you more information and
to pay attention to how you
emotionally and emotionally respond to
that to see if it feels like if it could
it be a fit or not. Right? What other
experiments could you run? Well, uh,
what you could do after you've done that
or alongside it is try to figure out if
there is a way for you to shadow
someone, say at an emergency room, right?
And this is, this is something
I've actually done. Uh,
and there's no harm in
figuring out how to ask,
uh, how you might do something like that
even if you are ultimately not granted
permission.
Right?
So even in a case that is particularly
seemingly difficult like that there are
experiments you can run and uh,
the,
the upshot of this is that you are
going to need to try a bunch of stuff,
right?
I was not planning on ever writing a book
ever that was not planning on writing
the four hour workweek. I, uh,
had had very difficult experience with
writing my senior thesis as an Undergrad
and I'd sworn to myself,
I would never write anything
longer than email ever again.
So if you had asked me
at age 25 or even 27,
probably if I wanted to write a book,
if I want it to be an author,
the answer would have been
absolutely not hell no. But in the,
in the process, and I did this
accidentally, but you can do it by design.
In the process of teaching classes,
uh,
related to entrepreneurship and getting
a very strong response from students who
are undergrads and, uh, uh,
master's students from
certain aspects of my talks,
I began to think, uh,
it could make sense to,
to give a separate guest lecture.
This is at Princeton at the time focusing
on something that I struggled to label,
but nonetheless ended up calling
lifestyle design as opposed to, uh,
how to build a fast growing a bootstrapped
business and how to engineer that to,
to function.
And it was through that
seemingly unrelated practice and,
uh,
brainstorming that the content for the
four hour work week before the title ever
existed came about.
And then someone else suggested in effect,
just like added a snarky comment
to a feedback form at Princeton,
which is not rare,
which was,
I don't understand why you're
teaching a class of 40 students.
Why don't you just write a
book and be done with it?
Which I don't think it was a serious
recommendation. It was just a Dickish,
a dickish response from a dickish kid
has been trained to think that's awesome
at Princeton. But, uh, nonetheless,
that stuck in my head and I took
notes on possible chapter titles,
headlines, content, et Cetera,
so that I could get to sleep
because it gave it insomnia.
And then only had conversations with
agents and so on after someone made
introductions without really asking
me if they could make them or not.
And then the book was turned
down by 27 publishers. Right?
So it's almost like that entire path
was something that I turned away from
multiple times.
And nonetheless,
it is turned into one of the
greatest gifts I've ever received.
Certainly that experience paved the way
for everything, including the podcast, uh,
and failures can also offer
you tremendous opportunities.
Right after the four hour chef,
which really completely burned me out.
It's a very difficult book to put together
on us, on us, on stay suicide deadline.
If I had not been burned
out by the four hour chef,
if I'd still had a lot of gas in the tank,
I would have never tested the podcast
format as a sandbox for intellectual
exploration and having the
types of conversations I
now have a weekly basis and
share with the world never would have
happened if I had not run headfirst into a
brick wall with the four hour
chef. Uh, so number one, just in,
in review because I want
to make sure that, um,
try to summarize this and then have a
chance to call some of the folks. Um,
number one,
if you're having these feelings of being
unfocused or not sure what to do with
the rest of your life, that
is normal. And in fact,
the majority of the world is having that
type of feeling at least a few times a
year. Uh, so number one, don't
freak out because it's normal. Um,
and number two is doing assessment.
You really need to understand where you
are and what your baseline is before you
can make any type of plans or draw up
possible experiments for finding the
things that you feel you lack.
That would be the 80,
20 principle at least as one option
that I think is particularly effective.
And then the second is coming up with
experiments and identifying different ways
to stick your toe in the
water or different waters
to gauge how that feels and
whether that provides you with some
degree of inner peace or excitement.
Uh,
and I do think that those are two pretty
good litmus tests for a lot of the
decisions that you make
might make in life. You know,
does it excite you and are you excited
to talk to other people about it and uh,
which, which are separate. They don't, you
don't have to check both of those boxes.
And then,
you know,
how excited are you or a peaceful argue
when you wake up in the morning and how
easily do you go to sleep,
right?
Like anything that can facilitate
sort of those four metrics I think,
uh,
generally falls into the good
decision category in my experience.
Uh,
but a,
you don't have to figure it out for
the rest of your life and I think it's
highly likely that you will
at 27 particularly given
the rate of technological
change and new industries
that will be created, um,
will in fact have multiple
careers throughout your life. And,
uh,
you don't have to figure out which one
to stick with because I think that might
in fact be a losing
strategy for most people.
You want to develop skills
and relationships that
transcend any one narrow,
uh, area of specialty, less
your, you know, some type of
nanoparticle. A physicist who's, you know,
committed to really specializing,
that's fine too. But from the,
from the sound of, of, of,
of where describing, um,
I would say experimentation,
experiment, experiment, experiment.
Does that help at all?
Yes.
I appreciate your thorough answers.
It never does disappoint
my pleasure. You know,
I'm just trying to make,
make something up that sounds believable.
So I'm glad it
aid you in any way that it
is genuinely though how I've,
how I've approached things,
uh,
with very rare deviation for the last say,
certainly the last decade and I
would say even a little bit longer.
So I'm going to let you
get back to your day. Uh,
but thanks for blending and ear and
thanks for filling out the form.
I'll ask you again about the cocktails,
but until then,
thanks for the call and said, I appreciate
everything. You have a good day. Right?
All right,
you too man.
Bye Mcneil.
I getting that pronunciation right.
It is for me.
Well, it's not speak to you soon. I
might flip the whole thing, but we'll,
we'll see how it goes.
How are you this afternoon?
Grind?
Yeah.
First,
you know,
there's,
there can be a time and a place that
can be a time and a place for it.
So how can I try to be of assistance?
I can't promise good answers,
but I'll, I'll do my best.
Awesome. Well, you know, it's team,
they might not be as good,
but,
uh,
today was a regarding
relationships and you know, uh,
basically you, you're very methodical
in everything that you do. Uh, you know,
you kind of plan ahead and you always
like try and anticipate any downsides and
plan for those Yada Yada.
Um,
so that's kind of my mindset and
I've learned a lot of that from you.
I was wondering how can I do that in
a relationship where my partner and my
girlfriend is and isn't
really so prone to that or um,
kind of bottles up or doesn't want
to plan due to the anxiety of it.
I think we have some, we have some
fertile ground to explore here.
So I might rely on followup
questions from you to direct this.
But, uh, I can tell you how
I used to think about it now,
how I think about it,
which is evolving
as we speak.
But I realized
in the last say five to 10 years that
my ultimate nightmare would be dating a
long tear version of myself.
So they're the sort of assumption
number one is that I am looking for a
compliment,
someone who is a compliment and I
have a fantastic girlfriend right now.
We've been together for a pretty
decent stretch of time and,
uh, she, she's proven to
be a fantastic compliment.
I can explain what that means in a
second to me as it stands right now, uh,
I am not looking for a duplicate.
And at the same time,
I'm looking for someone
with shared values, right?
How do they view truth?
How do they define success if
they define success at all?
Right?
So they should be shared value could be,
and I think it is on many levels,
uh,
how you define certain terms that people
tend to strive for or strive to avoid
and how you answer certain key
life questions. Outside of that,
there's a lot of room for flexibility.
And what I have found is for me at least,
uh,
what is helpful when you perceive,
say, I'm fucking, get
myself in trouble here.
Let's say
we're both, I can't blame
it on the booze. Um, so,
uh, and, and this applies to the last, uh,
probably the last four or
five relationships I've had,
which have all been with
incredible women, uh, and, um,
brilliantly strong women in different
ways that I separate in my mind what is a
emotional fragility or lack of
resilience from sensitivity?
And I think this is a really important
distinction, which I didn't by the way,
draw for myself for many decades
and I think it did a lot of damage.
In other words,
sensitivity to me is reflective.
Uh,
have to use one, a metaphor,
a precision instrument,
right? So if you have a scale that gives
you your weight but it's in 10 pound
increments,
that is less sensitive than a scale that
gives you a pound by pound increments
and a very sensitive scale
would give you down to the gram.
And so on.
Uh,
the question then is how someone
wields that sensitivity and uh,
whether it is a help or
a liability or when it,
or asking the question, when is that
sensitivity a help or a liability?
So you find,
I think that historically for me,
I have viewed any type of feeling
of feelings to be unhelpful,
to be a primitive clouding
of logical analysis
and uh, uh, for a long time. Therefore,
my response to emotional responses
in myself was to stuff them down,
cut them off, mute them,
turn down the volume.
And as a result, I made some
really bad decisions. Uh,
there were times when it was helpful.
Yeah.
Yeah. And you use both.
Right? So I think that it's,
it's a mistake to
exclusively rely on either,
but the,
there is a lot to be said for the hundreds
and thousands and millions of years
of evolution that have given us rapid
processing ability that doesn't have to
run through a four quadrant
grid in the analytical mind.
There's a lot to be said for it,
right? If a deal looks great,
but you get the Heebie jeebies from person
you were doing the deal with, I pay,
it's a lot of attention to that.
The reason I bring it up is that I think
it is equally easy to say date a in
this case,
you know,
we're both dating women date a
woman or a partner who is very,
very sensitive and to mistake
that for weakness, right?
So one thing that I try to do is to
get a very clear understanding of how
sensitive their instrument
is. Med, for instance, uh,
one of my ex girlfriends,
I only realized after we'd been
together for several years,
that when she walked down the street,
she was so empathically receptive that
she could basically feel the pain and
emotions,
almost like a contagion of people as she
passed them walking down the sidewalk.
Like walking down the sidewalk in New
York City was incredibly emotionally
depleting for her. And I did not, I
didn't realize she was that sensitive.
I didn't, and that's not a, uh,
it's not a value judgment. It is an
assessment of Eicher instrumentation.
And that changed how I related to what
I'd previously perceived as like very
unreasonable and maybe immature responses
to things. Does that make sense?
So that's, that's kind of 0.1. And, uh,
I find it also very,
I find it more productive these days
and I should say right off the bat,
which I didn't,
that uh,
many people have suggested or asked me,
what are you going to write the for
our relationship and aside from as a
terrible sounding title,
the fact of the matter is I don't
think I have right now a whole lot to
contribute to that conversation.
There are 1,000,001 books out
there about relationships.
Some of them are very good.
Uh,
I think the five love languages is
actually an excellent book and it's been
recommended to me by, by some of the
most impressive humans on the planet. Uh,
off the record.
That might be a separate one.
The five love languages.
No, no, no. I mean maybe somebody
should write that one too. Uh,
the five love languages I do think for
particularly for very Spock admiring left
brainers and I know that the left and
right brain functions are not as cleanly
delineated as this,
but just for the sake of simplicity,
that book is very helpful. And, uh,
where I was going to go
next though is that, uh,
for,
for quite a long time,
my response to perceived
weakness was frustration.
And it still is sometimes,
uh,
the frustration was based on my
perception of whatever their reaction was.
And I had no, I had no visibility
into their internal process.
This goes by the way for employees,
it goes for everybody,
not just significant others.
And what,
uh,
I've,
but I've certainly come to practice a
lot more is before getting frustrated,
asking what they're experiencing,
asking them to describe
how they're feeling it,
recognizing that their response
exists whether you want it to or not.
So you might as well have a bit more
resolution on what they're actually
experiencing. And it can end
up being very, very reasonable.
And not only that, but even if it is
from your perspective, unreasonable,
uh,
simply recognizing that their
experience is valid and even saying,
I can see how ABNC it would be
very difficult. I totally hear you.
I could see that.
And can I have friends who
have experienced similar
things or I've experienced
similar things,
often diffuses the situation without you
having to offer a solution at all or to
such a critique the response.
Um,
so that's another sort of
consideration. Um, there is a,
this is the type of thing that's
probably going to get me in trouble,
but here it goes.
So that the 20% of you out there who
just love to kind of sport outrage on the
Internet, you can use this
one. Uh, uh, there's a, there,
there's a book that I highly,
highly recommend for everyone to read
and I've recommended it before for many,
many different situations,
uh,
or to as education and a toolkit for many,
many types of challenges that can crop up.
There's a book called don't shoot the dog,
which is written by,
I believe it's Karen Pryor and it's at,
it's at its most basic a book about a
positive reinforcement and it happens to
teach a lot of lessons
through discussion of, uh,
sort of animal conditioning, right?
Marine animals, dolphins and so on.
Also looking at every
possible creature imaginable.
And I think the back copy of the back
cover of this book says something like
whether you want the cat to get off of
your kitchen table or like your mother in
law to stop nagging you, this book
will give you the tools you need,
something like that.
And uh,
the title I think does not do
justice to the book. Uh, but it's,
it's very useful,
particularly when you,
how long have you been
dating your girlfriend?
Yeah,
it'll be like two and a half years.
Okay. So two and a half, three years
in both of you probably have a,
I think this is true for
most couples by this point.
Certain triggers for each other.
You have certain ha ensure you have
habits that annoy the shit out of her.
Maybe she bites her lip,
maybe she does it.
I'm sure she has a few that drive you
nuts and they're probably also exchanges
where in you end up in a self
perpetuating cycle of some type.
Right. And like I'm, I'm not saying this
is trivia relationship, but for instance,
right, like you perceive her as
being clingy or needy in some ways.
So you push away or shut down,
which makes her even more
fearful that you're withdrawing.
So she doubles down on the
cleanness and the neediness,
then you double down on the
pushing away and it's just
that type of dynamic x,
it might exist.
So in those types of dynamics,
it's very useful to have
as a reference point,
a book like this that covers principles
of positive reinforcement, right?
Because the negative reinforcement
can work, but there are a lot of
side effects. Does that make sense?
So sec for instance,
and this book is a lot of examples.
Uh, negative reinforcement can work. Yeah.
It's like if you want to use
a shock collar with a dog,
uh, and I'm, by the way,
just for everybody out who's just like
waiting to throw pitchforks at my head,
I'm not comparing women to dogs.
I'm comparing humans to
animals because we are animals.
All right? So just chill the
fuck out. Right? Uh, and,
and I think a lot of our problems day
to day quite frankly is thinking that we
are uniquely special,
uh,
like
animals when a,
for most intents and purposes, that's
just not the case at all. Like there's,
there's plenty of great literature and
science that we can review to get a
better understanding of why
we do some silly things and,
uh, engaged in self defeating
behavior and thought patterns,
which from an evolutionary standpoint,
make a lot of sense.
So this is part of that,
that education for me at least,
and the benefit of it is what are the
benefits is that you're not reading about
evolutionary biology in a purely
theoretical or abstract way.
I mean, there's some great books by
Dawkins and others that can inform this
conversation.
What's nice about something like a
don't shoot the dog is that it gives you
tools you could immediately practice
in real life. Uh, so that's,
that's one I would suggest that will give
you an alternative Palette of options,
mixing a lot of metaphors,
Palette of colors, I, he,
options that you can paint with when
you're, you're in these situations.
Uh, and, uh, give me another,
can you give me a specific example of,
of a situation or a response is
something that you wish were different,
whether it's ongoing, uh, preferably
something that repeats, right?
Something that you see repeatedly.
She's going to kill
me.
Robert, Robert, Robert,
Robert. Don't worry about it. Continue.
Oh, yes, yes, yes, exactly.
You know, income inequality, right.
I do make a little bit more than her,
which is,
I'm sure there's always
income disparity, but, uh, I,
I've always been very frugal my whole
life, like in terms of, you know,
all we save a ton, don't live
beyond your means or whatever. Uh,
and anytime I tried and talk financials,
it just, I get shot down. There's no, uh,
there's no discussion to be
had. It's just, well, you
have yours and I have mine.
Let's just figure it out for
somebody. I wanna, you know,
and the rest of them, rest of my
life where it becomes difficult,
especially when I've been raised.
Um, so financially conscious
as I am. Okay. This is a good example.
And because it's,
it's a,
it represents a really
common source of friction.
Really, really common. I
mean, this is, this is,
this is not a rare conversation and it's
not a rare conversation where one or
more parties shut down.
So I can only speak to tools
that have been helpful to me.
I'll, uh, speak to a tool that's
been helpful to me and also a buffer.
And I'll explain what I mean by that.
So the tool which can become a bit
rote and repetitive if you overuse it,
is a nonviolent communication. And, uh,
there are many books on the subject.
Uh,
there is a particular audio
book version that Neil Strauss,
eight or nine time New York Times
bestselling author recommended it to me.
I believe the first name is Marshall,
the author. The audio book has,
I think a peace sign on the cover and
it's several hours long. In any case,
nonviolent communication.
You can certainly read the
Wikipedia entry for the basics,
but in effect,
it is a,
it is an approach to communication that,
uh,
aims. And I'm probably going
to piss off a bunch of,
uh,
nonviolent communication,
black belts out there who are going
to say that I got it all wrong.
But for the purposes of
our conversation right now,
to minimize the likelihood of provoking
a strong emotional response in the
person you're speaking with
and in yourself. And the,
I'm going to try to,
to sort of recall this template right now,
there are different ways to approach it,
but the way it will generally
start is along the lines of,
you know,
when a B and c happened or when you did A,
B and c and the F,
this first part is has to be objective.
It cannot be debatable,
right?
So it could be something like
when we agreed, uh, you know,
when we agreed to meet at three o'clock
and you turned up at three 20, it's what,
it's, what a video camera
would have recorded. Uh,
it makes me feel x,
uh,
because I have a need for why,
right?
It makes me feel sad because I have a
need to feel that we're in this together
and that we're, we're going to always
strive to keep commitments to each other.
Uh, and then there's a specific ask,
which is like, would you be willing to,
and the the would you be willing
to, could be anything. It could be,
would you be willing to set aside a
time to have a conversation about this
anytime that's convenient for you?
It's really important to me because
for instance, in your case, like I,
I literally want to spend the
rest of my life with you and I,
this is important to me because I was
raised a and c like would you be willing
for us to set aside some time
whenever is convenient for you?
Put it in the calendar so we can
actually talk about this. Uh,
and it's a template. The goal
being what I described previously,
I would look into nonviolent communication
for these types of conversations that
have storico.
He produced the same response whether
in your partner or in yourself.
Right.
And then the buffer that I was
mentioning is in this took me,
it's so obvious and yet it took me 41
42 I can't even remember how old I am
right now,
but whatever my age is right now,
I should have figured this out earlier.
And that is,
it's not just the message,
it's the Messenger.
And what I mean by that is when,
when you get into a pattern,
this is in my experience
where a partner says a,
the other partner shuts down or respond
to the B and it's just groundhog day
that what's what may
be needed and it's not,
they're not mutually exclusive.
What might be required at both is not the
perfect word smithing that is going to
be like you're Luke
Skywalker in star wars,
like shooting through down
the line and the death star.
Like it's not the perfect prose paragraph
that's going to just be stow this
miraculous epiphany upon your girlfriend
is going to be like, oh my God,
now I see it.
Right.
Rather than hoping to like craft the
perfect Gettysburg address that's going to
like revolutionize how
she thinks about finances.
Maybe she just needs to hear exactly
what you're saying through someone who is
less threatening or with whom she has
an established that pattern. Right.
And then I'm sure that I,
again,
I'm not a relationship counselor,
but in my experience when I'm like,
I can't believe she does x,
I usually have a very active
role in provoking that
somehow. Right. So it's, it's,
it's likely that the credit slash
blame is shared by both parties.
Uh, but in the last, uh,
year or so I have been,
and I'm like embarrassed to admit this,
I don't know what that's about.
We can unpack that another time, but, uh,
found a relationship coach to meet with
or speak with on a regular basis and she
will speak to me individually.
She'll speak to my girlfriend individually
and then we'll have group calls,
uh,
has enabled my girlfriend to say things
or convey things to me through someone
else who can also act as
a reality check for her.
And for me when I have a
concern or a criticism,
she's more than willing to tell me that
she thinks it's unreasonable or that
I'm, and as she's put it, she's,
she's not for either one of us.
She's for the relationship.
And how did having someone who is a
regular part of your fostering of the
relationship as a couple, even
when there is not a problem, right?
Ku is consistently there to ensure that
like the plants are watered before they
start dying has been incredibly,
incredibly helpful and can diffuse a
lot of this stuff through a myriad of,
uh, of different factors. Uh,
one of which being you can say to this
say relationship coach or whoever you
might choose to work with therapists that
you'd really like to bring this up in
a safe space where the three of you can
talk about it and where she can voice
her concerns to you maybe separately,
maybe together.
And having someone to facilitate that is,
uh, at least in my experience over the
last year, extremely, extremely helpful.
It is also helpful if you or anyone like
me can get a bit overwhelmed or feel
overwhelmed when a partner comes
to me with emotional challenges.
Right. And you, me, at some point
you'll have to develop the ability,
I'm not saying you don't,
I will have to develop the ability and
I am to kind of better just sit and
witness the experience of an emotional
challenge without having to like
immediately jump in and offer solutions
within 30 seconds and be like, okay,
right problem. Got It. Let's
be solution focused. Uh,
which left brain go.
Yeah.
Which surprise surprise not
always make things better.
Uh, I'm, I'm getting better
at that. And it's, it's, it,
it's a process of practicing and training
and so on from it because it doesn't
come very naturally,
uh,
to have someone else that your partner
can vent to who is not you is really
worth the money and time in and of
itself and who you can vent too,
by the way,
so that you don't blow up over dinner
or God knows what at your part and then
say to yourself for the next two weeks,
for fuck's sake, why did I do that?
What a like 12 car pile
up of emotional trauma.
I have to now try to clean up this.
So that's the buffer that,
that I might,
I might suggest,
and it's relatively new to me to have
that because I like to think that I don't
need things like that and to have
realized that that's, uh, it,
at least from my experience so far,
very penny wise and pound foolish,
particularly if it sounds like you're
very committed to being with your
girlfriend and want to be with her
for a very, very, very long time. Uh,
so those are, those are
a few of my thoughts. Uh,
I don't know how helpful those
are, but they've been, they've,
they've been helpful
certainly to me thus far.
And
um,
fired one five love languages.
Don't shoot the dog nonviolent
communication and don't
shoot the dog by Karen
Pryor.
Right.
And then some messenger is
another one. I was like, yeah,
it's not always about the message for me
playing in my head. Uh, thank you again.
I just wanted to say thank you,
uh,
for everything that you
do and for the call today.
I hope you have a wonderful
rest of the day and uh,
hopefully this makes it to the podcast.
If not,
is it possible to send
a recording of it to me
podcast? I'm sure. I'm sure this will
end up on the pod test, so don't worry,
it'll be just a, you, Robert, me and
a couple of, couple of, a
couple of million best friends.
All right, good luck and thank you.
You're welcome. Have a great day.
Bye Bye. Hey guys, this is Tim again.
Just a few more things before
you take off. Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little morsel of fun before the weekend
and five bullet Friday is a very short
email where I share the coolest things
I've found or that I've been pondering
over the week. That could include
favorite new albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends for instance,
and it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work week.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled
out and just drop in your email and you
will get the very next one and if you
sign up,
I hope you enjoy it.
This episode is brought to you by
wordpress.com I love work for us.
I have used it for so many years.
It's my goto five bump of
blogging and creating websites.
I use wordpress.com for
everything every day. My site,
tim.blog is built on it. The website's
forum books to the tools of titans,
tribe of mentors, all in wordpress.com
and the founder Matt Mullenweg.
When my close friends has
appeared on this show, many times,
just search that moment like Tequila,
fairness for quite an exciting fun.
Whether you're looking to create a
personal blog, a business site, both.
You make a really big impact right
out of the box when you built on
wordpress.com and you'll be in good
company. It's used to buy the New Yorker,
Jay Z, Beyonce at five 38
tech crunch, Ted CNN time,
just to name a handful,
and one of my friends at
Google shall remain nameless,
has told me that wordpress.com offers
the best out of the box SEO imaginable,
and it's one of the many reasons that
nearly 30% of the Internet is run on best
you do not need experience or to hire
someone that's perhaps the best part.
wordpress.com guide you
through the entire experience.
They have hundreds of
designs and templates that
you can use and it's easy to
get started.
There's no need to worry about security
upgrade posting any of that debt for 24
seven support. And they're
very, very responsive.
You've questions they get right back to,
and this allows you to create the
highest quality with the least amount of
headache and friction. So if
you're building a website, period,
when my friends come to me and ask
what I use, what I recommend they use,
the answer is wordpress.com
to check it out.
Do you want to get started today?
Learn more with a 15%
discount off an ed plan.
Go to wordpress.com forward slash Tim
create your website and find the plan is
right for you. It's a
little more, take a look.
wordpress.com for slashed him
15% off a brand new website.
Check it out.
This episode is brought to you by Peloton,
which I've been using
[inaudible] for about a year now.
Peloton is a cutting edge indoor cycling
bike that brings live studio classes
right into your home. You can also
do on demand, which is what I do.
We'll come back to that so you don't have
to worry about fitting classes into a
busy schedule or making it to a studio
or gym with a hectic or unpredictable
commute. I, for instance,
have a Peloton bike right in my master
bedroom at home and it's one of the first
things I do. Many mornings I
wake up, I meditate for a bit,
then I knock out a short 20 minute ride
in my undies. Hard to do that at the gym,
take a shower and I'm in higher
gear for the rest of the day.
It's really convenient and has become
something that I look forward to see.
You have a lot of options
for one if you'd like.
You can ride live with thousands of
other writers across the country on an
interactive leaderboard keeping motivated.
There are also up to 14 new classes added
everyday with more than 8,000 classes
on demand and you can pick
based on length, 45 minutes,
20 minutes, whatever music,
hip hop, rock and roll or save, low
impact versus high intensity or interval.
If you could pick the class structure
and style that works for you and in my
case I quite like Matt will produce and
I tend to do on demand and listen to a
lot of and watch many of the
same classes over and over.
But I'm kind of promiscuous and also
enjoy classes from a lot of the other
instructors.
They have Peloton and amazing roster of
incredible instructors in New York City
with a whole range of styles
and personalities so you
can find what you're in
the mood for it.
You also get real time metrics that you
can use to track your performance over
time. And that will help, I would say
catalyze you to beat your personal best.
Now that all sounds good, right?
Gamification, Yada, Yada, Yada.
I didn't think that it would work
for me or in any way incentivize me,
but they really 100% hit the
nail on the head. I was very,
very impressed with how motivating it
was and it worked tremendously to keep me
pushing, which quite honestly takes
a fair amount. I can get quite lazy,
particularly with anything
that edges on endurance,
which is kind of more than five reps
of anything for me. So check it out.
Discover this cutting edge indoor cycling
bike that brings a studio experience
right to your home Peloton is
offering listeners to this podcast,
a limited time offer.
Go to one hello [inaudible] dot com
that's o n e Peloton p e l o t o n.com and
enter the code Tim,
all caps at checkout and get $100 off
of accessories with your Peloton bike
purchase. So get a great workout at
home anytime you want. Check it out.
Go to one Peloton [inaudible] dot com
and use the code Tim, to get started.