Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism.
This episode is brought to you by wealth
front and this is a very unique sponsor.
Wealthfront is a massively disruptive
in a good way, set it and forget it.
Investing service led by technologists
from places like apple and world famous
investors.
It has exploded in popularity in the last
two years and they now have more than
two and a half billion dollars
under management. In fact,
some of my very good friends,
investors in silicon valley have millions
of their own money in Wealthfront.
So the question is why? Why is
it so popular? Why is it unique?
Because you can get services previously
reserved for the ultra wealthy but only
pay pennies on the dollar for them,
and this is because they use smarter
software instead of retail locations,
bloated sales teams, et cetera. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
I suggest you check out wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim take the risk
assessment quiz which only takes two to
five minutes and they'll show you for
free exactly the portfolio they'd put
you in and if you just want to take their
advice, run with it, do it yourself.
You can do that or as I would,
you can set it and
forget it and here's why.
The value of Wealthfront is in the
automation of habits and strategies that
investors should be using on a regular
basis but normally aren't great investing
is a marathon,
not a sprint,
and little things that you may or may
not be familiar with like automatic tax
loss harvesting,
rebalancing your portfolio,
cross more than 10 asset classes and
dividend reinvestment add up to very large
amounts of money over longer periods
of time. Wealthfront, as I mentioned,
since it's using software
instead of retail locations,
etc. Can offer all of this at low
costs that were previously completely
impossible right off the bat,
you never pay commissions or
account fees for everything.
They charge 0.25% per year on assets above
the first 15,000 which is managed for
free. If you use my link,
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim,
that is less than $5 a month to invest
a $30,000 account for instance. Now,
normally when I have a sponsor on the
shows because I use them and recommend
them, in this case,
it's a little different.
I don't use wealth front yet because
I'm not allowed to. Here's the deal.
They wanted to sponsor this podcast,
but because of SCC regulations,
companies that invest your money are
not allowed to use client testimonials.
So I couldn't be a user end
have them on the podcast,
but I've been so impressed by Wealthfront
that I've invested a significant
amount of my own money, at least for me,
uh, in the team and the company itself.
So I am an investor and hope
to soon use it as a client.
Now back to the recommendation
as a Tim Ferriss show listener,
you'll get $15,000 managed for free
if you decide to open an account.
But just start with seeing the portfolio
that they would suggest for you.
Take two minutes, fill out their
questionnaire@wealthfront.com
forward slash.
Tim It's fast. It's there's no
downside that I can think of.
Just take a look, see what
portfolio they would create for you,
and you can use that
information however you want.
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim
this episode is brought to you by 99
designs when your business needs a logo,
website, business card,
thumbnail, or any other design.
I recommend checking out 99 designs.
I use them myself.
I've used them for many years.
I used them to create book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to becoming number
one New York Times bestseller.
I've also used them for
banner ads, illustrations, and
much more. With 99 designs.
You get a variety of original designs
from designers around the world.
Give your feedback and then pick your
favorite. Your happiness is guaranteed.
So check out some of my competitions in
designs and some of your competitions
and designs from fellow Tim Ferriss.
Show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and
right now you can get
a free $99 upgrade on your first design.
Check it out,
99 designs.com forward slash Tim.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
each episode it is my job to deconstruct
world class performers to tease out the
habits, routines, favorite books, serials,
whatever it might be that you can
test and apply in your own life.
And this episode is an interview you've
been asking for since before I started
the podcast,
Morgan Spurlock.
He would also have been on my top 10 dream
list when I was drafting up potential
guests for this podcast.
In the very beginning,
Morgan Spurlock at Morgan Spurlock on
Twitter is an Oscar nominated documentary
filmmaker based in New York, which is
where we did this interview in his office.
He is a prolific writer,
director, producer, and Human
Guinea pig. His first film,
which many of you will know,
supersize me,
premiered at the Sundance Film Festival
in 2004 winning best directing honors.
The film went on to win the writer's
guild of America best documentary
screenplay as well as Garner and Academy
Award Nomination for best feature
documentary. Since then, he's directed,
produced and distributed
a ton multiple film,
TV and digital projects
including some that I love,
arguably even more than supersize me
and I enjoyed that movie a ton including
the CNN series, Morgan Spurlock
inside man, the FX series,
30 days and the films were in
the world is a song of bin Laden,
confessions of a superhero freakonomics.
The greatest movie ever sold,
which you talk about quite a bit in
this podcast and many, many others.
Morgan's latest project is a
tech startup called collect,
c l e c t.com.
Check it out.
CLE CT like collect c l e c t.com
which is a community for high spending
collectors with a onestop
marketplace where people can browse,
sell and buy collectibles of any type
imaginable. And for a nerd like me,
this is just heaven,
Star Wars, smurfs comics,
a Millennium Falcon made from motorcycle
parts is one actual real example.
If you go to the website,
you can see that imagine comic con
Pinterest and Ebay with a lot more thrown
into the mix and as someone who owns
10,000 poly bagged cardboard back to comic
books at home.
Yes,
I am a Dork and this episode we cover a
ton and I wanted to ask Morgan many of
these questions for years we talk about
how Morgan got his biggest breaks and in
some cases made his own luck.
We talk about tips for aspiring
creators and filmmakers,
how to get people to care
about important issues.
That is a very tough needle to thread.
Favorite books, documentaries, movies,
et cetera. Morgan's thoughts on the
future of media and storytelling and much,
much more.
Before I recorded this episode,
I threw up on Facebook and Twitter
a request for questions for Morgan.
And there were two links that popped
up a couple of times that I wanted to
address because it underscores a
scientific literacy problem that I want to
highlight.
So everyone listening,
if you haven't read bad science
by Ben Goldacre or the Appendices,
which are an excerpt from that in the
four hour body, you should read these. Uh,
because a number of
folks asked, well, why a,
are there particular articles that have
trouble replicating the results that
Morgan had in supersize me?
The first one,
which is related to a teacher who lost
61 pounds using caloric restriction,
but with junk food,
losing weight does not apply.
It is fundamentally completely a different
protocol so that you can just dismiss
out of hand.
And then the second one was related to
a study by Frederick Nystrom in Sweden.
And the article that was most often cited
was actually preliminary data and the
preliminary data,
as it turns out,
just like with split testing ended
up getting flipped in a lot of ways.
When it got to the final results,
which I tracked down and ultimately the
results are as follows and this is from
Skyler tanner.com but uh,
it is a reprint effectively
others suffered almost as
much as Spurlock with one
volunteer taking barely two weeks to
reach the maximum 15% weight gain a lot by
the ethics committee that
had approved the study.
And it goes on to say that these results
are highly individualized and this was
a study that allowed exercise and I
should highlight that as not what Morgan
did.
So again,
you need to be basically scientifically
literate to assess when the media spins
studies to serve their own interests
in the form of a headline very often.
So I feel very comfortable supersize me
at this point and there are some people
who said it's impossible to eat 5,000
calories a day. I would beg to differ.
You can eat a lot more
than that on a daily basis.
You could read the four hour body for
more on that. With all of that said,
please enjoy my wide ranging
conversation with Morgan Spurlock.
Morgan, welcome to the show. Thank
you. I'm stoked to be here. Yeah,
I'm really excited to be in your offices.
Finally.
I know we've had a couple of lunches,
a couple of dinners over time. Yeah.
And it's nice to see the operation.
And I thought we were talking just before
we started recording about breakfast
and he said, well I don't
usually have breakfast, but
if it's a breakfast meeting,
I can't be the guy sitting there
kind of judging the other person.
That's right. Do you get that a lot
after supersize me, what happened?
Whenever I'm at a restaurant,
people will walk by and they'll look at
what I'm eating and sometimes they'll
comment and so they'll look at what
I'm eating and though, and you know,
sometimes I'll see what's
on my plate and another time
better than Mcdonald's. Right.
And so I get it and I'm like,
it's been 12 years like that.
I'm going to be, that is my,
I'm married to that forever. That's your
thing thing. I'm all, I'm okay with that.
I was at the Russian baths yesterday
here just about to pull off the underwear
and uh, there were two fans who
walked up and they're like, Hey,
trying to get four hours where the sauna
in 15 minutes. And I was like, Yup,
I kind of deserve that. I guess I'll be
the four hour guy. And definitely, yeah.
When somebody asks you, what do
you do, how do you answer that?
I say I'm a storyteller. That's what
I am. I'm a professional storyteller.
Where did that first start in
terms of being bitten by the bug?
Was there a particular experience or
mentor who steered you in that direction?
Yeah,
I mean I made,
my mom was probably the biggest
one when I look back as a kid. Um,
like I loved comic books.
I started drawing and writing my own
comic books when I was really young. Um,
just in a notebook like this.
Like I would make the squares draw the
blocks in making your draw the characters
tell the stories and uh, and so, yeah,
I mean that was when I was like
maybe eight or nine years old.
My mom was really encouraging of that.
So I think she was probably the first one.
And then at the same time they
were, you know, it was the 70s,
so the parents took you to see things you
should never take kids to see in movie
theaters. We didn't wear helmets on
bikes, we didn't wear seat belts in cars.
You pack 10 kids into the back of the
cutlass and took them to baseball to cat,
listen to going to baseball practice.
But like,
so my parents would take me to see
movies like jaws, the exorcist,
things you would never take a kid
to see today. It's this, this,
this wrong in so many levels. But um,
so they were taking me see these movies,
but these were the movies that
made me want to make movies.
Like I loved horror films.
And so like the movie scanners,
like when that guy's had
exploded in scanners, that
was the moment where I said,
I have to do that,
whatever that is now.
What was it about the head
explosion was just the shock value,
the ability to grab someone's attention
and just the way that it looks like the
for, cause when I was a kid, I
originally wanted to be Rick Baker.
I wanted to be Tom Savini. Like when
I saw American Werewolf in London,
I mean it blew my mind what great,
it's a great movie and
what the effects did then.
And these were all practical effects
from his hand growing to a snout growing.
Um, there was no CGI,
it was all, they was,
all things that somebody made and
created and figured out how to do.
So that was kind of the
bug that I had first.
It was kind of wanting
to be in that side of it.
And then once I learned you could actually
go to college and learn how to make
movies and you know, direct
movies and produce movies, I said,
well that's the path I want to go on.
So you went to film school? I went to,
I went to film school first at,
at Ua.
I tried to get into USC
film school and I applied.
I got into the broadcast
journalism school, this was
like in 1989. And so I said,
well, I'll go to USC, I'll go there.
Cause like if you're going to make moves,
you've got to go to California,
you got to go to Hollywood.
And I grew up in West Virginia and so
Hollywood was a million miles away.
Good wrestling state, good rest,
exact rates. They for wrestling, even,
especially when they're not family
members. But, um, so I went,
so I went to Hollywood because I
said this is where I have to be.
And so every semester I would apply to
film school at USC and every semester I
would get rejected from film school
at USC, I applied five times.
I still have all the rejection letters.
I keep them all. I kept them all. Um,
and so finally,
the fifth time I was like,
I can't keep putting all
my eggs in this USC basket.
And I was so stupid at the time.
Like I wouldn't apply to
UCLA just out of principle,
which is so dumb when you think about
it because UCLA is in such a better part
of town. It's such a more beautiful
cancer. You just adopted the rivalry.
Israel already, like I was a Trojan
through and through. I was like,
I'm not going to go to UCLA. I'm not
getting even apply to their film school.
So I applied to Nyu and I got into Nyu
and so I moved to New York and New York
is so much better for me as a person.
I think,
I think it suits my personality much more.
Not to mention my skin tone because I,
I'm spectacularly Pale over, but we're
both on the tail end of the spectrum.
How did it fit your personality? I
see. I think that I grew up in a,
in a place and in a family and are in a
culture were you mean what you say and
you say what you mean.
And that's kind of how I was brought up.
And I think that New York is
very much a city that, you know,
says what it says and means what it
says and we'll tell you to your face,
you know, it will stab you right in
the chest and tell you like, you suck.
And here's why. And his word, what we
don't like about you and what you do.
Whereas in a, you know, Los Angeles,
it's the inverse yet is the university
in la at least we'll actually sit in New
York rather if it's about money,
you'd know how to interact with
someone and if they're blunt,
it might be a brace of beliefs. It saves
you time and you know where you stand.
At least.
I know from the,
I know from minute one where I stand
with somebody in New York City,
whereas in La you talked to somebody and
the whole time they're talking to you,
they're like looking over your shoulder
to see who more important or more
interesting might be coming into the
room. That's so disconcerting. Yeah.
Like life first futures to La. I was
like, well, what is happening right now?
Like somebody else here. What
about, what about me? I got here,
uh,
the experience in film school.
What were the most important lessons
that you learned in film schools? Well,
the cool thing was, I mean it didn't want
you, when I was at film school, there is,
it taught you the hustle.
Like the thing about Nyu is you had to
raise your own money for your movies.
You had to, you had defined by Hook
or by crook anyway to make the film.
So I mean that was,
it was so realistic and I mean it was a
much more independent mindset I think of
preparing you for life after film school.
Whereas at USC,
like if you were in film school there,
they paid for your movies and your
pendant. Bird. Yeah. And they,
and they own your movies
like so he basically USC
pays for your films then they
own the films. I had no idea. Yeah. Um,
cause it's kind of part of their legacy.
Like people who go through the
directing program, we pay for the films,
but now we own Ron Howard's movie,
his student film forever. Um,
so I think for me it prepared me
much more for what was coming next,
which was the hustle. You know, what,
what you have to do when you get out.
What was your first, uh, in your mind?
Major project after film school?
Um,
what was my first major project
after film school? I mean,
and by major I mean in your own mind and
my mind, I tell you that. Here's what,
well, there's, there's an interesting that
it had happened to me after school. So,
um,
I got a job,
my first job was being a PA on the
professional at the Lucas on film.
And so it's a pretty sweet gig. It was
a pretty sweet gig. And so here I was,
I was 22,
23 years old and it was awesome.
Like it was so exciting to get to be
on this movie and kind of see him.
And so I was kind of Schlepping, you
know, being a PA for the next three,
two to three years working
on any movie I could get on.
So I was a pa on that
movie and then I was on,
I worked on woody Allen's
bullets over Broadway and, um,
barbay Schroeder's kiss of death.
And so it was on kiss of death where,
um, I got offered a job. I've
got a friend of mine, a job,
a girl named Sarah Casper, who
I'm, I went to film school,
which she produced my senior thesis film.
It's one of those things where you get
out of film school, you finish your thing,
your senior thesis film,
you're like,
now I'm going to send this out to film
festivals and this is going to win all
kinds of awards. Hollywood's going to come
calling, I'm going to get my big movie.
And then none of that happened
and nothing, I'm nothing happened.
So you convince yourself that I'm going
to finish this thing and everything's
gonna Change and I'm going
to get these big movie deals.
And of course none of that happens.
The,
I'm probably 2.01% that happens
to everybody else. It doesn't.
Um, and so I got out, you
know, not that didn't happen.
So I was like just hustling through you
kind of inching my way up the ladder of,
of production.
And I got a friend of mine,
a job on this movie in
the casting department.
She was working for a woman named Tracy
Moore Maribelle who I to this day,
I look at it as kind of one of my mentors
cause she changed my life completely
by what happened next.
I'm,
Sarah was casting for this job for
someone to be the spokesperson for Sony
Electronics. She goes, so she goes, yeah.
She goes, I can send anybody in for this.
You should go audition for this job.
And I was like, I don't have an agent.
She goes, I can send
anyone, it doesn't matter.
And so I went downtown to
pick up film from set one day,
dropped it off at technicolor on
my way back to the office. Um,
I ran an audition for this thing and two
weeks later I found out I got the job.
And so everybody in the, I was like, oh
my God, that's great. Congratulations.
Here's the bag. See you later. Like,
everybody was so happy. I was sleeping.
I was like, good, get out please out. Get
out of this. They get out of this movie.
Um,
and so over the next two and a half years,
I traveled around the country working
for Sony as like this carnival barker on
stage like that. So they went to trade
shows, they went to sporting events,
they went to colleges,
you name it.
And they were one of the sponsors of the
bud light pro beach volleyball league.
Yeah. So it's so it's sorta
like Ron Popeil origins,
like selling Sony from the
state. It's a big, chose this,
it was this giant tour truck that
when I first went on the road with it,
it was all about Sony auto sound.
Like Sony had launched this
big car stereo division.
So it was all about getting P and I
didn't have to know anything about the
product.
I just had to get people to come over.
And so I would just like on this stage,
say, come on over, check this out, blah,
blah, blah. And people would come up and
toward the truck and look at everything.
And then the next year it
became Sony playstation.
Then the next year it became Sony Vio
when they launched their computers.
And while I'm on the road with
them, my boss on this, at the time,
a guy named David [inaudible] said,
we need to make a video about this
tour and what we're doing. Um,
who should we have do that? And I said,
you should have me do that. I said,
I went to film school,
let me make that.
And so I made this film
for them about this.
And then I made a bigger film
for Sony about mini disk.
And then I made bigger film
about something else for them.
And then probably then my biggest project
that I ever did with them was there
kind of ces, the consumer electronic
show in like 1990 burning man for nerds.
It's like burning man for nerds is exactly
what it is, is it's super nerd prom.
And so I made kind of their ces
experience movie where you went into this
theater and I mean they spent
millions of dollars on it.
And it was like the biggest
thing I'd ever done.
So the biggest thing I
did out of film school,
the first biggest gigantic thing
I did was that wow. And so,
and it was so like off track of where I
thought my career was going to be going
or what I thought I'd be doing.
But little did I know that all of those
things that I was doing were ultimately
putting me on a path where I am now.
So this is a theme that recurs a lot in
these interviews with say for instance
Jamie Foxx,
where these things that were seemingly
unrelated to his end destination prepared
and perfectly for it.
Totally.
And I was going to ask you a little
later in our conversation about how you
build rapport with people. Yeah.
But let's dig into it right now.
So if I watch say inside man jet
love or a, you know, 30 days. Yeah.
I'm consistently impressed with how you
get people to embrace you from different
worlds and accept you and trust you.
How did you develop that?
Or have you always been
hardwired for that? Oh,
I think the biggest thing you have
to do is, is you just have to listen.
The minute you start listening,
it's amazing how people will talk to
you and how people will embrace you.
We live in a culture where we don't listen
to begin with. I think that's one. Um,
and I think we also live in a culture
and we live in a world where a lot of
people aren't honest with each other
and just don't kind of openly have
conversations with you and,
and talk about things that are hard to
talk about or talk about things that may
be difficult or, or hurtful,
um, or potentially hurtful.
And I think that if you come in
to those types of moments, just,
I think I'm wanting to kind of wanting
to understand and wanting to understand
where somebody else is coming from.
It doesn't have to be confrontational,
it doesn't have to be ugly.
Um,
you can have a really honest above
board conversation that is meaningful.
And I think that's, so for me, I
think that's the biggest thing is I,
I think the best thing I do
sometimes is shut up and listen.
So if you had,
let's just say you were teaching,
went back to Nyu and you're giving a
guest lecture to would be documentarians
and somebody came up to you and they said,
you know what,
I just had some incredible opportunity.
I'm actually going out this weekend to
interview 10 people for my film for the
first time. Yeah. I've never
done this before. How do I
get them to open up? Right.
What would you say to them?
Um,
I would say first talk about things
that they care about. You know,
get them to talk about things that are
meaningful to them in the beginning. Uh,
things that they like,
things that they love.
You don't want to go right in to like,
so what's it like to have cancer?
You don't want that to be
the first key question.
How do you want to kind of work up to
this? Cause you want to, you want to have,
it's it's relationship.
You're building a relationship with
someone over the course of a conversation
and you want to have them trust you.
Um,
and part of what you also want to do
in that conversation is offer up things
that are similar and kind of where
they're coming from or experiences that
you've had that kind of put them in a,
in a comparative level.
And I think that then you kind of build
up and build up and then you can start
chipping away at the
information you really want,
but you need to take the time to build
that, that relationship. I think the, uh,
the providing of, she lets me ruining
the podcast right there with my thoughts.
Okay. This is, this is
cinema, audio verite, the, Ah,
the advice you just in the movie theater,
everyone,
the advice you just gave about
being, well, I'm paraphrasing here,
but you're being vulnerable
yourself to illicit vulnerability.
It was also something that was underscored
for me by a guy named Neil Strauss
who's an author but wrote for rolling
stone and New York Times did a lot of
interviews and it's incredible how that
gear shifts the entire dynamic. Yeah.
Uh, why warrior poets? Why
warrior poets? That's, yeah,
that's the name of your company
is the name of my company.
And it came a few years ago by,
I'll give credit where credit is due.
There was a, a former assistant at the
Gersh agency who's now a full agent,
a guy named Sean Barclay, who right after
supersize me, I went out to La to have,
you know, it's like when you go
out and they have the meetings,
like we want you to meet all these people,
the deathstar meetings with like
you have already been meetings.
And so I'm being driven all around town,
meeting with all the studios,
meeting with all the folks.
And so I,
as I'm being driven around by
then assistant Shawn Barclay, um,
he were just talking about, you know, you
know what I want to do, what I want, my,
what, what, what are we going to do next?
And by that point we'd
already sold 30 days,
30 days was already going to be the
thing we did after supersize me.
And so we were talking about kind of
the path that I want to be on and the
stories I want to tell. And you
know, what's important to me.
And then I said I want to, I'm
starting a new company. I need,
I need a new name because my
old company, this is, this is,
I'll have a quick aside.
My first company was a web company,
so we started off in
2000 with a web company.
The idea as the bubble was
exploding was I wanted to create a,
a content company where we would create
programming online and then spring
boarded off to film or television.
So we created a company called the
interactive consortium. Terrible name,
terrible name, but it's been, it's
that interactive in the title.
So it must've been something and it was
a consortium of talented people that
came together to tell stories.
And so there was,
there was a logic in my mind just
to [inaudible] name was terrible,
but we call herself the con for short
cause we called ourself the consortium,
which,
and it was the con,
if you look at supersize
me at the beginning it says
the con that's the title of
Guinea, which I thought was
a great name for a company.
Not when you're trying to raise money,
it's not a good name for a company
that's not a good chasing financier's.
You don't want to be called the
con Jd Salinger and associates
and associates. And so this
was, so that was the, uh,
so that was the previous
name of the company. I said,
I want to start a new company.
Um, and, and so he said, well,
what about warrior
poets? And I said, as a,
as a big brave heart fan and as a
Scotsman, I said, why? Because I,
because I'm Scottish and because of
Braveheart, he goes, hey, he goes,
warrior poets has nothing to do with
Braveheart. He goes, that's a, that is a,
a phrase. It was stolen by, by
Mel Gibson for the movie. He goes,
warrior poets were around throughout
history. Like these were people who, um,
who were poets or who were
musicians or who were,
who were people who the masses
with their wit and their in their,
in their writings,
their music.
But when time came to fight
for what they believed in,
they would lay down their instruments
and pick up swords or pick up or pick up
whatever they had to go fight or spears
to go fight for what they believed in to
fight for their country. And I was like, I
said, that's exactly what we are. I said,
we are warrior poets. Yes, that's the
name. And so that's where it came from.
And how do you choose your projects?
Should it be more specific?
How did you decide to do 30 days after?
Supersize me cause I mean Bam suddenly
got the iron, you know, the, the,
the irons hot. Yeah. And as,
and this was before we got the idea
for 30 days before supersize me,
he was even finished. So we were in
post on the movie. Um, we said, I said,
I decided we just submitted
the movie to Sundance.
So we had even gotten into Sundance yet.
We just submitted the film and I said,
we should have a test screening of the
movie just so we see what's happening.
And cause that's what you did. You had
test screenings. The studios all did it.
I said, we should do what they do
to be successful. We should do that.
So we got clipboards cause clipboards
make you look 30% more official.
And we stood outside of the Angelica
right up the street on the corner of house
in and Broadway and we said, excuse me,
is people were coming out of the movies.
We like,
would you like to come to the test
screening of a new independent documentary
and be like Ooh yes I would.
That would be great.
So we signed up like 50 people who came
over to the gold crest screening room on
the west side. And it was myself
and my two editors. Um, Julie,
Bob and Stella went over to the screening
and the 50 people watched the movie.
And then after the film, this one woman
stood and we came down front and we said,
anybody have any questions or
anything in this? One woman said,
I just want to say thank you.
Thank you for making this
movie and showing the world
finally how terrible these
corporations are, that they're
screwing us and they're killing us.
And then a guy on the other
side of the is a hold on, what,
what movie did you watch? And he's like,
what are you out of your mind? He says,
that's not what this movie's about it
all. And so they start you, you're crazy.
You're crazy, you're crazy, you're crazy.
So the yelling at one
another and I just lean over,
lean over to my editors and I'm like,
this is awesome. This is amazing.
This is going to be,
she was incredible.
But it elicited this like awesome
visceral reaction in people.
Like it really struck a chord.
And so the next day when we were
back in the edit room, I said,
how do we do that every, every
day? How do we do that every week?
Like how do we transition this into
something because of the film and the film
was fast.
Like I got the idea for the film on
Thanksgiving of 2002 and a year and a day
later,
the day after Thanksgiving,
2003 I got the phone call that we got
into Sundance. So I mean it was fast. Wow,
that's really fast. For a
docket super fast. Like from,
from idea to like delivery
in the film festival.
What happened on Thanksgiving that
triggered this? I was sitting,
I was sitting on my mom's couch in a
spectacular trip to fan haze when a news
story came on about these two girls
that were suing Mcdonald's. Um,
and so these girls said, we're fat, we're
sick and it's your fault. And I'm like,
well that come on. That's
crazy. Said. He's like, you're
going to sue somebody for,
you know,
selling you food that you bought that you
ate and then blame them for it. I said,
how can you do that? And
then a spokesperson for
Mcdonald's came on and said,
you can't link our food
to these girls being sick.
Can't link our food and these girls
being obese, our food is healthy,
it's nutritious, it's good
for you. And I was like, well,
I don't know if you could say that either.
And I said,
cause if it's that good for me then
shouldn't I be able to eat it for 30 days
straight with no side effects? And I
was like, oh, that's it. That's it.
And so that was the, that was the,
that was the moment. And then, yeah.
So then a year later we got into
the festival and, and so it was,
we were in the edit. I
said, how do we do that?
How do we do that on a regular basis?
And we said, let's make it a series.
Let's make it a series where,
and,
and the original idea was it was going
to be me and every episode kind of
putting myself into these situations.
At which point my girlfriend said,
you're not going to have
a girlfriend very long,
cause I guess it makes me then I'm gone
for six months at a time when we do that
six episodes of that show.
Um,
but as soon as the movie exploded
at Sundance and we sold it,
I was on a plane to la and we sold that,
we pitched that show and
sold it to FX the next week.
So it was a week after Sundance,
we'd already sold that.
So the movie wasn't even in
theaters and we'd set up that show.
And in 30 days we,
were there any particular shows or,
yeah,
proposals that you weren't able to
make weather with that or incitement.
Was there anything that got
vetoed their results there?
The only thing that ever got vetoed
is when we were doing the immigration
episode. I wanted to have a great
episode by the way. Thanks. No, I mean,
I'm really proud of that
really strong episode.
And for me the best episodes of that
show are the shows that I'm not in.
Like I understand why everybody's like
now the ones that you're under the best,
but it's like, but that's, for me,
that's not the best because the best
proof of that show is people who have to
defend their beliefs and when somebody
has to get in there and basically to
people that disagree with
them or contract them to say,
here's what I believe and why, and to
have the courage to continue to one,
you have those beliefs be questioned
and also be open to kind of seeing the
world in a different way. It takes a
tremendous amount of, of, of courage. So,
I mean, I think that's the, I love those
episodes, but the immigration episode,
when we first came up with that,
um,
I wanted to go across the border and
have a coyote bring me over. I said,
I want to go to Mexico.
And I said,
and I want to come over with a bunch of
illegal immigrants and who are basically
sneak into the country with a
coyote and show how it's done.
And Big FX lawyer said, no. And I said,
well, come on. I said, and then if I said,
well,
let's talk to the Fox lawyer.
So then they went to the
next person above that,
the coyote being the term for someone
who facilitates. That's right. So, yeah,
so the, yeah, the coyotes are the guys
who bring you across the border illegally.
And so then I went to big
Fox, his attorney in big
boxes turning. He was like,
absolutely not. And so it
was the only thing that, uh,
that I really wanted to do
for the show that we wouldn't,
because they basically
said, if I, if I, and I did,
if I did it against their will and
I just, cause I said, why don't we,
why don't we just do it? We'll just go
shoot it and we can put it in the show.
And they're like, if you do
that, then, you know, they're,
they basically threatened it,
like cancel the show and then take
us off the air and not insure us.
And so I said, all right, we won't
do that. I got, and they're like,
if you hadn't asked us, that's right.
That's plausible deniability. I,
you've gone and screwed both. Now you've
gone and brought it up. So now it's a,
I'm a real believer in that it's
better to beg forgiveness than ask for
permission these days. Yeah. What, uh,
for someone who's unfamiliar with your
work, yeah. If you had to choose, say,
two or three films or television
episodes that you would,
if you could make mandatory viewing for
all Americans, what would they be? Um,
let's think. I mean, the supersize
me, I feel like everybody's seen.
So I'd be like everybody, I'm, I'm
stopping to people all the time.
We've seen that, which is
still mind blowing to me. Um,
but I think I'm in 30 days.
I love the,
uh,
the prison episode of 30 days I think
is a great episode people should watch.
Um, especially as we live in a country
where we're still sending people to prison
and we've turned prisons into
profit. Um, I think it's a, it's a,
it's a great episode to watch and it will
make you so angry. So I think that's,
that's one. Um, I love
greatest movie ever sold.
I think greatest movie ever sold in just
the conceit of that film is spectacular
for people. Haven't seen it. I'll
just give you the quick rundown.
It's a movie about product placement,
marketing and advertising
where the whole film,
it's paid for and made possible by product
placement, marketing and advertising.
Very Meta if spectacularly matter.
It's so good. Um, Mane and tail.
One of my favorite sponsors of all time
is they sponsored that movie for is you
don't know what Mane and tail his mane
and tail is a magical shampoo that it's
for both horses and people.
Yeah. Which I which I also love.
I love it cause cause you know how many
times have we all been there where we're
in the shower with our horse
and we say why?
Why do I need to products high heart.
Why is there just not one shampoo
for both of us? I'll tell you,
I'll tell you a quick story,
which is my favorite things when we were
making that movie because when I saw
this I found it and you see it, you see
in the film when I find this in a store,
like I had no idea this existed and I
find this product and I'm like it is one
of the greatest days of my life that
I have found this product that I'm,
and you read the label and it gives you
like the instructions on the back of a
bottle of mane and tail are amazing.
Like is it tells you how old are you?
Use It to watch your horse.
It's ridiculous. And so I keep,
so I start calling Devon Catsa Devin,
who is now a very good friend and he's
the president, president of the company.
So I'm like calling you.
I'm stalking him,
trying to get him to return my call to
be in the movie, to be in the movie.
And finally he calls me back and he
says, um, Egos. So, so just tell me,
what is this movie about?
Anyway,
so I explained that what the
movie is and he goes, so what,
so how would you see us in the movie?
Like how would we,
because we don't pay to be in movies,
you know, we don't do that, you know, so,
so how would you see? And I said,
okay, well here's, here's how it is.
So now picture of this. So it's a
close up on a bottle of Mane and tail,
and the camera slowly starts to pull back.
And as the camera pulls back,
you see me washing my little
boy's hair in, the camera,
pulls back a little bit more.
And then you see me and we're in a bath
tub and you just see me washing my hair
in the bathtub and then the camera pulls
back a little bit more and it pulls by
more in the ECB turned to my left and
I'm washing my Shetland pony and the guy
goes into the phone is silent
for a minute, and then he goes,
that's the greatest integration I've ever
heard in my life. It's amazing. He goes,
oh, that's fantastic.
Oh for a minute there,
I thought you were gonna do
something weird with the product.
But then he goes on to tell me,
he goes on to tell me,
because apparently it was
in the Will Ferrell movie
blades of glory. And he said,
he goes, so, so I said to will, I
said, listen, I just want to make sure,
like you're not going to do anything
like masturbate with it, are Ya?
And I was like, I love it. That's where
he draws the line of what's weird.
We'll barrel masturbating with Mane and
tail in blades of glory would be weird.
Me In the bathtub with a horse. Totally
fine. Totally fine. Oh my God. Yeah.
It's amazing. Okay, so back to the
results. So there's that movie inside man.
There's so many episodes of inside man
that I love the season one of inside man,
we do an episode about elder
care and this is on Netflix.
All three seasons of
inside man or on Netflix,
all three seasons of in 30 days or
on Netflix season one of inside man,
we do an episode about uh,
about elder care where I move in
with my grandmother and it is for me,
it's one of the most raw,
honest and powerful things
I've ever made. Yeah. Awesome.
Yeah. Uh, the, the marijuana
episode also a super,
super strong,
such a good show and it's like that Guy
Steve de Angelo and what they're doing
up at harborside medical in, in Oakland
is phenomenal. Like, cause you go there,
you have these visions of
what dispensaries are going
to be and everybody thinks
they're like dodgy and shady and it's
going to bring crime to the neighborhoods.
And this place is beautiful.
It looks like a health clinic and they
run it like a health clinic. They have,
they have a health instructors who were,
there are, they have reiki instructors,
they have psychiatrists
that you can meet with.
Not to mention all the product
that you can buy there. I mean,
and it's run like a proper
clinic and it's phenomenal.
Like that's how every clinic in America,
it should be like every dispensary
should be. When did you go?
Just since we're talking about health,
I think it was the inside man, uh,
when you went to Thailand Bumrungrad yeah.
And Bronwyn Grad and Thailand,
which is incredible facility.
It's phenomenal.
Would you ever w why or why not?
Would you go to Butler and
Grad for medical treatment
yourself? I mean, I would,
I would go back after being there.
I had such a great experience and
depending on what I had to have done,
like if I had to have surgery that had
real serious recuperation where I was
going to be laid up for like weeks going
there and having the surgery done and
then knowing that I'm going to uh,
be on a beach for like the
next four weeks in a place,
it's going to cost me a fraction.
Um, I think is worth it. And uh,
and I've spoken to people who since
that episode had gone there for medical
procedures just because they
saw the show and they're like,
it's half of what it was going to cost
me in the states or less, you know, it's,
it's remarkable. Yeah. Particularly,
I mean if you're doing say an elective
surgery or something that doesn't have,
you're not having a brain tumor treated
right necessarily might not be covered
or it might not be covered. Exactly. I
mean, I went to Nicaragua at one point,
this is when I was writing the four
body and realized, wait a second,
if I just do say my,
my full panel of blood testing,
what is considered sort
of the highest end,
and I don't necessarily recommend
Nicaragua for everybody, but uh,
while I'm there on vacation, it
will pay for my vacation. Yeah,
that's what she was incredible.
That's right. And not only that,
but they did a stat, which means
for people who aren't familiar,
you get your results back in 24 hours.
So it was like literally turned around
everything in the hospital in four or
five hours. It was just phenomenal. Well,
that's what I love it when I was a
bummer Grad, you'd get a blood test,
everything's in one building.
She'd get a test on downstairs and I'd
go upstairs to see my next doctor and
whether it was an MRI or
a blood test or other,
other panels they were doing,
and you have your blood test.
I get it done downstairs.
And by the time I got upstairs,
the doctor already had all the results,
like in real time.
They were getting the results to them
because they also process the blood in the
hospital. So it wasn't being sent out to
a lab like they do here in the states.
You didn't go down to the,
what are those lab clinics that you always
end up going through their own popups.
Oh, Labcorp, Labcorp, labcorp. Where it's
like a guy in like a basement with like,
you feel like you're going to a
methadone clinic. It's rough. So dodgy.
But it's like everything,
everything in one place.
And part of the reason they said
why we can do it so cheaply is cause
everything's under one roof.
We're not kind of third partying anything.
And he's like, and I'm there and I'm like,
why can't we just do more of that here?
Why can't that just happen here? Medical
tourism, that's, I feel like I should,
I should. Uh, well people go watch the
episode. Can people, there we go. Episode.
Yeah, they can watch it. It's a,
it's a season three of inside
man album run Grad U. M r u n g.
R. A. D. Correct. And uh, people will
be very, very impressed. It's, it's,
it looks like a more seasoned,
not at all. Yeah, exactly.
It's not what you would
expect at all. Yeah. Uh,
one of the questions that came quite
a bit from my fans was how do you get
people to care about important issues
in an environment where there's such a
delusion, such a barrage of noise?
Yeah. How do you accomplish that?
Yeah, that's a great question. Cause
it's like every day we feel like,
are we even doing anything they did.
I'd actually are people paying attention,
you know,
you,
you hope that you make things that will
make a difference or that people will
listen to or at least create
some level of empathy and,
and change of viewpoint for someone.
And I think that,
I think the hardest thing is one,
getting people just to watch.
So I think once you get them to watch,
I think that the way that I hope people
get affected is because when we tell the
stories, I get affected by them. Um, once
you get immersed in them, and I mean,
you know this better than anyone is once
you kind of get into these worlds and
see it, it's a part of you forever.
Like that becomes a part of your life.
And whether it's me going to a foreign
country for medical tourism or um,
you know, me was, I was doing in, in,
in this past season where I'm just
like eliminating toxins from my house,
all these like poisons and
cleaning products and stuff
that we use everyday that
we just don't even realize. Um, I
think that, uh, I think for me it's,
it's taking people on this
vicarious journey with me.
And so long as I am open
and honest with you,
then you're willing to pay attention.
And I think that's a big one. Um,
a friend of mine a few
years ago gave some,
gave me some good advice
where he said, uh, he said,
you can't be afraid to show your scars.
He goes, that's, that's, that's what you,
that's who you are.
And he goes and you can't,
you have to continue to stay true to that.
And I think that's,
it was some of the best advice I ever got.
What would you consider
some of your scars?
I think it's just being open and honest
about your life. I think it's, you know,
talking about the fact that,
you know,
I'm divorced and talking about the fact
that, you know, I uh, um, you know,
kind of what led to that and,
and,
and being open and honest about your life
and the things you've experienced and
not being afraid to talk
about that you know,
your upbringing and how that affected you.
I think the more you can have those,
the, that, that honesty in those
relationships that you build with people,
that creates a trust and it creates a
trust not only with the people who watched
the show, but with the people
that you're talking to.
If you are looking at a particular idea
that you want to put force in the world
or explore and it could be adapted to
documentary format or television format,
what are the factors that lead
you to choose one or the other?
You mean whether it's movie or TV? That's
right. I think it's about, I think it's,
it's can it sustain one because there's
some movies that are meant to be some
ideas that are going to
be movies and there's,
and you see this a lot of time when you
watch documentaries when 45 minutes and
you're like, this should
be done now as, but,
but everybody wants to make
a feature movie like, no, no,
I'm going to make it a
feature. And it's like, no,
this should have been about 40
minutes, 45 minutes, 50 minutes.
But they end up making it 75 80 and
that lasts 30. You're just like, oh,
it's just trudging along and it
should have been over. So for us,
we avoid that by never kind
of putting ourselves there.
And so we say this is this,
there's things that are meant to be
90 minutes because they're big, big,
deep explorations.
But especially now there's other ones
that you can take to TV and I can have an
even deeper exploration if I can do two
to three episodes on it and therefore
episodes on it, um, that are hour long.
And then you can have a real deep dive
into these topics. Um, I think that,
uh, so for us, what, I mean
this was, that's why it's great.
Like I loved being a storyteller right
now. I love being a content creator,
being a filmmaker, a director,
whatever you wanna call it,
because there are places now
to tell all these stories,
whether it's 90 minutes or 30 minutes
or 20 minutes or 10 minutes or three
minutes, like we made an amazing bunch
of movies, um, a few years ago, uh,
called focus forward,
um,
that GE paid for where we basically
made these three minute short films that
were all about innovators
around the world,
people who are doing incredible things.
Um,
and each one of these movies were three
minutes long and they're powerful.
They're,
they're so beautiful and inspiring and
now like they've seen like they'd been
seemed like 100 million people around
the world because it's one of those where
anybody will give you around the boxing.
Like anybody will give you three
minutes and once you watch one,
then you'll watch too. You watch three.
What we saw is it whoever, if you,
if you made it through one, then you
watched five, the average was five,
which is awesome. So going back
to the guest lecture at, uh,
Nyu. Yeah. So I'm going to, we're
going to be calling me soon now.
Hey, uh, we heard the lecture.
Yeah, the podcast and Tim's right.
You should come to a guest lecture
in Septic, the administration at Nyu.
And so you have all these bright eyed
bushy tailed students who are say fixated
on the feature film
documentary and they say,
I know you say that we, we, we could do
these short things but you know, really,
really obsessed with this
idea of doing a feature. Uh,
what cat warnings or
advice would you give them?
And I just want to repeat one thing that
you mentioned before we got started to
be, we're looking at my, the
audio equipment and I have
here, which is very simple.
It's, it's a zoom h six which h with XLR
cables that plug into simple is good,
simple, good. Sm 58 sure. Mikes.
And we were talking about, you know,
fancy every time I tried to get fancy
and could they give this to you or you
have a big assignment? I hope
they gave no, no zoom. That
one's on me next time call me. Uh, the,
and you said once you get fancy,
fancy gets broken. That's right.
And it's just such a nice mantra I think
to keep in mind that could really help
someone. What did, what warnings or advice
would you give to aspiring documentary?
Me, the biggest thing is we
try to overcomplicate things.
When you start making movies or
even TV shows, whatever it is,
you have these grandiose
ideas of everything that
you need and everything that
has to, has to be done.
And especially today,
like the youtube of vacation of content
creation and content consumption has
shifted our,
our concept of what,
what it means to make something
good or palatable. Um,
we are infinitely more forgiving of
stuff that looks dodgy for good story.
You can sacrifice quality for great story.
So for me it's like,
it's all about the story.
It doesn't matter.
Like I'll watch shaky camera footage now.
I'll watch somebody like
shitty thing on their phone.
So long as it's a great story and I'm
engaged because we've gotten to the point
now where we are past that we're forgiving
of all that. True Vadio too. Yes.
Rubato like you'll,
you'll so long as I can hear it and
it's not just the whole time I will,
I will be, I will still be forgiving of
it. Um, and I think that's what I tell.
I tell young filmmakers all the time, his
story first, it's all about the story.
It's like everything else about what you
want it to be or how long you want it
to be. It should be as long
as it needs to be ultimately,
but it's all about the story.
And if you've gotten the beginning and
middle and an end and you've told your
core in 40 minutes or 60 minutes,
then don't stretch it out because
now you're just putting your,
just your dressing ups on the,
it doesn't need it.
If you wanted to give people examples
or resources for masterful storytelling,
there are any particular books,
films, resources. For me,
the best of the best resources
are the movies themselves.
Like, I mean I'm such a,
I am such a movie freak,
um, for nonfiction movies,
like if you're watching nonfiction sounds
like my favorite nonfiction film of
all time, which kind of pushed me
to seeing documentaries, excuse me,
seeing documentaries.
I was like a viable outlet for
my creativity as I got older was,
it was when I was in college, I saw the
Joe Berlinger and Bruce and off ski film,
Brother's keeper, brother's
keeper, brother's keeper,
which is one of the greatest
films. Everyone, this is
like, it is in New York City.
As you guys can hear. This is what happens
in New York. We get a train going by,
you can hear everything rumbling in
the office. Sounds like an earthquake.
It's an earthquake. Like all the glasses
shaking. It'll stop in a second. This is,
this is New York. Um, the, so it's
a film called brother's keeper.
And I saw it in a movie theater.
Uh,
cause I heard everybody
talking about it and was like,
I have to go see this film.
And it was the first time I think I
probably ever paid to see a movie,
a documentary in a movie
theater. And um, cause I,
I was in film school so we were watching
a lot of docs in school but never been
never gonna actually where I bought
a ticket. And so I bought a ticket,
went to see his film and the film is so
good, it's so dark and it's so creepy.
And it's about these three brothers
where one of them is accused,
it's an upstate New York.
So it's like these three country
brothers where one of them is accused of
murdering another one.
And as it goes on in the trial of the
sky being brought up for murder charges,
that there was like,
there was like incest and it's like,
I mean it gets dark and weird and so good,
but that's one of his
films were that there's,
there was so many levels of emotion
you feel when you're watching that.
And it was so beautifully shot.
And one a years later when I got
to meet Joe and Bruce, I just,
I mean I gushed over them like this movie.
I was like, that movie changed my life.
Like it is one of the greatest movies
I've ever seen in my life and I to this
day, I mean I'm still such a fan. Like
when I see people, I'm a little fan boy.
When I see somebody that I look up to,
it's like I will go over and just
like and just like cover them with fan
girlness. Yeah. Who else falls in that?
I mean Errol Morris is a genius.
Like Errol Morris, Errol Morris,
who is like that guy. His the amazing,
here's the thing about if you,
if you go to Errol Morris Morris's website
arrows, Morris is such a craftsman.
Can you describe who he is and I apologize
them is the Errol Morris did the fog
of war. Errol Errol Morris did
the thin blue line like years ago.
Errol Morris was one of the
guys who started putting
like real dramatic produced
recreation's in movies.
Like when he did the thin blue line,
people attack to the film.
And this is crazy to think about back
when he made this and whatever 80
something, they're like, this isn't a
documentary. It's like you got real yet.
Yet you fake get actors in there doing
things. You've got stuff that you staged,
you stage things in a movie that's not a
documentary. And when you look at that,
like the movies gorgeous but it,
but it set the tone and it's like,
it basically changed what we think of
what a documentary could be. And so, um,
you know,
at the same thing happened years later.
I remember when I was on a panel
with Al Maysles and Al Maysles,
there's like right when supersize me
came out and Al Maysles told me, he goes,
he goes, yeah, what you do, they use
what you do isn't documentary. He goes,
you don't, you don't make
documentaries. And I, and again,
it was like there was a
transformational moment, um,
of I think what people's interpretation
of what a dot could be was why did he
say that? Because he saw it being
like from a first person standpoint,
he didn't see like me telling a first
person story as being a documentary. Um,
same thing. He didn't think Michael Moore
made documentaries. Um, and so he's,
so that was said that was kind of his
idea. But like Errol Morris, you know,
back to this amazing craftsmen,
like his stuff is so beautiful
and if you go to his website,
like how Errol Morris like really pays
the bills as he makes commercials. Um,
because there's not, it's not like
we're going out and buying boats,
making documentaries say,
let's be honest.
Like we don't have like a fleet of
Ferraris outside. It's like you,
you make these movies because you
believe in them and what they represent.
But if you go to his website, it's like
if I, and I think it's Errol morris.com.
I'm not sure if you go there.
It's like,
it has like all these commercials that
he's made and just experiments that he
does with the cameras, which is
awesome. Like, and you see like how he,
he will take somebody crazy commercial
money and do something he's never done.
And then once you tries that,
he starts to apply those
tricks and transplant and
transplant it to his movies.
And it's cool. It's so cool to see.
But it's like he's a, he's a talent.
Like I have mad respect for him.
And then there's somebody like Steve
James who I think Steve James is just a
great storyteller. Steve James did hoop
dreams. He did Stevie, he did life itself.
Um, apart from Steve James
just being an epic human being,
like he's a magnificent human, like I'd
say all the time. Like when I grow up,
I want to be Steve James because he's a,
he's just a great individual who
treats people well, you know,
his is, you know, we'll return
anybody's phone call, talks anyone,
he's the last guy to leave when students
are asking him questions. You know, I,
I really admired that. And
so there's, there's Pete,
things like that that I take from people,
but, but he's also a great filmmaker.
You know,
he really believes in what he does.
And so I think when you look at his films
and he's one of those guys who makes
movies over years, you know, like he'll
make a movie for like five, seven,
eight years and, and that type of
dedication I really, I really look up to.
That's a huge commitment. That's right.
And on the, on the point of films,
so do,
do you still,
why still make films and the reason I
ask is that when we're talking about
formats and say the future of media,
I think about this quite a lot.
There are people who say can create very,
very popular blogs and then get courted
by the big publishers in New York City
and published books.
And the book still to this
day for whatever reason,
occupies a unique part of mind,
space and human beings.
It just carries a level of Gravitas that
is not associated with the Internet.
Right. Quite wrongly, I think. Yeah.
But people can become sort of part of
the cultural zeitgeist and have a real
impact with books in a way that is very
difficult with something that is viewed
as a femoral online.
Yes.
Do documentaries still have that in and
maybe it's just something I perceive
that difference compared to say TV
or is that, am I making that up? No,
I mean I think that what's happened
though now is there's been a couple of
things that have happened.
One on the heels of like Hbo and Netflix
and showtime and especially Netflix
where more people,
I think I've seen the things I've
made on Netflix than anywhere else,
which is fantastic.
I think that they have created a larger
audience for documentaries than ever
before.
And I think that type of hunger is what's
also starting to drive this push into
smarter nonfiction television.
Um,
both from a Netflix standpoint
and from a television standpoint.
Because what happened in television
is there were all of these people,
all these networks, and it started
with like FX. It's diverse, diverse.
It was HBO who raised the
Bar for scripted television,
started making scripted television beyond
what any of us thought was possible
for TV. I mean, they just started crushing
it. And so then other people said, well,
we should be creating that level
of television. That's, I mean,
when I was working with FX back in the
day, John Land Graph, brilliant guy,
one of the smartest PV people you'll
ever meet in your life, um, said this.
That's what we like. We want to be naive
to HBO for, for Commercial Television.
And that's what he created.
Like he was the champion that made that
and raise that bar for FX. And then,
you know, then showtime did. And now
if you look across the spectrum of TV,
every network has at least one
amazing show. Like USA has Mr. Robot,
which is spectacular. Like every, you go
down the line, everybody's got one big,
big fiction show,
but nobody had smart nonfiction.
Everybody kind of left that down here.
It was lowest common denominators.
So while the rising tide lifted
all the ships for fiction,
it didn't happen for nonfiction.
And now people are realizing as,
as they're abandoning ship with these
all these crappy TV shows that were
missing the boat.
There's higher expectations from our
audience and now they're starting to push
that, you know, as HBO did
with the Genx. And again,
HBO leading the charge of Let shanks
was great. It was fantastic. They said,
let's show people that you can make
smarter nonfiction, dark, dark, so dark.
And so there was that,
there was making a murderer on
Netflix and now everybody's like, oh,
people want to see smart non fiction.
We should be doing that.
Which is great for us. It's great for
people like Alex. Give me, um, who's, uh,
Alex give me who did smartest Enron.
Smartest guys in the room. Yeah,
he did the Scientology movie going clear,
going clear. Oh God, another creepy one.
Alex, he's, he's a great person
I should talk to on the podcast.
He's an amazing filmmaker.
And again,
somebody I really look up to because I
think he's, he's incredibly cerebral,
very smart. That was a, I mean,
the amount of data crunching and just
review required to make going clear was so
evident. Threat in the making.
And the thing about it, and he's,
he is a deep researcher and I
really, I, I think he's fantastic.
But,
uh,
but it's one of the things that for people
like us who have been kind of living
in the space and making this
type of conduct for a long time,
it's fantastic because now it just opens
up and broadens the spectrum. So for me,
I feel like there's still a place to
make movies and, and then there's,
now there's a, now there's
more places to make smarter TV,
which I think is really exciting.
What do you think you will be few
head to speculate. What do you, what,
what do you think you'll be creating
an five or t three, five or 10 years,
whichever we're,
we're about to start doing some
really awesome VR projects like that.
It'll be this year we're going to be
doing some incredible stuff. We've, we've,
we've held back for, I didn't want
it to kind of jump in early, um,
as everybody else is kind of jumping
on the Vr bandwagon. And we've been,
we've been smart about what we've been
navigating through and the projects that
we want to make.
And so that's,
that's going to be something
that's going to be real. And,
and I think that VR has the ability
to become an empathy machine.
I think it has the ability to put you
in places and experience things and
feelings in a way you never have before.
Um,
so that's super exciting for
me as somebody who believes
that you can actually,
you know,
start to chip away and make the world
a better place with entertainment.
You know,
I think movies and TV shows have a
profound impact on our belief system and I
think that, uh, there's just something we
can do there. So for me, I think that's,
that's where it will be. I
think we'll be doing, I mean,
it's in five years probably won't
be exactly five, maybe closer to 10,
but there's going to be one
pipe that delivers everything.
There's gonna be one pipe where I watch
everything, whether it's on my TV,
at home, I'm on my, on my tablet, on
my phone. It'll be everywhere. I mean,
one pipe that feeds everything.
And that's going to be an exciting
time for a couple reasons because now
anything I want to see is suddenly going
to be right at my fingertips, wherever,
whenever, wherever, I'll be
able to watch anything awesome.
But simultaneously you're
going to be to the point of,
still back to the Youtube effication of
our viewing habits, where, how do now,
how do you now bring eyeballs?
How do you let people know it's there?
And I think that's the next step.
You know, there were three stages of,
of real shifts in entertainment
that I think were big.
And one of the first one really helped
me because it made supersize me possible.
And there was like this
democratization of production,
democratization of cinema where suddenly
anyone with a camera and a computer and
a good idea could make
a movie that was huge.
So now suddenly everybody
had access to the tools. Um,
you could put in the sweat equity,
you can make something really cheaply and
easily get it out for the world to see.
Next was kind of this democratization of
distribution where now I didn't need to
have, you know, Sony or or,
or paramount put out a movie and a
movie theater. I can put it online now.
Anybody in the world could have
access to my content, you know,
via youtube or via Vimeo.
But now how do you get people to see it?
That's the problem. So it's
out there, but it's invisible.
Now comes the next big step, which
will be huge as the pipelines converge,
which is almost like this
democratization of curation,
this democratization of marketing,
how to now we point people towards what
matters and that's where it's going to
be.
Influencers are gonna be people like you.
It's going to be people like me who
people trust and those voices are going to
be even more resonant as we move forward
because people are going to trust in
them even with even more,
I think importance
here. Here. Yeah, I agree.
I was a VR skeptic until I had a demo
with the HTC vive running valve software
in Seattle where I was fully kitted out
and in maybe a 20 by 20 foot space and
where you can walk around, we can walk
around else come up yet. Oh God. And what,
just what struck me as
someone who for a long,
long time listeners to this podcast know,
maybe I may or may not have dabbled in
various types of plant medicine or other
molecules,
the time distortion that I
experienced in that immersive Vr,
which is still model t by comparison
looking towards say what's going to exist
three years from now. Yeah. I thought
I was in for five or six. No, no.
I thought I was in for five or six minutes
and I was in for almost 25 minutes.
Wow. And I, that's when I was like, okay,
there is something really
fundamental going on. Yeah.
And you said this empathy machine,
I mean,
just like the simulacrum and uh,
the ability to elicit emotion is so
far beyond anything coming from a flat
screen. That's right. It
was just mind blowing. Yeah.
It was just that I was just at Google
this past week and meeting with their VR
guys and seeing some of the
stuff they're working on and you,
it's like you're in the matrix.
Like suddenly it's like,
it's the closest thing I could imagine
to suddenly being neo and taking the pill
and being thrust into the machine that,
that, that I could. And it's, I mean,
what's coming is incredibly exciting.
Yeah.
And it just as and as a and as a content
creator and as a storyteller to it just
makes you realize we've barely begun to
scratch the surface of what's possible.
Like it is, as you said, it's a
model t like it is so early and it's,
that excites me. Like we've always been
a very early adopter of technology. I,
you know,
we've always been,
we've always tried to be a
little ahead of the curve and,
and what we use the tools we use
to tell stories. And so for me,
I think this is going to be incredible.
Which filmmakers out there do you feel
are pushing the envelope in terms of
technology or innovations in the space?
Because I know Vibey for instance like
James Cameron and his cameras phenomena.
I mean James Cameron I think
invented the camera that
he used on the last movie.
Like it was him and his partner created
the pace camera and camera to use on
Avatar. Like they changed the whole
box that made that movie. It's bonkers.
He invented the technology
that created like the, the the,
what was it like the chrome, the chrome
cop in terminator two because, no,
but everybody's like we can't do this.
And He's like I'll fund it myself.
And what's,
what's so cool about that?
Creating like a storm to
basically do that technology.
Which a correct me if I'm wrong,
cause you'd be the person to correct me.
That the abyss,
which I enjoyed but was not,
I understand the commercial success is
where he honed that technology that later
enabled him to, to create the use it in
terminator two. That's exactly right.
Which is such an awesome story.
And it was out of that yet cause
it was out of that where he,
that's where he got the idea of what
could happen with this other character.
And what it could be. And He poured all
his own money into making that a reality,
which I love. I mean, I'm
somebody who fly. I mean,
I'm a real believer that you should
always bet on yourself first and pre.
When we made supersize
me, I remember I was, uh,
because this was right when we sold our,
showed MTV the first show we
created online when, you know,
from the interactive consortium when we
had that company, because here's the con.
So when we created the first show we
created under the con was a show called,
I bet you will.
And so we sold that show to CBS and
then to MTV and then nine 11 happened.
So we had proof of concept,
we proved that we create,
could create programming
online in spring boarded off.
So we created the first show to really
go from the web to television as a series
sold at the MTV. Then nine 11
happened. Everything stopped.
Like production just came to a stand still
in New York City. So we had no money.
I was evicted from my apartment.
I was sleeping in a hammock in
my office that was so that's,
so every morning I would get up and
go to the gym around the corner,
The New York sports club
to like shower and workout.
I was in great shape because it
says I didn't have a choice. Um,
and that would come back
to my office and we had,
I still have people coming to work and
to make sure that they could pay their
rent and pay their bills.
I took out credit cards and so I was
basically paying their rent with credit
cards. I was paying their
bills with credit cards.
I was paying credit cards with credit
cards and I amassed about a quarter of a
million dollars in credit card debt,
um, in, in about a year. Wow. And so,
but I still had an office and I still had
a business and I was like, I'm not, as,
I was like, you know, I'm,
I'm still betting on us.
And so that's when MTV green
with the series and we did
53 episodes of that show.
And during that time I paid off
like $50,000 worth of that debt.
And then when they cancelled it,
I had another 50 grand in the bank.
And I was like,
well,
I can either pour this $50,000 into that
bottomless pit of debt or we can make a
movie because we owned all the
equipment. Again, is the same thing.
We had the cameras, we have the
computers, let's make a film.
And that film was supersize me and it
changed everything. Oh Wow. Yeah. So I,
so that's why I mean like James Cameras,
when those people that I really look at
and admire because he will always bet on
him and he'll always bet on his ability.
If you haven't read the New Yorker
article about James Cameron when he was
making, um, when he was making
Avatar, not only is he a genius,
but he also is a bit of a bully and says
like some terrible things to people who
work for him.
There's some of the greatest lines that
you'll ever hear him say to human beings,
which there's a guy who's like rigging
lights. Um, and he says to the guy,
and he goes watching you lights,
like watching a monkey fuck a football.
And he yells to another guy, he's like,
hiring you is like firing too good men.
It's like, ouch. Some of
the lines are phenomenal.
It's like I read that and I worked with,
but he was a thing. But it's like, I mean,
pardon me is, he may be saying this
and I worked with a guy years ago, um,
a guy named gene Licht who ran a printing
shop back when I was in college and
worked for, I worked for gene
through a friend of mine at Nyu, um,
who worked there,
ran the print shop.
And so I would go to this print shop
and gene was one of those guys who would
basically yell and scream at the top
of his lungs and say terrible insulting
things that I thought.
I thought it was spectacularly funny
and really entertaining and um,
and so for me, but I also think
he did it in jest to be funny,
even though he was mean about it.
But he was also saying it in jest also.
Make other people laugh, which I feel like
James Cameron is doing the same thing,
but it's a, so gene, you know, rest in
peace. He was a, he was a phenomenal guy.
James, uh, this is a quick side note.
I remember it down the podcast. He
hasn't, I would love to do with him.
I've met him once.
I went on the zero gravity like zero g
flight where the the like the payload was
ridiculous.
I mean if we're really fortunate the plane
didn't go down cause it was like Elon
Musk, James Cameron, like you go down
the list. It was nuts. Amazing. And uh,
I had a chance to get some schwag
advertise Schwag because it was a,
it was uh,
I,
I obviously I paid for the flight and
brought a reader along actually who want
some type of competition I'd thrown.
And we all got tee shirts that
had been given to the staff, uh,
and the crew working on Avatar. And
this shirt was great. The shirt said,
and I might be getting
this slightly wrong,
but it was in huge font right across
the check and it's a chest. It said,
hope is not a strategy, luck is not
a factor. Failure is not an option.
Hyphen James Cameron. It was like, wow.
It's like setting the tone,
setting the tone for production.
And I wore that shirt when I
was reading the four hour body,
which just about killed me
literally and figuratively.
But one experience. Yeah. And it's,
you know, it's like, is there anybody,
you know,
who is that exacting and forward thinking?
Who is it brutal in some respect? I
mean I think, no, cause, pardon me,
it feels like you have to be so steadfast
in your belief. You have to go to,
if you don't drink the Koolaid,
nobody drinks the Kool aid. Um,
I mean it's got to be, who's the
other person that's probably in that,
in that same type of state?
Like Kanye is Kanye there and I meet
Connie is probably aren't even a different
level than like James Cameron,
but,
but comparable I think and kind of
maybe a mega, mega maniacal way. Um,
but I think that, uh, I think you have
to, you have to believe in you first.
Toray um, the, who's the, he's
a great writer. I'm commentator.
Uh, was, did, he told me the story
where he went to Connie's house once.
And so he's in Connie's house and inside
Connie's house there's a big giant
poster of Kanye,
like right inside the living room.
And so it's a Tory said to him,
he goes, um, he goes, Kanye,
why do you have a giant
picture of you on the wall?
And he goes, well, I got to cheer for
me before anyone else can cheer for me.
And I was like, there's some fantastic
logic and that's actually a good response.
Good logic.
I don't know if I can stomach the grief.
I would get for putting a huge,
like Tim Ferris posters herself,
like Burt Reynolds centerfold,
kind of. And if you've ever seen white
chicks, there's this one, Terry crews.
I don't know if my friends will
let me get away with that. Well,
as you come into my
office and there's like,
there's like posters of the
films that I've made the wall.
So it's like those are my, that's
my guess. My con you moment.
Got to cheer for yourself first. I know
we only have a few more minutes. Sure.
Just a couple more questions and then
hopefully we'll do a round two sometime.
But the, I'm not going to go through
all my usual rapidfire questions,
but one I would love to ask is what is
the book that you have gifted most to
other people?
Oh, um, I tell you what
though, there was a,
I gave the Bhagavad Gita to
a lot of people. Um, yeah,
this was right after,
I guess it would have been
right after my son was born.
And then right after I got divorced,
somebody gave it to me.
Andy and I got a lot out of it. And
then again, it's, there's been multiple,
multiple interpretations, multiple
writings of it. Um, um, but, uh,
there was one in particular
interpretation. I can't
remember who the writer was.
Um, the guy who basically did this, this
translation, but I gave that book to,
I don't know,
a couple dozen people
who they like. Yeah. I'm just like, tell
him I'm having a hard time right now.
I don't know what to do. And I was
like, you should read this book.
This is one of these books that has come
up so many times in my life that I have
not yet read. So this might be the final
I'm going to, I'm going to send you,
I'm going to send you the translation
that I read. Cool. Yeah, I appreciate it.
It's, it's kind of like the tout
ditching. It's like I put it off for,
I didn't put it off.
It just never took the step to read
it for decades and decades. Cool.
This is good. This is a nudge
that I need. And, uh, we,
we talked about technology earlier.
You have a lot of irons in the fire.
Would you like to tell people about what
you're up to in, in the tech space? Um,
yeah, so we, uh, this is,
this is a great thing.
I was just out at Jason Calacanis launch
in San Francisco where we give it,
we had a,
we had a company that had been in his
incubator slash accelerator for the last
four months called collect. And this
is a company that you can go to it,
you can go to [inaudible] dot com where
you can download the apps in the iTunes
store, but it's a, it's a, a company that
is held as you would expect l e c t got.
Yeah. Yeah. So it's the whole
genesis of this and what it is.
It's basically like a geek collectible
marketplace. So anything that is geek,
anything that you would imagine at
comicon that you love from, you know,
walking dead to whatever, you
know, posters to action figures,
whatever those geeky things you
love. Vinyl. Like I collect a lot of,
a lot of like uh, um,
like vinyl characters,
characters made by pop artists.
So anything, no matter what it is,
is that you can like find it on collect.
And so I was being chased by,
I was finishing a movie in London
and the founder of the company,
this Guy Steve Bromwell was
chasing me, chasing me, chasing me.
And he finally said a, and
I said, what is it? He goes,
you're the only person
that's going to get this.
Like you'll understand
in a couple of years ago,
I made a movie with Stanley
and Joss Wheaton about comicon.
And then two years before that I made
the Simpsons 20th anniversary special for
Fox. Like, so I'm, I'm like a geek to
core into my core. Um, and so I said,
what does it show it to me? So he showed
me just like a flip deck of what it was.
And I was like, I love
this. And so we sat down,
we talked about the company I
came on board is one of the,
one of the founders early on,
um, put money into the company.
And it's one of those where I just,
I believe in this like of the,
what is it to think? It's $18
billion a year that's spent on Ebay.
A third of that 6 billion is everything
that lives within this Keke space.
So I think there's a great place to give
people a better experience where you
can actually have a geek too,
geek experience. So there's a,
there's kind of a great
social atmosphere to it. Um,
but then there's also the ability to buy,
to sell, to trade with fellow geeks and,
and you know,
feel like you're actually getting
something you love because that's,
that's awesome.
Do you have any particular
favorite categories or items
that you've seen on the
site? Oh my gosh, there's so much fan art.
Like there's so much stuff that people
create on their own, which is awesome.
And so I love seeing the stuff that
people draw on their own posters.
They create a, it's, it's spectacular. So
for me, I love seeing things like that.
Um,
I love the people who have stuff that's
still in the original packaging that's
been on their shelves since like 19.
Some people have like original star wars
toys from like when you and I were kids,
it's still in original packaging
and like that's, that is dedication.
A lot of decades. A lot of self control
to, even when I was a little kid,
I still have all my old stuff like
original star wars toys. Yeah.
But like the heads are not on the hands
always got chewed off because it was a
little animal. Yeah. Like I still have,
like I have my original Darth Vader carry
case that's in my kid's room with that
I wouldn't let him play with for years
until like last year when I knew he
wouldn't totally like junk all the toys.
So now he can actually play with the
action figures. So Click C l e c t.com.
Correct. Yeah. And so, uh,
yeah, we just went through,
we just went through like our,
our kind of seed round. It's, it's,
it's exciting. It's a cool thing.
And it's like I love having had
my first startup, which I started,
you know what it was that 16 years ago
and was going around and doing all the
angel meetings back then.
I mean for me it was exciting to kind
of be back in that space. And it is,
it is a very similar hustle to
raising money for movies. Um,
you're just talking to,
I think a lot smarter people like with
the people that live and breathe in that
space are blue or people
who pretend to be.
That's right. That's true. That's true.
You meet, you meet a lot of them as well.
Okay. Last, last question
before we wrap for this.
This round one is if you could put a
billboard anywhere with anything on it,
not an advertisement necessarily
for anything you're doing,
what would you put on it? Um, oh.
I feel like right now it has to,
it would have to be a, has to be
something Trump related. Right now I just,
I would, I would have to
have something with like his,
with his tiny little hands and remind
people what that means when he gets to the
White House. Do you want these
little hands on the button?
I feel like I want to be,
do you want these puckered lips
yelling at foreign dignitaries?
Do all these little hands on
the button. Oh, please. God,
it's, it's becoming for reals right now.
It's, it's unbelievable. Yeah. I mean,
I'm in all, I'm speechless. I'm absolutely
speech. I feel like, I feel like it's, I,
it is, it takes a lot to make
Morgan Spurlock speechless,
but I feel like I'm in the middle of a
reality show. You're watching. It's like,
how is this actually happening?
I don't understand all this is happening.
Oh, good golly, Miss Molly. Yes, it was,
dude, these are, these are
scary, desperate and surreal
times that we live in. A,
where can people find you on line? Learn
more about you. Say Hello on social,
on Facebook, on, which is just, you know
me, it's a Morgan Spurlock. Then on,
on Twitter at Morgan Spurlock. Uh,
Instagram's at Morgan Spurlock NYC.
Um, snapchat. You'll be able to track
me down. I'm all over. I'm all over the,
all over the social media,
all over the interwebs.
So the interweb which do you tend to
eat? What is your primary, would you,
if I'm on Twitter all the time because
Twitter has become my newsfeed,
like Twitter is my AP exactly.
Like I'm on Twitter all day long
and it's just constant updates.
I use it in the same way. Yeah.
And I love that. It's like,
it is a constant new source. Um, we're,
I'll check in to other newspapers
along the day. Like, you know,
y'all check in with the times and, or
like, you know, talking points memo or,
or the New York Post or whatever.
Cause New York post is spectacular and
you have to, um, but I feel better,
but it'd be like the Twitter I'm, I'm
on, I'm on on Twitter all day long,
five like eight, nine, 12 times at Morgan
Sperlock at Morgan Spurlock. And uh,
I'll give you just since
we're talking about tech,
one tip that I found really useful,
which is a service called Nuzzel and use
the z e l, uh, made by friend of mine,
which effectively looks for patterns
among the people you follow.
And it will take,
say the top five stories that are being
spread and pushed out by the people you
already follow. That's awesome.
Create a digest for you that smart.
So it's a really,
really cool service that I'm
surprised Twitter didn't make itself.
You're saying I should stop
following Kim Kardashians?
Well it depends. Yeah, it depends
on who else you're following.
I guess you might want to stop calling
all of the Kardashians. That's right.
Great Fun. A really fun to hang
out and to be continued into.
Everybody listening, of course show notes,
links to everything that we discussed.
You will be able to
find@fourhourworkweek.com
forward slash podcast and organ.
Thanks so much for taking the time. Great
to see you, man. Thank you. All right,
until next time.
Thanks guys.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to a four hour work week.com
that's four hour work week.com all spelled
and just drop in your email and you will
get the very next one and if you sign
up,
I hope you enjoy it.
So does brought to you by 99 designs
when your business needs a logo, website,
business card, thumbnail, or
any other design. I recommend
checking out 99 designs.
I use them myself.
I've used them for many years.
I used them to create book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to becoming number
one New York Times bestseller.
I've also used them for
banner ads, illustrations and
much more with 99 designs.
You get a variety of original designs
from designers around the world,
give your feedback and then pick your
favorite. Your happiness is guaranteed.
It's a checkout.
Some of my competitions and designs and
some of your competitions and designs
from fellow Tim Ferriss. Show
listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash.
Tim and right now you can get a free $99
upgrade on your first design to check
it out. 99 designs.com forward. Slash. Tip
this episode is brought to
you by Wealthfront and this
is a very unique sponsor.
Wealthfront is a massively disruptive
in a good way, set it and forget it.
Investing service led by technologists
from places like apple and world famous
investors.
It has exploded in popularity in the last
two years and they now have more than
two and a half a billion dollars
under management. In fact,
some of my very good friends,
investors in silicon valley have millions
of their own money in Wealthfront.
So the question is why? Why is
it so popular? Why is it unique?
Because you can get services previously
reserved for the ultra wealthy but only
pay pennies on the dollar for them.
And this is because they use smarter
software instead of retail locations,
bloated sales teams, et cetera. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
I suggest you check out wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim take the risk
assessment quiz which only takes two to
five minutes and they'll show you for
free exactly the portfolio they'd put
you at and if you just want to take their
advice, run with it, do it yourself.
You can do that or as I would,
you can set it and forget it.
Here's why.
The value of Wealthfront is in the
automation of habits and strategies that
investors should be using on a
regular basis but normally aren't.
Great investing is a marathon,
not a sprint,
and little things that you may or may
not be familiar with like automatic tax
loss harvesting,
rebalancing your portfolio,
cross more than 10 asset classes and
dividend reinvestment add up to very large
amounts of money over longer periods
of time. Wealth Front, as I mentioned,
since it's using software
instead of retail locations,
etc. Can offer all of this at low
costs that were previously completely
impossible right off the bat.
You never pay commissions or
account fees for everything.
They charge 0.25% per year on assets above
the first 15,000 which is managed for
free. If you use my link,
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim,
that is less than $5 a month to invest
a $30,000 account for instance. Now,
normally when I have a sponsor on this
show is because I use them and recommend
them. In this case,
it's a little different.
I don't use wealth front yet because
I'm not allowed to. Here's the deal.
They wanted to sponsor this podcast,
but because of sec regulations,
companies that invest your money are
not allowed to use client testimonials.
So I couldn't be a user end
have them on the podcast,
but I've been so impressed by Wealthfront
that I've invested a significant
amount of my own money, at least for me,
uh, in the team and the company itself.
So I am an investor and hope
to soon use it as a client.
Now back to the recommendation
as a Tim Ferriss show listener,
you'll get $15,000 managed for free
if you decide to open an account.
But just start with seeing the portfolio
that they would suggest for you.
Take two minutes, fill out their
questionnaire@wealthfront.com
forward slash. Tim,
it's fast, it's free. There's no downside
that I can think of. Just take a look,
see what portfolio they
would create for you,
and you can use that
information however you want.
wealthfront.com forward slash
Tim and until next time,
thank you for listening.