Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
No question.
I'm a cybernetic organism living tissue.
This episode is brought to you by wealth.
Front.
Wealth Front is the future
of financial advice.
They become incredibly popular among my
friends in silicon valley and across the
country because they provide the same
high end financial advice that the best
private wealth managers deliver
it to the ultra wealthy,
but for any account size and at a
fraction of the cost. For instance,
they monitor your portfolio every day
across more than a dozen asset classes to
look for opportunities to rebalance
or harvest tax losses. Now,
would you do the same? Are you
doing the same? Probably not.
And the powers and the software wealth
front now manages more than $4 billion in
assets,
which is up from around 2.5 billion.
When they started
advertising on this podcast,
they're growing incredibly quickly. Unlike
old fashioned private wealth managers,
wealth front is powered
by innovative technology,
making it the most tax efficient,
low cost, hassle free way to invest.
They don't have bloated sales
teams or retail locations,
so they can deliver all of this
sophisticated financial advice and these
services at a fraction of the cost
of a traditional financial advisor.
So at the very least,
go to wealthfront.com forward slash
Tim and take their free risk assessment
survey. It only takes a couple
of minutes and Wealthfront.
We'll recommend a personalized portfolio
of investments. In other words,
they'll tell you exactly where
they would put your money.
So even if you don't use their service,
you have a huge leg up and you have
additional information for making good
decisions.
They use investment theory to automate
good financial behavior and decisions
that people typically don't make,
but should so go to wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim to get your first 15 k
managed for free or just to
get more details, check it out.
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim
this episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
I've used 99 designs for years for
all sorts of graphic design needs,
whether you need a logo, website,
book cover, anything else.
99 designs was created to make great
designs accessible to everyone and to make
the process of getting designs much,
much easier. So when I first started out,
for instance,
testing,
prototype covers and getting prototype
covers for the four hour body,
I want the contest drop. That is one
option. This is a great solution.
If you're looking for fast affordable
design work and the ability to choose from
dozens of options risk-free.
Let's say you need something late night,
quick turnaround while
people in other time zones,
other countries can also help you
solve that problem. Since then,
I've worked with 99 designs on a separate
path or a different option and uh,
that is the one to one project service.
So enact number of cases.
And I'll give you one example.
When I wanted to create the cover
for my audio book, the Tao of Seneca,
this was a very important project to me.
I decided to use their one
to one project service.
And with this service you can invite
a specific designer to your project,
agree on a price,
and then work together until you're
satisfied and they allow you to iterate.
And provide feedback and all of this
stuff and I haven't shared it yet,
but we also got some incredibly good,
really some of the best illustrations
I've ever seen from using this one-to-one
project service with a handful of
different designers and illustrators.
It blew my mind.
99 designs makes this all very easy and
efficient so you can check out the Tao
of Seneca design and other work that I
and your fellow listeners for that matter
have done on 99
designs@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim.
Again,
that's 99 designs.com forward slash Tim
little boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to
another episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
That is Molly chewing a bully stick,
otherwise known as bold,
fizzle in the background,
but you're not here for that.
You were here for what we do every
episode that is deconstruct world class
performers, whether they are from the
worlds of business, sports, entertainment,
chess or otherwise, to tease out the
habits, routines, philosophies, beliefs,
etc. That you can apply to your own life.
And this time around we have someone by
popular request who is perhaps all of
those categories wrapped into one.
Adam Robinson.
Adam first appeared on this podcast in
the becoming the best version of you
episode,
which was number two 10 so episode
number 210 alongside Josh Waitzkin,
who is best known for chest
Jujitsu investing and Rameet Seti,
best known for personal
finance and entrepreneurship.
So we had this round table,
how do you end your year?
All sorts of great stuff came up,
so I encourage you to
listen to that as well.
But this is a dedicated episode full
of Adams stories and life lessons.
He came out to San Francisco
to spend time with me.
I wanted to learn from him
and that is how it came to be.
Adam Robinson has made a lifelong study
of outflanking and outsmarting the
competition.
He has a rated chess master who was
awarded a lifetime by the United States
Chess Federation.
And as a teenager he was personally
mentored by Bobby Fischer in the 18 months
leading up to his winning
the world championship.
Bobby Fischer is considered by many to
be the best chess player who has ever
lived.
Then in his first career,
Adam developed a revolutionary approach
to taking standardized tests as one of
the two original cofounders of the
Princeton Review, his paradigm breaking,
or as they say in publishing category
killing test prep book, the sat,
subtitle,
cracking the system is the only test
prep book ever do with become a New York
Times bestseller. Then after selling
his interest in the Princeton Review,
Adam turned his attention in the early
nineties to the then emerging field of
artificial intelligence
developing a program.
They could analyze texts and provide
human like commentary is a Jack of all
trades, master of many. He was later
invited to join a well known quant fund.
Uh, we can get into that another but well
known quant fund to develop statistical
trading models.
And since he's established himself as an
independent global macro advisor to the
chief investment officers,
have a select group of the world's
most successful hedge funds and family
offices.
So in other words,
he is brought in to give
advice to billionaires and
mega billionaires and beyond
in his spare time.
For instance,
he's also become pen pals with Warren
Buffet and we dig into lots that he's
learned from Warren. This is
a wide ranging conversation
with a lot of takeaways.
I hope you enjoy listening to it
as much as I enjoyed recording it.
So without further ado, please enjoy
my conversation with Adam Robinson.
Adam. Good. Sarah, welcome back to
the show. Thanks for having me, Tim.
And we are sitting here
and constant Ferris on this
comfortable couch in viewing
distance of my lovely dog,
Molly.
And we could start just about anywhere
we have a thousand topics we could
explore it.
And I thought we'd start with an anecdote
that made an impression on me and I'd
like to explore it a little bit.
Could you talk about Warren
Buffett and his day planner
please? Huh. So, uh,
we were having dinner, 10 of us with, uh,
with Warren and he held up with the,
with great dramatic affect his day
planner for the year. And he said,
time is the most precious thing I have.
He said,
I'm going to show you how precious it is.
I'm going to show you my day planner.
And He,
so it's a little two inch by three
inch little booklet that you get at any
stationery store for the year.
And he held it up for all of us and he
rift through it and every page was empty
and that was his day planner
for the year. So, so it's,
it's really important to,
to warn that his time is
his most valuable asset.
And what does he do with all
that empty space? He reads
all day, everyday, all day,
every day.
Reads,
thinks and hunts for his next acquisition.
And so that's,
that's what he does with his time.
Does he think of himself as an investor
or an acquirer of businesses at this
point in time? How do you think he, he
thinks of himself,
you know,
everyone calls him the world's greatest
investor and he's certainly the world's
greatest something.
But I think he's,
he's is actually the world's greatest
builder of businesses and acquire of
businesses. And so that's what
he does. He acquires a business,
intends to hold it forever.
Let's,
let's talk about talking about investing
but take us a slightly different tack.
We were chatting over Thai food
a little bit about a book called,
and I'm Mike at titles slightly wrong,
but I believe it is a,
you can be a stock market genius.
It's something along those lines
by Joel Greenblatt. Absolutely.
And that,
that book had in him made an impression
on me and had an impact on me when I was
pretty young. I think I was a
little too young for it. Uh,
when I was around 16 or 17 and uh,
directly proceeded my first stock
purchase f ever, which was Pixar.
And uh, when I, when I met Joel
many, many, many years later,
this is probably just a few years ago,
he said that in some respects
people should read his books in the,
the reverse order of their publication
because the stock market genius book
really covers a lot of what some people
might consider event based investment or,
or training.
And I was wondering if you
had any thoughts you brought
up and I said, hey, let's,
let's talk about it in the conversation
when we're recording. You mentioned,
yes you are familiar with,
with Joel and then also you
brought up Lynch Peter Lynch.
And so I'd love to just hear you expand
on what you're going to say, but I,
I cut you off during dinner cause
I wanted to save it for this.
Right. So, so Peter Lynch one up on Wall
Street and, and uh, and Joel Greenblatt,
both brilliant investors,
both investing geniuses and, and uh, my,
my only concern about about empowering
individual investors is that when you
invest as an individual,
you are entering the,
the fiercest Gladys tutorial
arena ever invented.
And uh,
you're competing with highly incentivized
participants around the world,
uh, who are out for your lunch
and going to eat it if you're, if,
if you don't have an edge.
So I just want to be sure that individual
investors, when they choose to do that,
realize that it's, again,
a gladiatorial pit and a,
and you need an edge when you invest.
So what is your take on then
say a lynch or a Greenblatt in,
in that capacity?
And I don't know if it was [inaudible]
who could have been elsewhere when
there's a discussion about the edges,
the types of edges you could have and
one would be informational advantage.
One could be a analytical advantage.
Another could be say perhaps
a behavioral advantage.
And reading a lot about buffet, it seems
like at least one of his advantages,
behavioral, he's very unemotionally it
seems like affected by market movements.
Absolutely.
Uh,
and can divorce himself emotionally
from these temporary ups and downs.
Um, but, uh,
do you have any particular observations
related to Peter or Joel is relates to
advantages,
edges or otherwise?
You know, it's, it's so funny and before
we go any further, you know, I, cause we,
this is so much more intimate
than a conversation than
we had at the 92nd street
y in front of a thousand people. And, uh,
this is almost a like park or jumping,
um,
but a conversational version of that
where you leap from topic to topic,
not knowing where you're going.
Um, so the edge, Warren Buffet,
one of my favorite quotes
of Warren Buffet is, um,
if you're in a poker game for 30 minutes
and you don't know who the Patsy is,
you're the patsy.
And so you need an edge,
but you need to know that you
have an edge over the market.
And in terms of information
since, uh, 2000,
uh,
the,
a sec published a regulation
FD fair disclosure.
So in a sense, everyone has access to
the same information at the same time.
So information edges are very,
very difficult,
especially with modern
technology and, and, uh, um, uh,
other resources.
So information edges are tough,
behavioral edges are really important.
And you said buffet,
he's completely unemotional.
So yes,
when everyone is panicking,
uh, is when he gets greedy.
In fact, Buffett said a buffet
articulated in one sentence, the,
uh, the secret to investing. And
uh, and that's, uh, he said that we,
meaning he and Charlie Munger are
fearful when others are greedy and we are
greedy only when others are fearful.
And so the secret to investing in, in,
uh, public securities is knowing when to
be afraid. And knowing when to be greedy.
So what I'd like to do in this,
in this American Ninja Warrior course
of conversational park core is maybe,
maybe take a step back really far back
and did discuss a few of the experiences
of your childhood because I was not aware
that you had spent, was it two years,
two and a half years and a half years,
yeah. In the hospital. When you were,
when you were a kid, could
you describe why that was the
case? What happened? Sure,
sure. Well, it was a Blythedale children's
hospital, which was started in, in um,
wow, I think in the forties
by Eleanor Roosevelt. And uh,
it was for children with
longterm congenital illnesses
and I had a bone disease.
And uh, back then, uh,
the only way to cure it to was to put
you in a bed and wait for the disease to
kind of run its course. And so, um, I
don't know if you remember Forrest Gump.
I did the beginning.
He had those leg braces.
So between the ages of
four and six and a half,
I was wearing those leg braces in a
bed in the children's hospital. Yeah.
So what was,
what was your childhood like?
Ah, when, where did you grow up? It's,
so I grew up, I was born in New York,
uh,
and then was put in the hospital.
And then when I got out we moved
to, um, to Chicago, to Evanston,
Illinois, which sort of Northwestern
is. So if you've seen any of the movies,
like Ferris Bueller's day off
for home alone was raw, filmed,
and within a mile of where
I grew up. So that was, that
was the where, what would you
in debt if you were to paint,
because we talked a little bit about
in the last episode, Princeton Review.
Yeah. And we talked about that
chapter of your life in part,
but what were some of the formative
influences in your life up to say,
end of high school influences or
events, anything like that. You know,
being in the hospital
for two and a half years
as you're growing up, you,
you get divorced from your body
in a hospital bed and, and you,
you get divorced from the world.
The world is something out there that
you can't touch and you can't participate
in and you,
but you observe it and you think about it.
And,
um,
I guess one of the format of influences
was, was a meeting Bobby Fischer, um,
was my hero.
How did you meet Bobby Fischer?
And for those people who don't
know who Bobby Fischer is,
how would you encapsulate?
Ah,
Fisher is said by some to be the
greatest chess player of all time.
And I met him right before he won the
world championship and knew him right
through the world championship.
And then
sadly afterwards he began
to lose his mind, uh, to,
to paranoia and died in 2007,
uh,
sad. Um, but I knew him at the height of
his powers right before he won the world
championship. And, uh, it's
funny. Hi, I met him. He, um,
freshman year when I was in high school,
uh,
somebody beat me in a game of chess in
homeroom, beat me in like five most,
like I knew how the pieces moved,
but that was the extent of my knowledge
and this self frustrated me. I thought,
okay, I'm going to challenge them a
game the next day. And he beat me again.
In fact, he beat me every day
that week. So I resolved that. Um,
I would study this game,
uh,
and just in order to beat this kid by the
end of the year, that was my sole goal.
And uh, cause I was really into
swimming at the time, you know,
something four or five hours
a day, six, seven days a week.
And chess was really much a sideline
for me. But I got into the game and,
and I,
I decided to go to the library,
actually a bookstore and get a chest book.
And the only book that they had was a
book called my 60 memorable games by Bobby
Fischer.
And at the time,
this was four years before he
would win the world championship.
So I played over these games every
night there's 60 games and I realized,
but wait a second, he's played hundreds
of games. So I went to the library.
This is pre Internet for those of you
millennials who don't know what a library
is. And uh, and I, I got one,
it was the slow version of the Internet.
Yeah. This lowers and or the Internet.
Yes. When you actually had to
look up things yourself. And um,
I went through 20 years of
back issues of chess magazines,
laboriously every chest magazine that I
could find in the world and went through
page by page. And if I found a
fissure game, I would write it down.
So I compiled my own notebook of 700
of his games that he had played and I
played over these games for two,
three years and I knew them by heart.
When you say played over,
yes.
Does that mean you would set up a board
or did you do this in your head and you
would go move by, move through
both players? Exactly. Decisions.
Exactly. If you do it on a
board, not a board. Yes. Um,
some people could do it in their heads.
I mean,
you'd like Magnus Carlsen World Champ,
uh, or Josh Waitzkin, our buddy,
uh, they can do it in their head.
I had to use a board. And, um,
so, so I remember it was, um, my,
I was 16 years old with my mother on
Easter Sunday and a visiting her in New
York and we were walking up sixth
avenue towards Central Park,
beautiful April Day.
And I'm across the street
across sixth avenue,
right in front of Macy's. I saw Bobby
Fischer. So imagine this was my hero.
Right.
And again,
this was a year and a half before he would
win the world championship. And again,
for those of you don't know that it
would be like spotting bigfoot or,
I mean he was, or JD Salinger Baga sure.
Right. Right. Back in the day. And um,
so I said, mom, I, I know I, I said I
would spend today with you, but that's,
that's Bobby Fisher over the, I'll see
you later. So I had to cross traffic.
I ran up to him and I,
I said that Mr. Fisher,
Mr. Fisher in 1962 when you were playing
with Shefsky and the US championship,
you know,
cause I had years of,
of questions for him and I knew
all his games by heart and he just,
and he was, by the way, he
was a notorious reckless,
he had maybe two friends in
the entire world. And uh,
and he just looked at me kind of bemused
because I knew his games so well and he
said, well, I dunno, we're
going, I'm going to lunch. You
want to join me? And I said,
sure. Of course. Like right.
And that was the beginning of a friendship
that lasted two and a half years.
It actually stretched beyond that, but
after the world championship. But I,
I fell out of touch with them for about
a dozen years because he fell off the
map, the map where it doesn't
yours. So you met him, you,
how old were you at the time? He said 16
he was 28. 16 yeah. What was that first?
What was that first lunch like
if, I mean fantastic. I mean,
imagine you're meeting your hero that
no one gets to talk to. And here he is,
I'm inviting you to lunch.
I mean a fantastic, and uh,
I wish I realized at the time how,
how lucky I was and uh,
but I wasn't thinking about that.
I was only thinking about him
and his chess games and, and uh,
I remember talking with him
and people don't know. I mean,
I think of chess players
as um, you know, uh,
intellectual nerds and
very, uh, I'm not athletic,
but he was built like a, an Olympic
athlete. He was six, three, um, um,
an eight, literally two meals over
lunch, like two simultaneous meals,
two simultaneous meals. He just
demolished. Uh, again, um, uh,
and when I say an Olympic athlete, I don't
mean like a power lifter. He was, uh,
like a, like a, an American football
player I just for, but very lean and um,
had incredible, uh, energy when we walked
down the street. Again, I'm five, eight,
he's six, four, he towered over me
and walk with these huge strides.
I mean you have incredible power,
you know,
and the amazing thing
about Fisher was that,
and I don't think this has ever
been done in the history before,
he was entirely self taught.
He learned the game at the age of six
and then decided to take on the Russians
for whom chess was their national sport.
It was proof of their superiority during
the height of the Cold War and single
handedly beat them at their own game.
He had no coaches, no nothing, um,
and did it all on his own.
And a remarkable,
remarkable guy. We all, we, we,
I remember debating Motown songs with him.
Um,
we were at a diner, um, and we had,
we had dollars between us,
but we had no coins and they just have
these little juke boxes at each dining
table that you put in a quarter
and you have three songs.
We had a quarter between us.
And so we were debating which three
songs we were going to choose.
He loved Motown and so did I. So, uh,
I can't remember which songs we picked,
but I remember doing that with him.
How did that first lunch turn
into an ongoing relationship?
And maybe a better question to be to
what happened at in the last half or
quarter of that meal that led to a second
meeting. You can tackle it either way.
I'm just so curious because
people have these opportunities,
these golden opportunities,
right?
And then they're not able to capitalize
on them or it's a flash in the pan.
They have a great single story, but that
turned into an ongoing relationship. Why,
why?
Because I was totally focused on him
and that it never occurred to me when I
first approached him that he
would say, get lost kid. Um,
I just had questions and,
and he was my hero and it
was entirely innocent and,
and, and I'd done my homework. I
knew his games better than he did.
So I remember talking about games and
we played hundreds of games of speech
chess.
And so imagine playing pickup basketball
and you're a very good basketball
player, but you're playing with, you know,
Coby Bryant or more or, or curry, right?
I mean, what one of the grades? And, um,
and I remember I would play his moves
against him because I knew all of his
games by heart and then he would correct
me. Like he would say, I'd say, Oh,
I don't understand why he played that
because you said black is better in your
book. And he said, I did. I said,
yeah you did. And he said, oh,
I was wrong. It's better
and crushed me. Um,
and so it was a,
I think it was just because I knew it
was games so well I'd done my homework.
And, and I think the lesson
for, for everyone is,
is it if you've done your homework to,
to,
to be focused on the other person,
um,
and not your fears and reservations and,
and uh,
yeah.
So in terms of continuing the relationship
focused on them in the sense of being
curious about them as opposed to
worrying what they're thinking about you.
Exactly. Totally focused on them. And, um,
it's interesting cause he would
then reflect it back on me.
So the next year when he was
preparing for the Spassky match,
am I got to spend two weeks with them
Spassky these world championships for the
world championship right now you'd think
if there was any time that he wanted to
be alone, it was like preparing
for the oil change it. But I,
he invited me to spend
two weeks of them at a,
at gross singers and of gross singers at
the time was a resort in the Catskills.
And uh,
Muhammad Ali used to train there and uh,
so they invited Fisher to train for the
Spassky match and I got to spend a week
with him, uh, sorry,
two weeks with him at a,
they're all alone and watched him
prepare for the Spassky match,
which was really fascinating.
So he,
he play over games studying and then
he would turn to me and say, well,
what would you do here? And I said,
and when you say play over games,
and I apologize because I
wouldn't consider myself a
chess player, but sure, sure.
That means that he's sitting
in front of a board by himself.
He's sitting over a board by himself.
Well with me, I'm sitting next to him,
uh,
or rather across the table from him and
he's got a full chessboard and a book of
Spassky his games. It was
a red book, like 600 games.
And just as I did with Fischer's games,
he had a little red book of Spassky
these Games and he just played over these
over and over.
And it was really fascinating and I don't
think people realized Fisher conducted
the longest con in sports history,
a long con. And, and uh, if you're
not sure what a long con is, I mean,
I know you know Tim but, but uh, for,
for listeners along con is a, is a,
is a,
um,
is when a confidence man sets you
up and the payoff is years away,
not like later that day.
And so official when he was growing up,
played always pawn to king
for his, his first move, and,
and, and had a very limited opening
repertoire in terms of, in football terms.
He had a very limited playbook and he
always played the same opening moves and
he defied the Russians and defied
the world to beat him by essentially,
he's giving, here's my playbook, these
are my opening moves. Do your best.
And so from the age of 12
till the age of 29 when he,
right, so this is 17 years, he played
exactly the same opening moves.
And what was curious for me was that
when I was with him about a month before
the two, sorry, two months before the
match began, I noticed he was playing,
studying games outside is
opening repertoire. And I,
I asked him, I said, Bobby, what are
you like, why are sending those games?
And he just kind of smiled. Cryptically
um, and uh, he said, I dunno,
we'll see. And, and sure enough
against Spassky. Now mind you,
Spassky was supported by the
Russian chess machine, right?
Dozens of the world's top
players were all Russian. Uh,
who were supplying Spassky with
analysis of all of fishers,
old games,
but then he played an entirely
new opening repertoire.
He set them up for 17 years. He said,
these are the moves I'm going to play.
So imagine it'd be like a,
a box or always backed by leading with
his right hand and then all of a sudden
he's leading with his left and
they didn't know what to do.
They were totally flummoxed, dread pirate
Roberts and the princess bride. Oh,
that I'm not lefthanded yeah. Out
of those. That's exactly right.
The princess bride.
I a cane.
If we're talking about
her yesterday and what,
what are some of the other things that
you observed about Fisher or learned from
Fisher? Does anything come to mind? He
was very childlike. Um, very simple.
Um, in his analysis of,
of the Games, you know,
Oliver Wendell Holmes,
one of my favorite quotes is he said,
I wouldn't give anything for the
simplicity on this side of complexity,
but I'd give my life for the simplicity
on the far side of complexity.
And Fisher was the simplicity
It was the informed simplicity, not the
uninformed yes, like Picasso. You know,
it's funny, I always dismissed Picasso
is a painter. Not that I'm an art expert.
Um, but it's only when you,
when you see his paintings as a,
as a 16 year old and he's
painting like Rembrandt.
So when he went over and,
and Eh,
as an adult and started painting like
a child, it was an informed simplicity.
It was a choice. Um, and
Fisher was like that.
In what other ways did the
childlike nature manifests itself?
Isn't Doozy, ASM? Um, always he was
enthusiastic about everything, uh,
in the way that he
explained things. Like, um,
I remember once we were looking at a
position on the board and he had, again,
he was six [inaudible] four. He
was a normous and he, he, he, he,
he's trying to teach me a lesson about
the position of chess pieces on the board.
And he held his hand over a
few pieces and he said, if,
if your pieces can move outside of
your hand, they're too far apart.
They're not well coordinated. Like
it was a physical, an intuitive,
mm. Uh, encapsulation of
a very profound principle,
um, that, uh, the,
the illustrated again
physically with his hand,
your pieces move outside your
hand. Uh, the, the too far apart.
They can't coordinate and you're like,
do you mean your size?
Pancake my little head. Right, exactly.
Um, yeah cause he's hand
privately is half the board. Um,
yeah. So, so, um, so that, that's
how genius manifests itself. Uh,
as, as, as a child like simplicity.
What are other,
if there are other essences of
genius in your mind because you,
you and we talked about this a bit in the
first episode and I'm sure we'll touch
on this in a few different
ways in this conversation,
but you have been successful
in many different worlds
and you've met many people
who are geniuses in different domains.
So s aside from this,
okay.
Childlike simplicity that is on
the other side of complexity.
What are other essences of
genius in your mind?
I think the American
psychologist Maslow said,
if your only tool is a hammer,
you view every problem is a nail.
And I would flip that
and say that if you're,
the geniuses have very limited tool sets.
They have a hammer and they're
geniuses in looking for nails,
right? That's their genius, right?
They have a very limited skill set. Um,
but they, they master it and apply
it incredibly well. You know,
I'm reminded, uh, of the,
of the movie karate kid,
right? Or is wax on, wax
off, um, you know, uh, uh,
sand a floor. Right? And then he
had that crane kicky move. Yeah.
And he won the California State
Championship on the base of those three.
And I'm goofing here on, on, on,
on, on, um, on the karate kid. But,
but I think it illustrates
a, a, a profound point to,
to master a few skills.
Well and,
and then look for domains when you
can apply those skills and stay out of
everything else. Warren Buffett does
the same thing with [inaudible].
I was going to ask you, and, uh,
then, then I want to come back to you,
but in the case of say a buffet,
what are his wax on wax off,
crane kick, etc. What is his,
what are his primary,
uh,
superpowers and how much
are they neat versus
developed or acquired? Maybe
there's a better way to put
it. Right. Well, you know,
the, one of the great partnerships
of all time was, was, uh,
Charlie monger and, and, and
uh, and Warren Buffet and, um,
and, and, and the two of them spend all
their time just reading and just looking.
And I, and by the way, other
great ambassadors like Sam's,
I'll do the same thing.
They spent all their time on the prowl,
the prowl for ideas or
prowl for businesses.
Are they reading primarily filings?
Are they reading far ranging
books on different subjects,
on everything,
on everything?
You just don't know where you're
going to get your next idea.
Not so much filings I'm in. They would
look, read those two, of course. Um,
but read far and wide because you just
don't know where you're going to get your
next investment idea. And, um,
I think that's one of
their superpowers. And, uh,
and the other is a longterm
focus with the buffet and Munger.
So, um, when everyone is
panicking say, and in, in, uh,
2007 when the world seems to be imploding,
they're eagerly looking
for, for values. Um,
so they invest for the long haul and they
don't get distracted by vicissitudes,
economic or, or otherwise. Um,
you mentioned, so I'm going to go
back to you in the library. Sure.
All right. You're going through hundreds
of games and taking notes. Yeah.
On the Bobby or going through years back,
he was a magazines sure.
And taking down all the
Fisher Games. Yeah, I would
imagine. It's all I did. Right.
So I'm not,
I'm imagining there were not many kids in
your class or your school who did this.
So the question is,
what do you think your core strengths
are and what are some of the core
strengths you've developed that you
didn't have at, at a young age, right,
or weaknesses that you have have overcome?
Well,
I always look for,
and we talked about this at the 92nd
street y for things that don't make sense.
I look for patterns. Um,
I look for, for quirks,
even in my own mind. Uh, I
remember, let's see how old I was,
nine years old and I was
listening to Ms. Callahan,
who is my teacher and I was in love
with her and she was using, she, she,
she,
she was talking about something again,
I was just totally in
love with her and I don't,
I forgot what she was talking about,
but she, she's spoken and I realized,
she spoke the word of and I realized,
Oh, I don't know how to spell that
word. Now what was fascinating is,
I mean I had learned how to read when
I was five and in the hospital. Um,
but I was stunned that I didn't
know how to spell a two letter word.
And so I spent the rest of the
day trying to spell the word of,
and this is the way it did it. My
job is nine years old. I said, okay.
I knew the first letter was a vowel.
So on a sheet of paper
I wrote a e, I, O, u.
And then I wrote why cause sometimes wise.
And then I wrote all the consonants,
right, B, c, d and so on.
And I spent the rest of the day going
through every possible pattern, like a B,
and it's an APP is that of okay,
that's not, and then a c and a d.
And I went through every single
permutation trying to find the word of,
and um, I never found it because
of his is not a, uh, it's not,
it's not phonetic stuff. Another gay
phonetic, a tough language that way. Yes.
I didn't realize that at the age of nine.
Yeah.
But I think that was one
of my core strengths, uh,
looking for patterns and things that don't
make sense and being amused by my own
mind and failings. And, um, but I,
I can I interject for a second? For sure.
You can. Why do you, whenever you win,
why didn't you ask how to spell it as
opposed to going through that exercise?
Because I,
I wanted to,
because the real question was
why I couldn't spell it. Not,
not what is the answer,
what is the answer?
And it's such an important thing,
you know.
Thank you for bringing that up because
the questions you ask about the world
determine the success you,
you, you get in the world.
And one of my favorite
questions is Tony Robbins. Uh,
what would you do if you
knew you couldn't fail? And,
and so the questions we
ask are, are, are key.
So I wasn't interested in the answer how
to, how to spell the word of, I mean, I,
I knew that was trivial.
I knew it was a two letter word,
but what wasn't trivial is
that I couldn't spell it.
Why do you think that is?
Because that's an odd, that is,
it strikes me as very unusual that
you would have learned to read,
but then four years,
three,
four years later would have this word
that sticks out as something that you
couldn't spell away. It was
just one. It was one second.
I knew it was the way you can
forget somebody's, you know,
the name of vernacular in
a movie or something. Like,
I knew it was a momentary glitch, but
I was, I was fascinated by it. And,
and looking back on it, I was, I'm
fascinated that the age of nine, I, I,
I was very systematic.
I had two columns and spent the rest of
the day ignoring Ms. Callahan and the
rest of the class since I spent
most of my time daydreaming anyway.
And she would just let me trying to
figure out how to spell the word of very
systematically and that, and I thought
that was a good use of my time.
You mentioned questions and uh,
love to ask you because I
think they're related. You can,
you can place this at any time.
We're going to jump around
chronologically because that's our core.
That's park court. Never
know what, what's, what, uh,
obstacles coming up next.
Yeah. Decision making. What
is your decision making process for
choosing opportunities or your criteria or
how do you think about
choosing opportunities or
more so than finding when you
have
a number of different opportunities,
a number of different
paths you could go down.
What is your decision making
process or your selection process?
The problem is I'm so intellectually
curious that I really have to be careful
cause it's, it's going
down a rabbit hole. Um,
I'm going to have to limit the things
that I allow myself to be interested in.
And, uh, I think I choose
the one that's the most fun.
And, and, and I guess my
life is like par Corp Right.
Just jumping in and, and,
and, and knowing that Joel,
be resourceful than and land on your
feet and then be able to jump from there
too. So, um, I look also for,
for for areas that we touched on this,
the ball bearings principle, right.
For opportunities with things that
people haven't explored before and uh,
or they've explored the death and they,
they're no longer interested.
And so I tried to look for things
with, uh, with fresh eyes. Yeah.
And for the ball bearing spokes
we could go into it, but we,
we spent quite a bit of time on it.
And in the first episode of that,
I'm so you guys can explore that there.
I'd like to talk about post Fisher.
Where'd you go to college?
I went to Wharton Undergrad and then
I got a lot of great Oxford. Hmm.
And how did you choose
Oxford? And then, then,
then we're going to talk about
apples. Ah, Oh yes, yes. Apples.
I Granny Smith apples.
Okay. I chose Oxford. My, I,
you know,
my,
my father died when I was 19 and I was
pretty lost and I could have finished
Wharton in, in, in two years. Um, um,
two and a half years anyway, cause it's,
it takes six or seven courses a term.
And, uh, cause I, I found
everything really interesting.
And you were only required to take
four, take six or seven. And, um,
my father died and I,
I didn't know what to do and I,
I wanted to get away and I don't speak
any foreign language fluently enough to,
to go to a country other than like,
say England.
So I chose Oxford and I thought law would
be an interesting way to beguile. Um,
a couple of years, two,
three years. So, uh,
was kind of a default actually.
And, and while I was there,
I spent most of my time taking
dance classes in London. Um,
hip hop dancing in London.
Yeah. Yeah. Sorry. I,
I only,
I was the,
not the most conscientious law
student at Oxford. Um, but,
uh, but anyways, so that's
what I did. Yeah. If
you don't mind me asking, we don't
have to get into it if you don't want,
but how did your,
how did your dad pass?
I,
he took his life
and he suffered from depression as I did.
And,
uh, uh, you know,
I remember the last thing
he said to me before, before
he did, so, um, he said, uh,
you know, I'll always remember that
you did everything on your own.
And I didn't realize that he was
using past tense then. Right. He said,
I'll always remember that you did
everything on your own. This was the law.
And then two years, two hours
later, he was, you know,
the police called and said
he was dead. And, um, I, um,
and he did me a disservice because for,
and we'll get to this later in our
par core, uh, excursions. But, uh,
you know, for, for decades,
I th I did do everything on my own and
it's only this last year that I realized
the importance of the
other with a capital t,
capital o that magic is,
is unleashed in the world.
Only when you're, uh,
a circuit is, is, is,
is opened when you're,
when you're connecting with someone else.
And that's where the magic and
the miracles occur. And, uh,
I wish I had known that earlier. Why
don't you think you explored that earlier?
I wasn't aware of it. You mean the
other, yeah, the magic that occurs. Um,
cause I was always in my own world,
right? I mean, I was an introvert.
Um, in high school, I didn't
discover this till later.
There were people that
had never seen me speak.
People that were around me every day for
four years had never seen me speak. And,
um, and then, and yet I was so
animated with Fisher, right.
And running up to him.
Um,
so I lived in my own world and, um, and I,
the world of ideas.
So I'm an aware of other people
and of course we all are. Um,
um, but I was an introvert to,
to an other worldly extreme. And,
um,
and then only this year have
I realized and been excited,
really excited.
I'm um,
by engaging other people and you know,
and we should revisit those three rules
of success that we talked about it at
the 92nd street y um,
cause they're all about other people.
We can talk about them now if you'd
like or we can come back to it. Um,
do you have a preference? Nope.
Nope. You're the, uh, I'm the,
I'm the conductor here. Yes.
You're the ringmaster. All
right, we're going to come,
we'll come back to that after the,
the tragedy with your father
involving your father,
you head to Oxford,
you're taking dance lessons extensible.
You're there for law. Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, this is, this is
the left turn yet again,
but how do we talked about this
a bit last night and night.
I just remember saying what,
so how
do, how do apples enter
the scene? Oh yeah.
You mean my, my nutritional odyssey. You
Nutritional Odyssey. And why, why did it,
why did it become what it was?
Yeah. So, so I arrive at Oxford and,
and I had prepaid for room
and board and, um, you know,
it's a cliche to say,
again, this is back then.
Actually the food you can get
in England now is fantastic.
Um, but back then when I was a student,
it was a cliche to say English food was,
was awful. Um, but then
English institutional food was,
it was inedible. And I,
and I couldn't afford,
I could only afford to eat a one
meal a day and a out I, you know,
pay in a restaurant and a
cause I'd already paid for
room and board and I refuse
to eat the food. So I
used to go to this, uh,
the only restaurant that I could afford
in Oxford was a vegetarian restaurant.
And I started eating vegetarian food.
And I,
and I realized as the days went on that,
that there were three food groups.
Um, there were foods that
made me feel really good. Um,
foods that were neutral and
foods that made me feel bad,
and the foods that made me feel good. The
Granny Smith, apples, carrots, raisins.
Oh, I remember what the fourth
word, cabbage, cabbage, cabbage.
And um, the, the neutral
foods were vegetables,
green vegetables, red vegetables, um,
but not white,
like rice or corn.
Anything, any grains were
negatives. Uh, meet was a,
became a negative. Uh, and dairy
products were negative. And, uh,
so my whole life I'd been training
for five hours a day, swimming,
plus weight lifting.
And then at Oxford I do nothing except
eat granny Smith apples basically.
Um, how did the negative effect you? Oh,
Oh, if I had, oh, I love, for example,
milk with my coffee, and if I had so
much as a teaspoon of milk in my coffee,
I'd get a sore throat. I'd
get instantly congested. Um,
I'd get tired.
Um,
and so I just weeded all those things
out so that by the end of the year,
I was basically a fruitarian.
I think Steven jobs for a while was
a fruitarian. And, uh, and so as I,
and I was a board to be
around cause people would say
let's go out for lunch and
I'd, I'd, I'd have like
a salad or fruit cop.
The Mr had special please. Yeah.
It's exactly the Mister Ed special.
And so I come back and I had lost 20
pounds and it puts it in perspective for
people. I mean you are
not Bobby Fischer. Right?
So at the time before you lost
the 20 pounds, what was, what was,
what were your dimensions like? I
was a one 35 pretty solid muscle. Um,
cause I've been an athlete my
whole life and I'm at five,
eight said if I ever yeah, yeah. So then
you, you lost 20 pounds. Yeah. Yeah.
And, but I wasn't aware
that I was that skinny. Um,
cause your, I guess your body get mid
shifts with it, but I just wasn't hungry.
Like a meal for the for the day might
be a pound of apples or two pounds of
apples, maybe some carrots
really Mister Ed. Right.
And then I just wasn't hungry and some
days I would need it all. And, uh, anyway,
so I come back, uh, uh, to, uh,
to New York where I was living at the
time. Uh, my mother was living and, um,
I go to my brother's health club cause
I decide I should get back in shape.
I hadn't trained for a year.
Right. And imagine you Tim Ferriss,
not training for a year.
Right. And, um, so I, I,
I remember the first machine I sat on was
this Nautilus, a shoulder press. And I,
I set it for five plates,
like 50 pounds.
And because I didn't want to Overdo it
and my arms shot up, they were weightless.
And then, and then I asked my brother,
who was standing next to me, I said, man,
you just blow it a couple of plates
and then make a 70 also shut up.
And I said, okay, Matthew
loaded a couple more cars.
I need a little weight that's too
light. So he does so and, and then I,
I, I pressed like 20 times and said,
yeah, that's about right. And, um,
he comes around to the front of the,
of the machine and he said, okay,
I'm not going to do anything. I just
wanted to come back around to the cause,
the plates, the setting, we're
behind you right where I said it.
And he'd set it on the very lowest
setting. Um, like the full stack,
like the football players. Right.
Um, and every machine was like that.
I could max out on all
the machines easily,
um, with no effort. So odd.
It's so odd because I had,
you know, lost all this weight,
hadn't, hadn't trained for,
for over a year. And even at that
when I was at it's peak condition,
I wasn't able to do that prior to
the dietary odyssey that I went on.
And, um, had to explain
that to yourself. Well, I,
I actually then started doing research,
like I discovered for example,
that primitive man ate only
fruit. They've done, they,
they did a molar studies. They have, um,
they found of skeletons and things and um,
primitive man that if you ate to
vegetables, there were fibers,
scratches on the, on the
molars. And there were none.
So they concluded that primitive man
had basically eaten mostly fruit.
Um, and uh, so I don't
know. I think that was just,
you know what, now that I think about
it, Tim, it's exactly what you do. Um,
you endlessly experiment to find the
optimal combination of whatever to Max out
your performance on whatever dimension.
And that's what I did unwittingly. And,
uh,
you know,
I weeded out the foods that made me feel
bad and focused on the foods that made
me feel good. And that's what I did. So
I was at, I was a Tim Ferriss
acolyte there before you were around.
Have you, and I'm guessing you
probably not replicated the,
the, the Granny Smith
experiment I'm very curious at,
and I'm not recommending folks by the way,
that you go out and do the,
the apple only diet.
But we were joking last night about how
there are at least two foods that I've
experienced during
certain training periods.
It seemed to have an odd performance
enhancing effect. That one.
So this is a long story, guys. I'm
not going to get into this too much,
but for whatever reason,
tart apples. Yeah.
And lentils for me also, uh, which,
which many people don't respond well to,
but, uh, very, very odd
and well, you know, it's not
an an an, you know, and again,
neither of us is advocating,
you know,
that you start consuming
granny Smith apples, um,
exclusively,
but certainly you should pay attention
to your body's responses to any food.
And, and again, I, I had a
taxonomy of three food groups.
Those that made me feel good,
those that were neutral and
those best avoided and, and, uh,
and all of us should do that.
Um, not just with our foods,
with everything in our
lives. Right. Um, um,
optimize our functioning and
that's what you're all about
it, it isn't a lot of ways.
Now these days though,
you do consume your coffee with milk.
Sure.
So then I think this is how the io came,
powder came up. So have you, have you,
did you gradually reintroduce these foods,
including negatives that you
wanted to include or, sure.
I mean the,
I was a board a be with,
because people would invite me out
to a Japanese restaurant and I'd say,
oh, I really can't eat anything on the
menu. Do you have apples to apples?
Uh, um, and, uh, so, so it,
it took me a couple of years actually
to get back to normal eating.
And so right now I eat healthily.
Um,
but I eat some negatives. So, you know,
I, I try to limit dairy products, but, uh,
but I love, I love milk in my coffee,
so what the hell, you know? Um,
I know it's not optimal for
my body, but, but I enjoy it.
Was it, it was maybe Elizabeth
Taylor, I want to say. He said,
yeah,
something along the lines of the problem
with people who don't have vices is
that you can be pretty sure
they very annoying virtues.
Y'All need a few vices here and there.
Let's,
let's go back to the
three rules for success.
Uh,
can you, I'll let you take it
from here. The mic is yours.
Well, you know, and uh,
just by way of, of, uh, of, of background,
it began when you asked me how you, you
mark the end of a year. And I said, I,
I reflect on the lessons I learned the
the past year and I make a conscious
effort to apply them in the coming
new year. Cause you asked me this,
what a month ago, right? And it's
right, right back in December. And, uh,
and so I thought you asked me what
did I learn in, in 2016? And I said,
I learned three things and,
and I,
I learned the importance of fun,
enthusiasm, and delight in everything
you do. Absolutely everything.
Um, and first and foremost, um, fun,
enthusiasm and delight.
And we'll come back to that.
The second is connecting with everyone
you encounter on however fleeting a
basis. And you've been with me and
you see, I do that Uber drivers,
uh, maitre ds, everybody,
you name it, I, right. I'm,
I put that into action. You really
connect with the person, um,
in however fleeting that connection is,
but you,
you make an effort to make
a connection. Um, and, uh,
and the third is to lean into each moment
and each encounter and everyone you
meet expecting magic or miracles.
And,
and those were the three things I learned.
And the interesting thing about all of
them is that none of them have anything
to do with me. It's all about
the other person, right?
And when I say fun, delight and
enthusiasm, it's to create fun,
to lighten and enthusiasm for
the other person. Um, and that,
that goes for if you're
going to a meeting, um,
and you want us with a venture capitalist
because you're looking for funding for
your startup, or you're going on a
date, uh, or you're, you're, you're,
you're going on a job interview.
Forget the fact that it's an interview.
You're going to delight the other person.
That's what you're there for first
and foremost, and to make connection.
And if you do,
if that's your focus as opposed to
getting the job or getting the funding,
then you get magic and miracles. But
that should be your primary focus. And,
uh,
and what it does is it,
it gives you infinite power
because you want nothing.
And you're offering everything
all I want. I mean, that's what I,
in this moment now with you sitting as
sitting in front of you on your couch, um,
is to,
is to connect with you and to delight you.
So it's,
I'm playing a game I can't lose and
I'm in total control and I don't want
anything. And, uh, so, uh,
that's such a revelation for me and
I wish I had known that earlier.
How did, how did that, I'd be curious
to hear how that revolution came about.
So you mentioned depression earlier,
which I definitely want to talk about.
And I've certainly
talked and written about my
own battles with extended, uh,
depression and some very
severe episodes over the years.
And uh, you mentioned Tony
Robbins earlier. So Tony Robbins,
I remember underscored something
for me maybe a year and a half ago,
which was effectively suffering
is an excessive focus on yourself.
There you go. Yourself. Right.
That was a lesson that I underlined and
highlighted and revisited many times
since he imparted that to me because it
seemed like the best medicine for fixing
myself was to stop focusing on
myself in the, in many respects.
Absolutely. I, and I,
I've taught Tony Robbins
one of the greats, right.
Um, however, with respect to depression,
one of the insidious things, um,
Nah, insidious isn't the right word.
One of the sinister things about
depression is that it, it's a,
okay,
it works by getting a vice
grip on your thinking,
so you're incapable of
thinking outside of yourself.
Um,
that and really the,
the worst aspect of depression
between the ages of,
Oh golly,
14 and say 30. There wasn't a day. I,
I didn't wrestle with the hamlet
question to be or not to be. Um,
and, uh, the worst thing about, and some
days for example, um, I remember a period,
yeah,
for a couple of months I didn't leave my
apartment. I had the, the blinds drawn.
Um, I would order in from,
from a deli. Um, and the,
the, the worst aspect of,
of depression is that you,
you come to despise yourself and you,
you,
you believe that only now in depression.
Are you thinking clearly? Yes. And
that before you were delusional,
yes. This is [inaudible] and
you hate yourself for you.
You hate yourself for being diluted,
and that nobody understands.
Now.
Now I am thinking clearly
now nothing matters.
And, and, uh, and that's,
that's really the devil at work.
That's why I say sinister. Um,
because depression traps your thinking
and it hijacks your thinking like a virus
and, um, and you despise yourself.
You despise yourself for
being diluted previously.
And a lot of people in their
lives despising themselves.
What took you out of that pattern?
You mentioned, uh, I'm
blanking on the exact ages,
but you said something like
14 to 30 years. Sure. And
then, and then episodically.
Okay. After that point, um, I
mean, between 14 and 30, it was,
it was unrelenting. Um, it was a siege
of me against my, my depression. Um,
and then it was episodic. And
then I'm not sure. It just,
I don't know if it was biochemical.
Um,
but it just lifted.
And how,
if you don't mind me asking him when,
when it lifted,
how old were you when I say
lifted it again? It would get,
could come back. Sure. Um,
but I haven't, for example,
now I haven't had an episode
of depression and probably
a decade. That's a long
story, long stretch. And I,
I think it's a biochemical shift
cause depression also, as you know,
and the word depression
reflects not just the mental state,
but the physical state.
Your energy level is low. And I think,
you know, and to go back to Tony Robbins,
you know,
one of the great things about Tony
Robins is he's high energy and you think
about all like Richard
Branson and Elon Musk and you,
Tim high energy and, and, and one way to,
to, to, uh,
escape from slipping
into depression is to,
is to be ever vigilant about keeping
your energy level high and to notice the
biochemical markers
that precede depression.
So you can, uh, headed off at the
pass before you, you slip into it.
Because once you slip
into it, I mean, yeah,
you're no very difficult.
You're essentially,
you're going to go down that slope for
a while and then it's going to take,
you know, days, a weeks or months to
come out of it. What are some of the,
I guess not red flags,
but orange flags for yourself?
The biochemical markers that would
tell you check engine light. Okay.
Something,
something's going in the wrong direction.
Certain seasonal things like in the
winter and people suffer from seasonal
affective disorder.
I think it's really just noticing
your energy levels day to day.
For me personally,
that was the marker for me.
And each individual will
have markers that will be,
if you suffer from depression.
And by the way,
neither of us has giving medical advice.
Of course we're not the thing
we're invested in advice
or advice of any kind, um,
informational purposes, only
informational purposes only. But, uh, but,
but all of us should become aware of,
and again this is a,
a Ferris principle,
a Ferris first principle or axiom is,
is to,
is to be aware of what works and what
doesn't work and and keep experimenting
and,
and doing more of what works and less
of what doesn't work and uh, and,
and eventually you,
you,
you optimize and become a very
high functioning individual.
So I'm going to come back to depression.
I'm going to shift gears a little bit.
I'm going to come back to because it,
my interactions with you,
I know that your brain works very well in
this conversational format. Sure, sure.
So I'm going to allow the
question on depression,
which is going to be 10 years ago
when you seem to click out of that,
sure. Condition, what things
correlated, where there other things,
new people in your life, new behaviors,
dietary changes, whatever it might be.
We don't have to hit it right now,
but I'm going to let that we've added
as a parenthesis, we'll come back to it.
We'll come back to it because I know
that that will be working on the back
burner in your head, things
that work. And to provide some,
some context for folks.
So you were very kind to come out
and visit me in San Francisco and a,
you brought a lot of ideas with you and
I remember this was after at the 92 why
Josh agreed that you were one of the best
gift givers in the world and the gift
said would take you some time to prepare
and then they were ideas for me and you
came out to share them. And we've been
spending a lot of time together. Yeah.
You have also been writing a book and uh,
you've been taking a lot of bats.
And I remember asking,
do you always take baths when you are
working on some type of creative product,
uh, project? And he said, well, are you
familiar with the three bs of creativity?
I said, no, I'm not. So speaking
of things that, that work,
can you describe the three bs of
creativity or this is the three bs of
creativity.
Uh,
you know,
creativity is getting in touch
with your unconscious and, and,
uh, you know, you, you,
you consciously pose a question to your
mind and you allow your unconscious too
to percolate on it. And,
and Josh are bestie.
It's written extensively
about this. And, and, and,
and few people in the world
do it better than he does. Um,
but the three B's are bed,
bath and a boss and a,
and buses a is a, is a metaphor
for traveling. So when you want to,
when you have a problem
that you're, you've, your,
your conscious mind has
thoroughly exhausted,
then you give it over to your
unconscious and, uh, so you go to sleep,
right? That's bad. Um,
for me,
which could be a long overnight sleep or
it could be an APP, right?
It could be a nap. Um,
you want to get to the
dream state, um, a bath,
which you could do at any point also.
Um,
or you switch location bosses.
Again,
a metaphor just for
alliterative per purposes. Um,
[inaudible] you switch your,
your location and, um, and,
and that allows your, your unconscious
mind to, uh, to address the problem.
And that again, that's where the magic
occurs. Your unconscious, we in, in,
in Western civilization over the
last few thousand years, we've,
we've deified logic and rationality.
Um,
and the irrational intuitive
mind has gotten, uh, you know,
short the short end of the
stick and we dismiss it.
But that's actually our intuitive
mind and our unconscious mind.
I would say our primitive mind in that
sense is far more advanced and far more
powerful than,
than the advances we've made in logic
and deductive thinking, which is,
um, you know, our unconscious
mind is like a supercomputer, uh,
compared to the trivial apparatus of,
uh,
of our logical mind.
I've been,
this is something I've been thinking
about a lot in the last three years. Uh,
and some of it relates
to psychedelic research,
we'll call it. Ah, but ah,
that's there two episodes on that for
people interested. Uh, so Martine Planko,
Martin Polanco and uh,
Dan Angle and James Fadiman
if you want to look those up,
we're not going to dig
too deep there right now,
but I've tried in the last three years
to really pay more attention to and
sensitize myself to
these tiny perturbations.
Is that a real word? And uh, my,
my visceral response to things and to
really hone what I had trained myself to
ignore for so long.
And you were talking last night and also
today about being detached from your
physical body after the,
the hospital experience and so on,
and only sort of reintegrating those
sensory inputs and really relishing them
and paying attention to them recently.
And for me,
I've been doing the same thing in the
last three years instead of powering ahead
and ignoring all these physical cues
and what you might call intuition,
which has gotten a bum rap for
very understandable reasons.
I think it's abused and
misapplied and a lot of places,
but I've been paying attention,
trying to pay more attention to this,
what we might call primitive
but certainly evolved. Yes.
Instinctual reflexive response to things.
Absolutely.
And you know, the, the thing is that
actually I'll share a
fascinating experience. Um,
I was at a chess tournament 20 years
ago and I'm, I'm a rated master,
very, very strong. And I was playing
another rated master to big tournament.
The world opened in Philadelphia,
this is like 20 years ago. And, um,
and I had had a strong opening
advantage against this opponent.
And if you're unfamiliar
with the game of chess,
it would be imagine a
wrestling match where,
where you haven't pinned the upon it yet,
but you've,
he's having a hard time moving and,
and, and if it goes on much longer,
you are going to pin him.
So my opponent was squirming and cause
I had opening advantage and then I
blundered I lost a piece. Actually
I lost what's known as the exchange,
a rook for a night. Um, and uh, which is,
I lost one of my stronger pieces
for one of his weaker pieces.
So he had an edge and he was really happy
and I knew I'm going to lose the game.
I mean I was really pissed with myself
cause I blundered I wasn't paying
attention. And as I'm staring
at the board, and again,
I'm just really pissed with myself,
I hear a voice,
somebody whispers from behind and says,
uh, you can wait in this position.
Just like that. And I spun around
cause it Chester tournaments,
you're not allowed to give advice, give
advice. And there was no one there.
And I, I thought, oh, well
that's odd. I was like, sure.
Someone had just whispered in my ear and,
you know,
just to jump ahead,
it was my unconscious mind that was
tapping me on the shoulder. And, uh,
but it manifested itself as a
voice and a really distinct,
so I, I, um,
if you can imagine I'm looking at the
chess board and I don't want the opponent
to see that, uh, that I
have any hope or anything.
So I'm doing my best woody Allen
Imitation, you know, like, ah,
I'm going to lose this.
And, but meanwhile,
I'm studying the board really closely
and I see an incredible combination,
like the kind of combination
that Magnus Carlson would,
it would have been pleased with
himself if he had seen. And, um,
and I won the game. And, uh,
I lost every game after that
in the, in the, in the, um,
in the tournament because I wasn't
interested in the games anymore.
I wanted to hear the voice
that spoke to me. And, uh,
and the thing is that your
unconscious mind, um, the muses,
the gods, the universe, um,
are all whispering to you
all the time. And, and,
and you need to close
out your conscious mind.
Find ways to shut it down to hear those
voices because they're whispering all
the time and, um, and,
and you need to hear,
hear them and heat them.
Um, so, uh, like you, I,
uh,
had been actively looking for ways to,
to hear those voices because
they're there all the time. And, uh,
I think for myself,
at least,
I prided myself on not being
distracted by some of those things,
uh,
meaning emotional insights that
we're not tapping me on the shoulder,
probably punching me in the shoulder or
many years. And I remember at one point,
this is probably two
thousand four thousand five,
I was agonizing over this contract.
It was a, uh, it was going to
be a longterm business deal.
And I had a number of issues,
a number of issues with it as
well as the parties involved.
And I created these huge pro and con
lists. And I remember at one point,
agonizing over this for weeks and it was
just consuming my thoughts 24, seven.
And my girlfriend at the time asked me,
she goes, do you even trust this guy?
And I looked at her and I
go, not really. And she goes,
then don't do the deal. And I
was like, good advice. Right?
And of course if I had,
I immediately knew the answer and I was
trying to override it with some type of
hyper rational,
logical apparatus and it would have
been self defeating in retrospect.
I absolutely should not have done
the deal. And I'm glad that I didn't.
Right. So, so, so three
things jump to mind. Um,
so first you had a choice there,
right?
You didn't have to do the deal,
but because you want it to do the deal,
you were looking for ways to rationalize
what your unconscious mind was telling
you. Right? Your unconscious mind was
saying don't do the deal. Um, and uh,
in the same way that a,
so you don't have to take every deal.
And that's one of theW to
jump back to Warren Buffet.
That's one of his advantages is any,
he's written extensively about this,
that uh,
it's like the market is a pitcher and
an everyday it's going to pitch lots of
balls to you and you don't have to swing.
But you know,
once we got any of them that day,
you just wait for a fat pitch
and then you swing for it. Um,
so, so one of the, one of the dangers
when you really want something,
whether it's a relationship
or a business deal,
your conscious mind will rationalize and
will shut down your unconscious mind,
which is screaming at this point.
Don't do it.
Walk away whenever things seem a
little strange or a little off,
that's your unconscious mind
telling you they're really strange.
And really off and walk away cause
you always have a choice. Again,
whether it's a relationship or
a business deal, just walk away.
Okay.
Uh,
in a minute I'm going to come back to
the clicking out of repeated episodes of
depression. Then ask what might have
correlated or correspondence. Sure.
Even if it's not causal,
I'm just curious,
but I'm going to give you a taste of
things to come. This is a new exercise.
I'm going to be, Hey, wait, wait,
where's, where's? Oh, there she is.
I was looking for Molly.
She's asleep. Oh yeah. No.
Mollys mollys resting and typical pose,
which is half of her body on dog bed
head on the extremely hard floor.
You know, for those who you
don't know that Molly is,
if I have ever met a sweeter,
better behaved,
more beautiful dog in my life,
I don't recall. And, and uh,
so I was hoping she would come on over
and sit in my lap while, by the way,
she's 60 pounds. Isn't that like an easy
sit in the lap? But, but, um, she's,
maybe she'll grace us a little later
with her, with her, with her presence,
with her,
with her joy.
She's, she's, she is being
a good intro interview dog.
She's, she's figured out that this
is, this is usually a sideline gig.
Okay. But, uh, I'm going to
pull out a random question.
Allah,
the Tao Te Ching,
which is one of Joshua's favorite books.
So in the spirit of Josh,
who was a, in a, in
absentia here at the moment,
just going to pick a random question.
If I don't like any of these more Parker,
let's jump. Let's do it. What
are you, okay, here we go.
This is just pulled out of a,
a selection of questions.
What are you most daring about?
Wow. Oh boy. That, that,
that, that, that, uh,
I got to think about that. What
am I most during about? Well,
I'll tell you something. Um, 2017 is a
year about being daring about everything.
I don't know that there's a most daring,
I'm daring about everything
I'm doing about the future.
Do you view yourself as a risk taker?
You know, it's funny. Let's reframe
risk. I would love that. Yeah.
Which is why I throw it out
there. Sure. Of course. Um, uh,
so there are two ways to, to,
to, to live life and one is,
is in the pursuit of
gain or to avoid loss.
And those are the two options.
I think if there's another,
I think it's pretty binary.
Yup. Um, and, uh, you know,
nature has,
has evolved us as a species
to be risk averse, um,
to avoid taking chances and,
and not to lose
and to overreact to perceive threats,
right.
Because the penalty for overreaction
to perceived threats is less than
underreacting
right. Mc. And to go back to Fisher,
the great thing about Fisher
was he wasn't afraid to lose.
He wanted to win. And if it meant
he was going to lose a game,
so be it because he wanted to win and,
and he was willing to lose
in order to win. And, um,
you know, I, I play a game now
with myself, with the world,
um, that I can't lose. So there's no risk.
It goes back to those three things,
connecting with people, which I can do.
And I think I do pretty well.
Um,
creating fun and delight and
approaching each person with enthusiasm,
um, which again, I'm in
total control of. Um,
and leaning into each moment expecting
magic. I'm in control of all three.
So what's the risk? I mean I
have nothing to lose and, and um,
I'm in, it's a game that, uh,
yeah, it's game you can't lose. So
what's the risk? The simultaneously,
you made an astute observation earlier,
which we don't necessarily have to get
into the weeds on, but I do think it's a,
it's a good observation.
And it came up,
we were having Thai food and I mentioned
a book that I enjoyed a great deal.
Uh, but when I read it about, I'm guessing
now maybe seven or eight years ago,
called more money than God by,
I think his name is Sebastian Mallaby.
I'm not sure to get it.
Yeah.
But which I thought it was a very
intelligent overview of the origins of the
hedge fund and some of the,
the characters and styles in the,
in the hedge fund world.
Yeah, I know. Wow.
But you observed that many hedge
funds do not in fact hedge hedge.
Yeah.
Okay.
Right. Um, so, so yes.
So hedge funds,
the concept of a hedge fund
was originated in 1948,
however many years ago. That is, uh, um,
I'm not gonna interrupt the
flow of the magic of the moment.
Try to calculate that. That's
okay. We'll go with 40 or 52. Wait,
I'm going to do it right now. If need
to at 16. It's 68 years ago. Oh, no. 69,
because this is 2017 and I'm so the notion
of hedge funds was invented 69 years
ago and um, okay. But yeah, most,
most funds do not truly hedge.
And by hedge,
that means taking a position,
say buying apple stock or
selling gold or whatever it is,
and then simultaneously executing another
transaction that will protect you if
you're wrong about the first. Um, um,
so yeah, most hedge funds don't hedge. Um,
even though they think they are,
that there are various strategies
like being long and short, but um,
yeah, they, they're hedge funds
in, in name only. Uh, not,
not in fact.
Okay.
Let me grab another, another
question. Open up another card.
We just called this the park or debt. This
the stack. Yeah. The conversation. Right.
We have the rapid fire questions,
many of which we hit the last episodes.
We're not going to, uh, we're not
going to beat those to death, but,
okay. Uh, I'm gonna, I'm
gonna pick a new one. Oh,
come on. Come on. I'm not
afraid. This question, I,
I'm not this, this is ridiculous. This
is a presumptive question. I didn't away.
I didn't,
I didn't write this.
Why is it suspicious when
your lover starts talking
baby talk. That's ludicrous.
I actually have Chris, let me pick
it. Let me pick a different one.
When have you lost your way? Oh, well,
I, I think I lost my way years ago.
I think I only found my
way this last year. Um, and
again,
it was,
it was getting out of myself and
realizing it's all about the other person.
Um, you know, by way of metaphor
to create an electric circuit,
you need
to, you, you can't do it
alone. Right? And when you,
when you're charged with another
person, um, you, you, you,
you open up a cosmic circuit. I
don't, it's very hard to explain.
Um, but I've seen it in
real time and, and, uh, you,
you create magic. And, um, so I'm,
I'm on the hunt for it all
the time. I'm, I'm, I'm, um,
I'm on the hunt for magic.
So let's, let's talk about that
hunt for s for a second or a,
a potentially related tangent.
Sure.
At some point over the last two days,
you said,
let's talk about stoicism
and then you mentioned, uh,
you mentioned hedonism.
And so I'm going to let you run with
that and you got what you were requested.
I was hoping for Molly's right next to me.
Um, so, so stoicism,
which is an enlightened philosophy,
but at the same time that stoicism
all Molly, yeah, you can't see this,
but I'm getting, I'm getting links
from Molly here. Sweet dog. Um,
um, hedonism in modern culture has, uh,
the pursuit of pleasure, physical
pleasure, but in fact, it was a,
it was a profound Greek philosophy that
originated simultaneously roughly three
50 BC, uh, with, uh, with stoicism.
And it was the pursuit of pleasure,
but for them,
the highest pleasure was a spiritual
pleasure and intellectual pleasure.
And for me,
the highest pleasure is,
is creating delight for the other person.
Um,
so,
so I'm a,
I'm a hedonist about creating
delight and magic for others.
Um, and, um, so to go back, I,
I'm forgetting what the question is now.
It wasn't really a question,
it was more of a statement that I wanted
you to come at them. Maybe you're a,
you know, with soap, pathetically
hedonistic, stoic, well, maybe yes,
but like I admire the story yo x,
but for me,
the stoics are stoics are impassive,
impassive,
meaning not feeling and to,
to greet a success and failure
with indifference. And, and,
and I disagree. I believe
life should be celebrated. Um,
and the stoics, for me, and again,
they're enlightened or alias and Seneca,
these are
such wise people. Um, but,
but for me, there's something lacking
in, in, in stoicism because it's a,
to go back to our,
our earlier choice,
it's playing not to lose as
opposed to playing to win.
And we are physical creatures
on this plane to delight.
Um,
and I think that's what life is all about,
creating delight for others.
And in doing so,
you have the light for
yourself. Um, and um,
which is why I joked on stage and you
know, Jassa greed, you know, I said, I'm,
I'm the world's best gift giver and I,
I came here bearing gifts for you. And,
uh, I'm really, really
excited because, uh,
my pen Pal Warren Buffet, I'm, I'm,
uh, I'm creating a gift for him.
He keeps encouraging me to write,
uh, cause he sends the stuff I write,
he sends it on to his friends. And,
um, and so I'm, I'm writing a book,
um,
that I started right after our podcast,
a parable and I'm, I'm, I'm
rushing to finish it because, uh,
I'm going to see them on the
19th, um, in a couple of weeks.
So I have a week to finish
this bloody thing. And give
it to him as a present. Um,
and I, I'm, I'm really
excited about the book. Um,
I get such delight giving away presence.
Uh,
and people don't realize I'm totally
selfish because I'm the one relishing and
enjoying it.
Whatever pleasure they get,
nowhere close to what
I'm getting out of it.
And I think that also,
whether it's hedonism or stoicism,
that those are in fact
large umbrellas under which there are
many different species and a derivative
types of stoicism or hedonism,
sex almost. Right? Right.
Yeah. So if you look at say
stoicism, there are those who would,
who might talk about the practice
of stoic joy, which is joy,
but a joy that is not in tandem with a
commensurate emotional overreaction to
negative events. But I've
always, for instance,
one of the things that I've always
thought, well, you know, if I,
if I'm say 80% s stoic,
let's just say for, for the sake of
thought exercise, if I were 80% stoke,
what would the other 20% B and
with Seneca did,
which is actually what's in, in a
way what Charles Darwin did with, um,
to, to effectively hater
proof or critic proof. Uh,
his,
his writing was to insert his
position of his staunch as opponents.
Yes. In a, not only plausible,
but almost complimentary
way in his own work.
So Seneca knowingness as a
incredible order and also just,
uh, w what do we need to color red
or addition or a debater? And so on.
Took a,
he was his letters in his letters to Luke
Ileus when of his students who he knew
was a fan of Epicurus.
He would take choice tidbits of Epicurus
of the epicurean school and insert them
into his own letters, the moral
letters to Lucilius and, uh, and the,
the epicureans and a lot of ways we're
viewed as being the opposite. The stoics,
they were,
they were happy to tend their gardens
and they focused on the little pleasures.
And I'm simplifying it here,
but I always thought, well,
he did such a good job of embedding those,
that I would probably be at least
10% epicurean. And then the last 10%,
maybe that's,
maybe that's a some type of,
some type of a sympathetic hedonist or
at least maybe that's the aspiration.
Yeah. Uh, are there
any particular, you've,
you're a very widely read human being.
Are there any particular philosophers
who draw your attention or who you wish
people would pay more attention to or,
I realize this is a lot of commas. Uh,
if you had to prescribe,
say,
high school seniors to become familiar
with one or more philosophers,
do any, any names or even
schools come to mind? Oh Gee.
Um, could just be thinkers. It
doesn't have to be philosophers.
Right. Well, I mean, I mentioned this,
you asked a similar question
at the 92nd street y and I,
I'm going to start just to buy
myself a little time as I, as I,
I searched my memory for philosophers
that I would broadly recommend is Rumi,
the poet Rumi. And the wonderful
thing about Rumi as a poet,
and he was also a philosopher, is, um,
as he gets you in touch with the
magical and the mysterious and,
and I think we need to
be in touch with that,
all of us in everyday life.
Um,
and so I would say that,
um,
the, I would read Plato, um,
because Plato in the dialogues would,
would create an, an an interlocutor, a,
he would start arguing against himself.
Um, and again, in, in philosophical
discourse and in your own reasoning,
you have to place yourself
in the position of the other.
And if there was one theme today,
and certainly in my life in
2016 and moving forward in
my life is the importance
of the other. And, and
what is he or she thinking,
uh, or what does he or she want as
opposed to what I want or what I think.
And, um, and by the way, you
have to do this in chess. Um,
you know,
you're,
you're playing against an opponent
who also has plans in fact plans
diametrically opposed to
yours. Um, and so you,
it's well to take the other person, uh, in
mind and, and, and what they're planning.
We're going to jump back to that
bookmark that I sat a while ago,
the depressive ongoing depressive period,
intermittent episodes.
And then about a decade ago
or so, lifting, uh, lifting.
Did anything correspond to that? Well,
there any things you introduced or,
I think there was at
that point in my life,
so this is 20 2007 I,
I just made an abrupt decision to
okay.
To move away from everything in the past,
um,
that I had made many mistakes. Gosh, I've
made so many mistakes in my life, but,
but to, to, to,
to re to go back to first
principles and fundamentals and,
and, uh, and by the way, I
turned my back on, on, on,
on, on a couple of successful careers
and, and decided to embark on,
on a new one and to set myself up as a
advisor to two major
hedge funds. And, uh, um,
so I,
I think it was a decision,
a break from the past and
in it and a conscious one.
And I think that was,
that was the marker only
on a, let's just say you, you decide
that on a macro level to break from the,
yeah.
The past and many things in the past.
Let's say you do that after
dinner one day you go to bed.
How was your next day different?
Are you separating yourself from
contact with certain people?
Are you identifying when
old thought patterns come up
and stopping and trying to
replace them? What, what
is, what is the difference?
Well, you know, what the differences
are you, we talked about it when, when,
when we were walking Molly
earlier. So, um, again,
you're listening, so you, you the,
the, the, the, the, the, the audience.
You just, uh, you have to imagine
this. We're walking Molly on,
on the streets of San
Francisco and, uh, in, uh, in,
in a wonderful Selvin Canyon and Clave,
uh, that, that I've never known
about and where anyway, uh,
Tim resides. And so we're
walking Molly and, uh,
yeah,
Molly, when we're walking on
the left side of the street,
you always want Molly away from the
traffic. And so we're walking along and,
and on, on the left side, Molly is okay,
but when we switched to the
other side of the street,
Molly has to be on your right side,
which is again,
away from the traffic.
And, and Molly, again,
this is by way of metaphor you
said that Molly is, is more,
it's a little more awkward for her.
So she's got to be a
little more conscious and,
and thoughtful about what she does when
we're walking on the right side of the
street. And when I made a
conscious break to end, uh,
I mean I ended a relationship and I ended
a business and sided start a new and,
um, you become conscious, you know,
I think too much of our lives
aren't automatic pilot and,
and so like Molly walking on the
right side of the street just,
uh, it's, it's a little different for her,
so she becomes conscious of
everything she does. And I think,
okay,
that's really important to, to be,
to live consciously and mindfully.
And one way to do that is
to get yourself out of, um,
old ways of being, um, take a,
a new path to work.
Um,
I'm not saying you should
be dramatic and an end,
everything is, I didn't start
a new, but, um, you can, uh,
you can make little choices and again,
to live mindfully and consciously.
Um,
yeah, so that, that's uh, the,
the decision you made and you've pointed
out some very cool word origins or,
uh, I should say word components
at the very least. No, his mic up,
mix up etymology and entomology,
but I'm pretty sure the etymology,
we're not talking about if we're eating
Paleo for instance, what would we,
what would a new replacement
for companion be if companion,
which if you were to look at this,
let's just say since I don't speak Latin
Spanish combined with bread, with bread,
breaking bread with someone else,
you know,
what would the paleo equivalent of that
be or matrix the fact that if you look
at Matriarch or matrimony, uh,
there, there's a mother component,
mother related, uh, the, the
decision you made. And uh,
I might be making this up,
but I don't think I am making it up.
Incision decision to cut away.
Yes.
A cutting away to decide is to
cut, to cut away incision. Correct.
So the cutting away of relationship
business, all of these things,
if, well, I shouldn't,
I shouldn't project,
but for myself to do something like that,
it's very often something
I know I need to do.
It's something that on many levels I
want to do, but I put it off for a very,
very long time. I get
close and then I, sure,
then I flinch and then
I go back to my easier,
automatic way of doing things
or the devil that I know,
the comforts that I'm afraid to
replace because of the unknown.
What led you to get to the point and
was there a certain conversation,
a certain journaling exercise,
was there?
What led you to finally make the
Drager and make the break? I,
I think you just realize that,
um,
okay.
For me, I mean, it's different
for each person. You just,
whether you're being authentic and,
and I realized I wasn't being authentic
and I had to make a break and, and, and,
um, and start a new life. And, and, um,
and so I think authenticity
is a big thing. Um,
it's hard to be authentic
and, and, uh, but it's,
and their challenges and, and, and, uh,
I was going to say risks, but I, again,
to go back,
I don't know that there are risks if you
play a game and the game is all about
creating fun and a light for
everyone around you. And, uh,
you know, this reminds me of a joke. Um,
so, uh, I don't know if
you've heard this one.
So guy walks into a bar and a,
by the way,
this is a profound philosophical
point that I'll make,
but it'll only become clear once
I tell you the joke. So, um,
this guy walks into a bar and, um, and uh,
it goes into the bar tender and orders
a drink. And the bartender looks at me,
goes, I, I haven't seen you
in the bar before. Yeah.
Uh, and the bar, the, the, the,
the customer says, well, no, I'm,
I just came to town. And the
bartender goes, oh, whoa,
what brings you town and what do
you do? And he says, I'm a gambler.
And the bartender says, really?
And, uh, and, and he says, yeah,
I, uh, I'm a Gambler, a professional
gamblers, what I do for a living.
And the bartender goes, really?
You can make a living at
that? And he says, uh, yeah,
I never lose. And the bartender
goes, oh, Kimmy, a break.
And the the gambler guy, or the customer
says, yeah, no, I've never, I don't lose.
And, um, so, uh, the bartender goes, okay,
uh, give me an example. Let
that make me a bet. And so,
uh, the customer says, uh, to the, the
bartender, look, I'm warning you, I'm a,
I'm a professional gambler.
I just warn you that I never lose.
Are you sure you want to do this? And the
bartender goes, absolutely. And he says,
okay, uh, I'll bet you $50.
Hold on. I gotta make sure I get
this bet right. I bet you $50 that
I can, um, bite my left eye.
And the bartender rolls his eyes and slams
down 50 bucks, then it goes, you're on,
you're on. And um, so,
uh, the, uh, the, the, uh,
the gambler guy out his
left eye and bites it
in his mouth and, and, and pops it
back in and the bartender is furious,
but the gambler guy says, I, I warned
you and scoops up the money. And, um,
and, and the, and the, uh, have you heard
this one before? Oh, okay. So, um, again,
the path is really funny and then I'll
make the philosophical point about life.
And, um, so, uh, the bartender
goes, okay, give me another chance.
And, and the gamma guy says, look, I,
I'm a professional. I just warn you,
I just took $50.
Are you sure you want to do this?
And the bartender goes, yeah,
give me another chance. And the,
and the gambler guy says,
okay,
I'll bet you another $50
that I can bite my other eye.
And the bartender goes,
wait a second. Okay,
I missed the fact that
that one I was glass,
but there's no way that you're blind. I
know you don't have to glass eyes. Okay,
you're bros down 50 box.
And by the way,
other patrons are now circling around
watching what's going on and egging the
bartender on.
And um,
so the gambler guy takes
out his dentures and,
and gently bites his eye, the other
eye with the, with his dentures.
And the bartender is steaming
now because he's lost two bats.
He's furious. And, uh, the
gamma guy says, I want you.
And Anyway, the Gambler guy throughout
the evening is getting drunk.
He's buying drinks for everybody.
He goes to the back of the bar. Um,
and then he comes back to
the bartender and says, look,
I'm going to make it up to you.
I'll make another bet.
And now the whole premise of the whole bar
is around him. And, um, and so he says,
I'll bet you $500 that I can stand
on this bar right here on the bar.
Uh, stand up on one leg and you
see that vodka bottle behind you.
I can pee into that bottle and not
a drop of PE will go anywhere else.
But that bottle and the
parts in the course,
there is no way that that's going
to have any, a puts down 500 bucks.
And so as the gambler guy, so
the gambler guy, and by the way,
he's pretty drunk at this point.
He can barely stand up.
He gets up at the top
of the bar, um, uh, uh,
pulls it out and pees everywhere.
But the bod cabal pees all
over the bartender and the
bartender is laughing his
head off and, and so is everyone
else, right? And, uh, and the, uh,
the guy, the Gamba guy gets
a, you know, it does this,
finish this business and gets
down off the bar and, and the,
and the bartender triumphantly
grabs the, the 500 bucks, uh,
from the, the Gamma Guy. And
he says, ah, Ha, I, uh, I, uh,
thought she never lose. And the Gamma
Guy says, uh, I didn't. He said,
what do you mean I just took $500 from
you? And he said, uh, the Gamer guy says,
yeah, but you see that table, those
guys back there, those costs guys,
I bet them $2,000 that I could stand
up on this Barn, pee all over you.
And not only would you not object,
you'd be laughing when I did it. And,
and so, so, so the interesting thing
there, tie, we'll talk about a hedged bet,
right? The, as we were talking
about hedge funds earlier,
is that the power off is a,
there's a huge payoff.
He lost. Okay. The 500.
But there was a much bigger payoff.
And in life,
if your focus is on the other person
and delighting the other person,
again, whether it's a job interview
or a relationship, a date,
or you're looking to get funding for
your startup or pee all over him and give
him $500, right? But the payout,
the universe pays you
back on the back end. And,
and, and that's a faith. So that's,
that's the gospel that I preach
is the gospel of the other. And,
and focus on the other and exclusively,
and you'll get tremendous
delight yourself and, and, uh,
and the universe has a way
of throwing you, uh, uh,
extra. Uh, okay.
So much more than you could think.
And I'll give you an example of magic.
And I said before the, the, the, uh,
it's something I stop me if I said this,
the nice secretary.
Why did I talk about getting a present
for Warren Buffet and then, and then, uh,
the, the gallery. Okay. So,
so I, I, uh, I create, uh,
a Christmas present for Warren Buffet.
I want to send it to him. Right.
And my pen pal. And, uh,
and so I created a framed
pack of Beeman's gum,
which used to sell as a child.
And so it took me the Beeman's gum for
those of you who don't know, Eh, um,
the company that made Beeman's gum went
out of business about a decade ago.
And, uh, and Warren Buffet
when he was a child,
used to sell it and,
and I tracked down on the
Internet a candy collector and,
and asked him if he had a pack of
Beeman's gum from like 50 years ago,
like, like an old ancient pack. And he
said, I might in my warehouse in Montana.
And sure enough, he found it and I said,
I'll pay any price for it. I bought it.
And then I had a calligrapher right. From
small beginnings. Anyway, I had a framed
pack of gum that I was going to
send a Warren Buffett for Christmas.
So this is December 20 20th or so.
And I'm in,
I'm in the gallery and in
Tribeca and the gallery owner.
See Your City New York City. Yes. I'm
sorry. And, um, the gallery owner says,
do you like the frame? It
just been framed. And I said,
Oh, this is so beautiful.
He's just going to love this.
[inaudible] she doesn't know who I am
and doesn't know who this is going to.
It doesn't say for anybody.
And um, and I said, oh,
how am I going to get this to
Nebraska?
And she said, what do you mean?
I said, well, if I send it FedEx,
I don't care how many times I bubble
wrap at the gum will fall off the frame.
Like it'll fall off the backing.
That's shadow box shadow box. Right.
And I thought, oh, it's going to,
it has to be couriered. And I said,
how am I going to get it there? And
she said, oh, I'll take care of that.
And I said, oh, great. You know, a
delivery service. And she said, uh,
that'll liver presently. She said, yeah,
I'll take care of it. I said, well,
what delivery service? Cause I'd like to
know, just for future reference. She said,
Oh, I'm sorry, I don't think
I'll deliver this personally.
I said, what? I squinted at her.
I said, what? She said, yeah,
I'll take care of this free of charge.
I said, excuse me, this is Nebraska,
right? It's not like going
to some fun location, like
with respect to those of
you who are from Nebraska,
I mean to get all kinds of hate mail.
Um, but for the winter it's the winner.
It's the winter. Right,
right, right, right.
Why would you want to be going
to Nebraska? And um, she said,
she looked at me and she said,
I'll do it for free.
I can see how important this is to you.
And I,
I was so stunned and I just looked
at her young woman, maybe 28,
29. And I said, um, I said, you
know, I can't let you do that.
That's the best gift anyone's ever given
me. And I'm the world's best gift giver.
And here I was like, I like,
like ya'll one up. I got one up.
And I said, uh, I said, oh my gosh, I'm
really this kind of thing I would've said.
And I said, I can't let you do
that. I, I'll pay for you to do it.
I'm not going to ruin the magic cause
there was some impulse in you that wanted
to do that, to offer that to
me and I'm going to have to,
I'll, I'll pay for the
trip. So thank you. And,
and that's an example of the magic. She
didn't know who it was going to, uh,
didn't know who I was.
She just knew it was important
to me and in the, in the,
because I was so focused on getting this
present to someone that I cared about
and she could see that she
was swept into the magic.
And that's an example of the magic that
happens when you're just focused on
someone else instead of yourself
and a boy. I was humbled by that.
I mean, wow, I'm really went up in the,
in the present giving department. Um,
so the magic of focusing on the
other, on the other, yeah. Yeah.
Well I think you're a master of,
and I didn't know the pre,
let's say we met, when did we first
meet? I'm not sure if it was 2014,
1514.
I think [inaudible] 14 through Jackson.
I didn't know the Adam pre 2014 but
you strike me as an expert in what,
another podcast guest I, Gabrielle
Reece, Gabby Reese. Sure. Going first.
She said go first. Yeah.
I asked her if she,
if she had any parting request for
the audience, she should go first.
Meaning smile first,
make eye contact first to say hi first.
You're very good at that. And
I think that's part of, uh,
eliciting the potential magic of,
of that situation. Absolutely.
When you're really
the secret to everything
to creating in the world,
whether it's creating a
relationship or creating a business,
I don't care what it is,
is you have a vision of what's possible.
Okay.
And you
convey that vision to
the potential partner,
whether it's a business or a
romantic partner of what's possible.
And,
and you get them excited about it and
you get other people excited about it if
it's a business and so on. And, um,
and so yeah,
it's about having visions,
positive visions of what's possible.
Um, you know, and this is 2017 and I'm,
I think the world is in a
very perilous place right now,
but I'm very excited
for the world because,
because this is a fulcrum
moment and by fulcrum moment,
I mean a moment when you
can achieve great results,
maximally leveraging whatever
resources you've got,
like now is the time to act.
Um,
and we get fulcrum moments in our lives
as individuals and as countries and as a
planet. And this is a fulcrum year. Um,
and we all sense it,
um, that great changes,
positive or negative. We
gotta be careful, um, and,
and, and to, to seize the fulcrum moment.
Now is the time to press hard.
Um,
and I think the world's
got to do that, um, with,
with positive visions and excite.
Again, it's all about the other,
excite everyone with a positive vision
and we can create magic in the world or
not. And then we're in trouble. Um,
I'm really excited about 2017
for myself and for the world. Um,
yeah,
before we wrap up,
I think we might,
we might have a date with a Russian
bath. In Our Future. But, uh,
before we close the conversation,
do you have any parting
requests for the audience?
Questions for the audience,
suggestions for the audience,
anything you'd like
them to take with them?
Well, that was a big one, that this
is a fulcrum a year. I'm telling you,
just intuitively,
I know for myself and I'm sure as a,
as you the listener
reflect on your life and,
and there are great opportunities.
The world is such tremendous
beauty and possibility.
It's so exciting right now. And, and,
and yet everyone's focused
on the negative and,
and instead focus on the other and,
and positive and creating magic,
uh, lean into each moment and each
encounter creating magic. And,
um, and by the way, that's a great
editing principle. Like when you're,
you're in an, you're about to
argue with a cab driver or, or,
or with your spouse or with
your best friend or whatever,
ask yourself is what you're going to say.
Create the light and the other person
or magic. And if not, don't say it.
Um,
and
well, I saw you do that last
night with a, uh, with a hostess.
At a restaurant when the restaurant was
fully booked up. It's raining outside.
We walk in and,
uh,
and in fact it wasn't we, it was just
the two of us walked in because we had,
we had another party with us waiting in
the Uber because we didn't think it'd be
possible potentially to get a table.
Right.
And I don't remember the
exact wording that you used,
but you walked up and to brand.
I remember rolling at her. Yeah.
And,
uh,
and you just walked into
the exchange opening first,
second, expecting us to get a
table. Right. And Lo and behold,
she said, I feel like your chances
are very good after, you know,
30 seconds of Adam turning on the charm.
And then I called call their whole
Party in. And a few short minutes later,
after some, a little bit of, uh, of,
of me drinking wine and all of us
drinking sparkling water, we got, uh,
arguably the best table in the house.
It was the best table in
what's the most stable now.
Yeah. And, uh, because,
okay.
I just couldn't, I really,
I, I still remember, um,
which just about creating some fun for
her and she realized we were fun people
and fun energy and damn straight.
She was going to give us a table.
Shizam yeah,
Adam.
Uh,
I always love our conversations and
many more head conversational park war.
Exactly right.
She'll park where,
which is my favorite kind of park cord
because I can't damage my knees. And uh,
is there any where you would like
people to learn more about you online or
elsewhere, website, anything else
that you'd like to mention? Well,
they can always get in touch with through
my website, Robinson global strategies.
There's a contact form there and they
want to talk about global strategy or,
or magic. Um, they can
always drop me a line and,
and uh, and I'll respond. All right,
well on that note,
I think this is a great place to,
to temporarily table this ongoing
conversation that we have.
Andy Puberty, listening,
anything that we mentioned.
If fit is linkable on the Internet,
you can find all of the resources and
whatnot@theshownoteswitheveryotherepisodeandathosecanbefoundatfourhourworkweek.com
forward slash podcast, all spelled out,
four hour work week.com forward slash,
podcast and until next time,
thank you for listening.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work week.com that's
four hour workweek.com all spelled out
and just drop in your email and
you will get the very next one.
And if you sign up,
I hope you enjoy it.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
I've used 99 designs for years for
all sorts of graphic design needs,
whether you need a logo, website,
book cover, anything else.
99 designs was created to make great
designs accessible to everyone and to make
the process of getting designs much,
much easier. So when I first started out,
for instance,
testing,
prototype covers and getting prototype
covers for the four hour body,
I want the contest drop. That is one
option. This is a great solution.
If you're looking for fast,
affordable design work and the ability
to choose from dozens of options
risk-free. Let's say you need something
late night, quick turnarounds,
well people in other time zones,
other countries can also help you
solve that problem. Since then,
I've worked with nine,
nine designs on a separate
path or a different option
and that is the one to one
project service. So in a number of
cases, and I'll give you one example,
when I wanted to create the cover
for my audio book, the Tao of Seneca,
this was a very important project to me.
I decided to use their one
to one project service.
And with this service you can invite
a specific design of your project,
agree on a and then work together
until you're satisfied me.
I need to iterate and provide feedback
and all of this stuff and I haven't
shared it yet,
but we also got some incredibly good,
really some of the best illustrations
I've ever seen from using this one to one
project service with a handful of
different designers and illustrators.
It blew my mind. 99 designs makes
this all very easy and efficient.
So you can check out the Tao of Seneca
design and other work that I and your
fellow listeners for that matter.
I've done on 99
designs@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim.
Again, that's [inaudible] 99
designs.com forward slash.
Tim this episode is brought
to you by wealth front.
Wealth Front is the future
of financial advice.
They become incredibly popular among my
friends in silicon valley and across the
country because they provide the same
high end financial advice that the best
private wealth managers deliver
it to the ultra wealthy,
but for any account size and at a
fraction of the cost. For instance,
they monitor your portfolio every day
across more than it does an asset class
classes to look for opportunities to
rebalance or harvest tax losses. Now,
would you do the same? Are you
doing the same? Probably not,
and the power's in the software.
Wealth Front now manages more
than $4 billion in assets,
which is up from around 2.5 billion.
When they started
advertising on this podcast,
they're growing incredibly quickly. Unlike
old fashioned private wealth managers.
Wealth front is powered
by innovative technology,
making it the most tax efficient,
low cost, hassle free way to invest.
They don't upload it.
Sales teams or retail locations so they
can deliver all of this sophisticated
financial advice and these services at
a fraction of the cost of a traditional
financial advisor.
So at the very least,
go to wealthfront.com forward slash Tim
and take it they're free risk assessment
survey. It only takes a couple
of minutes and Wealthfront.
We'll recommend a personalized portfolio
of investments. In other words,
they'll tell you exactly where
they would put your money.
So even if you don't use their service,
you have a huge leg up.
And do you have additional
information for making good decisions?
They use investment theory to automate
good financial behavior and decisions
that people typically don't make,
but should.
So go to wealthfront.com forward slash
Tim to get your first 15 came managed for
free, or just to get more details, check
it out. wealthfront.com forward slash tip.