Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking. No else.
You posted a question.
I'm a cybernetic organism living tissue.
This episode is brought to you by audible,
which has the largest selection
of audio books on the planet.
I've used audible for many years and I've
several audio books to recommend right
off the bat. If you're looking for a new
one ready player, one by Ernest Cline,
you may have heard of it.
The Tao of Seneca by Seneca.
If you want to hear my favorite collection
of letters of all time as well as the
graveyard book by Neil Gaiman,
which is a fiction book I
use to reintroduce nonfiction
purists to the beauty
and truth and enjoyment,
affection, the graveyard book.
It is incredible and I like the
version that Neil reads himself,
but the entire ensemble cast is also fun.
Audible members get a credit every month,
good for any audio book in the store,
regardless of price and unused
credits roll over to the next month.
So if you didn't like your audio
book, no problem. You can exchange it,
no questions asked. Plus your books
are yours to keep with audible.
You can go back and relisten anytime,
even if you cancel your membership
and for some books, again,
graveyard book by Neil Gaiman,
I've listened to many, many times.
She may even just start over as soon
as you finish it the first time.
Audible also helps you to listen to more
books by letting you switch seamlessly
between devices.
Picking up exactly where you left off,
whether it's on your phone,
through your car from a tablet or
at home on an Amazon Echo, whatever.
You can get through tons of books, hands
and free while doing almost anything.
So that is part of the beauty of audio.
It is a secondary activity when
you're walking the dog cooking,
whatever it might be.
Audible content includes an
unmatched selection of audiobooks,
original audio shows, news, comedy,
and much more from leading audio book
publishers, Broadcasters, Entertainers,
magazine and newspaper publishers
and business information providers.
Maybe that's what I am,
a business information provider and right
now audible is offering listeners of
this podcast a free audiobook with a
30 day trial memberships. Check it out.
Go to audible.com forward slash Tim and
browse the unmatched selection of audio
programs. Download a title free and
start listening. It is super simple.
Go to audible.com forward slash Tim or
text Tim to 500 500 on your telephone to
get started today.
Check it out.
This episode is brought to you by ink.
Tell and I've used them personally ever
since I wrote the four hour workweek.
I've been asked over and over again
how I choose to delegate tasks,
how I do 80 20 analysis and so on.
At the root of many of those decisions
is a simple question. Actually.
Two questions. Number one,
how can I invest money to
improve my quality of life?
I use that in investing as well.
The second,
how can I spend a little money or moderate
money to save significant time inc
tell is one of those investments.
There are a turnkey solution for all
of your imaginable customer care needs.
I used ink tell during the launch of
the four hour body, which was very,
very involved and they provided 24
seven customer service for my land rush
campaign because it was critical for
me to take care of every person who
purchased my books and participated.
This allowed me to focus on the things
that I am better at, my strengths,
like the marketing plan that
we'd worked on for six months,
implementing that until
trains their experience.
Customer service reps to
know your business and your
products inside and out and
make your customers are raving fans.
They answer more than a million customer
service requests every year and they
can do so across all platforms including
email, phone, social media, texts,
even chat,
leaving your customers with poor
service or just mediocre service,
which by the way,
in a competitive pool is a huge liability.
Long wait times are unanswered messages
carries a massive cost and risk to your
business.
Ink Tell removes the logistics and
headaches of this type of communication,
allowing you to focus on your
strengths and grow your business.
It can be a real competitive advantage.
And I see many,
many ecommerce companies
and tech companies thinking
of customer service as a
good enough checkbox or an afterthought
and just like airbnb use design and
innovative ways to be a
competitor and to win that,
you can do the same thing
with customer service.
So as a listener of this podcast,
you can get up to $10,000 off.
That's a big discount.
$10,000 off of your startup fees and
costs by visiting intel.com forward slash
Tim. So check it out.
For more info, go to ink,
tell.com I n k a t e
l.com forward slash Tim.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job to deconstruct world class
performers, to tease out the habits,
routines, et Cetera, that
you can use in your life.
And this episode is a four or five
for the price of one which is free,
but four or five for the price of one
because my guest is none other than Doris
Kearns Goodwin who can be
found at Doris Kearns Goodwin.
That's k e a r n s Doris Kearns,
goodwin.com also on Facebook
and on Twitter at Doris K.
Goodwin. Who's Doris? Well, let me
begin with some background doors.
His interest in leadership began more
than a half century ago as a professor at
Harvard.
Her experiences working for Lbj in the
White House and later assisting him on
his memoirs led to Lyndon
Johnson and the American dream.
She followed that up with the Pulitzer
prize winning, no ordinary time,
subtitle Franklin and Eleanor and
the home front in World War II.
She then earned the Lincoln prize for
the runaway bestseller team of rivals.
For those of you who don't
recognize that book title,
you might recognize it as the basis for
Steven Spielberg's award winning film,
Lincoln, and she then won the
Carnegie metal for the bully pulpit,
the chronicle of the Friendship Between
Theater Roosevelt and William Howard
Taft.
Her newest book is leadership
in turbulent times,
and I love this book because it goes all
the way back to the very beginning and
looks at how the four presidents
she studied most closely,
Abraham Lincoln Theater,
Roosevelt, Fdr, and Lbj,
how they found their footing goes all
the way back to their first entries into
public life.
And we encounter them at a time when
their paths were filled with confusion,
uncertainty, fear, and hope.
How did they establish
themselves as leaders?
What did other people recognize in them?
But also how did they manage
their lives day to day?
How did they get to sleep?
Where there any tricks that they used?
Any social conventions or rituals that
they use to maintain composure in the
hardest of times? We dig into
all of that, and as such,
we get all sorts of tidbits and
life lessons from not just Doris,
we do talk about her life as well,
but these presidents,
she has studied so in depth.
And with that,
I had a blast with this episode
and let's just get right to it.
Without further ado,
please enjoy this wide ranging
conversation with Doris Kearns Goodwin.
Doris, welcome to the show.
Glad to be with you, Tim.
I have been looking forward to this
conversation and also very intimidated by
this conversation in my prep
and in doing all of my homework.
So I'm going to apologize in advanced
to you and my listeners if I embarrass
myself with my lack of domain expertise
as we get into many different things.
Uh, but I thought we could start with
something that does not intimidate me.
And that is some of your very
early childhood experiences.
I had read in the course
of doing preparation for
this conversation that your
father was an optimist and his optimism
was perhaps the greatest or one of the
greatest gifts that he gave you.
Could you perhaps just set the,
set the scene and explain some of the
circumstances and then also what that
meant, uh, to, uh, to
instill optimism in you?
No, I do indeed feel like it was the
greatest gift he could have given me.
He had a very difficult life,
which I learned about of course
when I was a little girl,
but never having met his
parents or grandparents.
Grandparents had come over from Ireland
and then my father was orphaned when he
was 10 years old.
His little brother was hit by a
trolley car when my father was 10.
The little boy was six.
His mother was pregnant,
he had a two year old sister
and the little boy died.
Finally from the trolley accident,
his mother had a child, died,
another child and um,
his sister and he were then put out to
other people after his mother died in
childbirth, his father committed
suicide. We learned this all later.
So here's this man, Michael Francis
Aloysius Carnes, 10 years old,
goes to work very early, eventually
becomes a bank examiner in New York state,
was great with numbers, something
that he did not give me as a gift,
but most importantly he somehow,
if you saw that man,
you would never know that sadness
that he had in his childhood.
He had a twinkle in his eye.
He loved life.
He gave me that optimistic spirit
telling me if you like people,
people will like you in turn.
And I,
it's been the way my life
has been led since then.
And like it's hard to
imagine what better gift.
There's confidence that I think you'd
get from your family and I think I got
that too.
But the ability to just get
through adversities with
resilience and to have that
hopeful feeling that things are
going to turn out all right.
Even though sometimes they don't,
you think they will again,
it's sustained me through my whole life.
Are there any particular examples that
you can think of or just approaches that
you remember your father taking to
coach you through difficult times or
difficult experiences when you were
perhaps not at the peak of confidence when
you were suffering hardships?
What approach would he
have taken or did he take?
Well, I think, you know,
in small and large ways.
I remember once I was in a concert
at school and, um, I was sitting,
we were singing old man
river and by mistake I,
instead of saying set of
singing old man river,
instead of saying he's tired
of living and scared of dying,
I said he's tired of dying
and scared of living.
And I was so embarrassed and
after I came out and said,
that was much deeper what you said,
he's tired.
Is that incredibly, I felt great and we
went and had some ice cream, you know.
And then of course,
because I was such a huge baseball fan,
I had to get through the failure of
the Dodgers year after year after year,
the Brooklyn Dodgers. And again, he
just said it will happen some year.
And he made me feel that wait
til next year will happen.
But probably more importantly, my mother
had had rheumatic fever as a child.
So she had a damaged heart and really
was an invalid for most of my childhood.
And so he saw what I had to go through
and what he had to go through where she
was not well. She had several
small heart attacks and again,
he just got her through it.
Got me through it and it all
sounds so sad what I'm saying,
but my childhood bizarrely was not sad
and I think it had a lot to do with him.
You also mentioned,
and part of the reason for
people listening that I'm
asking these questions and
I'm so interested in you as a person,
is that you are such a keen observer
and that's reflected in your writing.
Certainly reflected in your
speaking as well that I'm,
I'm interested in the formation of
your character strengths and so on.
Baseball. Uh, you mentioned baseball,
I don't know much about your
background with baseball,
but is it true and I can't believe
everything I read on the Internet, so I,
I certainly stand to be fat corrected
anytime that you were the first woman to
be invited into the red sox locker room.
Is that true?
Well, I don't know about the
first woman to be invited in,
but I was the first journalist
to be for sure enlist.
I happened to be at spring training on
the day that the order came down from the
courts saying that women journalists have
to be allowed into the locker room to
be able to do their job.
So the owners of the red sox said go in.
So it happened that I was the first person
to go in and it actually is a trivial
pursuit question and the New England
trivial percent yet. So it's a,
it's a great pride to have done it.
It wasn't that exciting to be honest.
I didn't see lots of guys in matters
of undress cause they, but they were,
I was there and I didn't
even have to interview them.
I just had to say I was there.
I'm okay.
Have you always been a s as
long as you can remember a,
an Aficionado of baseball?
How did that develop?
I think in so many ways. Um, my love of
history came from my love of baseball.
My father had grown up in Brooklyn and
then move to long island just before I
was born, but still love the Brooklyn
Dodgers. So when I was only five,
six years old,
he taught me that mysterious art of
keeping score while listening to baseball
games so that I could record for
him like on a summer afternoon.
The history of that afternoon
was Brooklyn dodger game.
And then he would come home from work
on the long I train at night and I would
recount for him with all my miniaturized
symbols, the K for a strikeout,
getting the guy around the bases.
Um,
I could tell him every play of every
inning of the game that had taken place.
And he made me feel, I was telling him
a fabulous story. So it makes you think,
even as a little girl,
there's something magic about history
to keep your father's attention for so
long.
In fact,
I'm convinced I learned the narrative
arts on those nightly sessions with my dad
because at first I'd be so excited
before I went into the sewage rendition,
I would say the Dodgers water,
the Dodgers lost,
which took the drama of
this two hour telling away.
So I finally learned you had to tell a
story from beginning to middle to end.
He made it even more special
for me when I was six.
He never told me then that all of this
was actually described in great detail in
the sports pages of the newspapers.
The next day I thought without me,
he wouldn't even know what
happened in the Brooklyn Dodgers.
So it really did I think teach me
the importance of telling a story.
In fact, much later I read an essay by my
heroine, Barbara Tuchman, and she said,
even if you're writing about a
war is a narrative historian.
You have to imagine to yourself,
you do not know how that war ended.
So you can carry your reader with you
every step along the way from beginning to
middle to end, not being an all knowing
person that says, oh, they won this war.
What's the drama if you
will already know that?
So I learned that just trying to keep my
father's attention and telling him the
story step by step of what
happened to the Dodgers that day.
For those who don't know,
who is Barbara Tuchman?
Barbara Tuchman is a female historian
and I only mentioned female.
His store in question is a very important
early female Pulitzer Prize winning
historian.
And I read a book that she wrote guns of
August when I was in college and it was
so beautifully written,
but more importantly for me,
she was writing about battles and
military stuff and things that you don't
imagine that sometimes a woman might
be so adept at. But more importantly,
she was just a beautiful storyteller
and writer. So as I, I met her later,
but she became a mentor in my imagination
I think when I was in college.
No, the point at which
history enters the scene, uh,
as such labeled as such,
even if baseball and your f
your experiences with your
father perhaps introduced
you to crafting this narrative arc.
Did that start in high school?
I had read,
I don't know if that's true or not,
but I had read that you had a fantastic
history teacher in high school who I
think won an award for best
history teacher in New York
state or something along
those lines.
Was,
was that a very influential period for
you and when you were specifically in
that class or were there, did history
somehow enter the picture prior to that?
Well,
I think beyond baseball,
the other experience that led me to
love stories from the past is because my
mother had had rheumatic fever
and had this damaged heart.
I love to listen to her tell
stories. I kept saying to her, mom,
tell me stories about new when
you were a young girl like me.
I somehow thought if I could keep her mind
talking about days when she was young,
before her illness said in that her
mind would control her body and this
premature aging process we were
witnessing would be stopped in his tracks.
So I was constantly saying, mom, tell me
a story about you when you were my age,
not realizing how peculiar that was until
my own three sons never once said to
me, mom, tell us a story about you when
you're our age. But I think it, again,
it instilled in me the idea
that stories from the past can,
can bring people who are different
alive when they were younger.
And then of course when I ended
up studying dead presidents,
trying to bring them to life.
So these two routes,
I think of my father's love of baseball
and my wish that my mother could be
younger and I could imagine her running
up the steps two at a time led to my
interest in the past.
But then I think when I got to high
school and wonderful high school in Long
Island, south side, senior high
school, his teacher, Ms. Austin,
who was the head of the social
studies department, she made you feel,
when she was telling,
I remember about FDR death as if
she were experiencing it. You know,
her eyes filled up and she did indeed
win an award as the best history teacher
in New York state.
So all of us benefited by having
that chance to see his become alive.
I love history so much now and I just
wish that every kid in school would have a
teacher with that kind of passion
because whenever I hear kids say, oh,
it's boring, it's just a bunch of
facts. And I keep thinking, no,
it's about people who lived before
they had drama in their lives. They,
they went through tough times.
Our country went through tough times
and the more you can learn from that
perspective, just like learning
from your parents or grandparents,
you're learning some generations ago,
and if I could just have a Ms.
Austin in every school in America,
that would be my dream.
When did you decide that you
wanted to explore biography as a,
as a, I suppose you're, you're
one of your many explorations of,
of literature and, uh, as a writer, when,
when did that first come onto your radar?
Or did you first think of it?
No, I think we're biography came
from was Lyndon Johnson. Um,
when I was in graduate
school and in college,
I was really interested in the Supreme
Court and thought I might actually go to
law school rather than graduate school.
Um,
but I did end up going to graduate school
and I had a great teacher at Harvard
Graduate School who taught the
history of the Supreme Court.
So my phd thesis was,
was on Supreme Court.
So I might've been studying these guys
in their robes rather than my dead
presidents were it not for the fact
that I got a White House Fellowship and
wonderful program that still exists today,
which takes people from 23 to 48 or 50
perhaps and brings them to Washington for
a year,
hoping that you'll get a sense of,
of the government and then go back
to your private life. You know,
having been enriched by that experience.
And I was at the young end,
I was only 24 when I was chosen and
ended up in a peculiar way working for
Lyndon Johnson and then helping him on
his memoirs the last years of his life.
And then writing my first
book on Lyndon Johnson.
So that's what set me
into presidential history.
That's what sent me into biography.
That random experience,
I mean chance plays a role in
so much of our lives. I think
I in the course of prepping
for this read that,
uh,
you had some doubts about
whether you would remain,
uh, in the White House. I, and I'm
paraphrasing here and pulling from memory,
which isn't always my strong suit because
you had written an anti war peace,
uh,
and that I guess at the time the president
decided to keep you around and that
if he couldn't convert you,
nobody.
Could I end up just wondering a,
if you could flesh that out a little bit
and be why he would make that type of
decision?
Yes. What happened is when we were
chosen as White House fellows,
there was a big dance at the White House
and he did dance with me that night.
Not that peculiar. There were only three
women out of the 16 White House fellows.
But as he twirled me around the floor,
he whispered that he wanted me
to be assigned directly to him.
But it was not to be that simple for in
the months prior to my selection as a
White House fellow,
like many young people,
I was active in the Anti Vietnam War
movement and had written an article with a
friend of mine that we had sent to the
new republic weeks before and had not
heard anything back on the need for a
third party candidate to challenge Lyndon
Johnson.
So it came out with the title two days
after the dance and the White House,
how to remove Lyndon Johnson from power.
Oh my God.
I was certain he would kick me
out of the program, or even worse,
he might destroy the entire program,
but instead, surprisingly, he said, oh,
bring her down here for a year and
if I can't win her over, no one can.
So I was not assigned directly
to him in the White House though.
I think I was too incendiary for that.
So I was assigned to the Labor
Department under, well Edwards,
who was a wonderful mentor.
And then Johnson withdrew from the race
in March of 1968 and right after he
withdrew from the race, he called me
the White House and he said, well,
you said I should be removed from office.
I've now removed myself.
Now you have to work for me the
rest of the time. And so I did.
I went to the White House.
And then as I say,
he asked me when the White
House fellowship and the
year working for him came to
an end to help accompany him part time
to his ranch to help him on his memoirs.
He wanted me to come full time,
but I knew enough about Lyndon Johnson
then that if you were completely in his
way, um, it was really hard to,
to keep your own sense of balance.
So I asked him if I could just go part
time and go back to Harvard to start
teaching, which is what I wanted to do.
And at first he said no all or nothing,
all or nothing.
So then the last day when he was in the
White House and he was going to leave,
the next day, he called me
back and just said, okay, it's
all right. Come part time.
And then he just got to
me, he said, you know,
it's not so easy when you're not in power
in the same way to get what you want.
I won't forget that you're doing this,
but just don't let those,
Harvard's poison your feeling about me.
So that was the extraordinary experience.
I stayed at the ranch much of the time
I was there, got to know lady bird,
got to know him very well, and, and
felt a great deal of empathy for him,
even though he never changed
my mind about the war.
I did see extraordinary success that
he had had in the great society and in
civil rights.
And I saw him struggle with how he would
be remembered in those last days and
last last years of his life.
So it was a very emotional experience
led to my first book, Lyndon Johnson.
And then from there I became
a presidential that story.
And somehow it wasn't that
I set out to become one.
What an incredible opportunity. I wonder,
and this is, I'll just ask you if,
if it's in an alternate universe,
I were able to ask him
directly why he asked you, uh,
to help him. What do you think
he would say? I mean, he,
he could have reached out to any
number of people. What did he,
what did he see in you or how would he
answer that question, do you think? Well,
he had a number of other people that
were working on the memoirs with him,
but I think to some extent,
because I was young and he knew that the
audience he wanted to reach where those
young people, because he felt
that they hadn't understood him,
even though he liked to believe
he had done so much for them,
which he had except for this, except for
this huge thing in the Vietnam war. Um,
he,
I was a woman,
so maybe it was easier to be
able to talk to me as a woman.
Um, and he knew that I loved listening to
stories and he was a great storyteller.
I mean fabulous, colorful,
anecdotal stories.
There was a problem where these stories,
I later discovered that
half of them weren't true,
but I loved listening on the less so I
think part of my attraction for him was
that I love listening to his tall tales.
Um,
there was also a moment when I worried
that part of the reason he had me there
was because I was a young woman, um,
because and but everything was perfect.
I kept talking to them
about steady boyfriends even
when I had no boyfriends at
all until one day he decided
to have a discussion.
He said about our relationship,
which sounded ominous when he
took me nearby to the lake,
conveniently called Lake
Lyndon Baines Johnson.
There's wine and cheese and a rent check,
tape table course,
all the romantic trappings
and he starts out Doris,
more than any other woman I have ever
known in, my heart sank. And then he said,
you remind me of my mother.
It was pretty classic and what was
going on in my mind. But nonetheless,
I was there when we used
to walk on the ranch.
I talk about this actually in the
epilogue of my new book because I tried to
bring all four of my guys,
Lincoln,
Teddy Franklin and Lbj to the whole
question of how they want it to be
remembered over time.
So I described a lot of the scenes of
walking with him every day where he,
his mind was just going back over the
happier parts of his life and also the
sadness of knowing that hopefully the,
or the sadness of knowing that the
Vietnam War had cut his legacy into,
but hoping that what he
did on civil rights would
receive some sort of bounty in
the time to come.
And it certainly did and it has,
but he died before knowing that for sure.
When you mentioned earlier, and
uh, I'm, I'm paraphrasing here,
but the referring to your decision
or your priority of doing,
uh, working with him part time, you said
something along the lines of when you,
when you were fully in his sway, it was
hard to maintain balance. So I decided to,
or asked for part time, uh,
what does that mean? Uh, if,
if you could elaborate on that,
on that,
you know, I think what it means is that
he was so powerful that you had a feeling
sometimes that, um, you
couldn't get away from him.
He wanted me to be there every moment.
I mean, even when he took a nap,
he would want me to be sitting in a chair
right outside the closet just in case
something happened to him or
just not wanting to be alone.
And this was a man who
needed company and you know,
I felt in some ways like a 24 years
old, am I going to be able to, you know,
to say, no, I want to go to the
movies tonight or I want to,
I just need some time or I want to read.
Um,
even though it was an extraordinary
thing to be in his presence,
I remember one time in particular,
you're just sparked this memory,
which I haven't thought about.
When he would have visitors to the ranch,
he would take them in his car and
show them the jumping antelope,
bluebonnets all he did narrate the
whole beauty of the ranch to them.
And when I was first working down there,
I'd be in the front of the car with him.
It could be an important person in
the back, like Dean Rusk or something.
And he'd say to me, look, doors,
look at the jumping antelopes but then
I remember one weekend I didn't go to
visit him at the ranch. Um, and I
think he was mad that I hadn't gone,
cause I'd stayed,
stayed at Harvard.
So the next time I was down I was in
the back of the car and he's saying to
whoever's in the front of the
car, look, look at the jumping in.
I felt like I was in Siberia,
is the matter with me.
I don't even want to be in this car.
I've seen these jumping in
a lot of the thousand times.
That was one of the Times I think I knew
that a small thing could be transferred
into an arc of power.
And at least at enough sense to think as
long as I've got myself back at Harvard
and I can come on weekends,
I can come vacations.
It really was perfect and I also
want it to be back teaching.
That's what I've been comparing. Four I
got my phd and I couldn't wait to teach,
so it was a balance I think between
the two, but it worked out really well.
Why couldn't you wait to teach?
I think I always talked or since I was
a little person telling stories and I,
I knew that if I could teach
now the kids at Harvard,
it was later than getting them in
high school or elementary school,
but at least then if I could make them
love history just as I had that I would
be doing something meaningful because I
thought in passing on that passion and
there could be one or two or three or
five kids in the class that might end up
really loving history.
Even if they didn't go into it
maybe for the rest of their lives,
they'd be reading history as they're
an avocation, not their vocation,
that I would do something that mattered
to me. So, and I really loved teaching.
I mean,
I only stopped teaching when I got
married and had my kids and couldn't teach
and write and be with the kids at the
same time. And it was scary. I mean, to,
to think of myself as suddenly becoming
a writer when I was much more sure of my
ability to teach. So I
left, I left Harvard,
I had two kids immediately
after I was married, my husband,
and I've already had a son from his
first marriage, his first wife had died.
So all of a sudden I have three boys and
I was finding myself hardly able to get
through the day, much less get anything
done. So I had to make a choice.
Will I continue teaching or
will I try and be a writer?
And so I had,
luckily by that time finished the first
book on Lyndon Johnson and was going to
be working on my next
book and had a contract,
but even then it took me 10 years to
finish the next book and I remember being
at a cocktail party in Cambridge at
one point where somebody said whatever
happened to Doris Kearns anyway,
did she die?
I wanted to hit the person is they had
three boys. That's what's happened to me.
It was able to,
I was able to balance.
I think being a writer better with
having the kids then I could if,
if I were teaching and
writing and having the kids,
but every now and then when I lecture
and it's a 45 minute lecture or 50 minute
lecture, I think yes, this
is what it used to be like
45 minutes is a,
it's a nice self encapsulated,
a beginning, middle and end compared
to perhaps 10 years. How did,
were there times when you didn't see
the light at the end of the tunnel or
weren't sure if you were going to finish
and did you have any self moments of
self doubt over that 10 year span? I
mean that's a lot to long period of time.
Well,
in fact each of my books and taken such
a long period of time that there are
certainly moments where you just think,
what am I doing?
I mean the book about Franklin and Eleanor
and World War II took longer to write.
Then it took the war to be fought,
which is really embarrassing.
And the book on Teddy and Taft took
seven years and the book on Lincoln took
nearly 10 years.
The reason is not as scary as it might
sound is that I always sort of have an
outline of knowing what I
want to do before I start.
It's sort of the lay person's,
I don't know that much about the person,
so I want to know what do
people want to know about them.
I'm not that much of an expert on the
person when I start and then I start
building the book usually chronologically,
if not from their childhood,
wherever I'm starting.
So chapters get done,
so it's not like I spend five years
researching and then start writing again.
Barbara Tuchman,
my heroines said,
you've got to start writing as soon as
you can because otherwise you'll really
feel this massive material is,
is unable to be worked on.
So yes, sure there were
times, but on the other hand,
it meant that I could have my own hours.
I,
my husband's was a rider
and we both wrote at home.
I didn't have to travel anywhere
to go and do what I was doing.
I didn't have faculty meetings at night.
I could be with the kids and I
could go to the little league games.
And I really appreciated that I was
now in a profession that allowed me to
balance as much as I could, even if
it meant I wouldn't produce 40 bucks.
I sometimes think,
what if I had been a man living in another
time and I wasn't involved with the
kids. I mean, it's a sad
thing to think about.
Maybe I would have produced more books,
but I would never tried it.
Oh, I think, I think you're
doing spectacular. I have, uh,
as I was mentioning earlier,
uh,
such an incredible level of
respect for the work you've done.
It's, it's very intimidating.
Uh, uh, on some level,
I'm not sure it's intimidating,
but it's fat.
Yeah, no, for, it's
teasing me who read the bully pulpit in,
which was very long book actually.
I mean,
900 pages that she was reading it at
night in bed and she fell asleep and it
broke her nose.
My new book is shorter than any of
those calls is going to be broken.
Well, let's, let's talk about
some of your guys and, uh,
per perhaps we could,
we're going to bounce around quite a bit
and we can take this and just about any
direction. But, uh, I,
I'd love to perhaps start with a
question about Lincoln and I've read that
you've said what's perhaps most
striking about Lincoln was emotional
intelligence
and temperament. Uh, can you, can you,
can you explain what you mean by that?
Absolutely. I mean, I think when
we look at the quality of empathy,
which I think isn't a critical
quality for any leader,
I think for some people it's inborn.
Others can develop it over time,
but for Lincoln,
even as a child,
when his friends would be putting hot
coals on turtles to watch them wriggle,
he would stop them and say, this
isn't right. We can't do this.
Or there are times when he found somebody
drunk in a pit hole and everybody was
walking by the person and he ended up
going back and picking that person up and
bringing him,
carrying him to a home.
And you can see that in him as a
child, but it's more than that. I just,
I felt that living in his presence
that I could become a better person.
I don't always think that I,
I have great respect for the
people that I've written about,
but there was something about Lincoln's,
and even forgetting how it made
him a great leader, which it did,
he just refused to let resentments faster.
He refused to let himself get
jealous of people. I mean,
it wasn't that he didn't have the normal
human emotions of jealousy or envy or
anger, but he said, if you allow
those to fester, they will poison you.
So there would be times when,
you know,
I might be jealous or something
or envious of something.
And I just remember I'd say Lincoln would
tell me, this isn't doing you any good.
You have to stop. I mean, there's
this extraordinary story of,
of Stanton who becomes his war secretary
and they had met when they were in the,
um, in the law practice together. And
the 1850 Stanton lived in Cincinnati.
Lincoln of course, is in
Springfield, Illinois.
But Stanton had a very national reputation
and had a big case to be tried in
Chicago. So the thought they needed
someone of council in Illinois,
his partner came and looked at
Lincoln saw he'd be finally getting,
it was so excited at the thought of
working with this extraordinary lawyers,
Stanton.
But at the last minute,
the case got transferred
from Illinois to Cincinnati.
So they didn't need Lincoln anymore,
but they forgot to tell him.
So he kept working on his brief.
He went to Cincinnati all on his own.
He met up with Stanton and
Stanton's partner on the
street corner and he said in
his typically gregarious way, let's go
up to the courthouse together and again,
stat and took one. Look at Lincoln.
He had a huge stain on his shirt.
His hair was disheveled,
his arm sleeves are too short
for his long arms and legs.
And he turned to his partner and the
partner said this later and said,
we have to lose this long
armed ape. It's awful, right?
And linkedin was humiliated
and they didn't open the brief.
He had painstakingly prepared.
But the amazing thing is he stayed and
watched the entire trial for a week
because he could see that there was some
brilliance and Stan and he wanted to
learn from him. And he went back to
Springfield, Illinois. And he said,
I still have to learn how
to become a better lawyer.
So he would stay up later at night.
He'd get up early in the morning.
He taught himself Euclid when he was
on the, on the on circuit in Illinois,
but most much more amazing life.
So after his first secretary
of war has had to resign,
everybody comes to him and said,
the only person that can mobilize the
north and mobilize the war department is
Edwin Stanton. He's tough. He can be a
bully at times. He can be insensitive,
but he's your God.
And Somehow Lincoln was able to put that
past hurt behind him and give Stanton
that most incredibly important job.
And in Kane came out eventually loving
Lincoln more than anyone outside his
family.
Now that's a story that just,
it tells everything you want
to know about him. He said,
I don't care if somebody disliked
me or like me in the past,
if somebody's been guilty of
ill treatment or abusive me,
if they're right at
this time in this place,
they're the right person for the time.
I trust that I'll be able to bring
out the best in them. And he did.
It's really incredible to hear these
types of stories and I think that it's
worth digging into perhaps
some more examples,
and I'd love to get your definition
or how you think about temperament.
Uh, because I've, I've,
I've read you describing temperament as
the greatest separator in presidential
leadership and maybe we could scratch
the presidential from that phrase.
I don't know. Uh, but I, and I
think it was, let me get this right.
Oliver Wendell Holmes Jr who said,
uh, about FDR, right? A psyche,
he has a second class intellect about a
first class temperament. What does that,
what does that mean to you?
I think what temporary means really is
your basic stance toward people toward
the world. Um, does it,
if you have the kind of temperament
that's got a certain base of confidence in
it so that you can surround yourself
with people who can argue with you and
question your assumptions,
do you have a temperament that allows
you to share credit when something goes
well, to take the blame when
something goes badly? Um,
do you bring out the best in other people?
Do you make them want to work because
you have a common sense of mission?
All of these are the basic way
you treat other people. I mean,
I suppose it is encompassed
in emotional intelligence,
but I think you're born
with a certain temperament,
but you also can develop a
certain temperament over time.
And I do think Oliver
Wendell Holmes was right.
I don't think it was right that
FDR had a second rate intellect.
I think that's defining
intellect by academic excellence.
And he was a mediocre student at,
at Harvard and a mediocre
student at Columbia Law School.
But he had an incredible
problem solving mind.
And he had the ability to
bring people around him,
experts in all the academic fields.
And these start out these evenings,
these brain trust evenings where they
just relax and tell funny stories and have
a couple drinks.
And then he would start questioning them.
And he was an incredible question or,
and he could bring out,
it was almost as if he was
excavating their brain.
And whenever he heard by verbal thing,
he could remember.
People remember in very different ways.
I mean, Lincoln remembered when he read,
he had an extraordinary memory that if
you read something over and over again,
it would stick in his brain like a
poem or a piece of Shakespeare's drama.
FDR learned by listening to other people.
And once he had the story in his own mind,
he could then tell it to somebody else.
So that,
and that's intelligence is
of a different sword I think.
Then just doing well on a series of
exams when you're in school. Okay.
If we're looking at say attributes
versus skills that are developed,
are the nature versus nurture
aspect of some of these abilities,
uh, or the temperament as you
mentioned. If we look at say,
and I think I'm getting this
right, uh, the Lincoln quote,
I either your opponent's Today,
maybe your allies tomorrow, what's,
was he always that way or
is that something that he
developed over time and became better at?
No, I think he did develop it over
time. In fact, I think most of these,
there are attributes that may be in born
that are perhaps like intelligence or
maybe even people's skills. Um,
empathy as I say, maybe in born. Um,
but the ability to
communicate in some ways,
but you can develop all
of these as time goes on.
And I think that's the important
thing for leaders to understand.
But in his case, I think,
um, when he was younger,
he had an extraordinary sense of humor
and he could really take down an opponent
by making fun of him.
And,
and he did that on a couple occasions
and there was one time when at the
audience loved what he was doing
and making fun of the opponent.
And then he saw the
opponent Ponant leaving,
leaving the audience and with tears in
his eyes. And he just said to himself,
this isn't worth it.
This is not the way you do it.
So he learned from the experience of
feeling guilt at taking down an opponent
that way, that if it were possible
to bring him on your side eventually.
I mean, obviously when he's
in the middle of the war,
the confederates are his opponents.
But even there,
when you look at that second inaugural,
what is he doing in that second
inaugural weeks before he dies,
but saying both sides,
you know both sides read the same Bible,
both prayed to the same God.
Neither his prayers were fully answered
where he's acknowledging that the North
had had problems with slavery,
justice the South had and then with
malice toward non in charity for all,
let us bind up the nation's wounds.
That's the the the words that say it,
but what really says it was that night
when he's elected president in 1860 he
knows he's had least much less
experience than any of us three rivals.
They were more celebrated, more educated
ones, but they'd been governors.
They'd been senators, Seward, chase and
Bates and he realizes I need their help.
The country is in peril.
These are the strongest and most able men
in the country. I need them by my side.
He brings them into the top
three positions in his cabinet.
Some of his friends say,
why are you doing this?
You're going to look like a figure head
having these strong people around you.
And he said,
I need them and I'll be fine.
And at the beginning some of them thought
they were more important than he was
sued.
In particular,
his secretary of state thought he was
running the show and that Lincoln would be
like a figurehead, but then at a certain
point like, and saw what sword was doing.
He knew he needed him, but he
put him in his place. He said,
I am the president and I will do this.
And they too became great friends and
Seward ended up admiring him more than
anybody else.
So I think he had an internal confidence
that he could bring these opponents
into as myths, but it wasn't easy. It
meant holding hands with a lot of them.
It meant having to chew them out.
When they started bringing their anger
toward each other out in public and, and,
and he had to keep going at it.
It's much harder than if you have the
same people around you who are all in the
same direction. You may not have as
many arguments and as many troubles,
but he was able to contain those
factions within his cabinet.
And then he was containing it in the
country at large because they each
represented a certain segment
of the population, whether
it's radical, moderate,
or conservative.
So it's an extraordinary way to do it.
But the interesting thing is, you know,
when I've talked to business leaders,
a lot of them said they were able to,
maybe, maybe not in that extreme way,
having those kind of rivals with you,
but to understand the importance of
bringing people near you who really can
argue and question your assumptions.
There's, there's a moment,
the same thing with FDR.
He's in a room with a bunch of generals
early before the ward even started the
Second World War.
And he's describing some pet project
that he loved and all of them are shaking
their heads and said, well,
that's wonderful. And he
looks over at George Marshall,
who eventually of course,
becomes the chief of staff.
And he says, George, you're,
you're not shaking your head. What do you
think? And he said, well, Mr President,
I don't agree with you at all.
And the room came to a silence and
everybody laughed and then thought,
well that's it for George Marshall.
And then he appointed him not long after
bringing him up like 14 names on the
list are more to be the head because he
wanted that kind of person around him.
So it's that strength. I think that inner
confidence that allows you to do that.
That's a critical question
in all leadership capacities.
Did you have any people you
surround yourself with who
you know will speak truth
to you or who have wildly divergent
opinions or political perspectives?
Is that something that you have
practically built into your life?
Or did you just have people already
who surrounding you who offer those
opportunities to hear dissenting opinions?
You know, it's, it's a really important
question. I mean, I think in my work,
so I've had a woman who's been my research
assistant for the last 35 years and
she's still working for
me. Beth, who's my manager,
my best friend, my partner in a
lot of things that we do together,
um, lives in California, has worked with
me for the last 18 years and I trust her,
I think more than almost anybody to tell
me when something I've done is not up
to par when something I've written
is not as good as it should be. Um,
and when, um, when maybe I'm, I'm
moving in some different direction.
And then my husband and I have a best
friend named Michael Rothschild who was a
writer and a sculpture and lives in Maine
and he has worked with both my husband
and me and we've worked within
on everything we write together,
everything we do together.
And he's absolutely,
I'm honest about this sentence isn't any
good or this year not making this clear.
So that's built in in a certain sense.
I'm not sure that I did it on the purpose,
but they, they are the kind
of people, Beth and Michael
and my husband, of course,
my husband read every single thing
I've written and not only edited them,
but would tell me when,
when I was going off in a
direction that really wasn't right.
I remember when I was working
on the book on the Kennedys,
and I'd always been interested in
medical history because the, um,
my sisters were both nurses and
my brother in law was a doctor.
And because of my mother's medical
history, so John Fitzgerald,
Rose Kennedy's father had gone to
Harvard Medical School for a year and I
thought, oh, this is great.
I can write a whole chapter on the state
of medicine and the 1880s, you know,
and then my husband
looks at it and he says,
but he dropped out of medical
school and he became a politician.
Why are you doing this? And Oh, I hated
to make that chapter go down to two pages,
but he was just dead.
Right.
But the other thing that happens that
bill bill's in descent is that, um, we,
we live in Concord,
Massachusetts.
And ever since the kids have been grown
and the kids are now joining us cause
they live back in the town, which
I can talk about later. But anyway,
we'd go out every night to eat at a bar,
one of this,
two or three bars in Concord that the
whole gang of us goes to one, one night,
one the other night and the next one the
next night. And in that group of people,
there are Trump supporters.
There are radical people,
there are moderate people and we
argue and talk about politics.
And I think it's really important for
me to be able to listen to goes other
sides when I'm going to be talking on
television or thinking about today as
opposed to thinking about the past.
Let's say you're having one of those group
conversations. You're at a restaurant,
slash, bar. So there may or may
not be alcohol involved. Maybe
if things get heated,
how do you or other people in the group,
are there any particular phrases you use
or interjections you use to cool things
a little bit? If they start getting to
ad Hominem or too heated is there is,
and I guess what I'm stretching for here
is if there are any tools or phrases,
approaches that people might use to create
environments where a group like that
can actually communicate and hear each
other's opinions without devolving into a
verbal fistfight.
Yeah. And obviously, you know,
all over the country right now,
it's a difficult situation where some
places you go in bars and they won't even
put the news on because they're afraid
it will rile the people and make them
unhappy. So it's, it's not been easy
discussions, not only this time,
but we've had a tribal feeling about
Democrats and Republicans for some time
through Obama to Clinton to Bush.
And I guess the best thing is as
long as you can just ask the people,
why do you feel that way?
Um, what, what makes you,
what parts of him do you like?
Or do you like this part of
what he's saying or not that,
and you can sort of parse it out
or they can ask us, you know,
why did you like Hillary? Oh, why, why
did you think she'd be okay? You know,
even though they might've thought she
was a terrible candidate and as long as
you can acknowledge, you know, that
yes, parts of her candidacy didn't work,
but this is what I thought she was
prepared for. Or on the other hand,
they could say he touched
a chord Trump did.
And people who felt they were being
left out and people who felt that they
weren't being listened to. Um, and
then, and then sometimes it does,
sometimes if it gets too
hard, then we just say, okay,
let's have another drink and change
the subject and talk about the red sox.
That's what does it. And there may, there
may be some Yankee fans in the group,
but usually it's not. So not, not up here.
So the red sox are a very calming device.
Not Mad at them too because they,
but not this summer, this summer.
They're doing great.
So, so this is, uh, what we're
discussing in this type of, uh,
looking for a different adjective but
still civil is fine. Civil discussion,
civil discourse about some, uh, these
potentially polarizing topics. We,
that is a skill that can be developed.
Do you have to practice?
But it can be developed and
I'd love to look back at,
uh,
some of your guys and to,
to look at perhaps some of the mistakes,
failures or roadblocks,
which I know you, you discuss, uh,
very, very directly in the new book,
uh, to, to, to maybe
give an illustration of something they,
they perhaps weren't very good at
that then later became good at, uh,
just to show us, uh, give us
some historical examples of, uh,
those,
those early mistakes slash weaknesses
slash roadblocks and how they dealt with
them.
Well, I mean, taking both Teddy Roosevelt
and Franklin Roosevelt, for example,
in both of them had grown
up in an extraordinary
privileged background and both
had a certain kind of snobbishness.
I think about people who
are not in their class.
When Teddy Roosevelt went to Harvard,
he looked up the names of potential
friends to see if they were on the social
register so that he would know they'd
be safe for him to be friendly with.
But then interestingly, he always was
interested in the outdoors, in fact,
in part because he was suffering
from terrible asthma as a child.
So we had to build the body that
would allow him to become a man and,
and to live on.
So in the summers he would go to Maine
with these guides and they would kind of
backwoods been guys and he just loved
being with them and he loved asking them
about their lives.
He had always been interested in curious
and other lives through literature,
but now he was seeing them. They knew the
woods, they knew things he didn't know.
And all of a sudden the fact that he
read more books than they did seemed less
important. But even so when he first
got into the state legislature,
he was a fiery kind of character.
And he went after a judge who we thought
was corrupt and he pounded his desk and
he said terrible things about him. And
he got a swelled head when the judge was,
was undone by the newspapers.
And then he realized that he'd become
so self important that he thought the
Democrats on the other side,
we're terrible people.
He wasn't dealing with them that only
he knew what was right. And as he said,
I rose like a rocket.
And then I fell to the ground and he
finally decided that you had to compromise
and collaborate and be with
other people and learn from them.
So an FDR, similarly, when he first
got into the state legislature,
he did very well at the beginning.
He was organizing a group of
people and he thought that the,
the Tammany bosses were all bad people.
And then he began to see my God,
they may be doing some corrupt things,
but they also are helping people
in the cities there. They,
the people who vote for them do it
because they come to their funerals,
they get them food,
they get the full fuel,
and he moderated his kind
of approach to politics.
But that's the thing that,
you know what Teddy said at one point
was the great thing about being a
politician more than if he
had chosen another field,
and I'm not so sure it's true today,
but it was then he said, I man,
who takes an active part in the political
life of a great city is going to be
meeting all sorts of people as a result,
and that's what he called fellow feeling,
which he said was essential for
any democracy. He said that by,
by going to places that he normally
wouldn't go, he went to tenements.
He was a police commissioner and
he roamed the slums at night.
It was a civil service commissioner,
so we understood what it was like to
take an exam and want to have a job for
that kind of clerkship.
He was in the army,
he had fellow soldiers that he was
leading and he lived with them and this in
the same kind of tent.
All of that broadened his experience
that he would not have had as a child and
by the time he reached the presidency,
he had what he called that sense of
civic life being marked by understanding
other people's points of view.
It's the very thing that's
missing in our country today.
He said a large part of the ranker of
political and social strife arises from
misunderstanding by one
section of one class.
They're so cut off from each other
that they don't appreciate each other's
passions and prejudices and because he
had spent time in the West where he went
after his wife and his mother died on
the same day in the same house to escape
his depression. He saw a
cowboys, he was a cowboy,
and it's that breadth of experience
that I think all leaders need to.
It can come through curiosity,
it can come possibly through reading,
but it comes to meeting people of
different sections and different places.
And that's what politics
in the best sense can do.
But today I think they're much more
narrowed down to the people who agree with
them and they don't have that same
broad experience that they used to.
There are people in government listening
to this podcast and I do know that
there are a number of senators who
subscribed to the podcast
and various policymakers.
What are some recommendations
you would have if,
if they want to develop
that broader perspective.
Are there any particular
actions you might suggest?
Any particular habits that just got a,
based on the historical accounts in
your research of these larger than life
figures that they could in the
current day somehow incorporate to,
uh, develop these types of
attributes that we're talking about?
I do believe there are.
I mean, think about it.
Lincoln used to have ordinary people
come into his office in the morning and,
and just talk to him about what
they wanted. They wanted a job.
This is the days before civil service.
And he listened to their
family discussions.
He listened to why that clerkship or
that post ship would matter to them.
And after a while his secretary's Nikolay
and Hey said to him, Mr President,
you don't have time for these ordinary
people. He said, you're wrong.
I must never forget the popular
assemblage from which I have come.
So Teddy Roosevelt took whistle stop
tours on a train six weeks in the spring
and in the fall.
And he went to places where he'd been
defeated as well as places where he had
one.
And then he would stop the train at the
local station and listen to newspaper
editors. You know, who would be
criticizing something he was doing.
He'd be talking to ordinary people. You
have to get out of the office. I mean,
FDR was not able because of his paralysis
to go around the country as much as
Teddy Roosevelt was, but he sent
on or his wife 200 days a year,
she would be going from one
new deal project to the other,
seeing which ones were working,
which ones wasn't. Bringing him back.
Stories of people who are
hurting during the depression,
the stories that he needed to
really to really work and Lbj.
If you look at the way he
dealt with the congress,
why was he so brilliant and getting
the two sides of the aisle together?
Because in the first six months
of his presidency after JFK died,
he had every single congressmen over
in groups of 30 to the White House.
They would then have started with drinks
together and then lady bird would take
the spouses and those days on a tour of
the mansion and then they would sit and
talk and then he would call
them up at six in the morning.
He'd call them at noon and he'd call
even a senator at 2:00 AM he said,
I hope I didn't wake you up,
but I just need your advice.
And then the senator says, oh no, I was
just lying here looking at the ceiling,
hoping my president would call.
But nothing beats spending time with
different people and not letting your day
get filled up just with the colleagues
and the and the people in the government
itself.
I mean,
Fdr said when he was putting over
the papers to the FDR library,
the first presidential library,
you said,
there's millions of papers here
of government talk to one another,
but the ones I value the most are the
letters from the people who are telling me
their stories and their opinions of
me and what I should do differently.
And those are the ones that I hope
people will read as time goes by.
So maintaining that connection,
whether it's a leader and and their
company and their shareholders,
or whether it's a president
and their constituencies,
and keeping that sense of
understanding and connection directly.
That's why FDR was so terrific on the
radio because he made people feel when he
was communicating with them that he was
talking to them individually. You know,
people would be sitting in their living
room or in their kitchen looking at the
radio, but they felt somehow
he was just talking to them.
There's a story about a
construction worker going home,
one nine as part. I said,
where are you going so early?
You said, well, my president,
he's coming to speak to me in my
living room tonight. It's only right.
I'd be there to greet him when he comes.
It's that sense of keeping that
connection. The higher up you go,
the more likely it is to narrow
the numbers of people that you see.
And all of these people reached out
across those barriers to keep fresh.
Even when Eleanor Roosevelt came
back from her stories, um, the,
what were the people were
feeling in the country,
they would always have dinner the first
night. So the story would be fresh,
not repeated over time.
You mentioned Eleanor, uh,
you also mentioned Lady
Bird Johnson. Are there any,
uh, first lady stories or attributes, uh,
that,
that you think don't get enough
airtime or that perhaps are lesser
known that should be better now?
Well,
I think the important thing is that the
importance of a first lady and so far we
have had just first ladies,
no first men.
The importance of a first lady to the
president goes well beyond whether they
contribute in the partnership
way that Eleanor did. I
mean, she was extraordinary.
She's the first lady to
ever have a radio program,
the first lady to speak
at a national convention,
the first to hold weekly press conferences
where she had a rule that only female
reporters could come to her press
conferences so that all over the country,
stuffy publishers have to hire their
first female reporter to go to Eleanor,
those press conferences,
but they all can't be as active in
politics as Eleanor was. In fact,
when bess Truman came in,
Eleanor said,
I'll introduce you to the ladies
of the press and Best Truman said,
why in the world I want to do that?
I'm not going to be talking
to the ladies of the press.
What you need to know is the same thing
you need to know about any partnership
is what are they contributing
to? One another. Um,
Teddy Roosevelt's wife Eden had no
interest in being a public figure.
She said the only time a woman's name
should be in the press is when she is born
in when she dies.
But she gave him the stability of a,
his family home.
Then the kids were part of his life.
He'd come home and play with the kids.
He knew that,
that they had a family that was strong
and stable and could withstand any of the
pressures of public life. So I think we
need to look at the, the way in which, um,
the wives and first ladies have
contributed to their husbands.
That may be very different, some
political, it could be a balance.
As lady bird was an extraordinary balance
to Lyndon Johnson. There were times,
even when I was at the ranch,
or I could see him get so angry about and
controlling anger is such an important
part of leadership.
And somehow as he was yelling at somebody,
she could just put her hand on his
knee and say, now, Linden, Linden,
you don't really mean that. You're
going to feel bad about this later on.
And somehow it just calmed him down.
So I think sometimes it's somebody
who's calm against the manic person.
Sometime it's somebody like Eleanor
who could actually argue with him.
And he said she was like a welcome,
a thorn in his side.
She was the person who could tell him
the truth whenever he needed to hear it.
Are there any other presidents that
could be someone you have written about?
Could be someone else you've studied.
It doesn't even have to be a president,
a leader, let's just say, uh,
who strikes you as particularly underrated
or overlooked and it doesn't have to
be one. Could be,
couldn't be more than one.
Well, you know, the, there's,
there's leaders that I don't
know about that. I mean,
that's what's amazing.
Even though I taught a course on
the presidency for years at Harvard,
I don't really know a lot
of our presidents. In fact,
right now I'm involved in a possibility
of a miniseries on George Washington and
I can't tell you how little I
know about George Washington,
which is really embarrassing,
but I'm so excited because now
I'll be able to live with him.
I'll wake up with them in the
morning and think about him.
I'm not writing about it. And it will
be quite as intense as it would be,
but helping us a consultant
on this documentary.
So I don't think he's underrated though.
I think people know about him,
but I'm sure if I were to go into
somebody like Cleveland, maybe, um,
Grover Cleveland,
if I went into James Polk,
which everybody who knows him says
now he's a really interesting guy,
you'd find more about it.
That's the thing.
When you study somebody
you get interested in, um,
and the fact that they
reached the presidency,
they usually means that
there's some ambition there.
There's some desire hopefully to,
to do something for the country.
There's some resilience because
they've all been through something.
So they become human beings.
And then you realize that maybe they're
underrated as a person because of their
judgment in history.
The way presidential historians
judge people can often be difficult.
I remember I happened to be at a
dinner at the White House in 1997,
so it was before Monica
Lewinsky happened to Clinton,
but there had been a
presidential historians poll
that came out that day that
ranked him sort of in the middle,
and he was so angry through the dinner.
He just kept talking about it.
I hung,
fortunately was sitting next to
him as a presidential historian.
So I was trying to make him
feel better that very day.
The owners of the Brooklyn Dodgers,
now,
the Los Angeles Dodgers had announced
that they were selling the team and there
was some thought that maybe they'd
come back to Brooklyn. So I said to,
I said to President Clinton,
I'd make you a corrupt bargain if you
bring the Dodgers back to Brooklyn.
I will put you up a notch on
the next presidential poll.
You can even really laugh.
I didn't think he thought it was funny,
but I thought it was funny.
Anyway, um, you know,
just mentioning that business though
of Lyndon Johnson and having anger,
controlling anger is such an
important part of leadership and both,
some of my guys was so much
better at it than others. I mean,
Abraham Lincoln had this wonderful
ritual that I think you can develop where
when he got angry with somebody, he would
write what he called a hot letter, um,
to the person releasing all this anger.
And then he put the letter aside hoping
he would cool down psychologically and
never need to send it.
The famous case of that is when general
Meade failed to follow up with General
Lee's army after the victory had
Gettysburg despite telegrams saying,
you can't let these Lee's army escape.
Um,
he did let Lee's army is
escape and Joe and, and,
and Lincoln was so upset about it.
Then he wrote a long letter saying,
I'm in measurably distressed or
didn't do what we asked you to do,
had you done so the war would have come
to an earlier end. But then he realized,
oh my God, he's still in the
field. This will paralyze him.
He puts the letter aside and it's never
even seen until the 20th century when
his papers are open. And a raft
of these kinds of letters exist,
never sent and never signed. So after the
book, team of rivals came out, um, uh,
CEO wrote me and he said,
thank God for Lincoln's hot letters.
He had written an email to a subordinate
thinking that the subordinate had done
something wrong.
And then he decided,
I think I'll just put this in
draft instead of sending it.
And he found out the next day that he
had been wrong about the information.
So that's one way to get through
with anger. FDR had his own way.
He would write drafts of speeches,
say his fireside chats would go through
five or six drafts before they would be
done. And if he was angry at a
congressman over a particular incident,
he would call out the person by
name. And the first draft, you know,
we'd call him a traitor to his class,
a terrible guy.
I knew young speechwriter
came along and said,
I can't believe he's going
to do this. This will look
terrible. The oldest speech,
right? He said, just wait until the
second draft. By the second draft,
the congressman's name
was gone by the third,
the negative adjectives were gone by the
final draft. All was sweetness in life,
but he'd gotten it all out
of his system by doing that.
So figuring out ways to get that anger
out in a way that's not going to hurt the
person directly and hurt your
own leadership is something
that my guys were able
to do. Lyndon Johnson less able
to, um, when he'd be angry,
he would go, for example,
to somebody's desk. And if the desk
was cleaning, think, oh my God,
the guy's not working hard. If it was
messy and think he's disorganized. And,
and then when he got angry,
he would just start yelling at the person
right there and then he'd feel bad.
And he might send, you know, a
present to them the next day,
but so much better if you can release
that anger in a different way.
Stanton Lincoln's war secretary,
um,
came by one day and he was furious at a
general. And so Lincoln said to him, well,
why don't you write to the general and
tell him what you're feeling? And so stat,
and comes back a few days
later and he reads them the
thing, and, and, and he says,
now, Stanton, what are you going
to do about? And he said, well,
I'm going to send it, of course.
And Lincoln said, no, you're not.
Just throw it in the wastepaper basket.
And he said,
but it took me two days to
write. And he said, I know.
And it did you ever so much good.
You feel better now?
That's all that's necessary.
Just throw it away.
And so after a little more
grumbling stand did just that.
And the interesting thing is when I,
when I interviewed President Obama
for a Vanity Fair exit interview,
I was talking to him about
Lincoln's hot letters and,
and he had read team of rivals, but we,
we re we went over it again and I said,
do you ever do that? And you said, what
do you mean? Of course I do all the time.
I said, what do you mean? He said,
I write dozens of letters and promote
them up and put it in the wastebasket.
So that's a lesson one could learn
pulling from that vanity fair piece.
I wanted to ask you about
this because at one point,
but I think I have this right.
You, you wrote at the beginning,
you've prepared for
this conversation today.
I realized that it was nine years ago
that you first called me on my cell phone
quote. Hello, this is Barack Obama.
I've just read team of rivals and
we have to talk about Lincoln.
So a couple of questions.
Did you know this call was coming?
Was it a blocked number and then
someone saying they're Barack Obama?
Did,
do you believe that it was a Brockville?
Like could you tell us a little
bit about that phone call?
No, remember he's just a
candidate at this point.
We're running way behind Hillary Clinton,
but obviously he had been a star at
that convention, so I had never met him.
But I'd heard him give that speech
because I'd been there covering it for
television. But no, I didn't
picture the room I was in,
in my house when I just answered
the cell phone and he said,
this is Barack Obama. And I thought at
first I didn't really, but indeed it was.
And what had happened is that he
wanted to talk to me about the book,
not because he was thinking
of creating a team of rivals.
He was so far behind
Hillary at that point.
He just was fascinated by Lincoln's
emotional intelligence. You know,
how he could forgive these people in the
past, how he could control his anger,
how he could share credit,
all those things.
So I went to his Senate office building
and talk to them about Lincoln.
And then the interesting thing that
happened is that when he then appointed
Hillary, secretary of state, his chief
rival, after he had won the nomination,
actually somebody asked him,
a journalist said to him,
would you really be willing to put one
of your chief rivals into your cabinet?
Even if he or she had a spouse
who could be a pain in the neck?
Of course it was meaning
Hillary and Bill Clinton.
And he then quoted Lincoln
and he said, you know, the
times are in peril. You know,
these are the strongest smells
people. If she's the strongest, yes,
I'll put her in. So then when he did,
it sort of became a term team of rivals.
So when I went to the inauguration,
covering it for television,
and there was a party the night before
where Hillary Clinton was and teasingly,
she came up to me and said,
you are responsible for my
being secretary of state.
Of course, not me, but
Abraham Lincoln. But yes,
I think leaders do learn from each other.
That's one of the great things about
Harry Truman was that even though he was
not college educated,
he loved reading history and biography
and he learned from the leaders in the
past. I mean, each one of them
I think learns from each other.
I mean when I think about it,
the book that I've written about
Lincoln and teddy and Franklin and Lbj,
it's almost like a family tree
because Lbj, his hero was Roosevelt,
who he called his political daddy.
Franklin Roosevelt's hero was Teddy
Roosevelt that he modeled his whole career
on him when, when Franklin was 28
years old and a law clerk, as I say,
not having been a great student
or even a great Locklear,
he and the law clerks are sitting around
and talking about what might happen to
them in the future and he said, I'm
not going to be practicing law forever.
I think what I'd like to do is to be a
state legislator and then I think I'd
love to be assistant secretary of the
navy. He loved ships and he loved maps.
They loved the navy. And then maybe
from that I could be governor,
and then who knows,
maybe I could be president exactly the
path that Teddy Roosevelt's and taken and
teddy was his hero. They would
just gently related. But of course,
Eleanor Roosevelt was Teddy
Roosevelt's younger brother's daughter,
and her father had died
of alcoholism young.
So teddy became a really
important uncle [inaudible].
So from the time that Franklin was young,
meeting the family early on,
and then from knowing Teddy Roosevelt,
the young men, that was his hero,
Teddy Roosevelt's hero was Abraham
Lincoln. And he used to read,
he read one summer when he was in the
middle of this terrible crisis of the coal
strike. He read the volumes, eight
volumes by Nicola and Hay on Lincoln.
And it just helped him,
he said,
to learn that Lincoln had been through
rough times before then Lincoln had had
to face radicals on the one side,
conservatives on the other,
and figure out a moderate point of view.
And in the middle of this coal strike,
he's reading this book
and it gives him solace.
And then of course Lincoln's heroes
were the founding fathers and George
Washington.
So it shows how short the history of
our country is that you could encompass
these four or five liters in the whole
history of the country who form a family
tree.
It's remarkable. It really is
incredible. I've been at just,
I think about say,
traveling overseas and you find these
buildings that are by not a small margin
so much older than the entire
history of our country. It's,
it's really remarkable. Uh, and uh,
I'd love to come back
to some of these habits,
uh, one of which we discussed the hot
letters say that Lincoln Wood, right. Uh,
are there any other routines or habits,
uh,
could be for anything for forgiveness
sharing or giving credit or anything at
all that have stuck with you that you
find particularly interesting or unusual
from any of the figures you've studied?
Well, I think, you know,
one of the things that teddy rose about
would argue was that procrastination was
a mortal sin, so that if he knew he
had to give a speech months away,
he would start writing it that day.
Just so that he wouldn't have to think
about when am I going to start it?
When am I going to start it?
Even when he was leaving the presidency,
he was supposed to give a speech in the
Sorbonne after his year in Africa on the
hunt. Then he went on, but he had already
finished the speech before he went,
even on the hunt to Africa.
And so there's so many times,
even for myself, if I have
something I really don't want to do,
I at least started so that I won't have
to think what am I going to start that
thing?
So that's a habit that I
think he developed in his
other people in the cabinet
whenever they had to give
a speech or go somewhere,
they would all be preparing ahead of
time and sharing drafts with one another,
which they wouldn't have done if it
had waited til the last moment. Um,
I think the most important thing,
however,
that they all figured out how to do
was how to relax and replenish their
energies to find time to think and relax.
You know,
I think about it in our 24 seven worlds,
so many leaders or even regular people
working in an organization feel I can't
take a vacation or I have to take
my email with me wherever I go.
I can't find time to do
anything else other than work.
But think of these guys that I'm studying.
They certainly had difficult situations.
You had Lincoln having to
deal with the civil war.
You have teddy dealing with the industrial
revolution and the huge gap between
rich and poor that arises during
that time and big labor strife.
And you have obviously FDR with the
depression and World War II and Lyndon
Johnson with the civil rights
struggle and here they go.
Lincoln goes to the theater more than a
hundred times during the civil war and
people criticized him for it.
They said,
how can you go to the theater in
the midst of all this? And he said,
I've got to get out of politics and out
of the war and for a few hours when I'm
watching Henry the fourth,
I could imagine myself back at the war
of the roses and I must have some relief
from this terrible anxiety. It will kill
me. And the theater is in or for Lincoln.
When he told funny stories,
he was a great storyteller and he could
tell stories to people who are around
him and they'd laugh
and when he would laugh,
somehow he was whistling off his sadness.
So humor in a certain sense was
his way of dealing with anxiety.
Teddy Roosevelt,
every afternoon found at time,
two hours every afternoon for either a
rock is tennis match or a a strenuous
hike and the wooded
cliffs of Rock Creek Park,
or being thrown around by two
Japanese wrestlers or a boxing match.
He loved playing this
game of single stock.
He would often injure himself and
these various games he played.
And then there was one time when he was
in the middle of the coal strike where
he was deprived of these any exertions
because he had an infected leg.
So he writes to the Librarian
of Congress and he said,
I need some escape from all this.
I want you to send me something on
Mediterranean history or something on the
history of Poland. And so in the middle
of this coal strike at night, he says,
and he writes back to the
Librarian of Congress and he said,
it's been such a delight
to drop everything useful,
everything relating to my duty,
particularly the coals drag and spend
an afternoon reading about the relations
between the Syria and Egypt,
which could not possibly do me any good,
but in which I reveled accordingly,
Franklin is the best.
I think in some ways he's the best.
So first of all,
he loves going to having movies at the
White House. He loves crossword puzzles,
he loves his stamps, he loves looking
at maps. He loved playing poker.
He really,
really knew how to relax.
But the best thing he did was
when he was in World War II.
He had a cocktail hour every night.
And the rule was that you
couldn't talk about the war.
You could talk about books you read,
you can talk about movies,
you'd seen gossip about people as
long as the war wasn't mentioned.
So for a few precious hours,
he liked Lincoln when Lincoln was
at the theater could relax totally.
And after a while,
this cocktail hour was so important to
him that he wanted his closest friends
and associates to be living on the second
floor of the White House to be ready
for the cocktail hour.
So the White House became the most
exclusive residential hotel you could
possibly imagine. Harry Hopkins,
his foreign policy advisor,
came for dinner one night, slept over,
didn't leave until the war came to an end.
His secretary missing my hand,
lived with a family in the White House.
I'm Lorena Hickok, who had an
emotional relationship with Eleanor,
had a bedroom next to Eleanor and the
princess from Norway and Xcel and America
during the war and lived with the family
on the weekends. And the great wisdom.
Churchill came and spent weeks at a
time and a room diagonally across from
Roosevelt's.
So when I was writing the book,
I just imagine all these people in their
bathrobes at night on the corridor of
the second floor of the
White House waiting for the
cocktail hour or having come
from the cocktail hour and
then being ready for bed and,
and wishing that when I've been up there
with Lyndon Johnson when I was 24 I'd
asked where did Roosevelt sleep? Where
was Eleanor, where was Churchill?
But I wasn't thinking in those terms then.
So I happened to mention this on a radio
program in Washington when no ordinary
time came out and it happened.
Hillary Clinton then in the
White House was listening,
so she promptly called me
up at the radio station,
invited me to sleep overnight in the
White House so I could wander the Carter
together with her and their husband and
figure out where everyone had slept 50
years earlier.
She invited me and my husband to sleep
overnight and we were given Winston
Churchill's room, which meant
there was no way I could sleep.
I was certain he was sitting in the
corner drinking his brandy and smoking his
cigar. That my map we figured out, yes,
Chelsea cleanses sleeping where Harry
Hopkins was and the Clintons are sleeping
where FDR was and of course we
were with Winston Churchill.
So it was pretty exciting.
Yeah,
that is amazing.
Are there any particular routines,
tools,
anything that you use to
rejuvenate or decompress yourself?
You have an incredibly busy schedule
or you certainly it just based on the
amount of work you put out it would,
it would seem that you are
certainly able to go, go, go.
So what have you built into your
schedule to help recharge the batteries?
Well, the most important thing I think
is that once it's time for dinner,
I don't work late into the nights I work.
I get up early in the morning,
I can wake up at five or five 30 I
love getting up before everybody else.
He is around and I don't look at email
until seven or seven 30 if it's winter,
I come downstairs and I have a fire
that I can turn on the fireplace.
If it's summer and it's air conditioned,
I put a blanket on myself and the rest
of the household hasn't awakened yet.
So those are really precious hours to to
just read over what I'd written the day
before and not looking at email,
not think of everything else I
have to do that day. And similarly,
by six 30 or so at night,
that's the end of work. Um, I,
we go out to dinner every
night as I was saying,
and when I get to that
bar with my friends,
it has nothing to do with
what I was doing that day.
We're talking about the game of the red
sox and we were talking about politics
and it's totally taking me away
to another channel of that.
And then because we've had season tickets
for the red sox for the last 30 years,
when I walk into the baseball game,
I obviously became a red sox fan after
the Brooklyn Dodgers abandoned me and
went to Los Angeles and I moved to Harvard
and became a red sox fan equally as
crazy as I was as a Brooklyn dodger fan.
But once I walked into that ballpark and
I keep score still and when I can there,
um, I feel like I'm in another place and
I don't think and worry about what I'm
doing.
And then when I get home at night,
I don't read history at night.
I read mysteries somehow.
That's what I need to do before going
to sleep is to read some mystery.
I don't know why I tried to put
the pieces of the puzzle together,
but just relaxing with a good mystery.
So there are ways to do it. I think,
I mean the,
the most interesting way of thinking
about anxiety from my guys is Fdr had all
these ways of allowing himself to relax.
He went on a fishing trip at one point
10 day fishing trip in the middle of the
crisis of Britain before
we were in the war.
And he came up with the whole idea of
lend lease on that fishing trip because he
was away from the terminal of Washington
where the bureaucratic structure
couldn't figure out how to lend money
or lend supplies to England because of
neutrality acts.
And so he comes up with lend lease.
I'm going with that is I'm going to
yes. I don't know what that is. No,
I absolutely.
So what happens is that when Britain has,
is already being bombed by
Germany and it's 1940, so it's,
we're not in the war yet. Um, he,
he knows that Churchill
has run out of supplies.
Dunkirk had happen so they're
destroyers were killed.
We need to somehow get our supplies
and our weapons to England,
but England has no money
to buy them anymore.
And neutrality acts say we
can't just give them to them.
So he comes up with the idea that we
will lend you our weapons and then after
the war is over, you will get
them back to us as if, uh,
neighbor's houses on fire and you're
going to lend them your hose to save that
neighbor's house,
but also save your house too.
And then in return for giving the weapons,
we got a lease on British bases all around
the world. There's really a good deal,
a good Yankee bargain.
But anyway,
it eventually gave us
money for, um, for Russia.
It gave us money for all of our allies,
not just money,
but supplies that were given to our allies
all over the world because of leasing
them rather than letting them buy it.
So on this 10 day fishing trip,
he comes up with the idea that he can
just lend the weapons and then get them
back at the end and it's really leasing
them rather than selling them or having
them buy it.
So it was a simple thing,
but nobody could figure
that out in Washington.
But the thing that really
struck me was that an evening's,
when FDR couldn't fall asleep,
when there was unusual tension
and the poker game didn't do it,
or the cocktail hour didn't do it,
he had this ritual that
helped him to fall asleep.
He would close his eyes and imagine
himself as a boy again at Hyde Park,
standing with his sled and top
the steep hill behind his house.
And he would go down the hill until he
reached the bottom and then slowly come
back up again to the top. And then
he'd do again, go over and over again.
It was his method of counting sheep.
But the amazing thing is
he's also liberating himself
from the paralysis by this
imagining. And in that
way he falls asleep. So,
and what Teddy Roosevelt would do
when he was anxious about an election,
and this I've thought
about a lot actually,
he would write letters to his
friends and his family saying,
don't worry if I don't win this election.
I've had the, the best life so far.
I've had a first rate run and it would
be selfish of me to think that if I don't
win this one, everything is lost. And
I've thought about that a lot actually.
I've thought about the fact
that if I knew I were dying,
and maybe this is dramatic way of putting
it because he was just worried about
losing an election,
but that I'd hope that it would give me
solace to think I really had a good life
and I felt like it was what I wanted
it to be. And I can't control that.
It won't go on any longer,
but I can look back on that.
Just like teddy looked back on his life
and I thought about it so much in these
last months because my husband got cancer
this last year and he was incredible
during the whole time.
I mean he's, he's still,
even though he couldn't enjoy food anymore
because of the radiation that he went
through, couldn't have his
trademark cigars anymore.
He went out every night with as
to our regular bar dinners. Um,
even though he was being fed by a feeding
tube during the day so that he would
get the nourishment he needed an I
actually learned how to you do the feeding
tube.
I couldn't believe that.
I learned that I was so afraid of my
technical abilities and I had to face that
fear and somehow do it.
But in the days before he died,
all of our friends came to visit him
because he was in hospice at home and
somehow magically,
he,
he woke up when people would come
and he had something to say to them,
something funny or something serious and,
and then he would go back to sleep
and then wake up again. But in,
in so many days before that he would say
he didn't necessarily know he was dying
right then,
but he knew that he had cancer and that
the radiation hadn't worked and he,
there was no sense of talking about death.
He was still working on a book that he
hoped to finish, but he kept saying,
I love this town. I love what's happened
to our life. Our kids are great.
How lucky we are. And I just hope I can
say that at the same way he did it made,
it made me less nervous about dying to
watch the peacefulness of the way he
handled it.
And there was an extraordinary moment.
I can't believe I'm only talking
about all this right now,
but I somehow gotten into it, um,
where the last thing he said to me,
he just looked at me and he had
this incredible light in his eyes.
Everybody said it was almost like magic.
And he just said to me, you are a wonder.
I mean, I will take that, those
words with me the rest of my life.
So I just hope I can be as peaceful and
loving as he was as he faced his own
death.
Thank you so much for sharing that.
I don't know how I got into all that,
but it has something to do with anxiety
and how you got to sleep at night.
Yeah. It's, I mean the,
the gratitude and appreciation that
you're describing a on so many different
levels. But first and foremost,
I'm sorry for your loss.
I can't even imagine what that
would be like. Uh, but, uh,
I thank you for sharing that.
No, you're welcome. He was great.
42 years of marriage and an
extraordinary life that he had. I mean,
he was,
you know,
he was involved in so many things that
people knew when the obituaries came out,
the breadth of it, people had
known part of it. I mean, we knew,
he wrote for Lyndon Johnson,
the great we shall overcome speech.
He wrote Bobby Kennedy's South
Africa speech, the ripples of hope.
He worked with l with at JFK when he was
only in his twenties and worked on some
of his famous South American speeches.
Al Gore's concession speech. Um,
but more important than any of that.
He was just involved in policy and in
the great society and civil rights.
And um,
and then he was in the
quiz show investigation and
that was made into a movie
that,
cause he was the young guy who had
discovered that those quiz shows when you
weren't even born, that was
push shows were corrupted. And,
and then he wrote a play
about Galileo and pope urban,
the eighth that was put on
in London and in Boston.
It was such a such a wonderfully broad
life and he was a great guy and a great
husband and father to our kids.
Our kids adored him.
I feel like
I'm unsure of where to go next with this.
That, that was such a beautiful story.
Uh,
and you're such a,
you're a gifted storyteller and
it seems to go back a long way.
You've honed that certainly
over time. And, uh,
you have some of the most incredible,
speaking of sports storytelling,
some of the most incredible book blurbs
and quotes from admirers of your work
for this new book leadership in
turbulent times. You have Warren Buffet,
you have an incredible, uh, collection of,
of fans who have,
have provided you with a
words for this book. Why,
why did you write this book? I mean, you,
you have such a keen sense of the finite
amount of time that we're all given on
this planet. Given your study
of history, certainly mortality,
your firsthand exposure to it.
Why,
why put the time and energy
into writing this book?
Well, you know, in some ways, I
mean, I started it five years ago,
so the times we're not as
turbulent as they are now,
but there was a sense that Washington
was broken even then and that we weren't
kind of leadership on the two sides of
the aisle that could get anything done.
And having lived through the sixties
having been there when the civil rights
bill passed and the voting rights bill
passed and aid to education and Medicare,
it was such a thrilling time to be young
to see our country moving together and
those directions.
I'd written about these four guys before,
but I hadn't really looked at them as
leaders and what it was that made them
able to not just bring two
sides of the altogether,
but lead the country through
such difficult times.
And I realized that each of the Times in
which they led were far worse than the
time we're living in now. So that if
we think this is the worst of times,
history will tell you no,
we've had more turbulent times before.
And we got through them. When you had the
right leader fitted for the right time.
I mean,
they all had different leadership styles.
They wouldn't have been fitted to be
in the other time or possibly. So.
It's not just a matter of the
constellation of traits you have.
It's whether or not those behavioral
patterns fit the challenges of the moment
of the time.
But I think what I really wanted to do
was just to understand how they became
leaders. I mean, we see them as iconic
figures now there, Mount Rushmore,
there's monuments. And I was giving a
talk to a group of college students,
you know, four or five years ago, and
one of them raised their hands and said,
but how can we, I was talking about
leadership lessons from the White House,
but how can I ever become one of them?
It's too far removed.
So the way I start the book is when each
one of them is running for office the
first time.
So they're not formed yet and they're
not going to necessarily succeed.
Lincoln in fact loses his first election
when he's 23 years old. But incredibly,
he says,
if I lose,
I've been already to familiar with
disappointment to be very chagrined,
but I do promise I'll come back five or
six times and try again until it's too
humiliating and then I'll give up. That's
incredible. That kind of resilience. Um,
teddy rose,
if they all suffered adversity,
and I guess I was interested in that too,
maybe because of my personal history of
my mother dying when I was 15 my father
died when I was in my twenties so that
I had encountered death at an early age.
But all of these people went
through terrible adversity.
Lincoln had a near suicidal depression
when he has word was no longer his bond.
He had broken his engagement to marry
and he was humiliating her by doing so.
He had failed in bringing
infrastructure projects to Illinois,
which he had promised to do, and he
really was almost ready. He said to die,
but when he was told by his best friend,
you have to rally or you will die,
they'd taken all knives and scissors
and razors from his room. He said,
I would just assume guy now,
but I'm not yet accomplished anything to
make any human being remembered that I
have lived. So that was his lodestar
that carried him through everything,
all the losses that he had. He
tried for the Senate twice. He lost,
he finally wins the presidency and then
he has the civil war in front of him.
So resilience and coming
through adversity.
Was it a key that I wanted to understand
that all that happened to all of them.
Teddy Roosevelt lost his wife and his
mother on the same day in the same house
in New York. His wife was
pregnant, having a child.
The mother had only 49 had
come to take care of her.
The mother got typhoid fever and died
and the wife died in childbirth on the
same day and that house and he was so
depressed. He left the state legislature.
He went to the badlands. He said he
had to be on his horse 15 hours a day.
He couldn't outride black hair depression.
But more importantly he
found solace in nature.
He found solace in the west and became
a different kind of leader because he
understood the West as well as the east.
And he came back and then went on to
this extraordinary political career.
But it taught him, he said that you don't
build your resume. Little by little.
He had always thought
before he had a pattern,
worked out and no longer did
that pattern seems so. He said,
I'm just going to take whatever job comes.
It seems really interesting to me cause
it may be my last job because he now had
a fatalism about life.
So his friends say,
why are you becoming civil
service commissioner? Why
aren't police commissioner,
this is below you. He said, no, I want to
do these things and if it's my last job,
so be it. And then of
course, most importantly FDR,
I mean what he went through
when he contracted polio
and was paralyzed from the
waist down, it allowed him
to emerge more warm hearted,
more connected to other people to whom
faded Delta and unkind hand than he would
have been before that, you
know, he said, if you spend,
you learn humility through something like
the polio and the paralysis. He said,
if you spent two years
trying to move your big toe,
which is frozen and you finally
move it and you celebrate it,
then the pressures of the presidency,
I'm not going to get to um,
what he did at warm springs by bringing
his fellow polios as he called them to
enjoy life again, not just to rehab
themselves in the warm springs pool,
but he would have wheelchair dances.
They'd play games and the soccer games or,
or badminton games in the pool.
He made them learn to live life again,
even with the affliction
of having been paralyzed.
And he emerged a different person. I
mean, it's extraordinary what he did.
I and I just find a human level.
I found these stories so
important to understand, um,
much less because it made them great
leaders. I mean, when he first made a,
an appearance after his polio,
two years afterwards,
he hadn't been in public life.
He was asked to give a nominating speech
or AO Smith for President in 1924 at
the Democratic convention.
And he was very worried about how he
could get from the seat with his braces
locked in place.
He could make appear to be walking if he
held onto the arm of somebody, his son,
strong arm,
get to the podium.
But he practiced and practice
that distance in his own
library time after time
and he was sweating and he got
up to the podium and he made it.
And he would practice even
when he couldn't walk at all.
He would practice crawling up
the stairs one stair at a time.
And each stair when he got hired,
they'd have a celebration.
When you go through that adversity or
a different person at the other end,
and Lyndon Johnson,
what happened to him was that he had,
he had a loss in a Senate race in 1941
and for him it was as big an adversity or
these other things where
because it meant the end,
he thought of his political upward climb
and sometimes people don't get through
adversity in a positive way.
They can go backward and he then just
accumulated wealth and power and was not
as interested as he had once been in
making lives better for other people.
Then he had a near fatal heart attack
in 1955 and as you often read about with
other people,
it changed his attitude toward his life
and he decided I need something more
than power. I need to make
that power put to a purpose.
And when he did finally get into the
presidency through the death of JFK and he
decided that the first thing he would
go for would be the civil rights act and
segregation in the south. Everybody
said, it's too risky. You can't do that.
You'll never get through the filibuster
and your presidency will be a failure
and you're not going to be able to win
the next election. And he said, well,
every now and then if you're playing
poker, you got to throw in all your chips.
So he had learned that through adversity.
So I think what I wanted to do was,
even though I knew them as family,
man, I knew their colleagues.
I had studied the times I'd studied
the substance of their leadership.
I wanted to understand how they became
leaders, how they got through adversity,
how they developed, how they learned
from their mistakes. And then finally,
the last part of the book
are case studies there,
the pivotal moments in their histories,
which are Lincoln's emancipation
proclamation, which is actually,
I'm coming out in a Harvard business
review. This, you know, in days actually,
the emancipation proclamation as an
example of transformative leadership.
And then with Teddy, it's crisis
management, leadership of the coal strike.
And with FDR it's turnaround leadership
with the hundred days and with,
it's surprisingly visionary leadership
for Lbj on civil rights. Though,
obviously there's a Coda about the war
in Vietnam or his leadership utterly
failed and it was an epic
failure of leadership.
But even when I was in graduate school,
we used to talk about big things like
ambition. Where does ambition come from?
Where do you get a sense of purpose?
How do you have many in your life?
These are the things you'd stay
up late at night to talk about.
And I realized that that was what I
wanted to come back to probably, you know,
this is in some ways a culmination
of 50 years of studying precedents,
but is that a different level?
It's a more personal,
emotional level about my guys
as I call them. And I've really,
it's really stretched me in a way
because it meant drama and history and
literature. I'm not
just biography, but uh,
other things to try and
understand psychology,
to understand how they lead
and how they became leaders.
This is such a gift of a conversation.
I've had so much fun and I am
completely certain that this,
this book is going to be so incredibly
compelling and valuable to readers
because as you said,
it's,
it's taking such a personal lens
to the stories and lessons learned,
visa vi these leaders that
it transcends politics,
uh,
and really touches upon so many
layers of the human experience.
I really appreciate you the time
to chat with me today and to teach,
to share all of this
and I enjoyed it so much.
This is so,
so weird to just be looking at this little
picture of your face and I feel like
we were talking to each other.
Terrific. I, you,
you so much.
Oh,
it's entirely my pleasure and I
really encourage everybody to,
uh, take a look at your new book.
Leadership Subtitle in turbulent times,
couldn't be more timely and
timeless in a at the same time.
And uh, I will link to
the book of course, uh,
to other, uh, pieces of your
writing in the show notes.
Everything we've discussed for people
listening will be in the show notes.
So you can find links there at Tim dot.
Blog slash podcast and Doris,
I have to ask you one more
question before we wrap up,
which is speaking myself as someone
who occasionally has trouble sleeping
mysteries.
Do you have any mysteries that you
might recommend or types of mysteries?
Absolutely. In fact, I just go
on reading one mystery rider.
It's sort of a binge reading.
So just recently it's been John Grisham
and the great thing was that I was
already into John Grisham when a few
months ago he came up to Boston with four
of his friends from old Mississippi,
including one who was 80 years old and
had a bucket list of things he wanted to
do and places he wanted to see.
And they were on a bus together and then
they would come to these various places.
They went to New York. And anyway,
when they came to the Kennedy Library,
part of the bucket list of the older guy
was for me to talk to them for a couple
of hours. So Grisham was
there. So it was so exciting.
I mean for me just having come into
reading all of his works to be actually
meeting him and hearing him talk about
how he creates a story and what sparks
his desire to write about a particular
law firm or a particular medical problem
that happens. So yeah,
there's something about,
there's something about mysteries
that just allow me to transport myself
somewhere else.
So I think Christian's a Greg,
I read Bill Clinton's new book and um,
I read,
I'm reading John Jake Tapper's
book right now, Hell Fire Club,
which is really good also.
So I have several of them
because when I'm up on a trip,
I have to take a paperback
was my suitcase is too heavy.
So if I'm reading a hard back, I have to
have another one going at the same time.
But I somehow gets asleep.
Well no one will ever accuse you
of being an underachiever. Uh,
you are so gifted at telling
stories that are worth telling and,
and also doing the,
it's such an incredible depth of research
to piece it together in a narrative
and a story arc that is easily digested.
I really appreciate you doing the
work that you do. And uh, once again,
thank you so much for the time today.
I thank you for yours.
Wow.
And to everybody listening,
like I said,
links to everything are in
the show notes, Tim. Dot.
Blog four slash podcast and next time.
Thank
you for listening. Hey
guys, this is Tim again.
Just a few more things before
you take off. Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the other
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend,
so if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work week.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled
out and just drop in your email and you'll
get the very next one and if you sign
up,
I hope you enjoy it.
This episode is brought to you
by Intel and use them personally.
Ever since I wrote the
four hour work week,
I've been asked over and over again
how I choose to delegate tasks,
how I do 80 20 analysis and so on.
At the root of many of the
decisions is a simple question.
Actually two questions.
Number one,
how can I invest money to improve my
quality of life and use that in investing
as well?
The second,
how can I spend a little money or moderate
money to save significant ink to tell
is one of those investments
there a turnkey solution
for all of your imaginable
customer care needs? I used Intel
during the launch of the four hour body,
which was very,
very involved and they provided 24
seven customer service for my land rush
campaign because it was critical for
me to take care of every person who
purchased my books in participated.
This allowed me to focus on
the things that I am better at.
My strengths like marketing claim
that we'd worked on for six months
until trains,
they're experienced customer service
reps to know your business and your
products inside and out and
make your customers raving fans.
They answer more than a million customer
service requests every year and they
can do so across all platforms
including email, phone, social media,
texts in chat,
leaving your customers with for
service or just mediocre service,
which by the way,
in a competitive pool,
the huge liability long wait
times are unanswered messages,
carries a massive costs
and risk to your business.
Intel removes the logistics and
headaches of this type of communication,
allowing you to focus on your
strengths and grow your business.
It can be a real competitive advantage.
And I see many,
many ecommerce companies and the tech
companies thinking of customer service as
a good enough checkbox for an afterthought
and it just like airbnb design and
innovative ways to be a competitor and
to win that you can do the same thing
with customer service.
So as a listener of this podcast,
you can get up to $10,000
off with this guy,
$10,000 off your startup fees and costs
by visiting [inaudible] dot com forward
slash Tim so check it out.
The more info go to [inaudible] Dot
com I n k a t e l.com forward slash.
Tim,
this episode is brought to you by audible,
which has the largest selection
of audio books on the planet.
I've used audible for many years and I've
several audio books to recommend right
off the bat. If you're looking for a new
one ready player, one by Ernest Cline,
he may have heard of it.
The Tao of Seneca Seneca.
If you want to hear my favorite collection
of letters of all time as well as the
graveyard book by Neil Gaiman,
which is a fiction book I
used to reintroduce nonfiction
purists to beauty and
truth and enjoyment,
affection graveyard book.
It is incredible and I like the
version that Neil reads himself,
but the entire ensemble cast is also fun.
Audible members get a credit every month,
good for any audio book in the store,
regardless of price and unused credits
roll over to the next month so he didn't
like your audio book. No problem. You can
exchange it, no questions asked. Plus,
your books are yours to keep with audible.
You can go back and relisten to anytime,
even if you cancel your membership
and for some books, again,
graveyard book by Neil Gaiman.
I've listened to many, many times.
He may even just start over as soon
as you finish it the first time.
Audible also helps you to listen to more
books by letting you switch seamlessly
between devices.
Picking up exactly where you left off,
whether it's on your phone,
through your car for the tablet or
at home on an Amazon Echo, whatever.
You can get through tons of books,
hands and ice free while
doing almost anything.
So that is part of the beauty of audio.
It is a secondary activity when
you're walking the dog cooking,
whatever it might be.
Audible content includes an
unmatched selection of audiobooks,
original audio shows, news, comedy,
and much more from leading audio book
publishers, Broadcasters, Entertainers,
magazine and newspaper publishers,
and business information providers.
Maybe that's what I am, a business
information provider. And right now,
audible is offering listeners of this
podcast a free audiobook with a 30 day
trial memberships.
Check it out.
Go to audible.com forward slash Tim and
browse the unmatched selection of audio
programs. Download a title free and
start listening is super simple.
Go to audible.com forward slash Tim or
text tip to 500 500 on your telephone to
get started today.
Check it out.