Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking it.
I'm a cybernetic organism living tissue.
This episode is brought to you by
Ali Baba and the gateway 17 event.
This is very cool,
so listen up if you are an entrepreneur
or business owner in the United States,
the stars don't always align but
this might get close. All right.
The opportunity is this,
the gateway 17 event,
which 17 is 2017 is hosted
by Alibaba and Alibaba.
If you don't know it,
you could think of as a combination
of Amazon and Google in China.
It is huge.
This event is designed specifically to
help you guys tap into the 500 million
consumers in the Chinese market there.
Fast growing middleclass is larger
than the entire US population.
Alibaba's created marketplace better
technology to help you connect with the
people you want to connect with those
500 million and now they were looking for
a US based businesses to fill the demand.
The gateway 17 event is
designed to help match,
make and educate you teacher
everything you need to know.
The speakers include Jack Ma,
who is the founder of Alibaba,
has an estimated net worth
of more than $20 billion.
This is his only speaking appearance
in 2017 David Abney, the CEO of ups,
Charlie rose and more. It's a two
day event. It's in Detroit, Michigan,
June 20 and 21st and it puts you in direct
contact with experts who want to help
you grow your business specifically to
access the 500 million in China end.
As a listener of this podcast,
there is a very legit offer
which more sponsors would offer.
This type of discount.
Alibaba is offering
you the normal tickets,
which are $500 $425 that is a 75% discount
if you sign up by May 25th so if you
sign up by May 25th you can get a $500
ticket for $125 if you use the code Tim
at checkout,
that's capital t lower case I m you might
have to try all lowercase or all caps,
but to start with capital t lowercase,
I am so check it out.
Just the website alone teaches you a lot
about the Chinese middle class and this
new consumer base which has
incredible purchasing power.
I happen to know a decent amount about it.
Go to gateway seventeen.com
that's gateway,
the number one seven.com and
enter the code Tim at checkout.
That's gateway seventeen.com there are a
limited number of spots and it is a low
cost event with potentially very,
very high upside. The right folks.
Let's check it out.
Gateway seventeen.com and use code Tim,
this episode is brought
to you by wordpress,
my goto platform for blogging. Writing
Online, creating websites, everything.
I love wordpress to bits.
My site,
every site just about that I have is run
on wordpress and the lead developer of
wordpress, Matt Mullenweg has
appeared on this podcast many times.
The very first episode
in particular is amazing.
The second I took a ton of notes on,
so he's checking out, but wordpress,
where do I even begin? I mean the
New Yorker uses it, Jay z, Beyonce,
they use it five 38 tech crunch,
Ted CNN time.
Whether you are looking to create a
personal blog, a business site, both,
neither,
something else,
you'll make a huge impact when you
build your website on wordpress.com and
directly from some friends at Google.
I'm not going to quote them by name,
but they say that wordpress offers
the best out of the box SEO.
That's search engine optimization
imaginable, so if you're on wordpress,
you immediately have a leg up on everybody
else on search engines and so forth.
In my experience, I'm no medical
doctor of search engine optimization,
but I will say that I used wordpress
for years and fell in love with it.
To the extent that I became very
close friends with Matt and then uh,
became an investor slash
advisor to automatic,
which runs wordpress sock on that is how
much I believe in this and that's how a
lot of my most successful products and
investments have come about because I'm
in love with x and then I seek out x.
Nearly 30% of the Internet
is run on wordpress and that
includes everything from
the huge sites that I mentioned to
neighborhood sites and it is super easy to
get started. There's no need to worry
about security or upgrades or hosting.
They offer 24 seven support
and handle all of that,
which allows you to focus on creating
the highest quality content that you can
with the least amount of friction.
I don't have to worry about downtime.
I don't want to have to
worry about getting emergency
emails if I'm on vacation
or something like that. And wordpress
is my goto solution for all of this.
I trust all of my most important text
on the Internet to wordpress and they
can't buy that with a sponsorship.
They can't buy that with anything.
I want uptime, uptime,
uptime, and quality,
and that is what I have selected
after everything that I've looked at.
So check it out.
Go to wordpress,
that's w o r d p r e s s.com wordpress.com
forward slash Tim to receive 15% off
of your website today.
That's wordpress.com forward slash Tim.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job each and every episode to
deconstruct world class performers of all
different types, whether from
chess, athletics, entertainment,
military or otherwise, to
tease out the habits, routines,
favorite books and so on that you
can test and apply in your own life.
This episode is a little bit
different by popular request.
We have Rhonda Patrick Phd at found my
fitness on the socials who is an American
biochemist and scientist.
Now,
whether you want to extend
life inexpensively by a
stem cell insurance policy,
you have read about that in tools
of titans or guard against cancer.
Rhonda has some very valuable
insights and experiences as well as
recommendations in this episode.
She tackles many of your most
popular requested topics.
This includes many things I've talked
about before that you guys have wanted
more detail and specifics on best
practices for fasting. For instance,
what blood tests are most important
for analyzing overall health?
The minimum effective dose
for the benefits of Sauna
and different types of heat
exposure, heat versus cold exposure.
We've talked about cold baths before,
how can they be used and how
should they be used effectively?
The most effective smart drugs nootropics,
thousands of you have asked me for this,
the latest fat loss research and much,
much more.
A little background on Rhonda.
She is known for her studies of the
mechanistic link between Vitamin D and
Serotonin production research that may
have important implications for the
understanding of autism and other
disorders and she also has a very popular
podcast found my fitness.
Dr. Patrick also conducts clinical trials,
has performed aging research at the Salk
Institute for Biological Studies and
did graduate research at St Jude's
Children's Research Hospital,
which I've had some involvement
with where she focused on cancer,
mitochondrial metabolism and apoptosis.
So I hope you enjoy this conversation,
which is really a master class with
Rhonda Patrick as much as I did.
Thanks for listening.
Hi Guys. Rhonda, Patrick here. Happy
to be here today to get things started.
Let's take an opening question from
Tim Ferriss. Tim Asks, what new areas,
experiments, discoveries, or hypotheses
are you most excited about these days?
Thankfully because I put a certain
percentage of my brain out here on the
Internet,
much of what I'm actively interested in
these days or have an interested in is
actually elucidated a little
bit as necessary context
for some of the questions
I'm going to answer here shortly,
but Tim's question does sort of give
a nice opportunity for an overview.
As a rule,
the things that usually get me really
revved up are ultimately optimizations
that we can make to our lifestyles that
might increase our functional health
span, our wellbeing, and lastly,
cognitive and physical performance.
Usually through deeper
understandings of biology,
health span or healthy functional
lifespan is especially of interest to me.
I sort of lead with that.
To me,
health span is living for as as we
can while doing our best to prevent
deterioration from the diseases of aging.
Talking about increasing health span is
one thing though often achieving it is a
different thing altogether.
The reason this is tricky is that the
most reliable way to treat aging is to try
to instead prevent it and
natural extension of that
fact means that the earlier
we start the better shot we have of
making a large cumulative effect over the
course of our lives.
Now the specifics of how to best
mitigate the damaging effects of aging
specifically is subject to a little bit
of individual variation as a consequence
of each of our little
genetic idiosyncrasies,
the combination of which
are unique to each of us.
This is an area that I'm especially
interested in and that I plan to invest a
little bit more into intellectually
in the coming months,
especially the interface between nutrition
and genetics known as nutrogenomix.
But the good news is there are certain
rule of thumb strategies that are able to
have a positive effect on health
and possibly even longevity.
In some cases it might mean optimizing
our diet around inclusion of specific
nutrients.
One of the most interesting and exciting
of which to me right now is a compound
known as Sulforaphane, spelled
s, u, l, F, O, r, a, p, h, a, n,
e, but also other related compounds that
fall into the same class of compounds,
broadly known as isothiocyanates,
all of which including sulforaphane being
derived from cruciferous vegetables.
What's interesting about so for Fran
is at this compound richly found in
Broccoli sprouts at about
50 to a hundred times.
What's found in mature Broccoli is that
it activates a special genetic pathway
in our cells known as NRF two and it does
so more potently than any other known
naturally occurring dietary compound.
This gene,
a master regulator controls over 200
other genes affecting whether or not
they're activated and doing work.
These include genes that are affect
our own antiinflammatory processes,
antioxidant processes,
and even the ability to inactivate
potentially harmful compounds that we're
exposed to on a daily basis from breathing
in carcinogens like benzine from air
pollution.
In a sense,
we're talking about an on switch from
some of our most native stress responses.
Our ability to cope with physiological
stress down to the cellular level
ultimately affects how rapidly
we accumulate the damage,
which we often refer to as aging.
But, and here's the interesting thing.
The reason NRF two a stress response
pathway is activated by Sulforaphane is
because the compound itself functions
as what we know as a Xeno hormetic a
compound that by virtue of being actually
slightly stressful to cells elicits a
biological stress response,
it has a cumulative effect that is
otherwise a net gain in resilience that
creates a benefit to
the organism as a whole.
This is actually somewhat unintuitive
if you really think about that.
We sort of have this very natural notion
that because excess stress is bad,
we should venture to avoid stress at all
costs. It turns out though that in fact,
perhaps as a consequence of
having received stressful
compounds in our diets for
millions of years,
things that evolved in plants such as
insect Antifa dance that help ward off
insects, we sometimes function
better for having them.
They can even induce neuro
stress responses that boost
neurotrophic factors that
lead to the growth of new neurons and
promote the survival of existing neurons
which may function to help make
compounds likeso for her pain,
potentially a candidate
as a mild nootropic.
We'll probably come back
to this in a little bit,
but the bottom line is is that if we
take this same concept that stress can be
beneficial known as hormesis and apply it
to other things like exercise, fasting,
heat, stress, cold stress,
some of the various benefits that
may be had from these many strategies
similarly come about as a consequence
of sometimes overlapping stress response
pathways.
This idea of hormesis and trying to
improve our capacity to be resilient to
environmental stress and even the stress
generated as a byproduct of normal
metabolism and immune function in
particular is a very useful framework for
evaluating the potential strategies that
might have promise in preventing even
aging. Okay. All of that said,
this is a great opportunity to jump from
these sort of big picture ideas back to
things of a more practical
application variety. Specifically.
The next question evaluates
a straightforward technique
that has caught my
interest and also happens to be broadly
applicable to almost anyone. All right,
so Brandon Beckett asks,
Doctor Rhonda Patrick,
you interviewed Doctor
Valter, Longo, doctor Satchin,
panda and Dr. Ruth Patterson on
time restricted feeding and fasting.
Can you summarize your best practices
for time restricted eating and who it
might not be a good fit for?
Okay, this is a fun question,
but before we dive right into best
practices on time restricted eating,
it probably helps to know what it is.
For the rest of you that may be listening.
Time restricted eating as it's called
an humans or time restricted feeding as
it's referred to an animal research is
this idea that by constraining our eating
within a certain time
window during the day,
ranging from only eight hours up to 12
hours per day, usually earlier in the day,
to align better with our circadian rhythm,
we stand to benefit from a
variety of different angles.
On the more extreme end of eight hours,
you're engaging in a slightly more
extreme type of time restricted eating,
which is more well known in the
fitness world in particular as 16 eight
intermittent fasting simply maintaining
a slightly more conservative time window
than you usually might has started to
show advantages as well potentially
functioning as a lifestyle intervention
that may be able to protect people from
obesity, metabolic related disease and
more at the population level. For example,
even an 11 hour eating window has been
associated in one study with a reduced
risk of breast cancer and potentially
recurrence by as much as 36% in women.
We'll get back to what the research both
mouse and human says about the duration
of the time windows involved,
but first,
let's talk a little bit
about the circadian aspect.
When healthy adults eat meals that
are identical in terms of both their
macronutrient and calorie content
at breakfast, lunch, or dinner,
the postprandial glucose increase is a
lowest after breakfast and highest after
dinner, even though the meals
were a hundred percent identical.
This is just one example that suggests
metabolism changes throughout the day.
We also know that in humans,
metabolic genes are more active during
the day and less active at night.
The underlying reason for this is
because humans are diurnal creatures,
which means that we conduct most of
our activities during the day including
feeding, exercising, and working,
and then resting at night.
What makes humans diurnal creatures is
the presence of an internal clock in the
brain referred to as the super
charismatic nucleus or Scn for short.
The part of this internal clock that
interacts with the external cue of light.
The SCN is also referred to
as the master Oscillator,
but light isn't the only
external cue we have.
We also have food influencing what are
known as peripheral oscillators that
occur in peripheral tissues such as
the liver and influence metabolism,
whereas light is the major
cue for circadian rhythm.
Timing of food intake regulates circadian
rhythm in peripheral tissues as well.
This facts sort of helps to explain why
time restricted eating as it's defined
by doctor Pan does work and that of
others begins with the eating period with
the very first bite or drink of anything
non water because even compounds that
exist in black coffee such as caffeine
can be reasonably expected to produce
metabolic effects that influence these
peripheral oscillators including activity
in the liver.
Everything from making neurotransmitters
to insulin to glucose transport inside
of cells to oxidizing fatty acids to
repairing damage is on a 24 hour cycle
clock that is influenced by these
external cues involving metabolism.
To sort of illustrate the
importance of circadian rhythm,
these clocks regulate thousands
and thousands of genes,
which is somewhere in the neighborhood
of around 10 to 15% of the expressed
human genome,
which means that our most basic metabolic
physiology is meant to be tuned to
behave differently depending
on the time of day that it is.
Even the bacteria that we harbor in
our guts have circadian rhythm with the
species of bacteria changing
according to the time of day.
Some bacteria dominate during the
morning and others during the evening.
Unfortunately with the invention of
artificial lighting and the varying work
schedules,
it has extended peoples eating times
to occur much later in the evening,
and this can have very
negative consequences.
Eating late at night may
also reset peripheral clocks
and result in misalignment
of metabolism,
which means when you wake up,
your metabolism is already
at the end of its cycle.
So that's the logic behind
the circadian aspect,
which gets left out of some
of the intermittent fast
and philosophies that are
popular and explains why time restricted
eating emphasizes an earlier eating
window and includes [inaudible]
xenobiotics as breaking the fast.
Something I've learned as a specific
point if it contention for people. Okay,
but shifting away from the xenobiotics
and circadian aspects to talk more about
the time window itself.
Animals that have been limited to a nine
to 12 hour feeding window in which they
can eat, but otherwise allowing them to
eat the same amount of calories that they
normally would.
They have shown that they can attain
some pretty amazing benefits including
decreased fat mass, increased lean
muscle mass, improved glucose tolerance,
improved lipid profile,
reduced inflammation,
higher mitochondrial volume protection
from mild age related fatty liver
protection from obesity,
generally favorable improvements in gene
expression and increased production of
ketone bodies,
which is interesting for another reason
we'll get back to in a minute time.
Restricted eating also has a
growing body research in humans.
Recent studies suggest that
mentioned briefly earlier,
eating within an 11 hour window was
associated with a decreased breast cancer
risk and reduction in recurrence by
as much as 36% earlier meal timing
associates with improved effectiveness
of weight loss therapy in overweight and
obese people for each three
hour increase in nighttime,
fasting duration was linked with a
20% lower odds of elevated glycated
hemoglobin Hba one c which is a more
longterm marker for Blood Glucose levels
for each 10% increase in the proportion
of calories consumed after 5:00 PM there
was a 3% increase in the inflammatory
biomarkers. C reactor protein,
otherwise known as CRP
eating one additional meal
during the day instead of the
evening was associated with an
8% decrease in c reactor protein.
Eating within a 12 hour window improves
sleep and increased weight loss in
normal weight people.
As a rule of thumb,
anything that has the potential to
mitigate chronic systemic inflammation is
something I personally consider
worth trying to dial in.
Since depression of inflammation is
thought to be one of the most important
predictors of successful longevity that
increases importance with advancing age
and also influences the risk of cancer
and even potentially mental health.
So putting aside the potential to have
better blood glucose control or protect
myself from obesity without actually
changing the composition of my diet.
Reducing systemic inflammation has a lot
of appeal to me now that we're all on
the same page in terms of what some of
the research shows on the benefits of
time restricted eating,
I would like to go back and address
Brandon's question about what my best
practices are surrounded
time restricted eating,
how you choose to implement some of this
information is ultimately going to be
dictated by life circumstances
that include practical
realities surrounding work
schedule and probably a million other
things. The flexibility of my schedule,
however,
has made implementing time restricted
eating admittedly a bit easier unless I
have a social reason that forces
me to eat later in the day.
I usually start my clocks
as soon as I wake up.
Thus I don't concern myself a whole lot
about what counts as breaking the fast
and what doesn't and I go by the strictest
of definitions. If it's not water,
it breaks the fast unless it's just
brushing my teeth. I don't count that.
If I wake up at 8:00 AM and have my first
sip of coffee at eight 15 then I make
a note to myself or I set an alarm on
my phone to go off one and a half hours
before the clock ends,
which is usually around 6:15 PM since I
aim for around a 10 hour eating window
and a 14 hour nighttime fasting window
when I'm feeling especially motivated,
I eat within an eight or nine
hour time window and fast.
We're 15 or 16 hours during the night,
which means if I have my first sip of
coffee at 8:15 AM that I stopped eating by
either four 15 or 5:15 PM I follow
the same procedure on days I sleep in.
Even though animal research shows
that this pattern has benefits,
even if you cheat on the weekend.
Now,
the reason why I chose a 10 hour window
is because it's a sufficiently tight
window of time to likely confer some of
the advantages of time restricted eating
without being unduly burdensome.
Personal compliance here being the issue
stretching for the nine hour or even an
eight hour window. However, it can be also
be interesting and may appeal to some.
Some animal research has shown that a
certain aerobic endurance benefit for time
restricted feeding in this nine hour
range but not for shorter fasts,
and if you think about it,
mice that only feed for nine hour periods
and are fasting for the other 15 hours.
It makes sense.
It takes around 10 to 12 hours for
liver glycogen stores to be depleted,
which is then followed by fatty acids
being liberated from adipose tissue.
These fatty acids are then transported
to the liver where they are converted
into ketone bodies like
Beta hydroxybutyrate,
which are then transported
to a wide variety of other
tissues such as the muscle
and used for energy.
So it sort of makes sense that eating
within a nine hour window and fasting for
15 hours overnight may lead
to endurance enhancements.
If we've managed to kick off a little
more ketone production the evening before
a run.
Anecdotally I've observed that personally
I feel an improvement in endurance
ranging from slight to pretty significant
in my morning runs when I've tried a
little bit harder to eat strictly within
an eight or nine hour time window.
Just as a closing thought,
I think there's still a lot of room for
more emerging research in this area to
teach us things that may be important.
Questions like what influence later
day endurance or weight training has on
mitigating the deleterious effects of
other suboptimal parameters like a later
in the day eating window.
How large the effect of xenobiotics like
caffeine and black coffee is compared
to potentially more important factor like
just keeping an otherwise tighter time
window with a slightly looser
definition of what is considered eating.
If you'd like to see interesting questions
answered about time restricted eating,
you can actually participate in a mobile
APP powered distributed clinical trial
by heading over to doctor
Satchin Panda's lab website,
which can be found@mycircadianclock.org
available for iPhone and android.
Basically you commit to a baseline
and then one of the patterns of time
restricted eating and then proceed to
submit timestamp pictures of your food
over the course of 12 weeks.
Of course,
I'd also be remiss if I didn't mention
that a mutual friend and someone that has
repeatedly been on the Tim Ferriss show,
Kevin Rose has developed a cool mobile
app to help keep track of intermittent
fasting in time restricted eating windows.
You can also check that out
if you're an iPhone user,
it's in the APP store under the name
zero as in the number of calories you
consume while fasting.
To sort of finish off this question,
as for who time restricted
feeding may not be a good fit for,
I'm not sure as an intervention, I
believe it is actually broadly applicable.
However,
I'm 100% certain that there is someone
somewhere for which a unique medical
condition may make time
restricted eating inappropriate,
especially if you expand the definition
of time restricted eating to me long
multiday fast, which should the
subject of Doctor Valter Longo,
his research in particular.
Definitely checking in with the physician,
particularly if you're going to do a
prolonged fast or if you're thinking of
trying time restricted eating but may
have a medical condition that for some
reason might somehow make it
unsafe. Okay. Next question.
Jassi seeing asks for all those that
don't understand the benefits of fasting,
how does doing a fast differ
from say eating a diet low carb,
high fat that puts you into Ketosis
and what key metrics, for example,
blood tests should someone look
at to know it is benefiting you?
Very interesting question because
as implied by the question,
there are at least a few
similarities between a low carb,
high fat diet and fasting, but there
are also obviously some key differences.
Probably the main similarity between
the two is that metabolism shifts from
using glucose as the major source of
energy to primarily oxidation of fatty
acids and ketone bodies as energy.
When it comes to fasting,
there are a few things that really
differentiate it from a low carb high fat
diet. One of the major benefits of
fasting, particularly prolonged fasting,
which is around four to five
days in humans that is not
found on a low carb high
fat diet is a dramatic increase in
autophagy and a pop ptosis followed by a
massive boost in stem cell production.
I toffee g is a genetic
program that is very important.
It clears away damaged cells to use for
energy while a pop ptosis is a genetic
program that causes damaged
cells to self destruct.
Both of these processes prevent damaged
cells from becoming cancer cells.
When we clear away damaged cells,
this also means those cells are
less likely to become senescent,
which is what can happen when
too much damage accumulates.
A senescent cell is
technically a living cell,
but it is not functioning in a way
that is consistent with maintaining the
overall health of an organ.
In fact, quite the opposite.
Senescent cells can accelerate the
aging of nearby cells and promote tumor
growth by secreting proinflammatory.