[inaudible].
The most common pattern that I've
seen after interviewing hundreds,
300400500 world class performers at this
point is that at least 80% have some
type of mindfulness or meditation
practice and if you are like me,
perhaps you've heard of this many times
and perhaps you even tried many times
and decided you do not
meditate, you cannot meditate,
you are not designed to meditate,
which is what I concluded for a very,
very long time until I tested a number
of simple options that may work for you
and I would anticipate that really one
or two will stick and have some type of
toehold and you'll be able to then develop
the habit over a week or two of doing
this and I would recommend trying
it first thing in the morning.
Here are a few different options.
Number one is using an app of some type
and there are several that are well
designed.
Headspace would be one the 10 in 10
that's 10 minutes per day for 10 days
straight is very effective. Calm is
another insight timer is yet another.
There are many on top of that. If you
want to go straight to guided meditations,
you could consider looking
for Sam Harris. Uh,
for Tara Brock, Vrac, ACH.
There are many different options and
they range in length so you can choose
something that works for you.
Next option is something like
transcendental meditation
where you actually take
a course and you have that
social accountability and
you pay for it and then you
will work with someone
for four days straight.
You will meditate in between
those sessions and you
will need to report back to
them and it is 20 minutes
per day, twice per day.
Encourage most people, at least I do it
once per day, normally in the morning.
That is mantra based meditation.
Another option is picking one song
that is very uplifting to you.
Like we're going to party
like it's 1999 by prince,
which is the one I actually
use in the early days.
And you simply listen to that song first
thing in the morning and focus on your
breath and you want to sit
in a comfortable position.
So I would sit cross legged
with my back against the wall.
You could certainly sit in a chair, you
could sit with your feet on the ground,
hands on your thighs, it doesn't
matter. You want it to be comfortable.
Listen to that song, focus on your
breath and when you focus on your breath,
this is very common advice.
What does that mean? All right,
we should get specific.
So a few recommendations.
You could focus certainly on
feeling it in your lower abdomen.
You can focus on feeling in your chest.
What a lot of people find helpful is
actually focusing on feeling the breath,
the inhale and XL right on
the edges of their nostrils.
And you might even notice that on the
inhale it's cooler and on the exhale it's
warmer, right? Those are two tips
that I find very, very helpful.
And the last recommendation I
would make is actually twofold.
So there two super short
options throughout the day.
If you find yourself feeling stressed
out or anxious or if about to say
something you might regret,
take a three breath break.
This is actually something
I started doing a,
I had heard 10 breaths that seemed
excessive to me, which I know is funny,
but I would pause to just focus
on taking three deep breaths.
That is a form of meditation
and mindfulness present
state awareness training.
The other is something called loving
kindness meditation or Meta TTA meditation
and this is very simple.
Instead of focusing on yourself that
you're going to focus on other people.
This was a breakthrough
for me and actually made a
big difference in my entire
experience in practice meditation and
really all you're going to do is sit down,
eyes closed comfortably and focus
on envisioning someone you care for.
That's where you start
a friend, family member,
whoever it might be and
wishing them joy and happiness.
You can do that any way
you want. All right?
You're wishing them joy and happiness
and a life free of pain and suffering and
you do that for one or two minutes for
one person and then you do it for one or
two minutes for the next.
And I've seen multiple friends try
this and they do it for five minutes,
either first thing in the morning
or right before going to bed,
and at the end of the week they tell me
that is the best week I've had in years.
All right, so that's another
option that you can test out.
So those are whatever it is, six, seven,
eight different options. Try them all.
You could try one a day for
a week. Find one that sticks.
And the imperfect program,
the good program that you follow is
better than the perfect program you don't
follow. So pick something
simple, get started,
and you can always add to it later.