Hello Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the Tim Ferriss show.
What you're about to hear is part two
of a multipart conversation with Kevin
Kelly, Co, founder of wired magazine
and all around fascinating guy.
If you didn't catch the first part,
you might want to do
that before venturing in,
but we cover a lot of topics and it's
a conversation, so if you don't mind,
your stories is more of a jigsaw puzzle,
then by all means keep on listening.
So without further ado,
please enjoy part two of the Tim Ferriss
show with Kevin Kelly. All show notes,
links,
et Cetera,
can be found@fourhourworkweek.com
forward slash podcast and thank you for
listening.
I think this attitude I can flat
out before my hands start to shake.
I'm a cybernetic organism living
does show what metal endoskeleton.
Does religion play
a large part in your life right now
in a certain sense?
Not in a kind of a ritual success.
I just wrote a book called
what technology wants
excellent book.
I highly recommend it.
Theory of,
of technology.
And I was trying to put technology
in the context of the cosmos.
So I think what religion gives me
his permission to think about cosmic
questions.
I'm right in the middle of finishing a
Kickstarter funded graphic novel that's
about angels and robots.
And the intention there was
to fictionalize the idea
that robots would some days
have souls, but these souls
would be coming from angels.
And so that there was this intersection
of these two and if possible worlds of
conscious robots who were in,
sold by angels and, and the,
and the reason why this
was sort of interesting was
that the idea was that, um,
the angels that insole us
have been trained, they had
been given moral guidance,
but if you don't give the spirits and
kind of moral guidance than they can wreck
havoc. And so it was this
idea that when we make robots,
we're actually going to have
to train them to be ethical.
We can't make a free
being and not train it.
So it was a way to rehearse and think
about some of the consequences of
technology today.
So I think my religion gives me
permission to ask those questions without
embarrassment to say, well, um,
what is the general direction
of the arc of evolution?
What is it pointed somewhere?
How does technology fit
into the greater cosmos?
What does it mean?
What drives it?
Why is there more of it?
Is this a good thing?
And so I think having a kind of,
I consider this kind of an other
view. So I have, uh, other view, the,
I'm sympathetic to other world views.
I don't necessarily have to believe
all the other world's you'd,
but I get the idea that if you have
an another world view that can be very
helpful in seeing other worldviews.
So people have a worldview,
even though they don't know it.
But I have a review and I
know that I ever, I mean,
really everybody has a religious
or a spiritual orientation.
Even if they're atheists,
they still have one.
And so there are some assumptions
that are at the basis of it.
And I like to question assumptions,
including my own assumption.
Two things I can't resist asking and we
can spend as much or as little time on
this as you'd like.
But recently grappling with a lot of
these issues of that I've been grappling
with, some of which are existential,
some which are related to death,
limited time on the planet.
I've become deeply fascinated by
indigenous use of plant medicine.
And I've had some very transformative
experiences that are difficult to put into
words because they make you sound
like a complete crazy person.
But yeah,
there's a somethingness that is a very
difficult to communicate without sounding
like you should be institutionalized.
What do you think the role for people
who aspire to do the greatest good in the
world,
what is the role of that type of direct
experience and is it possible to benefit
from that type of,
for lack of a better descriptor,
spiritual experience without a
religious framework around it?
Yeah, no, it's, it's a
really good question. So my
little personal story there,
of course the,
I was basically,
that was basically hippie or worked
for the hippie catalog and [inaudible]
catalog, which was about hippies
living in San Francisco. And, um,
all my friends were drug taking hippies,
but I for some reason never did.
I just had no appetite or inclination
at all for ever taking any drugs or
smoking pot or anything.
And when I was 50 years old,
I decided that I would like to,
to take Lsd sacramentally
on my 50th birthday.
And I did and I arranged with,
uh,
had a guide and I had appropriate setting
and I had some acid that I came from a
source that was extremely reliable and
it was a sacrament and it was a very
profound sacrament. And I think, yeah,
you can use drugs and recreationally and
for entertainment and I think that can
go somewhere. But I think there
was another powerful use of it,
which is kind of what
you're talking about it,
which is to elevate one
outside of yourself,
to lose yourself,
to be in contact with other
things beyond your ego.
And I think it can be done.
And I think unfortunately because of
the illegal status that we've had for a
long time,
the rituals and the practice around that
have not had chance to be developed or
communicated. Actually trying to find
this information. It was extremely hard.
It was one book that I did find
eventually from a guy who was doing LSD
experiments while they were still legal
and was able to accumulate enough wisdom
about it that that would be the
one place I would point people to.
But I think it is important that the
context and expectations and the,
the setting they call it, that that
revolves around it is very important.
And I do believe that these
can be extremely profound
and powerful experiences
for good. They can remain
long after. And you know,
most people who understand
this and don't abuse it,
understand that in fact the
experience was not in the pill,
was not in the chemical.
It was a real experience.
And so unfortunately there's so much
other stuff circulating around the use of
these drugs and the misuse of them that,
that it kind of information is often very,
very difficult to find.
But I do think maybe we're seeing a
moment now in the u s where the second
prohibition is being undone and at least
pot will become legal and maybe we can
return to revitalizing the
traditions and the necessary,
uh, settings are around that and
expectation that I'm not just potter LC,
but even other synthetic drugs can be
extremely powerful in removing the,
um, ordinary guards that we have. And
when we have an ego for on purpose,
we have all these things to keep
us sane in a day to day. Um,
functional exactly. Standpoint. Yeah.
Right. And so if you remove a completely,
you can become dysfunctional,
but if you remove it deliberately and
with great care, you can be opened up.
And I think it's that, you know, I
think there's an expertise there.
I think there's a lot of other
things that, that, that, um,
if we have the freedom and
the wisdom to not abuse it,
I think it can be extremely powerful. Do
you recall the title of the book? Okay.
So this is, or how people might
search for him? Yes. So this is, uh,
one of the many resources
that I recommend in my book.
Cool tools and cool tools is a
big catalog of possibilities.
It has about 1500 different items.
A lot of them are kind of like handles,
you know,
pliers and the grape cordless drill.
But it's much farther than that.
And I include things like,
what if you wanted to have a psychedelic
experience that was transformative.
What do you do?
And I would recommend this book or,
or I mean there's lots of
other things in it, but the,
I don't actually have the book in front
of me. I should, I think it's called.
Um, I don't remember.
It's okay. I will, uh,
I show notes.
We will list it as the right one.
And there's also a little tiny
book that came from England.
There was a cartoon guide
that gave of a street,
an unjudgemental view of all
the different drugs that were,
and what each one kind of did in Denton.
What the plus and minuses are without,
you know, recommending or forbidding
them. It was just saying this,
this is what it is.
That information also,
believe it or not is really in
short supply. It's like, you know,
what do you do with this and how's
it work and tell me the facts.
I don't need to hear a lecture either way,
like whether this is
great or this is terrible,
but just tell me what what's
going on. As, as you know,
I mean that kind of information
sometimes is extremely in short supply,
it's very difficult to find information
that isn't politicized. Yeah,
inaccurate or like you said,
so shrouded in either fear or irrational
optimism that it's almost intelligible
and certainly generally useless.
We'll put those books in
the show notes for people.
I want to come back to
one thing you said far,
far earlier and that was related to the
pieces that you tried to give away that
eventually wouldn't die and came back.
Were there any common threads,
any patterns in those pieces that that
you can pick out as being sort of a
uniquely Kevin Kelly theme
if for lack of a better term?
One of the things that I discovered in
my six months of trying to live as if I
was going to die in six months. Because
as I was coming closer to that date,
which happened to be Halloween,
October 31st it was I kept
cutting off my future.
I mean maybe like you,
I kind of tend to live in the
future of much more than path.
I'm always imagining I'm
saving this for something,
that I'm going to do this and
I'm kind of looking forward,
I'm going to do this here.
And so I was very much in the future
and then something that future was being
cut down day by day. I was
like, and I was thinking like,
why am I taking pictures,
taking the photographs because I'm not
going to be here in another two months or
something.
So,
so there was all these things that I'm
kind of cutting out and as I was cutting
them out, I had this realization, which
was the thing I took away from this thing,
which was that I was becoming less human.
That to be fully human,
we have to have a future.
We have to look forward to the future.
That is part of us is
looking into the future.
And so after I came out of the,
and I kind of embrace that and saying,
well you know that future forward facing,
that's what I do. That's what,
that's what I want to do.
And that's what I write about.
And in thinking about the future,
one of the things that is very hard,
because the paradox about the future is
that there are lots of impossible things
that happen all the time.
And if someone from the a hundred years
from now would come back and tell us
things, there's a lot of stuff we've
just not going to believe this.
It's like that's just,
that's crazy.
It's just like if we went back a hundred
years and told them what was going on
now they would say, you know,
that's just not going to happen.
I mean we could even go back 20 years.
I can go back 20 years and say we're
going to have like Google street views of
all the cities of the world and
we're going to have, you know,
and it's like a PD this for free, this
edited by anybody. You know, I was like,
they would say, you know, there's
no way I would tell them, you know,
most of it's for free.
They were saying there is no economic
model in the world that allow for that and
there isn't. But here it
is. So the dilemma is,
is there any true forecast about the
future is going to be dismissed any future
that is believable. Now it's going to be
wrong. And still you're stuck in this.
Like if people believe it is wrong,
if they don't believe it, you know,
where does it get you?
You're just missing.
So there was this very fine line between
saying something that is right on the
edge of plausibility at the same time,
right on the edge of having
a chance of being true.
And what I discovered that was helpful
and trying to get away from the kind of
assumptions that binus had,
just kind of extrapolate
was to think laterally,
was to go sideways.
One thing,
just take whatever was everybody knew
and say, well, what if that wasn't true?
A good example of that or an
example like everyone says, okay,
Moore's law will continue Moore's law.
It didn't continue. What would that mean?
What would happen,
and you can maybe I could
say for the audience,
but I'll just say even to remind me,
Moore's law is what
does it every 18 months,
the the size and cost of technology will
decrease by 50% something along those
lines. Let's say even worse,
there's speed involved as well,
right? More than it does say
that, but, but let's say subbing.
Right now we live in a world where
every year the technology is better and
cheaper. What if that wasn't true?
What if every year starting like,
you know, couple years from now stuff
was better but more expensive. That's,
that's a completely different world,
right?
Everyone assumes that things are
going to get better and cheaper. Well,
what if that wasn't true? So you can
take kind of an assumption that, again,
that's something that no one's
really examining like, uh, well,
one of the things I write about is
the fact that we're going to have a
population implosion globally,
that the global population
will drastically reduce in
a hundred years from now.
We'll have less population far, far,
far less than we have right now. And so,
all right, I have to bite it. That what,
because I've thought a lot about this
and the a, what would they call it?
The Mel Malthusian dilemmas.
Is that going to be,
do you think pandemic related, nuclear
weapon related, all of the above?
None of those. None of those,
no. Ai Coming into the,
the rise of the machines?
No.
Okay.
It's just pure demographics.
So if you look at the current trends
in fertility rates in all the developed
countries everywhere,
except for the u s they're already
either below replacement level.
So replacement level of means that you
just sustaining the population just
replaces itself. If it's
below, it means that there's,
it was getting less and less. So
Japan, all of these, you know, Europe,
they're all below replacement.
The U S is an exception because
of only because of immigration.
Got It.
Where people coming in,
otherwise we would be there and it
just would not be any news to anybody.
But the real news of people would
point a developing world. But you know,
Mexico is now aging faster than the u s
China is aging faster because of their
one child policy. Of course, Japan is
this completely is there a way underwater?
Completely. So even the one
exception is Subsahara Africa.
And there's really a kind of debate right
now about how fast or whether they're
slowing down, but generally around the
world, South America, the rest of Asia,
the rate and fertility continues to drop.
And here's the thing is that the
demographic transition that is happening
everywhere where people become urban.
And so every forecast shows the urbanity
the certification of the population
continuing.
And I can't think of any counter force
to stop these huge migration at the scale
that we're seeing into the city.
And as that happens,
the birth rates dropped down.
And even in places like Singapore or
other places where they have taken very,
very active countermeasures of cash for
having kids and daycare forever bonuses,
none of these work in terms of actually
trying to raise fertility levels.
So you have to understand that
to go above replacement level,
the average woman has to have 2.1 kids.
Well that means it has to be tons and
tons of women who have three or four kids
make up for those.
How many people do you know
with that many kids, you know,
living in cities and there's just
not, there's not enough of them. So,
and this is a projection. Some of these
are you in productions, they have three,
three,
they have a low high and a medium and
the low one is not good news because
there's not a large cultural counter
force for women to have three a lot,
you know,
a very high percentage of the publishing
to have three or four kids in a modern
world.
And that's why the the published and
continues to decrease every year.
What type of,
this is perhaps a tangent,
but one of the big debates in my head
right now is to marry or not to marry,
to have kids or not to have kids.
I never thought those would even be
questions in my mind and yet here I am in
and now they are. What are your thoughts
on having children? What type of people?
This is very broad but should have
children or shouldn't have children.
Whichever way of answering is easier or
how to even think about that question.
I think people who are privileged of
which you are should have children because
you can bestow so many privileges and
opportunities to your children and if the
world has to be populated,
why not populate it with children who
have as many opportunities as possible.
I also say from my own experience of
growing up one of many kids and having,
well I have three kids.
Uh,
one of my other regrets in life is
not having a fourth, but we were just,
we started a little bit too late and we
were unable to have a fourth but all my
kids with that we had a fourth to,
and I would say that as a gift to
your kids to have more than one.
And I know that from hanging out in
shiner where so many kids grew up only
children and this really,
really miss that there is a total gift
of the siblings and brothers to each
other. That is really very
profound. And there is also,
I know from my friends who have had
lots of kids that there is a tremendous
amount of teaching from the,
the older to the younger and that's
a lot of what they've learned.
And that the uh,
curve of the amount of energy that you
have to expand actually after three,
it doesn't really matter in
terms of the parents. Got It.
I have one friend who has nine kids and
I have another friend who has seven. Wow.
And basically how do they do
that? Well, the older kids,
we're helping to parent the younger kids.
That's the only way that it really works.
But there's actually basically they have,
you know,
they have five parents
instead of having two parents.
Right.
It's very traditional in a way.
I mean traditional meaning reaching back
thousands or tens of thousands of years.
It is of course in the old days,
maybe a 12 born,
but they rarely had 12 kids survive.
Right.
So that actually is a very
recent or I mean as far as like,
it's like the 18 hundreds kind of onward.
I hang out with the Amish a lot and they
still have these very large families
and they all survived.
So they have kind of,
in some sense it's sort
of an unnatural expansion.
And one of my predictions, again going
back to kind of like the assumptions,
one of my predictions is that,
you know,
in America in a hundred years from now
or whatever it is, there'll be, um,
the complete countryside
is run by the Amish.
The Amish take over the entire countryside
because they never sell and they have
like eight kids.
And then there are always people living
in the cities and it's like everybody's
happy. You know, you were all living
in the drive out to the Amish lands.
It's just fantastic. And uh,
they're very happy, you know,
doing their thing and running the farms.
And so I had been predicting
for years that dom,
which would come in and start
buying upstate New York.
And that's exactly what
they're doing right now.
Why do you spend so much time with the
Amish? This is news to me, but very,
very interesting.
And how long has that been going on
for awhile.
And does your beard have anything?
Is there any relation to the Amish?
I had the beard before my
interest in the armory show.
I'll show you some pictures
when I was 19 years old.
I do have those that don't
know I have an Amish beard,
which means that I have a
beard without a mustache.
The reason why the Amish don't have
mustaches that was at the time that they
were kind of adopting or dress code,
the mustache was all
military men and mustaches.
And so they were very anti military.
They refuse to serve in the,
they don't even vote,
but so it was there kind of rejection
of the military by shaving off their
mustache.
I hang out with the Amish because their
adoption of technologies is like seems
to us totally crazy because first of all
they're not Luddites complete hackers.
They love hacking technology. They have
something called how much electricity,
which is basically pneumatics.
The lot of these farms have a big diesel,
they don't have electricity,
but they have a big diesel generator in
the barn that pumps up this compressor,
that sense high pressure air
tubes and tubing into their barn,
into the homes and so they have converted
like their sewing machine washing
machine and stuff to nomadic.
Okay.
Seems like a bit of a sidestep
of the word of God. Exactly.
So we'll have the,
we'll have horse drawn buggies and horse
drawn farm implements and the horses
will be pulling this diesel generated
combine and you're thinking,
what are they doing?
Okay. Right. But in fact,
if you look at our own lives, and I've
done this many times, I can ask you Tim,
or you can ask me.
There'll be some weird thing like
we don't have TV in our house,
but I've got internet. It's like,
well, what is that about? Right?
So we all have these things,
but here's the difference is
the Amish do it collectively.
They're very selective.
They're selecting their technology
collectively as a group. And secondly,
they have to articulate because
they're doing collectively,
you have to articulate
what their criteria is.
A lot of us are adopting you try this.
We tried that.
We don't have any kind of like logic or
reason or theory or framework for why
we're doing stuff. It's just,
it's just one a parade of stuff.
But the Amish have a very particular
criteria and their criteria is there are
two things that they're looking for,
the main thing they want to do,
and the main reason why they have all
these restrictions like horse and buggy
and all this stuff, is that they
want to have these communities,
very strong communities. And so
they noticed that if you have a car,
that you'll drive out and shop somewhere
out of the community or you go to
church somewhere out in the
community or whatever it is.
But if you have a horse and Buggy,
you can go and he 15 miles.
And so everything has to
happen your entire life.
You have to support the community.
You have a community within 15 miles,
you have to visit the sick
and you have to shop locally.
So you're shopping with your neighbors.
So when a new technology
comes along and they say,
will this strength in our
local community or send us out?
And then the second thing that
they're looking at is with families.
So the goal of the typical Amish man or
women is to have every single meal with
their children for every meal
or lives until they leave home.
They have breakfast, they have
lunch, and they have dinner.
So breakfast and lunch is that they go
to one room schoolhouse and they peddle
back for lunch that their
parents had with them.
And that means that the businesses are
ideally in their backyard. So they have,
they have a lot of like shops and stuff.
If they're not a farmer and
they have a backyard shop,
which is actually has to be kind of clean
ish because it is in their backyard,
right? It's like not my, well
it is in their backyard. So
they really are, you know,
they really want,
I'm sure that there of metal working
shops and stuff would say really try to
keep nontoxic and work because
it's in their backyard.
And so that means that they
can come home for lunch.
They have breakfast and lunch,
so they're there on the premises and
they have every single meal with their
children until they leave.
And so they say, well,
what does technology allow us
to do that will help us do that?
Or will it work against that?
And then like right now they're,
they've been deciding whether
to accept cell phones are not,
even though they don't have landline
phones. So they're basically,
they're going to,
well,
some of them are going to accept
cell phones and they do that by,
there's always some Amish early adopter
who's trying things and they say, okay,
Ivan Bishop says you can.
He had to get permissions is you can
try this, but we're watching you.
We're going to see what effect this
has on your family, on your community.
You have to be ready to give it up anytime
we say that it's not working and they
do this on a kind of,
Paris by Paris is very decentralized and
so they try out always trying out new
technologies and they're always looking
to see does this strengthening the
families is a strengthening the
communities? If not, we don't want it.
What have you. I have two questions. I
guess the first is since you're normally,
as I understand it, based on the
west coast and northern California,
how do you get out to the Amish or is
there a separate community closer by and
then secondly, what have you
incorporated into your own life or your,
you're on family that
originated from the Amish.
Yeah. So I don't get to see
them as often as it went.
But actually it was when I go east,
I have some contacts that
I will exercise and um,
I would try to get,
like to stay overnight and go to
church and a buggy or something.
And this is Pennsylvania, but, well
actually Pennsylvania is the heart of it.
But actually there are more communities
in Ohio where my brother lives in Iowa.
There's a lot more happening
in New York, so, so the,
the Pennsylvania or the kind of ground
zero, but in fact they're bigger,
more extensive communities
outside of Pennsylvania.
I didn't realize that.
Yeah, the Amish Diaspora,
it is what I'm saying. They literally
are just buying up farmland there.
They're expanding,
they're constantly expanding.
They have a very small
attrition rate. Very large
families. They all are buying a,
basically they're buying
farms and stuff for their,
for their children and they never sell.
And so they also don't,
he move into areas as a,
they have a minimum number of families
that we need to move in at once.
But what did I learn from the,
well, one of the things that we had,
particularly when we had younger kids
was kind of technological sabbaticals or
satisfy, I should say. And I've now
seen other families who aren't even, um,
you know, aren't even religious.
Adopt that same thing,
which is once a week you
take a break from either,
you could define it however you want
it to screen or the keyboard or, or,
or connectivity or something and
you step back and you do that.
Not because it's like terrible
or poisoned, but because
it's so good. You know,
there's lots of people were kind of like,
they're going to drop out from
Twitter or they're kind of like, oh,
this is like a toxin I got
to get detoxed or something.
I think that's entirely wrong way to
think about it is you want to take brace
and it's not because they're toxic,
but because they're are so good.
It's like you want to step back so that
you can reenter it and with a renewed
perspective with a renewed appreciation,
with having spent time
looking at it a different way.
And I think that kind of rhythm of
having sabbaths and then yearly Sabbat,
uh, vacations, wherever, retreats and
then every seven years or whatever it is,
you take a, um, a true sabbatical.
I think that kind of rhythmic
disconnection or Sabbath
I think is very powerful.
It's something that,
that works very well and it was
something that we had in our family.
I take Saturdays off as it turns
out, as my screenless day, I really,
I really try to make that a
weekly occurrence and it's
incredible the, yeah, the,
the effect that,
that it has this sort of galvanizing
effect of just a mere 24 hours.
Not even that, if you just consider
the waking hours every seven years,
a vacation or sabbatical of how long
in your case or your family's guys?
Yeah.
Partly because my wife actually is
granted a sabbatical from the company she
works for,
which is Genetec.
It was one of the few
companies that actually have
a official sabbatical for all
other researchers at least. And
it's very meager. It's six weeks.
Of course, you know, a six week
sabbatical is basically a European and
well, the vacation, right?
You know, blackboard,
American, right. It's three years,
big thing. So yeah. So
we're, we're do something,
do something different.
So this year we're taking one and we're
going to camp in national parks for one
month of it. And then the other
two weeks we'll go to Asia.
But we haven't been to
allow the national parks,
I'm going to do a different
kind of project and I
haven't done before and we'll
do some kind of car camping. We haven't
really done a big road trip like that.
So it's all new for us.
What is the longest in the last few
years that you've gone without checking
email?
Oh,
probably two weeks.
And in China.
How do you manage that? Well,
but it was like, I just,
I was unable
bigger that because
China was blocking Google
makes, makes it, makes
it more challenging.
And I was in, um, I was in
some remote places and so
even the connection was hard,
but it was like they weren't, uh,
they weren't letting me get it.
I'm not a mobile person. My first
smart phone was an iPhone five and um,
I still not using it properly.
I use it for phone call.
Yeah. I don't, I don't use my iPhone as
an input device either. I just, yeah,
it just drives me nuts.
Can't type. When I travel, I
liked it to leave everything.
I spent a lot of my time
sitting in front of a computer.
I'm kind of like the Zen, you know,
walk walks. It's it, the wobble.
So like I'm here,
I'm like really online.
And then when I leave this studio,
I don't want to be connected at all and
I won't be, and I'm not checking email,
I'm not checking this other stuff.
And I can go days.
Typically I'll go days without choking,
even in the u s if I'm traveling.
And then if I'm overseas I will go
probably a three or four days before I get
the email.
That's pretty typical.
Do you, um, let me shift
gears just a little bit.
I'm looking at looking at long
now. Dot Org. Eric Command,
everybody take a look at it. The long
now foundation and humans are generally,
I would say pretty bad
at thinking longterm. Uh,
certainly when it comes to habit change,
very,
very high failure rate
with longterm incentives.
You're going to get diabetes in 20 years
for instance as opposed to you'll have
more sex if you have a six
pack when it comes to diet.
But the long now foundation,
I just want to read a few things
on this website for people.
So the long now foundation was established
in 1996 written as zero one nine nine
six two creatively foster,
long longterm thinking and responsibility
in the framework of the next 10,000
years. Then you have the 10,000 year
clock, which is a monument scale,
multimillion. Yael, all mechanical
clock is an icon to longterm thinking.
The Rosetta Project building an archive
of all documented human languages,
long bets. Featured bed
is here, Warren Buffet,
protege partners and LLC see a public
arena for enjoyable competitive
predictions of interest to society with
philanthropic money at stake and then
revive and restore, which is bringing
extinct species back to life.
So there is a lot here.
Can you explain to people,
cause I've,
I've greatly enjoyed many of the
seminars and speeches of the long now
foundation.
I'm a supporter.
I suppose I've even spoken there on
stage and love the email Synopsys uh,
that Stewart sends out. What is the
function of the long now foundation when,
what is the value?
The Lone Alpha addition is kind of
reactive is it's reacting to the very
inherent short term bias that our society,
particularly this technological society
particularly say that Silicon Valley
exhibits, which is often a focus on the
next quarter or the next two quarters,
the next year results needing
to be immediate, you know,
instant satisfaction.
If something's not on Netflix streaming,
we don't even wait for the DVD.
It's this really kind of very fast paced
short term thinking and also somewhat
blinded by the fact that we don't have a
lot of sense of history either. That um,
we're kind of ignorant about what's
happened in the past. And so the term,
the long now came from Brian Eno who
noticed that we have a very short now,
which is like the next five
minutes in the last five minutes.
And so the long hours a week is an attempt
to kind of expand that so that we as
a society and as individuals would try
to think about things at a generational
or civilizational scale.
So like how about like working
on something that might
take longer than your own
lifetime to accomplish?
So you start something now,
there may be make it so that it might
take like the cathedrals of all it would
if we were trying to make something that,
you know,
might need 25 years to accomplish,
how can we do that?
So we're trying to encourage people
to think in that perspective,
to take that perspective and then
to maybe move in that direction.
We're not necessarily saying we have to
have like the a mohs foundation where we
have to have like a master plan for the
next hundred years and we're going to
plan out the future.
No,
we're agnostic about what it
is that people make or do.
We're just saying that it
would benefit having, um,
thinking about the long term. And
I've often heard, uh, some people, uh,
who advised to counseling to individuals
about kind of thinking about the
longterm in your own life,
even though you might want to act
kind of locally and be spontaneous,
but you do want you to do one to kind
of keep in mind the fact that you know,
you'll be around for a while,
whether it's putting some savings away
or working on a skill that may take some
time,
more than the six months or a
year to acquire or you know,
whatever it is that you
can have both perspectives.
And so we're not attempting to get rid
of the need for people to survive the
need for companies to
have a profit this year.
We're saying there can be
additional perspectives.
In addition to that where we
say we commit to like a sigh,
a program of science research where it's
a pure science and the results of the
same mathematics is one of the most
profound things that we can invest in.
Even though most of the things in the
beginning seemed to be non utilitarian.
They don't have any purpose, but we
know from our own history that you know,
in 20 years they'll pay
off in some way or other.
And so being able to kind of construct
a society so that we can allow the
rewards of longterm investment,
longterm thinking,
long term perspective that would
make us better civilization.
I love the long definition. I encourage
everybody to check it out long. Now
you want more of the Tim Ferriss show,
you can subscribe to the podcast
on iTunes or go to for our blog.com
where you'll find an award winning blog,
tons of audio and video
interview stories with people like Warren
Buffett and Mike Shinoda from Lincoln
Park, the books plus much, much more.
Follow Tim on twitter@twitter.com
slash t Ferris.
That's t e R R I s s or on Facebook
at facebook.com/tim Ferris.
Until next time,
thanks for listening.