Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking. Now
I'm a cybernetic organism.
This episode is brought to
you by Wealthfront and this
is a very unique sponsor.
Wealthfront is a massively disruptive
in a good way, set it and forget it.
Investing service led by technologists
from places like apple and world famous
investors.
It has exploded in popularity in the last
two years and they now have more than
two and a half billion dollars
under management. In fact,
some of my very good friends,
investors in silicon valley have millions
of their own money in Wealthfront.
So the question is why? Why is
it so popular? Why is it unique?
Because you can get services previously
reserved for the ultra wealthy but only
pay pennies on the dollar for them,
and this is because they use smarter
software instead of retail locations,
bloated sales teams, et cetera. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
I suggest you check out wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim take the risk
assessment quiz which only takes two to
five minutes and they'll show you for
free exactly the portfolio they'd put
you in and if you just want to take their
advice, run with it, do it yourself.
You can do that or as I would,
you can set it and
forget it and here's why.
The value of Wealthfront is in the
automation of habits and strategies that
investors should be using on a regular
basis but normally aren't great investing
is a marathon,
not a sprint,
and little things that you may or may
not be familiar with like automatic tax
loss harvesting,
rebalancing your portfolio,
cross more than 10 asset classes and
dividend reinvestment add up to very large
amounts of money over longer periods
of time. Wealthfront, as I mentioned,
since it's using software
instead of retail locations,
etc. Can offer all of this at low
costs that were previously completely
impossible right off the bat,
you never pay commissions or
account fees for everything.
They charge 0.25% per year on assets above
the first 15,000 which is managed for
free. If you use my link,
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim,
that is less than $5 a month to invest
a $30,000 account for instance. Now,
normally when I have a sponsor on the
shows because I use them and recommend
them, in this case,
it's a little different.
I don't use Wealthfront yet because
I'm not allowed to. Here's the deal.
They wanted to sponsor this podcast,
but because of sec regulations,
companies that invest your money are
not allowed to use client testimonials.
So I couldn't be a user end
have them on the podcast,
but I've been so impressed by Wealthfront
that I've invested a significant
amount of my own money, at least for me,
uh, in the team and the company itself.
So I am an investor and hope
to soon use it as a client.
Now back to the recommendation
as a Tim Ferriss show listener,
you'll get $15,000 managed for free
if you decide to open an account.
But just start with seeing the portfolio
that they would suggest for you.
Take two minutes, fill out their
questionnaire@wealthfront.com
forward slash.
Tim It's fast.
It's there's
no downside that I can think of. Now I
do have to read a mandatory disclaimer.
Wealthfront Inc is an SEC
registered investment advisor.
Investing in securities involves risks
and there is the possibility of losing
money. Past performance is no
guarantee of future results.
Please visit wealthfront.com to read their
full disclosure, so check it out. Guys.
This is one of the hottest most
innovative companies coming out of Silicon
Valley and they're killing
it. They've become massively
popular. Just take a look,
see what portfolio they would create
for you and you can use that information
however you want.
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim
this episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is a great partner for
creating and growing your business.
It's a one stop shop for
all of your graphic design
needs, whether that's a logo,
website, business card, or anything else.
I used 99 designs to get book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to become a number
one New York Times bestseller.
I also use them for banner
ads, illustrations, and other
things. With 99 designs,
designers around the world compete
to create the best design for you.
You give feedback and
then pick your favorite.
You end up happy or you get your
money back. It's very simple.
You can check out a few of my
own designs and those of yours,
meaning Tim Ferriss,
show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and right now my
listeners, you guys will get a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
That's 99 designs.com forward
slash. Tim, check it out.
Amelia Boone has been called the Michael
Jordan of obstacle course racing since
the sports inception.
She's a mask and she's laughing more
than 30 victories and 50 podiums.
Her major victories include the Spartan
race world championship 2003 Spartan
race series point champion 2013 and 2015
and she's the only three time winner of
the world's toughest mudder,
2012 14 and 15.
She's also three times finisher of the
death race and dabbles in ultra running
in all of her first pair of time,
which I'm sure is massive,
uh, and has a flourishing and
high velocity career to boot.
Emilia, welcome to the show. Thank you.
Yeah, I appreciate you taking the time.
And I thought we could start with a photo.
So I was doing research for
this and went to your website,
which is Amelia Boone racing yes.com.
And can you describe the photo that
takes up most of the real estate on that
page?
Well, so the website needs a
bit about dating. I'm not, um,
a great website person. So
if, you know, if anybody wants
to volunteer, be my guest,
but it's a picture of me.
I'm,
I'm in the middle of barbed wire and I'm
crawling on my hands and knees and I'm
just kind of looking
around, semi perplexed. Um,
and to me that just kind of encapsulates
everything that I do. I'm bleeding from,
you know, my knees, my elbows,
and it's just crawling through the mind,
having a good time.
Microcosm. Exactly. The face of
obstacle course racing. Exactly.
It's not pretty.
And we met through Scott Keneally who is
putting together and may be finished by
the time people see this in
available rise of the suffer fests.
So suffer fest mentioned the blood, you
mentioned the dirt, the barbed wire.
Uh,
maybe we can explain to people who are
unfamiliar what obstacle course racing is
with the example of the
world's toughest mudder.
You describe what on earth that is.
Well, so that's kind of like the extreme
of obstacle course racing, right?
But in general, I mean, I think people
have been familiar with Spartan races.
With tough mudders,
you see people jumping over fire and
crawling under barbed wire and um,
it's just,
you know,
you're running along and you have a wall
to climb and you're jumping through mud
and you're using everything that you have,
um,
like it's just completely
physical experience. Um, but,
so I got involved back in 2011 when I
ran a tough matter with friends and then
signed up for,
there was this race that was announced
called world's toughest mudder,
and they're like,
you for 24 hours are going to
run as many laps of a course,
a tough mudder course as you can,
and it's going to be in
December in New Jersey. Um,
and so it like a bombing. I was like, man,
I can't think of anywhere. I'd rather
go. Then, uh, uh, New Jersey in December.
Um, and, uh, so a bunch of us sign,
I think a thousand people
signed up for this, like,
and nobody had any idea what
they were getting into. You know,
we'd all run like a tough mudder
or run a spartan race. Um,
but nobody had ever really
done it for 24 hours. Um,
so we went out that day and people
were trying to figure out like,
how do you stay warm for 24 hours when
you're in and out of water and, um,
you know, and it's December
and it's New Jersey. Um,
so we decided that we would wear wetsuits
or that wetsuits would be the way and
to stay warm and other people form
of triathletes, we're like, oh,
there's no way you can run for 24 hours
in a wet suit. You'll die. You know,
like the how your thermo regulation
will be all off or whatever.
Um,
but we did and,
and like halfway through,
so we all go out. Um,
and it's like 30 degrees outside
New Jersey. After the first lap,
there are about a thousand
people that would start,
I'd say maybe 850 people
dropped out first lap,
like,
like done
what,
like an hour or like a few hours into it?
Probably like an hour and a half.
And I remember going back in my tent
and like just shivering uncontrollably
being like, what am I doing? Like what,
what is going on here? You know, um,
you like walk past like the Med tense
and there were just people and they're
like lane on cots. They were using
like céline bags to like warm,
say lean to put under people's arms,
like a, like armpits to keep them warm.
And, um, so a few of us decided to keep
that we, you're going to keep going.
Um, and I think by, you know,
the night descended on us,
it was like 2:00 AM we were like walking
through the Wa wading through water and
like there was ice forming where like,
you know, breaking holes in the ice.
And I'm sitting here being like, what
am I doing? Like what am I doing?
But at the same time he's
having so much fun, um,
and out of a thousand people that
started that race, 12th finished
and I was one of two women.
Um, and uh, so that was,
that was the start of it all. And
I, uh, for some unknown reason,
I remember when I finished that race,
24 hours later, I was like, never again,
never again. And then like two weeks
later I'm like, sign me up. What's,
what's next? Sign me up. So, and the,
the drive to do this type of thing.
There's so many different approaches
I could take to try to dissect this.
But are your parents very surprised?
Not surprised at all or
somewhere in between?
Um,
I would say somewhere in between because,
so I've always been like
the high achiever type A,
you know, um, you know, I'm, I wouldn't
be at the top of my class. I wouldn't be,
you know,
like graduating summa cum loud and going
to law school and everything like that.
So I think,
yeah,
I read that one of your law
school classmates said that
you would find a way to
be competitive or to win in anything if
it were folding laundry or otherwise.
Oh yeah. Hey, I like if
I was like in law school,
these set of like my exercise is like
getting on the elliptical, you know,
like everybody else and I would like
find a way to compete next on the person,
like on the elliptical next to me.
Um, him, those are the days. Um,
but so I think the drive and
the determination like that
doesn't phase, you know,
like my parents like par for the course.
Um,
but in terms of like how
it manifested itself,
cause I've always been kind of like a
creature of routine and like I don't like
surprise.
It is and I want to be able to like,
like plan everything and know everything.
And with obstacle course racing,
it's so unknown when you go out
there, like for the most part, um,
when it first started, like they won't
even show, you wouldn't see of course map.
So you want to know what was out there.
And so I think that part
of their kind of like, wow.
Or like when I would sign up for the
death race and they would be like 72 hours
in the wood,
it's then you don't know what you're
going to be doing but have at it.
And so that was very kind of like
a typical personality for me. Uh,
where did you grow up? I grew up
in Portland, Oregon and Portland.
And what did your parents do growing up?
So my dad was an insurance
adjuster and, uh, my mom was, uh,
an environmental consultant.
Where did the competitive edge come from?
I have not said it's funny. He's like,
they have no idea. And like I have,
I think it's gotta be a Nate to be totally
honest because my parents were always
like, you can get C's,
that's fine or you can,
you can play this sport or you don't
have to play this sport or as long as
you're happy you just do what makes you
happy. And so there was more Portland.
It's never, it was never like, if
you think of like sage parents,
I was like the opposite of that.
Um,
so they were always telling me to
like calm down and take a break. But
Stat, I just thought it worked well.
Yeah. Right. Do you have siblings?
I do. I have an older
sister. Older sister, yeah.
She also competitively driven.
I mean we're pretty much like in terms
of personalities, like opposites,
polar opposites, polar opposites.
She's extremely successful.
But she came out about it
from a very like, you know,
way more laid back and you know,
like low key approach.
What to do you want to
be when you were a kid,
what did you want to be when you grew up?
I wanted to be a lawyer when I grow up.
And you nailed it.
I nailed it.
I was one of those people that I was like,
if I set my mind is something
that I'm going to do it.
So I would for lunch every day when I
was like at home during the summer and my
mom and I would always watch
Perry Mason and I was like, man,
Perry Mason like being an attorney,
he gets the bad guy to confess
every single episode.
That's gotta be cool.
Pretty amazing. It's great.
I remember Perry Mason,
so then I went to law school and then
realize that's not actually what happens.
And Yeah,
you were more a Perry Mason
than about lock person. Yes,
yes I was a Perry Mason person.
The,
so you decide you want to be a lawyer
and did that change that waiver or did
that stick with you all the way up until
the point that you became a lawyer?
I think it it pretty much,
you know,
I kind of thought of different
things in college. I really got,
I really fell in love with
anthropology and primates and so like,
you know, I really love
studying. Yeah. Monkeys.
And I thought for a pardon me,
I'm like,
maybe I should go to Madagascar
and hang out with the Lemurs, um,
or I could go get a lot degree.
Um,
so I double majored in anthropology and
political science and then decided to
take the safe route and
go with a lot of degree.
You Washington, uh, Washington
University University, yes. Right.
And uh,
what did you do athletically
in high school or college?
So growing up I was kind of like a,
I would say like a Jack
of all athlete and that
I played,
I was always on like a club team,
like asa softball or club
soccer, um, you know,
traveling basketball. And so I'd play
year round. Um, and I was always good.
I was on like the competitive,
the highest level teams.
I was never like a super standout
Allstar in any one single sport. Um,
so, you know, I played year round,
I know would shuttle back and forth
from practice to practice, um,
throughout middle school and high school.
But I started like paring that down and
I actually as high school progressed,
I got more and more into musical theater
and show choir and singing and I kind
of gave up sports and athletics.
So in college I actually,
I sang in an acapella group,
but I know sports,
no sports in college, no
sports recreationally. Were
you a runner? I would go
run to like stay in shape,
but running in St Louis kind of sucked.
So I mean it just like,
it was either like hot and muggy
or like freezing cold. Um, so yeah,
I didn't really,
didn't really do anything.
Let's say I'm going to jump around a
little bit like memento, but, uh, if,
if we were to look at say the
world's toughest mudder. Yeah.
What do your routines look like?
You said you're a
creature of habit as am I,
the hours before the competition,
let's just say like the day of.
What are your routines?
Um, so I always get up
like super early before.
Well I get up super early in
general every morning, super early.
So my alarm typically goes
off like right around 4:00 AM.
Um, that's what you didn't flinch on
us. We were talking about Jocko Willink,
the seal commander, and he wakes
up at four zero response. I'm like,
Oh, another one. Here we are
4:00 AM. Um, and uh,
so actually on race days it's
almost like I sleep in a little bit.
When did the races start?
Typically?
Um, they generally will start. World's
toughest mudder is a little bit different.
That one starts at two in
the afternoon now. But um,
like just a regular obstacle was raised
with generally be like seven 30 is the,
I got starting at 2:00 PM. So let's
use that example. You wake up at four.
Oh yeah.
Then I drive myself crazy for the next
however many hours twiddling my thumbs.
What, uh, what other
type of body prep, uh,
or mental prep do you do? Yeah, we use
the distraction technique.
So I tried to not think about really,
cause I can sit there and make
myself miserable over and over,
like like picturing the race or whatever.
But I find it helpful actually. Um,
I actually do a lot of work in
the mornings before races. Um,
so I'll catch up on emails and I'll
do things from like my attorney life.
Um, and um, then in terms of
like body prep, I, you know,
I do a lot of like foam
rolling, things like that. Um,
the older I get,
the more I realized like I can't just
like jump out of bed in the morning and
like, yeah, be spry as a chicken. So
you're 32, is that right? At 32 32 32
I would imagine you still have a
couple of good years left in you,
but is the whole lot worse cell over time,
the mobility work that you do,
what, what, what does that,
what does that actually
look like and in detail?
Um, so I generally carry like
an arsenal of every single,
like from a golf ball, a Lacrosse
Ball, a softball, a foam roller.
Um, and so I'm really
focused on loosening up hips,
loosening up hamstrings,
um,
and every single different little
torture device has, you know,
it's the golf ball is for the foot,
the Lacrosse ball works for
awhile on the glutes, you know,
the softball is great for the
hamstrings. Um, so I'm just, you know,
getting the muscles kind of warmed
up and loosened and perhaps, um,
and um,
I do,
I actually from a lot of various and
nagging injuries that I've always had,
I have like little physical therapy
routines that I always do too. You know,
like to get your glutes
activated and Ben thinks that,
yeah. What type of movements
do you do for glute activation?
Others is fantastic exercise called Jane
Fonda's that if anybody's ever been at
least for Glick,
glutamine or
where you're sitting there
and you're like, man,
I should really have leg warmers on.
Right.
I said the you're talking about, is
this like the bent leg sort of, uh,
the reverse thighmaster pretty much,
yeah.
It's the reverse thighmaster
[inaudible] on your side.
Yeah. Yeah. And like variation, like doing
fire hydrants like that too. You know,
like a dog lifting his legs. There's
all super sexy things that people like.
Like if you're, if you do them
in a gym, people are like,
oh God that was that girl.
Well I tell you,
I think that you probably get more
attention to in fire hydrants than I do,
at least unless I'm in
a gym in the Castro.
It might be a similar experience.
Uh,
and do you use any other modalities
for prep? Do you use any stem,
do you use anything like that pre-race
or is that set aside for other,
other purposes?
Pre race, not so much. No, that's
more like recovery, like recovery.
I'll like compression boots and stem.
Now our compression boots, the
compression socks are these actual boots,
the boots that inflate the
air pressure chambers that um,
you know, like kind of like flush
at supposedly flush out lactic acid.
So,
um,
that's, and that's post race. That
would be post race. Yeah. So, well,
let's talk about post race then.
So in terms of facilitating recovery
and so you finish the race. Yeah.
And is it true that you have not slept
for days on end after races or is that an
exaggeration?
It is
true.
So any long race that I've done,
like we're always having a
matter as a 24 hour race. Um,
I've done other races that are
longer 48 that are 60 hours. Um,
and I feel like it's,
I can't sleep afterwards and you feel
like you should be able to, you're like,
wow, I was just up for three days
straight, um, running around in the woods.
But my mind,
your body is so physically exhausted,
but my mind is still on so much
like on overdrive that I just,
I can't, so I mean, for
instance, this year, um,
after worlds have a smarter, we all went,
there was a group of staying at a house,
um, sat around, we're drinking
beers, watching football
game and I was like, man,
I should really be getting drunk right
now or something like that because like
I'm drinking, I've been running around
in a wetsuit all night long. I'm like,
I don't feel anything.
Like,
I don't feel any effects of the booze
or anything like that. I was like,
it just must be this adrenaline
still pumping through me. Yeah.
Um, did other people have the same similar
experience for, is that unique to you?
I think no, because everyone else just
kind of passed out and went to bed.
So I was like, hey guys, like say
okay, everyone's asleep right now.
Okay.
And would indeed when you cross
the finish line, yeah. Uh, as such,
you're done. W W what type of
recovery starts? What are the,
what are the actions that you take
in the hours following the race?
So I think one of the most important
things that people should do,
that they don't have to stay moving.
People want to finish a race
and especially a long one. Um,
and just like Lana couch or go to sleep
is the worst thing you can do cause
you're gonna wake up and like
not be able to move anything.
So I generally try and stay
walking. I try and stay active. Um,
you know, I will hop again on like a
foam roller or something like that.
And try it. You don't want to
be too aggressive afterwards.
Like you're not going to like hop on a
softball and roll out your glutes because
that's going to hurt really
bad. Um, but then just try,
just try and stay active.
And that is in like the next day too,
you know,
like gentle movement and things like that.
Um, do you use, do you,
are you a proponent of ice,
ice baths or anything like that or not?
If I can't, so I mean, I'm
not a scientist. Whatever.
I all I know is what works for me.
I know people have different opinions.
If I can get into an ice bath, I will,
but it needs to be like immediately.
So there have been races where there's
like a lake right next to me and I'm like,
if it's called enough,
then I'll just go jump in the lake
and kind of use that as an ice bath.
But if you're waiting
like four or five hours,
I don't really think it's going
to end up helping you in the end.
And, uh, I want you to
correct me if I'm wrong, 2012,
[inaudible] world's toughest mudder.
How did you place,
uh,
I one for females,
but I was second overall in
2002nd place overall. Yeah.
How did that feel? So it was
a really interesting race. Um,
how many competitors?
This was again,
there were about 1200 people I believe
is is generally every year. Um,
so there are about 1200 people. Uh,
it was once they moved it to November,
so it was supposedly a tiny bit warmer,
but actually it wasn't,
it was actually colder in
2012 and it was in 2011. Um,
and uh,
I guess I didn't realize,
I knew I was winning for women and at
this point we were about 24 hours or
getting close to the end and I was
about 80 some odd miles in and a,
as on the last lap, they were like,
okay, well you've won for women,
but the guy that's winning is
like nine minutes ahead of you.
So we're on this last
lap. Um, you know, going,
we'll end up with 90 miles and there
are all these people from tough mudder
headquarters and like all these
matters just like yelling at me,
willing me to go on because all they
want me to do is to win overall,
you know,
and you're so tired at that point and
like so kind of delirious that I guess it
didn't even realize like
the import of that situation. Like
how massive that would have been. Um,
cause I was just like, leave
me alone. I hurt, I'm tired.
Freezing.
Like I'm covered in like 10,
like millimeters of neoprene. Like
just, you know, and I'm like, I get it.
I'm trying to move fast for my
body, won't let me. Um, but yeah,
so I ended up finishing about nine minutes
behind the male overall winner. Um,
and uh, yeah, so it was pretty, I,
it didn't really hit me until like a
day or two later where I was like, oh,
I was that close. Ah,
okay. So did you not,
did you feel pride about finishing
second overall or where you just,
were you more disappointed that you
didn't finish first? Overall, no, no, no.
I completely felt pride and it's actually,
it's one of these things now that
when I race, um, it's almost,
I kind of look at the standing is cool
to win, you know, as it, as a female,
you know, it'd be like, Oh, I'm, I'm the
female winner, but I more look of like,
I have a con consistent goal of try and
place like top 10 overall, you know,
I want to be, I don't care, sex,
gender, like I just want to be,
I want to compete to the
best, you know, overall. So
the next female finisher, what
place was she? She actually in 2012.
She was third. Oh, no kidding. Yeah. Yeah.
Deanna Blagg. She's amazing. She, uh,
she's amazing. She's absolutely amazing.
And um, and she's like 46 year
old is years old from Australia.
Yeah. Just crushes it up
there. Yeah. All my excuses.
Right. And she's like the nicest
woman in the entire world too.
So how does her strategy
for training or in the race
itself differ from younger,
a younger competitor?
I would say, I think probably anything.
As you get older, you realize you,
you don't go out as fast, you
know, it's kind of like as you age,
you're never going to like out sprint,
you know, at 20 something year old. Um,
but you tend to have more mental
strength and more mental grit.
The older you get. I'm just,
because you're like, whatever,
this isn't a big deal,
you know, like you're more mature and
you can deal with pain and suffering. Um,
so I think that it's just kind of more
like a slow and steady, you know, and,
but just keep going one foot in front
of the other. Um, but to that extent,
that's kind of how I operate too,
is that I'm never,
I'm notoriously slow out of
the gate. Um, you know, in,
in the beginning of races I'm always like
struggling to catch up with everyone,
which is why I like longer
racist. Um, so then, you know,
but it's just kind of like, you
know, picking them off one by one
when,
when you are actually before that,
so suffering. Let's talk
about suffering. Yeah. Uh,
I was just reading a letter of Seneca's
is that guy that's the bust on the
kitchen counter over there.
Uh,
related to think it's on fasting and
celebrations, something related to that,
but it talks about exposing
yourself to suffering
along the lines of the more,
the more you sweat during peace,
the less you bleed during war.
Right.
And so I practice fasting among,
for,
for many reasons among those
being practicing hardship, right.
So I can endure it in
other areas of my life.
Do you do that in other places in your
life where you deliberately expose
yourself to different types of
pain or suffering as a practice?
Or is it limited to the suffer fest?
I mean,
with the, with the amount that I race, um,
there's plenty of suffering involved
in and, uh, in that sufficient, I know,
um, I guess, uh,
I can't do the fascinating thing I
got and I'm not good with that. Um,
once you're burning a lot
more calories than I am,
and like if I don't eat every few hours,
like it's,
it's trouble for anyone
around me. Um, but I,
I always try to train in less than
ideal conditions if I can. Um,
because I think that that,
uh, adds a lot to me.
It's super easy to go out for a
run when it's 70 degrees and sunny.
But like when I was living in Chicago,
which I did for the past six years, um,
if there's like a windstorm
or a thunderstorm, I'm like,
let me out, you know, like,
let me perfect time to go around.
There was one time that I, um,
they had shut down the lake front path
because the were coming over and I was
like, fuck it, I'm running anyway. Um,
and apparently police don't like that. Um,
so as I'm like,
okay.
Yeah, I'd love to see that. Please tell
me the police tried to catch you on foot.
Did that?
No. Well, there was a,
it was a bicycle cop who I was actually
surprised that he was like out in the
weather as well. Um, but
uh, yeah, and he was like,
you can't, this is shut down.
I'm like, I'm just training.
No big deal. No big deal.
Yeah. Did that, did that sway his,
know his position and no, not at,
not at all.
Uh,
so training in less than ideal conditions,
uh,
when you look back at
okay,
the races that you've run,
the obstacle,
uh,
of course races,
what has been the most
challenging obstacle for you
and what has been the most
dangerous?
MMM,
I would say in terms of challenging,
I always send you, so there's always, um,
I'm notoriously awful at
throwing a spear. Um, and uh,
it's well known communities that I
can throw a spirit saved my life. Um,
and so inspiring races,
there's always a spear throw and it's
actually his costs me like tons of
different races.
Um,
and it's funny because like it's one of
those things that if you practice you
would probably be pretty good at it.
But
like the, I like puzzled right now.
Okay. How about a throat? His fear? No,
like super come loudy
like ace lawyer and I thought it
was like world champion racer.
Okay. So continue not to interrupt
and I can throw spirit. No, no, no.
But it seems like the other thing you
would sit down and study and master,
you would think so.
I actually think that I'm playing
softball my entire life kind of screwed me
because I would like try and throw
it like you throw a softball,
which we do under,
yeah,
the underhand spear
Wah Wah Wah. She throws like a
girl. No, no, no. But come on,
the pitching does is completely different.
Right?
It's completely you referring to the
pitching folks don't get, don't get,
don't get all riled up.
Um,
so that's always been,
it's always been a challenge for
me and I finally figured it out.
But it's one of those things that like,
it's a,
it's such a silly thing to
struggle with, I think. Um,
but I guess that also could be the most
dangerous because if you miss a spear,
throw, throwing somebody
around. No, I'm joking. Uh,
but there are some,
in terms of danger for obstacles,
like there are times where
I'm sitting there being like,
why hasn't somebody died? And
these w Oh, I take that back.
That's really bad because to me
it did die. Um, but, uh, yeah,
but dangerous spart yeah.
Um, you know, when you're,
when you're racing for 24 hours are like
really long and you're like climbing
super tall things.
Like in the middle of the night,
I'm always thinking they're being like,
man,
one misstep and I'm falling
backwards and I'm, you know,
and I've taken some big diggers off
of walls just because you're so tired.
You just said diggers meaning
falls, awful falls, you know.
So how, then these are walls
that you're climbing over,
similar to a military obstacles,
correct? Correct. Yeah. Yeah. How tall
are they? Um, they very, um, you know,
some are AP, some are 10 feet, some are
12 feet, some have ropes to help you up.
Then, you know, others, you know,
there's big, like kind of like ladders.
I'm, you know, like military tack ladders,
you know, that like climbing out, um,
climbing out of water. So there was
one time, I think it was in 2012,
world's toughest mudder as you climbed
one of those out of a lake and it was
like 20 feet up, but it was in the middle
of the night. It was like frozen. Um,
and so you're like, it's like iced
over and you're like, I'm going to die,
I'm gonna die. Um, but yeah,
so there's all these little
dangerous and people, you know,
talk about the electricity
involved in tough mudders. Um,
which is like a very disconcerting,
because I've been hit so hard sometimes
that I'd like blacked out from the
electricity. Yeah. This,
this obstacle to folks. So, well,
so there's a couple
variations of it, but, um,
basically there's these wires hanging.
The worst variation was
called electric eel. And um,
you crawl through water
that's about like two,
three inches deep and there's
wires hanging down over your head.
Um,
and so you're,
you're army crawling through it and your
head is hitting these wires and we'll
occasionally, we'll like
shock you, Vacu, and it's,
is it 10,000 bolts? I don't, I don't,
or there's the difference between
voltage and wattage and I don't really
understand what it is, but one
will kill you in one won't. Um,
so this is supposedly the
stuff that won't kill you. Um,
but if you get hit and just the right
way and you're in water, I'm like,
I got hit so hard and like I,
my face smacked down through the water
and hit my head and then I like blacked
out.
I started crawling the wrong way.
And now it's one of those things
that like once you like do like that,
like something like that happens to you.
You just have like this insane fear of it,
you know?
And so it's the worst for me now.
Like trying to pressure the
trepidation beforehand. Yeah,
the people who get injured or
even the fatalities. What are,
what are the most common causes?
Honestly, I think the vast majority of
injuries are things like rolled ankles,
broken ankles. You saw what
you would expect. I mean,
I don't think they've never, and
the, and the, you know, the one,
the one unfortunate death that I think
that we know of that have occurred or
deaths that have occurred have been like,
you know, heat, stroke, dehydration,
like the things that you would like
ultra marathon. Exactly. Exactly.
It's not surprisingly for something that
is fraught with electricity and spears
and you know, like climbing up super
tall things and crawling Barb wire,
like nobody's like lost. And I don't
think from a Barb wire, you know,
so my buddy's got zapped in the eye with
one of those electric, uh, when, uh,
one of those electric lines, he was
not, he was not super happy about it.
Well,
I mean,
the worst of the worst extent of my
injuries are really like my body is just
covered in barbed wire scars like
scratches. You can, I can show you them.
But you know,
I looked like I was attacked by a tiger
that was wondering what kind of cat you
had everywhere. Rope Burns, you know,
I'm never going to be a leg model.
50 shades of tough mudder. Yeah,
I've heard of,
uh, the, uh,
surgery. I want to talk about
your knee surgery. Yeah.
Why did you get knee surgery and uh,
let's start with that. What was the,
what was the reason for
the knee surgery? So I, um,
last summer heading into like world
champion seed Shep season ended up tearing
my meniscus and, um, it was in
training, it was in training.
It was like, I was like running in Chicago
and they're like, potholes everywhere.
And then the like one of those,
like free is one of those freak things
where you'd like step in something and
you're like, ah, ah, my leg and I'm,
then I'm like running it off. I'm like,
oh wait, this actually isn't okay. Um,
and uh, so, you know, I went and I had
an MRI. I thought it was like, okay,
but they're like my leg. I kept locking
and I had to like physically unlock it.
And so I think with certain meniscus
tears that happens. And so, um, they just,
they had to go in there and, um, you
know, shaved down the meniscus and then,
um, there were some like tibial
plateau fracture and whatever fancy.
So I just had to stay off it for a bit.
Yeah.
When did, you said that happened? How
much long, how much later did you compete?
So,
so I raced again,
eight weeks post surgery.
Um, and I remember asking my
surgeon, this was the world's
toughest mudder, correct? 2014,
correct?
I did.
So I remember asking my
surgeon and I was like,
so how long until I'm back running? He
was like, maybe like four weeks and I go,
so could I feasibly run our race like
eight weeks later? He's like, yeah.
And I was like,
how long of a race?
And cause he was like thinking like
I was going to run a five. Yeah.
I was like, why? It's like 24 hours.
It was just like, so I never got his
blessing for it, but I did anyway. So
what did you do,
uh,
between the, what steps did
you take to rehab it? I mean,
what were the most important
things that you did?
I mean, I, I think most importantly
for me it was, it was getting into,
I got into physical
therapy like the next day.
Like I had the best physical therapist
in Chicago and she was fantastic.
She'd worked with me through other
injuries and things like that.
So we were pretty
aggressive and rehabbing it.
And then I just did whatever else I
could to work around it to stay in shape.
You know,
I think when people get injured,
they forget that there's so much
that they still can do. So, um,
I had a gym that had a skier,
um, which if you've ever seen,
it's like a rower turned upside down and
you pull it like you're cross country
skiing. Um, so you know,
for two weeks that was the only like
really like thing I could do to like keep
my heart rate up. Um, and
standby skier, hand bikes gear.
Um, I could row with one leg, but
then that kind of like throws.
Then my other leg was just getting
massive. Um, but you know, and I would do,
I like wrote a 10 K on
earth skier did 10 k,
which is the worst kind of torture you
can like do to yourself, you know. Um,
and just finding another,
finding other ways to work around it.
What other rehab modalities did
you find most helpful personally?
Um,
did a lot of like stem for to kit cause
I think when you go in you do electrical
stimulation. Yeah. Um,
so when you go in and you like
cut open your knee or whatever,
it shuts down your quad.
And so the main thing is getting your
quad to then come back and function again.
And so stem is really helpful and um,
you know like retraining that um,
to get it to fire. Um,
so that was, you know,
that was helpful.
Um,
I'm really like I'm a huge fan of
like art graston them with those
people and not from their air t active
release technique type of myofascial
release,
which is super depending on how you
have it done can be super unpleasant if
you're having like your, so as worked
on, Oh my God, I love that pain though.
I think it's like you like
having some like, yeah,
like therapist and with their like
ridge hand knuckle deep into your,
so as I had, just as a
side note, all right,
so I'm going to give a shout out to
this Guy Jesse Burdick who was a power
lifter who trains with a
friend of mine named Mark Bell.
I mean they do a lot of training
separately, but I think he pulls a, Jesse,
I apologize if I get this wrong,
but maybe he can dead lift more and more
than 700 pounds. He's a big unit. Yeah.
And we were getting ready to do,
he also does manual therapies.
We're getting ready to do
an art session and the end.
So he puts me on a table and kind of
drapes like one leg off and he goes,
the safe word is brisket and then
just proceeds to annihilate my hips.
So the basic idea folks,
if for those of you don't know it,
they are t and please correct me if,
if I get this wrong,
but if you have adhesions,
let's just say with scar tissue between
adjacent tissues you apply pressure,
manual pressure, a therapist applies
pressure between those tissues.
Then has you perform motions like an
overhead kind of reaching movement for the
lads to break apart those adhesions.
Graston which is having really thick
butter knives scraped all over you. Right.
Uh, I read that you use
something and I'm embarrassed.
I actually don't know what this is.
Dry needling. Oh yeah. What is that?
Sounds terrible.
Apparently
legal in California,
which is why you probably don't know.
It's like acupuncture on crack.
Um,
so an acupuncture is actually rightfully,
probably hate it cause I think they,
they think they think it's kind of
like a bastardization of what they do.
But so when you go and you get acupuncture
and the goal is like to not feel the
needle dry needling,
you actually are sticking the needle in
the muscle valley to try and get it to
twitch. And the twitch
is like the release. So,
um, it's like, and you don't
leave the needles in there,
so you're basically like poking
at a muscle to try. Yeah.
And the worst ever don't ever let anybody
dry needle your calf, your gas struck.
Because like if you get in underneath
like right and like the hamstring
insertion, like you will feel like
you got shot in the back of your legs.
And it can also be kind
of addictive because like,
you have somebody like poking around your
group meet and you feel as twitch and
it's almost like this like release of the
muscle. And what does it do for you? Um,
it's supposed to, you know,
for super tight muscles.
The idea a really. Yeah. Huh. So, yeah,
I had the, I had this,
this nutty experience, uh,
and if people want to see photos of me
in excruciating pain getting art done by
Charles Poliquin, and you can
see that in the four hour body,
it's kind of hilarious. But the IDA
separate experience with something called,
uh, let's see. I guess
it would be called, uh,
I want to say neuro puncture,
but I might be getting that wrong.
This was done with Dr. Lee Wolfer many
years ago with shallow injections of
prolo solutions. So, yeah.
And what happened though,
and we improvised this point is she
was working on my infraspinatus.
So this is a rotator cuff muscle that
at all that always gets sore for me.
And I read it.
I had reconstructive shoulder surgery
and I probably sit like a collage,
like chest collapsed, uh, the, you know,
Gollum when I'm typing also,
which is no good. But, uh,
she was working on my infraspinatus
and she was doing the,
the kind of sewing machine approach with
these, these shallow injections. And,
and we both here,
and it sounded like someone was
scraping ice off a windshield.
And it turned out that I had these,
these just this huge clump of calcium
deposits at the back of both shoulders and
shit. So we ended up just, well, we,
it's the royal we, she ended up, uh,
using the needle basically as a scraper
to kind of break down these calcium
deposits.
And what was fascinating is no shoulder
pain for months afterward after
chiseling these out wasn't the most
pleasant thing in the world. Uh,
so the dry needling, now that you're
here in California, no more sad,
sad times. No more
gluten meet posts. Yeah,
yeah. I go back to my lack of market dry
needling. Yeah. Well sometimes they'll,
I'll get acupuncture done and I'm
going to be like, can you guys like,
and like they'll accidentally, a muscle
will trigger and release and I'm like, oh,
that's fantastic dude. But
I'm honest people, I'm like,
I'll try anything once. And in terms
of like recovery or like, you know,
I'll just throw the,
especially because for most professional
athletes that they do, you know, they,
their job is like to be a professional
athlete and then to like Rehab and
recover and spend all that time.
I'm like training early in the mornings
I go and I sit at a desk for 10 hours a
day and then I like try and like
train and get in the evenings.
It's not an ideal,
like I'm not doing my body any favors for
like with what I'm putting it through.
What uh,
what, what is your
nutritional look like? Uh, and
then we were were were you serious earlier
when I asked you about breakfast? Hey,
we'll,
what was your answer?
And we were doing a sound check and I
asked her what she had for breakfast.
What was your hazard?
Uh, pop dot pop tarts. Um, no,
that's actually the poptarts has become
kind of this like running joke in the
obstacle racing community with me
because when I won the spartan race world
championships in 2013 I was so far ahead,
I was like 2030 minutes ahead of the
next woman and the race director yells at
me, he goes, million, what'd you have
for breakfast this morning? And I'm like,
pop tarts.
And I actually did randomly that day
cause they're really good source of easy,
easy Millie, digestible carbs.
Billy. I said, what's that?
You said or did you say your full
name? Sorry, I heard you say, sorry.
You said it Amelia. Oh, okay.
Got It. Sometimes I can't
say my own name. Um, and uh,
so it kind of became this thing that
like I would just like pre race ritual,
um, that would be like a good luck thing
to like a pop tart because I'm a soup,
I'm a really big person
into superstition and um,
it's kind of grown from there.
And now I see like I was at,
I was at a race the other weekend and
like everyone around me was eating pop
tarts.
What have I started?
Like what is it?
Everything,
like these pictures on Instagram of them
eating pop tarts and like they tag me
in it. Yeah. And I'm like, Oh
my God, I've created a monster.
This actually could be an incredible
opportunity for you to do whatever you
want.
Because I remember watching pumping
iron and Arnold Schwarzenegger's talking
about the guys would come up to him and
ask him for advice and he'd give them
the wrong advices.
And he was like,
tell them to go into the shower at the
gym and like scream all they're posing.
So you could, you could
actually, you could pull an
incredible April fool's joke,
but announced it a year later after
everyone has already embraced it. I know.
So now I'm like, okay, well what's
the thing? Like what's the, you know,
what other superstitions do you have?
Um, not limited to racing necessarily.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, I'm one of those
people that, so it's the same,
like I will wear the same sports bra,
like,
so we raised pretty much in like sports
bra and like compression shorts because
you want as little clothing to
like cut down the mud as possible.
So I'll wear the same, you
know, if I did well in a race,
like I'll wear the same outfit
for like the next race, um,
and especially at the same headband.
Um, and then if I don't do well,
then that one gets discarded,
you know? And so it's,
it's that kind of like your
typical, um, sports stuff. Um,
I actually have,
this is kind of embarrassing,
but a small little stuffed dog that
travels with me to all races and I'm,
because I'm typically by
myself and really cheap,
sketchy hotels because these races
are like in the middle of nowhere. Um,
so it's like my little guard dog.
And how big is the stuffed dog? Oh,
it's like fits in the palm.
Where did you get that? It was given
to me as again as a protection,
as a partisan.
The Guardian has a garden,
Doug. Um, so yeah, I mean it's,
it's just, it's, it's silly.
It's silly stuff like that.
I can be outside of pop tarts. Yeah.
What am I actually lead? Yeah. What is,
what is your,
let's just say your four
weeks out from a race. Yeah.
What is your,
what does a day of food look like for you?
That's hard to say. Honestly. Like I,
it's one of those things I've struggled
with that I've, I've tried every,
like I tried to do Paleo,
I tried to be like,
maybe I can become a fat adapted athletes
because for longer races I didn't want
to have to like rely on gels,
gels and stuff like that
because after a while it can,
it can be too much in your stomach.
But I just never,
I'm never going to be the paradigm
of good eating of like an and um,
I couldn't, couldn't stick
with like, you know, um,
the whole like, you know, trying to,
I couldn't go far enough
into like the fat adaptation.
Like it was just miserable. Um, I
like ice cream way too much. Um,
it's somewhat contra indicated
for Ketosis and adoption,
but much to my chagrin
boy, and I think I realize, I'm like,
you know, I'm, I'm performing well. Um,
I'm winning races.
So why change?
If it gets to the point where
I'm not doing well right then,
then I'll take another look at my diet
and, and switch it. But at this point,
it's like I run so much, I
put in so much, you know,
time that I'm like, whatever. I
enjoy food and Ali, kind of whatever.
What do you consume during a 24 hours?
MMM.
What is your, and this is actually
a question from a fan. Yeah.
Which was how does your gear that you
bring with you differ in an obstacle
course race versus an ultra marathon?
Yeah. Instance. Yeah. Um,
aside from the wet suit.
So I think it really depends.
Um, if you're running, I've,
as I've learned from like dabbling in
ultra marathons is that my body does it,
especially if you're running hard.
I'm,
my body isn't going to handle solid food
as well as like the stomach will like
stomach acid and stuff like that.
So there's a lot of like liquid,
like tailwind is a good,
you know,
something that a lot of people use to like
that it's really easy on your stomach.
That's a good name. Yeah.
Yeah. Um, and, uh, so,
but I also just find, you know, like
simple, I actually really love like, um,
like I like chewing on things like, like
cliff makes these blocks. So, you know,
like I do, I take in simple
sugars that, that um,
like fuel me through that.
Um,
how often do you eat
during a 24 hour race?
Um,
I try and fuel every,
like I try and fuel every 30
minutes to hour, get something in,
but little bits.
Um,
and then I'm telling you sometimes are
the best things during like a long race
are like,
Oh God,
I had a Krispy Kreme doughnut during
world's toughest mudder this past year and
it was like the most phenomenal thing
I never had. I'm salty things. Um,
you know, like you want to make
sure that you, you like, you, um,
your electrolytes are give you,
especially if you're running in a
wetsuit because you're losing, I mean,
you're losing summons.
It's such an incredible amount of fluids.
Yeah, I mean, so, um,
pickle juice, mustard,
things like that. You carry that
with you, their stations regrowth.
That there are stations there are
imagining like a camel back full of pickle
juice. Well I actually do, I carry mustard
packets with me. I'm a small package.
So because vinegar is it if you ever
have issues with cramping, um, you know,
they say that like the vinegar,
the salt and stuff like that.
Can pickle juice as well known
to stop cramps in their tracks?
Um, his old yes. Yes. Was that
makes sense. Yeah, I mean it,
that's a pickle juice is harder to carry
with you is you have like a little vial
or something like that. Um, but yeah, so,
um,
I think that for the longer the race gets,
you obviously need more gear
and especially depending
on like the cold and the,
and the weather and what your
conditions are. Um, and so, you know,
sometimes it's,
it's pretty massive.
You mentioning electrolytes.
It's,
it's fascinating when you look at
sort of the record of health issues in
endurance races,
most people assume that a lot of
it would be related to dehydration,
but oftentimes it's the complete
opposite where a lot of people,
the many people consume too much water.
And they get,
I guess hypernatremia yeah,
yeah.
Where are you dilute the sodium to the
extent that in some cases your heart
stops functioning. Okay. And, uh, the,
I recall I was doing this Kettlebell
certification years ago and it was just
like thousands and thousands of swings
and whatnot outside, right. In Minnesota.
And people were getting horrible
cramps and they're like, oh,
we're not drinking enough water and
heat shrink more. And I'm like, no,
that's not the issue.
You need some potassium tablets and uh,
it's, uh, but God, that could just
be the worst if, I mean, do people,
I would imagine there must be
a fair number of competitors
who just have to drop
out because they get it.
Quatre or hamstring cramps.
Zach cramps can be like super
debilitating. Um, and I think,
and especially like in
really hot races and,
and also I'm really cold races and
stuff like the extremes. Um, so that,
you know, it happens. It's the reason why
the longer the race is to get, you know,
like the more unknown and things
like that go into it. And so, um,
it can be, it's always kind of a crap
shoot, you know, like you're like,
come on body, please cooperate with me
this one time. But sometimes you can't,
you can't predict it.
So
what, uh, what supplements
do you use on a daily basis?
Um, caffeine, no, I like coffee.
So I am actually really,
uh,
have really kind of bought the hype and
the science behind beets. Beets. Yeah. Um,
so I actually,
I work with a company called [inaudible],
which is it's powdered beat,
um, concentrated beet. Um,
and so it's really that like if you,
I remember the first time I ever had
beet juice, which just tastes like death.
I'm like, yeah, I mean I, some
people like beet juice, but I,
I can't handle it. But like you feel
this weird like head rush almost.
And so I was like, wow, there might
be something to this shit. Um,
so it's a,
so I am really,
it's something that I
actually like drink ever,
like before workouts and
stuff like that and you know,
delivers the nitric oxide to help the
breathing and everything like that. Um,
so I think for endurance athletes,
you don't need,
I don't need the massive dose of caffeine
before I go out, you know, and Ron,
because he wants to be jittery while like,
you know, running for several hours. Um,
you need more of like the,
the,
like the help with the breathing and
keeping the heart rate low and stuff like
that. Um, and then I
also take, um, you know,
I try to stay away from
like antiinflammatories like
Advil and stuff like that,
just because I, you know,
it's, it's hard on the body,
but big believer on like
tumeric. Yup. Um, and uh,
other things like that.
Um,
then anything to try and help with
like bones and joints and, um,
so you've just taken her at like
glucosamine or MSM or what type stuff.
But I, I try and get a
natural, I'm like, uh,
like bone broth and gelatin and
things like that. Um, you know,
but it's bone broth as inexpensive habit
until I like bite the bullet and make
my own. Then I have to like handle
chicken feed and not really into that. So
you're in a good place for the,
for the, for the bone broth.
And I'm in the bay area.
I was like,
it was the three stone hearth
I think in Berkeley. Yeah.
Further down the peninsula. You got
some really good sources as well, right?
Unfortunately, yeah. Hippies love
bone broth. Oh God. It's like the,
it's the new thing.
And for anybody in New York,
I'll just give a shout out to a new,
I guess it's kind of a side Gig.
Started by a chef friend of mine,
Marco Canora who was in the four hour
chef Brodo they serve hot bone broth in
the winters in New York City,
Bro. D. Oh, it's amazing.
And you can get turmeric and or cumin.
You can get different flavored. Yeah.
You getting it. You can, you
can pay for the ad odds. Uh,
what is your prehab routine look like?
So the exercises,
what exercises do you
do to prevent injuries?
Yeah, so the main injuries
that I've kind of dealt with,
I've always been kind of
revolving like hips, um, and uh,
uh, you know, glutes, leg, most
runners, glutes that don't fire. Um,
so like the irony.
Yeah, yeah, exactly. Uh,
so, uh, like Jane Fonda's
are the, you know, the,
the gold standard. Um, but
it is, it's a lot of, um,
like kind of like stability work. Um, so
I try and do a lot of single leg stuff.
Um, what type of single leg stuff? Uh,
so single leg squats, you know, you
don't, you see like crossfitters,
do you like pistols all the way,
like asked to grab it.
You don't need to do that kind of stuff.
You know,
he's just like small little like,
you know,
mini single leg squats. Um, I try into,
like, whenever I'm standing around,
I'm trying to like, just stand on one
leg, like balancing and things like that.
Um, I do a lot of like
band, you know, like the,
the physio band like walks, so like
monster walks, right? You're the ex walks.
Yeah, the x walks. That's
that kind of staff. Um,
and then a lot of work, especially if as
a trail runner you really want to work.
Like you're,
I'm going to say what is your transverse
abdominis or like the really deep core
muscles muscle. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Um,
so a lot of exercises that will
like engage that, um, you know,
like bird dogs, um, and
uh, things like that. Just,
I mean,
they're there,
they're super like not fun
and little tiny movements,
but I think most people would
rather go like, you know,
squat 200 pounds and ignore those.
And that's not gonna help you.
So you're working on glue bead,
you're doing sort of ice
lateral or single leg movements.
Do you do step ups and he'd work on boxes?
I do. Um, I do too. I think.
I think and like lunges, um,
things like that. Uh, anything
that's requiring you to,
um, that is a required, yeah,
that like unilateral movement too.
So.
And how much time would you say you spend
on those types of prehab movements on
a weekly basis? It's probably about
15 to 20 minutes a day. 1520 days.
Did you do that pre workout?
Is it a separate workout
or after it's generally like,
I'll do a few like activation.
Um, one, you know,
like fire hydrants before and then after
it's generally afterwards at all kind
of devote 15, 20 minutes.
Um, to kind of that,
those like small little
strengthening baby exercises.
And how many miles on
average do you run per week?
Yeah, it's changed a lot. Um, I used to,
a few years ago I actually didn't really
put in that much manager. I was like, uh,
you know, running too much is not
good for you or whatever. I did,
I switched my training from to be more
running intensive because I realized that
if you're going to run for 24 hours,
she probably should run you ever. Right,
exactly. Cause I was just joking.
I'm like, I'm not a runner.
But then I realized that I actually,
I love running on trails and I love long,
long runs. And so, um,
now I'm probably putting in
probably about 60, 70 miles a week,
which actually is not
that much for a lot of UC,
a lot of runners who put in
like a hundred mile weeks, but
60, 70 miles away. Yeah.
How much time do you spend
doing other types of training,
like weight training or otherwise?
Yeah. Um, I do. So I used to,
I I do.
Um,
I generally will like crossfit
three to four days a week, um,
so,
you know,
or some kind of bastardized
version of my own, um,
if I'm not actually gonna make it
to a crossfit gym. Um, and to also,
cause I kind of pick and choose
what I like to do from that. Uh,
so I mean, I guess it would
be probably, I don't know,
five to six other hours of
other strength training. Um,
like interval training,
things like that.
What does your morning
routine or routines look like?
First, first 60 minutes of
your day you wake up? Yup.
Punched the roosters and
make them crow for him.
Uh, what happens? What is your,
what does your day look like
between say four and five 30?
Yeah. Um, I mean, I wish I could give
you an answer that's like, you know,
I go out and I do sun salutations. So
like breathing exercises or what? Well,
the sun's not even out of that hour,
but it's nothing really.
It's nothing really that interesting.
I mean, I wake up, um, you know,
I'll generally,
at that point,
I'll actually typically answer some work
emails that since I go to bed pretty
early,
probably I try and get to bed by nine.
So, um, sometimes I'll work emails
that'll come in like later than that.
So I'll answer those and I'm just,
you know,
gathering everything up and heading out
to if I'm going to the gym that day or
from hitting up the trails that
day. Um, so because I'll typically,
I'll train in the morning and then I'll
get ready and go straight into work and
you get to work about seven 30 or so.
Um,
and so if you eaten breakfast at
this point, are now, um, I will eat.
So Lee,
so I'll wake up the boards
just race days. Um, and this morning,
because this is the only thing that trunk
of my car as I was driving up here, um,
high temp pop charts in the
trunk of my car. Um, but, uh,
no. Also I'll generally wake up and, um,
I actually typically eat a few spoonfuls
of like nut butter to fuel before I go
out for like, if I'm going to go
run, you know, 10, 15 miles. Um,
it's a good source of, you
know, fuel to keep me going.
She'll just have like a few tablespoons
of almond butter or something like that.
Pretty much. Hmm. And
uh, and then, uh, yeah.
And I found out that,
you know,
it sits well and then I'll eat breakfast
after I train and then get to the
office, things like that. So what
does a non pop tart breakfast?
Uh, generally, um,
I'm a big fan of like omelets and eggs
and things like that in the morning. Um,
mainly because I really like catch
up and I always put ketchup on it.
It's just a vehicle for the
ketchup pretty much. I see.
You sense a sugar theme going on here?
Let's see,
don't take diet advice from a million.
Okay.
I want to just take a perhaps a
few of these fan questions. Yeah.
And we've hit on a number of them already,
but I didn't know I had fans.
But yes you did.
Unless they're all coming from Scott.
Uh,
you have a lot of fans among my fans
so that, this is a question that I'd be
interested to hear the answer to as well.
This is from Cindy, Paul Louis and
I'm probably masking that. What is,
what is your self talk during training
and during the challenges sound like the
moment when you want to quit?
No,
just to head this off at the pass that it,
the answer may be that you don't feel
like you want to quit but during it
extremely hard races or challenging times.
What is your self talk?
Yeah look like, cause I found like
many athletes and maybe not you,
but have sort of consistent routines
in terms of their self talk.
What's interesting,
especially with the long races is that
you're always going to hit a low part.
It's like,
and there's always going to be a part
where you want to quit, you know,
24 hours at like,
and for me it generally comes early.
It's like four hours in and I'm like,
God, I gotta do this for 20 more. When he,
um, you know, the sun setting and it's
getting cold, the wind's picking up,
there's a massive sandstorm,
whatever. Um, uh, for me,
I think I generally, it's hard because
people talk asked me about self talk.
I generally just shut my brain off and
I feel like that, that's what keeps,
I don't, um, don't really
think about anything. Um,
but I think when is that always
been the case? I think so.
I think that you just
will that into being.
I think I just kind of go, I, I, well
I use different coping techniques.
I sing to myself a lot when I'm out there.
Um,
just tell me you sing out loud
sometimes. Yes. Yeah. If I have,
if I'm not, if I have enough
breath, like, you know, um, so yeah,
you know,
there'll be like,
there'll be like a certain song for
every race that we'll just kind of like
replay it through my head. So, um,
2012 world's toughest mudder
was Macklemore's thrift shop.
It was like right before it hit big. No,
like right before it like busted out,
like, and I swear to God, I sing
that song over and over again.
I can't listen to it the same way.
What other songs is, so those like
your mantra was Macklemore? Yeah.
It was like your meditative mantra.
Pretty much 24 hours. 24 hours.
That's dedication of what
other songs have you used?
Oh God, they range like
all over the place. Um,
sometimes it's,
um,
sometimes it's just like
all kind of like seeing,
sometimes it will be like,
so my favorite hymn ever is,
I was raised Catholic and
whatever. And I love, you know,
I've always loved church music. Um,
so there's a Christmas Kong like low,
how arose? Air Blooming.
And it's like an old hymn.
So not at all what you would think
would be like running through my head,
like running a race. Sometimes
it does, you know? Um,
and uh, but then there's
other raise, it was Kanye.
It was like Kanye is monster was, or like
the song was called Monster, you know?
So
what do you do other racers do that
as well that you're aware of or do,
do you, do any other top
racers have coping, uh,
approaches that you think are interesting?
Do you know? I think that
a lot of people have like that self talk.
Like I've always tried to,
and I think this is pretty common,
is that like a lot of us will try and
break up the race into small segments
because if you look at the whole picture,
it will get overwhelming if you're like,
I have a hundred miles to run and you're
like crap, you know, but if you're like,
no,
I only have three miles or I'm just going
to focus on getting through these next
10 minutes.
And so I've always found that a lot of
people who do long endurance events,
we'll break it up into small,
manageable chunks, you know,
and just focus on the next
few minutes ahead of them.
And I think that works pretty well.
Do you,
I mean,
it sounds like you probably have some
form of meditation when you run and I
think that in terms of just mindfulness,
I'm sure it's a very present
state or where to start with,
but do you have a separate
meditative practice if anytime?
I don't,
I've tried.
I went to this like retreat
thing that was fantastic.
And I tried to do this meditation session
and I just like 20 minutes and I was
like, I got it, move and do something
and they didn't get out of here.
So for me it's almost like
the meditation is like,
is, is working really
hard. Like, you know,
like sprinting or running
or lifting heavy weights.
Like that's like my yoga practice,
you know?
Uh, no. I don't know what this refers
to, but since we'll, Hicks is asking,
are you going to do the 24
hour battle Frog in March?
Does that mean anything to you?
It does, yes. It's a, it's a race.
It's another 24 hour a obstacle race.
You know, maybe, I don't know. My,
my schedule next year is, is
kind of up in the air. I really,
I really want to kind of like venture
and challenged like myself in new ways.
And so I think I'm going to be doing
a lot more like pure trail races too,
which I haven't really had a chance,
especially without being out
here in California. Um, you
know, it's a much better,
like I love climbing,
running up mountains and stuff like that.
So why did you decide to move to
California? Um, a variety of reasons.
I think the main was I, I'm from the
west coast, I want to get back here. Um,
and then it was a time for a transition
and a career for me. Um, you know, uh,
I had been at a law firm for six years
and it was great and they were fantastic,
but kind of wanted to try
a new, like, you know,
going in house and working,
working for a company there. And,
and then I actually, I'll
be honest, it totally,
the training and having mountains and
hills around me, it was really hard.
I am the happiest when I am out on a
mountain running around somewhere and I
couldn't do that in Chicago.
So
are you able to disclose the
company that you're working for?
The I uh, yes. Um,
so it's this tiny little company
you may have heard of it.
Um, maybe not, I don't know.
I worked for apple. Yeah.
It's a good company. I have, I have a lot
of, a lot of friends at the mothership.
I just wanted to make sure they would
allow you to at least admit that you right
there on like my linkedin and
Facebook profile. It's public. Yeah.
Uh, this is a very racing
specific questions. Steven McKee.
How do you keep your body limber after
ice or water immersion during a race?
Keep moving. Just keep moving.
I mean, because, yeah, I don't,
yeah.
Otherwise if you slow down,
that's when your body temperature
goes down and then you're going to get
hypothermic.
So,
so let's, let's, uh, let's
go to the third act. Okay.
Which is rapid fire questions.
They don't have to be rapid fire answers,
but the word successful,
and you hear the word successful.
Who's the first person who comes to mind
and why it's so hard because,
and this is going to be your typical
lawyer answer where I'm like, well,
because successful can have
so many different definitions.
No, that's fair though.
But just, just, yeah, sort of reflexively.
So this is going to be kind
of strange answer probably,
but I always find people who have like
transitioned their careers throughout
their, who've had like, who've,
I guess you have been flexible in their
careers and who have transitioned.
This answer's not coming out right. Okay.
Here we go. I'm going to use an exam,
do that all the time.
Don't worry.
Um,
Australian record,
like a 22nd intro for this little audio
book yesterday and it probably took me
47 ticks.
Right.
Well,
um, so the example, yeah.
So I'm going to give you an example of
a person who I find successful and then
I'll explain why. Perfect.
Um, triple h, triple h.
So I am a huge wrestling fan, huge
professional wrestling fan. Um,
and, uh, the reason why
I'm in using, I could use,
I could use a number of
people as this example,
but the reason that I'm going to use this
is because I find people who have had
like one who,
so he had a very successful wrestling
career but then transitioned into the
business aspect of it.
You find so many people on it.
This is interesting being in,
I guess you could technically call me
kind of a professional athlete. Um,
you see a lot of people who I find are
very kind of short sighted in that,
in that they're like, well, I,
you know, I'm racing now and that,
but they don't think about what happens
when they can no longer do that.
So people who have been able to have
very successful athletic career and then
transition to the business side of things
or to think far ahead, you know? Um,
and so those are the people that I look
to that I'm like, you know, they have,
they have everything,
they have the athletic side of it,
but then they also have the business
acumen and are smart enough to know that
their body isn't going to
be there for them. You know,
Oscar, Delaware, a good example
too with golden boy productions,
right? Very savvy. I mean, if we want
to keep going professional wrestling,
you know, it's like the Rock, you know,
like things have transitioned to being
an actor. It's done. All right, so true.
Which is a great example of that. Uh,
so Paul avascular, really smart guy.
I had him on the podcast a listen
to it. It just blew my mind. Really,
really,
really savvy guy.
Right, right. Okay. So triple h I,
I agree. I also view him,
he works out at I think,
midnight every day with Joe to Franco.
Like after his entire right. He
is very, he, you guys have, right?
You have the OPP,
you have the opposite schedules,
fan of routine and which I know
and I've heard him talk about too,
and that's how I get by and like,
I don't care where I am in life,
if I'm traveling,
if I'm on the road for work,
like I'm going to create a routine there
and stick with it, you know? And so
what is something that you believe
that other people think is insane
or any controversial
beliefs that you have?
Interesting.
And if nothing jumps to mind,
we can also come back to that,
right?
Hmm.
Yeah. I may need to come back to that
one. Okay. We'll come back to that.
What book or books have you
gifted most to other people?
MMM,
I'm going to butcher this author's
name because I always do. Um,
house of leaves by marks. Um, Mark Daniel,
Daniel Lew ski. Um, so,
and the reason that I say this and that I,
um,
and that I would give this is that so,
so many people now read on like kindles
or technology or things like that.
This is a book that you have to hold
because there are parts of it where you
need to turn it upside down to read it.
And I forget the style of what is
called the style of writing. Um,
there's actual like Shondra for it,
but like there are certain pages where
you are reading it and it turns in a
circle.
So it's in like an entire,
I think that reading a book and you know,
holding the physical book and turning
the pages is such a lost art, you know?
And so there's something that,
this is a book that's like
an entire sensory experience.
It's a fantastic story. It's brilliant.
It's kind of like a story within a story,
but then it requires you as a reader
to be like active and involved,
you know?
And I think that's just so cool because
you don't see stuff like that anymore.
And especially now when people read
things on their iPads or their kindles or
whatever.
Um,
and kind of like holding a book
is something that we no longer do.
So
House of leaves. Very cool. Do you have
any favorite documentaries or movies?
Uh, my all time favorite movies.
The Goonies, the Goonies.
I mean, it's quality film.
It's the quality. It's not, it's
not, it's not going to like,
it's not life changing,
but you know, it's uh,
any favorite character
from the Goonies? Um, data,
data, data is great. And
just power. I mean, like,
yeah, I've grown up in Oregon and you just
had to like, that was, that was my jam.
We didn't have much to claim being from
Oregon, but we could claim that movie.
What is the, uh, purchase
that is most, uh,
for less than a hundred dollars
purchase of less than a hundred dollars.
It has most positively impacted
your life in recent memory.
Um, this is really funny. So menuca honey,
bandages and uh,
the,
so I get banged up a lot.
Um, racing I've seen,
yeah, there's some of the
photos that you sent me.
So before we do these interviews,
you know, I ask for short Bios,
some photos that might be a usable,
and I'm looking at one of them.
You're climbing up this red and
you're just covered in blood.
So yes,
you get banged up.
So, um, this past summer I actually,
there's this one obstacle called Shirleen
traverse where you basically called
tyrolean traverse. Prolean. Yeah.
So it's like you've seen like in the
military guys, they like it's a rope.
Then you either go under it and
it's just a rope traverse. Yeah. Um,
but you can also go on top of it. It saves
your crib. Um, and I decided one day,
one race to go on top of it,
saving my grip and I was wearing just
a sports bra and massive rope burn all
down the front of my, and like the
worst pain is like a second degree burn.
And I discovered that the only thing that
would take away the steam where these
like honey bandages and there's only
cvs was the only place that sold them.
CVS has manuka honey bandages and the
only visit, or I can find him online too,
and a sweater.
It was the only thing that got me through
like the next few weeks in like no pay.
But now I use them all the time for
all of like my scrapes and it's,
they're great, like antibacterial
and blah, blah, blah.
I mean with a number that I bought,
I'm sure it's over.
I've spent way more than a
hundred dollars on them, but
I knew Connie Benn and just cool. Uh, no,
I usually ask about morning routines.
We already covered quite a bit of that.
What other routines or habits do you
find important in your day or week?
Um, I, it's very easy for me to,
or I think it's very easy for a lot of
people to get disconnected from, you know,
people around and especially now in our
like social media type of world is that
like you, you know, like something
on Instagram or you know,
favorite something on Twitter or whatever,
whatever the things are that you do.
Um, so it's very
important for me to, like,
I always set a time every single week
and I called my parents like at the same
time and I called my sister
and, um, to try and make those,
those, um, you know,
personal connections and stuff like
that because it can be so impersonal now
with everything that we have,
you know,
technology that you can be like friends
with people that you've never met in
real life.
So I always try like me that routine
like every Sunday at the same time,
calling the parents, you know, just
kind of like keeping me grounded,
things like that.
Do you have any wind down routine?
What does the hour before bed look like?
So I generally, um, okay,
can't wait to hear this.
No, I was just like,
I was just trying to think of like if I
actually had, cause generally I'll be, um,
you know, watching Monday night
raw, um, some other fresh,
I don't watch a lot of TV, but it's
either sports or professional wrestling.
When I do, um, you know, I,
I am generally one of those people that's
like so tired by the time is I'm going
to go to bed. I don't really
need a routine. It's just
like, it's like, all right,
it's time to go to bed.
Oh, cool. Yeah. Got It.
Uh,
if you could have a billboard anywhere,
what would it say you put anything on it?
Okay.
I think I would say,
um,
I think it would be
something along the lines of,
um,
no one owes you anything.
And I think that this has been something
that lately I feel like there's such a
level of entitlement now
in people like that, that,
oh, I, I deserve this, or I
blah, blah, blah, this. Um,
and at the end of the day I'm
like, it's hard work. You know,
the people that I find the most
successful people that I think,
one thing that I've always
prided myself on is that like,
I've worked really God damn hard
for everything that you know,
that I've gotten or that
I've done in my life.
And you can't expect handouts from people,
you know, the, at the end of the day,
all that you can,
that you can count on really is yourself.
And so like, I don't expect
people to give me anything. So,
and I really wished like, you
know, so you see people now, like,
I don't know the level of entitlement
that people think that they deserve a
handout or deserve help sometimes.
Sometimes I'm like, no, make it yourself.
Make your own opportunities,
you know?
Yup. That's very pronounced
here in Silicon Valley too.
It's like, I know you just had a great
idea when you went to the bathroom,
but it's not worth $50 million yet.
I'm sorry. Exactly. Uh, so this,
this is,
this is not one of my normal rapid fire
questions and I'm sure I'm getting a lot
of grief for this from my fans,
but I have to ask because, uh, I,
I know a lot of very successful
women CEOs and so on,
uh, so 2012 second
place overall. Yeah. Uh,
I mean you could, you could
have potentially, I mean it's,
well within the royal possibility
you could have won the whole thing.
Do find it hard to date. Is
it, I mean, is it that I,
because I'm imagining if I
put myself in your shoes,
it must be in, you're in, you're
extremely successful in your career.
Is it hard for you to find someone
you respect enough to date?
Because I mean then they're like the
mental, physical, emotional toughness.
I don't spheres,
so I don't think that it's so much me.
That's how it always starts.
No, I honestly, I,
so I tend to be attracted to
people that are almost like,
I don't want to say the
exact opposite then me,
because then that sounds like I'm
attracted to people who were like aren't
successful.
But what I found is that I need somebody
who's very complimentary to me in terms
of like very kind of,
I admire people that are super laid back
and go with the flow and very adaptable
and just, you know,
everything that I'm not.
And so I think that like for me,
it's not so hard to find people like
that. I think I though, you know,
sometimes you do get,
you'll hear, you know,
it takes a certain type of
guy who can be secure with,
with being with, you know,
a woman who, you know,
beats 99% of the dudes at like
a sport or whatever. Um, and,
and that feels weird to say because
that feels like, I'm like being like,
look at me, I'm sending to the
facts are the facts. But um,
you know,
it's,
I think that it tastes actually a guy
who's very secure in his own right.
You know, you can't, I can't like date
somebody who's like, who's not, um,
you know, secure in who he is because
then that would just be disastrous.
It sound like it would get very far.
And then what,
what advice would you give your
25 year old self and place?
Place us 20 and 25 I'd be
interested to get it for both ages.
So wait, where were you? What
were you doing at 20 and then 25?
So 20, I was finishing up college. Um,
probably just getting ready to apply
to law school. Super, you know,
like hardcore driven,
going to be partner in a law firm one
day, you know, like all those things. Um,
I think at that time I would
tell myself to relax. Um,
and uh,
you know,
that you can't predict where
life is going to take you.
Um, and because now looking at him like
would I ever expect that I'd be like the
world's top obstacle racer.
We didn't even know what the fuck off.
So where it wasn't even around at night
wasn't, you know, wasn't even a thing.
Um,
and uh,
so and I think at 25 I was finishing up
law school and I was starting my career
as an attorney. Um, so I
would probably be similar,
but I think what I would tell, I'm
actually going to give you, I would,
I would tell my 28 year old self,
which is when I started all
of this obstacle racing stuff.
And
okay.
I would tell myself it really doesn't
matter at the end of the day. Okay,
that sounds bad, but like
don't take it so seriously.
Um, you know, and at the
end of the racing itself,
the racing itself,
because when you reach it started out
as totally fun and then you reach a
certain level of success and everyone
then it becomes this pressure and
everything like that.
And I think that it's not
all of the stress and the
pressure and everything that
I would put on myself from
it. It's, it's not worth it.
It doesn't change the outcome. I'm either,
you know, ready or I'm not to like,
you know, beat somebody. Um,
so at the end of the day,
kind of keep it all in
perspective and I'm like,
it's kind of hilarious.
I'm running around in the mud,
being shocked by electrical things like
running around for 24 hours in a wetsuit.
Like, just keep that in
perspective, you know,
like it's kind of ludicrous
what I'm doing, you know,
so have fun with it.
You know,
cause there's so much time that I think
that it wasted not like putting so much
pressure on myself and not having fun.
And now I've kind of like
come full circle. I'm like,
ah, it's just fun. You know?
Who would you,
who is someone or who are people
you would like to meet some day
if anywhere?
God, I see that light list
is like massive. You know,
who's, who's, who's up
at the top of the list?
Ronda Rousey,
Ronda Rousey.
I like to me strong,
I have an entire list like strong females
who are at like the top of what they
do. Um, she's on my list too. Right.
Um, but then I that also extends to,
you know, just other things
that are like not athletic,
really inclined,
you know,
so you see like Sheryl Sandberg and like
that the females that have made names
for themselves and you know, as top
executives and things like that. Um,
so I, I'm not like Rah Rah
girl power type of person.
But you know,
finding other women like that and seeing
what makes an tech and seeing how they
survive is,
is always really interesting for me.
What, if any, asks or requests
do you have for the audience?
And this is the, this is the
last question or request. Yeah.
Anything you'd like them to do
or think about or
consider or all the above.
Right. You know, I think, um,
one of the things that
I've learned is like,
and what I would tell people is like,
be open to experiences, you know,
and especially with, they're
probably like sitting, oh, people,
if they're sitting here listening to this
are either already in obstacle course
racing and are like, man, this
shit's bananas. It's great. You know,
so I don't need to
convince them of anything.
Or if they've happened
upon this and they're like,
we don't understand what this
chick is doing. Actually. Um, like,
I don't know. I would say go out there
and like, you know, try something new. Um,
and you know, so if that's off, if
you want to go out and run off score,
which of course like great,
but I wouldn't be where
I am today without,
you know, just like saying
sure. And trying something and,
and seeing where that leaves me.
So I think that's always kind of important
to keep in mind. So try something new.
Yeah, that's good advice. I'm
asking them to do something there.
I think it's good. Good advice. I mean,
do something just for the fuck
of it I think is kind of right.
Coming back to your,
don't take it so seriously.
Like not everything has to
figure into your five year plan.
And I think that's hard
because for me it's like I've always
been not like super plan or five year
person. So it was something that I
actually have to remind myself. It's like,
try something new, Amelia.
Like just do it. Yeah, why not
do it. That was, that was one
of my, I call it a resolution,
so it wasn't a new year's resolution,
but when I've done did a lot of
unusual experiments last year, uh,
we won't get into right now,
but one of the,
one of the realizations was be playful.
Like you don't have to be so God damn
serious about things all the time.
I mean the psych do something that doesn't
have an explicit point or an angle or
whatever it might be.
Right?
Yeah. If somebody told
me the other day, um,
that the only thing at the end of the day,
the only thing we have is time.
If you really cut through all the bullshit
out there and like this is funny when
you asked me about like who do
you think is successful? I'm
like,
seriously,
I think the most successful people who
are out there are people that are happy
that are just like,
they may not have it all,
they may be dirt poor or they may
not be educated, they may, whatever.
But if they can art everyday life
smiling and just generally happy.
Like when, if you break it
all down, all we have is time.
So why spend it been miserable?
So like go do something that
makes you happy and like,
and have fun with it because
you're not taking it with you.
That's your, your, your most valuable
non renewable resource. Exactly.
As far as we know,
when the my time finally comes and I
realize that there's like a super cool
world on the other side, I'm
going to be like, God dammit.
Well Amelia,
thanks so much for taking the time
and work working people say hello,
find you on the interwebs and so on.
Uh,
my grossly needs updating website,
[inaudible] dot com. Um, but I
actually am most active on, um,
Twitter. Uh, it's just the
handles Amelia Boone. Um hmm.
It's funny what Buddhists, any,
any at the end? Emilia Boon.
B. O. N. E. Correct.
Um,
but you fair for Warren?
I tweet a fair amount about the
Seahawks and professional wrestling.
So if you're not into that, you
probably don't want to follow me. Um,
and uh,
then I'm on Instagram as well.
It's a a our Boone 11,
because Emily Boone was already taken
by the time I joined that a are been 11.
Correct. Um, and I'm on Facebook. Um,
I don't have an athlete page because I
don't really like that or believe in that,
but you can follow me but I don't really
become friends with people I haven't
met before in life cause that
weirds me out. So Twitter,
so Twitter and Instagram are your
best friend. Instagram. Cool.
Well this has been a blast.
Everybody listening we will link
to the books and so on the Menuca,
honey,
bandages and whatnot,
everything mentioned in the show notes
and you can just go to four hour work,
week.com all spelled out forward slash
podcast and that will have all episodes
including this one. And I'll
create just a short, a short link.
You can go to ourself short link,
but URL,
you can get a four hour workweek.com
forward slash Emilia and that will go
straight to this episode.
And [inaudible] once again,
thank you so much for
taking the time. And, uh,
I would say let's go for a run sometime,
but I have some training to do before
I'm prepared for that and to everybody
listening,
as always.
Thank you so much for sticking
around and we'll see you soon.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work week.com that's
four hour workweek.com all spelled out
and just drop in your email and you will
get the very next one and if you sign
up,
I hope you enjoy it.
This episode
is brought to you by 99 designs when
your business needs a logo, website,
business thumbnail, or any other design.
I recommend checking out 99 designs.
I use them myself.
I've used them for many years.
I used them to create book cover
prototypes for the four hour body,
which went on to becoming number
one New York Times bestseller.
I've also used them for
banner ads, illustrations, and
much more. With 99 designs.
You get a variety of original designs
from designers around the world,
give your feedback and
then pick your favorite.
Your happiness is guaranteed to check
checkout some of my competitions in
designs and some of your competitions
and designs from fellow Tim Ferriss.
Show listeners@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and
right now you can get
a free $99 upgrade on your first design.
So check it out.
99 designs.com forward slash.
Tim
this episode is brought to
you by Wealthfront and this
is a very unique sponsor.
Wealthfront is a massively disruptive
in a good way, set it and forget it.
Investing service led by technologists
from places like apple and world famous
investors.
It has exploded in popularity in the last
two years and they now have more than
two and a half billion dollars
under management. In fact,
some of my very good friends,
investors in silicon valley have millions
of their own money in Wealthfront.
So the question is why? Why is
it so popular? Why is it unique?
Because you can get services previously
reserved for the ultra wealthy,
but only pay pennies
on the dollar for them.
And this is because they use smarter
software instead of retail locations,
bloated sales teams, et cetera. And
I'll come back to that in a second.
I suggest you check out wealthfront.com
forward slash Tim take the risk
assessment quiz which only takes two to
five minutes and they'll show you for
free exactly the portfolio they'd put
you in and if you just want to take their
advice, run with it, do it yourself.
You can do that or as I would,
you can set it and forget it.
Here's why.
The value of Wealthfront is in the
automation of habits and strategies that
investors should be using on a
regular basis but normally aren't.
Great investing is a marathon,
not a sprint,
and little things that you may or may
not be familiar with like automatic tax
loss harvesting,
rebalancing your portfolio,
cross more than 10 asset classes and
dividend reinvestment add up to very large
amounts of money over longer periods
of time. Wealthfront, as I mentioned,
since it's using software
instead of retail locations,
etc. Can offer all of this at low
costs that were previously completely
impossible right off the bat,
you never pay commissions or
account fees for everything.
They charge 0.25% per year on assets above
the first 15,000 which is managed for
free. If you use my link,
wealthfront.com forward slash Tim,
that is less than $5 a month to invest
a $30,000 account for instance. Now,
normally when I have a
sponsor on this show,
it's because I use them and
recommend them. In this case,
it's a little different.
I don't use wealth front yet because
I'm not allowed to. Here's the deal.
They wanted to sponsor this podcast,
but because of SCC regulations,
companies that invest your money are
not allowed to use client testimonials.
So I couldn't be a user and
have them on the podcast.
But I've been so impressed by Wealthfront
that I've invested a significant
amount of my own money, at least for me,
uh, in the team and the company itself.
So I am an investor and hope
to soon use it as a client.
Now back to the recommendation
as a Tim Ferriss show listener,
you'll get $15,000 managed for free
if you decide to open an account.
But just start with seeing the portfolio
that they would suggest for you.
Take two minutes, fill out their
questionnaire@wealthfront.com
forward slash. Tim,
it's fast. It's free. There's no
downside that I can think of. Now,
I do have to read a mandatory disclaimer.
Wealthfront Inc is an SEC
registered investment advisor.
Investing in securities involves risks
and there is the possibility of losing
money. Past performance is no
guarantee of future results.
Please visit wealthfront.com to read their
full disclosure. So check it out. Guys.
This is one of the hottest,
most innovative companies coming out of
Silicon Valley, and they're killing it.
They've become massively popular.
Just take a look,
see what portfolio they
would create for you,
and you can use that
information however you want.
wealthfront.com forward slash
Tim and until next time,
thank you for listening.