Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking. No else.
Now
I'm a cybernetic organism living.
This episode is brought
to you by a cent protein,
the cleanest least process protein I've
ever consumed and I have tried just
about everything since well
before the four hour body.
I've started my day with
20 to 30 grams of protein.
First thing that has
been part of my routine,
but I don't always have the time or
necessarily the desire to cook an entire
meal.
So what to do.
Protein powders can be a fast way
to get this protein needs met,
but most products are full of crap.
They're bleached, they have excess sugar,
terrible artificial sweeteners or
just straight forward low grade,
low quality protein ascent contains zero
artificial ingredients and the parent
company is actually a cheese manufacturer,
so they produce their own native proteins.
It's,
it's really fascinating and I've looked
at they're processing it takes where it
took them about five years to develop.
You can mix the protein in as little as
four ounces without any clumps or issues
of mixed ability whatsoever.
And they nailed the taste.
They tested, for instance,
the chocolate version
282 different versions.
They put a lot of money and a lot of
time into r and D for this particular
product. If you love coffee, they also
have a brand new cappuccino flavor,
which is a variation I've enjoyed.
If you prefer to test something outside
of the traditional vanilla or chocolate
and they have both way
and my seller casing,
so if you want to say improve body
composition and recovery overnight
slow-release, you can take the my seller
casein or in my case, whey protein.
I would take postworkout for instance,
or in the morning, so check it out.
These guys were really fascinating.
Visit [inaudible] protein.com
forward slash Tim, that's a s,
c e, n t p, r o, t, e,
I n.com a sense like
first ascent going up,
a scent protein.com forward slash Tim
and you will receive 20% off your entire
purchase.
If you want a very quick 20th 30 gram
dose to start your day or after workout,
this is a fantastic option. It is arguably
the best that I've found, so again,
chicken up a scent,
protein.com forward slash. Tim
this episode is brought to you by
99 designs whether you need a logo,
custom website, APP, book
cover, or anything else.
99 designs was created to make great
design accessible to everyone that's you
and to make the process
as easy as possible.
I've used 99 designs for years now.
I've used them for book covers,
some mock ups for the four hour,
which went on to become a number
one New York Times bestseller.
Illustrations of all different types
for the multivolume, the Tao of Seneca,
which you can check out and other graphic
design projects for a long time now
and I've been very impressed
by the quality of their
designers and illustrators
and you don't have to take my word for it.
You should check out some of my
projects@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim
I really encourage you to take a
look because you will be impressed.
99 designs.com forward slash Tim nine
nine designs has freelance experts in more
than 90 design categories
in their platform.
Lets you work directly with
one designer that you choose.
If you like their stuff,
which is what I did for the Tao of Seneca,
or you can get concepts from multiple
designers and then pick your favorite.
So whether you're starting a business
or just looking for extra design help,
resources, et cetera. 99 designs
has a solution right now.
You guys,
my listeners can receive a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
To checkout your first free upgrade,
please visit 99 designs.com forward slash
Tim and click the link on the landing
page. You can also find their
samples of projects from you guys,
listeners who've used 99
designs for logos, apps,
even product packaging,
so check it out.
99 designs.com forward slash Tim.
Hello Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
each episode is my job to
tease out the habits, routines,
belief systems, decision
making, frameworks, whatever
it might be, backstories,
failures,
and what they've learned from them that
you can borrow from performers and apply
in your own lives in some fashion.
In this episode,
we're going to feature three guests,
so [inaudible],
Susan Cain and Graham Duncan and I
won't get into their bio's right now.
So mentioned Nani was introduced
to me by Brian complements.
Some of you may know as the cocreator
of the hit show billions as well as a
filmmaker,
writer,
director known for
flicks such as rounders,
the illusionist, and the
list goes on and on. Uh,
Susan Cain speaking myself as someone who
considers himself an introvert who can
for short periods,
pretend to be an extrovert.
What she writes about is
very, very applicable to my
own life. And Graham Duncan,
very understated person who tends to
stay out of the public eye out of the
limelight. And you may notice for
those of you who spotted the names,
all three of them are
featured in my latest book,
tribe of mentors that Grim Duncan has
no social media profiles in the book.
And that tells you a lot about Graham.
All three of them I should
note share something in common.
And that is that I would view
all three is people who are very,
very expert at mitigating risk.
So I don't view them as a throw
caution to the wind risk at all bunch
whatsoever.
Nonetheless,
they had been very good at capping
the downside and making various career
decisions and bets that have paid
off. Very, very, very, very large.
So I hope you enjoy this as much as I did.
And uh,
I will let these three brilliant
guests take it from here.
Our guest today is so chain
Nani on Twitter at [inaudible],
s o m a n c h, a, I n a n,
I on Instagram at [inaudible] c
or you can find more about him.
So [inaudible] dot net soman is a detailed
planner filmmaker in New York Times
bestselling author,
his debut fiction series.
The school for good Knievel has
sold more than a million copies,
has been translated into more than
20 languages across six continents,
and will soon be a film
from universal pictures,
a graduate of Harvard University and
Columbia University's Mfa Film Program.
So in began his career as a screenwriter
and director with his films playing at
more than 150 film
festivals around the world.
He was recently named to the out 100 and
has received the $100,000 Shasha grant
and Sun Valley Writers Fellowship,
both for debut writers.
So the right book can slip right inside
of you and somehow wake up the part of
you that's asleep.
It can actually put words to the thoughts
that your soul can quite get ahold of
without at least a little help.
And there's so many books
that have done this for me,
but there's three in particular that
I've read over and over and over.
The first is the war of art by Steven
Pressfield, which is this slim,
tiny little book about the
creative process. It's,
it's almost like a Tao te
Ching for artists that every
time you read that you go
deeper and deeper into
this idea of overcoming the
innate resistance that faces
anybody who wants to make a change in
their life, especially a creative one,
and every time I read it at lights,
this crazy bonfire inside of me that
reminds me just how far I have to go in
order to trust the creative voices
inside of me instead of the eagle voices.
Because that's the real crisis with our
creative work is that it requires us to
trust the silent voices, the
ones that we actually, you know,
don't hear as loud as the positive and
negative ones that are always judging the
work that we do.
And it's easy to mix all these voices up
and end up quietly abandoning your own
ambition often before you
even start your project.
These eagle voices are also why I became
a pharmaceutical consultant at 21 years
old hocking Viagara instead of writing
fantasy books and movies like I do now,
because at the time of pharmaceutical
consultant belt, like a safe job,
the kind of normal job that you tell
your parents about and they tell their
friends about and makes you feel like
you're doing something right with your
life.
And so these ego voices are also why I'm
afraid to date Ivy Leaguers, I guess,
even though I reluctantly
have to admit that I am one,
because when you go to an Ivy
League school, you're tagged as,
as a success before even accomplished
anything before you even know who you are.
And so it's stokes this very fragile
sense of self and it makes you play
completely safe. And ultimately to
make any real progress in my own life,
I had to decondition myself from my own
education and really believed that I had
nothing to lose. So yes,
Pressfield's war of art.
That's where I would say the yellow
brick road starts for a second book, um,
uh, to something unusual, which is
a little life by Hanya Yanagihara,
which is a whopper of a novel that tracks
the friendship of four male friends in
New York City over the
course of almost 40 years.
You honestly won't find a book
more polarizing or divisive,
but to me it's the greatest
work of fiction I've ever read,
primarily because it hits a nerve that
I've struggled with my whole life,
which is that all of us have baggage
and wounds and pain that have shaped the
way we see the world. But we so
often hide it or compartmentalize it.
And because of that,
we close off parts of ourselves
and make our lives a lot smaller.
A little life reminds us that the pain
we feel is shared and it's a common human
bond.
We shouldn't be ashamed of it.
And that if we talk about
it and shine a light on it,
it's the first step to becoming a whole
person instead of a fragmented one.
I honestly can't imagine a more
ambitious or healing or moving book.
But what's also funny is that a lot of
people hate a little life and consider it
the worst book ever written. Um, my
brother despises it and he says, quote,
it's trash. Basically the
literary equivalent of
rubbernecking at a car accident.
So take that for what you will. Uh, Tim,
if any of your listeners ended
up reading a little life,
I'd be curious to hear
which camp they end up then.
And then I was thinking for the
third book, given my profession,
it made sense to think a little younger
because I honestly think the greatest
exercise you can do when you're stuck
or in a Rut in your life is to remember
what your favorite children's book was.
A book that you read over and over
and over again and never got tired of.
Because somewhere in that book is a
clue to not only what makes you tick,
but also to your life's purpose.
My book was Peter Pan,
which featured a title character who
is at once charming and also a complete
narcissistic pathological demon.
And I think it was at ambiguous space
between good and evil that I sparked to as
a kid. And I'm now exploring
for a living as an adult.
What purchase of $100 or less has most
positively impacted your life in the last
six months or in recent
memory? Oh, this is easy.
It's called mother dirt.
It clears your skin and it costs $49.
My skin was a hot mess for most of my
adolescence and into my twenties and when
skin problems fall you into adulthood,
it's so frustrating because it becomes
completely demoralizing and it psychs you
out and it wreaks havoc on your
self esteem. And in my case,
I tried to fix them with willpower,
which meant that I tried every single
product on earth and I tried to
antibiotics, which kill your
stomach. I tried harsh cleansers,
which dry out your skin and really
make everything so much worse.
And then I was trying every three step
cleansing program, this side of Sephora,
which just that my skin even
more inflamed and wrung out.
But then four years ago, I discovered
mother dirt in a New York Times profile.
Back then,
I think it was known as a plus biome.
And their theory was super simple.
It was that skin naturally needs a o B
a which is short for ammonia oxidizing
bacteria in order to stay healthy
and clear. But soaps, creams,
and all the things we use to help our
skin end up killing all that natural
bacteria. So if you stop using those
products and restore that bacteria,
naturally, then all of a sudden your skin
goes back to its normal healthy state.
So my brain instantly connected with
this. I was like, yes, this makes sense.
I want to try this.
So I wrote them begging them to become
one of their Beta testers. And um,
luckily they agreed and mother
dirt came in a little spray bottle,
which I kept in my fridge.
And within a week of using it,
my skin was really completely clear
and I've been using it for four years,
every single day.
The trick to making it work though is not
to use other products that'll kill the
bacteria while you're using mother dirt.
Mother dirt literally becomes your
routine. So I threw out all my fantasies.
It's Zapping pore,
unclogging oil and shining micro dorming.
We promise this will make you look like
Natalie Portman creams and toners and
cleansers, all of it. And it
was really the best day ever.
And all I do now is spray my face
twice a day with mother dirt.
I don't use anything
else. It's that easy. Uh,
their website is mother dirt.com and I
have tons of experience with this product
so your listeners should feel free to
shoot me questions if they have any of
them, uh, if they want to try
it or if they're using it.
How has a failure or apparent
failure set you up for later success?
Do you have any favorite failure of yours?
Oh, this story. Hearts to tell. I
don't know if I've ever told it.
The biggest failure I ever had was with
my thesis film at Columbia's Graduate
Film School and movie.
I poured all my savings into at that point
about $25,000 and worked on for eight
months and a day before my
final showing to the faculty,
I suddenly got a really bad
case of cold feet. And um,
there was a reason for this,
which goes back to what I said earlier
about Ivy Leaguers and fragile egos.
Columbia film school had this
diabolical little system,
which I don't even know if they still
have today, but after the first year,
the faculty all got together and
gave out this one big cash prize.
I think it was $16,000 to whoever they
thought was the most promising director.
I ended up getting that prize,
which ended up being a lot more of a
curse than anything since it directly led
to the failure that happened next.
So with my thesis film,
I wanted to prove so badly
that I deserve that price,
that I was the most promising director
that put their faith in the right
student. So the night before
my jury showing, you know,
instead of being content with all
the work I put into that film,
I completely panicked and decided I
should show it to one of the professors on
the jury hoping that he'd
reassure me he didn't.
He thought it was slow and quote,
feckless.
That word still stings anytime I hear it
or read it and recommended I slash the
whole movie to pieces and
make it half the length.
Instead of looking for a second opinion
or balancing his feedback against my own
thoughts of my work. I panicked.
Like I was a headless rooster.
This professor was obviously on the
jury and I wanted to stay the faculty's
blesseds son. And so I trusted external
validation at this point in my life,
more than my own creative compass. So
like a lemming. I followed his advice.
I spent the whole night and doing eight
months of work and re cutting the film.
And the next day I presented at,
uh,
this hacked up Frankenstein to the
faculty who absolutely demolished it.
They literally thought it was
the worst movie in our class.
Probably one of the worst movies they'd
seen. Um, you know, come into the,
the thesis presentations.
Our credibility I'd earned over the
past three years went up in smoke.
I wasn't invited to participate in
the public film school for Festival.
Lots of gossip about how I never should
have gotten that scholarship floated
around how I had no talent,
how I'd let the prize get to my head.
And of course it did,
just not in the way that they all thought.
A few weeks later I ran into one of
those disappointed faculty members,
one who'd been a huge supporter of my
work before this and now could barely look
at me.
I told them the story of the last minute
cutting I'd done the night before my
presentation and he asked me if
he could see the original version.
So I showed it to him and I
just remember the way his,
his eyes kind of lit up
like stars and he said, ah,
there you are. Now I
see you. Incidentally,
that short film in its original version
went on to great success and it started
my whole career. But here's
the lesson that I, you know,
remind myself of constantly and
I hope you can take away from it,
which is that don't let someone knock
you off your course after you've put in
all the work.
You have to trust the work you've done.
You have to always trust the work.
If you could have a gigantic billboard
anywhere with anything on it,
what would it say and why?
If I was in Hollywood,
the billboard would say their line and
actually have to remind this to myself
all the time.
Every time I'm on a call with a Hollywood
producer or a studio studio executive,
I actually pull up a screen
saver with those two words.
They're lying in all caps and I watch it
sort of spread across the screen during
the call over and over,
and it makes the whole experience a lot
more productive and less frustrating.
This reminds me of my first
experience in Hollywood.
I was coming out of film school.
I had written a script that a lot of
producers and studios were interested in
and at my first ever studio meeting,
the exact sweeps into the room.
[inaudible] it's the best grip that
he's ever read. And he's like, kid,
we are making this movie.
And he slams his fist on the table.
After that meeting, I never heard
from him again. And uh, yeah,
obviously he didn't make the movie.
But I think it's a depressing
billboard to focus on Hollywood's lies.
So let's pick another one
if I'm anywhere but la,
the billboard would say
if you can conceive of it,
it's probably wrong and use a meditation
taught me that most of the ideas and
opinions and rules and fix
systems I have in my mind,
those aren't the real truth there.
The residues of past experience that
I haven't found a way to let go of
and to be open to life, to be truly
ourselves. It's our job to be aware,
only aware, not to clutter that
precious awareness with judgements.
So I need meditation as my primary weapon
to survive life to let me study my own
brain like,
like a detective looking for thoughts or
thought patterns that I can let go of.
Because the secret to happiness I've
learned isn't really happiness at all.
But cultivating silence
and say to me this,
this big blank beautiful space and the
only way I know how to make more blank
space is through meditation.
So 20 minutes a day, every day,
wherever I am. Often I use the headspace
app because it logs your progress. So,
um, it gives you a little bit of an
incentive to keep a streak going,
but all you need is a comfortable chair
and silence and meditation becomes the
portal to the rest of my day.
What is one of the best or most worthwhile
investments you've ever made? Oh,
it's definitely flying trapeze lessons.
Those are like shock therapy for the
soul because as soon as you get on the
platform for your first class,
it's 50 feet high.
And so you're instantly making all these
cerebral calculations. You're like,
I'm going to jump this way and then I'm
going to do this and then my legs are
going to go over the bar here and
I'm going to drop into the net there.
And it's all complete and utter bs
because once you jump off the platform,
you realize in an instant
that you have two choices.
Either you trust your body or you die.
And for someone who makes
a living with my head,
I need that kind of primal therapy
to reintegrate with my body in a,
in a very sort of forceful violent way.
And just one class,
we'd be realized that
underneath my mind's chatter,
my body actually has everything under
control. If I'm willing to just, you know,
take the plunge and fly.
This reminds me of a related story,
which is that I'm a compulsive crossfitter
and at first my favorite skill when I
started the classes was box jumps.
It felt so controllable that if you just
jump on a box of a certain height and
you clear it, you get to build the box
higher and try it again. It was linear,
it was Pavlovian and rewards of control
freak like me in the clearest possible
way. But at some point I hit a
plateau and I couldn't jump any.
I got frustrated,
I tried to will myself higher.
I was watching youtube videos all day
trying to find out like what I was doing
wrong and it just led to me
forcing it again, again and again.
And compromising my form and wiping
out a lot. Yeah. And you know,
no matter how much I grit my
teeth and did it again and again,
I couldn't get past my max of 42 inches.
So I finally said, that's my Max.
I told my trainer, uh, Dave,
I said, 42 inches. That's it.
That's my complete Max. And
he disagreed. He's like,
you've gotten to this height by jumping.
Anyone can jump,
you can control a jump,
but the only way you're going
to get any higher is by flying.
And you can't think
your way through flight.
So I had to relearn box jumping
to get past my imposed Max,
my cerebral Max,
and find my real maximum.
And this required the same trust in
my body as a trapeze. Did jump commit,
let the body do the work. And if there's
one thing you can take from this,
it's that you can find something in your
own life that forces you to have this
experience. Jump, commit,
let the body do the work for there's
trapeze lessons or an Improv class or just
freestyle dancing in your room to Rihanna.
Let your body show you.
It's natural intelligence.
Give it the chance to show you.
It's going to be the most intimate
experience you'll ever have with yourself.
What is an unusual habit or
an absurd thing that you love?
I feel like this is a guilty pleasures
question and I have so many of those.
Everything from Celine Dion to peanut
butter slather popcorn to the movie
showgirls. So that horrible TV show, Alf.
But here's one, I guess that's
more important to me, which is an,
it's not something I confess to regularly,
but every night before I go to bed,
I pull out old issues of
Archie comics and read them.
It's not a new habit.
I used to read Archie as a kid
before I went to bed back then also.
And it's because Riverdale's and the
comic always seems so crisp and bright and
welcoming. Riverdale was a complete
opposite of the kind of school I went to,
which always felt so dark and morose
and always made me feel scared somehow
before having to go there
on, um, Monday mornings.
And so just reading the Archie
comics gave me this suit,
little soothing, warm feeling,
um, before I drifted off to sleep.
Then I still get to this
very day when I read them,
but maybe more importantly closing the
day by reading the same thing I did when
I was younger, gives my life this
sense of perfect order somehow.
Maybe there's a deeper
lesson in this also,
I know I'm technically a writer
of young adult literature,
but I never think of my audience that way
or I never think of myself as a writer
for kids because I think the things
we'd love when we're young are still the
things we love when we're older,
we just forget or we give up or we
quote grow up and that's why the old
fairytales always held so much for
me because they worked for everyone,
young or old.
It didn't matter who you were.
Just like Archie works for me on our old
and so maybe we all grow up in body one
day,
but I'm not sure our soul ever does and
that's why the best stories somehow can
touch us all and transcend things like
age or nationality or culture or anything
like that.
That's why the best stories are universal.
In the last five years,
what new belief,
behavior or habit has
most improved your life?
I know I should offer
something deeply profound here,
but honestly the thing that's most
improved my life in the last year is
unfollowing hot people on Instagram.
There's this amazing short story by
Ted Chiang that started all this called
liking what you see that did a real
number on me. The story of sorts,
that beauty has become this kind of alien,
modern day super drug that with filtered
and face doing social media and we
touched models on ads and
porn so easily accessible.
We've completely overloaded the centers
and overstimulated ourselves so that our
natural instincts can no longer recognize
or react to real beauty anymore and
that's making us confused and miserable
both in how we judge ourselves.
And also how we judge others and that
crystal clear warning that beauty is
literally ruining our lives.
Like the worst drug woke me up
because if we're not careful,
and this is where I fell into this
trap and was completely guilty of it,
our social media feeds become filled with
people we follow only because they're
beautiful or because we're envious of
their lives and without really realizing
it, your feed turns into this
torture device and assault
of beauty and perfection
designed to make you feel inadequate.
And so opening up Instagram doesn't
inspire, inspire you anymore.
It just makes you start to hate live
your own life since you can't possibly
measure up to the gods and goddesses of
all these perfectly filtered pictures
and it makes you intolerant of
other people's real imperfections.
And then it makes you start to despise
the weight of real people and real life
and invest in shallow, flimsy,
kind of two d mirrors of it.
It makes you constantly judge
your own life against others.
It makes you fragment and
your own consciousness
because you're living outside
of your own life in order to
get the perfect picture of it.
It's completely and utterly deadly.
And so I would say you have to use
social media to make yourself better,
to make yourself feel better,
not to punish yourself.
And that honestly has been the most
valuable change in my life in the last
couple of years.
What advice would you give to a smart
driven college student about to enter the
real world?
Hmm.
Let's start with the advice that I'd give,
which is make sure you have something
every day that you're looking forward to.
Hopefully it's your job,
but if it's not,
which isn't completely universal
and understandable condition,
maybe it's a basketball game after work
or a voice lesson or your writing group
or an open Mike night,
maybe it's a date.
Have something every day that lights you
up because it'll keep your so hungry to
create more of these moments instead of
getting dragged down and to kind of the
Rut of having you know,
a job that you're not excited about.
And I'll also remind you what
really fulfills you in life.
When I was a pharmaceutical consultant
and I was completely miserable,
I used to come home from work and work
on my novel that would eventually become
the score for good and evil.
I never intended to publish it.
I never intended anyone to read it.
I just did it to offset the
misery of a job that I hated.
And over time I loved
writing the book so much.
So they used to leave early sometimes in
order to work on it and slowly the work
started to, to, you know, the, the novel
starts to take over my work life too.
I found myself secretly working
on it, you know, in the mornings,
during meetings in the corner,
during office, during lunch.
And eventually I got fired because they
figured out I wasn't doing any of the
real work and I was actually working on
my book and the truth was I wasn't upset
because I had discovered what
had made me happy at that point,
which was telling stories and nothing
was going to put that genie back in the
bottle.
US for advice that ignore a little part
of me dies every time someone tells me
that they've taken a job as a stepping
stone to something else when they clearly
have no interest in that job whatsoever.
And I think it's because the truth
is you only have one life to live.
Time is super valuable.
It's the one currency that we're
all fighting to get more of.
And so if you're using the idea of
stepping stones and jobs that you're not
really interested in
to get somewhere else,
you'll probably relying on somebody
else's path or definitions of success that
was created in the past and I think
it's more important to live in your own
present and try to make your own path.
It's going to end up being more
fulfilling for your own life.
What are bad recommendations that you
hear in your profession or area of
expertise?
Too often aspiring artists put
this pressure on themselves
to make the creative
work their only source of income that
they can't be an artist unless they're a
full time artist.
Somehow and in my experience it's just a
road to complete another misery because
of art is your only source of income.
Then there's unrelenting pressure on that.
Art and mercenary pressure isn't just the
enemy of the creative elves inside you
trying to get the work done.
But mercenary pressure also often
leads to really bad and rushed work.
So having another stream of income dreams,
the pressure on your creative engine,
if nothing comes of your art or
it flops and miserably, whatever,
you still have an iron clad plan to
support yourself and so you quit of soul,
feels a lot lighter.
It feels free to do its best work.
And I'm still a personal practitioner
of this, even though I could easily be,
you know, full time writer because
after four books in a movie deal,
I want a separate side stream of income
in order to be able to write without
feeling like it's a matter of life and
death. So I tutor kids on the side.
I help them with their
college applications and
I've been doing that for the
last 10 years and really no plans to
stop because it makes the books better in
the end if I don't feel like,
um,
the books are my only source of livelihood
in the last five years, what have
you become better at saying no to?
I am convinced that the reason Hollywood
movies are often so terrible is because
everyone is so busy hedging their bets
that they're working on a thousand
projects at once.
They don't want to commit to anything
for fear that it's going to fail.
No one is giving anything
their full focus.
So when I worked on the
school for good and evil,
I decided to take the opposite track.
I decided to commit completely and
the series has taught me to be patient
because when I'm writing a new book,
that's all I work on and I say no
to all other creative projects,
no matter how lucrative do I
miss opportunities. Absolutely.
But it means that when
the books hit the shelves,
I know that I've left everything on the
page and they're the absolute best I
could have done,
which then gives a series the greatest
chance to survive through time.
It's easier to say no though.
When professionally I know what my
driving need is because if you're driving
this to build income and
provide for your family,
then you'll say no to anything
that doesn't further that goal,
but if you're driving, you need to
stop your own business for example,
then you need to be a bit more promiscuous
and trying out ideas until the right
one hits. In my case, my driving
need is always unequivocal,
which is I want to make something that
lasts and that means committing to my
current work,
like a marriage and believing that if
I give these six books in the series,
everything I have then
better opportunities will
eventually rise to replace the
ones that I passed up.
When you feel overwhelmed or unfocused,
what do you do?
So feeling overwhelmed usually
means one of two things.
Either my blood's trapped in my head
and I need to get out there and exercise
and move the blood around and you know,
give myself space to breathe or more
likely my to do list as become completely
overpacked and my brain.
No,
there's no way I can reasonably get done
everything I've set out to do and so
that's when the solution is taking out
the calendar and start canceling things,
moving things around,
you know,
seeing what I can take off my plate and
then I can feel the promises of operate.
Once I hit that threshold of knowing that
I can reasonably accomplish whatever I
want to do.
Now feeling unfocused is all different
because it usually means I haven't quite
locked into whatever I'm working on that
a part of me still thinks I can pull
the ripcord and bail
and is afraid to commit.
It usually happens in the first three
months of writing a new book because that
lack of focus is usually just fear.
Fear that the new book is terrible fear
that is going to fail miserably and sync
my career early on. I used to give
into that fear and four books later.
Now I know that I just
have to hold on tight,
grip my teeth and blow right
through it like a ghost.
Our guest today is Susan Cain.
See a I n on Twitter at Susan Cain,
Facebook author Susan Cain,
quiet rev.com is her website.
Susan is the cofounder of quiet revolution
and the author of the best sellers,
quiet power,
subtitle,
the secret strengths of introverted
kids and quiet subtitle,
the power of introverts in a
world that can't stop talking,
which has been translated
into 40 languages and has
been on the New York Times
bestseller list for more than four years.
Straight.
Quiet was named the best book of
the year by Fast Company magazine,
which also named Susan, one of its
most creative people in business.
Susan is the cofounder of the quiet
schools network and the quiet leadership
institute and her writing has appeared
in the New York Times, the Atlantic,
The Wall Street Journal,
and other publications.
Her Ted talk has been viewed
more than 17 million times,
probably more than 20
million at this point.
And it was named by Bill Gates as
one of his all time favorite talks.
How has a failure or apparent
failure set you up for later success?
Do you have any favorite failure of yours?
So a very long time ago I used to be
a corporate lawyer and I was a very
ambivalent corporate lawyer and anyone
could have told you that it was in the
wrong profession, but still I had
dedicated tens of time to it. Um,
you know, three years of law school when
you're clerking for a federal judge,
six and a half years at
a Wall Street law firm.
And I had a lot of very deep
relationships with fellow attorneys,
but the day came when I was very well
along on partnership track that the senior
partner in my firm came to my office and
sat down and told me that I would not
be put up her partner on schedule.
And to this day,
I really don't know whether he meant that
I would never be put up for partner or
just delayed for a long time,
but all I know is that I burst into tears
right in front of him and then asked
for a leave of absence.
And I left work that day.
And I remember bicycling around and
around Central Park in New York City,
having no idea what I
was going to do next.
I thought I'd probably travel and I had
all kinds of plans to go to India and so
on. But instead, and,
and this all happened in such a kind of
Seddon and cinematic way that it will
defy belief.
But
what happened is I remembered that
I had always wanted to be a writer,
which seems strange.
You would think.
I had always had that in the
back of my mind. But, um,
my writing dreams where something I forgot
about had forgotten about for a very
long time. Um, but I started
writing that very night.
And then the next day I signed up for
a class at Nyu and creative nonfiction
writing.
And the next week I went to the very
first session of that class and it really
was like a kind of epiphany moment.
I felt like I was finally home.
I had no expectation of ever making a
living through writing because you always
hear about how difficult that is,
but I was just clear to me that from
then on I was going to put writing at my
center and so I decided to just look for
freelance work that would give me lots
of free time to to feed my hobby.
Now,
if I had succeeded at
making partner on schedule,
I might still be there today.
You know,
kind of miserably negotiating
corporate transaction 16 hours a day.
It's not that I had never thought about
what else I might want to do other than
law,
but there's something about being
inside of very intense 16 hour a day.
Her medic culture,
like a lot of practice that makes it
really difficult to figure out what else
you might want to do.
What is one of the best or most
worthwhile investments you've ever made?
Best Investment I ever made was the seven
years of time that it took me to write
quiet.
I really didn't care how long it took
and though I very much wanted the book to
succeed, I felt good about that investment
of time regardless of the outcome.
Cause I really didn't know
what was gonna happen,
but I felt so certain that writing in
general and that writing that book in
particular was the right thing to do.
So what happened is, well first of all,
I had two kids along the way. So
of course that slowed me down. Um,
but also I handed in a first draft
after the first two years and my editor
basically said this is very crappy.
And she said,
take all the time you need and start from
scratch and go home and get it right.
And you might think that that was
a moment of grand discouragement,
but it was actually exactly the opposite.
I remember leaving her office elated
because I agreed with her and I knew I
needed a lot of time to get it right.
Um,
and I was thrilled at the publisher
was giving it to me. You know,
I had never published a word before quiet
and I felt like I was learning how to
write a book from,
from scratch.
And most publishing houses rush books
to market a long time before they're
really fully done, you know, just
because of economic exigencies and, and,
and I feel like if she had done that,
there would be no quiet revolution.
What is an unusual habit or
an absurd thing that you love?
I really love sad,
minor key music.
And the funny thing is I find that kind
of music very elevating and transcendent
and not actually sad at all.
And I think it's because there's kind of
music is really about the fragility and
the preciousness of life and love.
So if you're curious about
some examples for me,
Leonard Cohen is my patron saint.
Ah,
you could try listening to dance me
to the end of love or to famous blue
raincoat or pretty much to anything
that he's ever written. Um,
if you're not familiar with his work,
I'm sure you know his song. Hallelujah.
That has been made into a
cover a gazillion times,
but that really is only
the tip of Leonard Iceberg.
I also love this song
called [inaudible] by um,
an amazing guy named Eden Rice.
Hell,
it's a really gorgeous song of
a man longing for his beloved.
And it's really about longing in general,
whether you're longing for
God or for heaven or whatever.
My favorite word in any
language is the word, so dodgy,
which is the Portuguese word that's at
the heart of Brazilian and Portuguese
culture and music.
And it basically means a kind of sweet
longing for a beloved thing or person
that will likely never returned to you.
And I know that sounds a long
so desperately sad, but again,
it's so hard to articulate it,
but there's something so incredibly
beautiful and transcendent in that very
idea. And if you want to hear
the music expressing that idea,
you could try a band called modular
deus or the singers sees area,
I'm not sure I'm pronouncing her name
correctly, but sees Adria, a Vora,
something like that. And by the way, my,
then my next book or my whole kind of
nixed work chapter of my life is all about
this topic of,
of how loss and longing are
such an essential part of
love and art and growth in
general.
What advice would you give to a smart
driven college student about to enter the
real world,
smart driven college student?
Um,
you're going to hear so many stories of
people who risked everything in order to
achieve this goal or that goal, especially
when it comes to creative goals.
But I don't believe that your best
creative work is done when you're stressed
out because you're like on the edge
of bankruptcy or some other personal
disaster.
It's really just the opposite.
So you should be setting up your life
in a way that's as comfortable and happy
as possible.
And that often means setting it up in a
way that doesn't appear very creative on
the outside.
Because here you're tapping into kind
of more conservative structures, um,
but what you're really doing is freeing
yourself up to accommodate your creative
work.
So I often ask myself whether all
those years of of Wall Street law,
we're a waste.
Given that what I really was meant,
I think to be doing the whole time was
to explore human psychology and you know,
do what I love to do.
Now I'm writing about what
it's like to be alive.
It's really how I think of my work.
Um,
but the answer is that no,
it was totally not a waste for so
many reasons. I mean, first of all,
because I learned so much about the
so called real world that would have
otherwise been a mystery to me.
And second,
because a front row seat at a Wall Street
negotiation is as good a place as any
to study the ridiculousness
of being human. Um,
but most of all maybe is because it
gave those years that I spent practicing
law,
gave me a financial cushion when I was
ready to use it to try out a creative
life. I wasn't a huge cushion. I
had not managed to see if that much,
but it didn't make a huge difference.
So even once I started my writing life,
I spent tons of time setting
up this little freelance
business on the side where
I taught people negotiation skills.
And it was something that I felt I could
use as long as I needed to to support
myself when my,
my real center always was writing.
And I like the,
the thing I was trying to do the whole
time was take the pressure off the
writing so that the writing
could always be a source of,
of joy and satisfaction.
So I told myself that my goal was to get
something published by the time it was
75 years old and that was it.
Um,
so I met my goal a lot earlier than that.
Okay.
So I am not saying by the way that the
smart driven college student who wants to
have a creative life should spend 10 years
in corporate finance first. Very much.
Not saying that I'm really making a
more basic point that you should just be
planning how you're going to make
ends meet and have a way to do that.
And that way, the time that you do
spend on your creative projects,
and it could be 30 minutes a day,
it could be 10 hours a day,
but you want those moments to be about
focus and flow and occasional glimpses of
joy and you do not want them to be
associated with financial stress.
When you feel overwhelmed or unfocused,
what do you do?
I Love Espresso and I would
happily consume it all day long,
but I'm really afraid of habituating
to it and losing its magic powers.
So I only allow myself to have one latte
a day and I save it for when I'm doing
my most creative work of the day because
it really does jumpstart my mind and
this almost magical.
It has a kind of magical power.
And also by now I associate latte
and it kind of pub bloviate way,
um, with writing, which then
gets associated in a pub,
Low v and way with the pleasure of coffee.
So it's all really good feedback loop.
My guest today is Graham Dunkin.
You can find out more
about him at east rock cap,
cip.com Graham is the cofounder of East
rock capital and investment firm that
manages $2 billion or so for small
number of families and their charitable
foundations.
Before starting these truck 12 years ago,
Greg worked at two other investment firms.
He started his career by cofounding,
the Independent Wall Street research
for a medley global advisors grand.
Graduated from Yale with a Ba in ethics,
politics and economics.
He is a member of the council on Foreign
Relations and serves as Cochair of the
Sohn Conference Foundation,
which funds pediatric cancer research.
Our mutual friend Josh Waitzkin who
introduced us and you should look up Josh
Waitzkin if you don't know who he is,
I'll give you a hint.
Searching for Bobby Fischer.
Josh Calls Graham quote,
the tip of the spear in the realms of
talent tracking in judgment of human
potential in high stakes mental arenas
and quote, and that is a mouthful,
but Graham is,
I've gotten to know him over the years
is more and more impressive with every
encounter that I have with them. And if
you want to hear more from Graham ideas,
his thinking frameworks,
everything you can sign up for his monthly
email newsletter@grahamdunkin.blog.
What is an unusual habit or
an absurd thing that you love?
So Tim,
I wear the SUBPAC wearable physical sound
system while I commute on the subway
to my office and sometimes I
wear it while I work at my desk.
You strap the system to your back and
chest and I'll let you feel the vibration
of music through your whole
body. Music producers, gamers,
and deaf people are the primary users.
And I find the full body experience of
music makes listening to music or even a
podcast that has a lot of base,
more of an immersive somatic experience
rather than just a conceptual head
thing.
If you could have a gigantic billboard
anywhere with anything on it,
what would it say and why?
So I have two candidates. First,
it's not how well you play the game.
It's deciding what game you want to play.
That's by Kwame Appiah,
who's a philosophy professor at Nyu.
And I like it because it
separates striving from
strategy and reminds me to take
a macro view of whatever I'm doing.
Like in a video game where you can zoom
out and you suddenly see you've been
running around in one corner of the maze.
It loosens my relationship
to the game too. It's Kinda,
it's the game of the game.
Helping to separate,
having ambition from being ambitious
or accessing hustle without actually
becoming a hustler.
Another quote that I really like is from
the Buddhist novelist George Saunders
who said in an interview with the New
Yorker that he has an image of people's
nectar indicating containers
from Buddhist like Saunders.
Think everyone has a Buddha nature.
That good core of your being.
Some people sometimes lose lose
track of it, but it's there.
I think it's such a good
assumption to have about everyone,
even if you're wrong
sometimes that that's there.
And I also love that image it of nectar
and decaying containers that helps me
visualize the stream of Buddha nature
flowing through all the lovely flawed
living and slowly dying creatures
that we all encounter every day.
And I sometimes get this glimpse
of how my three year old daughters,
three year old self is so temporary
Buddhist like to say we're all on fire and
it's so beautiful. Sometimes
tune in, just see the flickering.
What are one to three books that
are greatly influenced your life?
So the psychiatrist's Sam Burundis has
a book called making sense of people.
That had a huge impact on my thinking
and I sometimes give a copy to people who
are building a new team and doing a lot
of hiring or even a friend that might be
deciding whether or not to get engaged.
As part of my role, an investor,
I interview four to 500 people a year
to decide whether to hire them or invest
in their various startups and investment
funds and most useful mental model.
I've found to help understand,
help me understand what makes people
tick is the one that Brenda's described
eloquently in his book.
The model is called the big five or
ocean and the o stands for open minded.
The C stands for conscientious,
the e for extroverted,
a for agreeable in for
neurotic and the academics,
academics who developed the model clumped
every English adjective that can be
used to describe somebody's into
categories and then they reduced them to a
small set of factors as they could.
So have lots of people agreed they
could call somebody both gregarious and
outgoing.
Then they decided that was the same thing
and they kept reducing that down until
they got,
say extroversion as a primary factor.
And in the academic
literature on personality,
the big five is like the
equivalent of gravity.
There've been thousands of studies and
it's considered much more statistically
accurate than alternatives
such as Myers breaks.
And so if you want to picture it
like for a high openminded picture,
Leonardo Divinci for high conscientious
picture Robo cop for high extroverted
picture Bill Clinton.
And for the opposite highly introverted
picture Obama for low neuroticism
pictured the dude from the big Lebowski
or any stereotypical Californian and for
high neuroticism picture of Woody Allen
or Kanye West or most New Yorkers I
could free associate about the big five,
but I'll leave it there if
you want more than checkout.
San Brenda says book and Scott Barry
Kaufman is also obsessed with the big five
and writes a bunch of
useful stuff about it.
There are two other mental models that
have greatly influenced my thinking about
people and teams. The first
is Harvard professors. Uh,
Robert Keegan's model
of adult development.
Keegan argues that adults develop and
make sense of reality in five discreet
phases.
He lays out his theory in his
1994 book in over our heads,
which is unfortunately
not available on kindle,
but his velum paper back in the title
in over our heads is a reference to how
the vast majority of adult Americans are
at this socialized stage of development.
We call it level three that have and they
have difficulty taking other people's
perspectives and they tend to follow
assumptions given to them by society as
opposed to assumptions they freely choose
and he points out like in modern life
that many activities such
as parenting benefit,
if you can set boundaries and not care
what your kid thinks it needs to direct
them and doing what you
think they should do.
I feel like I sometimes
see what I imagined to be
socialized stage parents who
are afraid of, they're almost afraid
of their kid on some level they they,
they take what their kids think too
seriously and I want to be their friends
first and parents second.
There is when I'm interviewing somebody
there's something that can feel a little
bit icy when you're interacting with
self authored people cause they aren't
sourcing their approval from you.
You can either,
there's something about the tone of the
interview that is distinctive and to try
to make this more concrete.
There's this amazing example in chapter
nine of in over our heads or Keegan
describes a couple who are both operating
from my self authored mindset and it's
a very distinctive description of the
way they make sense of each other and of
being married.
That totally reminds me of one of Tim's
podcast with Laird Hamilton and Gabby
Reese where Gabby is describing the
way she relates to layered into their
marriage in a way that to my ear is super
unusual self authored way for people
who are interested in
learning more about the model.
I recommend Keegan's later book immunity
to change where he describes the model
briefly at the beginning of the book,
I'll read a quick excerpt
just so people have a feel.
Having a socialized mind dramatically
influences the sending and receiving of
information at work.
If this is the level of mental complexity
through which I view the world than
what I send will be strongly influenced
by what I believe others want to hear.
Let's contrast this with
the self authoring mind.
If I view the world from this
level of mental complexity,
what I send is more likely
to be a function of what
I deem others need to hear
to best further the agenda
or mission of my design.
Consciously or unconsciously, I have
a direction and agenda, a stance,
a strategy and analysis of what is needed,
a prior context from which
my communication arises.
The self authoring mind creates a filter
for what it will allow to come through.
It places a priority on receiving the
information that is sought information
that I haven't asked for it in which
is not have obvious relevance to my own
design for action as a much tougher
time making it through my filter.
It's easy to see how all of this could
describe an admirable capacity for focus
for distinguishing the important from
the urgent for making best use of one's
limited time,
but having a means to cut through the
unending and ever mounting claims on one's
attention.
The speaks to the way the self authoring
mind is in advanced over the socialized
mind, but the same description may also
be a recipe for disaster if one's plan or
stances flawed in some way.
If it leaves out some crucial
element of the equation,
not appreciated by the filter or if the
world changes in such a way that a once
good frame becomes an antiquated one.
Contrast this self transforming mind
both values and is wary about any one
stance,
analysis or agenda.
It is mindful that powerful though a
given design might be this design almost
inevitably leave something out.
It is aware that it lives in time and
that the world is in motion and that what
might've made sense today may not make
as much sense tomorrow. Therefore,
when communicating people with self
transforming minds are not only advancing
their agenda and design. There are
also inquiring about the design itself.
Information sending is not just on behalf
of driving does also to remake the map
or reset the direction
someone wants to hear how a person's
sounds when they make sense of reality at
the self transforming stage.
Then I direct them to listen to
Tim's early podcasts but ed Catmull,
the Pixar founder and president,
the loose but strong grip that
kept mall has on his own beliefs,
his fluid and flexible
relationship to time.
There's this slightly a femoral quality
and comfort with paradox that comes
through in the interview and he in the
interview when Tim's interview with him,
he's actually a bit of a
difficult interviewee and he
feels a little hard to pin
down at times.
For instance,
he refuses to answer Tim's question
about what he would tell his 20 year old
self because he says now he has a way of
understanding that his 20 year old self
simply couldn't understand.
This is all very consistent with a self
transforming mindset which happens later
in life for most people if it
happens at all, it's an example.
It would surprise me to hear Catmull
say or think any version of quote.
I'm just trying to stay relevant as he
gets older and from one perspective you
might be losing ground versus younger
people in this industry or he fails to get
his phone calls return,
but his way of making sense is likely
that he gets to define who or what is
relevant not as peers in silicon
valley or the movie industry.
One last self-transforming example I
would give is the voice of the narrator of
the home parable by Louise Gluck. If
you Google it, she's really amazing.
The third mental model that I
find myself recommending lately,
not in a book but on a slightly obscure
website called work with source.com and
it's based on a European
management consultant who
studied hundreds of startups
and realize that even when
there are multiple cofounders,
there's actually always in every case
he found an actual single source.
The person who took the first
risk on a new initiative,
even if that risk was only picking up
the phone and calling the other cofounder
and he argues that that source maintains
a unique relationship with the gestalt
because of the gestalt of the original
idea and has that person has an intuitive
knowledge of what the right
next step for the initiative is,
whereas others who joined later to
help with the execution often lack that
intuitive connection to the
founder's original insight.
And these guys argue that many
organizational tensions in power struggles
actually often revolve around lack of
explicit acknowledgement of who the source
of the initiative is.
I was talking about this with a common,
an angel investor recently,
and he had found that consistent with
his sample of startups and he noted that
many founders seem to hire friends as
cofounders more to quell their own anxiety
during the early highly ambiguous days
of a new company than to fulfill a
specific role.
This can work fine as long as everyone
is clear on who the sources their spa.
And it's a little paradoxical,
here's the responsibility to fully own
the role of source rests in large part
with a source of themselves.
Handing off the source role of an
issue to another person is possible but
extremely difficult and
it's often mishandled.
And these guys know that a key to a
successful transition is for the original
source to actually move on and allow
the new leader Remnick move this.
Um, I was speaking with an investment
manager about this and he had,
it was consistent with a study he had
done of stock performance following
founders,
CEOs departing their businesses.
And you found that any subsequent positive
stock performance was correlated with
the founder completely leaving the board
rather than hanging around to mentor
the next CEO.
So through that Lens,
Gates remaining on the Microsoft
board during bombers tenure may have
contributed to subsequent lack luster,
stock performance,
embalmers inability to kind of
exert his own creative vision,
whereas bomber leaving the Board has
allowed Satya Nadella to fully assert his
own creative vision.
I encounter this dynamic of myself
sometimes in running a multifamily office
where we manage money for Forbes 500
families and second and third generation
sometimes struggle with how to relate
to the original patriarch and the quote
source of their wealth.
And it's,
my observation is often the responsibility
room for real transition is in the
hands of the original source.
It's the lesson from George
Washington's song in Hamilton musical.
As Washington declines, Hamilton's plead
around for a third term and he sings,
we're going to teach
them how to say goodbye.
What purchase of $100 or less has most
positively impacted your life in the last
six months or in recent memory?
So I recently bought the
fitness F I n I s swim pedals.
They somewhat magically lengthen out my
freestyle stroke and when I combine them
with some fins, I use the
ones from Cressy, crae,
Ssi feel sometimes like almost flying
through the water for non-swimmers.
I highly recommend the canned
sardines from [inaudible] mat I. Z.
I feel like one of my
proudest accomplishments as
a dad is that my two younger
kids eat sardines with me
most mornings for breakfast.
They're super high protein,
high good fats.
There's no need to supplement fish
oil and Mathias sardines aren't fishy.
I usually add avocado with salt and
lemon and the kids love him and I often
alternate the sardines with
canned wild salmon belly,
which they call [inaudible], r e s t
r Eca from the company. Vital choice.
The bonus on both of those is that
when the Zombie apocalypse comes,
she you'll have canned food ready to go.
How has a failure or apparent
failure set you up for later success?
Do you have any favorite failure of yours?
I have so many failures.
I'm just going to pick one and my role
in in investing in and seating investment
firms,
I do really extensive reference checks
on people in order to try to accelerate
the process of building mutual trust
with them and I should note that I have a
somewhat oddly specific aspiration to
be the best in the world are among the
best in the world in terms of being
able to really do a reference on someone
they feel like it's a real art form to
gather private information in the form of
multiple perspectives about how someone
has played a repeat iteration game in
the past and then try to accurately
how you're going to play in the future.
I had to find success as gathering
enough honest perspectives on someone to
mimic how I would know someone if I had
sat next to them at work for five years.
We at least truck.
We tried to do references in person and
it's a huge time investment and link
2007 I was about to back a firm and we
conducted a final reference check with
the investment manager,
his former boss who was quite negative
and skeptical about his former analyst.
I remember I asked him what percentile
the analyst was in terms of all the
analysts who'd ever worked for him
and he said top 60% which I thought I
misheard it first and I've never gotten
that response again in a reference and
it surprise me given that the analysts
had given me this guy's name as a
reference.
It wasn't an off list reference.
He was on his list and it made me pause.
I'm proceeding with the investment,
which then proceeded to
work out amazingly well.
As the financial crisis unfolded and I
had a lot of regret about the size of the
profits I missed.
Later on an emergency,
the reference source may have had an
agenda to sabotage his former proteges new
firm.
Then several years later I was evaluating
another investment manager to partner
with in toward the end of our diligence
process. I got another reverence,
not quite as negative as that one,
but it was mixed and but I felt like
at this point I was better able to hold
multiple prospective simultaneously
without experiencing cognitive dissonance.
It's like the state of negative capability
that Keith's referring to as useful
to writers.
And this time having those mixed data
points only me only made me do more work
and I gained even more conviction in the
character and competence of the miss my
manager and that investment has ended
up being super profitable and I think
absent my earlier failure,
I wouldn't have had the ability to
see the reality of the situation.
And it also just helped me
appreciate something I try to do,
which is I try to hold people's
perspectives with a light grip,
which is the knowledge that they and I
have very incomplete maps of reality.
What are bad recommendations that you
hear in your profession or area of
expertise? So I think people
massively overuse the term hedge fund.
They fetishize it a little too much.
It reminds me a little bit of a similar
issue is that Ray Dalio found when they,
when he used the word depression in
2008 to describe some of the underlying
dynamics in the economy,
he found that his readers had
too much baggage with the word.
So we switched to using
the word deep process.
And Yuval Harari makes a similar kind
of reframing move by referring to us as
CPS because we have so much baggage.
But being human and being in the Senate,
you know,
being in the center of the species who
the most important species and in a
similar way I think people
now have weighed too much
baggage with the word hedge
fund. The press and the
managers themselves have made,
it almost jumped the shark.
And I've been telling people lately I
think we should start using h structure or
something like that,
but to instead capture the
concept of incentive compensation,
I don't think it's useful to see a hedge
fund or a product or even the hedge
fund industry because these are just
temporary collections of flawed brilliant
people who in any given year decide to a
sequel to the movie they made the prior
year.
The only product is the set of future
decisions that the portfolio manager makes
think get divorced or the crest if
they're second in command leaves.
The quote product completely changes.
And I think thinking of it as a product
ignores the reality that the only source
of stability is actually whether the
mindset of the team leader is resilient or
even antifragile,
which is the Nassim Taleb thing about
actually getting stronger with volatility
rather than just enduring it.
When you feel overwhelmed or unfocused,
what do you do?
So I asked myself what would be
the worst thing about that outcome,
not going the way I want and actually
started using it out loud with my kids.
And we recently, my eight year old
daughters started asking it back to me,
which was karmic full circle.
I really like to be punctual and
we were late to drop her at school.
And I was impatiently hurrying
her along and she asked me, dad,
what exactly would be the
worst thing about being late?
And it in the moment it
completely shifted my mindset.
I like the question cause it often
surfaces a hidden assumption in this case,
maybe some UB subconscious script of
I'm playing the role of father and our
family meets our commitments
or some version of that.
And another good related question is
Byron Katie's thing about the opposite of
your story be true. I think that
that question serves the same role
in the last five years.
What new belief,
behavior or habit has
most improved your life?
I began swimming most mornings and I
find it often shifts my mindset for the
entire rest of my day there.
Some swimmers talk about
this concept of water feel,
which is getting a grip in the water
and pulling your body past that point
instead of ripping your
hand through the water,
ripping your hand would through
the water moves you forward.
But it's a lot less
efficient and less graceful.
And I really liked David
Foster Wallace's speech.
This is water and where he's making
the point that so much a water,
so much of life is water to us.
We're swimming in it,
we can't see it cause we were either in
a hurry or not awake to our context or
in key and language.
We are subject to it.
And when I stopped to really
feel the water before I pull,
it shifts my way of being in from one
of kind of thrashing towards the end of
the pool somewhat mindlessly to a more
effortless flow of working with the
reality of the water where I am.
What advice would you give to a smart
driven college student about to enter the
real world?
So lately I've been thinking about careers
through Dan Siegel's model of mental
health where he says picture river flowing
between two banks where one side is
chaos and the other side is rigidity.
And Dan points out that mental illness
is all reside on one bank or the other.
Schizophrenia is on the chaos side,
OCD is rigidity and basically healthy
integration is swimming in the middle of
the river is his argument.
And most college students have started
life closer to the rigidity bank is my
observation.
And over the course of their careers
will experiment with swimming toward the
middle. And I've come to think of
the lane right next to rigidity,
the rigidity bank as an appropriately
conventional one four w in your twenties
when you're in your twenties and you're
kind of acquiring the skill of refining
reality.
It's a place to swim where it's important
to learn the jargon of an industry and
apprentice under somebody to develop
judgment and discover your own zone of
genius.
And I think swimming in the Middle Lane
happens most often in people's thirties
or forties to stage where you begin
crafting your own language for what you do
as an increasingly strong poet.
You, you make your craft, your own,
you feel your life is more self
expression than simply playing out other
people's roles for you.
And then some small percentage of people
will pedal over to the lane next to
chaos,
which is a place where you find novelists
like Robert Parasail egg and David
Foster Wallace investors like Mike burry
or Eddie Lampert or entrepreneurs like
Steve jobs and Elon Musk and I
experienced them as consistently asserting
reality a through k through
powerful storytelling,
while always bearing the risk that their
egos grow too big and their creative
narcissism gets to well defended,
they lose situational awareness and they
basically lose their feedback loop with
reality. I visualize them almost
flopping onto the bank of chaos.
And so if you look at it through
this lens, then precincts,
wrestling with sanity towards the end
of his life, Steve Jobs is magical.
Thinking about his illness and Eddie
Lampert's and Randy and framing of his
investment in seniors may have all been
examples of these guys losing their feel
for where they can mythologize to the
point of bending our collective reality.
And then they suddenly
briefly appear crazy.
I think Musc in particular drives hedge
fund managers of the wall as half of
them are short as shares because he exudes
so much promotional hucksterism as he
asserts reality.
And half of them are long because he's
actually thinking on a hundred year
timescale and it's very confusing.
And East truck,
we always say that if you want to have
variant perception it helps to be variant.
And I remember interviewing Mike Burry,
Steve Eisman and all the
other somewhat fringe,
somewhat variant investors who were
shorting subprime mortgages in 2006.
And uh,
the all the,
basically all the characters that Michael
Lewis captured so accurately in the
big short and the housing
bubble is obvious in retrospect,
but at the time almost everyone thought
they were completely smoking dope.
And the current crypto scene.
The cryptocurrency scene reminds
me a lot of the subprime short, uh,
ecosystem because the opportunity attracts
the most or the more variant players
have nothing to lose from disrupting
the status quo. So I'm crip,
you've got all the libertarians and the
end employed macro hedge fund managers
and all the kids.
There's this great quote by one of
the characters and Tom Stoppard's play
Arcadia, the crypto guys like,
which is the future is disorder.
A door like this has cracked open five
or six times since we got up on her hind
legs.
It's the best possible time to be alive
when almost everything you thought you
knew is wrong.
I think that mentality of
saying bring it on to chaos,
that now that now is the best
possible time to be alive. To quote,
learn to love the rain is Josh Waitzkin
says it's really hard for people who
have succeeded in the status quo context.
And so I think bitcoin could just be
a bubble due to QE post the financial
crisis or it can be a change in how we
organize human activity at the level of
the Internet itself or both.
And I'm at the moment trying to hold both
perspectives without needing to decide
yet trying to stay, I think of as an open
chair instead of striving for closure.
I'll finish up the career question
with one last quote from the very self
transforming Charlie Munger,
who at 93 has no filters left and he,
he's more wisdom percentage than
almost anyone I read. He says,
I've noticed in a long lifetime that
the people who really love you are the
people where you scrambled together with
difficulty and you've jointly gotten
through and in the end those people will
love you more than somebody who just
shared in an even prosperity
through the whole thing.
So this adversity that seems so awful
when you're scrambling through actually is
the sinecure of your success, your
affection, every other damn thing.
The idea that life is a
series of adversities in
each one is an opportunity to
behave well instead of badly is a very,
very good idea and he says,
and it works so well in old age because
you get so many adversities you can't
fix, so you better have some technique
for welcoming those adversities.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short
email from me every Friday?
That provides a little more soul of
fun before the weekend and five bullet
Friday is a very short email where I share
the coolest things I've found or that
I've been pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the other
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance,
and it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend,
so if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour workweek.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled out
and just drop in your email and you'll
get the very next one and if you sign up,
I hope you enjoy it. This episode
is brought to you by 99 designs.
Whether you need a logo, custom website,
APP, book cover or anything else.
99 designs was created to make great
design accessible to everyone that's you
and to make the process
as easy as possible.
I've used 99 designs for years now.
I've used them for book covers,
some mockups for the four hour body,
which went on to become a number
one New York Times bestseller.
Illustrations of all different for
the multivolume, the Tao of Seneca,
which you can check out and other graphic
design projects for a long time and
I've been very impressed with the quality
of their designers and illustrators
and you don't have to take my word for it.
You should check out some of my
projects@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash.
Tim, I really encourage you to take
a look because you will be impressed.
99 designs.com forward slash Tim.
Then then designs has freelance experts
and more than 90 design categories in
their platform. Lets you work directly
with one designer that you choose.
If you like their stuff,
which is what I did for the Tao of Seneca,
or you can get concepts from multiple
designers and then pick your favorite.
So whether you're starting a business
or just looking for extra design, help,
resources, et cetera. 99 designs
has a solution right now.
You guys,
my listeners can receive a free
$99 upgrade on your first design.
To check out your first free upgrade,
please visit 99 designs.com forward slash
Tim and click the link on the landing
page. You can also find their
samples of projects from you guys,
listeners who've used 99
designs for logos, apps,
even product packaging,
so check it out.
99 designs.com forward slash.
Tim,
this episode is brought
to you by a cent protein,
the cleanest least processed protein
I've ever consumed and I have tried just
about everything since well
before the four hour body.
I've started my day with
20 to 30 grams of protein.
First thing that has
been part of my routine,
but I don't always have the time or
necessarily the desire to cook an entire
meal,
so what to do.
Protein powders can be a fast way
to get this protein needs met,
but most products are full of crap.
They're bleached that excess sugar,
terrible artificial sweeteners or
just straight forward low grade,
low quality protein ascent contains zero
artificial ingredients and the parent
company is actually cheese manufacturer
so that they produced their own native
proteins.
It's,
it's really fascinating and I've looked
at they're processing it takes or it
took them about five years to develop.
You can mix the protein in as little as
four ounces without any clumps or issues
of mixability whatsoever and they nailed
the taste. They tested, for instance,
the chocolate version 282 different
versions. They put a lot of money in.
A lot of time into r and D
for this particular product.
If you love coffee, they also have
a brand new cappuccino flavor,
which is a variation I've enjoyed.
If you prefer to test something outside
of the traditional vanilla or chocolate,
and they have both way
and my seller casing,
so if you want to say improve body
composition and recovery overnight
slow-release, you can take the micellar
Casein or in my case with whey protein,
I would take postworkout for instance,
or in the morning. Check it out.
These guys were really fascinating.
Visit [inaudible],
routine.com/ that's a s, c e, n t, p,
r o, t, e,
I n.com the sense like first descent going
up the same protein.com forward slash
Tim and you will receive 20%
off your entire purchase.
If you want a quick 20th 30 gram dose
to start your day or after workout,
this is a fantastic option. It is arguably
the best that I've found. So again,
chicken up a scent,
protein.com forward slash Tim.