Quick sound test.
This is transition from t to Tequila.
How do you feel about that decision?
I'm pretty excited and off we go
at this altitude I can run flat out
before my hands start shaking the oils.
You posted a question.
I'm a cybernetic organism
living this year.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
I interview some of the world's top
performers, whether that be in investing,
sports, entrepreneurship or
otherwise film art, you name it,
to extract the tools and resources and
habits and routines that you can use and
in this episode I have the pleasure in
beautiful San Francisco to interview an
icon of tech,
but you do not have to be involved with
tech or even understand tech to get a
lot out of this conversation.
Matt Mullenweg is one of my close friends.
He's been named one of PC world's top 50
people on the Web Inc coms 30 under 30
and businessweek's 25 most
influential people on the web.
Why you might ask, has he received all of
these accolades? Well, he's a young guy,
but he is best known as a
founding developer of wordpress,
the open source software that powers
more than 22% of the entire web.
It's huge.
He's also the CEO of Automattic,
which is valued at more than $1 billion
and has a fully distributed team of
hundreds of employees around the world.
However,
Matt started off as a
barbecue chomping Texas boy.
So how did this all come together?
It certainly was not the grand
vision from day one at all.
And Matt is an incredible human being,
is a gifted musician.
He is able to eat more than a hundred
chicken mcnuggets and in one sitting,
and we'll talk about why and how he
did that and we really dig into the
specifics of how he hires,
what he looks for in people.
We get really, really nitty gritty
into his favorite books, his routines,
music habits,
work style.
He's one of the most productive
people I've ever met in my life.
I think you're really gonna enjoy this
episode. Be prepared to take notes,
but if you want all the links and
resources and everything else,
of course you can find them.
As always in the show notes,
just go to four hour workweek.com forward
slash podcast or just go to four hour
workweek.com all spelled out and click
on podcast and that'll take you to the
show notes. So without further
ado, please enjoy Matt Mullenweg.
Matt, sir, welcome to the show
had Hattie, Hattie, Hattie.
So let's explain the how to howdy
because there's some context missing.
Of course we know each other.
Where does the howdy from? Uh,
I was born and raised in Texas,
fine state. He was a fine, greatest
country in the world. And uh,
you've taught me a great many
things related to barbecue
related to photography,
so thank you for that.
You got me very interested in photography
and we've traveled a lot together.
But for those people who don't know who
you are, when, uh, when someone asks you,
what do you do,
how do you answer that?
These days I'm probably best known
for once eating 104 chicken nuggets.
And one setting. Are you serious?
Yeah. Wow. I did not know.
How old are you need does that like
last week. Now you won't forget it. Um,
and then on the side I do,
uh,
we're going to open source
publishing platform called wordpress,
which power is such an amazing sites such
as the four hour, everything for Tim.
That's true. And others like New
York Times, Wall Street Journal, um,
about 23% of all websites now
are on wordpress. That's amazing.
And how did wordpress start for people
who don't know the origin story?
Sure. Uh, well it's an open source
project and it actually started, uh,
as a fork or a derivative of an
already existing open source project.
So it was this thing out there
called [inaudible], which um,
I was using and blogging with myself
and the, the crater disappeared.
So the development stopped and myself
and this guy in England named Mike Little
picked it up and kept working on it.
How old were you at the time? 19. 19.
And were you self taught from, from
the standpoint of programming? Yeah,
I tried to take some classes in school
and they were just all terrible.
So I would programming,
especially open source programming,
like the web was the best place to learn
it. And what made the class is terrible.
I'm just, I'm always curious
why, why did they fail?
Why did they not appeal to you? Well, I
didn't go to a great school to start with.
I was at University of Houston.
I had amazing high school experience,
a high school for the
performing and visual arts.
One of the best experiences of my life.
But then I stayed in Houston.
You have h was all right. But uh,
the computer classes in particular,
I think like 20 or 30 years ago,
Microsoft basically
changed the curriculums are
influenced the curriculums of
May these colleges. So even
though this was 2002, 2003 there,
the web had already happened, you
know. Right. It was a thing. Yeah.
But they are still teaching you like
Microsoft visual basic and like you're
building like buttons on
Windows Apps, sons, sons,
really a white knuckle stuff as I did.
And so you see began working on this fork.
And could you explain what
open source means? Sure.
For people who aren't familiar with it,
open source is for me the
most important idea of,
and it's supposed to in my
lifetime, I actually, uh,
so think of open source like
a bill of rights for software.
And I think this is incredibly important
now that more and more of our lives are
influenced or governed by software.
It basically says that here's a four
freedoms that are inalienable rights you
have when you use open source software
and the licenses that wordpress is under.
The GPL says you have the freedom
to use the software for any purpose.
So that means you can make a,
Matt has funny hair blog if you want or
you can it or whatever you like and you
can see how the software works,
you can modify the software and then you
can distribute those modifications to
your friends.
And this sounds pretty basic and trivial,
but a lot of what we use it would be the
equivalent of if you open the hood of
your car on there was just a black box
and you could be fined or go to jail for
trying to modify things, tampering with
it. Yeah. We're trying to understand it.
And let's, uh, so you,
you're working on this fork.
At what point does it become
wordpress from the beginning actually.
So with a capital w and a capital p for
everyone wondering that if you want to,
I don't see Mech at angry much,
but if you want to really hit one of
his pet peeves, it's the lowercase B,
lowercase B.
Actually,
it's not possible to write wordpress
with an uppercase w and a lower case B on
wordpress as it should be, as you
should. It'll auto correct it.
I also feel badly for every transcendental
meditation teacher and I brought up,
I was like,
does it bother you when your TM always
turns into a trademark symbol in there?
Like, oh my God, how did you know that
they need their own platform? Evidently.
Uh, so when did it become
wordpress? When was it,
when was it Chris and wordpress as the
name actually was one of the first things
that came up with a friend in Houston
named Christine had the idea for the name
and um, she checked to the.org was
available and I registered at that day.
And that really brought it together
because [inaudible] slash cafe log,
if you have a slash her name, something
wrong in the beginning, but, um,
wordpress, I just liked it from the
moment I heard it. I was like, oh,
this feels like something that
has a little bit of Gravitas,
but still it's pretty accessible.
And the focus is in the early days,
which kind of distinguished us
from what we're at fort from.
I focused on web standards,
um, cleaning up the code,
making sure that what we were out
putting was really tight and then
installation. So it created
something called the famous
five minute installation.
Um, so the standards would be like, and I,
I'm using maybe a sloppy metaphor,
but making sure that the
grammar and everything is
standards so that it can have
the widest adoption and tinkering
possible. It was more at the time,
the web platforms,
you would build a website for Netscape
and you build a website for Internet
explorer and you'd use different
code for both our sites.
We've worked with one and not the other.
I said,
so web standards who create a common
platform between them. Got It.
And the installation ended up being the
biggest thing we called it the famous
five minute install,
even though it was neither famous,
it's famous to the two of you guys.
But it became a self fulfilling prophecy,
right? Because people said, oh it's,
it's famous and it's only five minutes
and competitive software at the time
would take 30 minutes an hour to set up.
And also that's how some
of our contemporaries like
movable type made their
money in the beginning cause you
could pay them to install it for you.
So the economic incentive was not
to make the installation easier.
So we just came in with that from the
beginning and it was really appealing to
folks.
So you were right simplifying to get the,
well,
it's very interesting because
you were open source at the time.
He did not have a profit motive.
Nope.
And therefore you are not incentive
on is to complicate the profit.
There were no golden handcuffs,
right, like likened to loose,
which is true for a lot of industries.
Professional Training for instance,
uh, is very much like that.
There are very few trainers
are incentivized to make
themselves unnecessary,
right?
To make themselves obsolete.
So they'll have a rotating schedule and
different types of mezzo cycles and so
on that keep you tethered to
an ongoing program of training.
What's the Mezo Cycle? Well, you, you
can have different types of cycling.
For instance,
if you were leading up to a power
lifting competition or a wedding,
a trainer, it could very similar. Uh, you
always want to look like a power lifter,
especially if you're a lady
for your wedding. Uh, you can,
you can cycle the type of training.
So you might have,
let's just say arbitrarily,
uh,
70% of your one rep Max and you work
between 70 and 75% of your one rep Max for
four to eight week period, something like
that. And then you go into a new cycle,
which is, uh, I'm making this up again,
but like 90% of your one rep
max are between 85 and 90. And,
uh,
so that would be that that has a place,
but I feel like just to bring it
back to two wordpress is that,
uh, I feel like the, the,
the number one priority of any good
physical training trainer or nutritionist
should be to enable their client with
the know how and tools that make them
themselves obsolete. Uh, so
this complicate the profit is a,
is is a real problem in a lot
of industries. What actually,
so my favorite classes in college where
the political science and philosophy
ones and because you think about
systems instead of necessarily just and
incentives versus, uh, what works
or what gets you to the next thing.
So, uh, again, kind of like what you said,
a personal trainer is not going to be
incented to put themselves out of a job.
Um, can you create a system,
something you've done with,
through your work where people can
self enable and from the early days of
wordpress, we, we'd always think,
okay, well if we do x today,
what does that result in tomorrow,
a year from now, 10 years from now?
And it was kind of silly to think
about 10 years from now, but it's now
12 years old.
So I did that longterm vision
develop. What were the components that
helped you to develop that longterm view?
Because you're a young guy.
I mean, you still aren't,
despite the fact that you don't have
a three in front. How old are you now?
31 as of last week,
I was so tired of the under 30 awards that
you're getting every year. I was like,
God, can this guy just turned 30 already?
I feel badly about myself every year.
It's award season. Huh?
Here we go again. But, uh,
what helped you to develop that,
that longterm view besides maybe these,
these political poly sign classes?
Yeah,
I think the, uh, political science really,
really helps because any particular
aspect or figure I've really loved,
uh, to cities. It's actually
a classic. Um, he wrote, uh,
I think it was the Peloponnesia book
about the Peloponnesian War and he was one
of the first what we
see now as historians.
So he would go back and writing
about this series of events.
We'll kind of look at the why and what
was the environment which created these
things rather than saying Xyz happened,
saying this is what the world was like
and that caused Xyz had happened. Um,
but the,
the metaphor I think of the most because
as simple as just like a dog chasing
the car, right? Like what does the
dog do if he catches the car? Right.
It doesn't have a plan for it.
Yeah.
So I find it just as often
an entrepreneurial side,
people don't play for success either.
Hmm.
Like if we create a
marketplace for plugins, right?
What is the natural conclusion of that?
If it's really, really successful, um,
well it's really, really successful.
There's not that many free plugins, right?
It looks more like an APP store on
Ios or android where everything's paid
because that's what the incentives will
be for the developers over the long term.
And
so let me ask you, this is a somewhat
oblique question or unrelated seemingly,
but do you, are there any hedge fund
managers that you really get along with?
You don't have to name them by name,
but you could sir. Our investors. Okay.
Who are some of your investors and we'll
talk about what they've invested in
tiger global.
So there's an amazing guy, Lee Fixel
over there. He works on the private side,
not the public equity side, but it's
a hedge fund that end of the day, uh,
insights, true ventures. I
have. Some were actually,
you've been blessed from the very
beginning with really great investors.
I know of a handful of hedge fund managers
very closely who were extremely good,
but a lot of them are macro.
They would describe themselves as
sort of macro guys, uh, which, uh,
I'll hope to go into another time.
But the point being,
they are very good at looking at sort
of primary effects, secondary effects,
tertiary effects and trying to,
trying to predict the various butterflies
effect that can then inform a trade
that other people aren't thinking of
or a position that other people are
thinking of. A, I think you're
very good at that. Um, what,
okay.
If you had to call yourself a world
class at something besides eating chicken
mcnuggets, what, what would
you, what would you say that is?
It might be related that because
the mcnuggets now thinking of systems,
um,
and sort of environments and ecosystems
and how things sort of cascade because
the, uh, you know, running an open
source project there. The, the,
the joke in term is BDFL so benevolent
dictator for life is technically my role
within wordpress,
but it's the most powerless
dictatorship ever because, uh,
oh, obviously you don't have an army,
you don't have the ability to tax. Uh,
but you don't really
have a carrot or a stick.
You're not paying people to do things
and you're not punishing them if they
don't do things.
So you really earn a position where you,
the things you do have control over,
like let's say the website or how
the code works or the license. Um,
you have to think of the
implications of that.
And then it's really just the power of
a bully pulpit, you know, once a years.
It's like the state of the Union
speech is happening from Obama. Uh,
once a year I give a state of
the word speech and try to,
that's at word cope at word camp.
Yeah.
I tried to think what are the things
that have been influencing me and the
things that won't happen naturally in
the wordpress ecosystem that might need
another push or might need to expose the
community is something that they're not
thinking about. So a lot of
times at Word Camp San Francisco,
I'll bring in speakers like yourself or
other folks who aren't in the day to day
wordpress, you know, hubbub, right.
Despite my best efforts to muck things up,
I was very happy, very,
very pleased that, uh,
our friend Nathan was so kind at the
barbecue world championships that sponsors
a,
do you still sponsor a team there?
I didn't last year as a first year.
I haven't been in a couple of years.
All right.
And Mason,
who's a tremendous developer,
help to build a plugin called probation,
which allows me to white list someone
who leaves in a good comment that has
aspects of, of questionable behavior,
whether it's too much cursing,
maybe attacking someone else,
putting in too many links, um,
which is a hugely helpful
features. So thank you. Listen, uh,
and the, that customize that, that,
that ability to customize has always
appealed to me about wordpress.
What are other, uh, we can look
at it through a different Lens.
What are some of the mistakes that would
be competitors to wordpress have made
that prevented their wide,
wider spread adoption?
Hmm. Most of our, uh,
most contemporary competitors,
so the wix.com Squarespace,
etc. They focus more on it being a
service rather than it be something that's
super extensible. So, for example,
that feature you just described, um,
we'll never be in court precedent. It will
never be what in core wordpress. It's,
um,
you know that it's a relatively small
audience isn't useful for the edge case.
Yeah.
And you know what to be like other people
who maybe have the same prominence as
your blog, it would be useful for,
so there is an audience out there,
but it's not the tens of millions.
They use wordpress.
So if you're building a service like
wordpress.com or like Squarespace,
one of these others,
ah,
because you essentially have one
code base that everyone runs,
you have to sort of designed for the
majority or what you think the majority
he's going to want or be a
where with wordpress with.
It's sort of infinite good
sensibility of themes and plugins. Uh,
there can be a million
Neesha's and in fact, uh,
with the way plugins are distributed for
people that run wordpress themselves,
almost no two are alike.
Right?
L when you think of the theme
plus the plugins at each blog,
each one's its own unique,
beautiful snowflake, right?
So you're not trying to decide what the
average Susa shoe sizes in the world and
give everyone a nine, uh, well,
so our competitors will say, ah,
it's this checklist of features and we're
going to do these 10 things wordpress
does, and maybe we'll do this one better
than this one better. And honestly,
like a smart team of a couple
of developers could probably
do that in a year. Um,
but to replicate the,
you know,
35,000 plus plugins and themes is
sort of, it's a huge moat. I mean,
it'd take lifetimes.
and@whatpointdidyoudecidetocreateautomaticwordpress.com?
Sure. So, uh, I should say what automatic
is. I'm a master company where I work,
um, and I became CEO last
year and basically it's,
they'd wait until he had a three in front
of your day and they had to wait until
I was 30.
Um,
so it was basically taking the idea that
there are some services for wordpress
that aren't appropriate for the open
source side is this distributed nonprofit
thing.
And so,
and also that I wanted to create a
company that I wanted to work at.
And so that became automatic.
Um, what was the question? Uh,
how did you decide to create automatic?
Ah, you know, what it was, is it was spam.
Okay. Tell me more. So you know,
things on the web get spam. Oh yes. I'm
very well aware whether it's your email,
a contact form, you know, spammers will,
I think I have 100,000 more than a
hundred thousand spam comments in my wow.
Spinning. Righto. So what's been
protecting you as a plugin called Akismet?
Correct.
So kismet is anti-spam system.
And what had happened was I kept riding
anti-spam plugins that were just plugins.
So there was just code that would run on
your blog and they would work for like
an ever decreasing amount of time.
So like the first one stopped spam for
like a year and the second one stopped it
for like six months.
And then it got to the point where I'd
release a new version and like the next
day the spammers would work
around. I was like, these,
I always had like an idea of like a,
I apologize to anyone Russia name Ivan,
but like I like this guy in Russia, I
like to download a plugin like, oh ha ha,
I can work around this so easily.
And um, and so I thought, Huh,
like this is asymmetric warfare.
We're never going to beat the spammers
cause they are like the bully on the
playground unless we team up.
Right.
And so Akismet is sort of a assist pack
of wolves that tear the bullies apart.
Yeah, it's a pack of wow, I like that.
Or maybe it's like circling the wagons,
you know, it kind of protects you for,
it's more like visually less violent
and it's able to adapt as quickly as a
spammer spammers where, um,
because it's a centralized service.
I built some centralized services before
that were expensive to run and costing
me a lot out of my own pocket.
So I wanted to make it a business
so it can be self sustainable.
I didn't want this something sort of
running on my charity or if I went away
this would stop.
So that's why we also need money
for food and I don't need that much.
We'll talk more about that
later. Got It. Not to interrupt.
So akismet spam and that was the first
part of auto of automatic and it made
perfect sense because it was something
that wordpress, the software couldn't do.
It was something that was a service.
It was something that I wanted to have
a sustainable business model and I'm,
so that was actually the first
thing. I kind of the, I left seen it.
So I moved out to San Francisco, I
got a job at CNN. It was awesome.
I was there for about a year and
basically the weekend after I left I just
hacked like the whole time and
released the first version of a Kismet.
What year was that roughly?
I believe it was 2005 2005 and was
that the period in which you were
experimenting with Polyphasic Sleep?
Or was it before or after that question?
Um, no, I did the polyphasic
sleep before then. Okay.
So that was a,
that was when I was still in Houston.
And for those people who don't know Polly
physics leaves is very controversial
concept of taking what
would normally require,
say eight hours sleeping Mano phasic
meaning one block in breaking it up into
multiple fragments. I wrote about
this in the four hour body and men,
do people get excited about that?
You did positively or negatively. Uh,
so what was it you were experimenting
with? Was it Uber Man? Uh Huh.
So it's about, what is it between
two and two and a half hours,
something like that in a 24 hour
cycle in a 24 hour cycle. So it,
the four hours on and then
2030 minutes of sleep.
What happens if you miss one
of those neps your wrecked.
But this was probably one of the
most productive periods of my life.
So I wrote wordpress and that time
and also something called BB press.
And I remember, I remember your
answer, but I'm curious if, uh,
if you remember what you told me, why
you stop polyphasic sleep, what happened?
What did I tell you? Um,
you got a girlfriend.
It turns out, I know girlfriends
don't like that sleep cycle.
No one would have predicted that the
getting into the girlfriend and maybe the
beginning of the girlfriend.
Um, and maybe that's that.
Maybe that's why Mary someday, you know,
someone who also be on polyphasic sleep,
but the seems like you're
really tense household.
She has to type, double rack and do
polyphasic sleep. What? All right,
you brought it up. Why are you
obsessed with divorce check? Oh yeah.
So Devorah is an alternative keyboard.
So instead of that,
I was going ASD F it's
a oh EU for example.
And all the letters it's f for a and m
actually are in different places. So it's,
it would be a competitor to Qwerty.
Yes. Right. And it's more efficient.
So I think I was 14 or
15, I thought, well,
I'm going to probably be
typing the rest of my life.
And so if there's a more
efficient way to do it, um,
I should learn that.
And it took about a month.
It's Kinda like learning a
new instrument actually. Uh,
and I just kind of went cold Turkey
and learn a type of work and I've been
doing it. Yeah, we're 15 years now. Gosh,
I'm old. And do you still offer rewards
to employees who pick up the work?
It's more like public shaming
and or highlighting. Um,
we do a little hints like it's a, it's
a dictator with a little more teeth. Uh,
we'll, we'll, uh, you know,
in our Christmas pack we sent out like
a Devorah keyboard cover for your laptop
or little a DV Xen,
which is a DV z.org is actually a great
website that tells you all the benefits
of work even better than I have.
So there's things like in a,
I'm making up the numbers,
but in a year of typing and query,
your fingers move like 18 miles and a
divorce, they move like two miles. Wow.
I guess almost an order of
magnitude more official.
I never thought of it this way, but
there's the speed benefit, which uh,
I'm very impressed.
I was very impatient with the divorce.
I did play with it for awhile and then I
had to switch laptops with people and I
wasn't tech savvy enough to to figure
it out or not. It was in Europe I think.
And I was just like having trouble
with the settings and they got very
frustrated.
But uh,
would you say there's an argument for
Devorah tech being easier on your tendons
and carpal tunnel and all that? I'd say
that's the most, um, the biggest benefit.
So I, you know, again, a type for a
living and I've never had any problem.
What type of keyboard do you use? Uh, I
just use the keyboard of my laptop mostly.
Now do I?
Yeah.
They used to have this funky ergonomic
keyboard that kept your hands,
your palms, more verticals
that right? Yeah.
You emailed me about that the
other day. What was it called? Oh,
I have no idea what I'm asking.
I looked it up and I told you what it was.
But yeah, it was where the
keys were actually sort of
slanted in. Right. And um,
so it's almost like
you're holding joysticks.
I mean in that hand position with your,
with your fingers extended and it is,
you know what, that keyboard
is very comfortable and I
like it, but honestly the,
just the, I'm not really limited
when I'm on my computer by the speed,
I can type meaning unless I
was transcribing something.
Like right when you're talking,
I'm limited by the space of extra dollars
transcribing and or have it every now
and then, um, you know, I'm really
limited by speed I can think, right.
Which is much slower than 120 words per
minute or whatever I can type and um,
so really the comfort
is what does it for me.
It's also kind of a cool security
mechanism when someone sits down at your
laptop and like they can't do
anything quickly, anything,
but it is Devorah is built into
every single modern day computer,
windows and Mac.
So you can just as a setting,
if you go to into international
keyboards and you can do it. Um,
and I'd highly recommend, you know, you
have a pretty hardcore of listeners,
so pretty hard core habit of writing too.
Um, yeah, I would check out the work,
but there's also a slightly more efficient
one called coal Mac that if I were
starting today, I might do call Mac. How
do you spell Comac? C. O. L. E m. A. K.
Um, now the difference between
Courtney and Devorah is like,
let's call that 50% in between like
Devorah can call Mac is like two or 3%.
So got it. I haven't switched again,
just because it's only marginal. But, um,
if you're coming from Courtney, yeah.
Pick one of them. Huge. Cool. All right.
We will link to all that in
the show notes. Uh, automatic.
Hmm.
Is it coincidence that automatic is
spelled with an m a t t in the middle?
That was a typical egotistical founder.
I tried to work my name and
everything and uh, should do that.
I should, I could, I could, Tim is short.
I could stick it in the
middle of a lot of stuff. Uh,
automatic itself is,
it's a unique company in a lot of ways.
How,
how has automatic different from
the average tech startup out there
had a lot of ways. So the first and
foremost is that everything we put out,
we're open source to the core.
So most technology companies,
the Ip of our software is one
of the chief values of it,
and we open source from
released to the public.
The vast majority of the Ip we create.
So that's the first and foremost,
and it's really the key to the
philosophy of automatic. And the second,
which is I think the future of work
and the future of all companies,
is that we're totally distributed.
So we're now over 300 people and 37
countries and well over 200 cities.
So most people work from home or in
coworking spaces, wherever they are.
We have a headquarters
here in San Francisco,
but it's only got about
20 ish people in it.
And every time I've been to the
headquarters, look, where's everybody?
Oh wait there teach tee shirts.
I can get that deck.
They're going to be a teacher.
But we just needed a place
to get mail and subpoenas.
Do you get a lot of subpoenas? Ah, yeah.
It's like everyone who publishes them,
it's like if Bill Gates, Scott takedown
notices for people using Microsoft word,
like we just get everybody
contacting us for everything.
Every type of a disagreeable content
that's published on wordpress results in
some type of letter. Yup.
That sounds like fun. Well,
the more clueless the attorney, the more
likely they're all the contact us. Right,
right. And, uh, focusing on
the distributed aspect, uh,
how did you make that decision
and how early on, I mean, what,
what was the process like?
Tell me the story of how you made that
decision is literally from day one and
it's, it was influenced by
the fact that, you know,
wordpress is an open source project
before I created the company automatic.
So the first four or five
people at Automattic, we're
all in different cities. Um,
you know, we had Vermont's Texas,
I was in San Francisco actually.
The very first guy was in Blarney Ireland,
Cork County, which is like the Texas.
I were the blarney stone. Is it as it
over the blind? This is the blarney stone.
So you, uh, you climb to the top
of this castle thing and you kind
of hang off the side and Eric kind of
upside down and you kiss this stone.
She's as old guy was trying to hold you
and it's probably not
sanitary, but yeah. Um,
I was very shy before I
kissed it about 10 years ago.
And now you're down talking
to you. Okay, well hold on.
I want to talk about nervousness and
boldness and shyness for a second.
We are going to come back
to the distributed nature
of automatic. This is not,
in fact the first time that I've
interviewed you. Do you remember,
do you remember the very first,
maybe you can tell people about the very
first phone call that I made to you?
Was that an interview?
No, I was saying I was, I was calling
you to ask if I could interview. Yes.
So Tim, this was pre for our
work week, right? Yeah, it was,
I think it was 2006 so it
was an old school or early,
early 2007 my Tim Bona Fides out
of like, oh yeah, back in the day.
Um, and I got the I, my phone never
rings and I almost never answered,
but for some reason I answered this and
I'm this weird guy who talked very fast,
did
monologue for like 10 minutes. I don't
know, it was actually 10 minutes.
It was really bad. But this was
a Timbo Tim Ferriss and he was
telling me about something,
I don't know,
I think it was like verbal shock and awe.
It was,
I was trying to establish my
credentials and a mutual friend,
Mj Kim had had made the intro and I was
worried you would hang up because I was
aware, I was aware of vaguely that you
did not, you weren't really a phone guy,
so you're trying to get an all the words
before I hung up. That's right. Which,
which is not the best policy in the world.
But we did end up,
it worked getting know each other and
I wanted that story to be told because
it's easy for listeners or
readers to assume that, you know,
my pitches have always been great
and then I was born that way. No,
I've had thousands of horrible pitches.
Some of them just by the luck of the
day you happen to contact someone work.
But it's despite your, despite your
technique, not because of it. So
distributed from day one,
what are the tools that you
currently use to make that work?
So open source projects mostly work like
this and basically what they do is they
say you use things like,
well back in the day I'm going to say
some old technologies and then we'll get
some new technologies,
IRC,
which is sort of a old text
chat or I am system. Um,
you collaborate using
distributed source control.
So we use subversion is the modern day
equivalent would be something like get
hub. So you basically have ways that
you can, we get email mailing lists, um,
forms, all the things that, you know,
people do even when they're in the
same office. [inaudible] they, they,
I am each other. You just make that the
primary way you communicate and that,
so that's what we did from the very
beginning. I mean, what our Max started,
we literally, it was
bootstrapped beginning, had
no money. And I thought, well,
why would I was in San Francisco?
But why would I move all these people
to the most expensive place in America,
right? When we also have no money?
And I'm most investors. Fact,
a lot of them said, oh
yeah, when you raise money,
you can finally move everyone there.
But you know, Donica and Ireland's was,
became ready to start a family.
And you know,
people are different places for
different reasons and it's true.
The Bay area has some amazing talent,
but you also have, well two, two things.
You have some incredibly talented people
all over the world who for whatever
reason don't want to live here, even
though it's a pretty cool place. Yeah. Um,
you also have, you know,
some of the largest,
most successful companies in the world
market caps of over a trillion dollars
combined competing for the same 20 or
30,000 engineers in one place in one
place, right? So when you add
up Cisco, oracle, apple, Google,
just go down to the dimensional, the
startups, linkedin, Facebook, Twitter.
Plus all startups. Um, they're, uh,
they're all fishing in this pond, which
is a little bit over fished. Yeah. Um,
again, not to say there's not
great people, it's just that, uh,
perhaps back in the day when you had
to go to like one of these universities
like Stanford or MIT to learn the things
to create a scalable webscale startup
or service. Um, it was
important to be clustered there,
but now you can learn all this stuff
on hacker news and you can read,
read it and you can,
you know,
learn everything you need to do to build
the next wordpress from anywhere in the
world and in place.
You have an internet connection.
So there's some super smart people all
over. And so we just started to say,
well, just like it's silly to discriminate
on the basis of the, just say gender.
I've said,
we're not going to hire a man or a woman.
It's dumb because you're just cut
out half of the possible hiring pool.
So by definition, people who hire would
be not as good as if you looked at 100%.
We said,
well,
we're going to look at the 99.9% of
the world that doesn't live in the San
Francisco Bay area.
So not only are you getting better
talent because you have a larger pool to
filter from.
What can you do with the cost savings
of not having to build out a huge
infrastructure for a campus?
I don't know if there's actually a cost
savings because once you start flying
people around and things like that,
like it does add up and we give people a,
an allowance for example,
a $250 per month coworking allowance,
they can use it at Starbucks or cafes,
they can use it at a coworking space. We,
so we, we invest in people's a space
because we want them to be productive.
But I think what it really comes down
to is just allowing people freedom,
autonomy and something that was actually
inspired when I finally read your book
is some lifestyle arbitrage.
Yeah.
I mean you can make us San Francisco
salary and live in Argentina or Alabama or
wherever you want to. Cause
a lot goes, it goes very,
very far and that's kind of
cool. And um, or like myself,
like I travel most of the
time. Where is the, uh,
your 37 countries,
what are the most heavily weighted
countries were represented?
Countries. Oh, an order. It's probably
it's English speaking countries in order.
So it's a United States is about two
thirds. So again, more than majority. Ah,
we love us some Canadians.
I love Canadian. Um,
UK, Australia. Those are kind of
the top four or five. Yup. Ireland.
So because we're still,
although we're totally distributed,
we're still speak English,
right? So places where, uh,
so that's like the top five and
then have the other 32 countries.
Um, many of them, we just have
one person in them, right.
We only have one person in India.
We have I think three or four people
in Argentina, one person in Brazil.
So it just kind of ends up being
whoever the coolest, most. Uh,
I was going to say
bad,
but I don't wait
for a few who don't know. Matt. He
never curses. He has a lot of trouble.
It'd be like forcing Mr.
Rogers to say fuck on the air.
It would just be the most excrutiatingly
painful thing to watch. So yes,
there are bad, bad button
bad, but engineers, Tim, now
I can't send this to my mom.
We can, we can bleep the f.
It's all right. You know,
I actually don't have a problem with
cursing. I just don't do it myself.
And how long has that been? Has
that always been the case? No,
I don't mean you're from Texas.
And again,
I don't let them in and get
all the tech ops curse a lot,
but I'm from Long Island.
It's like you can't avoid it.
That's half of what we say.
This is actually a myth in the company
that you can't curse around me or I'll
get mad. But it's just not true at all.
Um, I have no personal problem with it.
I feel like I would've picked up on that.
How long have you not been cursing?
I feel like I must have read
a book when I was younger,
like a James Bond type book or something.
And I, cause I recall the sentence,
I just don't remember the
context and if someone's like,
you know the English language has more
words in it than any other language in
the world.
And so you can find your way to express
yourself and some of these other
hundreds of thousands of words
now obviously words like f word are so
versatile you can use them in a million
different ways. But the, there's
a lot of other really good ones.
So I tried to have all
expressed myself in another way.
It's always struck me and I feel like
such a course unrefined sort of knuckle
dragger with the amount that I curse,
which is I, I enjoy being around you.
And a the is something we've talked about
on the podcast before with other folks
is surrounding yourself with people
you want to be the average of.
And so I like one of the reasons I
enjoy being around you is that you,
you forced me to become very
aware of how much I curse,
which oftentimes I think it is reflective
of lazy thinking just in the way that
if you overuse the word interesting, like
Oh, interesting. That is a garbage word.
It means nothing like come up
with a better word or, uh, my,
my particular crutch was
pretty, oh, that's pretty
good. That's pretty expensive.
I was pretty awesome.
And I got so annoyed with it.
The way that I tried to fix it,
which very
well actually for a period of time was
requiring that every time I say pretty,
I add fucking after it no matter who I
was with that guy that's pretty fucking
expensive on it's pretty fucking pretty
or whatever, which, which solved it. But,
um, the, what are the
current tools that you use?
So you had IRC and so on,
but what, what do you,
what's the state of the art
within automatic for managing,
keeping that machine running
with the distributed teams.
So we actually ended up
creating a tool called P two.
So you can get it at [inaudible] dot com
and that is a basically
a replacement for email.
So automatic basically sends no emails.
I get all the emails I get is
from people outside the company.
And think of pizza too.
Almost like a social cast or a Yammer
or can like an internal Twitter or
Facebook, but really work oriented
where people can post short things,
long things, blog posts and bed,
youtube, rich media, mockups, images,
audio, anything. And it's a
threaded asynchronous discussion.
But because it's not email,
I honestly don't know why people
use email so much in companies.
Because imagine that you're a company,
you're a team of 10 people
and you joined that team.
How do you catch up with a past
two years of conversations?
Do you get people to forward you like
all the emails they've been doing,
if someone leaves,
like does everything in their inbox,
what does everything in
their inbox disappears?
And all that sort of locked
in knowledge has gone.
So everything in automatics public by
default, all of our stats, all of our,
everything, everything, everything
like Saturdays, equity. Uh,
so we're not buffer where we publish, you
know, salaries and equity, but the, um,
so just for context for people who are
not in this world of tech buffer apps,
actually a, an app I use every day
are very useful for scheduling,
but a buffer app allows you to schedule
a different types of Facebook posts,
Twitter posts, etc. Uh, among many,
many other things. But they're,
they're extremely transparent,
uh, in, in with their information.
So they publish a formula essentially.
Yeah. That how they determine their,
it's like a base salary,
like salary is 50 k for support plus
a multiplier for experience plus a,
you can get equity or more salary or
things like that. So theory, the formulas,
public, um, I think some of that stuff
goes a little bit too far and it,
it had reads as many
problems as it solved.
How do you draw the line or how do
you decide where to draw the line?
It's really a judgment call.
And also thinking about what is
the logical conclusion of this.
So how does that system work?
One,
we're 10,000 employees
or 100,000 employees. Uh,
and does it just sort of
kick the can down the road?
So the thing I think about
the buffer system isn't,
it's not bad that their salaries are
public. In fact, government jobs,
salaries are public and many companies
have sort of stated titles and levels
that have certain ranges,
but then it just kind of,
it kind of kicks the can down the road.
That why is this guy again in spirits
multiplier of 1.3 and mine 1.1 you still
have the kicking the can
down the road, man. Uh, it's,
if it purports to solve the idea
of compensation to inequity,
right? Um, there's still
a subjective measures that have a big
impact on what the formula at the output
of the formula. That
doesn't really help. Um,
so is it what I think of is,
is this going to make the company either
solve a problem that we can't solve
otherwise or is it going to make
it better overall? And so, uh,
so all of our communication being
public does, and it's all searchable.
It's all indexed. It's all tagged. Um,
I could look you up in our system and
see every meeting anyone's ever had. Wow.
This guy really doesn't know how to use
computers. Yeah. The going back now,
you know, almost 10 years,
we turned 10 this year.
So that's pretty powerful to have that
sort of record of everything and it's all
searchable and indexed.
So that I think makes sense.
And we're very trusting internally.
Like if we're working on an acquisition,
for example, in my status
updates, I do weekly,
I'll put that I worked on this
acquisition in theory that could leak,
it could whatever.
But I find that when you trust people,
they tend to do the right thing versus
if we try to like really lock everything
down, I feel like that would
engender a two way loyalty. Uh,
so p two a slack I really
loved. Can, you know,
slack has come up a lot recently for
me, including for very small teams. Uh,
can you explain slack it? Sure. As
I pour water all over this table.
That's all right. That's right. It's,
it's, it's would supposedly, you know,
I would assume the tree is exposed
to water. That's going to be okay.
So at some point, so slack is kind of,
for us, it's a replacement for IRC.
So imagine a,
it's a real time chat platform
that actually has a lot
of the benefits of p two.
You can embed media in it and things,
but it just makes sense for, for I am,
so we used Skype before,
but again it didn't really scale for us.
So if you're the hundred and fourth 101st
person to join Automattic and we use
Skype for all of our messaging each other,
you have to add a hundred people to your
contact list and be accepted by each
one of them.
Um,
rooms have limits for how many people
they can have and just all these arbitrary
things. It's not suited. And slack,
you can DM anyone in the company. Uh,
everything's, they also have a really
great search. There is public channels.
Anyone can join this
private groups and it just,
it's done by some of the
folks behind flicker,
Stuart Butterfield calendars
and it's just really well done.
Like it's pleasant to use.
Loved the name. So it's a, yeah,
it's a positive association just in
the name. It's an enterprise tool,
although you can use it for, I have,
I'm on like four or five teams down,
including some that are just
groups of friends. Uh, but it's,
it's really pleasant to use like it's
consumer grade and I'm in consumer grade
as a compliment.
You mean the Ui?
Like the user experience is
consumer friendly and user friendly.
It could compete with a Facebook or a
Twitter for its usability versus where
most enterprise software just,
and I was looked by as designed by
someone who was very unhappy. And
why not use p two for
the IRC? Like chat. Oh,
um, it's not chat. Okay.
So p two is threaded.
It is real time, but you wouldn't use
it like a chat client. Got It. Um,
where slack is a chronological,
so there's no threading and
yeah, it's instantaneous. It
comes to your phone. It's,
it's more like I am application.
Got It.
And would you use [inaudible] for project
management type stuff as well? We do,
yeah. Okay. We have bug trackers.
Different teams use different things.
I mean as fabricators, some use
get hub, some use track, uh,
we allow teams a lot of autonomy in
choosing the tools there. But, um,
all the communication really happens on
Pto. So think PTO replacement for email,
a slack or replacement
for Skype, Skype. I am,
and that's really between those two.
You can take over the world. I love it.
And, uh, for those people
who are not aware of, uh,
who are not part of the tech
world, no, no, that was a,
that was a coaster that was
a very metallic Scandinavian
coaster that was stuck
to the bottom of the glass. It's, that's
the downside of these coasters. Uh,
we're sitting at my place,
chilling.
We were going to do Tequila sipping a,
I don't want to incriminate Matt,
but I have to get on the
road a little bit later.
So I don't want to have a,
I don't wanna be swimming in
the Casa that are going to us,
which is my favorite spectacular. But
it's my favorite too. It's so good.
It is good. And just to digress because
this is worth digressing on. Uh,
I was introduced to
customs that are going to,
is the first time because I ended up
doing some military training with uh,
some, some active guys, uh,
and some deployed guys when they were
back for a brief period and they would,
uh, they would do a full day of shooting
exercises and then they would dismantle
their guns and clean their guns while
slowly sipping. Casa did I go in,
it's like the most manly session ever
and had no ammo around, very safe.
And I never liked Tequila.
I'd always disliked to kill him and he'd
given me a horrible hangover and a Casa
dog [inaudible] is not intended to be
mixed with anything and it's just amazing.
I think Tequila is the most underrated
alcohol actually. And it's very expensive.
So for people who it's something,
it's for special occasions for sure.
People have a bad impression of Tequila
because they drink a bunch of stuff and
then at end at night
they do it Tequila shot.
So they've mixed like 20
different alcohols or they
drink things like Margaritas
that are full of sugar that are like
incident hangovers from me. But just like,
uh, yeah, I love Casa turn on us.
I was introduced to it by a friend in
New York named Shanti and she was like,
you have to check this out.
I was like, oh, come on.
Why am I going to pay it as much? I was
like, wow, this to is delicious. Yeah,
it's amazing actually if you drink,
I believe that.
So if you stick to just Tequila
and it's a good Tequila,
like I don Julio 1942 is also pretty good.
If stick to good Tequila all night long.
Obviously with limits, you don't, you're
not hung over in the morning. No, I agree.
So if you're looking for
a hangover cure guys, uh,
you could test responsibly a
civic tequila personal tools.
I'd love to talk about some tools
that you have, say on your laptop.
So one of them that you introduced
me to that I love is momentum. Yeah.
Could you explain momentum?
So momentum is an extension for
chrome that when you launch a new tab,
it shows you a beautiful picture. Uh,
it says, you know, Hi Matt. Hi Tim.
You put in your name, you, I guess you
could have been, could put in my name,
but I have to be creepy
and it asks you a question,
what is your focus for today?
It has a light to do thing I don't use,
but really for me it's,
it shows the time and she's this beautiful
picture and often like a nice little
quote at the bottom, whether in the
corner, just, it's kind of a clean,
fun thing that when you launch a tab,
because by default and chrome,
I feel like before it was like your
most recently or most frequently visited
sites,
which is distractions essential for me.
So I'd be launching a new tab and be like,
oh, let me click this tech meme. Like,
oh. And then 20 minutes later you're
like, what am I doing? Not only that,
but if you open a new tab, uh, I find
it useful. Personally. It's, I'm,
the photos are just amazing.
They're so gorgeous.
It bugs me that the quotes have
no attribution at a new feature.
If you hover over the quote,
it will tell you who it's from.
I feel like that should just be displayed.
They removed it a little while ago.
I don't know why, but now if you hover
over the quoted, I'll tell you it's fine.
But the photos are absolutely stunning,
which catches your attention.
And the reason that's
important is when you,
each day it'll prompt you to type an
answer for what is your focus for today.
And then it will display that every
time you open a new tab. And for me,
if I open a tab to do
something unimportant, trivial,
or just that is a pure distraction,
I'll be like, oh, oh yeah,
I should really get back to that.
The road,
the heck is paid with lots of
new tap tone down language.
This is a family program, man.
Uh, so what other, what other, uh,
tweaks or tools do you have on
your laptop you find helpful?
Ah, definitely, uh, among
constantly simple notes.
So that's actually a company. I
liked it so much. We acquired it.
The company automatic bought a few years
ago and it's a very simple notes app
that synchronizes instantly
basically across web, Ios,
android, desktop. There's a
great desktop client for Mac,
so I pretty much live
in that new additions.
I started using Wunderlist.
Wunderlist,
I've heard a lot of good
things about funder list.
It's like w analyst Chad Feller works
there now. Oh cool. I'm good guy.
Really liked it. So I just started
doing that this year actually. Um,
is on my computer, Spotify,
you know, standard stuff.
What, uh, what are some of your
other most used apps on your,
your smartphone? Hmm, well, obviously
wordpress. Yeah, of course. Okay.
I'll get the plugs out of the way in the
beginning. So let's say wordpress note.
Got It. Chan from messaging,
I've actually become really in the
telegram, telegram. So telegram.org,
it is a free fast and uh,
encrypted,
optional, really good encryption by
the way, a messaging app that's isn't,
Facebook isn't,
whatsapp isn't anything else and it's
super good and they have a desktop client
as well. I like what's that? But like I'm
on my computer the majority of the day,
so I need to be able
to message from there.
And I message only works with iPhone,
other ios devices. So it's pretty nice.
So telegram you can use on your phone and
on your laptop. Yeah. Which I love. My,
I is broken. I won't, I won't
pull you in for tech support,
but I'll do it after he's
telegraph. Um, slack,
uh, something. So in terms of like
making myself a better person,
the row is the seven minute workout app.
Uh,
calm.com which I'm an investor in and
kindle in a reading kindles meditation up.
Now I'm not, not, that is
not the meditation APP.
I need to do some more dual dual end
back training though. I got those.
Those terrible called is a meditation mat.
Yes.
How often do you meditate? Not
Enough. I feel like that's dodge.
Is that once a month or what's not enough?
Um,
so where I am in this New Year is I'm
trying to do it for five minutes per day.
That's perfect.
That's just where I'm starting out.
I'm actually inspired a lot by you talking
and telling me about how meditation's
becoming a big part of your life. Uh, I'd
like to work up to where it's, you know,
maybe a twice a day or media session.
Um,
but I've struggled a little bit
even when that five minutes.
So putting call on my home screen and
just kind of just saying, you know,
you can do anything for five minutes.
There's really no excuses for
not doing five minutes a day, um,
can eat tonight for fitness.
One of the things I did a while back
was I would just try to do like, oh,
it started with one. So just before
I got in the shower, do one pushup.
And no matter how late you're running,
no matter what's going on in the world,
you can't argue against doing one pushup.
Like, right, come on, there's no excuse.
So I have to find,
I just need to like get over that initial
hump yet with something that's almost
embarrassingly small as a goal
and then that can become a habit.
I think this illustrates a
really important principle,
which is rigging the game.
So you can win. People don't like
to fail. And if you set the pass,
fail mark too high for an activity.
For instance,
a lot of people make
new year's resolutions.
They decide they're going to go
to the gym four times a week.
That's too much for someone who
doesn't go to the gym at all. Yeah.
And if that's the past,
Phil,
Mark and you go three times a week
are going to feel like a failure.
Whereas if you psychologically set the
the hurdle at one time per week for
instance, and you only have to
spend 15 minutes of the gym,
then you can earn bonus credits by doing
what would've previously been viewed as
a failure. Right? Someone should
write a book on that, right?
God,
I can't do another
600 pager.
We're the four hour body has another
point that I think is very important,
which is,
uh,
the layering of behaviors
or sequencing and behaviors.
So if someone has a 100 pounds
to lose or 50 pounds to lose,
I think exercise is the
wrong place to start. Uh,
for a whole host of
reasons because of diet.
Exercise is the wrong place to start.
A diet is the right place to start
because exercise is an additive behavior.
It's something they don't currently
do that they have to make time for.
Whereas especially if they're overweight,
they're definitely eating.
So they have set aside time to eat and
they're just substituting in different
default meals, which is
very, very, very easy. Uh,
met my first a slow carb follower
who's lost 200 pounds recently.
Wow. Yeah, that's a lot. That's a lot
of pounds. That's a lot of pounds.
It was a question I wanted to ask
you if it's okay to, yeah, sure.
I've been reading a little bit more
about fasting and intermittent fasting,
so yeah,
there was like a couple of tweets worth
of advice you would give for fasting.
Yeah, definitely. All right.
I think interim if you have
incredible discipline. Uh,
I think the intermittent
fasting, uh, for instance, um,
I think his name is Martin Birkin, lean
gains. I think he does quite a bit here.
Uh,
he may or may not be a fan of my stuff.
He's not a fan of a lot of people up,
but that's fine.
I'm okay with it because
even if he doesn't like me,
I think he's a good resource
for intermittent fasting.
A lot of people who sustain
intermittent fasting.
And I'm not saying Martin,
I'm saying a lot of other people who
are figureheads in that community, uh,
consume massive amounts of two
things on the male side. Caffeine,
they consume a lot of stimulants and uh,
some of them consume
anabolics like Diana Ball,
which is an oral anabolic intergenic
steroid that inhibits appetite
significantly. Uh, so you want to,
I would encourage you to test
intermittent fasting and see how you feel.
But I personally prefer, and I'll be
writing quite a bit about this, uh,
to do a,
I did a seven day distilled water fast.
And I think the,
I think the longevity benefits known and
unknown and health benefits known and
unknown of doing that are,
are very significant.
And it happens if you don't
distill the water. Well, you know,
that is a great question.
They don't,
the doctors who supervise me did not
want me to be consuming any supplemental
minerals or electrolytes,
which was interesting because I
thought it would be the opposite.
And in some cases when
people get very weak,
they'll supplement with say bully on
broth or something like that. But uh,
they don't want you to be ingesting any
type of supplemental minerals, vitamins,
etc. And, uh, that was
a tremendous experience.
I actually want to do that at least
once a quarter and possibly do a 14 day.
I just read where like after the
third day of like a water fast,
you start producing more white blood
cells, your body starts to say, uh, yeah,
I mean that, that wouldn't surprise me
at all. I'd have to look at my labs.
Of course I did tonight.
I did your analysis every day and,
and loud you way your poop.
I did not weigh my poo because I got
to tell you there's not much poo.
When you're not eating for
seven days, uh, by, uh, you,
you have to be careful with the amount
of water you drink because if you're not
consuming any sources
of salt, uh, you can,
you can develop, you can overconsume
water just like anything else.
And there have been examples of people
who've died as a result of say radio show
competitions where they have competitions
to see who can drink the most water.
It's a terrible idea,
I think it's called is things aren't
ready or Cambodian new tree mia,
I think it is, which is a, a,
an extreme lack of sodium and other
things that that interferes with your
ability to conduct electricity
and muscles like the heart. Uh,
but the intimate fasting for the,
it works for a lot of people very well.
But the vast majority of people I have
seen who use it end up using crutches of
some type like stimulants.
So you trade one problem for
another and in fact you can,
you can also end up losing fat,
not because of the intermittent fasting,
but because you're consuming
six cups of coffee a day. Uh,
so I just don't drink coffee. What's
that? I still don't drink coffee. Why not?
You know, I think I have enough
vices in my life. Are you an,
are you an investor in a coffee company?
Blue bottle coffee.
So I don't drink coffee,
but when I do blue bottle is the,
uh, no. Okay. You don't have to
answer this, but I'm curious.
What are some of your other,
uh,
suitable for Mr. Rogers vices? What
are some of the other advices? Wine,
women and song, right. It's all goes back
to the classics. Those are places again.
Um,
no,
I feel like probably the thing I struggle
with the most is because my work and
what I do is connected.
Now I'm talking to people online.
I'm on my computer and especially
since taking over as CEO the past year,
what I really had to do is
unscheduled more on my life. Right.
Create more space. Right. Um,
read a lot more than I used to because
I find that when I don't have that space
where I'm just in the, I'm not going to
call it flow. When a men sort of like the,
the hedonistic treadmill of pings
and chats and tweets and not even,
not even necessarily being distracted
by like Facebook or Twitter,
but like even just work stuff,
right?
You don't take that step back that allows
you to have the creative inspiration
or the ideas for the
next big thing or the uh,
your mind works to the problem in a
different way. Right. The deloading phase,
there's blocks of time.
What have you found helpful
for creating that space?
Oh, another interesting thing about
automatic is we have almost no meetings.
Let's talk about it.
And so I only have three standing
meetings at automatic standing,
meaning physically
Staley. Oh No. Standing.
Like it's always standing on a calendar.
I see.
So every other week.
What makes those meetings worth doing?
Um,
so there are meetings with
groups of people who are
responsible for three areas.
That automatic, one for
all of wordpress.com and
everything related there.
One for jet pack and
all the plugins we make.
And then one we just called business,
they're called a.com.
Dot org.biz. So the commission, the
organization and the Bids Group,
um,
and businesses,
basically all the people who work on
making money at automatic. Right. Got It.
It's all the VIP guys on
that team adds, so the, the,
the commercial side,
because to be honest,
the vast majority of [inaudible]
don't think about revenue at all.
Yeah. There's just a few of us at
shoulder. The burden for everyone else.
It's really a good thing. I mean, what,
what do the other people
primarily focus on? Um,
I don't know. Comics, Tequila,
what they're having for lunch. I
mean, you think about the user,
you think about the experience,
you think about what is the thing,
the hardest thing is spending the most
time on the most important things just in
life in general. Definitely. And
especially when building products,
like it's so easy.
There's a term in open source called
bike shedding and it's this idea,
do you know what I do? But I want
you to explain it. This is concept,
I'm going to butcher the story,
but you know,
someone brings a proposal for a nuclear
plant and a to a city council and it's,
you know, this 200 page thing and they
kind of flipped through it and um,
but it's like too much for people to
comprehend and then not nuclear physicist
or activist anyway,
so they're just kind of rubber stamp it.
And then the next person up wants to
build a bike shed off the main road and
everyone has an opinion like what
color the bike shed should be.
Should it accommodate
tandem bicycles should,
which color should it be?
And so there's an amazing website called
bike shed.org and a cool feature of it
is that you can type in
as a sub domain a color.
So we type green.bike shed.org
it'll give you a green background.
And then the text of this
original mailing list posts,
which is like a BSD thing from like
probably 13 or 14 years ago now. Um,
that tells a story and talks about how
usually proportionately the more trivial
something is,
the more likely it is that lots of people
have opinions and feel like they can
have an impact on it.
That's so true.
And I want to talk about also
you're auditioning process,
but first we're going to hear a few words
from the find sponsors who make this
show free for all of you.
So please don't skip ahead.
Things we have coming up with Matt,
we're just getting started.
We're going to talk about
his auditioning process,
what he has in his carry on bag.
This man travels the world all the time.
We're going to talk about
investing Warren buffet music,
his rituals around productivity as it
relates to music and on and on and on.
So please don't go away and here you go.
Our fine sponsors,
the Tim Ferriss show is
brought to you by on it.
I have used on IT products for years.
If you look in my kitchen in my garage,
you will find Alpha brain chewable
Melatonin for resetting my clock when I'm
traveling. Kettle bells, battle
ropes, maces steel gloves.
It sounds like a torture
chamber and it kind of is.
It's a torture chamber for
self improvement and you
can see all of my favorite
gear at [inaudible] dot com
forward slash Tim. That's o,
n n I t.com forward slash Tim and
you can also get a discount on any
supplements, food products. I like
hemp force, I like Alpha brain.
Check it all out on
it.com forward slash Tim,
the Tim Ferriss show is also
brought to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is your one stop shop for
anything. Graphic design related.
You need a logo, you need a website, you
need a business card or anything else.
You get an original design from designers
around the world who submit drafts for
you to review.
You are happy or you get your money back.
And I have used 99 designs for book
cover ideas for the four hour body,
which went to Number One New
York Times for banner ads.
And you can check out some of my actual
competitions@ninetyninedesigns.com.
Forward Slash Tim,
you can also get a free $99 upgrade
if you want to give it a shot.
And now back to our show,
we've taken a potty break,
which gave us a chance to upgrade our
beverage since I've canceled my driving
plans this evening from t to Tequila.
So bear with me one moment,
uh,
actually met,
perhaps you could elucidate enlightened
us about some of your favorite music at
the moment while I, while I very geisha
like pour us some lovely Tequila.
I will be monitoring your
technique. Um, yeah, I,
I'm so late to the game
by just discovered, uh,
about say Tila Tequila because
I did not just as governor,
I discovered Sam Smith the
opposite of Tila Tequila, um,
who just, his voice is super haunting.
Um, but enjoying milky chance.
Lately they have a cool song
called stolen Tila Tequila.
Now they have a cool song called a
stolen dance. What type of music is that?
What would you call that?
That's interesting. So they
have kind of a reggae feel,
but it's like a guy with a guitar and
sings combined with a guy who kind of
plays the laptop, like more of like
a beat, almost like a DJ. Very cool.
And I saw them live in San Francisco.
Great show. And I'm that same I,
I listened to a lot of hip hop and a lot
of jazz. And you play instruments also?
Yeah, primarily saxophone. When did
you learn to play the saxophone? Well,
I started in second or third grade.
Really? Yeah. So I started pretty young.
My Dad Played Sax so I
always want to do it.
And I had gotten kicked out of
piano for doing what? I don't know.
They said I had no musical talent,
so on to prove them wrong.
What is wrong with some teachers?
Believable. Cheers by the way. Cheers
Andy.
Uh,
so the saxophone was your
transition from piano and, uh,
is there anything,
are there any skills that you
developed through the, uh,
through the sacs that have had,
that have translated to coding
or anything else? You do?
Almost everything. Um,
so from how to breathe and be on stage
in front of people for speaking gigs and
whatnot or just anything, you know,
you're in front of a group of people, um,
how to interact. So in jazz is all about
listening and responding. You know,
you're kind of co composing on the fly
when you're improvising or in a quartet
or something.
I had to learn new things.
So sometimes for different,
if I played in like I'm musical
theater band or something like that,
like I need to double on Piccolo or
flute or clarinet or another instrument.
So I'd have to learn that
fairly quickly. Um, and just,
I would say most importantly,
the concept of deliberate practice,
which I know you're a big fan of,
just absolutely.
I remember I had a teacher once who told
me like if you only practice the things
ray sound good, you're never
going to get better. You recap,
you reach kind of a local
maximum and that was a trap.
I actually had fallen Eczema.
I need to learn what this
is just a a constrained,
constrained maximum.
Yeah.
You reached the best that you're going
to get within this sort of limited sphere
of limited sphere.
You're not moving on to the next fear
and especially back when I was young,
I think I was more self conscious and
so when I practice and it'd be at school
or at home,
I'd want to sound good for whoever
might walk by or hear me or anything and
that's not how you get better.
You just kind of get really good at
the 10 things that you're practicing.
But the people who practice
the best sound terrible.
I think they're squawking and squeaking
and doing long tones and overtones.
They sound like they're,
it's funny,
one of the most best things you can
do to sound better on saxophone is,
was what's called long tones,
which just playing a single note for a
really long time and then go into the
next note and playing that for a really
long time. Why does that make you better?
Um, is it an endurance thing? It helps
your ambition and your tone. Your what?
Ombre. Sure. What does that,
so the ombre shirt is basically the
position and firmness of your mouth around
the mouthpiece and
basically that it's the,
it's basically the seal around the
maltreatment jokes or think of like a,
a brass instrument when,
you know,
they have this sort of circular mouthpiece
and they do like that sort of thing
inside of it. Um, they use an
Omniture to change the pitch.
So you, the position of the math,
it's also the position of your throat,
the way the air is flowing, the position
of your tongue inside your mouth,
that determines where the air goes.
It's different for different instruments,
but ultimately that, and the breast
support is what determines your tone. Hmm.
And
Yeah.
You, uh, listen to a lot of music.
You're an avid consumer of music.
Do you still listen when you work to one
track or a handful of tracks on repeat?
I do. Tell it to explain
this. Explain what, uh,
the last thing that you, that you listened
to in this way and why you do that. Um,
literally today, this Sam Smith
Song, uh, I'm not the only one, uh,
which is actually just blogged about it.
Check it. Oh, I can plug my blog man. Dot.
T t does a great domain
name. Thank you. Yeah. Um,
where's t t Trinidad and Tobago.
Trinidad and Tobago actually just
renewed it for another three years,
the wildly three years. I'm curious
out. It's a really weird, you know,
it was unregistered when I got it. So
just luck of the draw. Yeah. I literally,
well, it wasn't luck of the jar,
just no one went through the,
the jump you had to go through to
register it as it's a pain in the ass and
trying to wire money to Trinidad.
And I was in my,
I was in like the Bank of America
on third and Brandon or something,
fourth and Brandon and they're like, sir,
are you sure about this? I'm like, yeah,
yeah, it's fine. I read on the Internet,
it's fine. The internet said it's,
it's okay. Someone contacted me, I'm going
to send them a couple of grand and I,
yeah,
they were very concerned about the money
I was wearing to this Trinidadian Bank.
But um, yeah, the,
I find that on your blog you put a video
of just a youtube music video for the
song, but the, um,
that's just because youtube is the
easiest way to share music now. Sure. The,
the Nice thing about a song on
repeat is that I can really enjoy it,
but something about it allows my
brain to background it as well. Um,
I have a couple of albums that I
can do the entire album on repeat,
but what I can't do is
something new or novel.
So like a Pandora or Spotify or radio
distracts me because I'm like, oh,
what's this?
And then I'll start next day.
I know I'm like on the artist's page
and on their Wikipedia and like really
digging into it. So I really want
something I've heard sometimes,
literally a thousand times before.
What are some of the other songs that
you've heard a thousand times? Um,
I really like, uh, John Mayer's
who says who says I can't,
kids don't, which is kind
of funny cause I don't, uh,
what is another one? Um, some
Connie songs like gorgeous, um,
power. Yeah, there's just different,
whatever it is at the moment. Um,
oh, it's Kendrick Lamar is amazing. So
Kendrick Lamar has a song rigor mortis.
It's actually kind of upbeat,
so it's a pretty intense song.
And his lyrics are fast and
furious. He's, in my opinion,
the greatest lyricist of this generation.
What was the name of it?
I don't even recognize the
name. I'm Lamar. Kendrick
Lamar. Oh Man. Yeah. He um,
ever when someone told me that a year
ago who Taylor swift was, I'm really
out of the slipstream of
pop culture. Um, yeah,
Kendrick Lamar is definitely in my top
five favorite rappers right now. And He,
um,
yeah,
his music actually has a lot of jazz
influence on many things he does in their
song, rigor mortis samples,
a jazz track and um, it's,
all of these tracks are shorter.
So the, um, the Sam Smith is like,
I think three and a half minutes,
uh, who says is like two 56 or so,
um, rigor mortis is under three
minutes and just put them on a loop.
So I borrowed that habit.
Now remember you told me about this and
then I thought it was genius because uh,
I,
I had used different albums for different
books and for those people who haven't
heard this,
because it does help some people a lot
to write if you're writing period is best
at night and you feel very isolated,
which I did late at night,
I generally did my best synthesis,
not research, not interviewing,
but synthesis from about 10:00 PM
to 5:00 AM and would be a loan.
And it was just very
hermit like,
and I felt very isolated to be in
the quiet and darkness about myself.
So I would put in earphones, listened
to music on, repeat it very often,
something without vocals
and pendulum for instance.
And I would then watch the same
movie over and over and over again.
But it would just be my peripheral
vision because the images of human beings
would make me feel less isolated and
it was very comforting. So I had, uh,
the Bourne identity,
the first and Shaun of the dead
for the four hour work week.
You wanted the bond movies
too. Rail, I've seen hundreds,
probably thousands of times because
I would just leave it on repeat.
So I might play five, six times a
night if I'm really in a session.
And then for the four hour chef,
the funny addition was the first thing
that I clicked on Amazon prime that was
available on Amazon prime, which was
babe. So I ended up watching all the,
with the pig with the pig farmer hogget
it. And it's actually a really movie.
Yeah, it's a brilliant movie.
There's a lot hidden in that movie.
There are a lot of subtle details.
Just like Kung Fu panda is g as a
genius that I have not seen. Oh,
it's, it's fantastic. I love when
they made these movies for kids,
but they put cool stuff
in there for adults, like
Aladdin and many other movies.
Yeah. Yeah. Really fantastic.
So, all right, so that's
the, that's the music trick.
The repeat. I have a colleague who does
the movie thing and like I do. Yeah.
And I get the movie on mute
though. Oh really? Yeah.
And I listened to the music for him. He
does big Lebowski and a few others. But,
um,
the only,
the only variation I've introduced in
the past few years is that I like this
electronic Edm type group
called the Jane Doe's.
They're also friends and they do
some mixes and they have some,
I guess it's called trap music and rap.
This is where I'm getting out of
my element a little bit. But, um,
I find that if I'm doing things like
email where I need to be a little bit
higher energy and go through a lot of
things, uh, that's really good for me.
I love it. Uh, auditions.
Tell me about auditions.
What are, what are auditions,
how do they work in automatic?
Why auditions?
So one thing that's really important
when you're in a distributed company is,
I mean there's no one looking over.
Your shoulder is no manager walking by.
There's no one even who knows
whether you started work,
where if you started work
at all or what time he did.
So you really need to hire people
who are self motivated and can manage
themselves to some extent.
A Ton of autumn additions were formerly
freelancers or Ctos at other companies
or things like that because they really
need a lot of ability to self direct,
have self management,
which is a tough skill.
Like it's still something that
I work on everyday of my life.
So what we found,
we've tried every hiring,
especially when we started, you know,
I was much younger and I thought,
oh well we should do it like the other
companies do it. So we tried, you know,
how many manhole covers are there in
Manhattan and Mckinsey and Google Brain
teaser is the brain teasers or
the Google stopped doing them.
I think Microsoft is most famous for him.
So we did brain teasers,
we did coding tests,
we did a thing where you like ask a hard
technical problem and have them write
the code on the whiteboard.
We did it where 20 people
would interview the person,
not literally 20,
but you know,
like la interview after interview and
then you sort of get a consensus and not
had a great correlation
with how productive and
great that person wasn't the
company later. Um, and I also
started seeing no correlation.
I think because I dropped out of college,
I was very entranced by
people with masters or PhDs.
It turns out it has no correlation
with how effective they were in an
organization.
So it we started to do is we found,
I looked back to the first
couple of people, I said, well,
I worked with these guys before we worked
together on the open source project
and so how can we sort of set up a hiring
system that where you actually do the
work that you're going to do in the job
and that's all you're judging them by.
You don't care about anything else.
And so we try to make the interview
process as much like the actual work as
possible so we don't do voice or video.
It's all text chat because that's how we
primarily communicate also prevents you
from any subconscious bias
getting romanced by whatever
voice or presentation of
the person might have. Yeah. Um,
or maybe they have a funny
accent or something like that.
That doesn't matter in our company.
Um,
unless maybe they're a salesperson
and their ability to convince you of
something or have a charisma
is important for their job. Um,
there's really no benefit.
So these in person or even
voice or video interactions.
So we, uh, we have a pretty
good system for this. Now.
We get a ton of applications.
I'm actually over a thousand
applications behind now. Okay.
How do you filter a thousand applications?
Uh, so I book in the process now.
So where we've evolved to is I
review all the incoming applications.
I do a first pass at them and
I pass them on to a team if it,
if they seem promising or
interesting to you look for a while.
I can't tell you everything.
Okay.
When you look for or disqualify against,
I look for passion,
attention to detail, um,
drive beyond the things that they
need to do. You know, and I'm totally,
I'm totally down with quirky,
you know,
what questions do you ask to
get an indication of those
things? So at this point,
all I'm doing is looking at emails. So
literally there's no chat, no anything.
So it's purely based on the Karen
effort that they put into this email.
And we've tried forms and things they
fill out before and we've gone back to
just a free form email because I want
to see what kind of attachment that use
and want to see how their email client is.
I want to see if you can tell they've
copy and pasted things because different
texts, different font sizes, right?
So all of those are indicators and not
any one of them he's displaying textbooks.
Any one of those would not be a
Yay or nay, but the combination,
you get a pretty good sense. And then
I pass it onto a team. The team has,
for example, for engineering, they have a
system where everyone again looks at it,
they kind of rate it,
uh,
they choose a certain number of
people would make it the next stage,
which is like a very simple code test,
takes about half an hour.
Sometimes it's called a
fizzbuzz test and programming.
And just what does that mean?
It just a basic super basic
thing that anyone was,
does it stand for something
that, yeah. So you,
you move some variables around that,
our fears and buzz and your range of
different ways or you repeat them or you
sorta array or something like that.
But it got it a basic thing that anyone
can figure out and that's filters out a
surprising number of people even who
make it through these first few screens,
simple coding tests, and then
they screw that up. I don't know.
Okay. All right. Fair enough.
I had this application for this managing
editor position and I was astonished at
how people would go through
75% of the application.
This is a woof woof form. They'd get
to a question that asked, let's say,
you know how you would get
the rock to be on the podcast,
what would your process look like? And
they would say, now on second thought,
I'm not interested in this job.
And then they would go to the
bottom and still hit submit. Wow.
I was very puzzled by that.
Yeah.
There's a lot of odd behavior
and jot out a job application,
so I don't know if you know,
but I'm hiring a new executive assistant,
personal assistant, and I
referenced you're managing
editor, hiring post. Ah, I,
I blocked, quoted the section where you
say why it's terrible to work with you.
Yeah. I think it's important.
I've tried to not disguise that,
but I haven't been super explicit
about it in the past. And I,
if I just need someone who finds that
Shackleton expedition type description
appealing as opposed to off pudding, you
know, someone who wants a perfectionist,
someone who wants to see someone who wants
a person like me to edit the hell out
of their work. Yeah. And uh, so I found
it very important, but so you have
them go through a simple coding
test. I liked that, by the way.
I went to Antarctica last month in the
South Pole and so I've been reading the
Shackleton, I think it's the endurance
book. Yeah. It's such a fascinating story.
So fascinating. Yeah. The,
for those people who don't know the
classified ad read something like seeking
men for dangerous journey,
return, uncertain glory,
glory upon success. Something
on hate, low pay. Hey,
harsh conditions. I had a friend who
jokes, she should make that her a Okcupid,
right? The Tinder description. Probably
get a lot of responses. Uh, the,
the code test and then what happens?
We'll do a trial project.
So basically we don't actually,
we're not trying to get code out
of people or anything like that.
We just do something that looks like the
actual work and we're not just looking
at the code they produce, but how
they communicate, how they commit.
And that's a paid project. Yeah. So
we put everyone on just a flat rate,
$25 per hour contract. Um, and from it,
most people who apply how jobs are ready.
So it's often a nights and weekends thing,
right.
As long as the expectations are set,
that doesn't matter.
If you could only work one hour a week,
that's okay. Just let us know. Um,
some people will actually
take vacation to do it,
so they'll take time off from their job
and you know, kind of go at it full time.
Um, if you're applying for
happiness engineer position,
you'll answer tickets or
do live chats. So, um,
we try to replicate the real
position as much as possible.
And then if they make it
through all of this, um,
they get sent back to me for a final
chat and that we'll do on slack. Now.
He used to do it on Skype and I just um,
go back and forth to them usually
like three or four hours actually.
But because you're typing
so it takes a little longer.
And for that I try to
determine a cultural fit,
um, really get to know the
person because I have a,
afterwards I like,
let's say we're hiring engineer,
before I send the offer letter, I decided
what team they go on. So kinda like the,
that's the thing where you put on a hat
in Harry Potter and it decides which, oh,
I don't know.
I know you're talking about it decides
which school you're going to. Yeah.
So by yeah, right. By talking to them,
I'm partly determining like which
team will they fit best with?
Because the other 300 people in the
company I've done this with and so I know
what their strengths and weaknesses
are over their personalities are,
what time zones there.
And so really putting a lot of variables
into deciding where someone goes.
Are there any simple questions that give
you a particular amount of depth into
someone's personality? Yeah, I'm,
I'm constantly iterating the question
list and I'm happy to show it to you after
the vodcasts. But, um, every
interview is different.
I'm just almost every single one.
I try out something new or very it.
Or what is your spirit animal?
Um, what is your spirit animal?
I mean [inaudible]
you know,
it doesn't matter.
And you know,
some questions I retire and it's totally
different and it's not like a preset
script or anything.
Like sometimes things go one direction
and then just go with it. Um,
but at the end of it,
if decide to make an offer,
we talk about compensation and
then I send out the letter.
What percentage of people fall
out in that last chat with you?
Falling out in the last
chat is pretty rare.
Especially now that the
systems before it are so good.
So the hiring teams have gotten quite,
quite good at automatic.
It's tough because hiring is not
something that you get good at.
And T we've done at five or 10 times
and you've seen people work out and not
workout. So it's really just something
that you need experience. So I,
I tell people like when they go
in this new role, my, you know,
in the beginning here and make
some mistakes and that's okay,
we'll plan for that. Um, but then you
learn from that and your triangle it.
Do you have an opinion of top grading?
Do you know anything about top grading?
I find references completely useless.
So yeah,
including when you go outside,
what they give you as references and
you try to contact people. It just,
I haven't found any,
it's takes a ton of time and I haven't
found any sort of correlation with the
ultimate quality of the person.
So I heard about top grading and tried
it for a few months, wasn't worth it.
It didn't work very well.
I have an article I can,
we can go to the show notes and Harvard
Harvard Business Review where I wrote a
kind of five or 10 pages on this.
So that's the process.
I would love to include that at the,
I actually have that printed out because
of an old man and highlighted. Cool.
Which is a weird thing I do. Sometimes
I'll print something out, take notes,
highlight, and then rescan it back
into Evernote to be OCR. Cool. Yeah.
Which uh, which I like a lot cause I think
better tactically. Is that a real word?
I think so. Uh, uh,
what is the book that you have
given as a gift most often
besides the year without pants, which
you can feel free to mention? Oh yeah,
there is a book about
automatic and wordpress.com
called the hero without pants
written by a great orthoscopic. And um,
it tells a story about how it work. Uh,
I give a lot of different books as
gifts because everyone's different.
So there's one by and apologize now
because I can't pronounce anything cause I
just read,
I don't actually talk that lunch while
you were pronouncing crayons is crowns
earlier, which round, which I thought
was amazing. I was like, crowns,
what are crowns? They eat?
I was like, oh, crayons.
Maybe it's a southern thing. I don't
know. But, um, now for example,
I've given a few times a book called how
Proust can change your life by Elaine.
Did baton field guide to getting lost
by Rebecca Solnit is one I've given.
That's cool. What does that about? Uh, I
don't know if I can summarize that one.
Actually getting lost. Yeah.
Um, there's Rebecca Solnit.
Why doesn't she look? Oh, actually
she is, that's what she's written.
She writes for New York or a little bit
everything. Um, the effective executive.
That's great. Well that's Peter Drucker
read anything by Peter Drucker. So good.
His goal. So good. So I recommend
that a lot in the company, uh,
words that work by Frank Luntz. I did.
I read that on your recommendation. Oh,
did you like it? I did, yeah.
How would you describe that?
Let's say former
or Carl or has current,
yeah, he's like the, the linguistic
head of the Republican party,
right. So inheritance tax, death tax,
or controlling the labels of conversation
and understanding of what language
works well for certain purposes.
Really fascinating. So, and depending
on how, if someone likes that book,
I liked that book,
then I might point them to George Lake
off like he has a great seminal work from
the 70s called woman fire and dangerous
things or just other books about framing
and language. Um, so there's, you know,
there's a book for every purpose
and I find myself finding new ones.
So for example, last year I just
started reading fiction again.
I hadn't read fiction for about 15 years.
I did the same thing.
What did and any favorites so far y'all?
I didn't read fiction for probably 15
to 20 years and is one called the hard
boiled wonderland at the end of
the universe. Work Hubby. Yeah,
I really liked the quirky one and he
has a lot of jazz references and things.
I like the majors. I
have not read. It was a,
it was a really good one and I'm working
through a few different ones now.
Like Shanti Rom and the untethered soul.
I've just been trying to carve
out more time for reading.
The kindle is the device that even
if I don't use it for a month or two,
I'll still keep in my pack and
just because it's aspirational.
But when I can get in a good flow,
I'll read a little bit every day,
sometimes first thing in the morning. And
that's, uh, just my whole life is better.
Well, you're the one who
convinced me to get a kindle.
I don't know if you remember, we've gone,
we've got a number of trips together.
Thelma and Louise Style and attended
WordCamps in Greece and Turkey and uh,
well Vietnam was a trip for room to read,
which is a great organization.
But I remember in Greece had this
backpack full of 14 books and I was just
popping my, you know, my, my discs in
my spine lugging this damn thing around.
And you had your tiny little
kindle touch and you're like,
how's that working out for
you? It's like, it's terrible.
Although what you would
do when we were waiting,
because you would actually lift it like
a weights. That's true. That's true.
I use my backpack. Uh, I have
a, I have a hemp backpack.
That's reinforced that I can use
for exercises and swings and stuff.
I remember Kevin Rose
once when we were in,
we went to China on a trip for tea
tasting and I would wake up in the morning
and I would do exercises.
It was so hot there.
I would do exercises with
this backpack in my, you know,
tidy whities like expos,
you underwear.
Kevin took a video of me doing upright
rows in my underwear, which uh,
I had to confiscate and delete,
thankfully,
although I don't think it
would do anything bad to my
reputation because I don't
have one to protect at this point.
I think if you looked at a side by side,
you have the backpack full of book
muscles and I have the kindle muscle.
That's true. Although
to your credit, uh, you,
you did get into a physical
fitness and kettle bells and so on.
How's that a, has that, has that continued
or is that, is that paused the moment
it has continued pretty well. Look,
can you look leaner than the usual?
I shouldn't say the usual.
That's not fair. Then puffy mat,
and there's a puffy Tim too, but I
haven't seen you puffy in quite a while.
So the thing that I started
doing just most recently,
this most recent summer was running
and it's kind of randomly like I was in
Italy. It was really pretty. I thought,
now let me try going for a run.
And it killed me. Like I barely made it
like half a mile before I had a walk.
And then it just kind
of started building it.
I think my next one was
like a month later I get,
it wasn't like I was instantly
attached, but this, um,
there's a guy in the company,
he calls himself the crazy
running guy and he let him,
who's this joy Joe Boyd sting
and he actually, or boats,
boat boats then, sorry,
sorry, job. Um,
he started doing this thing where he'd
land at the airport and then run to the
word camp from the airport.
So 20,
30 for our grand meetup in Utah,
he ran from Salt Lake City to park city.
It was I think 50 or 60 miles.
That's insane. And so, uh,
at our grand meetup this year,
which was in park city,
he ran little running
workshops every morning.
And so I went out with him and he
was like, Hey, don't focus on speed.
Tried to do 180 strides per minute.
So smaller steps,
even if you're on slower
focus on your heart rate,
like all these sort of different things.
And it completely transformed me where
before I had my legs would always be
really sore, like my whole body would her
and after I ran, even though I loved it,
like I was just in too much pain,
I just slowed down and then start
being able to go much further.
There's really interesting
guy named Doctor Romanov.
I don't know if you've ever
come across the stage. He,
he founded a method of running called
the pose method and talks a lot about the
forward lean and using gravity to
assist your money is your money.
You could use gravity.
If I could figure that out then I Mesic
gravity do assist you're running as
opposed to heel striking and pushing.
And,
uh, there are some really
fascinating videos of him
running on ice, for instance,
by using that forward lean. Very,
very cool stuff. So you might enjoy,
I started with the vibrams.
Yeah,
I switched to just some super
thin trail running shoes,
but I still run more on the
front or middle of my foot. Yeah,
you have to be careful with the
minimalist shoes. You can really,
if you get too aggressive in the
beginning, particularly since the,
it's not just the impact on the soft
tissues of the foot and the connective
tissues. Most people who
have walked with an elevated,
he'll even an inch for
a long period of time,
have a chronically
shortened Achilles tendon.
So suddenly when you stand flat footed
and you're leaning forward on top of that
to run, you can cause Achilles
tendon tendinitis or tendinosis,
which is really painful. Really bad. Yeah,
I've done that before. And it's true.
Like for awhile, my right Achilles
was kind of sore, but I had a friend,
we were training up for a half marathon
together and he ended up really injuring
his feet,
which is tough because he's a fireman.
So is that my best friend in
Houston, Renee? So the, um,
he ended up,
you gotta be careful with this.
So I know you're not a huge fan of running
and that's high impact and it's a, it's
not that I'm, it's not that I'm not a fan,
it's that,
uh,
I choose my exercise based on my
objectives and thus far I have not found
running to stack up favorably compared
to other things. I could say that. Yeah.
And I think that it running is much
easier to justify as a moving meditation.
Uh,
and certainly it's fantastic for travel,
but that's why I have my bag that
I can use as a weight. Also. Uh,
I would like to get better at running,
do the Lyme disease and
everything that I've dealt with.
I have partial tears in both acs,
both elbows and both hips.
So I'm going to have to work up to any
type of impact. So I'll start with,
I'll start with,
uh,
some of the calisthenics I'm doing now
and then graduate to a low impact jumping
rope oh yeah. To, to really condition
the lower legs in particular.
And then, um, I'm doing long walks, also
his way wave of, of conditioning the feet.
So I'll do two to three hour walks
very routinely and make phone calls,
batch my phone calls my I love when
I'm in a new city and I can do a run.
It's a great way to see a city.
Oh definitely.
Because you're at just the right speed.
I did one in Washington DC we could
tear ago and he's just so cool.
I felt like I was on an episode of House,
a car.
It's like I'm going back to Washington
monuments and like the Lincoln memorial
and like running around the mall.
It was so cool.
That's what Bruce Lee used to do.
You just traveled with his running shoes
and when he first landed he would go
for an orientation run.
Nice.
So one of the first things I do in lieu
of the jog or running is a bike tours.
So I'll do sort of cruiser bike tours
in any new city that I want to get
acquainted with.
Uh,
I would love to ask a couple of
questions that came in through Twitter
specifically. Uh, I am at t
Ferriss. Two R's, two s's.
You are at photo p h o
t o m. A t. T also upon,
yeah. Remember you used, Oh,
I never noticed that. Wow.
You just realize that.
I just noticed that you are,
I forgot you're the pun master.
And in Japanese they call
those. Oh yeah. IGETC Yoga,
which is dad jokes Yad gags.
And you do puns all the time.
You have as long as I've known you. Okay.
I should have known. All right. Photo Mat.
That makes perfect sense. So
we've covered some of these, uh,
Joe Pella Koski acts, asked about how
you, uh, acquired developers. We are,
we already talked about that.
Uh, this is from Andy Von A.
Would you still bootstrap versus
taking angel money, seed money,
a software tool like wordpress if
you were starting over in 2015,
why or why not?
That's an interesting question.
I'm not sure if he thinks we're totally
bootstrapped or that we've raised money.
So the, I'll say what we did
and what I would do again. Um,
we bootstrapped
for the first few months and then
I raised about a million dollars.
This was automatic. This is automatic.
Yeah. Wordpress is a whole separate nd.
Um,
so for automatically raises about a
million dollars in 2006 and that was in
hindsight,
we didn't need it,
but I'm glad we did it because I felt
responsible for these other lives.
You know,
the other people who were sort of betting
on joining this company that was run
by like a 20 year old. And um,
so I want to have some certain,
I want to have some money in the bank
that said even if things went to zero,
we all have a job for at least a year.
So that's why we raised that first money
2008 we had an acquisition offer for
north of $200 million, even though we
were just, I think 18 people at the time.
And so use that to turn into a round and
did about 12 million a primary capital
there. And then we didn't raise
money again until last year, 2014.
So I was pretty anti raising money.
As you can imagine for the six years that
we didn't do it. How much should you,
is it public health she raised last
year or is 160 million? That's a,
that's a big number. It is the valuation
public. Uh, it was over $1 billion. Yeah.
It's also big number, even
bigger number. Uh, if you were,
if you were starting over
again developing wordpress,
would you make a for profit entity
like wordpress.com or automatic sooner?
Um, so it wasn't a matter
of nonprofit and for profit,
it was just a matter of
not even thinking about it.
Loose amalgamation of random
people working together
and then a for profit that
came later. Nonprofits, I'm not as
much of a fan of his, I used to be,
wordpress does have a
wordpress foundation.
Just the rules around them are mostly
designed to prevent people from cheating
on their taxes, which we don't care about.
And they restrict what you can meet.
Yes. Meaning we paid taxes
to the cows go home. Right?
So those rules to prevent abuse end up
constricting the good and organization.
Can do a lot of ways.
So I don't think I would start another
nonprofit in terms of raising money when
things,
it became very clear to me once I became
CEO is the opportunity costs of being
as lean and sort of break managing
the company to break even as we were,
we can do big acquisitions.
We couldn't invest in infrastructure,
we couldn't do a lot of things that make
a lot of sense. Now. Like for example,
since we raise money, we're building
at a 11 data centers worldwide.
So for worldwide he's is a wordpress.
It's going to start getting a lot
faster because we'll be closer to you
physically.
Um,
I was [inaudible] that we would have
considered before and we're doing now, so.
Got It. I would, you know,
if you can set expectations correctly
with investors and raise money on terms
that allow you to stay true to your
principles and remain in control of the
things that you want to be in control
of. I think it can be, you know,
I would highly recommend it.
Um,
but there's shared expectations
are really important.
So I think that would be an expectation
that's important to you. Um,
an expectation that we're
not going to IPO this year,
next year or the year after that. Like
it's not a priority of ours. Got It.
Just time, just agreeing on the timeline
and example for us would be, um,
that we don't monetize
step back. So, you know,
can you explain for people
what jetpack is? Oh, sure.
So jet pack is a plugin for wordpress,
so it gives you all the
best of the cloud services,
a wordpress.com things that like resize
and optimize your images for whatever
client is visiting, whether
on mobile or desktop, um,
things that auto posts your
blog post to Twitter, Facebook,
Pinterest path everywhere.
Um, stats, you know,
this is all the things built into jetpack.
Um,
that for us is really about
getting more users of wordpress.
It's not about charging
for some of those features.
And now jetpack has huge amounts of usage.
It reaches a very influential audience
and investor looking at the company might
say, Ah, if he's Charles like a little
bit of money for this jet pack thing,
you'd make hundreds of
millions of dollars,
but we need to be on the same page that
that's not something that we're planning
on. And so let's do it. You
have the optional, the same.
It's always good to have an option,
but for me,
the thing that's been messaged as being
super transparent and super upfront,
and I think it's true of
relationships of anything.
Like if you can set your
expectations with your investors,
that's what they appreciate and um,
it, you invest in a lot of things.
I invested a lot of things at automatic.
Yeah.
I haven't Jummah which I'm honored to be.
It's been really fantastically fun so far.
There's an asymmetry to what you do
because you will hear maybe hundreds of
pitches for every company
that you have invested in.
So I find the smartest guys in the world,
when you get to the very top echelon,
they have perfect bs detectors.
Yeah. It's much better to say,
I don't know.
Then they try to make up an answer
to something you don't actually know.
So we'll just kind of refreshing actually
that just honesty and transparency is
actually, even when you're raising at
north of $1 billion is the best policy.
Yeah.
Such a fascinating landscape.
This is a question from Chris Saka ask
Matt if he will take you shopping for a
bad ass suit. I guess I
should say a bad butts. Who?
It's funny cause I actually say bad ass.
I just didn't because you
did this whole setup so
I was trying to set expectations
if you,
I mean you have some pretty good suits.
I've seen. I do, I have some suits but um,
I like suits because it removes all the
decision making. I don't like matching.
I don't like picking out outfits that
will match, which is why I like suits.
It's either tee shirt and jeans or
suit.
I do very little in between.
If you're going to go for a
suit, Tom Ford, Tom Ford,
the way to go. They're pretty
amazing. Any particular soup now? No.
Go into the store. They'll set you up
and your body types different to mine.
They'll, they'll find something that
makes you look great, but they, they,
they're cut as much younger
and much slimmer, a much, um,
more shaped in a way.
I love Catone or Loro Piana
or like different folks,
but they tend to be made for older men
to be honest. So I lived their materials,
but I ended up tailoring
them and re cutting them.
How did you get into clothing and fashion?
Because it wasn't always this way?
Um,
I have no idea.
It might've been the influence of my
good friend Ome on MOLEC and know he,
he appreciates the finer things in life
and I think that for who created giggle
and for people who don't
know, yeah, go home.
He's a journalist now VC at true
ventures. Um, and one of my best friends,
one of the first users of wordpress too.
I think that of course in anything,
like if we're talking about Tequilas,
if we're talking about class,
where if we're talking about microphones,
like there is as a spectrum and
you can go deep on any topic.
And I find it fascinating, you
know, when he meets someone,
that's one thing I always keep in mind,
like everyone is interesting if
you're ever bored in a conversation,
the problems with you and not with
the other person because 100% agreed.
That's what any good journalists
will tell you also. Yeah,
it's just all about figuring
out what someone's really into,
what they're passionate about, and then
when you find those passions, it's just,
I find it fascinating that like go deep
on chicken raising or whatever it is.
So on purchases,
what is the last hundred dollars or less
purchase that you made that had a very
positive impact on your life
are the first thing that comes
to mind is quite embarrassing.
The gimp suit. No, I'm just kidding.
I used to make so much fun of like Marin
moms who were a Lulu Lemon all day,
but since I started running and
working out more, she's out.
Lulu lemon is freaking awesome,
like really great stuff.
Now it's kind of expensive.
Like it's definitely what this,
it's like shopping at whole foods where
you walk out in the check and I'm like
Whoa, how did that happen? About like two
tee shirts and some sweatpants. But um,
super high quality. I love how the
tax tear out so there's no tags allow.
The shorts are reversible and I found
especially as a travel constantly some of
these sort of long sleeve material
shorts will be super sharp, super soft,
super warm. I can run them, I can
sleep in them, I can do whatever the,
speaking of packing,
I will link to this in the show notes,
but you recently put up a post about what
you have in your carry on bag and that
is a genius carry on bag.
I shouldn't say that.
Maybe since I haven't seen the article
yet, but based on previous experience,
you're very methodical.
What's the one thing people can do one
or two things with carry on luggage that
will make the biggest
difference in your opinion?
It's supposed to about my backpack.
So it's about the things that, I mean,
I brought my backpack here, I carry
my backpack almost constantly. Um,
especially being what type of backpack
is up ads that is a very Indiana Jones.
I thank you.
It's,
it's from a company called hard graft
and linked to it in the most, um,
it's leather. They, it's, it's a
little pricey but it's really good.
I'll keep that for the next decade.
Um,
so because I can work from anywhere,
I have to work from everywhere.
That's the downside.
Yes.
And you never know when an emergency
he's going to pop up or anything.
So I tend to have within sort
of a 10 to 15 minute radius,
um, the tools I need to be
productive anyplace in the world,
including if I'm an Antarctica,
that might be a satellite phone.
If I'm in a different country,
maybe that's a local Myfi card or,
um, and so I'm just constantly bringing
things in and out. I was hesitant to,
to do a post about it. You asked me to
do a post about this years ago. I did.
And I kept putting it off
because it kept changing.
So every time I'd start I'd like to take
a picture of my bag and then it would
change. By the time I wanted to email.
You still use, I think it's cold.
Oh, this is, I have one right
here. This is since I am packing.
Uh, well this is gritted technology
by cocoon. You still use this? Oh Wow.
Yeah.
I use a big grid it,
but this is a company called cocoon
for you people who can't see with
clairvoyance. What we're
looking at. It is a,
it's basically a sheet. Mine is
about five inches by 10 inches. Uh,
mine's eight by 10 I think.
Yeah,
your zip by 10 and it's a perpendicular
straps of elastic that you can stick
cables into iPhones,
into batteries,
into chapstick into as opposed to just
having a big mess of stuff in 15 pockets.
I find my stuff always falls out.
Like I just pulled it out
and it was like half empty.
So things are constantly
falling out of it.
I don't know if the way I walk or
whatever, but I always put it back in.
So the key for me, I used to lose
things all the time. In fact,
at one point I would lose
my keys so much. Um, I've,
I still have an old car so it has a
different door, key and ignition key.
So I made literally 15 copies of my Dorky
and I wrote photo mat on it and then I
gave it to all my friends.
And even like some random people I meet,
like instead of a business card,
I just give them a key to my
car with the idea of being,
you have as when I lost my keys.
So one would have the ability or
when I locked my keys in the car,
we need to teach you how to had a, had
a Jimmy your door. We need to get you,
we need to get you some, uh,
some locksmith keys. I'm not
sure if that's legal. So,
uh, with it within the
boundaries of legality in your
state or jurisdiction. Uh,
but yeah,
so I find that now I have
places where everything goes.
So my mouse for example, always goes in
the right front pocket of my backpack.
And if any time something's not that,
like I keep a bowl by my front door.
The is always going there.
You said that it was a bowl,
a bowl right by the front door.
Um,
anytime something's not in that
place and I see it, it's a bug.
So I try to put it in that place as soon
as possible because otherwise I know
I'll forget. And then you know,
I'm coming over, I have a meeting,
I spend 10 minutes looking for my wallet
because I just stuck it someplace.
It's in the fridge or something, you
know, I'm always losing something.
Actually I lost one of our
initial investment checks.
It's a check for $400,000.
That's not good to lose. It
was a investor, Phil Black,
who is actually still on the board
today and he wrote a paper check,
like the kind that you would use the
grocery store or like from normal things.
As a foreigner, as most money I've
ever seen in my life. I was like,
I was 20 years old. I was like, what
is this? I expect it to be a check,
like a publisher's clearing the you have
a table, you could surf Lego, right,
like a floating carpet from Aladdin
down to the bank. So we raised,
luckily the other investors wired
their money because, and this place,
this check and I was thinking,
oh my goodness,
like what do I do with this situation?
Like cause obviously like he could stop
the check but then he's just and trusted
me with 400,000 and I've lost it.
Like what's the most irresponsible
thing you can do? So like do I tell him,
do I not tell him? Is he going to
notice at some point and months pass,
literally months pass.
He doesn't say anything.
I don't say anything because
you didn't want to ask him.
I didn't ask him and I'm going back to
Houston for Thanksgiving and I opened the
book I'm reading and
I'd use it as a bookmark
and it kind of fill out the book on the
plane. I was like, oh, oh my goodness.
It's quite a fine. That's better than
$20 at the pants you just washed. And uh,
so first thing I did when I landed,
I went to the Bank of America also.
I expected it to be like when you
hit Jackpot on like a slot machine,
like you've deposited 400 grand
checked like bell should go off.
Like they should like give you a
gospel of champagne or something.
But total non just dishonor events at
this local branch of Bank of America.
I just was like, oh, here
we go. Like okay, goodbye.
It's the most anti climatic thing ever.
But besides here you have
people behind you. I didn't,
I told them like a year later and he was
like, oh man. Yeah, he just hadn't looked.
So speaking of big numbers, how the hell
did you end up beating 140 or whatever?
Chicken mcnuggets why did that happen?
104 hundred and four.
I don't remember how long ago. It was
probably about 10 years ago at this point.
11 years ago. But the Superbowl was
in Houston, Texas. And, um, you know,
I lived like a mile from the reliant
stadium where they were doing the super
bowl. And so I was watching
and as for the super bowl,
all the Mcdonald's did a special where
he get 20 big nuggets for like $4 and I
was super broke at the time.
And so it was like, man,
I'm just going to stock up on these at
the way you might get like cans or you
know, things or ramen or
like cans of Campbell's,
which I would do when they went on sale.
I always buy a bunch of them.
So I just like got a bunch of
mcnuggets and then I was just stuck.
I love me nuggets and I the kind
of like sweet talk the person.
So they gave me lots of extra that sweet
and sour sauce and the Mcdonald's sweet
and sour sauce is not like sweet and
sour sauce anywhere else in the world.
Like all sweet and sour sauce is red.
And for some reason there's this brown,
I don't know why you might
been genetically engineered
to be as addictive as
possible. I don't know. It's so
good. So I just start popping them.
And next thing I knew it was 104 so
it wasn't even a better or anything.
You just rampaged through
104 while watching the super
bowl. That's it. Was this,
it was the Superbowl where Janet Jackson
had the wardrobe malfunction. Yeah, the
breast explosion. Sorry, I missed
that. How was, it was a gratifying,
I was watching it with my family and
there was like this moment of silence
afterwards were like,
what just happened?
I was completely mortified and I think
I had a laptop and the Internet and Wifi
I had the time. So I was like,
I put like what just happened?
Like I'm going to go on
the Internet and see.
And it turns out like what happened
happened. Like there was a wardrobe
function and I'm a good friend of mine
was in the audience about 15 feet away
from her. And you know, there's all
the theories that it was planned.
Yeah. And she said she was so pissed
off, like looked so angry. She has,
it was not abs. Absolutely
not planned. I could've, yeah,
I would have bet that it was planned to.
This reminds me you're
shocking moment with your,
you're mortified little
bit with your parents.
When I went to the movies
with my entire family, uh,
and I was sitting next to my brother
and my parents were sitting on the other
side of my brother. We went to see
the girl with the Dragon Tattoo,
which I had read.
My brother had one credit and those of
you who've read the book or seen the
movie will know there's one particularly
just mortifying seeing a minute or two
beforehand. I was like, oh
yeah, excuse me. I have to
go get to go to the bathroom.
When I came back and my brother's like,
you fucker,
you knew exactly what was going to happen,
didn't you? And I was like, Yep. Yeah,
I did. Sorry about that. My
identical story was titanic,
which as much as much tamer,
but I just for some reason went to see
titanic with my mom and I was like, oh,
I think it's about to
happen that sees the car.
Seeing the car scene are there where
he's drawing hers. And I was like,
I'm just going to leave for
a few minutes and I cope.
It's over by the time I get back.
Uh, to switch gears a little bit,
when you think of the word successful,
who's the first person
who comes to mind and why?
Hmm.
It's funny because he's getting
totally panned in the press right now,
but I think of Jeff basis.
Why'd you phases?
Well, why didn't you getting
pin? This is how I get informed.
Ah,
the fire phone was a complete flop.
They went down hundreds of
millions of dollars of inventory.
Obviously it didn't sell well.
Um,
and articles have come out since then
saying how like he micromanage the whole
process and things like that. Um, I'm
actually gonna do a blog post about this.
One of my favorite business books is
called the halo effect and it talks about
the case study they use is Cisco and
sort of the 98 to 2002 time period.
How,
and sort of when they were on the rise
and one of the most valuable companies in
the world, high stock. And when
Saint John Chambers is genius,
they acquire companies, they don't have
to invent everything. They can, you know,
acquire dozens of companies and integrate
them and the competitors just can't
compete.
And then once they started crashing again,
nothing changed about the business.
But the stock goes down the same.
Sometimes the same writers were saying,
Oh, it's a mishmash of infighting.
They have all this like technology that
doesn't integrate and they can't invent
things so they have to acquire it.
So Lou,
the same strategy is viewed
in a totally different realm.
And this is halo effect as
a case study going on right now with
Amazon. So we're a few years ago,
everyone said how Amazon
makes these big bets.
They're willing to lose money for years
and years and something like the kindle
and just ruthlessly iterate over
and over Amazon web services,
they go into places where no one says they
should go. Um, the fire phone flopped.
And everyone's saying, Ah,
these idiots, you know, this,
the attention to detail becomes
micromanaging, you know that everything.
But ultimately what I admire in the
longterm as Jeff Bezos has convictions
around things and he's going to be wrong
sometimes I don't expect them to be
perfect,
but I do expect him in my idolize mine
to continue making those big bets and
he's probably not taking it for risk if
he doesn't super mess it up every couple
of years. Oh, I totally agree.
And just the story of basis.
I haven't read the everything store.
I would like to,
I don't know if you have
excellent book. Yeah. Uh, but uh,
sounds like a good time to buy Amazon.
This is not investment advice.
Consult your regulatory attorney
and professional wealth advisor,
but it's when those types of sort of
capricious judgements are made based on a
one off event,
especially in the,
well sometimes this macro related,
sometimes it's just a
single launch related. God,
it's so funny how quick,
how quickly people are deterred.
All though I will tell you most of the
time I don't believe the words as they're
written on the page. I think they're
just journalists with a tough job,
which sometimes I think
borders on unethical,
which is having to churn out a lot of
content and tenuously on an unreasonable
schedule and to come up with insights
that are with rare exception,
very,
very difficult to produce
on demand as Aha moments once a day
or five times a day or 12 times a day.
So they end up regurgitating or rewording
things they've written before and the
people with the most knowledge about a
given topic don't necessarily have any
incentive to write about it.
Absolutely not.
So do you buy and sell individual stocks?
I don't right now.
My personality, my intestinal fortitude
is not well suited to public stocks.
Uh,
I don't like having the option
on a daily basis to buy and sell.
Yeah. I like doing a ton of
due diligence, investing in,
for instance, a startup and
then betting on a seven to nine,
seven to nine year growth
curve or longer or longer.
Now automatics coming up on 10
yeah. And I'm not, I'm not overly,
that doesn't,
that doesn't concern me.
It actually consoles me because it forces
me to do more homework on the front
end. I agree. Um, I use wealth
front and also an investor in,
but or both an investor and Melbourne's,
I get individual stocks,
like if I like maker bought and
sold to a company called Stratasys.
So I ended up with a bunch of Stratasys
doc and it was really knowing to have
like this minute,
the minute number that moves.
Like that's the one thing I wouldn't
look forward to it being a public company
is, oh, raising money is hard as well
because basically saying something,
your life's work, this is what it's
worth, right? They're quantifying it.
I can't imagine what it's
like with the minute,
the minute vagaries of the market.
Public markets.
I'm so,
I'm so continually impressed by people
like nuts and Talib or many of the hedge
fund guys out there who are develop a
hypothesis about a particular way to
approach a short,
a short sale or short position.
So they're looking at the
subprime mortgage crisis
and they're trying to bet on
that happening or the sovereign
debt issues in Europe for instance.
And their ability to just bleed for
extended periods of time with these option
positions and function as normal human
beings and be okay with losing money
every, all losing money every day and
having people tell you you're an idiot.
Yeah. Uh, where you, I just,
I can't fathom actually handling that
well personally. So oddly enough,
the binary nature of startups suits
my psychology well because it,
it's applying a constraint and removing
decisions than I might otherwise botch
emotionally.
So I can be very highly rational on the
front end and make a specific type of
investment that precludes me from
making stupid emotional decisions.
And emotionally you want to buy high
and sell low at that? Oh, definitely.
If it's dropping, I got like I get out
of it. So if it's rising and like, oh,
it's great,
I'm going to buy some more.
Are there any particular
books on investing or books
that you've read that have
helped you think about investing?
My, he said that the man, uh,
[inaudible] you're the one who introduced
me to the Black Swan actually I was in
Greece. I don't recommend
that to everyone. So I love
the Black Swan. I love it.
Uh, fooled by randomness.
Antifragility his latest one.
I love his book of Aphorisms.
I kids writing has been super
influential on me both in,
in and of itself and also in the works
that he's pointed me towards because he
makes a ton of sometimes annoyingly
so references to other things. Yeah.
But I came introduced me to emerge a
echo and other really fantastic author.
So, um, he's great. And then, you
know, reading Warren Buffett's letters.
I was leading a Warren Buffett friend Fan.
I wish I were a big Warren Buffett
friend. I am a big Warren Buffett Fan. Uh,
and I know that name is,
is bandied about a lot by of
course millions of investors,
but the annual letters,
getting it straight from the horse's
mouth as opposed to the second or third
hand interpretations is just phenomenal.
It is something I can say.
You asked about what we look for for
candidates hiring, um, clarity of writing.
I think clarity of writing
indicates clarity of thinking.
Writing is honestly one of the hardest
things they do everyday at various.
You've written a couple
now I've tried to write
a book. I can't, I haven't been able to
do it. It's a very masochistic process.
I would not want to inflict on,
on anyone unduly.
But I love reading about writers in the
process of writing like bird by bird and
Lamont or on writing. Well,
I Williams enzyme, um,
there Ernest Hemingway and writing,
which I think I got from
this podcast actually. Yeah,
that's a funny one because when you
can rent well you can think well.
And so when I find obviously
in Warren Buffet's letters,
the thinking is so clear.
And so that's something I look for in
these sort of random emails we get our
cover letters or resumes is a well
written. If someone's a great writer,
they tend to be a great
programmer or efficient or
something else. So, um, again,
it's not everything, but it's
a strong indicator. So just
a few more questions. Uh,
the first is
from wow. Valora Thor, that
is a fantastic name, sir.
What role will wordpress spelled correctly
play in online content outside of the
browser example, given mobile apps,
Apis, et cetera. In the near future.
It's inside baseball,
but a very good question.
So there's been basically two
waves and WordPress's history. Uh,
we started to just blogging Lily's just
a blog and you'd have the rest of your
website doing something else. Then
you'd plug the blog in your wordpress,
we'd spend it to be a CMS.
It was the second wave of wordpress and
then it started powering your entire
site.
So,
and that's been really the past five or
six years where we become almost like
the dial tone of the web.
Like if you're starting a website,
he started with wordpress and then
you plug other things into wordpress,
whether that's ecommerce
management, CRM, whatever it is,
it's a plugin for wordpress.
This third wave that we're going
through right now is word press as an
application platform.
So people are using the primitives
and the things afforded by WordPress's
infrastructure,
the things that we wrote to write a
blog and CMS to write other things.
The primitives are the elements of the
infrastructure that we're used to create
those things in the first place.
Yeah.
So think of a primitive as a
basic building block. Got It.
So like a social primitive one that
Kevin Rosen invented was like this
embeddable button that lets you vote
on things, right? The dig it button,
which is now the like button,
the tweet button, et cetera. Um,
that's a primitive semis. So we have
primitives around user authentication,
around content types,
around caching, around URLs,
around lots of things that if you're
building something from scratch,
you got to do all this stuff, right?
So if you can start with wordpress,
it's saves you months. Um,
not for everything, not for
everyone. But if you know,
wordpress, it, you know, you start, um,
I'm gonna ask you [inaudible] 80 miles
per hour because I like asking silly
questions. Uh, as a, as
a nun, non programmer,
how does, uh, and I know it
differs significantly, but
how does that differ from,
say, ruby on rails, whoever be
in real estate and they similar,
it's people using wordpress
as a framework. It's a
framework which does a lot,
has a lot more things built
out than like a ruby might. Um,
so think of it as the thing
that wordpress does built.
If what you want to build looks like that.
So not a game, not a chat application,
not something like that.
If it looks like content,
we've already managed more content than
anyone else in the world at this point.
I'm using our data
structures using our APIs.
It's probably the best way to go about it.
What are some of the big companies or
publications that use your platform?
It's pretty much all of them
at this point. Washington
Post, Wall Street Journal,
New York Times, um,
international papers, uh,
new media. So Giga Ohm, tech crunch,
recode, all the tech blogs basically.
Um, years mean it's really
the technique, very flattered.
But I try it,
if you look at tech meme,
like we'll typically power 50 to 70% of
all the sites that are in tech meme on a
given day. Um, tech meme. For
those people who don't know,
would you say it's fair to say it's a
roundup of tech news from around the web?
It's one of my vices.
We talked about vices earlier.
So t e c h m e m e.com.
It's um,
it's algorithmic and human. It's the
best tech newspaper in the world like it,
and it just links you to places.
So almost like a drudge report,
but it's so much better. Um,
you go to the primary sources.
So what sometimes might be not even news,
like a tech crunch or verge,
but the actual person like you or me,
real interested,
they'll link to the originals as well,
which is really nice.
What if you had to point
a 20 year old entrepreneur
who's looking to start a company, let's
just say it's tech for the time being,
what two or three books or resources
would you give to them or suggest to them?
I'm going to repeat with the effective
executive or anything from Peter Drucker.
He actually has one, I think it's
called the art of entrepreneurship.
It's got entrepreneurship in
the title. Super good. Again,
these are old now and like from
the seventies or eighties though,
but they're so good.
He's just one of the clearest thinkers
about all these things about management,
about entrepreneurship.
When I was getting started,
I actually really loved the art
of the start by Guy Kawasaki.
Aggregate it since then. Yeah, no,
it, it stands up pretty well there,
but I'm really inspired me.
I think she read the four hour work week.
Just I'm going to plug you go and
a recent one, like a brand new one.
Um, I'll say two brand new ones. I'm
sorry you asked for three to give.
You can keep going. You can go. Um,
the hard things about hard things
by Ben Horowitz. Pretty good.
Entertaining more than anything.
Like I read that book, I was like,
I would never work for this guy but
I'm entertaining and some good lessons.
And then Peter teals zero to
101 I thought was excellent.
It's to one is great and
people should definitely,
if they find that interesting
and they are going into tech,
I think try to read the original
classmates as well. Yeah.
By Blake masters I believe. Exactly.
They're really just tremendous.
All of these guys. I mean don't take them
as Gospel, like disagree with them, uh,
interpreted in your own way.
Um,
if some people who are admire quite a
bit like saying Marc Andreessen, uh,
when we first pitched him,
the whole meeting was about
how distributed companies
were a terrible idea.
And he was like,
well,
what do you know that every other tech
company that's been big in history
doesn't the Facebooks, the googles,
the Microsofts to everything.
And so why should you do
something different? Um,
and it turns out it was a good meeting.
I thought it was terrible.
Me I thought was the worst
meeting of my like entire career.
And I thought that's his style is he
challenges you and sees how you spot.
But um, you know, sometimes
going against the orthodoxy,
doing the things that other people can't
do. I think of it like business judo.
What can we do that now Google makes
tens or hundreds of billions of dollars
more than us? What can we
do that we can't do? Well,
they're set up best to work in the office
culture and where's it at best to work
in an office culture so we can get
the smartest people in the world who
sometimes leave Google cause they want
to live in Salt Lake City or Adelaide,
Australia or someplace else for whatever
reason, it doesn't matter. But, um,
they're just as good as anyone
inside the mountain view offices,
but they just don't happen to be
in mountain view. It's like the,
it makes me think of the book, the
starfish and the spider. And, uh,
particularly with the open source
component, right. Open sources.
I'm going to the open source.
Wordpress isn't going to die. Uh,
even if even if automatic
were to cease operations. Uh,
well even to this day,
we compete with people 10 times their
size and 10 or a hundred times a
capitalization. Uh, in 2014,
one of our competitors,
Squarespace spent north of
$45 million on advertising.
They did Superbowl
advertiser, didn't they? Yeah,
they're going to do more this year.
That's expensive. But they had to. Yep.
You know, that's the only
way they can get customers.
Where because we have this
community because we have these, uh,
hundreds of thousands of developers
all over the world because we have, um,
the sort of intrinsic, I think,
goodness of the software.
We don't have to spend advertising in
2014 we spent about a million dollars on
advertising and that was mostly events.
And you do love events.
I love your events too. They're
very well done. Thank you. Uh, okay.
Two more questions.
If you were sent to desert island
and you could bring one album
fest, a lot of book questions, I'm
trying to come up with something else.
One album,
one album and two other items that were
non survival related, what would they be?
The album's really tough.
There are some really perfect albums out
there. Like I think Radiohead's okay.
Computer. It's like just a perfect
album and it works as an alum.
The individual songs don't
work as well or like, uh, uh,
frank ocean's mix tape,
alternate out. I like that.
Some of these that are just so good.
Kendrick Lamars, good kid. Matt City,
you got check checkout chick,
Kendrick Lamar.
I know you're not as in as the
hippity hop. Oh that's not true.
If it's break beats are danceable and
I like the lyrics. I'm all for it
like Eric B and Rakim and that.
Ill How old are you?
67.
I'm just giving you a hard time but
this is a new guys that are super close.
There are some good guys.
I what I don't like is the homogenates
we have a lot of the beat structure
that has been sort of commoditized for
top 40. That stuff makes me insane.
But if it's,
if it has some unique
flavor rhythms yeah. All for it.
Yeah. You like Kendrick Lamar. Um,
so probably one of those albums and if
I have to pick one, I'll pick a jasmine,
uh,
Sonny Rollins saxophone colossus.
I could listen to that album the rest
of my life and learn something new every
day. Uh, in terms of other
nonessential items that aren't books,
I'm not going to say a kindle
or an encyclopedia or something.
Know a 50 millimeter,
1.4 Prime Lens. Okay.
Is the Lens I would take to a
deserted islands and I burned easily,
so probably a umbrella.
You and I bond over that. I thought I
was the only human who didn't tell him,
but alas, Hark. Matt Mullenweg.
Uh,
last question.
If you could give your 20 year
old self a piece of advice,
one piece of advice, what would
it be? Slow down. Slow down.
Why
we talked about it with running earlier,
like slow down to go further. Um,
I think a lot of the mistakes in my
youth where mistakes have ambition,
not mistakes of sloth,
sloth and um,
I think building foundations, building
things that last for the long term.
Obviously some of that's
happened, but, um,
some of it I think I
rushed through education. I
definitely kind of squandered,
you know,
even when I was in high school,
like they put great books in front of us,
like the great Gatsby or
subsidies or something,
and they said it is I dug into,
but like others like Fitzgerald,
I just can't do the bare minimum to pass
the class or pass the test when now I
would kill for the luxury to just like
really sit down with one of his books and
dive into it and discuss it.
Um,
and so just slowing down
whether that's meditating,
whether that's taking time for yourself,
away from screens,
whether that's really focusing in on who
you're talking to or who you're with.
But as I've aged,
I know it sounds ridiculous.
Yes.
It's interesting because I had a
lot of living in dog years though.
I mean the amount of experience that you
can press into each years. Unbelievable.
Well,
I have a lot of,
I had a lot of success at a young age
was intimidating because you sometimes
think,
am I ever going to top this or did
I peak at 20 or 21 when I was doing
polyphasic sleep? And writing these
new things and everything since then,
some downhill.
Um,
you wonder about impact on the world.
But ultimately it's funny that now
what I more about is a lot narrower.
It's like the people who you love and
the people that love you and you don't
always choose either of
those, right. It's not as,
he can't help you fall in love with life
would be so much easier if you could.
That's true. And do you don't always
choose who falls in love with you and,
but there's responsibility on both.
And really focusing on those people I
found has contributed more to my happiness
and I want to say anything else. I
think that's a great place to end. Matt,
where can people learn more about you?
Find you on the Internet?
A M a. Dot. T t from my main
blog on wordpress, Twitter.
I'm at photo mat, p. H. O t o m. A. T.
T. And I'm pretty much every network.
Follow me on Spotify. I share some cool
stuff on there. Awesome. All right sir.
Thank you so much.
And uh,
we shell Polish this off with another
small glass of sipping Tequila.
Thanks everybody for listening and
thanks for going whatever, Matt. Cheers.
Thanks so much for listening everybody
to find links to Matt Spotify to the
music, to the books, to everything
that we talked about in this episode.
Just go to four hour workweek.com
forward slash podcast that's four hour
workweek all spelled out,F , O, u r h o,
u r workweek.com forward slash podcast.
And if you liked this episode,
there are others that you can find there
that I think you would enjoy including
for instance, uh, ed Catmull,
who is president of Pixar.
We had a fascinating conversation about
the power of storytelling and how they
built that company.
You could also find an episode called how
to think like Elon Musk and Jeff Bezos,
which is an interview with Peter
Diamandis, chairman of the x prize.
This one was massively, massively popular.
You can find all of that and much, much
more@fourhourworkweekdotcomforwardslashpodcastandasalwaysitrytoputbonuscontentvideosfromtheseguestsonfacebookatfacebook.com
forward slash Tim Ferris,
t I m f e R R. I s.
S. Until next time, thanks
so much for listening.
The Tim Ferriss show is
brought to you by on it.
I have used on IT products for years.
If you look in my kitchen in my garage,
you will find Alpha brain chewable
Melatonin for resetting my clock when I'm
traveling. Kettlebells, battle
ropes, maces steel clubs.
It sounds like a torture
chamber and it kind of is.
It's a torture chamber for
self improvement and you
can see all of my favorite
gear at [inaudible] dot com
forward slash Tim. That's o,
n n I t.com forward slash Tim and
you can also get a discount on any
supplements, food products. I like
hemp force, I like Alpha brain.
Check it all out on it.com forward slash.
Tim,
the Tim Ferriss show is also
brought to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is your one stop shop
for anything graphic design related.
You need a logo, you need a website, you
need a business card or anything else.
You get an original design from designers
around the world who submit drafts for
you to review.
You are happy or you get your money back.
And I have used 99 designs for book
cover ideas for the four hour body,
which went to Number One New
York Times for banner ads.
And you can check out some of my actual
competitions@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim,
you can also get a free $99 upgrade
if you want to give it a shot.
That's 99 designs.com forward slash.
Tim.