So it is cold.
It is miserable on a
Friday here in California.
And I was in San Jose and I
thought to myself, why even bother?
I should just do something
completely unproductive.
So I came up here to Berkeley to do what
any emotional eater would do and that
is consumed massive quantities of
chocolate at one of my favorite chocolate
makers in the world.
Scharffen Berger here in Berkeley.
So let's go kill my pancreas.
So here we are here with dried and Brian,
what's your job?
What's your full name? Is My name
Rankin's here. And I am a, uh,
and uh, just here you, uh, show you a
little bit about what we do here and uh,
take some chocolate. All right, so this,
this is an excuse for me
to eat massive quantities,
a chocolate and a have insulin,
pour out my eyeballs and just
have a good time in the process.
Those of you who follow me in and
the blog and know that my diet,
Saturday's my off days. So Saturday I'm
Olathe anything. I want it, it's Friday.
So I'm taking it in a bit early this week.
Uh,
but generally at night I
will have a nightcap of a
glass or two of wine and some
relaxing listening to music as well
as a couple of nibs of chocolate. Uh,
usually the higher cocoa concentrations.
But I'm going to let you take the floor
and just walk us through what we have
here. Sounds good. Well this is our,
uh, this is our current line up here.
We have a number of different
chocolates. Um, here on,
on our right here we have our extra dark,
which is an 82% kick content.
Now that that could count content,
uh,
really signifies the amount of the
percentage of this bar that comes from the
podium.
So 82% of that is,
is from the cocoa beans and 18% is,
is sugar and a small amount of
vanilla and a small amount of western.
So this is our darkest chocolate.
If you're looking at, you know,
pure Cacau Coco Punch.
Um,
then we have our 70% or 62.
All right, this is our, this is our,
and then we have our milk chocolate
and milk chocolate is 41% get cow,
which doesn't sound like a lot,
but it actually is. That's a very,
very dark milk chocolate.
Really gives a great combination of both
no flavor and also a chocolate flavor.
And then we have a new bar that we just
came out with, which is our milk Coleman,
um, with uh, with sea salt, which has,
which is our traditional milk chocolate
with almonds, dusted with sea salt,
sort of that sweet and sour
or sweet and salty flavor.
And then we have a limited edition
bar that we came up with recently,
which is a blend of several different,
very unique beans from Trinidad,
Grenada, the Dominican Republic.
And also then as well. So, you know,
this I saw earlier in the shop and I
was excited to try it because this,
this version over here,
the 70% is actually really what
I use along with the guitar.
They make some good,
uh,
but the Scharffen Berger 70% is
what I've used to make truffles.
I took classes with a
chocolate tier in Saratoga,
which is a nice small town
you might have visited before.
Also great for motorcycle riding. And so
I have a lot of experience with the 70%,
but I'm looking forward to tasting the
full spectrum or at least taking us
through a tasting of Chaga.
Cause I think most people they would
be familiar with the concept of wine
tasting. Maybe they know a few different
types of wine. Sure. Uh, perhaps even tea.
They know a few different types of tea,
but shut people of chocolate.
I think they might think
of dark and milk chocolate,
but really not much beyond that
distinction chair. Um, and just,
just for the sake of giving people
a full idea, white chocolate,
my understanding isn't even shop,
isn't it?
It's the cocoa butter and or well it is
technically chocolate according to the
FDA. Okay. Um, but it's uh,
it actually has in it is chocolate
because it contains a component of,
of cocoa beans, which is the, which
is the cocoa butter. Right. However,
it doesn't have as, as you
can tell, it's, it's white.
It doesn't have the cocoa solids,
which loosely translated,
it's really the cocoa powder.
So it doesn't have the,
a lot of the components that
are healthy food. Right. And uh,
and it's oftentimes very sweet.
Okay, cool. Well, let's, uh,
what else do we have here?
So at least I see the samples here,
but what are we looking at right here?
And then here we had, we just had,
these are some raw cocoa beans from
Madagascar and then we have this year is
some,
some nibs from Madagascar.
This is from this next one
is from a farm in Trinidad.
And then we also have a selection from
a deep in the glory and the mountains of
Venezuela.
Um,
these beans have you come
on horseback to get to us.
So wow. Or a long trip
from Venezuela to, well,
it also area and also involve the garbage,
getting them out of the mountain.
So it took a while.
So it's a very unique being in
terms of it's genetics and the nibs.
Are those just ships from the cocoa beans?
Yeah,
essentially nibs are cocoa beans that
have been roasted and then had to show
him. Okay. So you wouldn't want to show
those, you wouldn't want to chew on these.
But if you roasted them and took the
shell off and sometimes they're hard to
take off button,
we can see that there is a show
sort of like uh Oh reskin sure.
A little bit harder. Then inside of
there is actual those bids. It's a, yeah,
it's the sort of immediate,
the bean,
the caudal Eden's of the seats
per product developer. Right.
That's your technical title.
Um,
your product developers at companies
like Yahoo and other places.
But I think being a product developer
at Scharffen Berger and means something
quite different. So
what, what is your job?
What do you actually do as a product
developer? Well, it's uh, it's in general,
it's research and development.
So I work with several other people
in the company to source beans.
So we actually traveled to different
countries and by the book of these,
we work with the farmers to help them
to improve their quality of their cocoa.
And then you are able to buy it from
them, usually at a higher price, which is,
which is a great relationship because we
received higher quality beans and they
receive a higher price for them.
So it's a really mutually beneficial
relationship. Um, so that's one component.
The other component is actually making
and maintaining some of these blends here.
So Shark Hamburger,
um,
we've always taken a traditional
look at chocolate and that,
and we'd like to find a chocolate
for a number of reasons. Um,
it creates a more consistent land.
It also can create a more
complex chocolate flavor profile.
So when you say blood, do you mean the
different deans from different sources?
So it'd be like a maritime,
the right word.
Blending varietals. Okay.
Exactly. Cool. Um, our founder,
John Scharffen Berger, came
from the champagne business
where that's very common,
um,
creating and developing complex flavors,
a number of different meetings.
He's sort of our, is our forte.
And you can see here we have,
for instance, this bar here has,
has between eight and 11 different beans
in it at any given time. And you know,
sometimes a certain sort of, uh, you know,
it might be less available
and at a certain time of year,
so we'll have to insert another,
another type of view.
And therefore we're constantly changing.
And we have a flavor profile
that sort of locked in our heads.