[inaudible].
Hi, good morning. We're here
today with Timothy Ferriss,
who's the author of a new book
called the four hour workweek.
Timothy is a CEO of a multinational
company and a guest lecture at Princeton.
Timothy, how do I get a four
hour work week? Is that possible?
The four hour work week is possible,
but you need to completely
unplug and reset,
and the reason that's necessary
is because there is an epidemic,
and I do mean epidemic in this country
of information abuse and information
addiction where people have come to
believe that checking email 200 times per
day,
having a blackberry to your head or in
your hand while you're at dinner or on
the subway or in your car or with your
friends is the path to becoming more
productive and more
successful. I mean, it isn't.
It isn't because giving everyone
around you, every person in the world,
immediate access to you is inviting
interruption and inviting minutia to
completely invade your life, which is
happening to everyone and happened to you.
It did happen to me. I had no
intention of writing this book,
but from 2000 to 2004 I was working
at startups in Silicon Valley.
I started my own.
I'm was CEO and I worked from
7:00 AM to 9:00 PM every day.
I checked outlook hitting send,
receive 100 to 200 times per day like
a rat with a cocaine pellet dispenser,
slept under my cubicle, sent emails
on Thanksgiving to prospects.
It was a depressing scene and it's a very
unfortunately common scene and I think
everyone is at a point of overwhelm.
There is more information
than we can possibly organize.
Time management is dead.
Turn that, turn that around.
The way you turn around is you have
to completely unplug and reset.
That means that you need
to take a step back.
Forget about what people expect you to do.
Forget about what's popular and really
look at what works and what is consuming
your time. So there are four
steps. There's definition,
elimination, automation, and
liberation. Definition is simple.
First need to define your ideal lifestyle.
What do you want to be doing from when
you wake up to when you go to sleep?
And so what do you want to
have? What do you want to be,
what do you want to do and how much
does that ideal lifestyle cost?
And that becomes your target
elimination is simple.
It's getting rid of everything,
all the static, all the noise,
all the interruptions, all of the
micromanaging, all the people possible,
the interfere with getting
you to the ideal lifestyle.
The third automation is about taking the
few remaining tasks that are important,
the time consuming and either delegating,
automating or somehow outsourcing
them. So in my particular case,
I have an army of MBAs in India,
that 25 of them who worked for $4 an
hour and take care of tasks that would
otherwise consume hundreds of my
hours. And then the last step,
liberation is about the final ingredient
in lifestyle design, which is mobility.
And then also how to use
the time once you create it,
which is very difficult for most
people. Okay. This is fascinating,
but that's the point.
It is difficult. I mean,
how do you put the blackberry down had,
aren't you worried that you're not going
to make as much money that you're going
to lose clients? Do you have statistics
that show that that's not the case?
I have statistics that would
absolutely make your head spin.
So if you're interrupted
by email and phone,
there was an experiment done at
kings kings college for example.
It showed that people who were stoned
scored six points better on IQ tests and
people who were interrupted
by email and phone
and that good to know at 26% of people
in the American workforce are on the
verge of a nervous breakdown.
The system is not working.
So it's not a question of of if I should
do this as a question of when it is the
only real alternative.
So one simple step that people can take
a baby step to prove the concept is to
simply use an autoresponder,
set up an autoresponder that
tells everyone who emails you.
I will be checking email twice a day.
It's great idea at 11 and 4:00 PM if you
require a more urgent response before.
One of those two times, call
me on my cell phone. Okay.
If I start losing customers,
I'm going to call you, Tim.
You can call me what's going to
happen instead of losing customers,
you'll get more done in the next 48 hours
than you would in the next two weeks.
Well, I appreciate this and I, uh, I
look forward to my four hour work week.
Thank you very much. You're very welcome.