Joe, welcome to the show.
Tim. Thank you so much buddy.
Then I'm so excited to
finally have you here.
So thanks for flying out.
Of course. My pleasure.
Here we are in Tay Hos and where to begin.
I mean we've had the opportunity to get
to know each other over the last while,
which has been super fun,
fed some unique peak experiences,
which I'll leave nebulous just so
everyone's really uncomfortable with that
statement. And, and uh, where to begin?
We were talking about this,
I was having excessive
numbers of Macchiatos earlier
while I was watching you
eat your French toast.
And uh,
I think the question to start with is
what is your first memory of causing
trouble or getting into trouble?
Well, um, let's see. To go back,
I think it would probably be around
second grade has a second grade.
Well,
you have to understand, when I
was young, I was really into art,
into drawing and around the second grade,
the teenage mutant Ninja turtles came
out, right. And like big deal, big deal.
I was totally hooked on
Tele. Michelangelo, Raphael,
everybody like I was,
I was in it.
And so I started drawing them and
I just had such a good time drying.
Then I would show them to my classmates.
I remember the second grade
and my classmates started
to want to buy them from
me.
And so I would mount them on this
like really special poster board.
And I'd come into class and like I would
be selling these for the total of $1.
If you want to get a big one,
I would sell you the bigger ones for $2.
And so I was having a ball. I'm
doing what I loved, making drawings,
the classmates and like make an
extra, you know, allowance every week.
A dollar is a lot of money when you're in
second grade, we deal, it's a big deal.
And so, uh, I at one point that my
teacher pulls me aside and she says,
I need to talk to you.
And she begins to explain to me that
students were so interested in these
drawings that they were asking their
parents for extra lunch money and their
parents were like,
what are you next to lunch money for?
And they traced it back to me.
And the, the teacher shut me down.
Like you can't be doing this.
All right.
So already
signs of looming misbehavior.
Uh, yeah. And, and the
signs of, of, uh, you know,
spotting an opportunity
and doing something about
entrepreneurship. Yeah. Yeah.
It was also, you know, you can say
my first brush with regulation.
Yeah. First brush that, that,
that may or may not come in handy later,
maybe.
And where were you at the time?
Just the places geographically.
Where did you grow up?
Uh, my parents are from New York. Uh,
Wa my grandfather's heritage
back in Italy and Ireland,
grandfathers in Brooklyn,
parents grew up in long island,
moved to Georgia right before they had me.
So I grew up in the deep south and I was
in, you know, the town of Warrensville,
which is next to Snellville,
which is near Lilburn,
which is not far from Norcross.
We just kind of close to Atlanta.
So if you went, you know, an hour in one
direction, you'd, you'd be in, you know,
farm fields and you know,
horse ranches and um, it'd be,
uh, you know, it was, it was, it
was a south in every kind of way.
So you're selling these drawings now,
where did that impulse come from?
And I ask,
because I've had the chance to spend
some time with your dad. Awesome guy.
It's true.
We were together at a date with destiny
event and you had the very good idea of
basically creating animal house by
renting a house together on Joe Bnb,
otherwise known as Airbnb.
And Your Dad's awesome.
A also seems to be very entrepreneurial.
So that's why I'm asking. I'm not implying
it came straight from your dad, but, uh,
could you maybe talk about
that and then also what were,
what were some defining
characteristics of your childhood?
Well, certainly in both of
my parents and quitting.
My Dad were very entrepreneurial. They
both worked for themselves growing up.
So I had this, um, you know,
environment where I saw my
parents forging their own path,
sort of their success was fully
dependent on how hard they worked and how
ambitious they were in their,
their careers of what they were doing.
And my dad certainly was entrepreneurial,
you know,
he was always coming home with
something on the weekend saying,
I've got this new product idea, I've got
this new service I found and, and um,
you know, or basement was full of these
different attempts at different things.
Um,
and so there was this,
this spirit of trying things out
by all means in our household.
What were some of the things
that you're done trying?
Um, I don't know. Some early
Internet things and the mid nineties,
as the Internet started to
come out, um, you know, I,
I don't actually remember
what were some of the things that caught,
what did he, what did he end up doing?
Um, well, he ended up
working with my mom and, uh,
they both were in the
health food industry.
So when you go into whole foods and you
see enough vitamins and supplements in
the vitamin aisle,
they were the representative between
the manufacturer of those products and
getting into the shelf of those stores.
What was interesting was to tag along
with with them on business trips where
they'd drive around the south from South
Carolina to Tennessee to Alabama and
getting to see how they interacted with
these store owners because it wasn't
just whole foods, it was the also the mom
and pop vitamins tours as well. Right.
Independence, independence. And so, um,
it was really fascinating watching them
interact with the store owners and it's
just seeing how far they would
go to serve people. You know,
I remember one time specifically we're
in Tennessee and it was really late at
night. Uh, all the other store
employees have gone home.
It's my dad and myself and the store
manager and we're sitting there stocking
shelves were like, this is Tennessee.
Yeah, we're doing somebody else's job.
But for my dad, it was just
about creating a connection with,
with the store owner and really I guess
going above and beyond what was required
of you. And so I really took
away from that, those, you know,
observations of watching how your
parents treat people. Um, you know,
there's just,
it was really nice to see and it
definitely planted a seed in me of like,
you know, going out of your way for
those that you're serving your customers.
Was it your,
was it your dad's idea to bring you along?
Did you ask to be brought along or
something else? I don't know. Yeah.
I remember the,
the very first morning in the
House that we rented Florida,
we had heard of date with destiny being
nicknamed by some people date with death
because the schedule is so intense,
right?
I 1216 God knows how
many hours it's up to,
up to the powers that be the big man and
so on. And it can be very hard to get,
food can be very hard to get a break.
And even if you do get a break,
maybe there's a line of 300 people from
60 countries waiting to get a chicken
wrap so you're not gonna
get your chicken wrap it.
So we had stocked up with bars and
mixed nuts and yogurt and jerky and
everything imaginable and it
was scattered all over the place
and got up in the morning and the entire
collection of food had been rearranged,
like a point of sale display.
It was in perfect order. It was ready
for a storefront. And I was just like,
did you do that to my two of my
friend Avi? And he's like, no,
I definitely didn't do that. I, and then
I knew Emilia hadn't done it. I was like,
who did? I was like, oh. Then Joe Sr
like, you'd be like some eggs. I'm happy.
I'm making some eggs. Would do like
some side. I was like, wow. Yeah.
So it makes sense. It makes
sense. That attention to detail.
You got a little taste of, oh,
it was great. I was thrilled. Uh,
what else did you,
what else did you experience in childhood
that, that stuck with you? And I'll,
I'll,
I'll lead with one thing that I
originally asked you all about and when we
initially spent time together
also related to Tony Robbins,
Tony's the glue that holds us together,
which I didn't expect to
really be verbalizing that.
It seems at least up to this
point that he's been a, a, a,
a consistent character in the background
or in the foreground. He's a big dude,
hard to mess.
But we began talking about tennis because
I had just taken my first ever tennis
lessons,
uh,
with Jim Lair and Lorenzo Beltrami,
an incredible coach down to
Florida. But you were wearing a, uh,
Nicole Terry or bold Cherry Academy shirt
and I knew just enough having read the
open autobiography by Andre
Agassi to recognize the name.
So I asked you about it. Uh, so
it seems like tennis was certain,
certainly something that was also,
oh my God, what are the families?
So maybe you could talk
to them. Yeah. You had a
tennis family, you could say. I
think that's what they call that,
a time where every member of the family
plays tennis. We did coaching together,
we played in Alta and Usta together.
We did and competitions together.
And it was a truly a family
sport growing up. Um,
and so tennis was a huge part of my life
as a kid amongst a lot of other sports.
I think that's the things that stood out
to me of, of childhood and things that,
one of things I'm really grateful for us
is that whatever my interest, where my,
my parents would support it.
Um,
and I think they learned
this lesson the hard way. Um,
how so they,
they got me into a violin when I was
really young when I was like about four or
five years old, which you were interested
or not interested in it, right? I mean,
no,
and so I was taking violin lessons
and there's a recital that I,
I don't remember how old I was,
maybe six.
And I'm at this recital. It's in Savannah,
Georgia. I'm sorry, Augusta, Georgia.
And I'm definitely out of my depths here.
Like all the kids are bigger than me.
Um,
I'm not being able to keep up with
everyone else's plane and apparently I sat
down on the front of the stage and
just put my violin down and there's my
parents in the back,
probably the terrified look in their face.
And after that experience they switch
their perspective and said we're going to
support whatever his intrinsic
interests are. Right?
And so I was really grateful for
that. You know, throughout my,
my childhood sports, music and
art are the three things that, uh,
anytime I throw my weight behind something
they were right there to support me.
Whether it was, uh,
you know, practice law,
a sports practice or
sports equipment or um,
musical lessons or art supplies,
whatever the thing was,
they were there to support me in it.
What if not violin?
Where did you gravitate towards me
in music is in the violin lessons.
I do remember this, this part I was
so eager to finish the vine lessons,
violin lessons that I could go bang on
the piano that was in the same music room.
And sure enough, I started taking piano
lessons and I've, I've played ever since.
Cool. So you still play? I do, yeah.
I've got a piano at home and it's
like one of those things, you know,
it's the first thing I do when I get home
at the end of the day is I just go jam
on the piano. I either play some of
my favorite music from felonious monk,
Dave Brubeck or I just make
stuff up and kind of riff.
What other entrepreneurial experiences
do you recall from elementary school or
high school after you got
the kibosh thrown on the
teenage mutant Ninja Turtles?
That certainly wasn't
the end. You know, I,
I distinctly remember a whole bunch of
things from part of the common stuff,
right? Like I started a long
line business in my neighborhood,
so I put her on flyers on people's
doors and my neighborhood and offered 1
million car washing. And so, you
know, I'd Go Wah Milan for 20 bucks.
Um, no, that was quick money in
my pocket as a, as a kid. Um,
kind of getting into high school,
there was a one moment where senior
year came around and the senior year tee
shirt that did, did my
high school, it was,
it was pretty uninspiring,
let's just call it that.
And I thought,
you know,
I bet I could do something
better than that at this point.
I just got my first Mac,
my first apple computer
and it had Photoshop on it
and illustrator and graphic
software that you needed to, to
make you know, visuals. And so, um,
that's when it was actually warm
introductions to Photoshop was I just
redesigned the t shirt and I didn't have
any money really other than the lawn
lane money that was coming in.
And um,
I figured out how to get these tee shirts
made. I went to a local printer, um,
figure out how to do all the,
transfer the files to them and suddenly
I'm sitting on about 300 tee shirts and
I realize I got to go sell these things.
Okay, got it. So you took it
upon yourself to redesign the,
was it the highschool tee shirt?
Yeah, like this, the senior, the
senior at like the senior teacher,
the senior tee shirt, and then went out
and now you have a bunch of inventory.
I got a bunch of inventory
and I gotta go sell him. Um,
which will come up again later
in another story. Um, but yeah,
it was, it was, it was fun.
And actually I remember, uh,
I did better than break even on those
and people were really happy to have a,
a really memorable what the shirt, you
know, it was a riff on the, the tide logo.
The tide detergent.
Sure.
And so instead of Saint Titus had seniors
class of 2000 Brookwood high school
and um, it didn't really, well
see, so you didn't, you didn't bet
the farm and lose the farm yet,
at least broke even.
Yeah. Yeah, it was, it was,
it was fun to, to learn, you
know, how did you, some of the,
the graphics programs like Photoshop
and then also figure out like how do you
turn that into something, right.
How does it leave your screening,
become some of the physical, and so
it was a great lesson. If anything.
Where did you think, now this was
senior year in high school? Yeah.
What did you think you were going to do
when you grew up per se at that point?
Well,
or what did you want to do?
So every year from elementary,
middle and high school,
the art teacher would tell you need to
take more art classes because it was a
talent that I had that stood out and then
they recognize it and were telling me
about it.
And so you're,
every year I would invest
more into art classes and I,
at one point I was driving downtown to
the land of College of art and weekends
to take figure drawing classes.
Sometimes on weeknights I drive
down for painting classes and,
and then something really
incredible happened.
I applied for this program called the
governor's honors program in high school
where they take students from around the
state of Georgia across all disciplines,
math and science and languages and art.
And they pick about 30 students
or the state for each discipline.
And then if you get in,
you go to a college campus for the summer.
And he actually said he college level
coursework in whatever the discipline is.
So I went for art and had
an incredible time here.
It was surrounded by some of the other,
you know,
the best artists in the state of
Georgia and other high school students.
And I had teachers who were
co collegiate level, uh,
challenging us the same way
they would a college student.
And I freaking loved it.
And there was one woman in particular,
her name was Donna and she was like one
of those people in life that you have
along your journey who helped you.
It helps,
it helps you see something else about
yourself that maybe you don't quite
realize yet.
And so she sat me down one day during
this program and really kind of laid out
what it might look like if I pursued
art after, after high school.
And she was one of the first persons
that got me really excited about,
she made it realistic for
me to even think about it.
Was that even a practical
idea? Right. And she's like,
there's one school you have to go to.
It's the Rhode Island School of design.
And I'm like the what,
where's that
and so something to Bahamas?
Yeah.
She put a [inaudible] on the map
for me and I was during that,
that program during that, that summer,
um, I really dove into painting.
I did this painting that was about
eight feet by four feet wide,
stretch their own canvas and really like
threw myself and understand materials
and paint better than ever ever before.
And we had the show at the end of the
program so you know everyone in art,
the discipline got to have like a gallery
show and there was my painting on the
main wall when you walked
in and it was really like,
it was a moment for me to realize
that a people are appreciated.
The images that I made and my
art and seconds, I loved it.
Like I really felt challenged.
I felt creative. It was,
it was allowing me to fulfill all these,
these desires that I had to,
to create things.
How much of that was the environment
versus the medium do you think?
I think the,
probably the environmental a bit more
cause the medium could have been anything.
Right. I mean, we did wreck
wreck, who, pottery and firing.
We figure drawing and painting.
We were exposed to all kinds of
different mediums and materials.
I think the environment is what I fell
in love with the being challenged,
challenge being surrounded
by the creatives. And um,
and really that's what
triggered me to say, Huh,
this Rhode Island School of design thing.
So the next summer I did their high school
program and got to spend six weeks on
campus basically as like a, you
really act like a freshmen, right?
They give you again, college level
courses and afters do at Risley.
I fell in love with the campus, fell in
love with the people and you know, as it,
as a junior in high school, I'm
like, I gotta go here. This is,
this is where I feel challenged.
So then what happens?
Well,
so before I leave, um, high school,
there's a, there's another story
about, um, entrepreneurial Joe.
Um,
so I haven't told the story in a while.
Uh, but so when I got to
high school as a freshman,
the senior class right before me had
pulled off as amazing senior prank.
So at our high school,
the mascot was a bronco horse.
This was the Brookwood Broncos, and
they went down the street to this, uh,
like a country Western store where
you get cowboy boots and cowboy hats.
It's called horse town east. And on the
top of their sign, which was pretty tall,
it was a couple of store,
a couple of stories tall,
was this giant full sized plastic horse.
And somehow the senior class figured out
how to get the horse down from the sign
and then they'd put it on top of our
school. And so the last day of class,
everyone came in, there's a giant full
sized plastic horse on top of Brookwood.
And so when I showed up as a freshmen,
everybody was talking about it. I,
everyone's like, yeah. Did you hear
what the senior class did last year?
But for the graduated, yeah, and it,
I just started to think to myself,
I can, I want to outdo that. I've
got four years to think of something.
I'll keep it.
Surely I can come up with something better
than the horse on top of the school.
So I set myself a challenge, uh, frank,
um, by senior year. So the years go by,
it's not senior year.
Um,
and we have about four months ago and
I still haven't thought of anything.
And the clock's ticking.
It's now three months ago.
I still haven't thought of anything.
It's now two months to go and I uh,
I get on a Google, I search, you know,
high school senior pranks just to see
like what else is out there because I'm
still committed to figure something out.
And so I keep coming
across the same stuff.
You've got a super guru,
the locks, the doors,
you've got Philip Cups with water and
the gym and put them all next to each
other.
They like knock over and then you've
got three pigs out in to the school and
label them one to four so everyone thinks
there's the third pig pigment around.
So you know,
it was like the repetition of how many
sites were covering these banks is like
these are not original.
And that was one of my cards here.
Like this needs to be something original.
I'm not going to just
like copy another prank.
And so we're now like three
weeks until graduation.
Don't have any prank.
I haven't figured it out yet.
And my sister was a cheerleader and so
she'd have this cheerleading practice
after school and normally I'd have
to hang around and take her home.
And so, um, outside after school one
day, and she's nowhere to be found,
this is before cell phones.
And the way that you track somebody
down at that time was to, um,
they'd make some announcement
over the intercom system.
They like called her names. So I go
into the front office and by the way,
I went to high school in Georgia.
That was one of the largest,
we had over 4,000 people in a high school,
right.
So this is one of the biggest
high schools in the state.
And I thought that to access
the inner calm would be some,
you go in some room, there'd be some
big system. It'd be super complicated.
So I'm in the front office and I'm
looking at the secretary and I go, Hey,
I'm just trying to find
my sister, Kim, can you,
can you Pedro over the Intercom and the
start? He goes, oh, sure. Just a minute.
She picked,
she picks up the phone and she hits lb
zero zero on the dial pad and then she
talks into the phone, Hey Kim,
Kim Gebbia, your brother's here,
please come to the front of the building
and everything she said into the phone
came out over the intercom system
and I'm watching this and I'm going,
it's that easy to get into the intercom
system of the largest high school in the
state of Georgia.
All you have to do is have access to
the phone line and hit pound zero zero.
I'm like, oh my God. It
was this big Aha moment.
As I'm watching this unfold
in front of me and I go,
all I have to do is get one
of those splitter jacks,
plug it into the same phone line,
and then I can run a cord of another
phone somewhere else in the closet or
something. And then I could call in and
have access to the whole intercom system.
So for a week I'm toiling on this.
I'm like,
how am I going to route a phone
cord without anybody noticing it?
And then finally it dawns on
me just get a cordless phone.
You can be anywhere in the school
and have access to the inner call.
So this point I recruit one of my buddies,
Mark Eisenhower, who looking back,
probably wasn't the best accomplished for
this position because he played on the
basketball team, was about six foot
four with bright blonde hair, right?
Not In conspicuous conspicuous at all.
Um,
and so we go,
we go to the school that weekend
and we have this grand plan that um,
we'll,
we'll maybe trick one of the janitors
until letting us into the main office.
And when he leaves somehow will like
plug in this cordless phone in school.
Um, it, it definitely was not a well
thought out plan at this point, but, um,
we didn't have a lot of times,
so we hit, we just went for it.
And so we went to the school,
it was on a Sunday afternoon,
I think the janitor saw right through us
do not let us in the office.
And so we left a bit empty handed,
but we weren't given up.
This was too good.
So I employed another friend,
her name is Chelsea Hughes.
And so the three of us came up with a
better plan that we'd go up on a week, uh,
on a, on a, on a weekend.
And there was a community school office
that we knew would be open on weekends
and that office connected like he's
inner chambers to the main office.
And if we could just get into that one
we thought was you could go through the
sequence of other doors to
get into the main office.
And so Chelsea went up and tried to
figure out where that principal was that
that um, community school
director. And so she,
she identified him on the far side
of campus. She signaled to mark,
mark signaled to me,
and I'm outside in like a black Hoodie
with my backpack full of the phone,
a flashlight. And mark gave me the
signal following Mr. Robot. Totally.
I go running in through the lobby of
the school right into this community
director's office and then it's
pitch black and I'm, I'm like going,
going through all the doors.
It's like chamber by Chamber
until you get to the main office,
the front desk I'm getting,
I'm there and I moved the desk to the
side and there's this giant jumble of
chords underneath it.
I'm trying to figure out which one,
what the hell is the phone line.
And then I trace it back to the wall.
I pull up the splitter piece,
I put it in,
and then I plug in the cordless phone
and the phone from the desk into the same
line.
And I'm trying to bury the cord
base underneath the pile chords.
And this point, I'm sweating, my
heart is racing. I'm like, oh my God.
In the darkness of this office,
definitely not supposed to be there.
And all of a sudden there's
a tap on my shoulder.
My heart jumps a torn around it. It's more
like hovering over him. He goes, Joe, me,
we got to go. Mr Choke is on his way.
And I'm like, all right, I'm done.
So we pushed the desk back. We go out
the back entrance into the parking lot,
we meet up with Chelsea,
I pulled the cordless phone out of my bag,
I turned it on and we get a dial tone.
We have access to the intercom.
So the next question is what do
you do with that access? Right.
So the next day
I decided that I was going to make a tape
mix of different songs deploy over the
intercom system and I play,
I put together a mix of pink Floyd.
We don't need no education and Alice
Cooper's schools out for summer and I
haven't got so detailed
about this that I am.
I had my mom help out at home.
She didn't know she was helping me,
but we had two phone lines in the house,
went for their business,
one for personal use and I would call
one phone line to the other and have the
tape player next to it to figure
out the right volume on it,
the right distance from the phone,
and have my mom on the other end and
telling me if it was loud enough or not.
She helped me calibrate the right uh,
the right volume for the tape player.
So the,
the phone is embedded.
Um, the tape makes tape, mixes is made.
It's now the last day of school and I
woke up that morning and I was nervous.
I'm like, ah, got to do this today.
All right. Prank is happening.
So I go to school a little bit
late on purpose. So as it works,
um,
I parked,
I parked my car in the parking lot
and in one pocket I've got the phone,
the other pocket, I've got this
tape player, I can't help it,
like on Sony Walkman and I'm
walking through the parking lot.
It's just just me, there's nobody
else. And then all of a sudden
our school police officer shows up on
his golf cart and he turns the corner and
he's coming straight towards me
and there's nobody else around.
It's just him and me and he's coming at
me and I'm staring at him and I'm like,
just be cool. Just be
cool. He doesn't know.
And like as you're getting closer to
my heart's racing faster and I'm like,
Oh my God,
I've got this,
the bolt is in my pocket of the phone
and the tape player and he makes eye
contact. I mean the golf
cart goes by like, okay.
So I walked to the front of the school
and there's like this overhang area where
the buses pulled up and um,
there's the benches and then the,
these glass doors before
you go into the main lobby.
And so everything's cleared
out except for this one kid,
he must've been like a freshman
or a sophomore or something.
And he's sitting there and
I'm like waiting for him to
leave cause I didn't want
anybody to see what I was about
to do and he's not going anywhere.
And think to myself, I have to do this
now. Like I can't wait any longer.
So I just run up to him. I get
right in his face and I go, look,
you can't say anything about
what you're about to see.
And he was just totally freaked
out. And he goes, oh, okay.
And so I go behind one of these, these
brick columns that was holding up the,
the overhang and around the column you
could see into the glass doors and end
where the officers were the phone basis.
So I pulled the phone out,
I pulled the tape player,
my hands are shaking and I'm like,
I'm just thinking stuff. All right,
let's go time. I turned the phone on,
get the dial tone, I hit pound zero,
zero. My hands are shaking even more.
I think this deep breath,
and actually this beep comes over
the whole school to signal there's an
announcement and I can
actually hear myself breathing
through the inner calm and
I'm like, all right, this right
now say it playing the tape player.
I set the two down next to
each other and as I'm doing it,
I flicked the volume all the way just
to be safe cause I'm thinking of itself.
I don't want to come across as too
soft and the volume. So I'm like,
I got to throw the volume the way up.
So I said to Tina next to each other
and I walk into the building and that's
when all hell broke loose.
I opened the lobby,
I go into the lobby doors and the music
is blasting out of the intercom system.
Schools out full.
So it's like the speakers
are about to explode.
It's like so freaking loud. And
um, when you get to school late,
he had to go to like a checking line to
sign in. And so I'm in the checking line.
There's like two people in
front of me and this is,
this is the scene I'm in this like,
you know,
kind of high school lobby to
my left are all the offices,
including the one where the phone
is to my right is the gymnasium,
add them gymnasium. Two of
my buddies combusting out
while this music's blasting.
They're laughing so hard because
they realize that it was me.
The coach comes out of the gym, starts
yelling at him, you get back in here.
We don't know what's going on.
What are you going to get back in here?
I'm just sitting there with a
straight face, not packing a smile.
I sign in and then to get to my class,
I have to walk past all these offices.
Right? And so while I'm doing
that, I hear what's going on.
They're yelling at each other. People were
sticking their head out of the office.
Who's it coming from in there? No, I
don't know where it's coming from there.
I got the phone in their hands.
You can hear all the Datacom then
hitting me like numbers on the phone,
trying to shut it off. They had no
idea where the heck it was coming from.
And so as I'm walking past
these sequence of offices,
I catch a glimpse into the principal's
secretary office and then into the
principal's office, which has
even a deeper layer. And I see,
I catch her face and it's bright
red and she's yelling at somebody.
While this music's still playing it.
Right? Right now we're on to pink Floyd.
At this point we don't need no education
and so I've just been going on,
but it's like three,
four minutes.
Then at this point I'm walking through my
classes in the very back of the campus.
I'm walking through the halls,
I'm totally by myself while the music's
playing and every time I walked past the
classroom,
there's a little skinny like glass window
and you can kind of get a glimpse into
it.
And as I walked patsy classes,
I take these double books and people are
like on top of their chairs and on top
of their desks and people were dancing
and I get to my classroom right as the
tape ends.
And look,
I thought for sure they're going to
shut this off in like 20 seconds.
So I didn't make a tape very long.
It was like a couple minutes
and I need a and a tape.
It probably would have
played for 20 minutes. Right.
So I get there right as a tape ends,
I opened the door.
People are staying on top of their desks.
People were dancing.
The teachers at her desk
with her head in her hands,
like totally lost control of her
class and it's like the record stops.
I walk in, everybody turns and looks at me
and goes, Joey was at you, and I'm like,
no, I don't know what that was. And so
finally the teacher gets
control of the class again.
We sit down and everyone's looking
at me like, Oh wow, that was awesome.
What was that? I'm like, I
don't know. I don't know.
And so not two minutes later,
there's a knock on the door
and administrator walks in.
She walks over to the teacher,
the class goes dead silent.
They whisper something to each other
and then they both turn and look at me.
The administrator comes by my desk.
She goes, Joey, get your stuff.
You're coming with me. And I'm like
seeking him. Desole I'm like, oh no.
She gets outside. She slams the door,
we're in the hallway and she goes,
you want to tell me what's happened
to back there? I go, I don't know.
You're talking about, she's like,
we've got mark in the office.
We know what happened and I'm like,
I don't,
I don't know what you're talking about.
And she goes, you can make this hard,
you can make this easy on
yourself. When I was like, ah.
So we walk all the way back to the front
of the campus and the whole way she's
berating me,
chewing my head off of all the damages
that I caused and all the issues that
were created with the phone system.
And we go to the secretary's office and
we walk through and I see mark there and
he's got his head in his hands. And
Mark is, you're very tall, very tall,
very blonde, very blonde, very
obvious accomplice. Yes, yes he was.
He was a good buddy and a good friend.
And I appreciate his help in
this endeavor. And so he's,
he's down like this.
He's like totally crushed and he sees
me and he looks at me and he goes,
and I couldn't tell what he was saying.
So it's just trying to mouth
the words analysis of the to me.
And so what are you saying?
He goes, it was the janitor.
So we get through the secretary
office into the principal's office,
Connie quarterly.
Never forget her name.
They slammed the door and I'm staying
there with my backpack or in a green izod
shirt.
I will never forget this.
I mean my brown khaki pants and a green
izod shirt with my backpack and there's
Connie quarterly at her desk with their
arms like this kind of huffing and
puffing face is bright red.
She's got the phone and the tape player
and the phone cord and the phone base on
her desk and around her
or the 20 administrators,
including the school police officer.
It's the biggest school in the state
of Georgia. We had on a police officer.
And so they're all like this, like arms
crossed, huffing and puffing, right?
And I'm like, Oh fuck. Like
what? Heart's racing. I'm like,
what is going on here?
Every one of them took a turn,
it may just to yell at me about something.
Connie coy starts the army.
How did you get to the office?
You broken energy and she's like,
like really angry. And I'm like, ah, like,
like I'm starting to feel a
little bit bad about this. Like,
like I'm not sure what this
is going to go. Like is this,
am I going to get off on this? Or like,
oh there's some consequences here.
I have no idea.
And so from that they lead us
into this like negotiation room,
which I've never seen.
It was this long wooden table,
but he's like leather chairs are on the
whole side of principal corlies at the
head of the table. Mark and I are
now senior across from each other.
We get administrators standing
over us with their arms crossed,
like we're going to make
a run for it or something.
And she likes charts like
negotiating with us. And um,
this is the part that it actually pissed
me off the most is that she started to
threaten our scholarships and she looked
at marsh, she goes, mark, you know,
I know you've got,
I'm a basketball scholarship to this,
the school in Georgia that you go into.
I hate to have to call the
coach and tell him about this,
this incident she gives me,
cause Joey,
I know you're going to that
art school in Rhode Island.
I hate to have to call the admissions
office and tell them about this incident.
And that point I was like,
there's no way you're getting in the
way of either of our dreams because we
tapped into the high school in
your home system. Like right.
So she made an offer, she goes, um,
we could press charges for breaking,
entering and tampering and school
property and some other things.
Or you can do this list
of things which included,
um, wiping down computer screens and the
library, you know, during the summertime,
um, ironically setting up and taking
down the sound equipment for graduation.
I like if you were the chores and
like manual labor basically. Um,
and so mark and I, obviously we say, well,
we'll do the chores and the need of
labor so that we can graduate pressing
charges somehow equated to not being
able to graduate and get your diploma.
And so from there we go into the
school police officers office.
His name was officer Harrelson and it's
a good cop. Now this guy. Yeah, right.
This guy had the deepest kind of grizzly
voice that you could imagine a office
officer Harrolson here.
Brookwood high school.
So we're in the office and he
calls her parents and this is,
this is like probably where the
worst part of the whole story.
He did not know the update that we
opted in to do the manual labor.
He thinks that we're not graduating high
school now, so he calls my mom. He goes,
Miss [inaudible]. This is officer
Harrelson here at Brookwood high school.
Yes ma'am. I've got your, your son in
custody here. Yeah. Yes. Right man,
it doesn't look like he's graduating
this year. Oh No. Yeah man.
And he's right here. He hands me the phone
and I heard this tone of voice in my,
from my mom. I've never heard since.
I never everyone here again. She goes,
you could ride home after school.
I can't believe you click.
I'm like Mamba League.
We're going to graduate.
So she thinks her son's not
graduating high school. Um, I'm like,
thanks officer house and it
was really kind of view, um,
and does the same thing at the mark and
we're walking out of his office and this
is the best part. He pulls us to
the side and he goes, Mark Joey,
I've been at the school for over 20 years
and you need to know that was the best
damn prank I've ever seen.
Officer Harrelson. So we
go through graduation. Um,
one little funny spent Levy does it,
you know,
he had your honors cords and a different
club cores that you were on your neck.
Mark and I were phone cords
to honor the it senior prank.
People were raving about it. Um, and we
came back, you know, two weeks later,
did you wipe computer screens in
the library? And I'll never forget,
we're outside on meet the same overhang,
like dusting off our rags and all these
buses pull up and all these bus drivers
start pouring into the school passed it.
So it has like some bus driver, you know,
end of year celebration or something.
And one of the bus drivers actually
walks over to us and she goes,
are you the two boys?
It pulled that prank with the intercom
system and mark and I looked at each
other and we're like, yeah.
She goes, you know, you are,
you two are our lens in this
county. And Morgan are like, what?
Like how did they hear about it?
Like all the bus drivers and
the county that we moved in.
So,
um,
it was this incredible
moment of having an idea.
I have this ambition to do something
that was original. In this case,
there was no property damage.
Nobody got hurt,
which is to me the essence
of a great prank. And, um,
that was part one of the story,
part one of the story.
Well, all right, I'll bite. I'll fight.
What's part two of the story?
It's a part to the story. Um,
I'm in college,
this is about two years later and one of
my roommates comes home one day and he
says, Hey, have you heard of that
show? It's on MTV. It's called, um,
uh, high school stories, pranks
in controversies. And I go,
no, no. It was about, he's like,
yeah, I was, I was just watching it.
It's like they showed this,
this, uh, some high school,
they had this high school was prank. I was
like, I sat up in my chair. I go, really?
You tell me about that? And he goes,
yeah, they film these guys who get this.
They super glued the locks on the doors
of this high school. And I'm like,
you have to be kidding me.
The oldest trick in the book [inaudible]
making a show about high school pranks
and they're doing a super glue
in the Loc Prank. I'm like,
I have to get in touch with the producer.
So I get online and I tracked down the
producer of the show and I sent them an
email that was a teaser of the story,
but not the full one. And basically said,
if you wanna hear the rest of it,
here's my phone number.
Probably about 30 minutes later, my
phone rings for the 200, two area code.
And when I see NYC and I get on the
phone with this producer and he's like,
I really intrigued by your email,
are always looking for good stories.
What does it,
what he got?
And I told them the abbreviated version
of what you just heard. And he's like, oh,
I love this. I'm gonna Pitch
this to my executive producer.
We're to get back to you.
It's about three or four days later you
get another phone call from a t one two
hey, this is Leslie from MTV.
I'm the executive producer here.
Really loved your story.
Want to hear more about it from you.
So by the end of the call, she's in
love with the story and she's like,
you know what we're going to do? We're
going to send a crew down to Georgia.
We want you to come back this summer.
We're going to reenact the whole thing
and included in the next season of a TV
show. So that summer we got to go back
to Georgia and reenact the whole thing.
Now, however, this is
only two years later,
the same administration and
principal is still there.
And they did not have a lot of friction.
I was going to say the wounds
have healed over quite yet.
Definitely not healed. They
definitely had a grudge. Um,
because if anything we just
embarrass them like right.
They had no idea how to
turn it off. I'm like, yeah,
there's no damage or anything that
was really done that's permit.
And so they declined reenacting a school.
So ironically went to one of my rival
high schools and refilm the whole thing
there. And even more ironic is that
the principal, the new principal there,
it was a former administrator when
I pulled a prank at my other school.
So he was intubated, familiar what
had happened at that point. He was,
he could laugh about it. Um, so that
summer we reenacted the whole thing. Um,
Chelsea and mark and I got a couple
of their friends to be extras in the
background and it aired later that year.
And MTV.
Amazing.
So it seems like your brushes with
mischief just seemed to reinforce your
appetite for mischief of sorts in a way.
Perhaps.
Perhaps now when we were
hanging out earlier today,
I ask a question that that I often ask
of friends I'm going to sit down with and
it was in effect.
Can you give me any cues?
I don't want to hear the story,
but can you give me any cues that might
lead to a fun discussion and and one of
them I said,
I don't want to know the story because
I want to hear it fresh and when we're
recording and one of them was NBA time
worked with or in NBA and I have no idea
what this refers to,
but that's a cue.
Tim. I think this story starts
by telling you a fun fact.
I seen Michael Jordan naked in person.
Okay, this is a good start.
Now we're talking about
locking room, hotel room barbecue. My job,
I had a high school job where I worked
as a ball boy in the NBA for the Atlanta
Hawks and that was my job in high
school. Okay. I love basketball.
I played my whole life
and I was reading these,
I used to read the newspaper every morning
when I was growing up over breakfast,
whatever. I would just consume
the newspaper. And so, um,
one day I'm in the sports section and
there's an article about a bat being bat
boys for the Atlanta Braves and being
ball boys for the Atlanta Hawks.
At the very end of the article it said,
if you're interested in becoming one,
send a letter about yourself to this
address. And I'm like, oh my God. Yes.
Like that would be so cool.
Right? So I send a letter,
but actually I sent it on
the day of the deadline
once it passed and I sent them the day
of the deadline and I kind of forgot
about it until that next summer I get
a phone call and this guy introduced
himself as Chris Tucker,
the strength of the head strength
coach of the Atlanta Hawks.
And he goes, yeah, we got your
letter and we really liked it.
We want you to come down to
interview for one of our board,
our ball ballboy positions. I go, this is
awesome. I'll be there. So we get down to,
um, at the time it was a the Omni, um,
but for the head Philips arena and
I'm interviewing with them, you know,
tell them about my life and my love for
basketball and these things and I get a
call back a few days later
that I got the job. So this,
I'm like a freshman in high school,
right? I'm like barely like 16, maybe 15.
I'm 15 years old and I start working,
you know,
in the locker rooms of the Atlanta hawks.
And actually my very first game,
I'll never forget this was the hawks
versus the Toronto Raptors and they threw
me onto the,
the visitors because the ball boys
for the home team and the business.
Can you explain what a ballboy doesn't
basketball because I'm an idiot when it
comes to group sports or team sports.
I know the ball boy or
ball girl does in tennis,
but in basketball I have no idea.
It's a bad,
there's different tiers
right at the entry level.
Tier is you're wiping
the sweat on the fort.
When a player falls down in the
middle of the game, all right, right.
People go out with the mop and the
towel and you're just wiping the sweat.
So the players and slip on the court,
it's like the entry level position.
And I did plenty of that. Um, as
you work your way up the tier,
then you work on the side of the court
and you'd actually run and grab the
players, warm up pants and jacket.
When they went to check into the games,
he'd be at half of like sitting on a
half court with them and you can't have a
towel when they came in,
you know,
sit back down on the bench and then the
next year was he'd worked behind the
bench and actually assist the trainer.
And so you'd be handing the Gatorade
over their shoulder. Oh, cool.
And they sit down and give him the towel,
get them their, their, their warm up,
their, uh, their jacket with a Hoodie.
And then the highest level was doing that
for the visiting team. Right. And so,
um, and whatever they needed to set
up the locker room before the game.
You've run any errands that
need to get done, you break the,
lock him down at the end of the game,
the whole thing.
So you get to the game like three
hours early and do all this. Um,
you end up running
errands for the players.
Sometimes you'd be like a nice
tip or horse grant one time,
give me a hundred dollar bill, it's
a big deal. Take us back to the bus.
And it was pretty cool.
And so they threw me my very first game.
They throw me to the visitors side,
Toronto Raptors, tar afters. And um,
it was my first experience, right of
like being around some amia greats.
Marcus Camby. I remember it was on the
team at the time. This guy watched play,
uh, at Umass in college and
like really admired and um,
uh,
it was my first exposure to
professional sports locker room too.
And everybody comes in and they just
take the clothes off to get changed in.
Like nobody gives a shit. It doesn't
matter at the end of the day. Um,
but for me it was like,
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. Where am I?
Lots of negative pressure athletes.
It was my first experience. Of course,
you get used to that. It's no big
deal at a certain point. Um, so I'm,
I'm in the MBA and I did
it for three seasons.
I got to work alongside the Lenny Wilkins,
the head coach to Kevin Mutombo,
Steve Smith, uh, some
of these NBA greats. Um,
and there were some really incredible
moments that happen. Um, one of them,
one of them was when the hawks
played the Chicago Bulls.
Jordan's still playing. This is 1999, um,
one of his last seasons. And, um,
I'll never forget this,
so you have to imagine the scene
ruin Philips arena and, uh,
the hawks are actually winning,
which is amazing.
And the place is going nuts. You can't
even hear yourself think it's so loud.
People are screaming. They're, they're
playing music over the loud speakers.
And I'm working the bowls
bench, right? Which is like,
you've got Scottie Pippin and Steve
Kerr, Dennis Rodman, uh, Michael Jackson,
Phil Jackson, Michael
Jordan, like the whole,
the whole rostered help rostered and
some work in the bowls bench there down.
Phil Jackson called a timeout and the
place goes nuts because the hawks are up
and in front of me.
Jordan pops down Rodman's on the left.
Pippins on the right.
Phil Jackson.
It's like right here and he's furious.
Like this guy's using xsplit as like
you'd never believe he's yelling things.
I feel like I can feel his soul
like his spit, like hitting my face.
He's just like,
and I'm like right behind Jordan.
He's right here and the places again,
so loud,
people screaming at the top of their
lungs and um, I'm doing my job right.
I give the guys a towel and then I'm
getting the Gatorade. So I'm like,
I'm going to start with Jordan.
Obviously he's right in front of me.
So I reached around. I,
you're on this side. Um,
so left, left hand, like over the
shoulder, left hand over the shoulder.
Jordan is facing this way, talking
to pip and who's right next to him.
I reached around and Rodman,
who is to my left,
turns quickly bumps my elbow.
The Gatorade quickly goes upside
down and straight into Jordan's lap.
There were only few in my life.
I've been as terrified as that moment.
Phil Jackson's yelling at me,
Michael Jordan spins around and he goes,
hey man, watch it. And I'm like,
oh my God, like my heart's racing.
I'm like Jesus Christ. So I did what
anybody would do in that moment.
If you spill something,
you tend to wipe it up.
So I grabbed the towel and I'm
patting down Jordan's thigh.
Like now I'm like in the huddle,
right?
Rodman's laughing at me because he
realized what he'd done had done.
Phil Jackson's like right
here, like spitting. He's
yelling so hard and I'm like,
I'm sorry Jordan.
I'm like trying to like dry as leg up
with his Gatorade spill that went right to
his lap and oh man, I'm like
sweating profusely. Right?
Cause like you're going to get like the
TV crews are like in the huddle to the
camera's in your face.
It's like high stress
moment as a ball boy.
And so are you had one job.
Don't pour the Gatorade on Jordan's balls.
Well obviously unfortunately Robin and
made that quick spin knocked me not your
fault. So I'm like, the,
the buzzer goes off and it's like time
to get back on the court and I'm still
like patting down like Jordan's
leg and he's like, oh, come on man,
get up.
And um,
I think right after that he actually
had like a whole bunch of points.
He three on the slam dunk or something.
I think
the moral of the story there
is a, you know, when he,
when I spill Gatorade on Jordan,
make sure you clean it up.
What it seems like there's
another pattern here,
which is
getting comfortable with
uncomfortable situations.
Right? Or exposing yourself
to discomfort. Yeah.
So that you're comfortable
sphere of action expands. Right.
Uh,
what,
what was your next brush once you get
to visit these, you're in [inaudible].
Were there any formative
entrepreneurial experiences
that come to mind?
Absolutely.
Were.
And I, she'd explain also if I may
interject just for a second that, okay.
One of the reasons I wanted to explore
a lot of these stories is that it's easy
and I think typical for people to take
a single chapter in someone's life and
isolate it and view it as the whole story.
Right?
But there's so much backstory and so
much development and so many experiences
that lead up to the small piece of the
puzzle that people tend to think is the
whole puzzle. Right? Right. So just for
people listening and watching, that's,
that's, and I just enjoy
your storytelling. So
that's another piece of it.
But the [inaudible], right. So
this is, this is a level up,
I mean risky, you have a lot of
talented people are his name,
uh,
any entrepreneurial memories or
experiments that come to mind from risky?
Yes. So I decided to go to
busy, to study fine arts,
to be a painter and I didn't
really know what that meant.
I had this vision of maybe one day,
you know,
being able to exhibit in New York or
something, like do the gallery scene.
I couldn't actually picture it, but, um,
really wanted to go to study art and
painting. So when I got to campus,
they have this week of orientation and
you get your class schedule and you get
to meet upperclassmen.
And um,
some talking to this
guy and fellow students,
fellow fell student upperclassmen
and he's saying, Oh,
who do you have for your courses?
And freshman year they give you the
foundation stuff like drawing two
dimensional design, three dimensional
design, liberal arts, art history,
and some going through
the list of teachers.
And I say this one teacher's name
that makes his eyebrows go up.
I go,
I've got Gareth Jones for three d.
And he goes, you've got
Gareth Jones. Oh Man.
I go, what is it, what it
is, this guy? And he goes,
just wait for the chess set project.
And I go, what's the Jess said project?
And he goes,
you'll see.
So my very first class is with this Guy
Gareth Jones teaching three dimensional
design. And picture this, we're in this
art studio with these concrete fours.
He's like rickety metal stools,
plaster covered kind of work surfaces.
It's a little bit cold, it's
September, New England. And you know,
it's a very first class. And I'm
sitting around with 18 other freshmen,
we're all trying to make sense of
where we are in the world and what this
thing's all about.
And this is about to be our first
impression of what does it like to be a
student at risky.
And so we're sitting there and all of a
sudden this guy wearing all black with
this big poofy had a hair comes out and
he stands in front of us and he's got
this Welsh accent and he goes,
I just want you all to know that half of
you are going to fail my costs because
he won't finish the chess set project.
I don't think it's off.
Oh my God,
that's what this is going to be like here.
Like half the people I with my left,
I looked to my right,
one of them is going to be gone because
going to fail out. I'm like, oh my God.
And we're all looking at each
other like is he serious?
And he goes on to explain
the chess at project.
And so in addition to
your weekly assignments,
the chest at project is this semester
long project that takes place outside of
the classroom on your own time where
you have to choose a three dimensional
artist,
like a sculptor like Henry
Moore and architect like
Frank Lloyd Wright furniture
designer, a fashion designer, and
you had to find a book about them.
And from that you had to select of their
work to recreate and you did it in the
format of a chess set,
which means it didn't have to
look like actual chess set pieces,
but you take one of their creations and
replicated eight times for your pond and
had to look exactly like
the picture in the book.
You took another one of their creations
and yet her replicate twice for the
rooks in three d in three d and Yet
to do it at 12 inch scale God and just
looking at a picture,
you'd figure out what it's made of,
what's the backside look like,
what's the underside of the like?
And at this time I had a
growing interest in furniture,
furniture design.
And I came across this furniture
designer from the 1920s and thirties,
named Garrett Rietveld. He was a
Dutch architect and designer. Um,
and he did these really beautiful chairs
that are actually in the museum of
Modern Art. They're classics.
And I thought a couple of things.
One is, as I got to know Gareth
Jones, the professor room,
it became very clear that this
guy was super opinionated.
He would argue to the death to
make sure that he was always right.
I would watch him like,
just are you students? Like,
like relentlessly to make his point.
And out of that,
I just had this growing thinking of like,
wow,
like I'd love to prove this
guy wrong at some point.
And so,
um,
I also thought I'm going to
throw myself into this project.
There's no way I'm
failing. In fact, I wanna,
I wanna I want to complete this project
and if I'm going to commit so much of my
time to this and I'm going to make
chairs from this designer Garrett,
refilled at the end of it, I want to
come out with something I can use.
I don't want 12 inch chairs.
I actually want full functional chairs.
And so I'm like, this is a really great
idea. I'm going to share this with Gareth.
So I call him over and I'm like,
Gareth,
I want to make full
size functional chairs.
And My expectation at this time
was that he's going to, you know,
give me a high five and say,
Joe, you can do it. You got this,
I believe in you instead,
Tim. He goes, Joe,
I really don't think you can do it.
Really focus on the smallest scale.
And he walks away and I'm like,
no fucking way.
Like, all right buddy, now you really
have to do it right. All right pal.
Like you just lit every fire that you
needed a light. We forgot how to do this.
The thing is I didn't know
how the hell to make a chair.
I've never worked with wood before.
I never heard power tools like,
like actual machine shop tools.
And um,
I was really stepping into unknown on this
and I had a semester to figure it out.
So I just committed every,
all of my time to making this
project happen on, on weekends,
Saturday nights my friends would be going
out to parties on campus and I was in
the studio trying to figure
out how to make chairs.
And so I started by going to the
furniture department and talking to
upperclassmen and actually sat with the
head of the furniture department name is
Rosanne Somerson.
And I told her about my ambitions and she
looked at me with kind of a crazy face.
It's like,
you're never going to figure this out.
But she was encouraging and she pointed
me to some upperclassmen who then
started help me understand wood
and machines and the tools,
table saws and band saws and leads in the
things that you need to make furniture.
And so piece by piece I started to
figure out how to make these chairs I was
sourcing would, I had access to
the shop that they were giving me.
And the thing is I never told
Gareth where it was in the projects.
So every check in and be like how's
it coming? I'm like, it's all right.
And I would downplay my progress.
Meanwhile in my dorm room is starting
to fill up with these chairs everywhere.
And so I like, I worked
my butt off and I just, I,
that whole semester I was like hacking
my way through it and I get to the the
pawn so I have to pick, pick one of
his chairs and make it eight times.
He made this beautiful bench out of just
four pieces of wood and I'm thinking to
myself, wow, these benches is really big.
That's a lot of wood. I can't afford this.
I don't know. I'm just a freshman
in college and so I'm out.
You had to cover all your material
costs. Oh yeah. Okay. No, no.
That's an important detail.
Right? So study job. At the time,
I was trying to like find
this harder. I could. And so
I'm in the quad one day outside
the freshman dorms and um,
I make an observation.
Everyone's standing around smoking here
in the quad and there's actually newer
to sit,
Huh,
I've got this bench design
that I'm going to make.
What if I approached the school,
get them to pay for the wood,
I'll make the benches from or project,
then they can have them afterwards to
put in the quad for people to sit on.
So I go to the, the head of
resident's life. I pitched
him the idea, he gloves it,
they fund a few thousand dollars
worth of this inch thick plywood.
And in doing so,
I get access to the schools,
wood shops and this school's
craftsmen like who work on campus.
And so now I've got their help to help
fabricate these, these benches. Amazing.
And they paid for all the wood, which
I definitely could never have afforded.
And so,
um,
by the end of the semester I've amassed
16 full size functional chairs and
Gareth had no clue and actually finished
the last chair at about two in the
morning, the night before the final
crit, the day before the final crit.
Chris, his critique, right? A critique.
In art school you have these critiques
where you put your arm, your workout,
and then the professor and the class
critique you and that's how you learn how
to improve as an artist or designer.
And so it's like now December,
it's freezing cold outside.
It's providence and I specifically chose
the slot right after lunch to present
because I figured when everyone's out
getting lunch, I'll get my roommates,
a couple buddies to help me carry all
these chairs and assembled them in the
space.
When people come back,
there'll be this great reveal
moment because nobody has
any clue except a couple
of friends. Exactly what I've
pulled off here. It's him.
My only regret from this project is that
I did not have a camera in my hand to
take a picture of Gareth's face
when he entered the studio.
I'm swear,
I'm standing there and he comes marching
in and he picks his head up and he
looks at the room suddenly and you can
see him counting and his head is 15, 16.
And he looks at me and he
goes, Joe, you've done it.
You've proved me wrong.
And I'm like,
the rest of the critique, we all send
my chairs and we talked about that,
the project. And um, I got
very hard marks obviously.
And um,
it was one of those breakthrough moments
where you have somebody that you look
up to tell you can't do something and
you are literally tasked with something
you've never done before and
somehow you persevere through it.
You asked for help, you,
um, you figure it out.
And on the other side of
that, I was sitting there in
this chair's thinking, wow,
like if I could figure this out,
what else could I figure out? Yeah.
Like this seemed like an impossible
feat before this whole thing started.
And here I am,
I'm sitting in these chairs,
the professors like beaming at me like,
and it was just like one of these,
these moments.
It did one has in life where you
sort of crossed a threshold of,
of understanding your limits.
And at that point I had a new,
a new bar or a new set of limits.
How did you feel for,
from the point that he said that for
the rest of the day, what, what did,
what did the rest of the day look like?
I mean, well first of all I was so tired.
I'd been up for, um, actually I hadn't
slept for about three days before that.
So over 48 hours I was without sleep.
Um,
so I was delirious a B
I was just so relieved.
And then third I was like,
there's the six excitement
inside of me was like, I just,
I just proved myself wrong.
Well what else can I
prove myself wrong on?
And suddenly it's like there was so much
possibility of anything at this point
forward that I come across.
It feels impossible.
I probably need to take a second look
at that and rethink that based on this
experience.
Because again,
like how do you make a chair and then
how do you make 16 full sized functional
chairs at the end of the pro
over a course of a semester.
And so what's cool is that
the bench has gotten stalled.
Students are sitting in them for, they
lasted for a couple of years after that.
And so the legacy of it, not we'll
only went to the benches, but the,
the story of what had happened became
his story that he told every class after
that. So that's, that's really
powerful and a bunch of levels,
right? I guess, uh, not only, and I have
to, I don't know the guy of course at all,
but I have to give the professor
credit for being willing to say, Hey,
like you proved me wrong.
Maybe as also just in that moment,
the power of that reinforcement for
you as it is a big deal. I mean,
that's a really big deal.
Potentially.
Life-Defining influction point of sorts.
Secondly,
the few things occurred to me. You
created eight. You also created a,
a product, an outcome that
people could use, right?
Versus a scale model.
And you created a story that would
then set the bar infinitely higher,
not necessarily the past fail mark,
but the,
you can fucking do this mark four
students for generations to come.
Like many, many classes to
come. That's a big deal.
I've said big deal a lot cause I think
you're a big deal Joe. Ah, it's true.
And uh,
one question that occurred to me while
I was listening to this was related to
the moment when he said that
you couldn't do it or you thought you
couldn't do it and how you responded to
that. It made me think of a story that I
heard from Alexis Ohanian Co founder of
Reddit when they went in early,
some relatively early in the development
of Reddit to meet with Yahoo.
And they were showing traffic numbers
and analytics to this Yahoo Exec.
And the Yahoo exact made this comment,
which probably to him or her at the
time didn't seem like a big deal,
but they said,
oh well this is a rounding error for us.
And to my recollection,
Alexis and his team,
in fact the office and they put you
are a rounding error up on the wall to
motivate the team,
but not everybody responds to what you
could view as a deathblow that way.
So where'd you get that from? Is
that from sports, from your parents?
Is it from somewhere else?
Is it just your programming?
Where do you think that comes from?
Just one source. I think sports
is definitely a way to, to,
if I had to point to something and played
so many sports growing up from tennis
to baseball to basketball, the track
and field and cross country. Um,
like some of those are team sports,
some of those are individual sports.
And in all of those,
I mean in any sport that's competitive,
you're trying to ultimately compete
with yourself to do a better performance
than you did the last time. Right. Um,
and so I looked at sports
as this constant. Um,
I was, I was in a game with myself and
like cross country was a great example.
That sport,
like for me was I feel like where I
honed my goal setting and was able to
practice pushing my limits. So every, um,
I would,
if I cross the finish line and I could
still really like walk and had energy to
me that was energy I could use on the
course through run a faster race. Huh.
And so eventually I got to this point
where I literally would collapse after the
finish line and it became so well known
that like the medics would be waiting
for me in that have the ice bags
and like they'd have like the,
the ivy just in case and like the parents
would be there to like pick me up.
And um, um, in the last, you know,
800 meters to the finish line,
I'd always try to find somebody who was
running a little bit faster than me and
I th I just would try to
accelerate to catch up with them,
draft them a little bit.
And then sometimes I'd be
neck and neck with them too,
like in the finish lines
with insight so close.
And I would just say out loud to
them, I'd say, you're not beating me.
You're not beating me.
And I'd,
I'd use that to motivate myself just to
try to run faster to get a better time.
That's amazing there.
I'm glad you brought up
the sports because Paul,
part of the reason I asked is that it in,
it's a slightly different lesson maybe
or one lesson that I took from sports.
I went to two different high schools.
The second high school I
went to had mandatory sports,
which I felt was really in retrospect,
important for a lot of kids and by
being forced to do various sports,
primarily wrestling in my case,
if you want to get better,
you're going to train with people who
are better than you. Yes. By definition,
you are going to be
beaten by other people.
And at least to my experts,
I started to view
any type of failure in that capacity
being beaten as feedback, right?
I mean you're, it's like a crit,
right? It's a, it's a, it's a,
it's a sports based crit. And, uh,
that's why oftentimes when a,
and if you have a good coach,
they're also going to be
pushing you beyond what your
perceived limits are. 100%.
Right. So you get into the habit, perhaps
subconscious or otherwise of asking,
is this impossible?
Really impossible because I never
thought I would break whatever,
six minute mile and I just did that.
And then I never thought I was gonna
break at five 30 mile and my coach just
helped me to do that.
Or I figured out this hack,
which is chasing the fastest person
in front of me and then saying,
you're not going to be me, are not going
to beat me. And then I collapsed on him.
Big Mess of a heap at the end button on
the last, hey, I just be five 30. Exactly.
Or whatever it is. Uh, and you, you
feel like you've, you've expanded it,
like you've,
you've pushed the limits of
what you thought was possible
within myself and that,
that for me it was like one
of the greatest feelings yeah.
That I had at that time,
which strikes me is that for me I didn't
have many vehicles for expanding that
capability. That was, that
was as tangible sports.
But design is super tangible,
right?
I mean you're building these chairs
and these benches and a should,
I should also just mention as
a side note that I want to,
I want to come back to [inaudible]
that I don't think it's ever too late.
People might be listening saying,
well hey,
I didn't have a great cross country
team or wrestling coach in high school.
So kind of up Shit's creek.
It's like no actually you can
still develop that, right.
With physical training and,
and other outlets to expand your
capabilities and your perception of what's
possible.
Sure.
And it's so funny cause that was a piece
of advice I got in seventh grade when I
started playing basketball. The
basketball coach said, Joe, Joe,
if you want to get better at basketball,
you need to play with people
who were better than you. Yeah.
And so when I used to go to the,
to the wide shoot hoops in the weekend,
I wouldn't play with
people my age or younger.
It actually play with the high schoolers
who were much bigger, much stronger,
much more talented than I was. And of
course I got pushed around and I'm like,
you know, you get bumped around
by guys who were, you know, um,
playing on the varsity team. But man,
my skills, the learning curve that year,
I feel like that was, that was like a,
another kind of threshold moment of like,
I'm not very good at basketball too,
actually. Okay. I've got some skills now.
And so I think since that,
since that moment,
I've always sought to try to find people
to play with who's better than me and
that'll certainly come up back
up when we talk about airbnb.
So the, so the Welshman yes. And
seeds, defeat gas, so to speak.
Um, I, I by the way, I, um,
I caught up for him with him,
caught up with him for a coffee about
12 years later and I had to ask them,
I'm like,
here's my experience of that conversation.
Like what the hell were you thinking? Why
didn't you get behind me? And he goes,
Joe, come on. I knew that if I told
you you couldn't do it, he would.
Oh you,
we have a great relationship.
And I seen him when I get back
to campus and it's very cool. So,
so phase shifts, you have that
experience, that experience
and is a great segway of sports
into my wrist experience.
I love basketball as we've
been talking about. And I,
I walked into the office of student
life one day and I go to the guy at the
front desk and say,
I want to play on the basketball team.
And he gives me this funny face and he
goes, we don't have a basketball team.
And all of a sudden there's
this like this awkward silence.
It was just staring at each other
and he breaks his silence by saying,
you can start one. If you want to and
you go, really what's involved in that?
And he goes, well, if you collect a list
of 12 other students that want to play,
bring it back to me. I'm like,
that's it. And I'm like, okay.
So I run off and they spent a week putting
a post up posters up around the dorms
and I gathered names of, you know,
11 other people play basketball.
It wasn't actually that hard. And
I come back to him like, okay cool.
Now when he goes, okay,
fill out this form,
take this to the student
government meeting on Wednesday
to get recognized as a
student organization. I'm like,
okay. So I go to the meeting,
I present the concepts, might have a
basketball team, here's the paperwork,
here's the names, here's the like what
we think we might need for a budget.
It gets pre approved from the student
government because then I'm like,
I go back to Mike, what's the
next step? He's like, okay,
well you need to find a gym. And, and so
one of these, one thing led to the other.
And that year we,
we started [inaudible] first basketball
team in 40 years and we started this,
this team,
it was like Hodgepodge Group of other
students and we would rent gym space at a
private high school in
Providence to go practicing.
And at this point we're just practicing.
Like we literally have,
there's no season and there's no games,
there's no other competition is
just us scrimmaging each other. And,
um,
we made some really basic uniforms
and just got things off the ground.
The next year when I came back to campus,
um, was, was different. I'm like, okay,
this year we're going to make a season,
we're going to play the teams. Like,
let's turn this into something.
Um, and so I get on the phone,
I start calling colleges in New England,
I'm calling community
colleges and you know, junior,
junior varsity schools. And, um,
I get on the phone with some of these
coaches and I introduced myself, hey,
this is Joe Gabby calling
from the [inaudible] on the
school basketball team and
I'd like to, hello? Hello.
Pretty much everybody's hung up on that
in the first couple of phone calls.
But then there was one college that took
my call on the ever forget it because I
had to sneak out of my graphic
design class to take the call.
It was a car key University
of Massachusetts and I'm
on the phone with their
head coach. He's like, yeah, okay cool.
Well we're not going to send down our
varsity team but I'll send my JV team and
I'm like, perfect, we'll
take it. So on December 4th,
2001 we had the first risky basketball
game Rizzy versus Clark University and at
this point like it's so informal for us,
we've got these basic meshed
jerseys that are like reversible,
basically a practice
uniform for anybody else.
And I'm a player coach leading the team
at this point and we're in not even her
own gym cause we don't have one in
some private high school gym around the
corner.
And the Clark University bus pulls up
and they're players start to get off the
bus and I'm going,
oh my God,
their shortest guy is taller than
our tallest guy. And they get it.
They had coach three assistant
coaches and a trainer comes off below.
It's just like 12 scrappy art school
students on the court with like Basic Mesh
practice jerseys. And I think what's the,
what's the coach came down to the court,
you kind of recognize what he got
itself into and he's like, oh boy.
And we had a few, I think about
150 fans Rizzy students show up.
That first game.
I say we got blown out.
It was [inaudible] 94 to 49 but in my
mind that was a huge win because we
establish something like we got a
team established and off the ground.
It's a real milestone at Rezidor.
Yeah.
And it was an incredible experience
next couple of years because it was like
running a startup, you know,
you had to put a team together,
you had to raise funding,
you had to create a brand in a market,
that brand yet to get
people into the games.
And one of the things I was most
proud of is that at Risley, the work,
the work loads are incredibly difficult.
And once you get into your majors, they,
you know,
they say like sometimes you never see
anybody again because they're just so
focused on, on the workload. And, um,
other than graduation,
the basketball games became the only
other time really during the year where
you'd have the full cross section
of campus under the same roof.
At the same time, students,
faculty, administration, um, uh,
professors,
alumni,
people from brown who were just curious
and want to come over and see what this
crazy Rizzy basketball team is doing.
And so it was this really cool moment
where you just bring people together.
And that was, I think really
the, the, the, the undertones,
the undercurrents of what
the teams really about. Sure.
It was about sport and competition and
staying in shape and the comradery of
being on the team. Second to that was
also about bringing people together.
Uh, thematically makes sense if we're
time traveling, looking forward. Yeah.
So that was a great experience.
Um,
I think a lot of people ask what the
name of the team is and um, you know,
because we're an art school,
we didn't have to have traditional names,
you know,
Rizzy and any art school is all about
self expression and I'm not holding back.
And so there was a legacy of names on
campus that all had a particular theme to
them. And so the hockey team on
campus, it's called the Nads.
So when you cheer it's go gonads.
And so when we started
the basketball team,
we had to sort of fall
in line with the theme.
So the team's called the balls and both
the nads in the balls are supported by
the jock straps versus the
cheerleading team. And, um,
there's a whole theme. I probably,
maybe we won't go into it here,
but there's like a whole theme of,
of sports at Rizzi that adds to the,
I think the, the levity and the humor of
it. Are they all testicle related? Um,
there was a, there was a, um,
I think there was a rowing team at
one point called the, uh, the shafts.
It might have been though the Lacrosse
team, I think it was called a shaft. So
it's a side note, side note
mix. I'm all caffeinated.
Do you know where the, the word avocado
comes from? And I don't, I'll tell you,
it comes from, I believe it's, I
want to say an older Mayan language,
but someone can correct me
on the Internet. I'm sure
they will. Comes from a word,
a Hakata t l at the end.
I'll cuddle and avocado grow on trees
hanging one lower than the other and
hairs. And uh, that means testicles.
So if you want to make a risky,
current Rizvi students who might
want to start another team,
you could go with the Avocados,
but it requires a bit of explanation.
What would that support be?
The most boring juggling
team and intramural juggling.
Remedial Juggling team juggling two, the
first and only juggling team in college.
So I have to ask,
because I've been wanting to
debut this question for a while.
We talked about crit, we've talked
about balls, which I think is a,
it's a bit of a reach,
but we can segway to buns.
When does CritBuns enter the picture here?
All right,
so it's freshman year at Risley.
I'm in a drawing class and the way it
works again is like he'd come in and it'd
be an eight hour class in the morning.
You'd pin your work up on the wall,
you're drawing assignment from
the week before, and he'd,
what do we spend all day critiquing it?
We're having to Kristen and people would
ask afterwards, how'd your crit go?
Oh Man, my crit was so hard and
my teacher was so rough on me.
Or like it didn't go well or it was great.
And about four hours in your picture
that the environment you're in,
an art studio, hardwood
floors, metal stools,
wooden benches for hours and have sitting
on these hard, uncomfortable surfaces,
your butt starts to feel it and
everyone's wiggling around trying to get
comfortable. So by the end of
the day, you're incredibly sore.
And I watch as my classmates exited the
art studio with this bun print on the
seat of their pants because
all the charcoal does paint
and ink that's on these
studio surfaces rubbed off onto her
pants. And sure enough, I look on mine,
my pants were ruined too.
So walking back to my dorm room and
thinking there's gotta be a better way
if we're going to enter these
credits for the next four years,
what have you had a seat cushion that
you could sit on to make you comfortable
and to keep you clean.
And so I got back to my dorm room,
I pulled up my sketchbook and I drew
that same bun print shape on the seat of
our pants and gave it some
dimension and I called it crit buns.
And you know at this point I had
no idea how to make a product.
That's just your first year of design
school. So I tucked the sketch away.
Now fast forward to five years later,
I've now done a dual degree in
graphic design and industrial design.
And at this point I know
how to make a prototype.
I know how to translate something
from a sketch book into, you know,
a real working prototype.
And so I make buns out of hard foam.
You can actually sculpted
out of the special foam.
And I have this full size hard, you
know, representation of the shape,
which is like,
you know,
two buns that come together and
there's a handle suits for portability.
I take that hard model,
I cast it in rubber and then I pour into
the cast a expanding polyurethane foam.
So when I took the lid off there was
looking back and meet the first soft
crippen's seat cushion
and it was great because now I could walk
around into my classmates, I could say,
hey, where do you guys think,
how much did you pay for this?
What kind of colors would you want?
And people of course had a cracked a
smile and they saw it and they had a good
laugh. Um, but I really hit a wall
because I had a one off prototype,
but I didn't know how to
get it to the next stage.
And I certainly didn't have the money
or the funds to do that on my own.
It was around this time my senior year
where I notice a poster on campus that
says, competition for the design
diploma. Submit your ideas here.
And at Risley they give you your degree
and paper to degree and they also give
the graduating class at
different object every year.
So I submit CritBuns for
the competition and it wins.
It gets selected to be given out to every
graduate from the [inaudible] classes.
He hasn't five which is like
freaking incredible. However,
they tell me this on May 1st graduation
is on June 1st that's not all the time
between that I have to deliver two
thesis projects for graphic design and
industrial design.
I definitely don't have time to take on
anything else is how many students are
in the graduating class.
It's about 600 600 so
I'm like, I'm so exuberant and
excited that like, oh my God,
they'll pay for the,
the the manufacturing of a couple hundred
cushions at the same time. I'm like,
how the hell am I gonna get this done?
Like there's absolutely no time.
And so I start, I get onto Google and I
researched. I searched foam manufacturers,
Tim,
I called every single search result for
the first 15 pages I was calling people
in India. I was comfortable in
England. I was called people in Texas.
I was calling people in California
and everybody said the same thing. Uh,
well son, um, you know,
it's going to take you about six weeks
just to make the metal mould and about
another four weeks for
production. Sorry, quick.
And I just went through everybody
who's getting no, no, no, no, no.
So then I went to my professors
in industrial design and
they also said this is
never going to happen in time.
Now I'm at this point,
the school is getting a little nervous
because the clock is ticking here.
And they call me and they say,
how's the project coming? And I'm like,
it's cool, don't worry. And they go, uh,
so it was going to happen. And
I'm like, probably. And they go,
well you have until Friday at five
o'clock to tell us if it's a go or none.
So I'm like, okay, and
what is this on a Monday,
on a Tuesday of this is like
Monday. Alright, so fast forward,
it's four o'clock on Friday afternoon.
I have no options.
Everybody's telling me no,
it's never going to happen.
It's impossible manufacturing and
take many, many weeks if not months.
And I'm like, I don't have that
many weeks. We've got three now.
And so I go outside the
industrial design building,
it's like a sunny afternoon and I'm
laying on the grass right on the,
on the river in Providence.
And I feel the breeze on my face,
the sound of the birds.
And I'm looking up at the sky
and I'm thinking to myself,
I have to figure this out. I can't,
I'm not going to give up on this.
What haven't I thought of yet?
Okay.
And I realized that the guy that runs
the metal shop in the industrial design
building, this Guy Steve, I
haven't talked to him yet.
So I run back in the industrial
design building. I go, Steve,
here's what's going on.
And he goes,
I've got this friend Sam up in Cumberland,
Rhode Island. He's got a tool shop.
Why don't you give him a call?
Maybe he'll help you up.
So I get on the phone with this guy, Sam,
and I just pour it out to him. I'm like,
Sam, this is what I want to
do. I give them every ounce
of enthusiasm that I have.
And at the end he goes, oh, you really
want this, don't you know, like yes,
whatever you can do. And he goes,
all right, here's what I'll do.
I'll move a couple of projects around.
If you send me the three d cad file today,
I can make the tool this weekend and send
it wherever you need me to send it on
Monday. And I'm like, Oh my God,
I'm going to call you right back.
Because I remembered there was a pool
float company that I spoke to the week
before in Connecticut who pool float.
So it's like they make like water wings
or whatever you would lay in and you
pull the noodles and the things that
float in water made out of foam.
And the guy told me, he said, well, I
remembered something. He goes, you know,
we can't make the mold in time,
but he finds somebody else,
we can produce the cushion.
And the other thing is it had to have
a silk screen on the top that said
[inaudible] 2005 on him.
And so I call back this Guy Christoph
at like 4:50 PM right on a Friday.
He should have been gone.
Like,
I don't know how I caught him still
in the office and I go, Chris, off,
it's Joe at rusty.
Like I found somebody to make them old.
He'll have it to you by Monday.
Can we make it work? And he goes,
you really want this,
don't you as whatever you can do.
And he goes, all right, here's
the address to send it to.
So I literally call the school back.
We might as well been five
o'clock and I'm like, we got it.
Here's where to send the Po, the
purchase order that, ah, two weeks later,
the day before graduation,
600 CritBuns showed up on campus
with a silkscreen on top that said,
Rizzy class in 2005
the day before it was impossible of how
do you make 600 CritBuns 300 read 300
blue with a silkscreen on top
in such a short amount of time.
And everybody's telling, you know, like
everybody just stared at me and was like,
this is never going to
happen. Um, I was exhausted.
It's gonna happen.
However,
it was so fun to see my classmates
running around with crit buns.
Everybody had a pair and like,
um,
it was really fulfilling and it was
worth all the effort and all the energy.
And I finished my two thesis successfully
on time and I got to graduate and
everything.
And while a lot of my classmates went
off to great jobs at some NASA doing
industrial design and summit,
um,
some of the big design firms
like ido and others, um,
I made a decision. I said, you know,
Rizzy and just design school in general
does such an exceptional job of helping
you come up with a creative process to,
you know,
think of really original creative ideas
there. They usually hit a wall though,
which is that you stop it at the
prototype and then you move on to the next
project.
And for me,
it built up this incredible desire
to figure out how did, how did,
how do you get to the shelf of a store?
Like,
how does your idea to transition from
that one off prototype all the way to the
shelf of the store? And so
I thought, well, I want to,
I want to decode this black box.
I have to figure this out.
So I made a decision that I was going to
use CritBuns to help figure out how you
get a product from an idea in your head
to a sketchbook, the shelf of the store.
So the day after graduation,
I started my first company
to make and sell CritBuns.
And the beauty of it is that I didn't
get paid for the graduation project,
but they gave me the metal
mould afterward, which is
a few thousand dollars.
So with the biggest expense out
of the way, I was off off the run.
So what happened? What
happened? A crypt punks,
why aren't you making crimp wants today?
So that summer I started to develop
the brand. I filed the patent,
which is design, has a design
patent on it, filed the
trademark and everything. And
I went back to the school that
summer and I said, you know,
that was so fun for the graduating class.
What if we did this for the incoming
class is a welcome to receive gift.
And they loved the idea and
they placed their first order.
And so on top of that order, I,
I tacked on my own inventory.
So I did this production run of I
think a thousand cushions, right?
And two things happen.
The first is that
there are now 400 students running around
campus with CritBuns actually using
them in the studios. I give the talk
to them, I could take photos of them,
I could actually start to build stories
and narratives around how they use the
product.
And second thing that happens is on there,
forget in my apartment in Providence,
in the basement of like this really old
kind of early 19 hundreds apartment.
Um,
I had about 10 boxes of hundreds of
CritBuns like filled up this entire room.
And I'm sitting there staring
at it. I'm thinking, oh boy,
nobody's coming to my
basement to buy these things.
I have to go to Allen's of the world
and Africa, how do I sell these things?
So I put together a sale sheet, um, and,
and I put on my best shirt in my best
shoes and like just the best kind of like
professional look that I could have.
And the first story I walked into was the
Brown University bookstore and I asked
for the store manager and we sit down
in this little conference room and I
started to go through
my spiel and I put the,
the sales sheet in front of her and a
sample of cushion and going through the
whole thing and a Mike,
you know,
given all my enthusiasm and about 30 or
so seconds in, she looks at me, she goes,
no thanks and gets up and leaves the room.
And I'm just sitting there,
this tiny little fluorescent
lit conference room by
myself with my cushion and
my sales sheet and no sale,
like actually pretty horrible rejection.
Um,
so I walked back to my apartment, very
slow walk, kind of like a Charlie Brown,
you kind of walk and,
and Athena myself. That sucks. I'm like,
how the hell am I going to sell these
cushions if that's the reaction I'm going
to get?
And it was in that moment where I
remembered this sales equation that I had
heard at this entrepreneur weekend at
Brown university that I snuck into one
time and the guy's talking gave this
equation for whenever you introduce a new
idea to the world.
It was an equation for receiving
rejection and how to move pass rejection.
And the equation was sw
squared plus WC equals m.
Oh wow. Hell of a memory here. I'll give
myself zero seconds. I already forgot it.
All right,
so most time sw square sw squared
must have seen SWC equals emo.
Alright,
so sw squared is some will love your idea.
Some waltz plus who cares equals move on.
He was the bucket. I like equation. So
I'm telling myself, okay, STB screw,
who cares? I just got to move on.
And so I did. I'm like, all right,
I'm just going to find another story.
Some people are going to love it,
some people aren't. It doesn't
matter. I just got to keep going.
I can't get hung up in one person saying,
no,
I need to go keep going until I find
it can find somebody that says yes.
So I went to the next door, they
said to him, went to third store.
They also said no.
I went to the fourth store,
which was this little tiny gift boutique
store on Thayer street in providence
sign affair. Yes. Had a Halloween, aren't
there? It's a hell of Halloween. It is.
That's crazy. Street of young for
Halloween. Um, so I go into the store,
I give them the pitch, the sales
sheet. Now at this point I'm,
I'm tweaking everything. I'm
iterating as I go. And the woman goes,
I'd love to bike. I love to
buy some cushions from you.
And I'm like, oh my God.
She goes, I'd love to buy
for, and I'm like, Themis,
I hell yeah, she could have bought
one and I would have been Abby.
So she starts to go to the thing,
well here's, you can ship them to,
and here's the address.
And I go, oh no, no, no.
I'll go pack them up and my house and
bring them back to you today. She's like,
really? I'm like, yeah. I ran home. I
packed up my cushion. I was so excited.
I gave them serum. I went back
later that night after they closed,
it's like it's dark on Thayer street.
I go to the front of the store and I
press my face against the cold glass and I
can kind of see my,
my breath in the glass and there's a
dim light on in the back of the boutique
that they're closed and I'm scanning
the store am squinting and there it is.
I can see CritBuns on the
shelf of the store. I'm like,
yes,
like I did it.
Like everything after that
point was downhill like I,
it was like I knew how to walk into a
store and you had to talk to him downhill,
downhill. Good sense, like you're
pushing the ball downhill. Right? Right.
Before I was like trying to climb
up hill against all these obstacles.
Now it was just like coasting downhill.
Now,
was that because you had the skills or
because you did proven to yourself that
you could do it? It to
myself, I could do it.
Is that like one proof point for cushions,
for cushions on the shelf of the store.
I'm like Hallelujah. Somehow it happened.
Um,
now I have like even more confidence to
walk into a store and meet with a buyer
and ask the question now
what's the process to get a
new product into your store?
And they could sit down with
them and talk about the products,
how original it was.
Um,
so I make trips to Boston and talked
to stores there. I go down to New York.
I talked to Pratt and he talked
to um, school, visual arts,
talked to Parsons. Um, um,
I talked to more stores and Providence
who was the furthest away you traveled to?
Soccer Ponds? When I go home
to Atlanta for the holidays,
it's all that stores in Atlanta.
I mean everywhere I went I was
always carrying a cushion with me.
I talked to anybody about it. Right?
It was like everybody I talked to,
I just practicing the sales pitch. And
just as to get comfortable with it. Um,
so at that product, in that
concept, just, you know,
it was never meant to be anything huge.
It was just meant to be Grad school in
essence to help teach me like the whole
stack of product development because I
was doing everything out of my apartment
from the distribution, the packaging,
the fulfillment, the website, the press,
like everything was run for my desktop
computer next to my bed in my bedroom.
Um, and so I got like in a very micro,
very small scale, I get the full,
you know, ecosystem of what it means
to run something. Obviously the,
a very small manageable
scale, which is perfect. Um,
and so one of the,
one of the defining moments was
I set a goal for myself. I said,
what's the store shelf that
would be the pinnacle for me.
Like what would I just
be the most proud of?
And one of the most heralded shelves
for any designer to get on is a shelf at
the design store, at the Museum of
Modern Art in New York City. Huge, huge.
I mean there's legends are there
like you can get IEM stuff,
you can get George Nelson stuff, you can
get like the greats of the greats, right.
Along with modern things of course.
And so I set my goal. I'm like,
I'm going to figure out how to
get crit buns into the Moma store.
And after two years of just not giving up,
I finally got my first order for Moma.
I will never forget that phone call.
Okay.
Now you are clearly gifted
or you've developed and
cultivated gifts with art and
design.
You've also had a lot of practice
pitching right through good and bad,
experiencing rejection and acceptance.
So what,
what got you the acceptance
and what was the, what was the,
what was the, what was the pitch?
What was the process?
At a certain point I think they realized
I wasn't going to going to go away.
And you're like, all right, let's just,
just easier to let this guy, he knows.
I never, I never asked him,
but the product that I'm
stolen out of their store.
Did you sell? Did you sent people
there to buy them? I didn't have to,
but I remember going,
I definitely made a trip down to New
York after I shipped him the order and I
walked in and there it was
in the shelf for the moment.
I took a picture and I just thought like,
wow,
like this seemed if you,
if you,
if I had told myself three years earlier
that I would have made a product that
would be on the shelf of the Moma store,
I would have said you're crazy. Like,
that's impossible.
So what gave you the,
the Chutzpah to pursue it for two years?
And was it the fact that you'd,
I think it was just so many impossibles
that you'd prove impossible yourself?
Was it something else?
It was just wanting to experience it.
That feeling like what I imagined
it might feel like if I were to ever
accomplish something that was so,
it's such a stretch goal for me. Um,
I don't know,
like I just the dough off the
relationship with the buyer at the time.
And I think that just evolved into
an order eventually in, um, you know,
at that point like, wow,
what was next, right.
Was that, now I'm going to prompt one
thing because it just popped into my head.
Was Moma before or after?
I want to say trade show in Japan.
It was before. It was
before. Yes. We can't,
I only remember bits and pieces of this,
but can you describe? Yes. Japan.
So the product ended up taking me
around the world and this was still for
colleges? Well, no,
I mean this is for any kind of gift
fair or any kind of event where there's
other designers selling their things.
So I got connected with this
website called design boom.com,
one of the biggest design
blogs in the world.
And they had this thing called
the gift, the Gift Mart. Um,
and they basically would invite designers
from around the world to come sell
their things at these big design week
events where it'd be really hard to afford
access to it as an
independent young designer.
They would kind of create
that opportunity for you,
pay for the booth where they actually
have the entire span of small fee to pay,
but nothing like the actual costs. And
so they subsidize it to make it possible.
And so I got involved in that and
it took me all over the place.
I traveled Sydney, Australia
where I sold the cushion. Um,
I traveled to New York and I traveled
to Tokyo for design week one year.
And this was fascinating because I got
to experience what it was like to sell
the cushion in person to
directly to consumers.
It's one thing to sell to a store manager
than it is to sell to actual customer.
Very different.
The other thing was [inaudible] has
these events where the alumni can come
together and sell their creations with
its ceramics or furniture products.
And so at this point I had figured out
after hundreds of interactions with
people face to face,
you know,
I designed my stand with the cushions
and a big sign said CritBuns, you know,
supporting creativity where others can't.
And um, I actually have seen
it so many times at this point.
I was able to break the sales
process down into five steps.
There were five stages to
the crip on sales process.
The first stage is what I call the,
what the hell is that stage where
people are walking by and they do this
doubletake and they look at it
and they're like, what is that?
But the shape and the color is
interesting enough to draw them in.
And so then they get to stage two,
which is called the touch and feel phase.
They grabbed the product off the stand,
they squeeze it, they realize it's soft.
The first smile, because also
my dating process, by the
way, please continue. They,
they kind of get a smile on their face
and they flip it over and they interstage
three which is the story phase.
So on the back of the package,
I tell them the story, you
know, in a couple of wines,
you know how the product was concepted
how has created who made it and she sees
him reading the story,
ah,
and then they smile and they make the
connection of why the thing is the way it
is.
Then they're stage four.
Step number four is tried and true.
I've seen this everywhere.
They immediately started going like
this with a cushion. They're here,
they're looking around cause
they want to try it out.
Does it deliver what it
says it's going to do?
Does it make any hard
surface more comfortable.
So I always have a demo chair
nearby for people to try it out.
And so people sit down on it
and as they're sitting on it,
I had a chair next to them
and I had s we never did them.
And I figured out the question to ask,
I asked somebody,
how do you see this
fitting into your life?
And what's amazing is that people told
me all kinds of different uses that I
never even imagined for the cushion
was actually 35 different uses for it.
People use it for camping trips,
people take it to baseball games.
Soccer moms love it for their kids.
Um,
pregnant women love it cause it takes
pressure off your tailbone and he sit down
cause it's got a dip in the middle people
with sky article of it because again,
the dip in the middle,
it takes pressure for tailbone.
I went so many uses for the thing just
by asking people that question and the
minute that people could connect it to
something that's important in their life,
there's a very high percentage that they
bought it in 1999 it like it wasn't,
you know, huge commitment bank
breaker. So that was stage four,
stage five I never could have predicted.
And this was really the
magic of learning what,
it's not only about a product
but it's about a story as well.
I would literally watch people
buy my product. They'd stand up,
they turned the next person in line.
He'd say, what the Hell is that?
And the person who just bought it would
literally tell them verbatim the story
of on the back of the package,
he would sell the product for me.
I would just sit back and watch this
happen and I'm like, this is amazing.
And I realized the power
of story in that moment,
that design is more than just a product.
It's more than just you know,
digital experience. It's that
cushion is 50% foam in 50% story.
It was a really valuable lesson and so
I used like I learned from that every
time that I went to these different
events. So here we are in Japan,
we're in Tokyo and it's really exciting.
My first time to Japan,
unlike thrilled like my senses are just
like overwhelmed with everything about
Tokyo.
And I'm at this five day
design events for design week.
This is back in late 2008 2007 and
so I go out there with 40 cushions,
which are these two giant
boxes like these, they take
up a lot of volume, right?
And I'm like,
I take those things on the plane and
then I take them through the Tokyo subway
system and like it's really
awkward because you can't carry,
you have to like drag them.
And it's like, I'm like this
know for those people who
haven't been to Tokyo,
every once in a while we all encounter
a subway car that has lots of space.
That is not the default.
Uh,
particularly if you're going
during any busy period,
there are in fact certain stations
where they have attendance.
Wearing white gloves will push people
into the cars so that the doors can close
and it's sardines in a can.
So I'm just imagining you dragging these
judge.
I've got my big backpackers backpack.
I've got these two giant cardboard boxes
of 20 CritBuns each that are like heavy
and awkward and trying to navigate
than the narrow subway system of Tokyo.
And I get to my setup at the,
at the design fair and I've got this
little tiny folding table to my left and
Ryan all around me or other
designers as part of design boom.
And I'm so excited as people
come walking up on day one,
I started talking to them to try to
tell them the story and nobody speaks
English.
And by the end of day one,
I sold a total of zero CritBuns
and we're thinking to myself,
oh my God, this is, this is not good.
I'm definitely not going
home with 40 cushions.
I need to change my strategy here
because this is not going to work.
The story's not translating the power
of the story that works so well,
has no impact here whatsoever.
So thankfully through the young designer
next to me is Japanese and we struck up
a friendship that's going to be
together for the next couple of days.
And I'm like, I, I'm have a problem
here. I need to translate these things.
She's like,
well,
I can help you translate if you
want to make any written materials.
So it designed this poster overnight,
this giant poster that is all in
Japanese with pictures of CritBuns.
Um, I had a picture of a stadium seat
with an Arrow pointing to it and you know,
stadium seat seating in Japanese and then,
um, and somebody kneeling in a garden,
um,
I had somebody meditating on it and um,
she was so kind that to translate for me.
I ran to Kinkos at night,
got it printed in downtown Tokyo.
Uh,
and the next day I had this beautiful
poster that did all the explanation and
had demo chair printed out in
Japanese on the demo chair.
And one by one somebody actually
made a sale and I was like,
oh my God, okay, this is going to work.
And then I had another guy who actually
happened to be a [inaudible] Grad who
was there just visiting.
He spoke Japanese and he's like,
if you will help translate, I'm happy to
do this for you. So, uh, bless his heart.
He was amazing.
He actually would like draw people
over to my little folding table with my
stacks of CritBuns everywhere.
And he would tell the story in Japanese
and I'll never forget the last day.
It was like towards the end of the day,
I mean he's Sorta kind of closing down
and we sold the last pair of buns and
there's this picture of him and I sitting
there at this empty table being like,
oh my God,
I can't believe he did it.
So I was able to pay for my trip basically
when the sale, these crit ones. Um,
and it was just a great lesson in like
having to figure out how to translate
your story beyond just, you know,
English speakers in my case. Um,
that, that was a role into
an experience. So man, that,
that project took me all over the place.
I got to meet the guy who
invented the foam finger. Sure.
Gerald Foss, who's here in Texas, um, uh,
to see if he wanted to do
manufacturing at one point. Um,
he'd go into his lobby and he's got like
the original foam finger from the 1970s
in the glass case. Right.
Totally random. Um,
I got to meet the late Billy
Mays. Oh, infomercials.
Oxyclean so I applied at one, many, many
more. Hey, I'm Billy Mays. We'll cover,
we're going to show you this
right now. And um, there was, uh,
the reality show at 1.4 inventors
and people that made products,
for some reason I was inspired
to submit CritBuns. Um,
and so I flew to la when one weekend and
I'm in this like lobby for the casting
with all these other inventors
and everybody like really
stuff like we'll have
stuff for cats. I feel like pet cats
like running around and, and like,
it's like a lot of pet stuff and
there's me like in one of my best shirts
holding my coupons,
like really proud.
And the priest comes over and they
mic me up and they're like, okay,
we want you to walk down that hallway
and go through those double doors.
And that's all they said. And so I'm
like, okay. So like on my products,
proud entrepreneur here,
I walked down the hallways to stick dark,
the lights were off this dark hallway,
all he can see,
he's like these two
eliminated doors at the end.
And I opened the doors and they're,
this huge conference table is
Billy Mays and one other Costar.
And then there's like all these cameras
and all these lights pointed at you.
He goes, Hey, I'm Billy. Nice. Come on in.
And I sit down in the chair and
suddenly among this like pitch session,
it was like shark tank before
shark tank. Right? Right.
Like I'm having to pitch him on
why my product so great. And um,
it wasn't going so well
until he tried it out and he like how she
got up and he sat down and 40, he goes,
oh yeah, that's what, this is a
pretty good. And, and then they said,
okay, thanks. And like
I walked out, it's like,
it's like blitz of like five minutes
of just pitch mode and what was like
getting peppered with all these questions
and all these lights on you and this
camera's,
I did not get on the show,
but it was just one of these crazy moments
of like these unexpected things that
this product, these experiences that
this project brought me see soon.
Why are you not,
why are you not the the Titan of the
CritBuns empire? Why did you stop?
So coupons,
this goes back to [inaudible].
I switched from being in painting to
being in industrial design largely in part
because I learned about
Charles and ray Eames,
two designers from the mid 20th century
that were a couple raves. The wife,
Charles is the husband and they
produce design that it's legendary.
It's still referenced today.
It's in the,
it's in the Moma and the
permanent collection.
It's iconic and they dedicated their lives
to producing the best designed to the
most people for the least price.
And they were really celebrated for
democratizing good design and making it
accessible.
I'd also add that the chair project
with Garth Jones and fell in love with
making things and realize that I
wanted to switch from this more um,
uh, creative pursuit of
painting, which was more about,
you know, the expression of,
of ideas through that medium into the
expression of ideas through industrial
design, which was cool to me because you
can make something objects and it can be
replicated thousands, hundreds,
thousands, millions of times.
You could actually touch millions of
people with your designs just like the
Eames had. And so this was my motivation
to switch into industrial design.
You could use design to improve people's
lives and it can be done at scale.
You could touch a lot
of people all at once.
And so [inaudible] and the industrial
design department did something brilliant.
Our first year in the program,
they put us all in in the the school
vans and they drove us out to the Rhode
Island state landfill.
And here we are
driving through these canyons of trash.
Like you have your faces pressed up
against the bus window and you can't even
see it at the top, well of the
landfill for, for the state.
And you get out to the top and you're,
you get out of the vans and you're looking
back over this just in a landscape of
garbage. And for me it hit me like
a ton of bricks. I'm like, wow.
Like I do not want to spend my life making
things that contributes to making the
landfill better, bigger. That
is not interesting to me.
It was like a really
impactful moment where I just,
I started to feel a slight sense
of guilt that I was now studying.
Um,
a discipline that is about making more
stuff and so it really kicked off this
enthusiasm or consciousness around how
do you make stuff that's environmentally
considered cradle the cradle cradle to
cradle. Yeah. I build Mcdonald's book,
which was also came in around
this time was hugely influential.
National capitalism kind of
came around in this time. These,
they're starting to be this,
this other way of thinking about
how we consume things in the planet.
And certainly I've,
you feel a responsibility as a designer
because you're pretty close to the
origins of those things. Sometimes
you don't decide the strategy of hey,
we need to make this product,
but you're definitely in it in the field
of view of being able to decide what
kind of materials to use, what's the
whole life cycle of a product. And so,
um,
with CritBuns I actually
delayed the launch of that
for six months because I was
trying to find a phone that was
environmentally considered and I called
everybody.
I sh I was talking to people in the
Midwest making foam out of soy beans.
At one point I found a woman in England
who started making plastic at a bubble
gum that you scrape off of the sidewalk.
Um,
but I couldn't find anybody that made a
phone that was perfect for the product.
So I decided to go forward the products
and that sparked this other idea,
which was, okay. Um, I've
learned two things from this. A,
the foam doesn't exist and be,
there's wasn't even a good source to
try to find the film in the first place.
Right?
Like Amazon was starting to really
emerge at this time and it was so easy to
find a book on Amazon or like content.
I was like,
why isn't there a site where you
can find sustainable materials?
I talked to some of my classmates that
we had graduated this point and um,
became very clear that whether you're
an architecture or fashion design or
package design or industrial design,
there was a growing consciousness around
we want to feel good about the things
that we're making. And so I realized
I'm not a material scientist.
Maybe I'm not going to invent the foam.
However, I know how to make a website.
So what if I started a site that would
allow any designer to connect with the
sources of Siena materials with
his bioplastics or you know,
reclaimed class or you know,
organic cotton.
And so a classmate and
I partnered up together,
but he named Matt and we created this
website to help solve our own problem of
having access to sustainable materials.
And um,
you know,
the site started in,
it was this combination of ecology
and in intellect. So we called it,
he collect and it was basically Google
for sustainable materials and we'd find
manufacturers around the world
and we plug them into the system.
And I was basically like a really high
in search engine and community for people
who cared about this topic.
So slowed down crit buns to
work on this website. You know,
the thing is that the,
the product remained.
I had figured out manufacturing abroad.
Um,
the [inaudible] website was up,
is getting press at this point from around
the world is getting blogged about I
shipping orders out of my garage this at
this point and moved to San Francisco.
My garage became CritBuns headquarters
and it got into some of the big catalogs
in the u s when it was called solutions
catalog. Just went out to like,
I don't know,
hundreds of thousands of homes.
And I had these orders
flowing in like my garage.
I had to employ some friends to come
help pack up CritBuns these orders of
hundreds at a time. It was insane. Um,
great learning experience and um,
you know,
in fact him something
Brock for you today. You kidding? Have
the original pair. Oh my God.
[inaudible] for you, my friend. Amazing.
This is incredible. Thank you so much.
Oh my God. Look at this very welcome.
Critbuns a seat cushion for artists
and designers for the love of the crit.
And then on the back we've got
buns TM. These buns approved
for use on hard surfaces. Buns,
not a life saving air flotation
device. Good, good note.
They're intended solely
for cheek to cheek comfort.
Amazing. Thank you. You get
the story on the back of the
label. Oh yeah. Here we go.
The crip on story hours of critiquing
from the cold hard dirty floor and give a
young design student more than a sore bum
provided the inspiration for a
better way. Colon, a seat cushion,
offering day long comfort and cleaner
pants to art students worldwide.
The name and shape they
originated from the charcoal bun.
Print students left behind a
metal stools and hardwood floors.
Dubdubdub critbuns.com the term crit
slang for critique is the presentation of
students' artwork before professors and
peers and is a staple of every art and
design school experience.
Wait a minute,
my favorite part.
So you've got pat spending trademark
copyright 2005 zero six juice studios LLC
critiqued in USA.
All rights reserved.
Drop us a line high brow@critbuns.com
printed with soy ink approved by the CBB.
O D I don't know what that is.
And then you have a bunch shaped
barcode on the back for scanning.
This is great man.
I can see how the chairs already pretty
soft, but it is already pretty soft.
I think I'll, I will save this for my
traveling hard surface experiences.
Thank you.
You're very welcome.
So Crippen's sorta is slowing down but um,
it's funny.
Every so often I still get an order. I
still get down to the garage still still.
I still pack it up and
ship it out and you know,
life's changed quite a bit since then,
but it's,
it's a great reminder for me of like
those early days and I have just hustling.
I was trying to get stuff done of like
the enthusiasm and the exuberance of,
of bringing an idea to life.
Like it was a rush.
And then you go from physical to digital.
What did you learn from the he collect
experience? Well, equal
like launched at a time,
and this might be hard to understand now,
but if you go back 10 plus years around
2007 web 2.0 it's happening on the
Internet and revenue is not cool.
Right? It's crazy thing. The new economy.
Webster point in our revenue was a cool
eyeballs, bought some cool traffic,
was great,
but the revenue didn't matter.
And so unfortunately we subscribed to
that as well with equal act and our
service is free and um,
we didn't make any money on it.
We bootstrapped the whole thing
and never took investment on it.
And the one thing that we did innovate
on that actually did make money for us is
we call it the green box.
The green box was basically like a
physical magazine that we shipped out on a
quarterly basis that allowed people to
build an actual materials library for
themselves.
So we sip ship actual samples with these
beautifully designed placards that gave
you all the information about it
with a special integrative hook.
So you can imagine a whole wall of
materials that you'd have in your design
studio or your design team in
house or consultancy, whatever.
The thing was that even at
design school for materials,
our brain and that did all right,
except it was so laborious.
I'd be down in the garage,
like zip tying things together
and have design all these cards.
And then get the stickers
and then like it just,
it took way too long versus
on how much we made. Um,
and so around this time I also have
a day job. What's Your Day job?
My Day job was I got a fellowship,
um,
from a book publisher
called Chronical Books. Yes.
And they had a fellowship, which is a
six month program for recent graduates.
Typically for graphic designers, they
introduced one for industrial designers.
I'm thinking, oh my God, this is perfect.
I've got a graphic design background
as well. Conoco makes beautiful,
beautiful books. They're books are
like objects, right. They really,
what I learned there was a about
the importance of detail and craft.
Now by fellowship,
I mean that sounds like you're
given a stipend to pursue your art,
but are you also, it was like a
glorified intern, glorified intern guy.
Much more attractive when
you call a fellowship.
It is much more desirable and it worked.
And I got that role for six months
and um, had a great time there. Um,
really got to work a long sentence
and worldclass graphic designers.
So that's how you're paying the bills.
While you're offering this free service.
And um, I eventually get in
a full time offer to take it.
And so I'm there doing industrial design
work, working on, on packaging for,
for high end books.
So they did the book for George Lucas
and star wars and I got to design the,
you know, the really high end case of
this book was huge. We'd like, you know,
it was like 20 pounds. It's like one of
those really thick coffee table books.
Did the package for Hugh Hefner.
He did a book on the centerfolds every
center fold since 1954 I believe,
starting with Marilyn Monroe.
And so I got to design this custom leather
briefcase that this book came in with
the blind and boss of the, um, the
playboy bunny on the front. Anyway,
there's a lot of cool projects there,
but at certain point equal collected
was growing and I realized it needed my
full time efforts. And so I made
a decision. I said, you know, um,
I need to either stick with this job,
which is getting very
comfortable at that time,
or I need to take this plunge insert
to really doing the startup full time.
And so, um, I quit my job since 2007,
2008 [inaudible]
job equal x and CritBuns full time.
And around this time the rent goes up in
her apartment and it's around this time
that my former classmate,
Brian Chesky museum with me,
you'd be my roommate and this is for
shadowing another major event in my life,
but we won't get there
just yet. All right. Um,
so make this plunge of stepping
into equal act and CritBuns.
Now all of this,
while I'm now living in San Francisco and
the thing is since high school,
since the first.com when
I was living in Atlanta,
I would come home every day and I would
be enthralled at the stories that I was
reading about of all these Internet
companies that were starting. You had, um,
you know,
Ebay and Amazon and Yahoo and excite.com
and Lycos and like there was so much
entrepreneurial spirit and I had this,
I had the sense that one day
I wanted to run my own thing.
I didn't know what was going to be
maybe as a gallery or something,
who knows if it was like what
kind of business it would be.
It's a chronicle was my
path out to San Francisco,
which is where I always wanted to be
because the first.com all paths lead back
to the, to the bay area. Oh
for sure. Right. And I'm like,
well that seems to be the place to go
if you want to get it off the ground.
And so I finally move out there.
I bring crit buns with me.
I bring the equalize concept with me
and I'm living in San Francisco and
during [inaudible] I had this,
this radar on in the back of my
mind that people that I met with,
friends that I made,
I sort of like trying to find somebody
else who had similar aspirations that I
did.
Somebody else who may want to co found
something with me in the future one day
and I can be a partner in
a business of some kind.
And so at the end of [inaudible] there
were very short list of people that I
felt I would just absolutely
love to start something with.
The guy at the top of the list
was this guy named Brian Chesky.
We got to know each other through sports
on campus because I ran the basketball
team, he ran the hockey team. So we
got to know each other via sports.
And there was one project that we had
together in industrial design were um,
it was for a client in the haircare
space and we got to reinvent haircare
products like blow
dryers and curling irons.
And for the final presentation,
Brian and I went in with this team and
our concepts were so wildly different
than everybody else's that I remember
looking at him being like, wow,
like this guy, when we're
in a room together, we can
do really creative things.
And as the year went on
and before we graduated,
I just had this growing feeling that like,
there's something special about this guy.
He knew how to rally people together.
He knew how to get them excited.
Uh,
he had his own project around fitness
that he got people to volunteer their time
to help do design on and marketing on.
And I just remember being
really inspired by him.
And it's the night before graduation,
he's about to move to Los Angeles.
I'm about to, you know, um,
I was gonna stay in providence
to work on crit buns
and I decided to invite him out to
dinner to tell him how I feel about this.
And so over a slice of pizza
on Thayer street. I tell
him, and Brian, I go, Brian,
I just want you to know, I think we're
going to start a company one day.
I think they're gonna write a book about
it. And he kind of laughed it off, Huh?
Yeah, yeah. And um, he ends
up going to Los Angeles.
I ended up finding my way to San Francisco
via chronicle books and very quickly,
once I'm in San Francisco,
recognize that it is in fact an
epicenter for entrepreneurship.
There's so much activity
going on around me.
Web 2.0 is like the web is back and
I'm start calling them like, Brian,
I know what's going on in la,
but you gotta get up here.
Like there's so much activity,
so much action happening
here. And he's like, yeah,
yeah,
I got some stuff going and like this
one on for at least a year of trying to
recruit him to get up to San Francisco.
And so at a certain point,
the roommates that I was living with
moved out and I'm left with this three
bedroom apartment and I call him like,
Brian,
I've got a room available. It's now
or never, if you're going to move,
this is the perfect
window to come up here.
I've got a room waiting for you with your
name on it and have to give him a lot
of credit. He made a courageous
move. He quit his job,
he packed his life into his Honda Civic.
And he drove from Los Angeles to San
Francisco, became a roommate, asks,
sorry Tim. There was this
incredible excitement in the air.
Like it's like the band is back together.
All right, what are we going to do?
Like what could we
possibly create together?
And this is the same week that
I quit my job at chronicle.
I've got CritBuns and he
collected in the background.
We're going to come up with something
big together. Uh, Brian and I,
and that's when I opened the mail.
One day,
that same week he arrives as a
letter from my landlord and it says,
Dear Joe,
your rent is now 25% higher.
And I run to my online bank
account and I see that, um,
I should not have enough money in the
bank because I have no paychecks coming in
to make rents.
Brian has the same problem and suddenly
our backs are against the wall.
This is like this dark,
stormy cloud that forms of her apartment.
All the enthusiasm's gone.
Now it's just terror and fear.
How are we not going to get evicted next
month? We need to make the rent check.
And that's what I'm
sitting in my living room.
One day that week I've got my laptop
open and I'm looking at the website for a
design conference for industrial designers
coming to San Francisco, you know,
two weeks later and it
says in big red letters,
hotels are sold out in San
Francisco. I'm thinking, Oh man,
what a bummer for somebody
who wants to come last minute.
They've got nowhere to stay.
And I glance over the top of the laptop
screen into the vast space of the living
room and start to think,
what if I pull my air bed out of the
closet and blowed up on the four?
We could host a designer for less than
the cost of hotel and maybe make some
money to make our rent check.
So email Brian,
and he loves the idea.
We actually get to more airbeds and we
start to think through this experience.
What if we offered airport pickup?
What if we gave them a map to San
Francisco in a bart pass at subway and we
cooked them breakfast in the morning.
And so we created this concept
called the air bed and breakfast.
We made a website, air bed and
breakfast.com it was four pages,
pictures of us pictures of their beds.
We talked about the neighborhood and we
were so proud of her website except who
the hell on earth knew who to go to?
Air Bed and breakfast.
Not exactly a high volume search term.
Right.
So one night we realized that
we have a marketing problem.
The conferences coming up pretty quick,
I mean you get the word out.
So we email the design blogs,
the top design blogs that were covering
the conference and neither of us had
really been on design blogs before other
than equal act and crit buns and it was
kind of a hail Mary.
We just sent these emails out to like
press tips at [inaudible] dot com the next
morning we came down,
we opened our computers and Tim,
it felt like Christmas there.
We were at the top of the design blogs
with headlines like need a place for the
conference this weekend crash with
Joe and Brian and there's some a loft.
Amazing networking. Your jam jam
is on an air bed and breakfast.
And this idea that we had a week or two
earlier was now being blogged about to
the world in the design community.
And so they responded.
We had emails from all over the world,
from Brazil, from England, from Japan,
of people dying to have one of
these airbeds in our living room.
People started sending us their linkedin
profiles and this design portfolios and
the resumes being like,
I was trying to convince us to pick them
to be one of the lucky three guests.
Amazing. At one point, my phone rings
with an area code that was unfamiliar.
I didn't answer it.
Suddenly have a voicemail,
I'm listening to the voicemail and it's
this guide named a mole who's telling me
he's going,
my name's mole.
And I just saw the air bed and breakfast
concept and I have to stay with you
guys, call me back. Uh, I, I have to
stay at the air bed and breakfast.
Here's my phone number.
And then in my inbox I've got like
two emails from this guy. I'm like,
how did he find me information?
Um,
so I called him back and he sends
his design portfolio checks out.
He's a Grad student at Arizona State
University studying industrial design and
he becomes our first guests and
then we accept two other people.
One woman named Kat and another
gentleman named Michael.
All were over the age of 30 cat was
a single soul traveler from Boston.
Michael was a 45 year old husband and
father of five from Utah and there was all
this excitement when the guests arrive.
It's like, you know, we made sure the bed,
the air beds were properly inflated.
There was a mint on the pillow.
Like we cleaned the place up in advance,
we stock the fridge with Oj and
bagels and you know, fresh eggs.
And we had everything ready
to go as to tell you Tim,
the next couple of nights were just some
of the most exciting cause this thing
unfolded that we didn't expect, which
is that, yeah, we made some money on it,
but more than that week we became friends
with them and we really get to show
them San Francisco through the lens of,
of us through our favorite things to do,
our favorite places to eat.
Imagine the difference of this yard,
a conference,
and at the end of the day you can retire
by herself to a hotel room that maybe
is so much generic or lacks and general
personality or why they came back to our
apartment, which was lively.
We're cooking dinner together.
We're sharing stories from
our days at the conference.
It was like night and day for them
and they had such a good experience.
We took her to her friend's house
parties after the conference some nights.
We took them to the best burritos in the
mission district to the farmer's market
at the ferry building
one morning. And, um,
at one point we gave during great
place to take visitors very building.
There was a Pechakucha talk
during the conference, Eric,
who's a Woah at what chocolate you,
it's that,
it's that format where you have 20
slides in like four minutes I've right.
And so I just moved and you got to give
a quick presentation and so we gave a
presentation about air bed and breakfast
in the moment that we're hosting people
in air bed and breakfast and we had our
guests up there with us and talked about
this concept that came together,
you know,
two weeks ago is now actually
unfolding in front of us right now.
And it was just like really met a moment
where the guests are now part of the
presentation about themselves
and it was totally insane.
Let's step five of the CritBuns
Aka airbnb sales process.
You're the story. So I'll never
forget when saying goodbye to them.
The door click closed and I
look at Brian and I'm like,
did we just get paid to make friends?
And that Tim is when
the gears began to turn,
maybe there were other people like us
who would also enjoy sharing their extra
space with people coming to their town
and want who want a local experience.
And so we told my previous roommate Nate,
who I found on craigslist, he was a
computer science graduate from Harvard
who when he moved out,
Brian moved into his room.
And now Nate story with him is we lived
together for a couple of months and at
night we come home from our day jobs and
we were working on our own projects in
the living room.
I was working on CritBuns.
Nate was working on his own
startups and it was remarkable.
I'm looking over my shoulder thing
and wow, this guy loves to work.
We have similar work ethics. And I'm like,
if I ever need a computer programmer,
I'm going to call a neat little did I
know that Nate was thinking the same thing
about me. Pretty designer McAllen, Joe.
So Nate moves out,
Brian moves in and after this one weekend,
um,
yeah,
a couple months actually passed
and we didn't move on the concepts.
We went home for new year's that year.
This is 2007 so it happened in October.
We go home for new years in,
in 2007 and in their invariably
people ask you, hey, how's it going?
What are you working on? What's
going on in San Francisco? Um,
and like were entrepreneurs and they
go, great, what are you entrepreneurial?
And I didn't really have a lot going on.
Coupons is kind of their eclipse kind
of, you know, uh, struggling along. Um,
there's no funding at this point.
But I did tell people about this crazy
weekend where he had these three guests
on airbeds in our apartment and it
was remarkable what happened next.
People either leaned in and he
went, oh my God, that's amazing.
I would love to travel
and stay with the vocal.
And the other half of the people
went, oh my God, you're crazy.
You had a stranger in your home.
What were you thinking?
And this lake visceral reaction that the
cause people in these conversations was
like, wow, like this really gets
people fired up and either direction,
maybe there's something here. It's a
Brian. And we come back in January.
Brian comes back, he's from New
York, upstate. He comes back and um,
we sh we had similar experiences. He's
like, yeah, I told people about it.
Any of that loved it or hated it. And
we're like, yeah, like maybe we should,
maybe this is the idea that we should
expand on. So we're like, okay,
we know we need a real programmer. So I'm
like, well, I'm going to call an Natan.
So get a drink with Nate.
I tell him about this crazy weekend with
these three guests. Nate loves the idea.
He's like,
wait,
we can use the Internet to get people
offline back into the real world with each
other. It's like, I would
love to spend my time on this.
So at this point we think the big
opportunity is a website for conferences,
for people to sleep on airbeds
and living rooms. This,
it turns out as a very narrow market.
We did not know this at the time.
So our logical next step is what's
the next big conference coming up?
We're hotels will sell out. Well, it
turns out that right here in Austin,
every march, it was quite a large
conference called south by southwest.
It also happens to be the place where
some preeminent tech companies went to
launch and took off like rocket ships,
including four square and Twitter and
some others. What year was this? 2008.
It's,
we're like,
we're going to build the next version
for south by southwest and this going to
take off just like the others.
So Nate hunkers down with us,
we start to code out of the next more
robust version of the site becomes more
than just four pages and we pull
all nighters for like two weeks.
And we watched Justin time for south
by South West and all this excitement,
all of this energy. Tim, we've
got a total of five hosts,
two reservations.
I'm no mathematician,
but that ratio doesn't sound favorable.
Well, one of the reservations was us.
It's actually Brian. Um, and, um,
Brian stayed with this guy here in Austin,
Mtn Dung and he had everything laid out
and he had the pillow and the towels and
the men's and some like, um, some
soup cooking in the background.
And he's a great host, right? He's taken
really seriously here at this time.
Like [inaudible] it was just
a classified service. Right.
And you came and you paid
somebody on a rival and Brian, um,
Brian tells the story that he forgot
to go to the ATM machine and so he gets
there and he goes through the whole night
and wakes up the next day and the host
has to awkwardly ask him, by the
way, where's my money? And runs like,
oh no, shoot, I forgot. I'll go to the
ATM today. Brian Forgot to go to the ATM.
Another night goes by this point. The
host is like, what kind of joke is this?
These guys just make a website to
freeload accommodations when they travel.
And so, um, Brian eventually
got to the ATM and paid him,
but he said that experience
was incredibly awkward.
Paint somebody cash and person inside
their home as like just not a great
experience. So afterwards, you know,
it was not a successful launch whatsoever.
I think we got one mentioned on Mashable,
like it was dismal and we debrief
on the whole thing and we,
we realized two things because we are
getting emails from people who are like,
Hey, I want to stay in a home but
there's no conference in the city.
How do I use your service?
And so we realized something,
well maybe this is more than
a conference website made.
This is just a travel website.
And what if we got rid of the awkwardness
of payments in person and allowed
people to pay with a credit
card in advance online?
And we just removed that whole
awkwardness from the customer experience.
And in doing so, we're like, wait, if
we did the trans, the transaction line,
we could take a small transaction
fee and a business model was born.
Um, and so at this point, uh,
Nate needed a little bit more enthusiasm
to get back involved in, in, in the,
in the concept. Um,
uh, of the three of us,
we all balance each other out really well.
Nate's the pragmatist of all
three of us. So he, you know,
helps ground us in reality and, and
progress and shipping things. Well.
Sometimes Brian and I can be, have
her head in the clouds and, and,
and really dream, um, it's
a perfect balance. And,
uh, Nate needs some convincing
that this can actually work.
So in the summer of 2008,
we realized that we could use some kind
of event to give this thing a spark for
this thing to take off.
And if you remember back in 2008
when everybody was talking about,
especially in the summertime,
the year of a presidential election,
John McCain versus Barack Obama
and Obama was attracting these
historic record breaking crowds.
He spoke in Portland to 75,000 people.
And it was identified
in June that the DNC,
the Democratic National
Convention later that August, um,
there was going to be a bit of a problem
because they moved the venue from the
basketball arena of 20,000
seats to Invesco Stadium,
which had 100,000 seats to attract more
people to come to Denver to see Obama
speak.
Therein lies a problem with the amount
of housing that exists in Denver.
They have 20,000 hotel rooms. Most of
them were already taken up by delegates.
And the headwind started to read
housing crisis in pending on Denver.
The mayor started holding pressure press
conferences to say he might open the
city parks for people to pitch tents
cause there was nowhere to sleep.
So we recognize and say,
wait,
what if we relaunched in time for the
DNC so we can ride the coattails of all
this press to gain awareness for
our, the next iteration of, of air,
bed and breakfast. So Nate
love the idea, we hunker down,
we spend the summer rebuilding the site
with online payments and the ability to
travel anywhere at anytime.
So this was the carrot for Nate,
was Nate needed to know that
there was some reliable,
you know,
mechanism to create awareness on the
horizon because to build a marketplace
without any awareness is like,
you know, the difficult civil,
the least difficult to say the least.
Um,
so we hit the ground in Denver.
We,
I remember we built a website,
this shiny new version of air bed and
breakfast and began on the phone with
press trying to pitch them like
we had no idea what we were doing.
I'm on the phone with ca like CNN
and they basically hang up on me,
but I've experienced with that from
some other projects in the past. Um,
so I'm like, I'm just gonna keep
going. And sw scared. Plus WC goes,
I'm all beautiful memory.
So what we learned,
what will we started to do is actually
contact a local bloggers in Denver.
Like CNN is not gonna answer a call,
but a local blogger loved
the story because it was of
their neighborhoods. And,
um, it was very human oriented of Denver
residents opening their homes to support
other fellow Obama supporters.
Um,
and so these blogs would write about it
and it turns out that's where like the
newspapers look for story ideas.
So in the newspapers wrote about him
and turns out that's where the local TV
broadcast,
it looks for story ideas.
So then we get a call from
NBC local affiliate and when
NBC does a story CBS and
ABC short we follow. So then we've
got the Denver press covered.
It turns out that's what the boulder
press looks to you for story ideas and be
started to become a regional story and
turns out when you have regional story,
that's what CNN looks to you for story
ideas. So within a matter of about
two to three weeks,
we went from zero listings in Denver to
800 people sharing their homes just to
this awareness through press. Again,
we had no money like there was,
we could hire like a PR firm,
we can like go buy online ads.
Like this is all just word of mouth,
like the press talking about us.
And then we get the call from CNN and
there was this funny moment where Brian
and I are doing a live interview in her
living room on a laptop through like
Skype or something. And we have,
we're sharing like earbuds,
what it looked like were conjoined to
each other because they're sitting so
close and we're doing this live interview
with this Guy Errol Barnett on CNN and
talking about this website and what it
means to people to be able to stay in a
home, uh, for anybody going
to the DNC. And it was,
and then when he'd have a CNN story,
that's what international press look to,
to create stories. Then Lamond
picks us up and the Guardian, um,
and press out in Europe.
And it's just amazing to see what happens
when an idea or a story starts at the
smallest nugget and works
its way up this chain, right,
to becoming an international story in
a matter of three or so weeks. Amazing.
You know, I have to give credit to, um,
to Seth Goden because I remember
during Crippen's I read his book,
all marketers are liars.
And I remember something that he
says in there, which I never forgot,
which is to make something
people want to talk about. Right.
It's like purple cow.
It's like make something that's distinct
enough that people want to talk about
it and it's differentiated enough.
And I feel like that concept was imbued
into like the early days of the company,
certainly decrypt buns and he collected
and definitely to air bed and breakfast
at the time.
And certainly if I watched it happen in
front of me making something that people
want to talk about, go from a local
Denver blogger story to international
press soon as it, is it safe to
say, would you consider that the,
the first or one of the first major
successful milestones for urban breakfast?
Yes, because we had um, a few hundred
people staying on the site that weekend,
including us. We got to go to
Denver. So Nate was busy. Hey,
Nate was really busy so we
had divide responsibilities.
It's just three of us needs
to do in all the coding.
Brian's handling all the press and I'm
handling all the design and the customer
service.
So let me hit pause and let me ask you,
would it make sense? And we can, we
can certainly decide on the fly here,
but we've got about probably
like close to three hours.
Would it make sense to have this be part
one and then follow up with a part two?
Oh, what do you think of that? We don't
have to, we don't have to, but we could.
What are your thoughts? Um, I'm open
to it and recorded another time. Yeah.
I'm just thinking like,
this is totally, yeah. We,
let's get people on a cliff hanger. This
is, I think this is a good cliffhanger.
Okay. So then I'll say, yeah. Okay. Go.
No, no, no, no, no. Go for it. Yeah.
I mean, because this like, this
deserves around too. So, so we had it.
It's, we had a few hundred people
actually using the service.
Brian and I split up responsibilities.
Nate doing doings, coding,
Brian's Zuni held the press.
I'm doing all the customer
service from my cell phone
and we have this incredible weekend
where our marketplace is working.
But you won't imagine what happens next.
Ooh.
dot.dot.
Okay. Amazing. No, this is perfect.
This is absolutely perfect. Uh,
so to be continued,
uh,
in the meantime,
as sort of a,
a temporary, uh, tie of,
of part one,
is there anything that you would
like people to take from this,
this first chronology that
we've walked people through?
Any ask of the audience or recommendation,
suggestion,
uh, that you would like
parting words of any type?
I think anytime that you introduce
a new idea into the world, there's,
there's bound to be somebody
or many people who rejected.
I think rejection is inevitable. Anytime
you're trying something new. In fact,
I'd say if you're not getting rejected,
you're probably not
trying to anything new.
Like you're probably not even
pushing hard enough on something new.
And my advice would be look at
rejection in a different way.
That equation for me was,
was just a way to reframe rejection as
an opportunity to keep going, move on.
And so my advice for everybody
watching right now is that, you know,
the gift of an entrepreneur's
reframe things.
And anytime there's a rejection that
you face, turn it into an invitation,
turn it into an invitation to keep
going and you can say yes or no.
You don't have to be at least
create this opportunity to,
to persevere, to get, to continue
going forward. And for me, every,
all the stories I've shared so far
from the senior prank that the intercom
system through decrypt buns through to
the beginnings of Airbnb are reframing
every know into a cool,
that person didn't like it.
I'm going to keep going until
I find somebody that does.
And also something at least that I see
from the outside looking in when you're
sharing all of these stories
and experiences is that
you are also over time by
exposing yourself to
rejection and reframing,
learning to in some way seek
out discomfort as opposed
to avoid discomfort and
that that's one thing
that also comes up for me.
And on top of that,
the fact that and why I,
I'm so excited that we were able to get
together to talk about some of these
many of these stories just of course,
just a,
a portion of your many life experiences
is that people are already familiar at
this point with Arab air BNB and all caps,
right.
Magazine covers,
uh,
one of the most successful
startups in the world, uh,
one of the fastest growing startups of
all time, et Cetera, et Cetera, et cetera.
And I think it's,
it's easy because as humans we want to
take shortcuts and create stories that
are easily graspable to think of
that as idea, execute success.
I didn't like it. It just came out of
the balloon was this overnight success.
But there's so much contributing to that
and so many diverse experiences that
yes, you had, but in some ways
you also help to engineer. And,
uh,
I think that's inspiring
to know that it wasn't,
it wasn't the byproduct of this immaculate
master plan that required you to be
Elan Musk times 10,
that you executed over two week period
and then you have an empire. No,
that's not,
that's not how it unfolds it all
a people think we woke up in Airbnb
was just created out of thin air that
couldn't be further from the truth.
And I hope if any,
there's any takeaway from the stories
that we've talked about today is that
there's just a long lineage of
trying things, bumping into walls,
getting rejected, like failing, reframing,
failure until learning and
trying to continue forward.
And so by the time airbnb came around,
it was like I'd been in the gym of
entrepreneurship for many years.
So it's like you don't wake up and just
run a marathon all of a sudden that no
does that. You train for it. And so
by the time it's ready for race day,
your body's conditioned for it and your
muscles and your system, your nervous,
like everything's ready for
you to go run 26 plus miles.
And I think entrepreneurs that
entrepreneurship is the exact same way.
And I think it's a misconception when
people look at the magazine covers and
they read the stories of a
successful company, they think, wow,
like the people that started that,
it just,
they built it and everybody came that
couldn't be further from the truth.
And like I think feel the dreams is
probably the worst movie ever happened.
Entrepreneurship because it created
this idea like, oh wow, if you build it,
they will come. I can tell you if you
build it, they don't come. Um, and it, it,
it takes us incredible perseverance and
sometimes irrational belief in yourself
to bring something to life in
the face of a lot of diversity.
And a lot of people saying
it can't happen. Um,
and so I hope if there's any takeaway
from the stories that I shared today,
it's that the simple act
of spotting an opportunity,
coming up with the original solution and
then taking that third but hardest step
of putting something into the world of
trying something to putting your idea
into practice.
It doesn't have to be the big idea.
It's just about being in the gym and
doing a Rep, the gym of entrepreneurship,
you're doing like a curls or something
like it's just getting in the habit of
those three things.
You spot an opportunity,
you come up with a regional solution
and you put your idea into the world and
the more you can do that, the better you
are at spotting the next opportunity.
And airbnb just happened to be a part of
the lineage of all the things I've told
you that happened before it.
So can you lay out the equation one more
time and what each letter stands for?
Absolutely.
Sw squared plus WC equals emo.
And what the stands for is that when
you introduce a new idea to the world,
some will love it.
Some Malt plus who cares equals move on.
Keep going until you find the
people that do love your idea.
All Right, Gel. Amazing.
Where can people say hi to you online,
find you,
where can they learn more about the
company and anything else that you might
want to mention?
I'd say go to airbnb.com and
if you want to connect with me,
you can follow along at on
Instagram at Joe Gibbs. Joe,
get on Twitter at Jay Gibeah and
certainly a crit buns is out there.
And, uh, for everybody who's watching,
listening, uh, we will have
links to CritBuns Joe Gibbs, uh,
and all affiliated links,
resources,
and so on for everything we talked
about in the show notes as per usual at
tim.blog/podcast.
Thank you everybody for listening.
And Joe, thanks for hanging, man.
So much fun. It's Super Fun, Tim.
Thanks for having me. Dot Dot. Dot
to be continued to be continued.