Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
Posting a question.
I'm a cybernetic organism.
This episode is brought
to you by freshbooks.
Freshbooks is become the goto cloud
accounting software for literally millions
of small business owners
who found a faster,
more efficient and much less stressful
way to deal with their numbers and
ultimately this helps you to
focus on what you are best at.
It is used by many of the fastest growing
startups I've invested in or advise
and it's equally used by many of the best
freelancers I work with on a daily or
weekly basis. It is one of the easiest
ways to send invoices, get paid,
track your time and track your clients
if you're self employed and managing
business sometimes means
wrestling with spreadsheets,
crumbled receipts and other scattered
pieces. Freshbooks can really help.
Freshbooks allows you to do many,
many different things very easily.
Preparing and sending a polished branded
invoice. It takes about 30 seconds.
You can set yourself up to receive online
payments from your clients in about
two clicks,
which on average we'll get you paid
twice as fast they're new proposals.
Feature means you can include a project
summary and timeline is part of your
estimate. There are many, many
other things. Tracking your time,
the quick proposals that I mentioned,
formatting free, super easy,
late payment reminders so you don't have
to chase people. Automatic expenses,
sharing files and messages with your
client's award winning customer service.
They are extremely responsive.
The interface is super intuitive and
there's almost no learning curve,
so in short it's easy.
It saves you time and right now freshbooks
is offering an unrestricted 30 day
free trial. For all of my listeners
to claim yours, check it out.
Go to freshbooks.com forward slash Tim
and enter Tim Ferris in the how did you
hear about us section and that is funky.
Spell t I m.
F. E. R. R. I. S. S. So again,
go to freshbooks.com/tim and
Inter Tim Ferriss in the,
how did you hear about us section?
Check it out.
This episode is brought
to you by legal zoom,
which more than 2 million Americans have
used to help start their businesses.
Past guests even such as,
well, wordpress lead developer,
CEO of Automattic, Matt Mullenweg now
valued at more than a billion dollars,
have used legal zoom to help
with their business needs,
specifically in his case
to form his company,
but legal zoom isn't just
for launching your business.
Their services include everything from
helping you to manage changing tax laws,
reviewing contracts, creating Ndas,
nondisclosure agreements, important stuff,
handling lease agreements and assisting
with really any other legal challenge,
hurdle, inconvenience that typically takes
time and effort away from running your
business.
The best part is that you
won't get charged by the
hour because legal zoom isn't
a law firm,
so they won't be running the clock up
and spinning circles just to raise your
bill.
Instead,
they just ask you to pay one low upfront
price for whatever it is that you're
looking to get all the card style.
So visit legal zoom.com and check out
their business section for all of their
services.
And if you want special savings,
that's the terminology in
the copy that they suggest.
I don't know what the special savings
is folks, but it's titillating.
If you want special savings,
enter Promo Code Tim Tim at checkout,
capital t, lowercase. I am again,
take a peek legal zoom.com
and enter Promo Code Tim.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job to interview and
deconstruct world class performers of all
different types from business,
sports, military chess, you name it,
science.
We bounced all over the place and this
episode is going to be wide ranging,
not only focused on business or investing,
although we do have an all
star in both of those arenas.
The guest is Scott Belsky.
He is one of the people I call most
for advice on a wide range of topics.
Who Scott at Twitter at?
Scott Belsky,
B L S K Y Scott belsky.com Scott is
an entrepreneur, author, investor,
and currently chief product
officer of Adobe. Big,
big company might have heard of it.
He's also a venture partner at benchmark,
one of the most famous venture
capital firms anywhere.
But this one based in San Francisco,
Scott cofounded by Hanson 2006 and served
as CEO until Adobe acquired the hands
in 2012 millions of people use the hands
to display their portfolios as well as
track and find top talent
across creative industries.
He is also a incredibly successful early
stage investor and advisor who has been
involved with companies like
Pinterest, Uber, periscope, among many,
many other fast growing startups.
And his latest project is a compendium
of insights and tactics for what Scott
calls the messy middle.
We all know we have that initial euphoric
start to big projects or companies.
And then you enter what you
might have heard of in uh,
perhaps incubator parlance.
In this case,
y Combinator I believe refers to
it as the, the trough of sorrow.
So you have this initial burst of
adrenaline and then there is a long middle
period with any type of creative endeavor.
They can get really messy and that is
where a lot of people give up or get
destroyed in one fashion or another.
And then there are people who make it to
the last mile and ultimately complete,
uh, many of these projects or have type
some type of acquisition or exit with
startup.
So this episode covers a lot of ground.
We talked about a lot
of these tactics and uh,
if for whatever reason you're thinking,
you know what, I want to listen to this,
Scott sounds interesting,
but I don't want to focus exclusively
business stuff or business building.
Don't worry. There's a lot
in here that transcends that.
And specifically we shift locations and
number of times in this episode we end
up in the sauna at one point.
And if you want a real life example of
how I ask my friends for help because I
was getting all wound up about a very,
very top of mind situation when
Scott showed up at my house,
jump about 55 minutes ahead from
where we begin the interview.
Uh, so the easiest way to
do that if you want to,
that's when we are in the sauna and I
ask him for help is as soon as we start
kind of hop an hour into the audio or
so and then jump back like five minutes
and it should be around there.
But there's a ton of of stuff that you
can mine that it's interview Scott is a
great guy and I had a blast
hanging with him and uh,
with that I will let you also through
your ears hang with none other than Scott
Dusky.
Scott, welcome to the show. Thanks to
him. Here we are at the kitchen table.
I didn't think we would
have a chapter two today.
We met earlier for some oysters and
beverages and caught up and I was picking
your brain on a number of different
things and we were trading stories and I
realized that you have, and you're
gonna know what I'm referring to,
how many Evernote notes?
Well a lot of Evernote notes,
but specific to what we'll be talking
about, I think it was a, this,
it started at maybe 830 or so a couple
of years ago when I started trimming it
down.
And you've been capturing lessons learned,
Maxim's mantras for yourself in the
process of developing this career.
And I hope this doesn't come off the
wrong way, but you've worn so many hats.
It isn't a single career.
It seems like you've lived many different
lives and people have already heard
the bio that I read in the intro,
but perhaps you could indicate the
roles that you've had in the companies,
uh, that you've been a part
of because they are so varied.
And I just want to underscore
how eclectic it is. Yeah.
A collectic for better or
for worse. Um, but, uh,
I was an entrepreneur back in
2005 starting a very small,
almost a lifestyle business at that point
to help organize the creative world.
A company called [inaudible],
five years of bootstrapping, um,
as a small team valuing resourcefulness
over the resources. We didn't have,
uh, a few near death
experiences in that process.
Then became a venture backed company,
which is a little bit more of a
traditional silicon valley like story. Um,
being venture backed for a few
years, growing really fast. Um,
went through an acquisition,
then started, uh,
found myself working in a very big company
as a vice president given what I came
in with as well as a few other
projects and a few new muscles.
They're navigating a big, a big
corporate experience. Then I decided,
you know what, I've been a seed
investor for a while. I like this.
People are telling me I should be.
An investor.
Jumped in and became a general
partner at a venture capital firm.
Total context switch, uh, learned a
lot of things. I'm the hard way. Um,
then realized I miss building,
wanting to get back to it. Now, uh,
am an executive at a big
public company. Um, Adobe,
the same company that acquired
us, but totally new position.
And I would say that,
uh, whenever I think about, um, best
practices, if there was ever such a.