Hey guys,
I'm going to explain the podcast gear
that I use for both in person and remote
interviews and the location right now
is the couch in my living room and this
couch is where a lot of my
interviews have been recorded,
whether that's with Mike Rowe, Adam
Robinson, many, many others. Dave, Mario,
they typically sit here and then I sit
over here and then the gear sits where my
acids right now,
and I'm going to show you a bunch of that.
So there are many different
tools in the toolkit.
This bag is a hunting bag,
which is a little small for hunting
and it's probably for fishing.
It's a Cabela's bag and I decided to
use it as my studio in a bag effectively
for podcasting. So I will travel with
this. I just came back from Austin,
Texas where I had this and
was doing recording with
say Cheryl strayed and many,
many others.
So let's take a look inside
first we have extra SD cards,
very important. Always, always,
always have several backup
SD cards because you will
end up having a tech issue
when you least want to have
a tech issue. First, Mike,
I'm going to show you is a yellow tech
Mike. This one is a little quirky.
This is from a or the model I think is
ixm and this is very cool Mike because
it's all encapsulated,
meaning you have the controls
for recording and so on
here for playback here and
it records directly to
an SD card at the bottom.
So this particular mic is very
useful for any recording on the road.
I've recorded intros. The welcome to the
Tim Ferriss show. My name is Tim Ferriss,
Blah Blah Blah. At airports. I've
done it in airplane bathrooms,
not recommended for audio bounce,
but nonetheless very versatile.
I use this because it also automatically
levels what you record for many of my
introductions,
even if I have access to the rest of the
gear that I'm going to show you because
it's so easy to use and so fast.
So that's number one.
And you will notice for all of these
backup batteries and backup SD card.
Trust me on that.
You want both.
And since this will oftentimes go into
a backpack separate from this bag,
I have the backups in this itself.
Next we have the zoom.
So this isn't h six presume I used to
use the h four n which I still sometimes
use, but it is more
primitive, easier to mess up.
And this is the basic piece
of equipment right here.
So the h six zoom is fantastic and
I upgraded for a host of reasons.
Number one,
the recording and a LCD
screen is much easier to use.
And next you have more ports
available for more people.
So the XLR cables, which I'll get
to in a second plug right in here,
so I can very easily have four
people recording to this device.
And you can select which tracks
you won't use if you're recording,
say music or something like that,
which I don't very often do.
You can attach different types
of extensions like these.
I very,
very rarely use those.
And that is the h six fantastic device.
I almost always use batteries as opposed
to an outlet because I never know if
I'm going to have access to an outlet.
So that is the h six.
Now how does this actually go together
with everything else? I'll show you
XLR cables. All right, so I
travel with many of these.
The only times that I've had real issues
with impersonal recording has been due
to loose fittings on XLR cables.
So you always want to travel with many
backups and these plug directly into the
side here.
So like that.
And then the next piece of the puzzle.
And so you can see I have a lot of these.
Uh, the next piece of the
puzzle is the Mike that you use.
So there are different options.
Some people will use a lav mic,
so lovelier mic like this,
and that will connect directly
to an XLR cable of some time.
What I found for my guests
and for purposes of simplicity
is that I like a very,
very simple Shure sm 58 stage Mike.
These are used by comedians.
They're used by, I'm sure, uh,
high school principals when they're
making announcements and auditoriums,
they are very,
very hard to break and you want to make
sure that you get a wind cover, uh,
because you will otherwise have
problems with your peas and so on.
Uh, and sometimes ss, uh, if you don't
have something like this on the mic,
these are relatively cheap.
They're probably 60,
70 bucks Max and you can buy them in
bulk and they simply connect to the other
end and you're in business.
You can record. Okay,
so next up we have lots of backups.
Okay?
Lots and lots and lots of Mike's
can imagine how much fun this is.
Taking a, a bag like this through Tsa. Uh,
there are constantly problems.
The next Mike I'm going to show you
is a little different. So this is,
this is the ATR 2100.
This is an audio Technica Mike.
And what makes this different
is not only does it have an Xlr,
but also has a USB.
So I will use this when I'm recording
remotely and doing something via
telephone. I, he Skype.
So this connects via Usb to the computer
and then I'll set up this mic stand
next to the computer so
it fits in just like so.
And I'm off to the races. A few
important points. Number one,
I use Skype and I use he cam call recorder
and there are many other options for
recording I'm accustomed to. That works
fine for me. So that is what I use.
All their solutions allow you to record
local audio on the part of the person
who is the interviewee.
What I have found,
because I've been interviewed VSR software
before is it creates a burden for the
person on the other end and if they
are say older or less tech savvy,
it creates more problems sometimes.
Okay, so there's a lot of tech,
it's obviously developing,
but I use ECAMM call recorder
and I use this USB mic.
You want to split the recording so
that you have two different tracks,
two different wave files for both
yourself and the interviewee.
This is very important.
If someone is a low talker and let's say
you're a high talker or a loud talker,
you need to be able to adjust
those post production. All right,
so those are some of the basics that you
will find in this first compartment of
the bag. And I'll cover just a few
more things and then we can move on.
Number one, what's on this side? Well,
I have charging cables for Iphone,
which I have all over the place.
I have this, what does this looks
like a garbage bag. This is a Poncho.
If you get caught in the rain,
trust me,
you do not want this bag getting wet
with all of this stuff. So this is just,
this is a Poncho that fits easily in my
head and we'll cover this and a backpack
and everything else that I have on.
What are these batteries?
Every long interview you do use
new batteries seems wasteful,
but I promise you it's better than
losing half hour or an hour of audio.
Always have backup audio and
then we have a separate charger.
This is a charger and a
speaker if I want to use it.
But this is a backup
charger for my iPhone, uh,
which I was sometimes in a pinch
use to record with an extension,
which can be a,
a road or Shure microphone that
connects directly to lightening port.
All right? So you can, you can
really see that when in doubt,
have a backup as Jocko Willink did.
His first public interview
on this podcast said,
and I've heard from other navy seals,
two is one and one is none.
That means have a backup cause fuel.
They have one of something.
It's going to break or
you're going to lose it.
And then case in point we have more phone.
All right?
Just in case something goes wonky, and
this is going to seem odd, but trust me,
you want to have lots of extra headphones.
Seems like overkill.
But when you better to,
better to have and not need than to
need and not have. And on that point,
guess what? I also have an
all of my bags to his brush.
You need an extra toothbrush because
you will find out when you have many
different bags that you
will for whatever reason,
forget your Goddamn
toothbrush all the time. Uh,
and then last I will show you
when I'm recording via phone,
there are a few ways that I keep track
of notes and prep for a given podcast.
If you're in person,
a lot of podcasters will advise that
you should record in person because it's
better. There's a certain
designer, thick wa,
something that you get in person
that you don't get via the phone.
I actually disagree completely. I think
that if you are a novice podcast or,
or even if you're a very experienced,
many of you will get better
results recording via Skype. Why?
Because when you're recording audio only,
uh,
you're able to put people more at ease.
In many cases you are
able to look at notes.
So not only can you look
at what you've prepared,
but you can Google things that you can
look up tangents that you want to explore.
You can write down things that you want
to explore later without distracting the
interviewee. Very important. And
there are also a lot of people,
even celebrities who when you hit
that record button in front of them,
that red light comes on,
they turn into different people.
Either they shut down or they
go into their sound bites,
they're prepared script,
whatever it might be.
So I really enjoy recording via Skype and
there are a number of tools that I use
to make it much more effective.
Uh,
so one of them is Evernote.
I use Evernote dozens of times
a day and have for years.
Full disclosure,
I became an advisor to the company
in 2009 because I ended up using it.
I've used it for research related to
all of my books, but this is a sample.
This is a sample screen and I'm
not going to read all that to you,
but this was for a Bj Miller who
is a palliative care physician.
Hugely popular episode.
Nobody really knew his name and he has
helped more than a thousand people to die
as a hospice physician. And at the
top I have how I was introduced.
So via a partner at Ideo via Adam Gazzaley
who is a neuroscientist who's also
been on this podcast.
Then below that I just have small
prompts and accidental doctor,
which is something I read about him.
Why is he an accident?
The doctor Zen hospice.org.
Sophomore, Princeton Dinky. Okay.
So this was a reference to his
accident which you had in college in
electrocution accident where he lost three
limbs. He's a triple, triple amputee.
So I'm wanting to talk about
that. Uh, photos from that time.
I noticed he was always smiling,
so just says photos from that time.
Always smiling. How manage
question mark. All right. Uh,
and so on and so forth. Struggle as a
source of beauty, no pain, no joy. Uh,
and then questions,
TF.
These are just thoughts that occurred
to me as I'm taking these notes.
So struggles,
a source of beauty.
That's a quote from him that I
wanted to dig into. Then after that,
so TF colon, how developed
more empathy, more compassion,
which is literally suffering together.
Practices, exercises, question mark. Okay.
So that is how I could refer to notes.
Looking at a screen,
which is very difficult to do in person.
So I am a big fan of recording remotely,
but now since I've done 200 plus episodes,
I feel comfortable
winging it more in person.
That doesn't make one
better than the other.
But if I want to connect with someone,
then perhaps I will try to do so in
person and then have a dinner afterwards,
say, or lunch beforehand, which is what I
did with Jocko. We had lunch beforehand,
then podcasts, then dinner together.
And we've since become good friends. Uh,
another thing.