Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
No,
I'm a cybernetic organism living.
This episode is brought
to you by boll and branch,
which is what I have on my
bed at home in San Francisco.
I use myself and there's a lot of
nonsense in the bedding business.
For instance, thread count, not a measure
of quality. Total myth. Egyptian cotton,
well guess what? It's a plant called
gossipy and Barbara didn't say,
I don't think that's how you say it,
but that is how I read it.
Generally not even grown in Egypt and
the made in Italy label that you're so
proud of.
Well,
you know you shouldn't necessarily pay
extra for that because it often means
that it's just finished in Italy
and woven in places like China.
The general industry markup for betting
is 700 to 800% at the usual retail
stores.
You'd go to Boland branch,
which is B o l l is
incredibly high quality.
They have a higher cost of
goods than many products.
You might buy it three to four x their
prices because they sell direct consumer,
so check it out.
Go to boll and branch.com that's B o
l l a n D E B r a n c h.com Boll and
branch.com and not that you need to,
but you can try anything you order at
home for 30 days. If you don't love it,
send it back and you get a full refund.
Go to boll and branch.com and use Promo
Code Tim for 20% off your entire order,
whether that's sheets, towels,
blankets, duvet covers,
anything and shipping is always free.
Chicken out boll and
branch.com Promo Code Tim,
this episode is brought
to you by exo protein.
It's one of the startups that I work with.
I love what they do.
These guys are making protein bars
using crickets, protein powder,
and before you screw your
face up and look disgusted,
I bet they taste better than any
protein bar you've ever had before.
I devour these bars after lifting
sessions. I take them with me on the road.
The recipes were developed by
a three Michelin Star Chef,
former head of r and d at the fat duck,
which was ranked the number one
restaurant in the world during his tenure.
The bars are paleo friendly, no gluten,
no grains, no soy, no dairy, et cetera.
They're high in protein and flavor and
extremely unique and they do not pop your
glycemic response up oddly enough,
and you can look that up on line to
see some stories on that Ferrin Stein.
That's the journalist who
looked at it on top of all that.
They are less processed than nearly all
protein bars. You'll be able to find.
This is your chance to see what the hype
is about and the founders were just on
the Forbes 30 under 30 list and they are
offering a deep discount to Tim Ferriss
show listeners. If you go to exo
protein.com forward slash Tim,
that's e x o protein.com
forward slash Tim today,
you can try a sampler pack with all of
their most popular flavors for less than
10 bucks.
That's extra protein.com forward slash
Tim and I would doing it relatively fast
and that's not a bs scarcity thing.
They're startup with limited inventory
and they sell out all the time.
That is what happened last time I
mentioned them, so check it out.
Exo protein.com forward slash Tim
well greetings ladies and germs.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to
another episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
This is a shorter episode instead of a
long format interview with an expert of
some type and we're
going to focus on Seneca,
my favorite stoic thinker
and author Seneca,
the younger his writing that I'm going
to highlight and excerpt is roughly 2000
years old.
Yet it is timeless and we are going
to listen to on the shortness of life.
This is an essay that I revisit
at least once a quarter,
along with all of his other
letters that you can listen to.
If you would like through the Tao of
seneca@audible.com forward slash Tim's
books and this particular letter,
I will highlight my favorite portion,
which begins with quote,
why do you torment yourself and lose
weight over some problem dot, dot dot,
and on it goes.
This is a fantastic reminder to mind the
critical few to ignore the trivial many
and much, much more. I hope you enjoy it.
Letter 49 on the shortness of life
a man is indeed lazy and careless might
do Lucas if he has reminded of a friend
only by seeing some landscape
which there's the memory.
And yet there are times when the old
familiar haunts stir up a sense of loss
that has been stored away in the soul,
not bringing back dead memories,
but rousing them from their dormant
state just as the site of lost friends,
favorite slave or his cloak or his
house renews the mourners grief,
even though it has been softened
by time. Now, Lo and behold,
Campania and especially Naples in your
beloved Pompei struck me when I viewed
them with a wonderfully fresh
sense of longing for you.
You stand in full view before my eyes.
I am on the point of parting from you.
I see you choking down your tears
and resisting without success.
The emotions that well up at the very
moment when you try to check them,
I seem to have lost you but
a moment ago for what is not,
but a moment ago when one
begins to use the memory.
It was about a moment ago that I sat as
a lad in the school of the philosopher
Celltrion, but a moment ago that
I began to plead in the courts,
but a moment ago that I
lost the desire to plead,
but a moment ago that I lost the ability
infinitely swift as the flight of time.
As those see more clearly are looking
backwards for when we are intent on the
present,
we do not notice it.
So gentle is the passage
of times headlong flight.
Do you ask?
The reason for this all past
time is in the same place.
It all presents the same aspect to us.
It lies together.
Everything slips into the same abyss
besides an event which in its entirety as
of brief,
compass cannot contain long intervals.
The time which we spend in living is
about a point nay even less than a point,
but at this point of time,
infant decimal method is nature has marked
by making it seem outwardly of longer
duration.
She has taken one portion thereof and
made it infancy and other childhood,
another youth, another the
gradual slope, so to speak,
from youth to old age and old age itself
is still another how many steps for how
shorter climb it was.
But a moment ago that I saw you off on
your journey and yet this moment ago
makes up a goodly share of our existence,
which is so brief.
We should reflect that it will soon come
to an end all together in other years.
Time did not seem to me to go so swiftly.
Now,
it seems fast to beyond belief perhaps
because I feel that the finish line is
moving closer to me or it may be that I
have begun to take heed and racking up
my losses.
For this reason,
I am all the more angry that some men
claim the major portion of this time for
superfluous things, time, which
no matter how carefully it is,
guarded cannot suffice
even for necessary things.
CICERO declared that if the
number of his days were doubled,
he should not have the time to read the
lyric poets and you may rate the dialect
Titian's in the same class, but they
are foolish and a more melancholy way.
The lyric poets are avowedly frivolous,
but the dialect Titian's believe that
they are themselves engaged upon serious
business.
I do not deny that one must cast a glance,
a dialectic where it ought to be a mere
glands or sort of greeting from the
threshold merely that one
may not be deceived or judge
these pursuits to contain
any hidden matters of great worth.
Why do you torment yourself and
lose weight over some problem,
which it is more clever to
have scorned than to solve.
When a soldier is undisturbed
and traveling at his ease,
he can hunt for trifles along his way,
but when the enemy is closing in on the
rear and a command is given to quicken
the pace,
necessity makes him throw away everything
which he picked up in moments of peace
and leisure.
I have no time to investigate disputed
inflections of words or to try my cunning
upon them. Behold, the gathering clans,
the fast shut gates and weapons
wetted ready for the war.
I need a stout heart to hear without
flinching this din of battle,
which sounds roundabout and all would
rightly think me mad if when gray beards
and women were heaping up rocks for
the fortifications when the armor clad
youths inside the gates were awaiting
or even demanding the order for a Sally
when the spears of the foam and were
quivering in our gates and the very ground
was rocking with minds
and subterranean passages,
I say they would rightly think
me mad if I were to sit idle.
Putting such pretty posers as this
what you have not lost. You have,
but you have not lost any horns.
Therefore you have horns or other tricks
constructed after the model of this
piece of sheer silliness and yet I may
well seem in your eyes no less mad if I
spend my energies on that sort of thing.
For even now,
I am in a state of siege and yet in the
former case it would be merely apparel
from the outside,
the threatened me and a wall that sundered
me from the foe as it is now death
dealing perils or in my very presence,
I have no time for such nonsense.
A mighty undertaking is on my hands.
What am I to do?
Death is on my trail and
life is fleeting away.
Teach me something with which to face
these troubles, bring it to pass,
that I shall cease trying to escape from
death and that life may cease to escape
from me.
Give me courage to meet hardships.
Make me call him in the
face of the unavoidable,
relax the straightened limits of
the time which has allotted me.
Show me that the good in life does
not depend upon life's length,
but upon the use we make of it also that
it is possible or rather usual for a
man who has lived long to have lived
two little say to me when I lie down to
sleep,
you may not wake again and when I
return you may never go forth again.
You are mistaken if you think that
only on an ocean voyage there is a very
slight space between life and death.
No,
the distance between is just as narrow
everywhere. It is not everywhere.
That death shows himself so near at hand,
yet everywhere he has as near at hand
rid me of the shadowy terrors,
then you will more easily delivered to me.
The instruction for which I have prepared
myself at our birth nature made us
teachable and gave us reason not perfect,
but capable of being perfected.
Discuss for me justice,
duty thrift and that two fold purity,
both the purity which abstains
from another person and
that which takes care of
one's own self.
If you will only refuse to lead me along
bypaths I shall more easily reached the
goal at which I am aiming for.
As the tragic poet says,
the language of truth is simple.
We should not therefore make that language
intricate since there is nothing less
fitting for a soul of great endeavor
than such crafty cleverness.
Farewell.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend,
so if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to a four hour work week.com
that's four hour work week.com all spelled
out and just drop in your email and you
will get the very next one and if you
sign up, I hope you enjoy it. This
episode is brought to you by exo protein.
It's one of the startups that I
work with and love what they do.
These guys are making protein bars
using crickets, protein powder,
and before you screw your
face up and look disgusted,
I bet they taste better than any
protein bar you've ever had before.
I devour these bars after lifting
sessions. I take them with me on the road.
The recipes were developed by
a three Michelin Star Chef,
former head of r and d at the fat duck,
which was ranked the number one restaurant
in the world during his tenure bars
or paleo friendly, no gluten, no
grains, no soy, no dairy, et cetera.
They are high in protein and flavor and
extremely unique and they do not pop
your glycemic response up oddly enough,
and you can look that up on line to
see some stories on that Ferran Stein,
that's the journalist who
looked at it on top of all that.
They're less processed than nearly all
protein bars. You'll be able to find.
This is your chance to see what the hype
is about and the founders were just on
the Forbes 30 under 30 list and they are
offering a deep discount to Tim Ferriss
show listeners.
If you go to exo protein.com forward
slash 10 minutes e x o protein.com/tim
today,
you can try a sampler pack with all of
their most popular flavors for less than
10 bucks.
That's exo protein.com forward slash
Tim and I would recommend it relatively
fast and that's not a bs scarcity thing.
They're startup with limited inventory
and they sell out all the time.
That is what happened last time I
mentioned them, so check it out. EXO,
protein.com forward slash.
Tim,
this episode is brought
to you by boll and branch,
which is what I have on my
bed at home in San Francisco.
I use myself and there's a lot of
nonsense in the bedding business.
For instance, thread count, not a measure
of quality. Total myth. Egyptian cotton,
well guess what? It's a plant called
gossip and Barbara didn't say,
I don't think that's how you said,
but that is how I read it.
Generally not even grown in Egypt and
the made in Italy label that you're so
proud of.
Well,
you know you shouldn't necessarily pay
extra for that because it often means
that it's just finished in Italy
and woven in places like China.
The general industry mark up for betting
is 700 to 800% at the usual retail
stores. You'd go to Boll
and branch, which is B o.
L l is incredibly high quality.
They have a higher cost of
goods than many products.
You might buy it three to four x their
prices because they sell direct to
consumer. So check it out. Go to
boll and branch.com that's B, O,
l l a, N D E, B r a,
n c h.com Boll and branch.com
and not that you'd need to,
but you can try anything you order at
home for 30 days. If you don't love it,
send it back and you get a full refund.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and use Promo
Code Tim for 20% off your entire order,
whether that's sheets, towels,
blankets, duvet covers,
anything and shipping is always free.
Chicken out and branch.com Promo
code, Tim, and until next time,
thank you for listening.