Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism.
Is podcasts
brought to you by Mizzen and main?
Don't worry about the spelling.
All you need to know is this.
I have organized my entire life around
avoiding fancy shirts because you have to
iron them. You sweat through
them, they smell really easily.
They're a pain in the ass.
Mizzen and main has given me
the only shirt that I need.
And what I mean by that and Kelly
Starr at loves the shirts as well,
is that you can trick people.
They look really fancy so you can take
them out to nice dinners, whatever,
but they're made from athletics,
sweat wicking material.
So you can throw this thing into your
luggage in a heap or on your kitchen table
like I did recently, and then pull
it out, throw it on with no ironing,
no steaming,
no nothing.
Walk out and you could probably wear
this thing for a week straight or make it
your only dress shirt and take it on
trips for weeks at a time. Never wash it.
It will not smell.
You will not sweat through it.
You got to check these things out,
so go to four hour work
week.com all spelled out,
four hour work week.com forward
slash shirts check it out,
slash shirts and you'll see someone.
My favorite gear, including the one
shirt that I've been traveling with,
this episode is brought to you by 99
designs or one stop shop for all things
graphic design related.
I've used 99 designs for everything
from banner ads to book covers,
including sketches and mock ups
that led to the four hour body,
which later became number one New York
Times Number One Wall Street Journal and
the brainstorming.
A lot of it took place with designers
from around the world and here's how it
works. Whether you need a t
shirt, a business card, a website,
an APP thumbnail,
whatever it might be,
you submit that project and
designers from around the world.
We'll send you sketches
and mock ups and designs.
You choose your favorite and you have an
original that you love or you get your
money back.
It's that straightforward,
and many of you who are listening have
already used it and created some amazing
things that I'll be sharing it in
the future. But in the meantime,
if you want to see some of my
competitions, some of the book covers,
as well as get a free $99 upgrade,
goto 99 designs.com forward slash Tim,
that's 99 designs.com forward slash Tim.
Hello Ladies and germs.
This is Tim Ferriss staring out through
my window at the eucalyptus trees
swaying in the breeze,
but that's enough poetry for this
episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
The Tim Ferriss show,
of course,
like every other episode is intended
to help you deconstruct excellence,
world class performers to
pull out the tricks, routines,
habits, books, et
Cetera, that you can use,
you can emulate to improve
results in your own life.
And guests vary from hedge fund traders
to that does make any sense at all.
Hedge fund managers to top performing
angel investors to people like Arnold
Schwarzenegger on the Celebrity
Front chess prodigies.
And in this case we have not only a chef,
but a a chef plus policymaker plus
would be professional athlete.
His name is Sam Kass.
Sam is a fascinating guy.
He went from getting a
history major at u Chicago.
Before that he was on the
professional baseball track,
then became private chef for the Obamas
and then ended up the senior policy
advisor for nutrition at the White House.
Uh,
he ran or help to run as
executive director the let's
move campaign which used
private sector partnerships to pursue
the goal of reducing childhood obesity to
just 5% by 2030 and for that he was named
number 11 on Fast Company magazine's
2011 list of the 100 most creative people.
And it's such a multifaceted story.
Sam is a,
a hilarious storyteller and there are
a lot of really concrete takeaways.
The book that he could not recall offhand
in this episode is a history of world
agriculture by Marcel
[inaudible] and Lawrence Roux,
Dar or Rwe Dart, r. O. U. D. A. R. T.
So in addition to the art of fielding
auto lendees books and some of the others
that he mentioned, there you have
it, a history of world agriculture.
So now without further ado,
please enjoy my conversation and
our conversation with Sam Kass.
Sam, welcome to the show. So good to
be here, man. I'm, I'm excited. Yeah,
it's uh,
it's,
it's an interview that I've been really
looking forward to and I am very,
very hopped up on caffeine. This is
that, this is a, an Amish morning for me.
I know this is,
I'm usually a 10:00 AM 11:00 AM kind of
guy because I'm a night owl and a lot,
so I'm going to jump into some
morning questions in a second.
But I wanted to first congratulate
you on the James Beard Foundation,
the leadership awards. Uh, thank
you. Uh, yeah, that means a lot.
It's a James Beard has been an
incredible, uh, organization.
I mean they are like the, the, the, like
that, you know, the Oscars for chefs and,
but they've taken up a lot
of the important issues
around food and nutrition and
health and sustainability. So you
have a, an award for that and yeah,
it's a great honor. I'm
excited. Yeah. It, uh,
so for those who don't know the
leadership awards, and this is a,
from their website quote,
recognize specific outstanding
initiatives as well as bodies of work and
lifetime achievement.
So that's,
that's a hell of a tag line and
we're going to get into all that.
But first a very important
question. Uh, eggs.
How do you prefer to make eggs
in the morning? So actually,
I've eating a lot of eggs,
uh, these days. And you know, the eggs
are one of the hardest things to cook.
Some of the great chefs in the world,
their actual, their tests for new cook,
we'd be, how to make an omelette
would be like their one master test.
So I actually liked eggs all ways.
Almost always soft though.
So either a soft boiled egg,
I'll do eggs over easy or
really soft scrambled eggs. Um,
and I guess the, the, the trick for
soft scrambled eggs is I, uh, you know,
have to get your butter nice. Not, I
cracked the egg straight into the pan,
let them cook for a second
and then mix them up.
And then before you think they're done,
take them out because they'll harden a
little bit as they sit on the plate. Um,
but, uh, I'll, I'll eat eggs
pretty much any, any way.
And do you, are you a tea guy,
a coffee guy? None of the above?
Uh, uh, both, all of the above. I
do a, I'll do coffee in the morning,
but we'll half and half and then,
uh,
either a little coffee in the
day or a tea and then I'll,
I'll definitely have some tea at night.
Um, some camomile tea or mint tea or some,
but, uh, yeah, I drink them both.
How do you, do you have
any particular, like, uh,
do you have any particular type of coffee
or a way of prepping or is it just,
you know, what, just treated as fuel,
whatever will get me through the day.
Hmm. You know, I,
I wouldn't say that I'm like one of
those coffee like lunatics who like,
you know, as wild, you know,
about every specific thing and talks
about it like wine, but I appreciate it.
Good Cup of coffee and I really,
one of my least favorite things.
Is it terrible cup of coffee? Uh, yeah,
I just, I can't, I can't drink it.
So I'm a big stump town guy.
You know, blue bottle does
a great cup of coffee. Um,
there's,
there's some really good coffee out there.
So I do French press in the morning. Real
simple, some half and half. Um, nothing,
nothing crazy.
What does the,
well,
actually I'm going to ask the the morning
routine question a little bit later on,
but you mentioned a coffee snobs,
and this is kind of a good segue
because you live in Brooklyn,
but you came from a town that is actually
really well known for coffee these
days. Just Chicago. Yeah.
And correct me if I'm wrong,
I could get some of my bio incorrect.
But you grew up with parents who
were both teachers, is that correct?
Uh, my dad's a teacher. Um, was
growing up? Well he was actually a,
he worked in the Ford factory when
I was very young. And then he,
then he changed jobs to become a teacher.
And my mom has been an education
like science education stuff,
the more from like museums and now she's
at the National Science Foundation. So,
but lots of teachers,
my and uncle are teachers.
My cousins are teachers and my sister's
a teacher. So I am, we come from,
I come from an educational family.
What was, uh, what was that
like growing up? I mean,
how did that impact you or affects you?
Um, I, it probably was more of the,
how I pushed back against it then,
how it is that that was probably
the strongest influence.
I wanted to be a professional baseball
player from the time I was like three all
the way through college
to be honest. And, uh,
I went to junior college trying to make
it to the major league. So I, I, you know,
as my parents pleaded with me to dig
into the books and hit them harder,
all I wanted to do was take batting
practice. And, and, and she, you know,
go after some fly balls. So
I, it came back to me when I,
when I transferred in
college and then beyond.
Did the,
do you have brothers and sisters?
I have a younger sister who's
still in Chicago. Got It.
And you ultimately in college
ended up at U Chicago.
Uh, and what, what drew you
to baseball? Why did you,
why did you play baseball?
Um, so I love, I love baseball for a
number of reasons. One, it is so hard.
I mean if you,
if you are successful 30% of
the time for your whole career,
you'll be a hall of famer. That means
if you fail seven out of 10 times,
you're one of the greatest players
in the history of the game.
And so that constant challenge and
constant challenge to get better.
Something that, you know, always
really drew me. It's also, you know,
it's a team sport, so you have
the camaraderie that is, you know,
really powerful and those bonds with,
with, with your teammates. But it's,
it's also an utterly individuals
sports. So unlike, you know,
soccer or basketball where if have
it a bad game, you kind of blend in.
If you make an error and baseball are,
you strike out with the bases loaded,
everybody knows like you messed up.
And so you really have to take account,
you know, responsibility and you're
held accountable for your actions.
And I think that those kinds of
lessons of discipline, hard work,
but also accountability
and learning how to fail.
And even if you failed five times in a
row, that sixth time you get a shot at it,
maybe the most important
time can win the game.
And how do you mentally prepare
yourself to walk into that moment?
Clearheaded and, and not carrying the
baggage from the previous failures,
which could impede your ability
to be successful when it mattered.
Like those are the kinds of things
that I just loved about baseball and,
and it really served me well and,
and all other aspects of life.
And you had a, you had a very good
batting average. I believe it's, uh,
it,
I've read that it was ranked among the
best in program history at a University
of Chicago.
Is that accurate?
Um, yeah. I haven't checked recently.
I'm sure some of the younger guys
that have taken over. I, when I left,
I think I was number three, but you
know, it was, it wasn't the, you know,
we were of c for the education,
not, not, not uh, the baseball,
but we had a very good team.
Um,
and I played two years of
junior college baseball,
just trying to get drafted where
basically all I did was play ball a six,
six hours a day,
seven days a week literally,
and sprint training in the morning. Like,
you know, it was, that's all we did.
So u of C was a little different. It
was a two hours a day, five days a week.
And I'll never forget the first practice
when coach outlined our schedule and
said that on Thursdays we didn't
practice cause we had science labs.
I just almost like passed out.
I didn't even know what was talking,
talking about science labs,
not baseball. So it was a,
it was an adjustment for me. Um, but, uh,
but it was one of the greatest thing
and probably the best decision I've ever
made was to go there.
Well, like you said, I mean if
you go to say Iowa for wrestling,
I mean wrestling is your
career in college, uh,
academics are secondary,
but it u Chicago you have obviously
very strenuous academic program.
What did you do that other players didn't
do that allowed you to not only make
it through u Chicago and the academics,
but to have that high,
a batting average for
that good batting average?
Um, that's a good question.
I'm not exactly sure I know
a definitive answer that,
I mean,
I had come from such a rigorous baseball
background and where a lot of the other
guys were, you know, came from, you know,
we're sort of playing baseball
secondarily that, um, you know,
that part came really easy
to me. Uh, and, um, you know,
I think the part that was
a real adjustment that I
could learn from them was
like how to really hit the books in a
way that I had never had to hit the books
before. And how do you organize
all that class work and you know,
the expectation that you're supposed
to read like five books a week? I mean,
I mean, that was like absurd to
me, uh, going in. So, you know,
I learned from them about how to balance
that side of it and from my side,
um,
you know,
I think the discipline and how you
efficiently use your time both in the,
you know, in the gym, in batting practice,
like how do you make the most
of what you're, you know,
what you're trying to get out of it.
Um,
I think was something that I
could bring to the guys and,
and was able to be
successful on both sides.
And the,
the,
the major you ended up choosing
was history. Did, was that a,
was that an immediate choice?
Did you know you wanted to do history?
How did you arrive at that?
Um, you know, I looked, I looked
at a couple other majors, um, uh,
but I ran the history because,
you know,
at the time there's a lot of things
swirling in politics. There's a lot of,
you know, there's a lot of work
there. There's like, you know,
the first Gulf War and there's
a lot of things going on that,
that I was paying attention to that
I didn't really understand what was
happening. Uh, and um, and I,
and I realized that if I wanted to
understand the world around me in politics
and everything that was happening,
having a, uh, a much better grasp on, on,
on history and where these things
have come from was going to help me.
And I think that that really propelled
me to, to focus in on history, which,
which I love. I'm a, I'm a history geek.
Do you have any favorite
history books or biographies?
Oh man, that's so tough. That's so tough.
I Dunno if I have one.
I'll tell you like I like some obscure
ones and I got to get you the author.
But there's like,
there's a history of agriculture book
that completely changed my perspective and
it's kind of boring. But
when you look at, you know,
if you're a geek and you look at like the
impact of simple tools have had on our
society,
the transformational shifts,
like we forget how fundamental that stuff
is. So I'll get back to you on that.
There's so many great biographies
and great history books.
Cool. Yeah, the, the, uh, I'll put the,
the title of the book and
so on in the show notes.
So we'll come back to that.
Uh,
how did you then,
this is kind of the missing piece in
that the Sam Kass puzzle that I haven't,
uh,
immediately been able to figure out.
How did you go then from majoring
in history at U Chicago to food?
How did you become interested in food?
So I had always, um, sort
of love food. You know, as a
kid I kind of liked to cook,
um, but it had no notion of ever, you
know, pursuing it professionally at,
in any way. Um, and when I
was at UFC, my friend, uh,
was the sous chef at this restaurant
in, in, uh, in Chicago. And I,
I didn't know him super well, but I
said, all, you know, one day, you know,
I think I'll go to culinary school when
I'm old and just so I can learn how to
cook for like my kids and wife whenever
they decided to show up. And he was like,
you know, well, don't do that.
Just come in and hang out at
the restaurant and see what
you think. So I went in,
it was like an Italian American, uh, spot
in Chicago, nothing, you know, nice place,
nothing too fancy. And um, and I loved it.
And so I ended up just
showing up and like, you know,
and potatoes and hanging out and trying
to learn some things. And the chef said,
well, if you're going to keep showing
up, I guess I got to pay you. So I'd,
so he did. But I mean, it was pretty
much an unmitigated disaster. Like,
I knew nothing and they, you know,
but I always work hard. So they,
they threw me on the line to work the
Pasta Station and Oh my God, it was,
you know,
the dishes that the chef let me send it.
The table most often came back cause they
were just on that overall, uh, so it,
you know, so I guess it
was a rough start. Um,
but so I had that one summer and then
I finished u of C and I had one one
semester left and I kind of kicked
my way into an abroad program. I got,
I got wait listed and then
sort of, um, pleat and made a,
a strong plea with the Dean to let me,
uh, let me into one of the programs.
I didn't care where, where we
went, where I went and went to,
ended up going to Vienna and I,
I said to the head of the program,
you know, I'm, I worked a little,
I worked this one summer in a restaurant.
I'm interested in food.
Like maybe there's a pastry shop
or something. I can go hang in,
hang out at once a once a week
or something. Totally casual.
So I landed in Vienna and she said,
so my husband's uncle's friend from
college son rides bicycles with the sous
chef of the best restaurant in Vienna.
That's literally what it was. And,
uh, and she's like, you know,
he, he can meet you tomorrow, um,
if you're interested. It's like, all
right. So I meet this dude crazy guy.
Uh, and he, he comes up to me and says,
are you the Yankee who wants to
cook on the street? And I said,
I am. And I said, all right, well, we'll
come, come to the restaurant tomorrow.
And so I did. And, um, it was a Michelin
Star, like best restaurant in Vienna.
It was incredible.
I knew nothing about food,
and they ended up taking
me in and training me.
I'm sort of old school European
style, like, Kick Your Butt,
uh, you know, until you can't take any
more and you figure it out. And, uh,
lots of stories from that,
from that, from that place.
But that's sort of how I
really was propelled into it.
Uh, so, uh, a few things I
just want to explain to people,
maybe not in the industry.
So shoes a sous chef is,
I guess that means under chef,
right?
That's kind of the second
in command in the kitchen.
Is that a fair way to put it? Just like
Suvi is under, under pressure I guess. Uh,
and the, so there are a lot of stories.
I know we, we talked about one, uh,
over dinner the other
night and I can't skip it.
So could you tell people about your
sort of baptism by fire in that kitchen?
Um, so many stories. Uh, I
think the one, yeah, the,
the, the, the, the, the fever
dream. A fever dream had. So, uh,
so it was December and uh,
and that's the busiest time of the
year by far for this restaurant.
And the, um, the guy who did all the fish,
meats and sauces,
what had to have surgery.
And so the executive chef had to take
over for him and now he was like 40,
and was a super talented guy, but
was like not cooking anymore. Like,
he wasn't running things and being
out with the guests and you know,
doing his thing.
So he was really unhappy about having to
cook the line during the most busy time
of the year. So he, he, like he walked
in when, when we got news and it's like,
all right, Yankee, you're with me.
And so he had this huge incentive to
teach me how to prep everything as fast as
possible because he didn't
want to have to do it.
So he taught me how to make
all the sauces, prep all
the meats, cook everything.
And so then we would work
the service together. Uh,
but in the middle of the month,
on a Friday,
the chef came down with like 104
fever and was completely laid out.
And it just so happened that my best
friend who was a road scholar, uh,
at the time was coming to
visit me from England. And, um,
so, you know, we're
supposed to go, hang on,
I was supposed to have the weekend
off and we were just going to hang.
And so he shows up and I'm like,
hey man, you're coming with me.
I'm putting you in a chef coat,
like we can't leave. And uh,
they had the breakfast cook,
this Guy Wolfgang who was at awesome dude,
but you know,
he was like,
he was like doing platters of
fruit and it needs a good cook,
but he didn't like Cook Dinner Service.
He never had.
So it was the three of us trying to
figure out this dinner service and it was
pretty funny. But the, at the end
of the night, the sous chef said,
alright, Wolfgang, you've got to
take the day off. Um, it's the,
it's the two Yankees on
the stove tomorrow night.
And like the kitchen went silent.
Like all the cooks were like, whoa.
Like they couldn't believe it.
And so we figured out the system.
My friends, a smart guy, so he, we studied
the words in German of the different,
like fish and meats
and whatever we needed.
So the next night we had like
a crate and we were packed.
And so the,
the sous would call it the order.
My friend would take out the fish or
the meat and then, and I would cook it.
And you,
and you know,
as I'm cooking on the other side of me
also cooking and facing me was the guy
who did all the vegetables inside dishes
that would go with my meat or fish and
I'd look up and he would just be standing
there kind of with his mouth open,
completely in awe of what was
going on because you know,
that station that we were working was
like what people would work their whole
career for us and incredibly prestigious,
well-paid position.
And here are these two Americans
who knew nothing about cooking,
working in a Michelin Star restaurant
on the hardest station in the kitchen.
It was hysterical. Uh,
and we made it like we,
we basically got through
without any catastrophe.
And I'll never forget when the last
ticket went out. The sous chef,
his name was Alice, he turns
around, he said, Yankees, we won.
And then like just in German shouted
for bottles of champagne and bottles of
beer. And, uh, and we had a good old
party that night. It was, it was, uh,
it was a ton of fun.
And,
uh,
I remember hearing this story and just
having my jaw dropped open because I've
had of course very limited
exposure to food and restaurants.
But during the writing of the flower chef,
when we first met men have been in DC.
Yeah, I remember going into
a handful of restaurants,
obviously different restaurants
that very different environments,
but when you're, when you look at a
line, not at a Michelin Star Restaurant,
but,
uh,
just at any restaurant during a busy
period and like 40 menus open at the same
time, it is complete chaos. I mean,
you have to be doctor octopus
to work one of the hotlines.
So it's like you guys were kind of yanked
out of the audience by the conductor
of the orchestra and asked to do
Violin Solos. Uh, it's, it's, uh,
I can't believe you guys
made it through that.
What's w what was your internal
self talk like when you got,
when you got the news and like when you
got the news or when you walked in for
that, that evening. I mean, how
did you prep yourself to that?
Because unlike baseball,
right,
like if you're putting out every three
out of 10 dishes is working in the
restaurant, you get punched
in the face. So yeah.
What was your self talk to?
It's a great,
it's a,
I mean I think that the key in a
restaurant and the key in any kind of high
pressure situation like I
think 75% of success is,
is staying calm and not losing
your nerve. And um, you know,
the rest you figure out, but once you
lose your, once you lose your, your,
your calm,
everything else starts falling apart fast.
And in a restaurant situation,
as the tick tickets start piling up and
like everybody else's is waiting on you.
So,
and particularly in this like the time,
it would have to be perfect cause
you go up on six dishes and the, the,
the guy who's doing all the side stuff
has like cooked all this and he's got to
get to the next round. So your timing has
to be right on. And if you're too slow,
all of his stuff gets yes.
You know,
it gets overcooked and he's
got to cook it again. Right.
So you can really throw off then.
So I think the key thing was
like mentally preparing myself.
Like when something goes wrong you
just stay calm and stay the course.
And I think the other thing, one of the
first thing the sous chefs taught me,
like he gave me some really fundamental
rules which have lasted me kind of
throughout everything I do.
One is the first is never serve
anything you wouldn't want to eat,
like never served crap. It's like
rule number one, rule number two,
which is just true.
Just so you know,
you can have a high standard
on everything you do.
Rule number two was when things get
really busy instead of just like,
like plowing ahead and just trying to
work as fast as you can and just go
through all the tickets.
He always would tell me step
back and come up with a plan.
So look at which dishes you
have and figure out what's
the most efficient way to
cook them. So if you have five of one
thing, don't just cook them one at a time.
Like get them out,
prep them together and do them together
so that those kind of like fundamental
rules, I tried to hold really close and
you just come up with a good system.
I think every great restaurant has an
incredibly strong system that when the,
the pressure gets heated, heated up
and everything's moving super fast,
you rely on that system to move you
through. And I think that was key.
We came up with a good system and,
and out it went. So I, I've no,
you're not focusing on too
many things at any one time.
Focus on cooking the things that
my friend was giving me and uh,
and it worked really well.
It was a,
it was so fascinating for me to visit
different kitchens and look at the layouts
and, and uh, and the,
the methods because they were really
sort of the internal workings of the
executive chef thrown out into this,
the architecture of the room
and the process and all that.
And just being so surprised at,
for instance, a Alinea in Chicago.
And how quiet it is. There's no
yelling, there's no screaming.
It's more like an operating
table. Uh, what is the most,
uh,
unusual restaurant that's a,
that puts out very good food that you've
come across in terms of just how it
works?
Hmm. Well, the craziest
kitchen I have ever seen.
So I worked at a Vac,
which is one of Chicago,
one of America's great
restaurants and you know,
it was really a wine bar that ended up
putting up such good food that it's won
James Beard awards and all kinds of other
accolades just because the food ended
up just kicking butt,
but it was not set up that at all.
So it was a teeny line if three people,
one big wood burning and gas burning
like kind of oven and a little stove and
what people do out of that.
It's just what we were doing out
of that with Tsung was incredible.
But the kitchen that's like blows me
away the most is the kitchen here in
Brooklyn actually, uh, at
Frankie's four 57. It's so tiny.
It's literally like two guys on to a
induction burners in a space that's like,
I don't know,
like five feet by 10 feet and they cook
for this huge restaurant at quality.
It's like one of my restaurants in
America. What was the name again?
Frankie's four 57.
It's unbelievably good.
And it's like you look at these two guys
back there with an n d two induction
burners and he, I just don't know.
I just don't know how they do it.
And it's, the menu is huge. I mean
it's, it's still, and it's delicious.
So what people can do out
of very small spaces is,
um, is pretty incredible. So
the, for, for people who you,
who don't know what an induction burner
is and then didn't correct me if Ryan
induction burner is basically a stove
top that you plug in and you can put on a
countertop,
maybe it's the size of like a large dinner
plate and it depends on what kind you
get. But he uses, as I understand
it, magnets to yes. Metal.
So you could actually take the pot off,
put your hand right on the
burner and not burn your hand.
You got to make sure you don't have
rings on. But, um, that actually,
uh, raises, so this, this is this
question of kind of elegance, right?
Because, uh, one of the questions I was
going to ask you later is what, you know,
what's the most interesting meal you
could make an a dorm room, right?
And you could, you could,
I mean, induction burners
in a five by 10 foot space.
I mean, that's basically a dorm
room that these guys are cooking in.
It sounds like if,
um,
if you had to limit your herbs or spices
to three choices for the rest of your
life, what would your three,
what would your three choices be?
Herbs or spices. Oh my God, what a
horrible, horrible question for me.
Only three.
Yeah. Or, or let you know what, I'll
give you a little bit of wiggle room.
A handful,
a handful.
I mean, I'd have to have chilies
of some kinds. Any kinds. Uh,
there's lots of kinds, but you know,
some, some chilies. I would have to have,
um, any herbs or spices. Uh,
I'm, uh, I'd probably have
to take Faisal and terragon.
I'm a huge terragon okay. Guy. Um,
spices. I mean, oh my God,
how do I pick just one?
Uh, Oh God. I Dunno. Like
Kumon is a big, is a,
is a really versatile big spice.
Um, I love pink peppercorns,
although I don't know if
that make the cut. Um, yeah,
that's a really hard question.
Oh, I know. That's why
I, that's why this is,
this is to get the tea to make the
shopping list for myself and I've terragon
terragon kind of revolutionized
eggs for me. Terragon and, and um,
white truffle sea salts of all things.
So,
which was recommended by a friend of mine.
How do you use Terry Dawn?
Oh Man. You can just check
on it. Anything. I love it
in straight and salads. Um,
you could chop it up with like
some parsley and some days on,
you can put that on fish on.
I use terragon on stake.
Terragon like little terragon and maybe
even a little butter on a steak is
delicious. Um, uh, anything seafood.
I find tarragon goes also
really well with, so you can do,
if you're doing a pasta like lemon,
you know,
a lemon terragon something seafood pasta,
a fill in the blank on the seafood,
you pretty much can't go
wrong. Um, so it's, it's, it's
one of those interests. You,
you know, you gotta be careful because
you can use it's strong. So, um,
you can overuse it pretty quickly,
but if you use it gently it, um,
it's a beautiful flavor.
You mentioned steak. What is your
favorite cut of steak and Y ou?
I guess favorite. I guess I'd
have to be a rabbi, a guy,
but I eat a lot of skirt steak, a lot
of hanger steak. Um, I love brazing.
So you know, lots of different, you
know, the bridge and cuts, ribs and such.
But if I'm going to have, like,
if I wouldn't have my last steak,
it would be a rabbi.
When you're cooking, remind for yourself
just, just for Sam. Nobody is. How do you,
how do you cook it?
A grill. I, you know,
if I'm doing for myself,
but really if I'm doing it for anybody,
I just throw it on the
grill really simple. Um,
and like medium rare to
rare and pretty olive oil,
salt and to sit sometimes pepper,
sometimes not. I'm not a big pepper guy,
so I don't put that black pepper on much.
I'm pretty much anything really. Um,
but I'll stake is the kind of the one
thing that I'd be open to that and yeah,
in a way you go nothing,
nothing fancy.
And you put the olive oil and
salt on beforehand or afterwards?
Beforehand. Yeah. And if I,
and if I'm going to do an herb,
like sometimes I'll put
terragon or some rosemary. Uh,
I always do that afterwards because I
find that when you put it on before just
burned and you lose the flavor.
But if you, you hit it afterwards,
particularly if you're going to sear it
on the grill and then finish in the oven
for a few minutes, which is often the way
to do it. If you have a thick cut, um,
you put that on. So it gets to, you know,
it cooks a little bit to round out
the flavor, but it doesn't, uh,
it doesn't kill the flavor.
Yeah. I always, um,
finish sort of sear and then finish it
the oven at a low temperature and uh,
just let the butter and whatever herbs
I'm going to use kind of soak in from the
top down. Uh, the, so the
pet, the pepper point,
you mentioned not much
of a black pepper guy,
but you also mentioned the
pink peppercorn. So would,
what would you use pink
peppercorns for them?
Which I haven't ever used or I don't that,
yeah, you can. I mean,
so you could use them on any meat they
like go great on like pork or if you
grind them up as a rub on pork or uh,
you could do on stake as well. Um,
you can, you can do a fun dressing,
a salad dressing with them as part of it,
but it becomes part of a,
a flavor. Whereas like for me,
black pepper, it's used like salt.
Right. And we use it on
everything, but salt doesn't,
it's all becomes part of the flavor. It,
it elevates the flavor. Worst pepper,
like layers on top of the flavor.
And it's,
it always just kind of blanket things
for me. And I dunno, I just, I don't,
I'm just not a fan, uh, uh,
of that sort ubiquitous pepper
flavor on everything. Um,
so on the flip side, if a,
aside from terragon, if someone,
if one of your very close
friends were to say, you know,
I love Sam but he really
overuses this ingredient,
what would that ingredient or
condiments or herb or spice spicy.
Mm. I Dunno, probably garlic,
but we all are guilty of using garlic
too much cause it's just so damn good.
It just makes everything better.
I, I literally have minced garlic in my
tea right now. I'm not getting, so yeah,
I'm guilty of the same sin. Uh, God,
uh,
how did you first meet the Obamas?
Um, so, uh, yeah,
so we're both from Hyde Park and
high park is on south side Chicago,
like where the universe Chicago
is and, and um, you know,
while he was a professor,
actually I known him just
from the neighborhood, uh,
and the first now first lady,
um, and when I was in
high school and then, uh,
but then lost touch with them for many
years and got reconnected with them when
I came back from my,
uh, my time in Vienna.
And then subsequent travels around the
world of sort of traveled for about four
or five years, you know, through
Vienna and then be passed. Um,
so I got reconnected with them sort
of right as the campaign was, was, uh,
was getting going.
And was that through evac or how
did you guys end depth reconnecting?
Um, so, uh, we reconnected because why
I be after I've, when I was in Vienna,
I was actually there illegally.
I had no worker's permit or anything
and ended up sort of getting run out of
town. Uh, yeah, so that's the story.
That's a story for another day.
Uh, and, um, so then I spent about,
um, for, for you four more years
passed that cooking and traveling.
And I ended up getting connected to a
family that had a place in New Zealand.
And so I cooked a couple of seasons
down in New Zealand and they were from
Chicago. So I, the, after the second
season I came back with them to,
um, to Chicago to work part time. And the,
the father of that family knew,
uh,
the first lady and happened
to run into her, um, on a,
on a plane and they got to talking
and, you know, and he was telling him,
telling the, the first study about, uh,
you know, me cooking for them. And, and,
and she's like, Oh, Sam, I
haven't seen him in years.
And so we got reconnected and,
um, you know, back then there was no
staff. It was basically just them,
grandma a little, they had a little
bit of help, but, but not much.
So I started helping out the first lady
as she had to get on the campaign trail
more and more when the
kids were still very young.
And so started helping her out with, uh,
with cooking some better food for them.
What's meals?
What were some favorite meals during that?
That, uh, intense campaigning period.
Oh, you know, that's all top secrets.
Just scared. Disclose. No, just kidding.
You know, look at the end during that time
and all the way through. I mean, they,
there's,
there's never been any
interest in fancy food at all,
really simple food that everybody's
going to like, you know,
lots of chicken or lean proteins, lots
of fish. We always do whole grains.
So if we're doing rice, there's always
brown rice and always, you know, you know,
good, good serving of vegetables.
Um, and just, you know, um,
nothing. It's always, I think
the thing that people, um,
you know, think about when
they think of private chef,
do you think, oh, fancy food,
but really you're in your home,
right?
So people don't want to feel
like they're in a restaurant.
And that's same was true in the
White House. And I think, um,
so we always kept at it really,
really simple. Um, and never,
never did anything. I mean,
we ate like everybody else
eats nothing, nothing crazy.
We'd love a good Burger, you
know? Uh, so things like that.
What if,
if hypothetically you had,
let's say five years from now you decide,
you know what, just for the hell of it,
I'm going to have a couple
of restaurants in Chicago.
And uh,
you go back at some point,
you're the owner and you decided to kind
of hang out at one of the restaurants
and Lo and lo and behold,
the Obama's come in for
dinner and they say, Sam,
make us whatever you think
will bring back the memories.
What would you make them?
How would I'm pretty right to marry?
Or would that make them a,
that's a great question.
I guess it depends.
The first thing I'd say is it depends on
what the season is because I think one
of the keys to great food is
cooking with the season, summertime,
summertime. So summertime, I'd
probably start with a like a,
a really nice tomato salad because I'm,
one of the best things about being in
the White House has been the first lady's
garden. And we got to pick, you know,
awesome produce right out of the garden,
right before dinner. So I'd probably
start with an awesome tomato salad. Um,
maybe do some barbecue chicken,
um,
uh, with Muslim good spice. I Dunno, uh,
maybe some potatoes and a,
just a bunch of vegetables.
So we would pick like P and
g Zucchini and Bazell Oh,
maybe a little egg plan or some peppers.
I don't know.
It just depends what's going on. We've
grown some great corn, so maybe do some,
some really good corn with
that. Um, some like that.
What's, um, what would the
tomato salad look like?
I love to me, if you've got
great tomatoes, you don't
want to do much John. I mean,
I think,
um,
if you don't have great tomatoes then
you've got to work with them some,
but you probably should just do
it different salad. Then I, uh,
I like it with a little onion. And on
this one, like typically have a red onion,
really thinly sliced. One of my big
things I hate thickly sliced red onion.
It's like as thin as you can
slice it thinner, the better. Uh,
but I'll actually in the tomato saddle
widening finally too is, is good. Um,
with some nice, uh,
olive oil and you know,
like a white Balsamic is
really nice on tomato salad.
It's got a touch of sweetness, um, in
any, any number of herbs like, you know,
you could do part holy parsley and some
Bazell maybe throw in some like green
beans or wax beans in there
that are blanched. So I'm like,
that sounds pretty good to me.
That sounds great.
What other pet peeves do you have
aside from overuse of pepper?
Thickly sliced onions. I love pet peeves.
I've got a million of them myself.
So what other things make you
crazy when it comes to food? Uh,
I think the thing that makes me the most
crazy in food is just when people try
too hard and they try to be
something that they're not. Like,
there's nothing more than I love them.
And I got a perfect fried wing
or like an awesome burger.
But I hate when there's like food that's
looks all fancy but tastes like crap.
Like, it's like just, just, you know,
if you can do food that's beautiful
and super welcome post and, and like,
I appreciate that too.
It's not that I don't like that,
but if you're just on foam everywhere
and doing all of some weird concoctions
because that's sort of trendy.
Like I hate the trends in food ag grill,
just well executed food and you can tell
it has a lot of love in it and a lot of
authenticity in it. And I think that
that for me is his most important. Um,
so I, I did generally, that's the
thing that like the determined
my experience, uh, and eating and
eating somebody's food. That was,
that was something that really surprised
me when I got to know quite a few
shifts in writing. The four chef was
that, uh, when they came to visit,
say my house for dinner or someone else
says the last thing they wanted to have
was a five course meal.
Yeah.
Like the last thing they wanted to have
with some type of foam sprayed onto
their plate with like tweezer cuisine
on top of it. They're just like, no,
just give me like a,
a really fatty burger or something
really simple that I can enjoy consuming.
Uh, the, uh, what, what made the,
the White House Garden unique?
Cause I know that,
that a lot of thought went into that
and I've become, I've never gardened,
uh, but I'd become very fascinated by
it because I, when I went to, uh, this,
this village called Ogi me in
Okinawa at one point, it has the,
the longest median lifespan in the world
and I just noticed that nearly everyone
gardened in some capacity.
Um,
so what made the White
House Garden unique?
Uh, well there's a lot unique
about that garden. Um, you know,
one is the first garden since Eleanor
Roosevelt Victory Garden during World War
II, which was a really
powerful symbolic garden,
but it was actually quite small and
really didn't produce food to eat. Um,
so the White House Garden,
the first age garden is really the
first garden since the late 1890s,
and that, that actually produced food.
Um, and, you know, it was designed,
it's whole purpose was to really
shine a light on, on food,
where it comes from, how it's grown,
how hard it is to grow good food,
and really lift up farmers all over
America that are producing the,
the nourishment that we need to survive
and, um, and, and make it educational.
And I, and I think that's
really it. You know,
so it was a working last card and
that we ate from every day. Um,
but also we had kids come down for,
towards tours on a weekly basis.
The kids would come and plant with the
first lady and then harvest and cook with
her a couple of times a year.
We had a compost.
It's a really talk about the importance
of giving back to the soil building soil
fertility, which is a huge
issue across the country. Um,
and we also had the first ever beehive on
the White House grounds, um, which, uh,
which is, which is just awesome.
And we got tons of honey,
but also could talk to the kids about
pollinators and why they're so important.
And we have a huge,
huge problem with Paul,
a climate colony collapse
disorder and we're,
we're losing bees and other pollinators
that, you know, really alarming rates,
which have massive implications
for our economy and our ability to,
to produce food. So,
you know, I think, um,
when you look at the whole picture and
what it's accomplished since that garden
planted gardening across the country
is skyrocket, it's up over 30%.
Um, and uh, so it's been a really
exciting and, and it was just,
it was a ton of fun.
You mentioned,
you mentioned a couple of things
that I think are really important.
The magnitude of the impact of B is
something I never really understood and I
still need to understand more, but, uh,
people talking about the butterfly
effect and the like, you know,
the be affect sort of the ripple,
the cascade of different sort of ecosystem
changes that bees are involved with
is really astonishing.
The second thing I would encourage people
to look into is what you mentioned,
which is the soil depletion.
And I remember at one point,
maybe one of the listeners can, can
find this, but seeing data that, uh,
I believe it was from China that looked
at the incidence and frequency of a
cancer diagnosis in
different regions in China.
And you could pretty much predict how
much cancer there would be based on a top
soil depletion in different
regions because they would
end up with trace mineral
deficiencies like selenium
and so on. Um, and uh,
I remember reading
about this at one point,
if something like in certain areas
because of a mono crops, you know,
like the wheat and soy and so on. In the
u s the top soil has gone from whatever,
10 feet to like 10 inches.
And what do you think needs to be done
or what can be done to help reverse that
trend?
So there's a, there's a lot that needs
to be done. And I'd say it's, it's a,
a topic that doesn't get anywhere
near the attention that it deserves.
But everything comes, everything
is based on the health of our soil.
It is the reason why we have such a
prosperous nation was that we had the best
soil in the world and it helped us
produce a surplus of crops, which allowed,
um,
you know,
big parts of our population to go on and
build and create and do other things.
Um, and the, the,
the dramatic loss across the nation on,
on our,
on our topsoil is something that is,
it couldn't be a more important issue
and it couldn't be a harder one to make,
get people excited about cause I got
dark. Like, what are you talking about?
You know, uh, there's lots of
things that need to be done. Um,
and I think they're
starting to see some change.
I think people are starting
to note to wake up to this,
we need to do much better job at rotating
our crops to rebuild fertility right
now where we're basically growing up just
a couple of crops and using synthetic
fertilizers to sort of make up for
the lack of fertility in the soil.
That's a problem. We're
having all kinds of, uh, of,
of problems from stemming from that
run off in our water. You know,
massive algae blooms and
the golf killing sees life,
there's lots of lots of
challenges going on there.
So I think we need to rotate crops.
I think we need to change our practices
to really focus on rebuilding that
fertility, um, using
different, uh, sources of,
of fertilizer and natural fertilizers.
And you're starting to see people taking
back some of that land and rebuilding
and hopefully that will continue
to grow. And people, I mean,
I think are going to continually have
to ask, you know, work on, you know,
sourcing food that's coming from farmers
that are, you know, uh, you know,
doing those kind of practices that are,
are more sustainable.
I think the thing that people don't
realize that if we use those kinds of
practices, that is the best, one of the
best tools we have to sequester carbon.
So agriculture is not only a challenge
to when it comes to sustainability and
our environmental challenges with,
with greenhouse gas emissions, it's a,
it's a significant producer of,
but it actually,
unlike other aspects of the challenge,
it can actually be part of the solution.
And so there's a,
there's,
there's exciting opportunity there that
we don't see in too many other sectors
that need to change.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm excited about the potential for a
kind of soil replenishment because I feel
like it could be effective in marketing
product. Does that make sense?
Like there's a,
there's a kind of economic self interest
that I think could be harnessed if
somebody could create the proper
campaign. Um, what, uh, what do you see,
or what do you think the
future is, if any of, uh,
say organic subsidies for
people who really want to,
or large companies that really want to
produce organic produce but view it as
cost prohibitive or,
or something along those lines?
Yeah,
so this is obviously a very complicated,
a complicated question and I'm really
complicated politics. I think the place,
and this again,
is hard to get people super excited about,
but I think the place to really start is
in research. So over the last 50 years,
we poured the vast
majority. I mean, you know,
hundreds and hundreds
of millions of dollars,
billions of dollars into researching
just a couple of crops. Uh, and,
uh, fruits and vegetables, uh,
writ large have not gotten,
mostly it's gone to corn and soy, some
weed, but mostly corn and soy. Um,
and that is a loud corn and soy to be
produced much more efficiently than it
used to. And so a lot of the
price difference, we talk
about the relative cost of,
of,
of say sugar and other things versus uh,
a fruit or a vegetable.
It is because we figured out how to
grow those crops much more efficiently.
And so if we invest that same kind of
research to try to figure out how to grow
foods and vegetables more efficiently,
we're going to make up a lot of the
ground. Now part of the challenges that,
you know, the people who are currently
growing say the fruits and vegetables,
no matter whether they're doing
it organic or not organic,
they liked the fact that they're the
only ones growing it so they not support
subsidies for other people to
grow more fruits and vegetables.
That's interesting. So there's really
tough politics because in Washington,
if the people you're trying
to help are against you,
it's going to be very hard
to move anything through.
It's hard to move anything through if
they're with you because there's always
going to, people meet people on
the other side fighting very hard,
investing a lot of money
and seeing that not happen.
So in this particular one is the politics
are really hard to get Congress to,
to the shift where we're putting some
of these substances now on the organic
side,
which is a different set of questions.
I think the market's going to have to
continue to drive the change and you're
seeing organic, um, uh, you know,
continue to grow at a very rapid way.
Although it's a still a very
small part of the overall, uh,
food economy.
But I think the more consumers demand it,
I think the more it's going to get grown
and it's going to become increasingly
more affordable for farmers to, to produce
it when we get some more scale there.
Yeah, it's a, it's a such
a thorny, gnarly topic.
Uh, and, uh, I would,
I would suggest just as a side note for
folks who perhaps want to eat organic
but have to pick and choose for
financial reasons or otherwise,
there's a list called the dirty dozen
and I think it might be the clean 15,
which is sort of the,
the 12 items produce items that are
best avoided that have the highest
concentrations of pesticides. But I think
the research is really, as you noted,
super important because if a,
it's one thing in the abstract to say
organic is better for reasons a, B,
and C of and avoiding
synthetic pesticides.
But if someone could actually look at say,
the,
the endocrin impact of estrogenic
compounds that are found in a synthetic
fertilizers so that therefore affect
fertility or whatever, then I think the,
it could get more airtime.
Um,
I will, I will, I will say just on one
thing, on this point though, you know,
I think people should try to
eat organic when they can,
but I think they need to eat fruits
and vegetables first and foremost.
So I think part of the, the thing to
be concerned about is, wow, um, I,
I would much rather
people eat a conventional,
any conventional food,
vegetable then like organic
chips or organic cupcakes.
Right, right. And I think, um,
you know, we're getting better,
people are raising more awareness.
Our agricultural practices are
getting better largely because this,
I was getting more and more expensive.
So farmers are learning how to be more
diligent about their applications.
There's obviously a lot,
lot longer to go,
but there's going to be some things that
we're going to need some insecticides
and pesticides and I think that's okay as
long as they're being used responsibly.
Um, but, uh, but I don't want people, I
think part of that we need to avoid is,
um, sort of fear based,
uh, if you eat this,
it's going to kill you because there's
just not the evidence there. There,
there's,
there's reasons for serious concern and,
and continue engagement in pushing
on some of these topics. But,
but it shouldn't keep anybody from,
uh,
from consuming that kind of a balanced
diet that, that we know is important.
Do you,
um,
so there was an article that came out
recently by Steve Case called the future
food is food. Uh, what
do you, what is your,
what are your thoughts on meal
replacements like soylent?
And so I actually tweeted about,
I tweeted about that article. I, I
couldn't agree with what's the more,
I mean Steve Basically makes the
argument that sort of high tech,
uh, artists like artificially
put together, uh,
drinks that you know, are based
on some science, you know,
Kinda could replace food. Um,
and I think the vision for,
for the folks that swelling is that
they can create a perfect meal.
So instead of eating a bunch of junk,
you can just conveniently drink this. Um,
so I, I, I don't, I
don't hate the sort of,
the vision there in the sense that
they're trying to do something good,
but if the future is a
disgusting, tasteless, uh,
soulless beverage to sustain,
you know, just to keep us alive,
that's not a future. I have much
interest in being a part of, I think,
I think it lacks authenticity.
I think at lax flavor,
I think it lacks happiness.
And Joy and all of that
goes into what a good,
good nourishment means to me.
And I think I see a role pre
made with elderly people and,
and others for improved sort of
dietary supplement, you know, uh,
meals like that. But I don't think
that's a solution that, uh, I,
for one, have any interest
in participating in, uh, uh,
I think real good food grown properly
that supports the people who are growing
at that supports the health of
the people who are eating it.
That is damn good is where
we should all be, you know,
driving for.
Yeah.
I've,
I've done an about face on this stuff
because I've always been a kind of
supplement addict and,
uh,
been infatuated with pills and potions
and whatnot as, as supplementation.
But I mean,
there's,
they're called supplements for a reason
and I've really found that I'm echoing
the sentiment of say, Nassim Taleb
wrote the Black Swan and antifragile.
So he uses a term called a
epistemological or, yeah,
epistemological arrogance,
which is overestimating how much you
understand about it. Anything as a human,
and I think it's naive to think I've
come to this conclusion anyway that you
can,
that we would understand every element
of what's in an apple for instance,
or what's in a slice of
Ribeye. Like we, we just,
there's so much uncharted territory that
it's naive to think we could take the
four or five things we've isolated,
put them in a pill and,
and, uh, sort of confer the same
nutritional benefit for instance.
I mean, that's kind of pointing
them a one, but, um, yeah, it's,
it's a very interesting, it's a
very fascinating subject, but I've,
I've gone completely in the,
in the whole food direction just trying
to consume a spectrum of colors every
day, for instance. Yeah. Um, the, um,
so can I, do I want to add
some of that? Yeah, yeah.
I think that is on the nutritional side
that that basic point and understanding
of our limitations couldn't be more,
right.
I mean we've tried very
hard to kind of reduce, uh,
our health to one vitamin or fiber or
this or that in a very reductionist way
and utterly miss the interplay between
all of these different vitamins,
nutrients,
fiber,
protein and also by the way completely
miss how our body processes.
So it's turning out that, you know, we
have 100 trillion bacteria in our gut,
100 trillion, which really what
we're doing is feeding that bacteria,
which then in turn feeds
us and it's going to,
the evidence is emerging
that the microbiome,
the gut bacteria is going to be one of
the most important things to focus on in
terms of improving our health.
And that we've lost quite a bit of
diversity in our gut and we don't,
but there's,
you know,
a couple hundred a species of bacteria
in our gut a little less and we are just
trying to figure out what does, what
and how they interact. And it's,
everybody's different. The complexities
here are just overwhelming. Um,
we know that they need to
be fed a high diet of fiber,
lots of fruits and vegetables.
Basically what they feed and from birth.
So like we, for a long time there
was parts of breast milk, the wheat,
the baby's couldn't digest
and we didn't understand.
We didn't think they were important,
but turns out actually all those
elements in breast milk are feeding the
emerging biome and the
young and the baby's got,
which is then gives it deals with the
immune and inflammation and all these
vital things and,
and digesting of food.
So there's like the complexity is beyond
anything that we can comprehend right
now. And, um,
I think we have continually like
w over and over tried to say was,
oh, it's fat as the problem.
And like turns out, okay,
wait, fat's not the problem.
Well, it's a deficiency in Omega
this and I'll, okay, well turns out,
well that's good, but it's not. Certainly
they'll panacea that was made out to be,
you know, every time we do this we get it
wrong. And so I, I agree with you. I mean,
I think there's some things that have
been tested over the Millennia and um,
which his, that kind of balance,
good diet of whole grains.
And lots of fruits and vegetables and
lean proteins. And I think that's where,
um, we, we were safest is
when we stay in that kind of,
uh,
that kind of space.
And I'm glad you mentioned safest
because it's not just, oops,
I didn't cover all my bases. When you
take a very reductionist approach,
for instance, when people, uh,
when the media got its hands on the
so called promises a Beta carotene,
right? People started consuming massive
amounts of Beta carotene in isolation.
It can actually cause a lot of problems
when you're not sort of consuming it and
it's natural, uh, environment,
so to speak. But yeah,
I'd love to shift gears and ask you
some, uh, some rapid fire questions.
They don't have to have
rapid answers, but, um,
when you think of the word successful,
who's the first person
who comes to mind and why?
Mm, well, two people come
to mind. Uh, Barack Obama,
uh, and my, and my father, but
for wildly different reasons. Uh,
I mean, Barack Obama's,
you know, success to me,
I measure based on,
um,
impact and the amount of impact that
I'm somebody who's trying to have in a
positive way on the world around him.
Nothing money or,
but it's sort of what you do with the
place that you've been given and you know,
um, there's lots of legitimate
disagreements in, in,
in politics and I'm sure there's
legitimate disagreements with some of the
things that the president has has
done. And, but he is, you know,
I know firsthand on a daily basis
that here's somebody who trying to,
and it has had a massive positive
impact on the world around him. So that,
that's something that, um, you know, I,
I very much look up to and admire and,
and you know, in my small, much, much,
much smaller way,
try to figure out how I can
have the biggest positive
impact on the world around
me. And I'd say, but on the flip side,
you know, but that takes, you know,
there's a lot of ambition that
goes with that and I'll, you know,
disappointments when you fail. Um,
on the flip side, like success,
my father is, um, he is a,
he's a fifth grade teacher.
Has He just retired
after 25 years? Um, uh,
he lives at an incredibly humble
life and, you know, as a, you know,
a union guy growing up and, and, and the,
and the teacher and in a union guy
and sort of in the school. And He, um,
he, he's utterly content. Uh, he,
he has a good community of
friends. He's, you know,
has a roof over his head and, and,
and meals on his table. In fact,
when I first went to that
restaurant in Chicago,
he had never spent $20
on a meal for himself,
which I only found out when I invited
them in for a meal at the end of my summer
time there. Um, so he's
just very content in,
in like the simple pleasures and
the sort of a simple life. And I,
and that's something that,
um, uh, is, you know, I,
I also try to take into what
success looks like is, is,
is that kind of contentness and
being appreciative of, of a,
of what you have,
right. Having the appreciation, not
just the drive for achievement. Yeah.
What's,
what book or what is a book that you've
gifted most often are gifted very often
to other people.
Mm.
Have gift in Dod and pushing around the
art of fielding over the last year or
two, uh, by Chad Harbach.
I love that book. Um,
it's like, it's, it's, so it's a baseball
theme, but it's really about life and,
and all that goes with
that and complexities of
relationships. And I don't know,
there's something that book just sucked
me in and I love the feeling of being
sucked in, which, you know,
it doesn't happen with that
intensity too often. So I,
that was a good one.
The Art of fielding. Are there
any, uh, any documentaries,
documentary films or movies that
have sucked you in, in that way?
Hmm. I love documentaries.
I'm a, I'm a big fan, uh,
and a good and a great movie as well.
The,
the last one I just saw
actually it just came out, um,
which I really loved called just
eat it and it's about food waste.
We waste 40% of the food we produce,
uh,
which is just insane.
There's no other major like life
system that is so inefficient.
And then it's about this couple that,
um, basically for, I forget how long,
six months decides the only eat food
that they has been wasted that they find
thrown away in some way, shape or
form. And it's unbelievable stories.
So really well done.
It's only an hour. Um,
I think it just aired on Msnbc actually,
but they,
they are having to have to give away
food. They find so much of that, um,
they can't eat it all and it's, so, it
was very powerful. Very well done. Um,
but that's the one that's top of mind.
Awesome. Check that out. That,
uh, makes me think there's a book,
a read a long time ago,
I think it was called the man who gave
up money or the men who stopped using
money,
something along those lines.
But it delves into sort of the
dumpster diving freegan movement,
I guess they call them instead of
vegans. Really fascinating. Um, what's,
uh,
what's hundred dollars or less purchase
has had the biggest positive impact on
your life in the last six
months to a year? Let's just,
whatever comes to mind doesn't
have to be in that time frame.
Um, yeah, the recent purchase, I
got a, I got a kindle or recently,
which I now before, uh, which
has been great. Uh, you know, I,
I know people, I'm like
way behind, you know,
behind the curve and not the highest tech
way to read, read, read things. But it's,
but it's been great because I'm all over
the place and, and so that's helped.
I also got an ice bucket and uh,
uh,
it's made the rose aid that much
colder as summer's starting to hit.
And that's been, oh, an
investment. Well, worthwhile.
That's a good call. Ice Bucket. Yeah.
Lovers and there's a great, you know,
I, um, grew up on long island.
There's a wonderful rosé
from a wolf or a states. Uh,
I know that it's really good
winemaker. Roman is just amazing.
I'm not too expensive either. What,
what does the first 60
minutes of your day look like?
Do you,
what are morning rituals,
whether when you were at the White
House or now that have been consistent?
Um, so pretty consistent
basic routine. Um,
the one variable and that like,
I used to do a lot more.
I don't do it anymore.
Like first thing I love to do from a
perfect world is to do a short stint of
meditation for like 10 or 15 minutes.
It's been hard for me to keep
those impossible for me to do that.
The White House for whatever reason,
I just think mentally quieting and
slowing my mind was just something that is
just say, wouldn't do as hard as hard
as I tried. Um, and exhaustion, uh,
also played a role, but I wake up and, um,
a workout, uh, five or
six days a week. Um,
do about 30 minutes of Cardio and
then do weights, uh, various, uh,
sort of sets. What type of cardio
do you do? So I'll do 10 minutes,
uh,
on the bike and then now I'm
been doing a 12 minute interval,
interval run, run. And then I'm,
I'm doing like another 10 minutes, uh, in,
in like 12 incline walking
at 3.5 on the treadmill. Um,
sometimes I do the elliptical,
I'm in there and then,
and then do weights.
Um, and then, and then,
uh, so the White House, it was always,
you know, take a shower, get ready,
and then I do oatmeal, a banana
and coffee. Since I'd been,
uh, out of the White House
I've been doing eggs. Um,
one of the, you know,
a couple of ways, uh,
some of my Colby tell us maybe some
avocado, salmon and then, and, and coffee.
That's been the routine
and then a way I go.
Do you do it? Do you do anything
in particular before bed?
Uh hmm. I don't have that
same kind of routine at night.
Often cause nights there's
like much more variable.
Like the morning has always been
the time that I take for myself, um,
and carve out because after that it's
like anybody's guess what's going to
happen. Um, but try to, you know,
try to come bring down a little bit.
But oftentimes, and certainly the White
House, I was working until one, two,
three in the morning, um,
pretty consistently. So, um,
it was sorta like you
worked til you fell off,
fell off your chair and call it to bed
and then got up a few hours later and it
started doing it all over again. So, um,
so I don't have that same
kind of night routine. Got It.
And when you, when you meditated,
what type of meditation did you do?
What did that,
what did that look like?
Um, so I, so I, the,
the woman who taught me is one of the
most amazing people I've ever known. Um,
she was an 80 year old woman,
uh,
who was actually from France who I met
when I was traveling on the border of
Malaysia and Thailand
on an overnight train.
She was 80 years old and she had spent
the last 20 plus years of her life just
traveling with a teeny little
for like eight pound backpack.
And that's all she had.
And she went everywhere and she was just
the most amazing person and she, um,
so it's like a, you know, but she's not
like a, you know, formal teacher. So,
you know, just trying to sit up, you know,
have good posture and just, you know,
fundamentally relax and
focus on my breathing is like
as sophisticated as I got.
Um, and trying to let your
mind relax and repeating that,
forcing your mind to get back to
that state, which is, you know,
it's always been such a
challenge. It's so hard. Um, uh,
has as sort of how I would do it
for as long as I, as, as I could.
But when I do it, I feel so much
better and so much more grounded and,
and sort of calm through the day.
It's a,
but it takes a lot of discipline to
carve out the time. Um, in any given day.
Yeah. I've found for myself because I
meditate 15, 20 minutes each morning,
Eh, usually 20, uh, two things
really interesting. Number one,
it takes about 15 minutes for me just to
let the dust and the or the mud settle.
Um,
so I really only feel like I'm meditating
in the calm sensor last five minutes,
but it's the you need,
I need the 15 minutes just as a warm up
or cool down maybe. And then secondly,
that posture I've noticed if I just
sit with very good posture and kind of
lengthen my spine, imagine my head
being kind of pulled up on a string.
Even if I don't get to some sublime state.
If I just focus and sit
that way for 20 minutes,
there's a huge benefit for
me anyway. I feel the same
way about that. Yup. Yup. Uh,
we'd love to ask some questions from,
uh,
people on Facebook and Twitter who were
very excited that we were going to be
chatting. Uh, the first is a tough
one. Uh, but it's from Andrew Zimmern.
Uh, Oh, I love that man.
He's awesome. Andrew's great.
That also has been on the podcast
and he wanted to ask some questions.
He hears them very often,
he gets asked them very often and it's
always curious how other people answer
them. So the first is, uh,
if it's illegal to sell cigarettes
to minors or drugs, slash. Booze,
why do we let fast food or
sugar drinks into schools?
Yeah, so, great question. So
a couple points. So one, uh,
because of the new standards,
uh, that are in play, um,
there are no more sugary drinks
in schools and those are out. Um,
and I actually need to give the, you
know, the beverage homies credit,
they actually volunteerily voluntarily
pulled out most of those beverages around
starting in around 2007.
But the new standards utterly
eliminate all sugary drinks.
You can have a low calorie in high school,
you could have a low calorie Gatorade
and you can have no calorie drinks.
So Diet Sodas are allowed in high schools,
not in middle schools and
certainly not in lower schools. Um,
so those drinks are out
on the fast food side. Um,
I have always been pretty
appalled that as some of these,
particularly the last healthy companies
have set up shop in high schools.
Now this is not ubiquitous by
any stretch of the imagination,
but they definitely exist in some number.
And I actually need to look and see
because their food does not meet the
standards. So unless they're
changing their offerings.
So I am not sure how many,
like where,
where they are in the evolution of either
what they're offering in schools or if
some of them have had to pull
out, you know, the truth is,
I don't know the answer that,
but I'll,
I'll dig into that and come back
to you on it. Um, but I agree.
I think it's really inappropriate
to be serving,
you know, have a fast food, pretty
unhealthy restaurant set up in a,
in a high school.
I find that to be,
I've always found that
to be very off putting.
Cool. Uh, yeah,
we'd love for people listening
who participate on the blog. Uh,
obviously there'll be a post with all
the links and resources and so on,
including things like, uh, you know,
organizations like American farmland
trust that have done stuff with,
if you want to sort of get
involved with some of these things.
But I would love to hear ideas for what
types of campaigns or angles could be
taken to remedy that from folks. Uh,
I do pay attention to the comments up.
Next question is from cinema air.
This is on Twitter. Best use of wine,
that's too old to drink.
So, um, you know, depending on the kind
of wine and you know, I think there's,
there's probably a little mad at depending
on where you are and how it goes,
but you know, that's how you
make vinegar. So, uh, you know,
grape juice turns into vinegar,
right? So, um, there you could, you,
depending on how close you can use
it, kind of in that, in that way,
a lot of people use it for
cooking, but you know, no,
no real chef would say you should,
uh, if it's not good to drink,
whether it's really not good to cook with.
So the truth is like there's a,
there's not much to do with it. I
gotta be honest. I would get that.
At least not that I know. Um, maybe
somebody out there has got a good thing,
but basically like drink it before
it goes bad is my best advice to you.
And you know, the thing that, you know,
if you get just one of those simple air
pumps with, with the, with the rubber top,
it pulls the air out, you add, you know,
a week or two depending on the wine,
a life to it. And that's what I use.
You know, we use that in our house. Um,
and it makes a big difference
because there's nothing worth,
there's like one of the worst feelings
in the world is dumping out a half a
bottle of wine that you didn't
get the finish. Yeah. Pain.
The, the vacuum is really cheap
and really effective. I, yeah,
I use the same device,
uh, on that point. Uh,
Stephan, I think it's Stephan. Um,
Bendel what should home chefs stop doing?
So wasting wine would be one.
Wow. What should home chef that doing?
La, there's, there's a few things.
Um, watch it. Home chefs started.
Do I need to spend more time with home
chefs to give you the best answer?
I think dragging the knife across the
cutting board like as like a shovel is
something that like you
never supposed to do.
If you need to like move like
the vegetables of scoop them up,
use the backside of the knife,
but like scraping the knife on the
cutting board just drives me crazy.
It's just really bad for your
knife. Dulls it immediately. Um,
something that I cringe at. I think,
um, chest, the home cooks need to um,
work with heat. Uh, I like
not be afraid of, of of heat.
More so particularly when you're sharing
fish, it's like you need that pant hat.
And so letting,
like putting it in,
like getting your pants super hot and
then putting your fish down and leaving it
and not touching it and letting
it get that Nice, you know,
a good sear, good Golden Brown
on it before you touch it.
It's like key to fish and those, most
people don't get their pan hot enough,
don't heat it,
don't ever get it out and up.
Don't take the time to heat it and
then play around with the fish, which,
which ends up really hurting. It's its
ultimate um, feel. But I think allowing,
I think babies,
the one thing that's the big difference
between a pro and a home cook is that
like the see the getting
real color on things.
Be it meat or any vegetable that's on
the grill or anything you're putting in
the pan. Like just let it go
when you think it's like ready.
Like give it another minute or
two and like get that really dark,
dark color on it.
It adds a ton of flavor.
When can you tell that your pan is hot
enough for that nice sear on a fish.
So like when you put the oil in,
like you don't want it to immediately
start smoking. Like then your oils done.
Like, don't put it in there. If it's
like you put it in, it's like smoke,
but like you should see the oil,
get that kind of those lines in it,
that kind of Shimmer and it should just
start to go off a little bit of like you
could see to us and little that
a smoke. Um, that's when you're,
you're ready to go. But
it should be like, ha.
Like when you put it in and she'd be like,
you're like,
it shouldn't be like go crazy. Like if
it's just like a little mild bubble,
like you're not,
you weren't ready.
And what, what type of oil do you like
to use with, with fish? For instance?
Um, you know, you can use a
lot. Like you can use olive oil,
it has a lower smoke point, but you
can, you can get away with it. Um,
I like grape seed oil is a great
oil to cook with. Um, uh, you know,
you can do high. He canola
is totally fine. Um,
uh, those are probably the main ones
to go with. Peanut oil is awesome.
That's expensive.
Yeah.
I've been playing myself a little bit
with avocado oil because it has high omega
three content, decent smoke
point, but it's so rich
depending on the food UniKey easily or
enhance or completely contaminate what
you're doing to try to make,
uh,
this question is from chaos and Nata.
Uh,
when you fall into a Rut in the kitchen,
uh,
what book resource or person
do you turn to for inspiration?
Oh, interesting. Um, so I
don't, yeah, it's a good,
I mean I try to get out and eat or go
to the store or go like see and feel and
touch and smell is the thing
that I try to do when I'm,
when I'm just sort of feel dad and
use the actual ingredient soon,
inspire what I'm going to do. But I'd
say the book that I read that I look at,
I really don't look at
cookbooks a ton anymore,
but the one recently that I have is all
of auto language's books are awesome.
How do you, Oh, wait a second
here. I know this name. Uh, how,
how do you spell that
name or the first name?
Um, a little lag at
lemme. Lemme. Um, O. O. T.
T. O. L. E. N. Uh, let me let,
let me just pull it up for you.
Um, Ott, o. L. E. N. G. H. I,
uh, he is an incredible chef.
Him and his partner, uh,
actually one is, he's a, you know,
there are Palestinian and Israeli,
uh, uh, team couple and um,
they have plenty is probably
their most famous book,
but they have Jerusalem and plenty more.
Their books are just spectacular and
the recipes are simple but so delicious.
Um, I, I definitely cooked a few
out of them and they're always,
they're always awesome.
If someone is new to healthy cooking,
where would you suggest they start?
What could they start with as
anything simple they could,
they could use to get the ball
rolling in terms of like a dish,
a dish, stocking the kitchen.
Unstacking stocking the kitchen. It was,
it's, it's a general question. So I'd say
you can interpret it any way you want.
So I think the key is
like starting simple.
And I think people whenever
they approached like, okay,
I want to make a change.
They think I got to overhaul everything.
And so then they tried to do a dramatic
thing and then then of course it's not
sustainable.
You can't keep that up.
You revert back to kind of who you've
been and it then you just completely
stopped. So I would think like little
things. So one place to start is vinegar.
If you want to start with a small like
getting really good vinegar makes us like
a salad, go from really
uninspired, so really delicious.
So one place that I did
actually invest a little,
if you're going to invest a little
resource in is getting some really nice
vinegar to make really beautiful
salads and salads or like some, some,
some kind of green, like a good combo
is some kind of some kind of leaf. Um,
some kind of texture. We had cucumber,
fennel or you know, various things,
acidity. So you could add, you
know, any kind of citrus fruit,
there's always great or
just a really nice vinegar,
some nuts of some kind and achieves.
There's unkind,
like a farmer Xan or Pecorino
or different, if you like,
that kind of basic components. It's hard
to really make it terrible. Sometimes,
Geez can throw you off.
So you can play around with that.
But you get good texture,
you get good flavor.
And if you have a nice vinegar like the
world is yours and that's a really good
place to just add some salad on
and you know, to your dinner is a,
is a great place to start. But I would
just try to add a piece of fruit,
try to add another thing
of vegetables at dinner.
Like if you just start there,
those two things.
And I think the other main thing to
start is drinking more water. Um, it,
there's nothing better than water.
The more water you drink,
the less sugary beverages
you're going to drink,
which is really key if you're going
to try to live a healthier life.
And um, you know that that's a great
place to start. And then from there,
you can you build from there.
Yeah.
The one or just to echo that for people
who might be following a diet of any
type of slow carb or Paleo or
whatever to try to lose fat.
If your liver is burdened
by even partial dehydration,
it's just not going to do a very good
job of helping you to you to oxidize fat.
So I've, I've noticed tremendously even
with getting into say ketosis because I'm
experimenting with that more water.
I drink, the more I walk, uh,
the better off I am, the faster I'll drop
into a state of ketosis. Um, but, uh, the,
the other thing,
just on your point with nuts and cheese,
if, if I've, it seems
like with almost any dish,
if someone wants to
impress a dinner guest,
just put Parmesan and sliced almonds
on anything and it looks real.
It looks really fancy and
it tastes amazing. Yeah. Uh,
and on that note, uh, this
is, will McClellan, uh,
there may not be a best meal, but what's
the best meal to impress a girl with?
But it's easy to make. This
is, I'm sure a question.
This is guys have a phobia. A lot of
guys have cooking in any capacity.
So what would be one meal that might
impress a girl? But that is easy to make.
That's funny. Uh, well I was just talking
to one of my best friends, in fact,
that guy who was with me in Vienna
and then he was telling me about, uh,
a date he was on in just yesterday
and he was saying, Oh yeah,
I cook that risotto again. I, you know,
he's like, man, yeah, you tell me that,
that one time. And I've grown with
that for the last 10 years. Uh,
I think it was, oh, it's a really
good, very easy dish, uh, to make that,
um, that you can do a lot of things with
that seems very fancy and impressive,
but isn't that hard. Uh, basic
risotto is you start, you know,
start with like an onion or shallot.
You Cook that down, you cook your rice,
you have a stock of some kind,
so you can buy a nice chicken stock or uh,
seafood stock depending on what you're
gonna put in there and make sure that hot
and then you're just adding some stock
as you go and you go. So sorry, onions.
And then you put the rice in it,
mix it around a little white
wine and let that evaporate.
And then you're just adding stock as
you go until the rice is like done.
Do you want it to be a little, you know,
dente that you want it to be a little,
have a little tooth to it's
you don't want it mushy. Um,
and then just finish it
with whatever you want.
If you're going to have like some scallops
and there you can do a whole seafood
thing. You can do a lamb or Zoho, you
could, you can do a vegetable risotto,
you can do anything you want and it's
hard to mess it up because you finish it
with a little butter or some olive oil
and a bunch of Parmesan cheese. So like,
it's like hard to go wrong there.
Um,
and it's sort of one of those dishes that,
uh,
it's hard to make it
perfect, but it's, it's,
it's easy to make it good,
easy to make it good.
It's so true for so many
things in life. Right. Um, so,
so I want to get a little granular on
this cause that actually like to try to
make it this weekend. So you, you, you
take the onions or shallots, those are,
uh, pretty thinly sliced, right?
You want a dice those up, you want to
make them very small dice, like a mint.
Got It. And then you throw that
in the pan or pot, I guess,
pot in this case with some like
olive oil and you just, uh,
would you have olive oil?
Would you,
would you have some type of
oil in there to start with?
Yup. Yup. So yeah, some olive oil, you put
that in and you cook it a little bit. Um,
then you put in your rice and you know,
you've,
depending on how many people you have,
you know, Cup Cup to two cups. You know,
if you're not doing a ton, you know, a
cup of rice should probably be enough.
If it's too, we'll will be enough. Two
people, then you cook that a little bit,
get that covered and coded
and then you add, you know,
a bit of of white wine.
Now the stock is the
stock already in there.
The stock's not in.
Their stock should be in a separate,
separate pot and it should be,
you should, it should be hot.
You should bring that to a boil
and keep that warm. Got It. Um,
onions. Then the cook that down and let
it kind of caramelize a little bit. Uh,
not, you don't want to color on it, you
don't want to color. Okay. And then you,
then you had the rise, then you
add, so you have a cup of rice.
How much white wine
would you put in there?
Yeah, I'm not sure. And I'm
not a great recipe guy. Like,
you just want to get a nice like couple
of splashes in, they're like, oh,
that's fine. I don't know, maybe like
a quarter cup. Okay. Um, at the most.
And then you, you cook that down. So you
want, when you, when you know you're,
you want to get rid of all the alcohol.
So you know that like when you lean
over the potty, you kind of put the,
what's evaporating kind of you,
you put your mouth nose over that.
If it kind of burns the
inside of your nose,
you know that there's
still alcohol burning off.
And like once that sort of burning
sensation comes and it's just like, okay,
that smells good, then you know,
you're, you're ready to go.
It should be pretty dry. It
should be drive basically, um,
before you then start adding your stock.
Got It. And then how long once
you had the stock, is the,
this sort of cocktail, is it on like
a medium feed or what's the heat?
Yeah. So you want it to
be a nice simmer, um,
uncovered simmer and you only use a
wooden spoon because you don't want to
damage the rice and you only want to
use a Borio rice. Really important, uh,
which is a nice starchy rice.
So you'll get a good,
a nice starchy kind of a broth.
And so when you, so yeah, so you,
so you just add the stock as you
go. So you cook it, you know,
it'll start absorbing you guys. Okay. I'll
need some more. You started absorbing,
you keep adding and now if you run out
of stock you can finish with water.
No problem. Um, uh, you know,
you want to heat the water up.
You don't want to put in a cold liquid
into your Giotto cause that stops all the
cooking process and kind of start breaking
down the rights over if you do that
too much
decided I'm going to try this this weekend
because it seems like you could also,
for instance with like scallops which
are so deceptively easy to cook,
you can kind of muck around
with the risotto and if
you're kind of flying by the
seat of your pants and
half screwing it up,
since the scallops only take whenever you
know, four minutes, two minutes to cook,
um, you can kind of do it last
minute and just drop them in.
Yeah. So for like if you're using
the base cops, the little guy,
it's like basically when you were,
Zoho is basically done or just, yeah,
you put them in,
you just give it a stir and he'd turn
it off and like they'll basically cooked
through, uh, just as it settles cause
you want, you'll want, so at the end,
so you cook it, it's getting close
whenever you're done. So like Bateman,
it's basically done.
Then you put in your primary John
and you put it in some butter,
you put in a little olive oil
and you give that a good stir,
you're going to want to let it just
rest for a minute and it'll kind of come
together. If it dries up, like
when you put it on the plate,
you wanted to just kind
of relax onto the plate.
Like you don't want to hold up and kind
of a ball. You don't want to run either.
So you may need to add a little
stock to you, make it, you know,
it should feel like it's got a little
soft but if not saucy, right? And,
but then you can literally
add whatever you want.
Any kind of herbs at any
flavor profile that you like.
Like if I love Bazell
asparagus and Zucchini,
I can add that at the end.
Let that basically warm up.
And you guys just have a beautiful
[inaudible] if you're doing scallops.
I love like a lemon seafood risotto
so you can add a bunch of lemon juice,
a ton of lemon.
Jeff possessed like lots of lemons asked,
maybe Swedes have a Lennon and say
shrimp and scallops and an terragon.
It's a great herb for that one
killer risotto. So you can,
that one will impress any, any
lady, m whoever, whoever asked that.
I'm going to try that. The Saturday.
A question from Carrie Kim Minsky.
Uh, what dish have you most
frequently made for house guests?
Wow.
Most this most frequently made.
I don't know the answer to that to be
honest with you. I mean, I love the grill.
I'm a just a grill freak. It's
super simple. Less dishes,
uh, and biggest flavor. So I
throw like PR when it's warm.
I throw everything on the grill, I
grill all of that. Stubbles like I,
we grow eggplant, we grow where
Piney, we grilled peppers, Zucchini.
I just,
it just all goes up there and took,
it's really healthy way to cook because
you're using very little. There's,
you don't need much, you know,
there's no heavy fats or anything. Um,
and I've been doing pork chops up there,
some stake,
even pieces of fish depending on
what it is. Shrimp. So, I dunno,
I just, I just try to keep it fun
and simple. I think the one thing is,
it's actually kind of reminds me,
I think the one other difference between
home cooks and and pros is just acidity
level. Like at when you think it's ready,
like add another lemon. Yeah, totally.
We always like pros bump up
the, the, the acidity level,
which is what is like one of the
Sikh that's like one of the secrets.
Just we add a little more acid and it
makes everything taste better. Yeah.
It seems,
it seems like pros use lemon juice is
as they might use salt at the time.
Yeah. Uh, what are some of the mistakes
that people make with grilling?
Um, what do they make with
grilling one? The grills not hot,
so they ended up not getting
very good color, um, to,
I think that's the, that's the
main mistake. Um, I think, uh,
they also like play with food too.
Like when you throw it on there,
like let it go, let it get that nice
color and before you start moving around,
um, and um, you know,
I think grills are best
when you get to see her,
but like if you're doing a piece
of meat or even a piece of fish,
letting it finish in the oven,
even just for a minute or two,
depending on how big your
piece of, uh, of meat is, the,
is the best way to do it because it,
it'll cook more evenly.
A lot of times if you are
using a really hot grill,
you'll get like a lot of well done and
then like a little bit of rare or medium
rare in the middle, but like the
sides will be super dry and tough.
So if you get a really hot grill,
got a great sear,
you'll lock the flavor and
then you finish in the oven.
And it's always the best way to do it,
yeah. To, to avoid the black
and blue steak. Yeah. Uh,
next question is from Daniel Law.
Haun uh,
what is the best way to systematically
develop and refine your palate? And, um,
I'll just,
I'll modify that and say what is,
what is one simple way
to start systematically
developing and refining your
palette?
Wow, that's an issue in
question. I've never, I've never,
I've never been asked that. I think, um,
I think basically just tasting everything
you possibly can and really tasting
it. Like, thinking about it,
like breaking down the flavor
and just paying attention to it.
I'm smelling things.
So smell is a really
fundamental part of tastes way more
than we realize. So I would, you know,
make sure you're really smelling,
touching,
and tasting as much as you possibly
can. Eat at restaurants, um,
go to farmer's markets, um, tried
things out and the more you taste like,
the more you'll start understanding
the subtleties and complexities. Um,
like, I don't know. I
don't know of a resource.
I mean that's just the way I learn
is like cooking and tasting things.
And that's the way most chefs learn.
I don't know of a resource that's like
a guide to palate development. Um,
I'm sure there's something out there,
but I don't, I don't know of it.
Yeah, it's uh, it, this was a,
this was a question I
had to tackle for myself,
um, when I was attempting to
learn to cook in the beginning.
So I would s I would say to Daniel,
a couple of things really helped me.
The first was, uh, going to restaurants,
going to the same restaurant,
say five days in a row.
Maybe you can't do five days, but going
there regularly enough on off days,
like Tuesday to Thursday,
Monday to Thursday to
get to know the staff.
I'm always keeping the menu with
you when you're eating so you can,
you can read along as you eat dishes.
So you know what's in it,
like the five or six,
seven ingredients,
whenever it might be a smelling
your food before you eat it.
It looks kind of weird, but it's smelling
food before you eat it. Cause I've,
I've always had chronic,
well up until I started using um,
kind of Sinus rinses,
I had chronic sinusitis and I have
a lot of trouble smelling. Um,
and then,
uh,
last thing would be for unfamiliar
ingredients that are mixed into a dish.
And this is part of the reason
that you would go during the week,
asking them to give you a little bit
on the side so that you can taste it
individually before you eat it in
the mix I've found and there's a,
there's a fun book called
the Flavor Bible also.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. That's good.
That is a cool book.
And a lot of chefs use that to come
up with unusual flavor combinations.
Next question is from ads.
Uh,
if you had to pack the essence
of life into a Burrito,
what would that burrito would be like?
The essence of life into
a Burrito? Yeah. Yeah.
Meaning like what would the ingredients
be? The food ingredients. Yeah.
Wow. All right. Here we go. Um, okay. Uh,
okay. I think I would have,
you'd have, um, uh, you know,
you'd have some brown rice in there for
like fortitude, sustenance for like,
you know, your grit and
determination. Um, I would have,
um, avocado, lots of avocado
for like the richness,
life, beauty, color,
flavor, like excitement.
I would have, um, would be my protein.
I definitely have beans. Um, uh,
I think beans are like this, you
know, the see their growth. Uh, they,
they, they, they harness
promise for me. Hope Opera, you
know, Opportunity, optimism.
Um,
I'd have a little,
maybe a little skirt steak
for strength and, um,
but not a lot.
Um,
and I'd have a Habanero
salsa for like the spice,
the excitement, uh, the, you know,
so the being vigorous,
uh,
part of what makes life so amazing.
Um,
and then maybe I'd let the chef throw
in one other mystery ingredient,
uh, to stimulate curiosity,
which I think is, uh,
the most important or
underappreciated quality of, uh,
of, of people who lives great,
successful, awesome lives,
which is just being curious about
the world around them. So I let the,
I let the chef throw a mystery, a
mystery ingredient in there. How's that?
I love it. It looks like, looks
like my cheat day on Saturday.
He's going to be doing
burritos. Uh, if, uh,
if, uh, just two more questions. Uh,
this is, this is really fun and, uh,
people can certainly let us know
if they want more, more. Sam,
I'm sure a lot of people will be the two,
two more questions for you.
The first is if you could give your,
let's just say,
uh, give yourself advice when you were
just graduating from u Chicago and what
advice would that be?
Okay.
MMM. Wow, that's a great question. Um,
well if I would've given myself advice
when I graduated from when I went in,
I would have said study a little
harder, you know, work a little harder.
But I, when I, when I left, I
mean, I, I think the advice that I,
um, that, uh, that I live
by, which it kind of holds,
which is basically get out there in the
world, be open to it, explore it, um,
uh, be, don't, don't,
don't worry about having a,
a clear plan because I didn't know
enough to have a clear plan. Um,
and you know, follow things that I really
cared about and, and, and go all in.
When I, when I found some that
that interests me because passion,
like passions and overstated word,
I mean I think passion develops.
So like I was really into food
and was interested in it and,
and I threw myself into,
into food, but I, I,
it didn't become a passion so I
can, you know, really combined.
Although I was like passionate about it,
did,
it wasn't a life passion until
I can like combined, you know,
food and nourishment with health and
sustainability and politics and policy and
what we're doing to really help make
sure that all people can live healthy,
productive, you know, awesome lives
through the food that they're eating.
That's what sort of became that,
that passion.
So I think a lot of people are like,
find your passion.
I think passion comes from
a combination of being open,
curious of really going all in
when you find something that, um,
that you're interested in. Um, then
then that, then that goes and I,
and I think always just trying to figure
out how to do the right thing, you know,
trying to remember why you're
doing what you're doing. Um,
is our kind of the lessons that I've
tried to live by and, and they've,
they've served well on the,
you know,
getting out in the world gives you a
perspective on a wherever you are that I
found to be transformative and um,
and just the foundation of, of,
of who I am. So, um, it's been,
uh,
it's been good.
No, I, I I really want to underscore
something you said then I think is really
important and that is just
related to finding your passion.
A lot of people ask me, how can I find my
passion? And I think that in their mind,
do they see this singular thing that is
this lightening bolt that knocks them
off their feet? And in
my case, just like you,
it was an unexpected combination of things
that came together by trying a lot of
things and being not having,
and Mike is,
it didn't have like a five or
10 year plan, but it was, uh,
I will do the best I can at this,
this next Gig, whatever that is,
and look for doors that open. And, uh,
so I don't want people to think,
to feel like,
and I've seen people reflect this feel
like a failure because they haven't had a
single activity hit them like
a cupid's Arrow or whatever.
Um, what if you could make one ask
of the people listening to this,
what would that ask be?
Oh, great question. Um,
what we might want to ask.
I think my one ask would just
be too, um, to be your engaged.
I think right now, uh, we're, we're
suffering from lack of engagement, uh,
around some of the issues that
really matter. And you know,
there's lots of solutions. There's
lots of different ways to think about,
and particularly in food, I think,
you know, there's, you know,
there's nothing more important than
making sure our kids are getting food.
I mean, we have so many hungry
kids in, in, in, in the country,
we're wasting so much food.
We're not getting enough nourishing
food and the face of climate change,
there's gonna be,
it's gonna be even harder to grow healthy
food and produce it at an affordable,
uh, at an affordable price for people. So
the challenges are higher and, and allow,
we're so,
I mean,
so engaging and caring and
trying to improve the food
system through the choices
that we're making every day.
There's a start.
And I think for people who
really get into, right,
it's starting to translate that into and
into politics and actually caring about,
um, these issues in terms
of who's us in Washington.
And I think that's a, um, the
politicians follow the people,
the end businesses follow the people.
Like they try to like shape decisions
and they market it, etc. But in the end,
they're following.
And so we need to lead.
And then we're leading every single day
in ways that sometimes we're aware of
and sometimes we're not.
And so I think that kind of awareness
and engagement can have a profound impact
on what companies are producing
and what policies are being made.
So I think that's my big ask,
at least in my, in my world.
But the truth is that that kind of same,
uh,
same principle applies to
just about any issue. Um,
and I think we just,
the more were engaged,
the, the, the more democracy
works. Agreed. Yeah.
Give a damn people, there'll
be apathetic, finds fun,
something to get excited
about and care about. Uh, Sam,
where can people find you on the Internet?
Uh,
where can people find you on Twitter?
I guess you're at Chef Sam Kass.
Yup. Yup. Sam Kass. Um,
Instagram is Sam Kass DC.
MMM.
Facebook. To be honest with
you, I said that up so long ago.
I didn't even know what my name is.
I have to look that up.
I got to get home that den
and the master of this.
Oh, wow. You know, I'm fumbling
my way through all the, uh,
all of the interwebs one day at a time.
I do have a website where people can,
can also check you out. Um, no, not
yet. That is in the works in process.
We'll process.
I will,
I will share that with people when it
is ready for fruits for its big debut.
Uh, Sam, well this is, this is
great. I really enjoy hanging out.
This was a lot of fun and uh,
for people listening you can
check out the links to resources,
books mentioned,
etc. Uh,
in the show notes and those show notes
in the show notes for every other podcast
are, which is that four hour work
week.com forward slash podcast. But Sam,
thank you so much for the time.
Tim has been awesome and you're,
you're, you're the best and you're,
you're helping people live better lives.
And it was a, it was an honor to be here.
Hey man, thanks buddy. I'll talk to
you soon. All right, take care. Bye.
This episode is brought to you by 99
designs your one stop shop for all things
graphic design related.
I've used 99 designs for everything
from banner ads to book covers,
including sketches and mock ups
that led to the four hour body,
which later became number one New York
Times Number One Wall Street Journal and
the brainstorming.
A lot of it took place with designers
from around the world and here's how it
works. Whether you need a t
shirt, a business card, a website,
an APP thumbnail,
whatever it might be,
you submit that project and
designers from around the world.
We'll send you sketches
and mock ups and designs.
You choose your favorite and you have an
original that you love or you get your
money back.
It's that straightforward and many of you
who are listening have already used it
and created some amazing things
that I'll be sharing in the future.
But in the meantime, if you want
to see some of my competitions,
some of the book covers as
well as get a free $99 upgrade,
goto 99 designs.com forward slash Tim,
that's 99 designs.com forward slash.
Tim
This podcast is brought
to you by Mizzen and main.
Don't worry about the spelling.
All you need to do is this.
I have organized my entire life around
avoiding fancy shirts because you have to
iron them. You sweat through
them, they smell really easily.
They're a pain in the ass.
Mizzen and main has given me
the only shirt that I need.
And what I mean by that and Kelly
Starr at loves the shirts as well,
is that you can trick people.
They look really fancy so you can take
them out to nice dinners, whatever,
but they're made from athletics,
sweat wicking material.
So you can throw this thing into your
luggage in a heap or on your kitchen table
like I did recently and then pull it out,
throw it on with no irony, no steaming,
no nothing. Walk out and
you could probably wear this
thing for a week straight,
or make it your only dress shirt and
take it on trips for weeks at a time.
Never wash it. It will not smell.
You will not sweat through it.
You got to check these things out.
So go to four hour work,
week.com all spelled out for our work,
week.com forward slash shirts,
check it out,
four hour work,
week.com forward slash shirts and
you'll see some of my favorite gear,
including the one shirt that I've been
traveling with. And until next time,
thank you for listening.
Okay.
Yeah.