So I'm talking today with Samuel Andrea,
who's a composer or Canadian composer
who's currently residing in Strausberg
where he's working as a composer and
we're going to talk today about music,
so,
but I think we'll start off by having
Sam talk a little bit about his career
and position itself so that we can move
into the,
into the conversation and provide a bit
of context for everybody who's watching
and listening.
So take it away.
Well,
I'm a composer.
I'm from Canada originally and I lived
there until I was 22 and I decided
actually fairly early on that I wanted
to live in France.
And so I moved to Paris where I studied
for quite a number of years at the Paris
conservatory.
Um,
I remained there for 12 years and moved
to Strasburg two and a half years ago
and I've been here ever since.
So I mainly a composer,
but I do a lot of other things as well.
I'm also a poet.
I'm also a teacher.
I'm also a performer.
So tell me a little bit about your
experiences in,
in North America first as a composer.
Well,
I should start by saying that because I
left so young,
I didn't really have the opportunity to
put together anything resembling a
professional career when I was living in
Canada.
Uh,
but what I can say is that I started out
in music by,
by producing songs when I was a teenager
and that became something of an
obsession.
I was very interested in a sort of
unusual branch of the sort of singer
songwriter tradition that involved
paying attention to avalon guard
manifestations of music and trying to
incorporate those into the pop song
format.
And there is a very fascinating and a
lengthy history of that.
And so that was sort of my initial foray
into music.
So I made a total of about eight or nine
albums of,
uh,
of songs.
And as I was going along with that,
I became more and more interested in
forms of musical expression that were
not easily compatible with the song
format.
And that resulted in a kind of
interesting tension.
And so towards the end of my sort of
very short lived career as a,
as a singer songwriter,
it became obvious to me that I couldn't,
I couldn't resolve the contradictions
between sort of popular forms of
expression and the sorts of things that
we're really starting to fascinate me
and just keep me up at night in the
format of the pop song.
So that resulted in a kind of schism at
a certain point where I was making songs
that really didn't sound like songs at
all.
And it was from that point,
it was a,
it was a fairly straightforward matter
just to abandon ship,
so to speak,
and,
and basically,
uh,
take up a full time composition.
You said that you were trying to
incorporate avant garde elements into
your songs.
So I think maybe the first thing you
could do is defined for the listeners
the difference between the song and and
other forms of composition because it's
not self evident to people standing
outside the professional musical
universe.
And also what you mean by avant garde
forms and why you were trying to
incorporate them.
Well essentially the song is a
vernacular format,
it's a,
it's,
it's a form of expression that deals
with materials that are familiar to
everybody in that are accessible to
everybody.
So in other words,
the standard pop song has three chords
for the most part.
And so these are,
these are very easy materials to
masters,
so anyone you know who's interested
enough in it can,
can take the trouble to learn those
three chords and put together something
resembling a pop song.
They might not be very good at it,
but you can still,
you can access the basic fundamental
building blocks of the pop song fairly
easily.
Um,
whereas other branches of a composition
are primarily written,
they're not primarily things that come
out of a performance tradition
necessarily.
In other words,
they might be initially encoded as a,
as a score,
and then only after the score is
written,
do you have hopefully a performance
tradition coming out of the piece.
Whereas an in pop music,
it's the opposite.
You start with the instrument,
you start with performing,
you start with,
with the sort of immediate to a sort of
tactile relationship.
You have to,
your instrument and the music sort of
flows out of that,
but you don't begin with the score with
the written document
and these avant garde elements that you
were talking about.
Two things.
What,
what got you interested in them?
Why did you think it was useful?
And uh,
and explain a bit more about what
happened when you started pursuing them.
I didn't think of it in terms of
utility.
It was something that had literally just
grabbed me by the throat because when
one thing that started to happen was,
uh,
in the,
in the sixties particularly,
you had this very brief cultural moment
when there was a kind of crossover
between,
between what the postwar avant garde
we're doing and,
and the sort of most broadly popular
rock acts.
So for example,
the Beatles on there on the white album
famously included the track called
revolution nine,
which is a sound collage.
It's a piece of a sonic art.
It is an absolutely no regard a rock
song.
And they did that because the,
you know,
John Lennon and Paul Mccartney,
we're interested in Stockhausen and
things like this.
And that's an extraordinary cultural
moment and the Beatles were far from the
only ones to do that.
So if you,
if you get interested in,
in that kind of music from that year,
from the sixties and onwards,
and you look at it closely,
you can't help noticing that there's a
kind of shadow world that's,
that's peeking through via these sorts
of manifestations and a lot of,
a lot of groups did,
did things like that as well.
The doors did that.
They did very,
uh,
strange sort of collage,
avant garde poetry and all sorts of
things that,
uh,
that,
that you can't easily square with the
demands of the pop song format.
So as I was listening to these things
when I was 12 or 13 years old,
my attention was instinctively drawn to
the more unusual elements of those
records,
which is interesting because when they
came out,
those were usually the tracks that
everybody skipped,
right?
But not,
you know,
I was instinctively fascinated by them.
I always thought that Jim Morrison's
foray outside of the song format was
generally unfortunate.
But,
and I was confused.
Of course,
when I listened to revolution number
nine,
although I thought that in the context
of that album,
it was very interesting because that
wall,
it's a double album,
which was a very remarkable album and it
seemed oddly enough to fit in some
strange way.
I mean that whole double album fits
together in a remarkable way even though
there's quite a diverse range of,
of a song formats that are incorporated
into it.
So why do you think the.
So let's do a couple of things.
Why don't we define what constitutes
avant garde period.
It's not necessarily a term that people,
they've heard it undoubtedly,
but people hear all sorts of,
what would you call them?
Let's call them terms.
They hear all sorts of terms that
they're not necessarily that haven't
been well defined.
So you could tell us about the avant
garde.
Tell us why it attracted you,
do you think as well?
Well,
first of all,
to define the avant garde.
I mean,
it's,
it's a military term and it simply means
the unfortunate souls that are the first
to go into battle out there on the front
line,
so to speak.
Um,
and so I suppose that in the,
in the artistic domain,
it simply means people who are engaging
in,
in forms of artistic expression that are
as yet untested.
Now there's a,
you can certainly debate whether that
term is at all historically valid
anymore.
Um,
and there's a strong case to be made for
saying that the avant garde in a certain
sense basically no longer exists because
it's been so thoroughly,
uh,
institutionalized and written about and
discussed.
And it's very,
very difficult these days to make a work
of art that actually shocks anybody,
you know,
that's a kind of an interesting thing.
And that's a very recent phenomenon
also.
I mean,
you can do absolutely outrageous things
and,
and have them be installed in public
places and it'll generate a certain
amount of civic controversy,
but nothing even remotely close to what
would have happened 60 years ago even.
So that's the first thing,
an interesting phenomenon in and of
itself,
right?
So there's a kind of extraordinary
tolerance for all sorts of artistic
expression.
But you could also argue that it's a
form of societal indifference as well.
You could say that,
well,
the reason nobody's rioting and no one's
shocked and and seeking to have these
sorts of cultural forms bend is because
it simply doesn't matter.
Those sorts of arts have been declawed
in a certain sense.
I mean there's an argument you could
make in that sense.
People are so flooded with sounds and
images now too,
that the sheer volume of those sorts of
things that we're to,
I also think inoculates us against or
also inoculate,
inoculate us against shock but also
makes it more and more difficult to be
sufficiently original to actually have
that effect on people.
I mean,
it's not like people have dropped all
their taboos because you see that the
Da,
the taboos about what can be said for
example,
just shift around.
But it certainly does seem to be the
case that it's harder for artists to,
to,
to play,
uh,
to play a role that it also,
I suppose speaks to some degree to the
degeneration of cultural norms around,
around all sorts of different areas.
Because if there are strongly
established norms,
it's a lot easier to violate them.
And that's pretty interesting because it
also means you can't be a revolutionary
unless there's a half decent tire around
to him.
Me End,
so.
Right.
Yeah.
So why do you think the avant garde
attracted you instead of it's.
I mean,
it,
it would have been more typical,
let's say for someone who started out
composing pop songs to continue in that
vein,
not to go down the rabbit hole of the
avant garde,
which is a very strange thing for anyone
to do.
Yeah,
a couple of reasons.
The first thing is that the,
the,
the pop song format is interesting in
that it,
it only works if you stay relatively
close to its parameters and if you start
to stray too far outside of them than
what you're doing basically no longer
functions as a pop song because it's no
longer vernacular.
And so I have a fascination with all
sorts of forms of music and the pop song
is an incredibly difficult medium to
work within.
Again,
because you,
first of all,
it's.
It gets completely unforgiving.
You're working in basically a,
an extremely compressed format.
It's very rare for pop songs to be too
much longer than three minutes,
so you don't really have much room to
maneuver and you certainly don't have
any room to maneuver structurally.
I mean you pretty much have to stick to
the verse,
Chorus,
verse,
chorus thing from the immense majority
of pop songs.
There's been very little variation in
that since since rock really since the
fifties.
I mean I know that three minute length
was.
That was actually a commercial
imposition if I remember correctly,
but that structure verse,
chorus,
verse,
Chorus,
what out of what did that originate?
Well,
that's a.
that's an extremely old forum and you
certainly have a.
there's a there.
There are broke forms such as the Rondo
or the returned mail though that have an
extremely similar forum where you
alternate one fixed element that keeps
returning the same way essentially and
then a secondary element that that sort
of gives you a certain degree of relief,
a certain degree of a contrast with the
proceeding element,
so that's a chaos order interplay I
guess of sorts.
At least that's the way I would
interpret it.
And why the three guards structure,
why,
why do you think instead of two chords
or four chords,
why,
why do you think that's dominated?
Well,
if three chord structure is the bare
minimum that you need in order to have
any kind of harmonic tension basically,
uh,
in,
in music,
generally speaking,
you,
you in tonal music anyway,
you have a very simple and effective
polarity between the what's called the
tonic and the dominant degrees.
And that's,
that's something that was,
that basically structured the entire
classical period of the baroque period
as well to it.
Unpack that for.
That's for us.
And tell us what that is.
Why that,
why that,
why that works musically?
White works aesthetically?
Well,
it's,
it's one of many possible strategies for
music.
And in fact if you,
if you go beyond the broke into,
into renaissance music or,
or,
or even earlier,
you don't have this sort of strong
polarity between two opposing harmonic
regions.
That was something that really came
about during the 17th century,
basically.
Conversational.
Do you think that,
like one of the things that I've noticed
about many pieces of music is that they
sound like dialogues.
There's an announcement on the one hand
and then there's the response on the
other and then there's an announcement
and then there's a response.
It,
it seems to me to be based in dialogue
based analogically metaphorically,
maybe in dialogue you hear that in many
classical pieces as well.
So I would say that it's,
it's,
it's a way of setting up an extremely
rudimentary story and extremely
rudimentary form of narrative in the
sense that you start with that
a region that is established that you,
that you basically have as your home
base essentially,
and then you,
you modulate to a different,
different harmonic region and through
this process of modulating,
you move from
your home base to somewhere else and
that creates a tension.
It creates a nostalgia and it creates a
need for resolution.
Um,
there are plenty of other ways you can
do right.
Well,
okay.
So That's interesting.
I mean for a variety of reasons.
One thing that made me that made me
think about right away is the proclivity
of small children to do that with their
mother in particular,
so the space around the mother is
defined as home territory,
partly because mother is familiar,
but also partly because if something
goes wrong and mother is their mother
can fix it,
so so there's.
There's a zone around the child when the
mother is there,
where there is access to immediate
resources that will fill in where the
child's skills are lacking,
and then what the child will do after
obtaining sufficient comfort from being
in the presence of mom is to go out far
enough into the world,
driven by their curiosity,
which which has an underlying biological
manifestation.
There's an exploratory system that
drives the child out there too.
It discovered new information and to
extend their skills by pushing against
the unknown and then when that when they
either get tired or when they go out far
enough so that negative emotion as a
consequence of threat predominates,
they run back to their mother.
And so it reminded me of that.
And it's also a microcosm of the hero's
journey,
right?
Which is the journey from a safe and and
defined plays out into the unknown and
then a return.
And that is,
well,
I wouldn't even say that's the simplest
story.
That's the simplest story that also
involves transformation.
So it might be the simplest good story,
something like that.
But I haven't mapped that on to that.
A chorus,
a,
what'd you call it?
Verse Chorus?
Yes,
yes,
yes.
So that and that return to stability.
So,
so you think,
so does that make sense?
That mapping as far as you're concerned?
Absolutely,
because one of the,
one of the main tenants of the,
of the,
the total harmonic system is that you
have an eventual return to where you
started out at the end.
So there's,
there's always the promise of a return
at the end and that's the essential
structure that you see in pop songs as
well.
So it's,
it's fundamentally a,
it's a directional to td logical sort of
structure.
Um,
and that's extremely different from,
from renaissance music,
which basically has a very,
very weak degree of directionality.
It doesn't seem to want to particularly
go anywhere.
It sort of floats and uh,
that's,
that's an interesting thing that,
that music sort of window off in this
other sort of direction.
Did you have any idea why that
transformational curd?
Well,
I think it's because there was a,
a need for a more dramatically intense
form of music and that certainly that
certainly took,
took place during the Baroque and of
course that's related to the power and
cultural influence of the Catholic
Church and the need to create forms of
artwork that would be extremely dramatic
and expressive.
And in Baroque music you have this
intensification of musical expression
that's,
that's quite striking in a sense.
You could say that,
that,
that strongly directional thrust that
you get in music developed even further
in the classical and then in the
romantic periods as well,
to the point where it,
it,
it becomes this sort of constant push
towards ever more cataclysmic forms of
expression until it actually ruptures
the fabric of music itself.
You,
you no longer can contain this,
this level of extra acidity.
Okay,
so let's go back a little bit too.
So lots of the people that are
listening,
I presume,
won't know the,
the
temporal relationship between those
periods of musical development that you
just described.
So why don't you go back to the,
to the medieval era and then just lay
out the periods of time across which
music developed and then we'll go back
to that idea of this cataclysmic
upheaval that sort of shattered the
structure of music.
Say in the 20th century.
Well there's only so far you can go back
because music has only begun to be
written down in a way that's,
that's reliably retrievable since the
late 14th century or so.
So if you try to go too much farther
back than that,
you end up with documents that are
extremely hard to decipher.
We don't really know exactly what these
things sounded like.
We've got about six years.
Yeah,
we've got about 600 years.
So roughly speaking,
the renaissance period extends to about
1600.
So roughly between 1400 and 1600 and the
Baroque is usually said to end with the
death of bar in 1750.
Then you have a kind of no man's land
that lasted 20 or 30 years where there
was a sort of in between period of,
of generalized experimentation,
but there wasn't yet a strongly
characterized style yet,
and then you have classicism that starts
really towards the,
well in the second half of the,
of the 18th century and romanticism is a
little bit more difficult to pin down,
but,
but Beethoven is considered to be one of
the earlier exponents of,
uh,
of a,
of a romantic style.
He died in 18,
27 so that more or less takes us to the
end of the 19th century.
Then you have something that you could
plausibly call late romanticism,
although that's very difficult to
define.
And that sort of dovetails with
modernism.
So can you set out some of the defining
features of each of those,
set out the defining features of each of
those parks,
let's say.
And then maybe you can walk us through
this idea that you expressed about
increasingly cataclysmic changes and
then that resulting in in sight 20th
century music.
That takes us back to the avant garde as
well.
The first thing I would say is that
these sorts of categorizations are are
generalizations.
I mean you can't,
you can't take 200 years of human
cultural endeavor and reduce them down
to a single word and of course these
things are constantly flowing and,
and,
and transforming and,
and they're all in there.
Also,
all sorts of overlapping.
I'm contrasting movements happening at
any given time,
so this is really just for the sake of
convenience,
but,
but if you want us to make a
generalization,
you could say that during the
renaissance,
music was essentially linear.
It was essentially melodic and and
contrapuntal.
In other words that you would have,
you would have individual voices,
individual lines that would be flowing
along together,
but music was not yet primarily thought
of in terms of vertical or harmonica
sonorities.
That really starts to with it,
with the Baroque early in the 17th
century,
baroque music has a much stronger
harmonic,
a dimension to it.
It's,
it's.
You could argue that it's harmonically
somewhat simpler than,
than renaissance music because it's more
codified.
That's when you start getting the first
treatises on harmony.
The first theoretical writings on music
also isn't the Baroque period.
It's also characterized by the use of
highly stylized and very strong dance
rhythms
that the classical period is essentially
a simplification of the Baroque style
and a certain sentence and music became
strongly divided between what you would
call foreground and background elements.
In other words,
you would have a very prominent melodic
line and then you would have an
accompaniment,
but the two are not necessarily of equal
importance.
Whereas in the Baroque and the
renaissance,
the voices would have tended to be
basically equal importance.
There's very,
there's very little foreground
background distinction in,
in Baroque and uh,
and pre baroque music.
So the classical style is a
simplification.
It's also a codification of musical
forums.
That's when you start getting the
symphony,
the string quartet a,
the concerto while the concertos with
broke for him,
but it starts to take on the
characteristics of a,
of other classical forms such as the,
the sonata in the classical period.
So you get this,
basically this is codification and the
simplification of the,
of the basic tools of music in the
classical period.
And in the classical period is,
is quite extraordinary actually,
because it's,
it's,
it was a rather short lived period in
which for a very brief span of time,
there is a,
a,
an overlapping of popular and savant
styles.
So you had,
you had sort of a vernacular dimension
in the classical period.
You had very simple popular forums and
popular forms of expression and you also
had the absolute highest degree of
musical science and they were combined.
I'm not in every composer,
but certainly the,
the one that comes to mind as having
been the highest manifestation of that
combination of the different qualities
is Mozart.
That's probably a unique historical
phenomenon.
I mean,
there's,
there,
there aren't very many composers that
can,
that can achieve that.
And in a sense,
you have to be historically lucky that
the state of the musical language,
when you're alive has to,
has to coincide with your own,
uh,
need to,
to push the boundaries of your art.
And so that's a,
that's an amazing thing.
And a romanticism,
more or less puts an end to that because
it,
it puts a tremendous degree of focus on
the individual.
It's,
it's an exacerbation of the idea of the
self and it,
it,
it elevates the subjective emotional
impulses of the artists to a,
to a very high realm.
And so you get these forms of individual
expression that begin to not really jive
with the,
the underlying rules of the art.
And that's when things really get
complicated.
Okay.
So that moves us into the,
into the,
uh,
you've just talked about the classical
period.
The next one that comes along is
romantic,
right?
Okay.
What happens during the romantic period
and you said Beethoven was nearly an
early manifestation of that with his
sort of cataclysmic
starts off writing music that's strongly
influenced by Haydn who's,
uh,
who's one of the most important
classical composers.
And by the end of his career,
he's doing pieces that basically are,
are destroying these forms from within.
It's very,
very interesting.
If you listen to Beethoven works like
the Hammerklavier Sonata for example,
or the late string quartet.
It's basically pulling apart these,
these,
uh,
these forums in it,
in a rather ruthless way.
And,
and,
uh,
just pulverizing them.
There's an analogy between that and what
happens in other fields of endeavor.
You know,
that the philosopher of science,
Thomas Kuhn talked about and,
and also the developmental
psychologists,
piaget,
what's with these revolutions in stages,
you when,
so for Piaget or for science scientists
were working within,
let's call it an axiomatic theory and
then make it a create new data into that
theory without disrupting the axioms,
but now along now and then some data
would come along that didn't even fit
within the axioms.
And then that data would generally be
ignored for a while because no one knew
what to do with it.
You know?
And,
and it isn't reasonable to leap to the
conclusion that if your theory doesn't
predict something,
that it should immediately be scrapped
because there's always the possibility
that the data itself is wrong,
but now and then something new comes
along,
that's enough to collapse the science.
In some sense all the way down to its
unstated assumptions which then have to
be recast now piaget thought of
something similar in terms of
developmental stages in children and in
adults that the same thing happened when
we were organizing our internal
representations of the world and but
Piaget coon seemed to be a bit of a
relativist and that he believed that
paradigm's could be in incommensurate,
that you really couldn't speak between
them.
It makes them a precursor in some ways
to to post modernism,
but Piaget's point was that each stage
transition in human cognition which was
accompanied by,
by the way,
by a descent into chaos of some sort.
As the anomalous data accumulated.
Each stage that emerged was superior to
the one before it because you could do
everything you could do in that stage.
Plus you could do more and so piaget
there was actually progress along the
along the stage transformations.
Whereas for coon,
although I think Kuhn is less a emphatic
about that,
that many,
many of his readers seem to think.
Whereas for cone it was more like
lateral transformation or something like
that.
I mean,
it's been a big debate,
but it sounds very much to me like
something similar is happening as
musical forms develop.
Oh sure.
It would be impossible to make the
argument though that,
that this is constitutes in any way a
progression or a,
um,
an improvement over time.
You can't really make that argument
about musical forums because they're
always checks and balances.
There are always pluses and minuses that
are attendant with any,
any novel form of musical expression.
Yeah.
Well that's the good things that seems
to distinguish art from science in some
sense is that it isn't obvious that art
is improving.
Right?
Right.
Whereas at least in principle,
it seems obvious that science is
improving in that piaget way is that we
could do everything we could plus more,
but art so maybe aren't really does have
that structure that Thomas Kuhn talked
about where that paradigms are
incommensurate and there's no,
there's no progression where science has
the more Eddie and structure where there
is actually something that you can
regard as genuine progress.
Well,
what you do have is a constant
oscillation between two fundamental
states and music history,
which is you have periods of expansion
periods in which axioms are tested and
rethought and periods of consolidation
in which you strip away and you simplify
and that's a.
that's a permanent feature of music
history.
It's a.
it's a.
it's a very interesting thing when
things start to get a little bit too
wild,
there tends to be a counter reaction and
a tendency simplification.
Certainly that's what happened in the in
the classical with regards to the
Baroque period.
So it's interesting because it kind of
implies that the entire system overtime
is oscillating around some sort of
golden mean or something like that.
I mean not that that thing actually
exists in some sense because it would
move,
you know,
where the appropriate place is going to
be dependent on the nature of the
landscape at that point,
but the case you're making is that
despite that there's some boundaries on
the movement.
There is so much chaos and which would
be,
I suppose,
too much revolutionary transformation
and I suppose that the degeneration
there would be,
the experimentation could be so extreme
that would actually break the boundaries
of what people are willing to,
to,
uh,
to accept as music.
There has to be,
be a social contract between the,
between the artist and the,
and the public,
unless you're making a totally hermetic
art,
unless you're making an art that is not
necessarily intended for public
consumption.
So that's a very delicate balancing act
of course,
because artists have the natural
inclination to explore and audiences
have the natural inclination to stay
close to things that are familiar to
them and that are already satisfying to
them in some manner.
So what do you think that contract is
exactly?
Because obviously the audience also
doesn't want to stay exactly where they
are.
It's very difficult to speak in general
terms of audiences because they're made
up of individuals and individuals have
wildly different approaches to music and
wildly different tastes in music as
well.
I mean,
one of the,
one of the extraordinary things about
music is that it has so many different
functions simultaneously.
If you were to take all of the different
functions that music fulfills and and
abstract out the music part and then try
to understand what phenomenon could
possibly cover all of those different
functions,
you'd be very hard pressed to think of
anything.
I mean music is,
is a,
it's a science,
but it's also a form of entertainment.
Okay.
So you were just speaking about that,
the actual function of music and so
let's,
let's pick it up there because that's a
really interesting issue and the
function and meaning of music and I
would really like to hear your thoughts
on that.
So let's,
let's go.
Let's go from there.
You can't speak of the function of music
because music has so many different
functions.
They seem on the surface of it to be
almost completely incompatible.
So you have music that functions as a,
as a form of an expression of religious
devotion,
but you have music as well that whose
primary focus is to get teenagers to go
out on dates.
You have a,
you have music that is crassly
commercial,
you have music that is a meditative and
sublime.
You have music that represents the
highest aspirations of mankind,
um,
and music that is piped in through
elevators.
I mean,
that's just a very,
very partial list.
I could go on and on and on.
So again,
it's a,
it's an absolutely amazing phenomenon in
terms of the sheer number of functions
that it,
that it covers.
Uh,
it's,
it's also,
it's good to dance to a,
it's good for movies.
It's a,
in anything you can possibly think of.
There's been some form of music device.
Those
functions is actually a little universe.
I mean the fact that that music seems to
be useful in movies is a strange
phenomena,
you know,
because if you go,
if you go see a movie that lacks music,
you,
you actually become aware of quite
rapidly that it lacks music and it,
it's much more two dimensional in some
sense that,
I mean,
you could do it,
but it's much more two dimensional.
It's much more difficult.
What the music seems to do is to Philly
in somehow for the,
for the locking context,
it,
you know,
it makes it rich and,
and moral Rio,
which is even more surprising and it
partly does that by exaggerating,
I think the emotions that are being
portrayed but it,
well obviously if you could say
completely what the music is doing in a
movie,
then you wouldn't need to put the music
in because you could just incorporate it
into a story.
But you talked about elevators,
dancing and movies among many other
things.
And those three things are
extraordinarily different because
obviously what's being piped into the
elevator is there to what,
calm,
the awkward silence something.
It's something like that with something
familiar.
Maybe it takes the edge off being locked
in an elevator with,
you know,
multiple other primates that you've
never met.
And people make fun of it too because
it's denatured music in some sense.
But obviously there's a demand and a
requirement for it and a function.
So,
um,
while anyways.
Okay.
So we talked about the multi,
multiple contradictory and paradoxical
rules that music can play.
But let's,
let's go a little deeper and why don't
you have,
why don't you tell us what you think,
what do you think music is doing and why
it's so important?
Assuming it is in fact important,
it certainly seems to be.
Well,
again,
it's very difficult to talk generally
about that.
And if you look at non Western cultures
and the role that music plays in them,
it's,
it's often extremely different from what
from what we do with it.
So for example,
a south Indian music is,
is,
uh,
is very,
very long and drawn out and it's a,
it's essentially melodic.
There's no harmony in it.
These are extremely long forms and you,
you can't,
you can't listen to them if you only
have five minutes.
It's a,
it's an entire experience.
A Tibetan music is very closely tied up
with,
with ritual,
for example.
It's a,
it's a way of reinforcing certain order
of doing things in.
So it's a,
there are all sorts of examples.
I think in more traditional societies
are more archaic societies.
The music is rarely divorced from the
surrounding context.
It's not divorced from dance.
It's not divorced for masks,
it's not divorced from the religious
context and one of the things you see as
cultural differentiate,
let's say you could say developed,
but let's say differentiate is that,
um,
there's a fragmentation of phenomena
into their,
into their higher resolution
subcomponents,
you know,
so the language of biology for example,
continues to expand as we develop higher
and higher resolution models of the
world.
And as a society has more and more
dimensions,
it's possible to specialize more in each
of the sub dimensions.
And that also both breaks things apart
but also allows for their further
manifestation.
So we could say as a general rule,
maybe as you go back into the past,
then the number of things that is
happening simultaneously along with
music explicitly probably increases.
You know,
I'd been struck by,
Oh,
one of my friends told me about going to
a,
a led Zeppelin concert in Sweden and
everyone was sitting politely,
you know,
he was from a culture where everybody
would have been standing up and cheering
and dancing and clapping and dancing
essentially.
Right?
Because of the music.
But that was frowned upon there,
which is very,
very interesting because it's an,
you know,
it's an indication of that kind of
almost artificial fragmentation.
So.
Right.
Well I think that,
I think that analysis is absolutely
accurate.
It's,
if you look at Baroque music for
example,
what you have is a generalized it kind
of stylized version of dense.
It's not,
it's not the same as,
as music that you would actually dance
to,
but,
but the,
the entire broke period really rests
upon dense rhythms and that,
that goes for pretty much everything
Bach ever wrote from,
uh,
from the cantatas down to the Fuchs.
I mean,
they're all based on dense rhythms.
Fundamentally,
that's a very interesting thing because
obviously nobody dances to a fugue.
I mean,
I suppose you could,
but that's not really its primary
function.
So very interesting thing happens where
you get music that is,
that is no longer explicitly devotional.
That is,
it's not explicitly meant to be
performed as part of a liturgical
service of some kind,
but it's not necessarily meant to be
dense to either a.
and that's if you,
if you look at music as being a
phenomenon that's easily existed for
10,000
years,
I mean that's the amount of the span of
time during which that's been the case
is,
is just a drop in the bucket.
This is a very,
very recent thing.
The idea that that you would get several
hundred or several thousand people to go
and sit quietly in a room while
someone's playing and just sit there and
listen.
That's,
that's extremely recent.
That really only starts to happen in,
in,
in really in the romantic period,
the idea of a,
of a concert per se,
where there's nothing else attendant on
the experience of the music.
Right?
Well and then pop concerts,
rock concerts,
a lot of that additional material has
been put back in the form of light show
and sometimes in more dramatic forms
than not.
But the light show I suppose is as close
as you can get to representing what
music is doing in a visual format.
And I mean that was,
that was conscious.
I know that it was,
if I remember correctly,
it was Ken Keasy in his,
in his band of merry pranksters that
first started to experiment with
electronic lighting and that sort of
thing in California when they were
experimenting with Lsd back in the
sixties and they were interested in
synesthesia and I know there were
classical composers who were playing
with that much earlier and I suppose as
well,
but in the non electronic format,
you could chase that back an long way.
The idea of spectacle encompassing
music.
So.
Okay.
So,
so let's circle around the musical
element a bit more.
I mean,
you've thought a lot about this and you
also write poetry and I also want to get
back to the periods after the romantic
because we never did finish that
discussion about,
you know,
the cataclysmic restructuring of musical
forms up into the modern period.
So,
but let's,
let's,
let's start by pursuing the,
the meaning issue.
Uh,
so you are gripped by music and the
avant garde and,
and you thought about it for awhile,
like,
and you've laid out some of the,
like the ordering functions of music for
example,
but there's a disordering function of
music as well.
So,
so give us some more your thoughts about
exactly what music is doing for people
and,
uh,
in a,
in the deepest possible sense.
Well,
one of the fundamental aspects of music
now,
if you were to try to define music,
you would,
you would probably have to conclude that
it has two essential components.
One is time and when is sound,
uh,
it's difficult to give too much of a
higher resolution definition of music
than that because it very,
very quickly starts to,
it starts to exclude all sorts of things
that are,
that are thought of his music.
But that's,
that's the essential a basis of it.
I would say that between the two,
probably the temporal dimension is the
most important.
And fundamentally I would say what music
allows you to do is to experience forms
of time that we cannot experience in,
in so-called real life.
So for example,
in,
in music,
you can have a sort of distension of,
of actual lift time or a contraction.
You can have multiple things happening
simultaneously.
Uh,
you can have people enter into
effectively a trance state where there
are no longer aware of time.
That's an amazing thing.
Also,
you know,
a lot of music has that explicit
function to it.
Well,
the idea,
you know,
music has always struck me as something
like a four dimensional sculpture that's
manifesting itself in three dimensions.
So when I,
when I listened to music and Stereo
listening of course enhances this,
you can see these notes spread out
spatially,
um,
in the,
in the three dimensions that you're
capable of perceiving from an auditory
perspective.
And so there are these patterns that
manifest themselves moment by moment,
but the entire pattern stretches across
time.
And so for me,
and then there's pattern upon pattern as
well.
And then there's transforming patterns
upon transforming patterns.
And to me that's a very close analog to
what the world is like.
And it's in its multiplicity of layers
that are all interacting in.
So far as anything is real.
It constitutes a pattern that repeats
either spatially or temporarily means
things like smoke,
for example,
a cloud of smoke is sort of pseudo real
in that sense because it doesn't really
have any borders,
doesn't have any real repetition,
but most things,
although it does persist across moments
of time,
which is a form of a,
of a patterning,
but most things that we interact with do
repeat at least to some degree.
That's what object permanence is.
The repetition of something across time
and music seems to model the persistence
and the transformation across multiple
levels all at the same time.
And,
and what you said about the distinction
of time is interesting because Murcia
Eliana,
who's great historian of religions and
Freud himself both,
both talked about the,
um,
the transformation of time and the
transcendence of time in certain states,
a fried noted that dreams were really
good at compressing time or extending
time and you know,
so people have that experience.
Sometimes they'll hear the alarm go off
in the morning and instead of waking up,
they'll incorporate the alarm sound into
a dream that seems to have gone on way,
way longer.
Sometimes hours longer than the alarm
itself and the Lee ad,
it talks about the he,
he concentrated mostly are much on the
dream time of the last of the original
Australians and they viewed normal time
is sort of ensconced inside of an
eternal time.
That was always present that that seems
to be something like the time in which
music unfolds,
something like that.
Obviously these are ridiculously
complicated things so.
Well,
the musical time is,
is a very complicated thing.
I mean if I,
if I listened to a piece of music that's
three minutes long in no way have I
actually experienced three minutes of
real duration.
I mean that's a.
that's an extraordinary thing and this
actually allows me to connect to your
question about the avant garde and
because one of the things that that
fascinated me when I was a teenager was
I would be listening to a,
a piece,
a 20th century piece that might be
extremely short.
It might be two minutes long,
but I would,
I would not be able to comprehend it and
that,
that fascinated media.
The idea that I would not be able to
comprehend a piece of music now
obviously that's that has something to
do with my personality and not
everybody's going to be fascinated by a
piece of music that they.
That they find impenetrable,
but in my case I did.
There's also something else to note
there is that because you're musically
gifted,
it's going.
You're going to have to go a lot closer
to the edge of what's regarded as let's
say,
conventional or even the edge of what's
regarded as music before you encounter
something that's impenetrable.
Whereas for the average listener,
let's say,
which in that category,
I would certainly include myself.
I don't have to go that close to the
edge before I run into music.
That's complicated enough so that I at
least have to listen to it multiple,
multiple times before I understand the
patterning and the repetition and it's a
lovely thing to experience.
When you listen to something complex,
say the fifth or sixth time at pieces of
it start to fail together.
I really had that experience with Bach's
well tempered clavier,
which I had to listen to.
Jay's maybe 20 times before I would say
I had anything remotely like enjoyment
as a but and that and that clicking
together of those patterns also seems to
be beautiful in some sense.
It's like you,
you meet the music with your
understanding and in that meeting of the
music with your understanding is that
tremendous revelation of beauty and
depth and and harmony and all of those
things that that are so good about it.
It's more than that.
It's,
it's life affirming.
That's.
Which is a very strange thing about
music as well and I've noticed that
psychologically,
like even nihilistic people,
deeply nihilistic people and hopeless
people still,
they have to be pretty damn depressed
before music loses its vibrancy and
savor and and life affirming properties,
which is a really magical thing.
I would say that being open to the
possibility that you could enjoy
something even though perhaps it's
difficult going the first few times you
listen to it is,
is probably a key aspect.
So that brings me back to this contract
between the composer and the listener.
Like see,
I think what stops a lot of people,
and I would again include myself in that
maybe particularly with regards to that
garde art,
is that in order to put in the time and
effort that would be necessary for me to
understand and appreciate something like
the well tempered clavier let's say I
have to trust that there's actually
something there and then I'm not just
having the wool pulled over my eyes and
that I'm some kind of fool.
And the problem with a lot of avant
garde,
at least the potential problem is that
it's very difficult to dismiss the
notion that you're being played for a
fool by,
by tricksters and jokesters and frauds.
And of course you are more likely to be
in that situation if you're listening to
something new.
So,
so I think part of people's hesitancy
and,
and unwillingness to throw themselves
into something that's truly new is,
is the suspicion that the emperor has no
clothes and that they're being played
for a fool.
But you decide how did you know what you
should continue to listen to?
So,
well
let's pull that apart for a second
because if you,
if you look at things like the
historical avant garde,
in other words,
avant garde movements that took place,
let's say a hundred years ago,
just for the sake of argument,
it's no longer avant garde.
It's been,
it's been thoroughly picked apart by
historians.
There's been a,
a,
a sort of extended,
a critical process that's already taken
place and that's sort of sifted out
these artifacts and decided what's worth
discussing and what's not worth
discussing.
So I mean,
one of the,
one of the incontrovertible facts of a,
of music history or art history in
general is that the works that are no
longer able to communicate something
vitally important to that addresses a
present concern tend to fall out of
favor.
History is merciless,
right?
It's,
it's absolutely merciless.
And I mean think of the tens of
thousands of closers that were active
during the baroque period.
We've,
we've,
how many have we retained?
There's maybe a dozen figures that are
sort of still regularly performed and
discussed and and generally known to the
public.
So,
I mean,
there's a,
there's an absolutely ruthless selection
process that goes on and of course one
of the fundamental difficulties of
addressing a contemporary or modern
forms of art is that that process of
selection hasn't taken place yet.
So you as a listener are necessarily
engaged with that process to a certain
degree because the,
the,
the process of,
of selection hasn't,
hasn't taken place.
There is an overwhelming likelihood that
what you're going to hear might not be
of the highest standard statistical if
you figure that there are just,
just to throw out a number of hundred
thousand composers active in the world
today,
how many of them are geniuses?
How many of them are producing work of
the highest order?
You know,
it's going to be a vanishingly small
percentage.
So that's not,
that's not to say that,
that none of them are doing extremely
good work.
It's just that if you're coming to that
world for the first time and you're not
familiar with it,
uh,
and you,
you don't sort of have the,
uh,
the context to be able to navigate
through that space with a reasonable
degree of certainty that you can sort of
sniff out the good from the bad then.
Yes.
It's,
it's difficult.
There's no question.
It's a good,
it's a good.
That's a good expansion of the metaphor
of the avant garde because what that
means is as an avant garde listeners,
you're more likely to be killed,
so to speak,
like the avant garde in a battle.
And it's the same if you're laboring on
the edge of musical composition,
the probability that you're going to
survive.
They're in a real sense and I mean
practical like day to day if you're
going to make any money,
but also that you're going to survive
into the future is extraordinarily low.
So this game.
So why play it like I would say,
well,
for,
for the typical listener who doesn't
know anything about baroque music or
classical music or romantic music,
you know,
who has,
who is afraid of it or,
or who's afraid of being made a fool of,
for their ignorance when they first
enter into it,
which is,
which can easily happen in,
which is quite sad.
Why should they go to the,
who should go to the effort of listening
to what's truly new and why should they
do it in Europe you've got overwhelming
musical capacity.
So you know,
it's clear in your case.
Well,
first of all,
the.
Okay,
the,
the sort of career aspects of,
of writing music that as you say,
lies is sort of on the edges of what is
recognizably musical to a broad public.
Well,
is it a higher risk game?
That's an interesting question because
if I were to say a try to start a rock
band,
you know,
and uh,
and,
and write,
write songs that were in a,
in a conventional format,
you could certainly argue that I would
have just as much trouble if not more
establishing myself than if I were
writing in a form of musical expression
that's more esoteric simply because the,
the,
the crushing amount of competition is
actually probably a lot greater in that,
in that domain than in much more highly
individualized forms of musical
expression and incense.
So in,
in a way you could argue that it's,
it's,
that's,
that's a difficult argument to make
because it is very difficult in any case
to have a career as a composer,
but it's probably somewhat easier to
carve out a space for yourself if you're
working in a,
in a rather individual musical idiom
than if you're doing something that the
overall culture is already completely
central.
Right,
right.
Fair enough.
Then what about the listener though?
So,
so I,
I buy your argument,
but then the listener,
like if I go back and listen to only
those composers,
that time has a conserved,
which by your own admission are
composers that in some manner,
some mysterious manner,
still have something to say,
which I also don't understand.
It's like,
what does it mean?
That box still has something to say or.
I mean it's the same as shakespeare I
suppose,
but,
but it isn't obvious what it is.
That remains to be sad.
I don't get that.
It's got to be something like the
culture has not fully incorporated all
of the perceptual genius that that
person had to offer it.
Like Bob hasn't been transformed into
cliche or into,
into implicit assumption or something
like that.
But you know,
because I think that one of the things
that artists do,
visual or auditory is they teach people
to see or hear the.
The impressionists are good example of
that because obviously their works,
well maybe not obviously,
but their works produced riots when they
were first publicly displayed and it's a
particular way of seeing the world that
has more to do with light than with
farm,
but for most people it's easy to look at
an impressionist painting.
Now it seems,
it seems it's so embedded into our
visual language that there's nothing
about it that seems shocking.
And so I think we've learned that and,
and I guess part of the question is do
we do,
do new composers teach us to,
to here,
and once we've learned everything they
had to say,
do we not need their lesson anymore?
It's got to be something like that.
Right?
Well,
the first thing I would say about that
is we've used the word avant garde quite
a lot.
I actually don't like that term very
much.
And the other thing I would say is that
just because something is unfamiliar,
it doesn't therefore follow that at time
on guard.
Right?
So I mean there are,
there are forms of music that would be
difficult for,
for a certain listener to assimilate,
but it might be something that was
written a hundred and 50 years ago.
So it might be something that has in a
certain sense,
being thoroughly absorbed since.
Bye Bye.
Let's say certain listeners who are
familiar with it or people who are
familiar with the history of music,
but for someone who's never heard
anything like that,
and it takes someone,
for example,
who is living in a complete indifference
to,
uh,
to art music in general and has never
heard Bob.
I mean if you played them a,
uh,
you know,
at 20 minute collection of fugues they
might find the experience completely
intolerable.
So I mean,
yeah,
so,
so one of the things that you're
suggesting is that the order great
composers are still sufficiently,
let's call them avant garde for the bulk
of the population so that there's still
hunger for,
for,
for what they were able to achieve.
It still doesn't answer the question of
why those people in particular.
I mean,
we'd like to think that they were the
greatest exponents of their art and me
and maybe they were,
I'm sure many great exponents have died
unrecognized and,
and some ones that are maybe not
comparatively mediocre have been brought
forward.
I don't think that happens very often,
but we would.
You're,
here's a potential,
a way to answer that question.
I would say that the great composers are
the ones that fundamentally they own
their material more thoroughly and in a
more deeply personal way than other
composers and other words is the minimum
of what you might call neutral material
in their music.
In other words,
material that is essentially,
that already exists that is almost like
found material in a sense and that you
don't have to work very hard to fashion
into something resembling a coherent
piece.
A great composer invents forms.
They invent a language,
the invent a universe.
Uh,
they take enormous risks and I mean,
these composers that we talk about that
are familiar names to a very wide swath
of the public.
Beethoven,
for example,
was an absolute avant garde,
asked in his time.
I mean,
the,
the first,
uh,
performances of a lot of his pieces were
truly shocking and truly upset people.
Uh,
it's,
it's a very relative phenomenon,
all of this,
right?
So,
I mean,
Bach was considered to be a composer by
the end of his life who was writing
overly thick turgid music that was
impossible to listen to,
that was sort of tortured and,
and ridiculously complex.
Uh,
so I mean,
any,
any composer you can think of that that
is considered today to be among the
greats as,
as at some point being horribly
denigrated and humiliated and spoken
badly of by the public of their time.
So that's a,
that's a,
that's just a permanent feature of,
of music history and
what you'd expect to though,
because someone who is,
let's say going in the right direction,
but who is way ahead of everyone else
is,
it's very difficult for them to
communicate what they're doing and it's
very difficult for them to distinguish
themselves from the naked emperor.
So.
Right.
Well,
it Ezra pound has a,
has a great quote.
He says that artists or the or the
intensity of mankind,
right,
right.
Pseudo pods,
you know,
like.
Right,
exactly.
Some of those parts get better off of
them.
Don't find anything of any value,
but now and then everyone moves in that
direction.
It's akin to the idea that dreams and
fantasy or are the pseudopods of,
of the mind.
It's the same kind of idea and very
might be the same idea,
in fact.
So.
Alright.
So let's go back to,
to your contention that you know of this
explosive transformation that finally
resulted in,
in the radical transformations of music
into the 20th century.
Do you suppose those transformations are
any more radical than the proceeding
transformations had been?
That gets us there faster,
potentially more quickly.
If you look at the,
the,
the expansion and the development of
musical language from the,
from the,
from medieval times onwards.
It happened very,
very slowly for a very long period of
time for centuries.
And then you could argue that it is more
or less coincides with the industrial
revolution.
It starts to,
at that point,
it really starts to accelerate at an
extraordinary pace.
And so let's take,
let's take that analogy further.
I mean many,
many things start to accelerate at an
incredible pace in the industrial
revolution.
People get far wealthier and far faster
than they ever had likely in the history
of mankind.
So,
and then perhaps that allows for the
funding of orchestras and the funding of
more full time musicians because you
have to have a pretty rich society in
order to have any musicians that are,
that are actually doing that and nothing
else.
And they have more leisure time as well.
Right,
right,
right.
So that's all working in a positive
feedback loop.
Yeah.
Okay.
So,
so it's happening faster.
All so.
So walk us through the post romantic
period and tell us what's,
what's happening and maybe we can then
get into the modern like I mean modern
contemporary period.
And,
and we can talk a little bit about your
attraction to that.
Well,
in a sense you could say that the
structure is that had been coalescing
since the Baroque,
the forums and the genres and so on
start to,
they start to break up in the,
in the romantic era,
they become highly personalized.
You get composers that have highly
individual projects and also very more
importantly,
you have composers that are starting to
break away from the patronage system
from,
from being essentially the servants of,
uh,
of the nobility and start having
something akin to an individual career.
And Beethoven is often thought of as
being the sort of exemplary figure of
that,
the,
the sort of the one of the first
composers and music history to do that,
to write pieces strictly out of his own
volition as something that he wanted to
express regardless of whether there was
someone necessarily who wanted to pay
for it or not,
or even who wanted to listen to it.
So,
so that's,
that's a very,
very fundamental change of perspective
when that starts to happen.
Yeah.
Well that's sort of,
maybe that's the dawn of the idea of the
individual genius that,
that.
And maybe that rises in,
maybe that rises in a conceptual space
also as a consequence of the ideas of
the enlightenment,
what the enlightenment did,
or the renaissance,
maybe even more accurately,
the renaissance started to dignify
creative individuals with the same
status that,
that before,
that sort of canonical data he's had.
And I think you see that transformation
in visual art in,
in the medieval period.
The archetypal figures have this very,
um,
what would you call it,
abstract.
Almost almost,
uh,
almost an like modern animation like
representation.
And it isn't until the renaissance kicks
in,
especially in northern Italy where the
divine
people Christ say,
and Mary start to take on recognizably
human forms.
They become individuals identifiable
individuals.
And I think that's a two way process is
that not only is the deity becoming
identifiably individual instead of
formulaic and abstractly represented
almost like a hero cliff,
but the individuals becoming dafydd at
that point as well.
And that,
and that seems to me to coincide with
the idea of the great artist and the
great independent artists,
which is very,
it's a very strange concept.
And that's gone.
And be also a function of wealth,
the mere fact that that
conceptualization is even possible,
you know,
I mean to take her back at the history
and you look at maybe the master of the
undifferentiated artistic and religious
form might've been something like the
Shaman,
but the Sharman was fundamentally a
healer and that was his,
that was his role.
And I suppose how you could say in a
sense how he made his living.
He just used all these cultural tools to
do that.
But,
but his economic base in some sense was
a lot wider.
So.
Alright.
So okay.
So we're in the 20th century and we're.
And we have this plethora of novel
musical forms and that's happening
because there's a lot more musicians and
there's a lot more listeners.
So the speed takes off.
And I guess another thing that happens
is that leaves the typical listener more
and more in the dust.
Well,
again,
not necessarily.
You have plenty of composers even in the
romantic period that are writing
essentially vernacular music that
doesn't push the boundaries terribly.
And the ones that we've retained,
again,
are the ones that contributed the most.
And the ones that deviated the most from
the sort of standard operating procedure
of the day.
So we simply,
we don't,
we don't retain the ones that were
average,
the ones that we're operating safely
within the bounds of what was,
what was accepted conventionally to be
music.
So that's,
that's the first thing.
So we have a,
a,
a view of history that is extremely
filtered in that sense.
We have no idea what it was like
actually to be alive in,
in,
uh,
in 18,
70 and,
and see things from that perspective.
So.
So that's,
that's the first thing.
That's a funny thing too,
because even with,
even with say rock music or any other
genre,
when you hear a band that was once
considered creative,
but you hear them 20 years later,
you can't tell that they're creative
because if the creativity was of any
reasonable sword,
it's been,
it's become,
I wouldn't say necessarily cliched.
Maybe that's what happens to the artists
that aren't retained is their
contributions become cliched because
everyone else picks it up and you hear
it implicitly in every other piece of
music that's being done.
And so you listen back in the past and
you think,
oh,
there's nothing in that that I haven't
heard before.
And so it seems to me that the Beatles
are a good example of that town,
at least for me,
when I listened to them,
I wouldn't say so much their earlier
stuff,
although it's got a vitality that,
that is still somewhat compelling,
but there later,
music still strikes me as sufficiently
surprising.
It hasn't all been incorporated into
the,
into the rock lexicon.
So
truly,
truly great music has a,
has a depth and it has a,
uh,
it has a,
a semantic overload in a sense that,
that no matter how many times you
listened to it,
you can't actually exhaust it.
And that's an extraordinary thing.
Yeah.
Well,
how can that be?
I mean,
it,
it leads me to conclude that the,
the peace must contain more than the
composer knowingly put into it in a
sense that,
I mean,
it's,
it's amazing.
It's an amazing thing for me to think
that a,
a container that would have had to write
in less than a week,
you know,
could,
that I could listen to that hundreds or
thousands of times and never get to the
bottom of it.
Yeah.
I mean that he put in his $30,000,
right?
His musical,
his depth of musical capacity was so
immense that he could put a lot into a
very little space.
But you see the same thing with great
visual.
You see the same thing with great art
period.
The greater the art,
the more it's inexhaustible and,
and it seems surprising.
The counter example of that is
propaganda I would say.
And you know,
or,
or the really crassly commercial music
which capitalizes on what everyone knows
and takes it that tiny step.
It varies at some tiny step.
So it's playing to the,
it's playing to the almost already sated
crowd and there's a niche in there
because it's good for people who want to
be pushed very,
a very tiny amount,
but it dies very quickly because
everyone can incorporate it's new
message almost immediately.
But that,
yeah,
that,
that whole notion of inexhaustible and
art,
it's an amazing thing and it has
something to do with the depth.
I mean,
I saw a great representation of the
Bible at one point,
a visual representation that showed
along the bottom was a graph showing
each different chapter.
So imagine a graph with a line at the
bottom and there's however many thousand
chapters there are in the Bible.
Each one represented by a bar,
tiny bar stretching downwards,
and the length of the bar was
proportional to how many times that
chapter or verse,
I think it was chapter,
it doesn't matter.
Was Cross referenced in the book and
some of those were Crawford Cross
referenced a tremendous amount,
but then there were curves drawn on top
of that,
linking all the cross references
together.
So you have this amazingly complex,
hyperlinked document where everything in
it refers to everything else and that
gives it this insane depth.
There's just no way of exhausting it
because there's an infinite number of
routes through it in some sentence.
And you know,
well that's,
that's certainly true with great works
of music.
They're like,
they're like iridescent luminous objects
that,
that say different things depending on
the angle at which you look at them and
so you know you can,
you can,
you can listen to a piece of music 10
times over the course of a week and
think that you've more or less exhausted
it in terms of what it,
what it can say to you.
You go back to the exact same piece 10
years later and you won't.
You might don't recognize it at all.
You might hear it in a completely
different way because you yourself have
changed in the intervening.
Right?
That's the other thing is the music is
the music actually exists in the space
where you made it and so your additions
of life,
what you've listened to your mood and
also the way you choose to go through
it,
especially if it's complex because you
can concentrate on one instrument or set
of instruments as opposed to another.
Like you can use them as the guide so
you can concentrate on the baselines or
you can concentrate on the sounds that
are much higher in the register and
every time you do that with a complex
piece of music,
it,
it's a different journey.
That's,
that's one way of thinking about it.
So that's also extremely interesting.
Okay.
So you were talking about how sudden
acceleration of music in the 20th
century.
So why don't you,
why don't you pick up on that?
Well really I mentioned earlier that
it's something that starts to take place
with the industrial revolution and it,
it,
it takes up,
it picks up extraordinary speed at the,
at the beginning of the 20th century.
And in a sense you could say that the,
the history of music in the 20th century
is not,
is not divorced from,
from the,
the world wars.
You cannot separate them.
You also cannot underestimate the
enormous significance that that had on
the development of the art.
I mean,
certainly after the Second World War,
there's a generalized sense amongst
European musicians that,
that fundamentally in an old order had
been overturned and had,
had proven to be absolutely rotten and
that,
uh,
there was,
there was a,
an almost paroxysmal desire to get away
from that into,
into,
into create entirely new musical worlds.
And that was definitely allied with the,
the,
this,
this need to,
um,
to,
to build a new and better society.
So you can't,
you can't separate those two things and
you have to,
you have to try to imagine yourself as a
20 or 25 year old composer,
you know,
growing up in a,
in a Europe that's been absolutely
devastated.
And the,
to the extent that there's practically
nothing left and you're trying to
rebuild on,
on top of that,
you know.
So that's,
that's,
that's the situation that the composer
is born in that era we were faced with.
So do you want to pretend as though
nothing has happened and,
and go back to writing late romantic
music or uh,
do you,
you accept that fundamentally something
enormous has taken place that you can't
ignore it and if you want to be an
authentic artist and if you want to
manifest the things that you can't help
but perceive,
then how do you do that and can you do
that within the confines of a language
that was associated with the period
before the war.
So that's a somewhat simpler fittings,
that's a somewhat simplified account of
events because certainly there was a,
there was a push towards ever more
personal and individual forms of
expression starting with the late 19th
century,
but it really accelerates and takes off
to the after the Second World War and a
number of reasons.
Well,
and also that that's,
it seems to me that it was,
it's that postwar period roughly
speaking that was what grabbed your
attention when you were composing your
pop songs as well and drew you in
through that particular rabbit hole.
So.
Okay,
so back to the post war period.
Right?
So one of the interesting things that
happened in Europe was that the,
the,
the need to reconstruct these different
states manifested also through a desire
on the parts of certain politicians to,
to,
to show how advanced their societies
could be through the medium of art.
So in,
in Germany,
for example,
enormous sums of money were put into,
uh,
into,
into music and they,
they,
they developed radio orchestra,
every single region had its own
orchestra,
very,
very high levels,
uh,
of,
of an artistic quality as well.
And,
and,
and so one corollary of that was that
they wanted their music to be absolutely
advanced and,
and absolutely striking.
And,
and that was a kind of a,
a very,
very strong impulse that began to be
felt in other European countries as
well.
And,
and France,
for their part,
had to also show that they were
investing in,
in contemporary art and contemporary
music.
And,
and so there was a very high degree of
subsidization of the avant garde and the
postwar period.
Now that's not to say that life was easy
for every artist because it most
definitely was not.
And it was an enormous struggle for
composers to produce this kind of work
and have it be performed,
but there was certainly a major
investment on the part of the European
states in terms of funding this kind of
musical expression.
So more or less,
they seem to have known instinctively,
even by your own argument that if they
were going to rebuild that this was
going to be part,
an important part,
maybe a vital part of the rebuilding
process and you wouldn't think that
necessarily because you would assume
that people's attention would be to what
you might regard as more practical
concerns.
But of course,
since we don't know what role music is
playing precisely,
but I'm rolling,
it seems to be incredibly important.
It's not that easy to figure out exactly
what's practical and what isn't.
Keeping People's morale up is of
incredible important or restoring their
morale as well as incredibly important
maybe above all else.
Right?
Right.
Absolutely.
So one of the essential functions of art
is his spiritual.
Whether people know it or not.
And so if you want to rebuild your
culture,
there's no better way to do it.
Then through the medium of art,
as far as I'm concerned,
I mean it's a.
it's an absolutely fundamental thing.
It's so fundamental that even in the
most in the midst of the most horrific
experiences a human being can be,
there is a.
There is a redemptive experience to be
had in art.
Right?
Right,
right.
Which is really,
really to say something.
I mean,
it really is to say something because
there's often you can find people in
situations often where nothing else
could do that.
There can't be matched by any other
means and many people have their lives
saved by art.
There's no doubt about that and I think
that's true on an ongoing basis.
Even with young people.
I mean certainly when they're going
through,
they're there,
late adolescent or even early
adolescent,
cataclysmic changes.
Many of them live for music and music is
helping them catalyze a group identity,
but deeper than that,
it's also providing them with the
implicit sense that there's meaning,
that the being is meaningful and that
there's meaning out hand and you can't
argue with.
The other thing that's so cool,
especially about music is you can't
argue with its meaning.
It just manifests themselves.
So it's,
it's outside of the domain of rational.
You can't criticize it.
You sound like a fool.
It's like,
well,
why are you dancing?
It's like,
well,
that,
that isn't a question,
and also there's no answer to it.
And why are you listening to music?
What's the point?
Is also not a question and there's not
an answer to it either.
It's self evident and it's almost self
evident to everyone,
which is fantastically remarkable.
It is indeed.
So the last thing I would say about that
is that fundamentally the way that,
uh,
that someone expresses them themselves
through music,
if it's authentic,
fundamentally it's not a choice,
you know?
So one thing that,
that,
uh,
that audiences might keep in mind if
they're,
if they're about to engage with
something that's unfamiliar to them,
is that if it's,
if it's a half decent work of art and if
the composer is,
is sincere in what they're doing,
then fundamentally it's something that
in a sense they have to do.
You know,
there,
there's not a strong element of choice
involved,
so it's not,
it's not an arbitrary thing to express
yourself in one way or another.
I mean it's,
it's,
uh,
it's something that,
that you,
you don't get to choose.
I've also noticed like I've had more
than my fair share of creative clients
probably I know certainly because
they're attracted,
for example,
to come and see me by the content of my,
my videos in my lectures and that sort
of thing.
And,
and one of the things,
and I studied creativity in,
in,
in some depth and its relationship to
personality.
And one of the things that I found that
really been struck by is that there is a
trait which is openness,
which is a fundamental trait and for
people who are high in openness is if
you imagine the person as a,
as a central trunk with a few branches
and the branches are the place where
that nourishment emerges up into the
back of course too.
But there's a,
there's a pathway of life along those,
of those subdivisions of the trunk.
Um,
if they're creative,
that might be the main part of them
that's alive and if that is manifesting
itself,
they just droop and die.
Sometimes they criticize them to death,
some themselves to death rationally or,
or,
well,
there,
there's,
there's a choice.
They can either pursue their creative
nature or they can wilt and die that
that's,
but that's not much of a choice really
striking to me how fundamental a,
an instinct that is and how,
how unrelenting it is and it manifests
itself in their increased proclivity to
fantasize and to dream and to,
and to find like a,
a,
a life inside of boxes that's
predictable,
unbearable,
really unbearable.
Whereas a conventional person,
a conservative person isn't like that at
all.
They find that routine soothing and,
and uh,
and the exercise of that predictable
duty,
meaningful and sustaining,
but a creative person that,
that just,
it's just death for them.
Well,
there's plenty of examples of,
of,
of creative artists who have had to
endure the most horrible suffering and
just terrible material circumstances in
order to pursue a singular creative
vision.
And I mean,
that's absolutely amazing thing that you
think that people would voluntarily
subject themselves to that.
So it,
it makes you wonder is essentially
voluntary.
I don't.
I don't know if it's worse.
It's alternative,
the alternative is worse.
And so they are possessed to some degree
by genius,
you know,
that's the genie,
it's a major thing to possess a person
and,
and it's,
it's a,
it's a fundamental natural
manifestation.
So is it voluntary?
You can either cooperate with it or get
crushed by it.
I think that's basically the,
that's basically that your choice.
It's still a choice and you know,
you do interact with your creativity.
It's not like it just pours out of you.
It's,
there's,
there's work that needs to be done.
Even though the sources there in some
sense,
which is also extremely strange.
It doesn't just pull her out,
although it does in some people,
but they all,
they'd have to have developed the
expertise necessary for that to occur.
It still effortful and demanding more to
well it's effortful and demanding and we
can leave it at that.
So.
Yup.
So what was back to the beginning of the
story,
since we're going to do the right thing
from a musical perspective,
you talked about being attracted to the
avant garde,
poking up through in some sense because
of your experimentation with integrating
that into pop songs,
but then that took you down this rabbit
hole that,
that propelled you into your career as a
composer and,
and into moving to Europe and all of
that.
So,
and you said that part of that was that
you found some of what you were
listening to incomprehensible and that
was a mystery to you wanted to pursue.
It was that you see that as a
manifestation of your musical ability
trying to perfect itself.
You found something you admired and
couldn't comprehend,
or what was it?
Well,
first of all could,
could we,
could we exchange the term rabbit hole
for four gleaming field of light?
That's how I would characterize it.
I think that's a little bit more
accurate.
Um,
well,
how can I,
how can I explain this?
There's a dragon with every gaming field
of light,
you know.
Now,
one of the things I would say is that
there are things that I,
I would I would hear and I would
instinctively know are are deeply
meaningful.
They are so,
so meaningful that I almost can't begin
to fathom their depths and you don't
necessarily understand them
intellectually.
You don't understand what how they are
made or or how they function or what
their component parts are,
but there's something in it that
fundamentally speaks to you on a,
on a very,
very deep level.
I can't explain why that is.
I can't explain why certain things that
I that I've heard or that I heard when I
was a teenager had that effect on me,
but they were they.
They were like invitations into a,
into a,
a,
a world of seemingly limitless potential
that you cannot refuse it.
It's like a form of fascination that
grip the grip,
the grip by the mercurial spirit.
You know,
what was that
curious?
Is this thing that flips around that it
can't help but attract your attention.
The God mercury and he's an emissary of
the gods,
right?
Yes,
exactly that,
and so if your interest is trapped by
something like that,
you find it spontaneously meaningful.
It is an invitation so you don't have to
follow it,
but if you do follow it,
you'll find what you're being invited to
for better or for worse.
Right,
right.
Yeah,
it's,
it's an instinctive sense that this is
something that is deeply meaningful and
you and you follow it and it takes you
places.
And so that's what happened with me.
I was listening to,
uh,
the composers have what's called the
second Viennese school,
so that's a,
that's a,
a trio of composers,
Barragan,
uh,
who I was,
it just instinctively fascinated by when
I was a teenager.
Now they're considered by some people to
be difficult composers to get into.
It really depends on the,
on the work.
I would say there are pieces that are
actually quite accessible,
but there was something there that
absolutely fascinated me.
And once I had,
once I understood that that world
existed,
I found it extremely difficult to go
back to what I had been doing
previously.
Now my music has absolutely nothing in
common with,
with theirs.
I mean it's,
it's stylistically very,
very different,
so I,
it's not a question of wanting to do the
same thing necessarily,
but it just,
it was a sign that there is a,
an enormous world of exotic knowledge
and experience to be had if you only pay
attention.
Well that's a good,
that's a good,
uh,
what would you call it?
That's a good phrase to think about in
relationship to life in general.
So,
and it's a good thing for people to know
because you know,
if you're living a life that's devoid of
sufficient meaning,
there is the probability that there's a
bunch of things that you could be paying
attention to that would rectify that.
It's not that simple because you can be
at states of mind that make that very,
very difficult,
but it is nice to know that those gaming
fields exist and that you can pursue the
flickers and,
and,
and find out where you're going to go.
All right,
so I'm gonna close this by pointing out
to everyone that Sam,
Andrea has a patriotic count,
www.patrion.com
forward slash Samuel.
Andrea,
is that correct?
That's right.
All right,
good.
And so,
um,
if you're inclined to,
to,
uh,
indicate your support for his work,
at least visit his,
his youtube website as well because Sam
has been made a lot of videos,
a number of different videos helping
guide people through the musical
landscape,
the complex musical landscape and which
seems to me to be a very useful
endeavor.
So anyways,
thanks very much for talking to me and
with everyone that's listening and uh,
well I suspect we'll do this again in
the future.
Yeah,
thank you for the invitation.
I really appreciate it.