Hi Everybody,
I'm here today again with Gregg Hurwitz,
an old friend of mine,
a former student from Harvard.
Um,
we've talked before and we've got some
exciting things to talk about today.
I'll give you some background on Greg.
First.
Greg is a New York Times number one
internationally bestselling author of 20
thrillers,
including out of the dark,
coming out in 2019 and two award winning
thriller novels for Teens.
His novels have won numerous literary
words,
grace,
top 10 lists,
and have been published in 30 languages.
He's written screenplays for or sold
spec scripts to many of the major
studios,
including the book of Henry and written,
developed and produced TV for various
networks.
He's also a New York Times best selling
comic book writer,
having pen stories for marvel,
Wolverine and punisher and DC,
Batman and penguin.
He's published numerous academic
articles on Shakespeare,
taught fiction writing and use English
department and guest lectured for Ucla
and for Harvard in the United States and
international.
And the course of researching his
thrillers,
he sneaked onto demolition ranges with
navy seals,
swam with sharks in the Galapagos,
and gone undercover into mind.
Controlled cults,
her which grew up in the bay area while
completing an Mba from Harvard and a
masters from Trinity called jocks in
Shakespearean tragedy.
He wrote his first novel.
He was the undergraduate scholar athlete
of the year at Harvard for his pole
vaulting exploits and played college
soccer in England where he was a fellow.
So that's greg.
Hello everybody.
It's quite an intro.
I think I'm just going to.
You follow me around everywhere that
before I enter a room.
Dislikes me.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's right.
That's the sort of intro that makes
everyone hopes you're a real son of a
bitch after reading an intro like that
so they can make it morally dislike you
the best thing.
Dislike Jordan,
as you know.
Yeah.
So we're not gonna talk too much today
about Greg's previous exploits.
Instead we're going to talk about some
of the work he's been doing in the
political realm recently and the reasons
for doing that.
So Greg,
I'm going to let you take that away.
Well,
so
look,
I write thrillers and I have.
The shorthand that I always give is that
about half of my friends were born
again,
Christian navy seal,
snipers and half my friends are gay acw
and I taught equally in the red and blue
states.
My readership is very,
very diverse and I think because of that
I have a real ear for the buzz words and
phrases and ideological shorthand that
really shut people up.
Um,
that just make them stop listening.
My politics,
I'm,
I'd say I'm a bit more of a classical
liberal and one of the things that I
talk a lot about is there certain
phrases that we've run up from both
sides that just make people completely
stopped and it's not dissimilar to what
we're trying to do when we're writing.
Right?
If you write and use buzzwords and catch
phrases and cliches,
it's less interesting.
If you already know what you think of 40
start writing and there's no room for
discovery along the way,
then you're not.
It's not real writing.
It's propaganda,
right?
It's an ramped.
You're never going to be surprised by
something in the third act.
And so there's a real overlap for that.
But I found,
and so one of the things that I've been
trying to do a given how polarized I
have found discourse to be and how I
found myself moving between vastly
different worlds is to try and commit
myself to ending or contributing to
ending polarizing discourse.
Uh,
and so part of that is that I've been
focused on trying to rebrand the,
the Democratic Party of working with a
lot of different candidates and entities
in an effort to get away from,
from gridlocked and more towards
solutions.
I have a view that's a lot like Jonathan
Heit who you've interviewed it lanes who
I think is a great description of the
need and necessity for both
conservatives and liberals in that,
you know,
conservatives like walls around things,
right?
They're like walls around gender.
They like walls around countries.
Build a wall is sort of a brilliant
republican slogan.
And the job of,
of liberals is to say,
hang on a minute,
if that wall is to impenetrable,
you're not going to have new ideas and
people and then we'll stop me to die.
And so for me,
and you and I've talked before about how
it's also the case for inventors and
entrepreneurs who kind of create things
which tends to be more of a liberal
leaning,
but if you want them run effectively,
often you need conservative managers to
come in.
And so I would want there to be stronger
parties on both sides.
I mean,
I want there to be better discourse.
I think if there's a stronger Republican
party,
it makes the Democratic Party have to
raise their game and come up with
solutions.
And out of the one thing I will say that
has been common and everyone who I
talked to is nobody's thrilled with the
level of political discourse right now.
So there's a couple of things there that
are really interesting.
I mean you talk about the necessity for
a high quality representation on both
sides of the political,
a political,
what do you call that continuum.
Let's say there are really powerful,
temperamental and philosophical reasons
for that.
So now you mentioned that the liberal
types tend to be entrepreneurs and
creators and a conservative types tend
to be managers and administrators.
So that that's pretty well documented in
the psychological literature,
but you see echoes of that and you,
you mentioned the border issue as well
because of course to categorize things
we have to put boundaries around them,
but boundaries can artificially separate
and make things stagnant as well.
So we have to have a continual
discussion about exactly where the
boundaries should be drawn without ever.
Also presuming that we should just do
away with boundaries all together
because that does away with category.
Then with regards to hierarchies,
well no know it seems to be the job of
the right wing to put forward the
proposition that hierarchies are
necessary from an organizational
perspective.
So if a bunch of people decided to go do
something of value,
let's say it's a collective value as
well as individual value,
then inevitably when they operate
cooperatively and competitively they're
going to produce a hierarchy.
And the hierarchy is actually a tool to
accomplish that task in the social
arena.
But the problem with that is that
hierarchy can become overly rigid and
corrupt,
and it can dispossessed people,
uh,
without,
without that dispossession being a
necessary function of the task that the
hierarchy's attempting to perform.
What's that?
It's always both,
right?
I mean,
it's always that we needed to organize
and there always are in equities.
The result of this,
the thing that I have found is that when
people lock into political conversations
from one side or the other,
it becomes all or nothing.
And for me,
nothing gets accomplished in all or
nothing.
And so a straw man,
you know,
Democrats,
that all of them just want to tear down
the whole system and you know,
those are some of the louder voices on
twitter isn't helpful anymore than a
claim that Republicans have no interest
whatsoever in the people who are just
disaster.
And a lot of what's important is to look
at,
you know,
conservatives who are thoughtful.
It's not like they love the fact that
people are dispossessed.
So the question becomes how do we all
help that and how do we actually have a
discussion and how do we,
how do we get away from the fact that
compromise toward solutions is somehow a
betrayal that if you compromise anything
from the furthest extreme,
your sort of portraying your own
ideology and your own people?
Yeah,
well I think partly you do that by
focusing on specific problems instead of
provider radiological solutions.
And that's so part of what we're trying
to discuss today and to contribute to is
that they raise centralization,
let's say,
of the political parties and also to
make a case for the necessity of
intelligent discourse.
Knowing that people on both sides of the
political spectrum have something
intelligent to say.
So the conservatives have every reason
to put forward the proposition that
hierarchies are both inevitable and
useful,
but also to keep firmly in mind that
they can become corrupt and that they do
tend to dispossess and the liberals have
every reason to keep in mind that
hierarchies are absolutely necessary in
order to get things done,
but that the dispossessed need a voice
so that the system remains both
permeable and fair and it's very
necessary for both sides to have some
respect for the position of the
alternative.
The alternative,
temperamental type,
let's say.
Well,
that's where we have to meet in,
in rational enlightenment discourse or
else we can't win.
You know,
talked a lot about the big,
the big five personality traits and the
ways that it orients differently in
politics.
So it's like Liberals or higher and
empathy,
right?
In higher and openness.
That's why a lot of artists do you find
are,
um,
tend to be liberal,
you know,
at least the good ones.
Like we have bruce springsteen and on
the other side it's hard for,
for,
for president trump to fill up an arena
with people who,
who are the artists of a certain caliber
and you know,
it doesn't mean that that higher empathy
is better and I think often when
liberals are talking,
they're trying to push through only
apathy and higher empathy and they're
trying to educate people in the higher
epa well to fix psychological traits.
And the other thing is,
you know,
Republicans or conservatives tend to be
high on conscientiousness and
conscientiousness codes for a bunch of
things that are really useful,
you know,
codes for better health,
better finances,
more stable marriages and longer
lifespan.
So one of the things when I'm advising,
you know,
democrats is like,
you can't,
if you have to win an argument on the
merits,
you have to make a better argument.
If you're losing people,
you can't just go to them and say be
more empathetic.
That's not an argument,
right?
It's going to President Clinton and
saying,
can't you just be an introvert?
These are sort of fixed traits.
And the other thing is is a lot of
conservatives are doing fine over there
where they're stable marriages and
longer life.
Well in the empathy issue is interesting
as well because it's easy for that to be
regarded reflexively as a virtue,
but an excess of pity,
let's say can be destructive.
There's a whole psychoanalytic
literature on the negative consequences
of of fostering overdependence let's
say,
and that's a real problem and there is
our managerial literature too that
suggests that less agreeable managers do
better as well as less agreeable people
in general having higher incomes because
they're better at arguing for
themselves.
So it is really necessary to give some
consideration to the fact that each of
these temperaments has it marked
advantages and disadvantages and a
proper niche where it can function and
and other places where it actually
constitutes a problem.
Well,
that's where we have to rise above
ourselves in me.
Like where did we meet?
We meet in freedom of speech.
There's a reason it's the first
amendment.
You know,
if I was dumb enough to be single issue
voter and that would be my single issue
because part of it is as,
as as a classical liberal,
I tend to approach Steve,
I have a strong amount of empathy,
but I also realize that that's not a
trait that I can map on to everybody
else in.
We're having a discussion that I have to
actually meet and make arguments for,
for people who,
who,
who approached the world in different
ways and have different kinds of
successes to make higher conscientious
arguments in a way that appeals more
broadly.
And I mean that's free marketplace of
ideas and we have to meet and figure out
and discuss these matters and if we're
not doing it in words we're doing with
fists tonight.
The other problem with agreeableness,
let's say an empathy,
is that the,
the,
the empathetic identification tends to
make the person who's experiencing it
feel immediately virtuous because
they're on the side of the weaker party,
let's say.
And there's obviously some utility in
that,
but it's not really.
It doesn't come with a set of solutions
to complex problems.
You know,
it seems to me that agreeableness is a
pretty good virtue for small units like
the family were egalitarianism.
Distribution is of extreme importance,
but it doesn't seem to work very well at
at higher levels of complexity.
So for example,
it's conscientiousness predicts
workplace proficiency,
you know,
it's the second best predictor predictor
after ICU.
Agreeableness is actually somewhat
negatively correlated and less and less
the domain has to do with direct
personal care.
And so I don't think agreeable to scales
very well,
which is why conscientiousness has to
enter into the picture
and that's very helpful motivator for
myself.
I look at a problem on my approach tends
to be empathy for people who have been
left out or have been who don't have the
right end of the dominance hierarchy.
And for me it's a motivator to look at
actual solutions and problems and issues
and there's a lot of real concrete
things that can be attacked,
but if you don't attack them from a
perspective that's morally
condescending,
you can actually get shit done.
Well,
it also,
it's also very helpful to increase the
resolution of the problem.
Right?
And,
and to stop trying to solve every
problem with one with one brush stroke,
most things are really complicated.
So intelligent political discourse
should involve decomposing a problem
like poverty,
which isn't our problem,
but a set of a thousand problems into
each of those thousand problems and then
trying to generate creative solutions to
each of them and then to test them.
And so the resolution of the,
of the discussion has to be increased.
And one of the things that you and I
have talked about was the possibility
that these longer form,
the longer form discourse,
um,
avenues that are available on the new
media,
like what we're doing right now might
enable us to identify and promote
politicians who are capable of high
resolution discussion,
who had the real solutions to real
problems instead of having to compress
everything into a six second soundbite.
Well,
the other thing that I'm finding really
heartening is a lot of the candidates
that I am working with interacting with
and at this point that's in the hundreds
are very focused on actual solutions.
And I'm trying to get a handle on,
you know,
the cultural conversation,
whatever the hell that is,
it benefits by blowing the extremes and
it feels like that's almost all that
we're hearing about.
And when I'm dealing with actual
candidates,
a lot of them are dealing with the anti
corruption healthcare jobs and education
like are aware of that.
That isn't the plan.
And so there's this amplifying the facts
and then we have a lot of sort of like
this cultural conversation about the
cultural conversation that things become
very kind of narrow and the level of the
candidates are operating at the level
that people are.
You know,
I'm,
I'm dealing a lot with candidates in
different states.
People are having a hard time right now
and they need hardcore solutions and
they actually don't give a shit about
everyone on twitter and facebook who's
preaching.
Every Mazda already unfriended them.
They need solutions.
They need a government that's
functional,
they need,
they want more transparency and
microcorruption.
There's a very common set of things that
govern people,
but there's this sort of amplified
effect from the extremes of the party
that are gathering the the attention and
the biggest tool that we have in a
democracy in some ways is our attention
and where we focus it and if that's
being hijacked by know bullshit
conversations and Straw men.
I mean I would love to engage with,
with reasonable,
you know,
Republicans,
a lot of whom are my friends and all my
colleagues to say,
look,
I know we can go and push everything to
extremes and find in debate and score
points,
but like you don't like some of this
shit anymore than I do.
Like what's an actual conversation from
our different perspectives,
assuming I don't have all the answers
that we can come up with certain
solutions that's going to take care of
people who are not doing as well.
You know,
who are not doing as well.
They're not keeping up with the economy
because that's not good for anybody.
That's not a game that is iterable
across multiple genes in generations.
If more and more people are starting to
see more and more not good for anybody,
even the people at the top,
so how do we seek to kind of balance
that out for people who don't have their
fair shot and during
conservative perspective you could say,
well,
how do we stabilize the hierarchy so the
tendency for or the multiple hierarchies
for the tendency so that the tendency
for people to stack up at the bottom
doesn't become so extreme that the
entire system starts to shake and
tremble,
which obviously isn't good for anyone at
all.
We're seeing a lot of shaking and
trembling.
I mean,
I think a lot of people in the last
election did not feel heard or seen or
represented in the choices of candidates
and a lot of people were like,
I don't care what it is.
It's not going to be business as usual.
Right?
So the solution isn't,
in my estimation,
to denigrate people who chose to vote
for president trump.
I think the solution is to talk about
the fact that we need to do better.
If we want to promote a.
If the Democrats want to promote a
viable alternative,
we have to do better with what our
messaging is.
We have to do better on messages that
are anticorruption and we have to make a
better argument.
Yeah.
Well the thing is,
you know,
I was on Bill Maher show a while back
and a lot of the panelists on his show
really taking pot shots at the trump
supporters and,
and you know,
with the typical sort of pejorative
center label that are leveled at them.
And I thought that was extremely
dangerous because they're basically
dissing,
let's say he was a terrible cliche about
50 percent of the American population in
the same percentage that's been voting
Republican for about 20 years.
And to just out of hand dismiss your,
the people who are voting differently
than,
than you as somehow primitive or
primordial or,
or foolish or are ill advised is very,
very dangerous.
And also more than that,
it's also an abdication of
responsibility because the Republicans
might have won the last election or
trump might have won the last election,
but certainly the democrats lost the
last election.
And so I would,
if I thought that their discourse would
have been a lot more productive if they
would have focused on the failings of
the Democratic Party,
and that's also a lot more useful
because if you can figure out why you
didn't succeed,
even though it very close election,
if you can figure out what mistakes you
made,
then you could rectify it.
That's exactly along the lines of the
things that you and I talked about at
length,
which is personal accountability.
It's like you get in a fight with your
wife or your husband is the best thing
to do to point out the 50 percent or 80
percent or 90 percent where they screwed
up or to actually reflect and think
about whatever percent it is at whatever
number that you can do something better
that's actually within your control.
And so for me,
that's a scalable notion.
You know,
I have many friends too wide and varied
and smart who voted for trump to dismiss
them all as idiots.
It's,
it's a very,
you can't denigrate it.
And plus we're married to them.
That's $50.
40 nine point nine percent of our
population,
we are married to them and we have to
figure out how to talk and to come up
with solutions that make sense and that
everybody can and so for me,
a lot of it is to look at what the
impulse was that was underlying that and
figure out where Democrats can be better
at seeing and hearing people and
furthering arguments in ways that feel
with legitimate and connect with people
and figure out what the messaging is.
So you always clean up your side of the
house first and it doesn't mean that
there's.
There's a number of policies that I'm
highly critical of president trump.
That doesn't mean that identity great
his followers or the people who voted
for him or that I will dismiss any
tendencies that they might've had or
hesitations that they might've had about
voting or otherwise.
The right message should be something
like,
I'm not so much white.
Your opponent is worse,
but by why you're better,
why your solutions are better,
why?
Why,
why,
why?
The grass is greener on your side of the
fence.
Why there's less corruption occurring
under your watch and and also marketing
the fact that the solutions that you
have are both reasonable and practical.
I mean that does require more elevated
form of political discourse and it would
be really nice if that could be
facilitated by these,
by these long forms that are available.
Hear the refrain all the time of the
Democrats don't have a message that
president trump is awful,
is not a message and I'd been.
I'd been really heartened with the
conversations that I'm having with
candidates right now that there's a huge
focus on kitchen table issues.
There's a huge focus on trying to tackle
health care and education to jobs in
ways that are more innovative.
When you talk to the actual candidates
who I want to start to pull it into more
and more conversations.
I have an enormous amount of of optimism
and the other thing is,
is your real money where your mouth is
stance against corruption and there is
something.
There's something called the disclose
act that a lot of Democrats are working
on which is fully disclosing all of your
donors,
you know,
releasing taxes.
I'm taking a pledge against no dark
money.
There's a whole number of different
resolutions,
you know,
I'm fighting voter suppression and that
means whether we lose or not,
it's not about fighting voter
suppression to sort of tell the vote.
It's like we need the right to win
elections or lose elections fairly,
and so there's a lot of positions that
are being put forth right now that I
feel are really heartening,
including a very strong anticorruption
stance because you can't.
You have to clean up what your site is
and in this wave of candidates and I'm
looking at,
it's been really impressive to me how
they're starting to further and
articulate what the,
what the argument can be from that side
and I think that's what we can also
start to find common ground to talk
about the corruption.
I mean there's a lot of republicans who
are enthralled with the level of
discourse right now.
Well,
one of the things that struck me when
I've been talking to you lately is we've
been talking about what happened with
the Democratic Party is also the idea
that the radicals,
the identity politics types managed to
take over the narrative to a large
degree,
partly because the extremism is more
attractive,
let's say among a dying mainstream
media.
It's click,
baity and and easy to attract attention
to and loud and and cinematic and all of
those things,
but also that the centrist Democrats
seem to have lost faith in their central
narrative or perhaps have failed to,
to produce one over the last 15 years
and that left a void into which the
extremist narrative,
the oppressor,
oppressive oppressor,
oppression,
narrative,
let's say,
or or pressure victim narrative has been
able to slide in and dominate because of
that void.
And so that's another thing that needs
to be seriously addressed.
It's like the center has lost its
narrative and,
and,
and that's something I'd like to see the
Democrats a deal with now in it,
in,
in the first ad that you generate it.
You had a farmer talk,
if I remember correctly,
you had a farmer talk about success and
about what that might mean if you could
obtain it individually.
I think where we have fallen down as
Democrats and and where we are now
reorienting is,
is,
is the discussion of aspirational
values,
meaning is it a rigged game?
Like we can absolutely point to things
that are disadvantages,
you know,
but to say it's a rigged game,
it's a regained.
The thing that we have to say is all
that we're in favor of our fair rules at
the starting gate and if you work
harder,
if you're an innovator,
if you bust your ass good on you,
like go buy a mansion in three cars,
you know,
go start a second business.
We have to be rewarding of success and
speaking to people's aspirations and you
know,
we talk a lot about income inequality
and the problem with that is what's the
opposite of that?
Is income equality.
Well,
nobody wants that.
If you look at the average salaries and
incomes of people in the Senate and
Congress,
they're doing just fine.
They don't want that either.
And so for me,
I think it's much more powerful to talk
about income injustice because it means
that people have a fair shot at the
starting gate and then they can
differentiate themselves by their own
abilities and their own willingness to
work.
And for me it's about the starting gate
and making sure that we look at things
that are there.
Yeah,
well and also that the emphasis that you
placed on rewarding actual achievement.
We also have to be in a situation where
we can admit that at least one of the
factors that differentiates people as
they move up competence hierarchies.
And we have to admit that some of the
hierarchies that exist are actually
based on competence and not merely on
oppression is the amount of effort they
into things.
And you know,
that's become.
That's become an anastomotic,
a proposition on many university
campuses where you're not allowed,
in fact,
to state that hard work because at some
of the people who have made it,
have done a,
done it as a consequence of working
extra hard.
Because I guess that undermines the
narrative that the whole game is rigged.
And the truth of the matter is the game
is partly raped,
like all games always are,
and that is unfortunate,
but you can't throw the whole damn game
mode because it's partly rigged just
unless you think you can put in place a
game that isn't going to be rigged.
And good luck with that.
It's
here's very interesting interview
between Weinstein and bench purell on
the podcast.
What's so interesting is there from
completely opposite sides of the
spectrum.
I think it doesn't hurt to find himself
as a socialist.
Well,
he's certainly on the left.
Yeah,
I mean so,
but you have them discussed and it was
very,
very civil discourse and I think eric
can do a much better job than I can of
discussing the ways in which the issue
isn't that there is a dominance
hierarchy and the people differentiate
themselves based on their hard work.
The issue is sort of what we've seen
with the separation of the working
class.
You know,
he,
he points to a lot of trends about
what's happened with workers' wages.
You're a ceo a few seconds ago,
made three times the average worker.
Now it's a $300.
It's not about overall people doing well
if there's an increasing exponential
separation between,
you know,
working people and people who are at the
top and I think that's the skew that's
problematic and the fact of the matter
is rather than pushing away and you
know,
we could talk a little bit also about,
you know,
conservatives like Ben,
but rather than sort of denigrating it,
there's a lot of good brains on both
sides of the fence and like wouldn't it
be absolutely lovely if we have
reasonable conversations about what we
all want to do about that rather than
the physician having to be income
equality versus only self reliance and
play yourself up by your bootstraps
because there's some people who can't do
that.
There are some fundamental problems with
the system,
this leading to people having a lot
harder time and everyone agrees with
that.
And if we can talk about the details,
you know,
it's sort of like when we talk about
universal healthcare,
I feel like you come in the door and the
minute you say it,
people are for and against.
And for me,
there's a lot of other arguments to
make.
It's like,
look,
we already have universal healthcare in
this country.
It's called emergency rooms.
It's UNAMERICAN and wrong to let people
die on the streets.
We don't do that.
But if people are uninsured,
the hospital passes on the costs of
insurance companies who raise our
premiums.
So the average cost of an emergency room
visit in the United States is 1000,
$233.
The average cost of a vaccination is
$19.
We're all paying for it anyways.
And there's also a lot less risk of
public health hazards and other things.
If we can figure out a way to come up
with a medical system that people are
getting the care that they want.
Preventive care is infinitely cheaper
than trying to play catch up in
emergency rooms.
And if you don't just walk in the door
and say,
I'm for universal healthcare,
I'm opposed to universal healthcare
because a lot of say,
look,
I was out of work and having a hard time
and I had to feed.
You are paying my own healthcare.
We have to frame it in a way of saying
this is good for the robustness of the
whole community and I think there's a
lot of arguments and discussions are
from both sides that we need.
We need all those brains pulling
together and it's one of the things is
I'm watching a lot of new stuff.
I would love to see increasingly
increasing conversations like the one
that Eric and Ben had where their stupid
from the opposite side who are engaging
very reasonably and seeing each other's
points and trying to figure out what
skills they can bring from the
respective sides of the proverbial
aisle.
So you see,
you think you see within the Democratic
Party in an attempt at least to increase
the resolution of the discussion and to
move away from the more polarizing
discourse you see that
starting to develop.
Absolutely.
So tell,
tell me some of those concrete things
you've seen.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
I've been meeting with a lot of
candidates.
I found there there's a candidate who I
really liked called Joseph Kopser is
running in tax this who's a 20 year in
armies ranger,
I believe he is a bronze star.
He's a graduate of Harvard.
Kennedy school is a professor at West
Point and what was amazing with him is
like he was talking about universal
healthcare.
He started his own business,
a private business that led to tons of
jobs and he's just incredible person and
he made an argument in a way I haven't
ever thought about it.
He's talking about healthcare.
He was like,
look,
I have my healthcare from the army for
life.
That allowed me to take a risk and go
out entrepreneurially to start a company
that then led to tons and tons of time.
Yeah.
You know,
there's evidence in Canada.
Our rate of entrepreneurial development
in Canada per capita,
it's actually slightly higher than it is
in the US and analysis has indicated
that one of the reasons for that is the
provision of universal health care.
People can take entrepreneurial risks in
Canada without losing their,
their fundamental safety net.
So you can make a conservative argument
for the provision of a certain level of,
of underlying security,
let's say
it was.
It was a great argument for me.
I mean the other thing is I'm seeing a
lot of candidates who are Democrats who
were very upfront with their support for
the second amendment and it's like,
look,
the second amendment is an amendment.
You can't just get rid of an amendment.
And I know that as a classical liberal,
when people come after freedom of
speech,
I get really pissed.
Right?
And people who were,
who were,
who were living in different regions in
different states that have different
cultures.
When they hear people start to attack
the second amendment or or when it's
global,
where it's all or nothing.
If there is an inherent threat that
comes with.
And a lot of it for me is to look at and
go,
look,
every amendment has certain limitations
on us.
Right?
So you can't stand up on an airplane and
scream that you have a ball.
You can't threaten the president.
United States that you're going to kill
him.
The first amendment.
We have parameters around it.
We already have them in place around the
second amendment.
Everybody knows you can't own a bazooka.
Everyone knows you can't own a dirty
bomb.
So instead of coming in and sort of
frightened people in their way of life,
if they handguns,
if they're hunting,
if they are weapons collectors,
if we can boil the resolution down to
say we're already having every amendment
we have or the first and second
amendment,
we have certain limitations that we've
placed on it for the community.
So how about if we just talk about
violent history checks,
let's just talk about that one piece.
So 90 percent of Americans are in favor
of that in 73 percent of the NRA.
And so to have a candidate stand up and
say,
you know,
I love the First Amendment,
I fully support the second amendment.
Believe me,
I've a lot of friends.
Your Army Rangers,
Green Berets and seals.
I know that cultural wealth and rather
than having some sort of frontal attack
on it to sort of say,
well,
what's reasonable if you can't yell fire
in a crowded theater?
How about if we only discussed that and
I'm standing with 90 percent of
Americans in 73 percent of NRA members?
It's a much more respectful conversation
and it's a much more solution based.
Also a humble,
humble or
appreciation because it it,
it requires a certain amount of
appreciation for incremental change,
right?
You will very ego inflating to do a
great thing to make a massive change and
much less so to work in the background
to make a small change,
but small changes are solid and they
tend not to produce terrible negative
consequences and to and to work
incrementally is to work realistically
and properly.
And I would also say meaningfully and,
and that that's another,
that's another element that needs to be
introduced back into the discourse is
like,
well,
why don't we,
you know,
the people who established the American
American system where incrementalists
fundamentally and they knew perfectly
well that we had a flawed system that
was always going to be flawed in the
best we could do is tinker away out
incrementally.
And that's a really lovely sentiment.
I think it's very,
it's very mature and wise to understand
that what you're working on,
it's like a highway.
It always needs repair.
There's always going to be construction
on it.
There's always going to be blockages on
it because it needs to be maintained and
updated.
But you don't,
you don't,
you don't scrap the whole thing with
every move.
And part of the problem with the
discourse now too is that every issue
becomes code for an ideological
position.
Like I have a real hard time with,
um,
all the environmentalist noise that I
hear on mainstream media in particular
because I always see it as code for a
very fundamental anticapitalist ethos.
And so I can't separate the wheat from
the chaff mean I know because I've read
a lot about ecological issues that there
are foolish things that people are doing
in the world for a variety of reasons.
Like overfishing is a real catastrophe.
And it was so as deep ocean trolley as
far as I'm concerned.
But when I read general environmentalist
claims,
and these include climate change claims,
I can't separate it from a fundamental
anticapitalist ethos.
And so I can't decide,
I can never decide whether I can trust
the
underlined to that man is bad in New
Jersey,
right?
That's not a rallying cry to say,
let me pitch original sin to you just to
say what are short term effective gains
that can be made in additional middle
and longterm in business for clean
rivers and clean oceans and for fishing
industries.
Um,
and also to talk about the things we've
accomplished.
I mean,
we closed the ozone hole and companies
did business.
There are actually solutions.
Um,
you know,
we've,
we've basically eliminated polio from
the face of the earth.
There's entrepreneurial and innovative
solutions for things that can also be
pro business.
We've reforested northern hemisphere,
you know,
there's more forest in the northern
hemisphere then there was 100 years ago.
So you said this thing about,
about incremental change.
And that's another thing I've been
thinking about a lot,
which is when we walk in the door and
say,
I'm for gun control,
or I'm prolife in,
in,
in every circumstance,
or,
um,
you know,
to come in with an absolute position.
I'm one of the things that's really
tricky is if you're not willing to have
a conversation,
if you're not willing to see grounds,
there was no terms under which you feel
that the,
the negotiation or compromise can be
satisfied and that gets really
dangerous.
And it's funny because it's something
that I always advocate for when people
talk about sort of a broad sweeping
systemic problem or justice.
The problem is it doesn't boil it down.
A level of resolution that you can get
traction from all the people that you
need because people feel like,
well,
what's the solution?
The solution is to throw everything away
positive and negative and change
everything.
They're not going to do it.
And it's a problem.
We solve the occupy Wall Street.
Um,
and you know,
it sort of spread from generalized
corruption.
And incidentally they were targeting
sort of the banks and the bigger systems
almost more than they were the
government who was allowing a lot of it.
But then as it kept rolling in issue
after issue after issue,
it starts to get very complex.
I'm like,
well,
if we can see it and make changes,
are there any terms under which you will
be satisfied?
And I think that's,
uh,
that's one of the aspects of coming in
on positions of like for Oregon to
universal health care for or against the
second amendment.
There's no ground to be had there
because everyone's is digging in their
heels and I feel like it's also a bit of
a product of a social media and the fact
that we've all been sort of infants
allies,
just sort of these lights and dobutamine
hits that keep driving virtue signaling
and that goes for both sides.
So it goes for both sides.
If you can get a real slam or digging on
your opponent,
the good for you.
And meanwhile,
in the middle there's a ton of
Americans.
There's a ton of kids,
uh,
in education systems that need real
solutions.
And it doesn't matter how much we're
signaling what our beliefs are in our
respective balls.
It doesn't come down to a real solution.
It's also much more difficult to
generate real solutions because it means
you actually have to have some domain
knowledge.
And it isn't obvious,
for example,
that the classic forms of media that
politicians have used to interact with
the populace have rewarded high
resolution knowledge know because it
becomes,
well it's easy for it to get tangled up
in the details for that kind of
discussion to get tangled up in the
details.
But these longer form conversations
might allow people to unpack some of
that in a more intelligent way.
Well,
there's a great discussion between Dave
and Ben Shapiro at one point talking
about abortion and they're on opposite
sides of it.
And what was really interesting was it
was civil and there was no denigration
of the opposing side.
Also we're saying,
look,
I don't have an exact answer of when for
me it becomes uncomfortable.
Like there is some point that did.
It moves from something that is into a
point that he's not comfortable with
abortion.
There's a certain date that that would
happen or certain point in trimesters.
And so it's,
it's.
And it's,
it's hard.
There aren't super clear and easy
answers.
And you know,
ben has a different position.
Obviously he's much more conservative on
that front,
but that's a position.
It's weird.
I have a lot of friends who were born
again,
Christians and it's like,
that's a physician.
You can't just dismiss,
like you have to talk about it like that
to human position for people who have
not belief.
I mean,
so for me,
what it really comes down to when
there's sort of different positions on
stuff that's really fundamental for
people is to say,
look,
I don't,
we,
I feel like Democrats have to talk about
it.
We use it or more humanizing,
which is,
I don't actually know what I would do in
that circumstance if my wife,
um,
you know,
was,
was pregnant or girlfriend,
uh,
like it's a really hard choice.
It's not something that just flippant of
like,
oh,
it's a cluster of cells and it carries
no emotional waves.
That's,
I just don't find that to be true.
But for me there's a certain point where
it's like,
that's ever true for anyone who has an
experience like that.
Right?
And I,
I feel right way to approach it the.
Well,
I think that the answer is like,
look,
I don't know what I would do.
I don't claim to have all the answers
morally.
The one thing that I believe is I don't
want the government coming into your
house and into your bedroom and telling
your life or you want to do like.
That's something I feel like it's so
deeply personal and sometimes all you
have are shitty choices and choices that
aren't good.
And the flip side for me is I don't know
what the alternative is when we're
really talking with specifics.
I don't know,
a government mandated pregnancy looks
like.
So if a daughter or a niece who's 18 is
pregnant and doesn't want to have a
child,
I don't know what the solution is to
that.
Like how does the government then
mandate that and oversee that.
And so these are conversations that,
that,
you know,
I think are legitimate conversations to
be had,
but,
but from a position of respect rather
than,
you know,
sort of slogans or the fact that the
people who are prolife or anti anti
women,
because there's a lot of women who I
know who,
who have,
you know,
deeply held prolife positions,
I think it has to be a bit of a
conversation for me.
I feel like these are really personal
choices.
I have a strong libertarian reaction to
it and I also don't understand what the
solution is going to be.
If that does become something that
somebody doesn't want to have a child,
I don't understand how the government
mandates that and what that looks like
for those nine months.
And so,
you know,
it's not an approach that is dismissive,
that's all or nothing.
It's an approach of having a
conversation about,
you know,
different values and we have different
values and we have to figure out how to,
how to talk about them in ways that
aren't dehumanizing.
So what do you think,
what's a good plan for the next few
months?
What do you,
what are you going to try to do?
Well,
I have a number of plans.
I mean,
one of them is to keep Democrats focus
on nuts and bolts issues.
I also really,
um,
there's a lot of republican voices that
I think are really important.
I really liked Evan Mcmullin.
I really liked where Wilson,
there's a number of commentators who
would been been really interesting and
compelling.
I listened to the broad spectrum of
everything.
I wake up every morning and also read
the drudge report and watch Fox News to
have an understanding of,
of what opposing narratives are so that
I can understand the full sort of
spectrum and what's bothering people,
what is it,
and my finger
Shapiro's a really good voice as far as
I'm concerned because he's as
intelligent and articulator of the
social conservative position as you
could hope for.
And so he's a great whetstone against
which Democrats could sharpen their
knives were taken.
If they can confront him in a reasonable
argument successfully,
then they've already got the argument
down.
Because.
And here's the thing with Ben.
He's got a great brain.
I actually would like it if he was
playing less defense and actually we
could be engaged the way that eric has
to be like,
look,
what is your,
what are your solutions and thoughts on
this from.
There are some things he said that I
deeply disagree with.
Like I don't believe that all trans
people are mentally ill.
He has some physicians,
but nothing that I've seen indicates to
me that he's someone who can conceivably
be reason with.
He's also pointed out in places where he
believes he's screwed up.
He's written a whole articles about
reversing his position on things or
stuff.
He said that was dom and well,
that's,
that's his words,
not mine,
but um,
you know,
it's like the Ralph Waldo Emerson,
foolish,
foolish consistency is the Hobgoblin of
little minds.
It's like how many of us have a
completely consistent set of ideas and
so I feel like with them,
and there was that big issue were marked
plus came out and sort of said,
well why don't we listen to him?
And there was a big uproar and then he
apologized.
And I think that's an interesting thing
to discuss because from my perspective,
your three views,
if you're liberal adventure,
one is that he's an alt right mouse,
which I don't believe.
I don't believe that he's so far.
All right.
I should say fascists.
Nazis.
Yeah.
And that's.
We need to define what the hell the alt
right is to,
you know,
the old right is basically a cover story
for white supremacy and for an f new
nationalist state and to target
everybody who's conservative as an
outright figure,
which is something that's happened to me
repeatedly,
is absolutely counterproductive because
our lectures on your opposition at all,
right?
I mean it's very easily disprovable.
But with Ben,
like let's for the sake of argument that
got to here,
which I don't believe,
why would you not want to pay attention
or follow him or keep an eye on him or.
No,
what he's saying,
it's not like he's some crack pot,
you know,
he's someone who's very influential and
has a lot of followers.
So even if it's the case,
which I believe it is,
I don't understand how not paying any
attention to what's going on with him.
It's helpful.
Um,
you know,
I,
I gotta say one of the highlights,
I think apple and facebook and spotify
and so forth just made with Alex Jones,
you know,
because they think they banned Alex
Jones.
But that isn't what happened.
What happened was they pushed his
millions of followers underground.
That was a very bad idea
and they're making a murder out of him.
Justifying know he's a little on the
paranoid side,
let's say is a real conspiracy
theorists.
And the best,
the worst thing you can possibly do to
someone who's paranoid is to generate a
conspiracy to take them out.
Well,
it is the best thing you can do.
When Alex Jones has said virtually
nothing that I agree with on any front
is to give him as much air time and as
much rope as possible
or at least allowing access to that in
the same way that everyone else has
access to it.
You know,
because a guy,
I don't watch Alex Jones,
but there are a number of people on the
right that I keep an eye on or the
farther right because I want to see what
they're up to and as soon as that
becomes impossible,
then you have no idea what those people
are up to and how the hell are you
supposed to be able to deal with it if
you can't figure out what it is.
Well worked for not watching it.
Like I'm a big fan.
I like I'm,
I'm a big fan of the aspect of the ECLU
was the Skokie,
which was we show up if Nazis want to
march right.
And we will protect their right to
peacefully march and it's like I have
people who I despise.
It's like get out there and appoint will
be crushed by the free marketplace of
ideas I have not believed,
but you have to allow for it.
And the more that we murder and shut
down.
Yeah.
You don't know how many people were
watching Alex Jones to keep an eye on.
Right?
You know,
I don't imagine it was a tremendous
number of people,
but it wasn't none.
Bryce,
Bryce will love you and I have talked
about this.
One of the highlights of my
undergraduate years,
um,
was when the bell curve came out and
there was a debate at the Kennedy Center
and Dick Herrnstein,
who I had as a professor had passed away
and Charles Murray was sort of left to
defend it against Stephen Jay Gould.
And it was a very high level of
discourse.
And Henry Louis Gates gave the
introduction.
Things were very,
very heated on campus because of their
claims about racial differences in Iq.
It was a very flashpoint issue.
And skip gates gave a spectacular
introduction and he said,
look,
there's a lot of sentiments roiling
around this issue and the best possible
thing that we can do is to dispute and
defend and dismissed the aspects of this
that aren't correct here openly and
publicly.
And there was a big debate.
A lot of the student groups stood up and
walked out after that,
intrigued from,
of the amazing intellectual minds,
uh,
of,
you know,
in the country.
And so I just went down and sat in the
front row because people that hit it
piled out,
it's like I wanted to hear the debate,
I want to hear the size from,
from,
from all different arenas.
And it was totally,
totally captivating,
but his point was once someone's a crack
pot and they don't have any followers
and it's stupid,
racist,
bellowing things,
it's fine to ignore people.
There's a certain point where when it's
Dick Herrnstein and Charles Murray,
there's a point where that needs to be
debated publicly and openly.
And the fact that the chair of the
African American Studies Department was
advocating for that to me,
I thought was really important and
should be heated.
That we need these things,
these debates to be had and the aspects
that are incorrect me to be for a in
enlightenment way in a very intense and
pollock.
And so that's something that I've always
sort of held to is I don't,
you know,
look,
I mean there's also part of this about
sort of a toughness argument.
My grandfather went down during the
civil rights movement.
He was a Jewish lawyer from Manhattan
and went down to the deep south to stick
up for,
uh,
to represent African Americans who've
been convicted of crimes against white
women.
There's one case in particular that was
totally ridiculous and he went down and
people tried to run his car off a cliff
and kill him.
And so part of it for me too is like I'm
from La Mindset of light,
tough liberals who want to,
who actually can stand up.
We need,
we need people to be toughened on all
sides of discourse.
And I feel like,
you know,
when people were burning copies of
ulysses,
I feel like we're supposed to be the
ones with the fire hose is putting out
the fires were supposed to be the ones
who can be really tough and standard
ground.
And if we can't do that,
if we're gonna duck from those fights
and that hardening of,
uh,
of,
sort of intense positive,
I'm really tough version of,
of what the points are that we're
arguing,
then it's not,
it's not a legitimate case.
We need to be.
That's what we need.
It's a tough time and we need tough
discourse.
Yeah,
well that and that is exactly why you
should seek out the most articulate
exponents of your have your opponent's
position.
You know,
I just had that experience talking with
Sam Harris and we talked for 10 hours
and you know there are things we agree
about.
One of the most fundamental things is
that both Sam and I are concerned that
our ethical structures,
it would be better if our ethical
structures were grounded in something
that was self evidently solid and so he
wants to do that.
He wants to ground ethics in the realm
of fact and I can.
I can understand that it's.
It's a perfectly valid desire.
I don't believe it's possible in the way
that he sees it as possible and we
talked about that a lot,
but I learned a tremendous amount as a
consequence of discussing things with
him over a 10 hour period because he
pushed me.
You need to be pushed,
man,
because all the kinds of holes and you
need to go in understanding that you
might not have all the answers
well,
but you don't have all the answers.
What I think is interesting is your
approach to that is to ground things in
an evolutionary model,
which I think is a pretty good bedrock,
right?
I mean that's been your sort of approach
to this is to talk about like a sort of
archetypal and evolutionary underlay,
but Sam's unbelievably articulate and
sharp.
I mean,
I had the pleasure of having dinner with
you and him and Douglas Murray in London
and it's a vibrant,
respectful,
sometimes disagreeable mode of
conversation that's incredibly fruitful.
It's also stressful as hell,
you know,
because you can definitely get put on
the spot and have your cherished
assumptions undermined as well as look
like a fool because you know,
some of the time,
even if you have an argument,
well thought through in that kind of
discourse,
you don't have it immediately at hand.
You forget about it.
And then it appear as if you're a fool.
And so you put a lot on the line and the
discussion like that,
but
no one's paying attention to any of this
for you to.
Right.
So,
so.
Well.
So one quick thing before we move on
with this.
So there's a lot of proposals that are
there that are floated.
Let's say there's an economic idea that
somebody has in that wants to be passed
on.
The first thing that I do with it is I
send it to.
I have a friend who's a really sharp
libertarian.
I have a friend who's a hardcore kind of
Wall Street Republican and I have
another friend who's kind of a big money
person.
So they represent sort of the different
poles of economic policy from the things
that some of the policies that might be
interesting to me.
The first thing they do is send it to
all of them and go poke as many holes in
this as you possibly can and tell me
what all blind spots.
And that's not only for me to cover all
those arguments.
It's also for me to be able to learn and
see if there's a better approach to it.
If it's fundamentally flawed,
and then certainly if I'm going to
advocate something that's a new policy,
I'm not strong on economics.
I mean it's probably my weakest spot,
but it's the sort of know if we're going
to advocate it,
what are all the pitfalls were falling
into and what are we potentially
missing?
And I find very few people are taking an
approach like this and there's one of
the things that I think is exciting.
It's funny with the idw has this sort
of,
um,
fear of an alt right overlay,
but the majority of guys skew pretty
liberal.
I mean,
if you look at Joe,
if you look at Dave's certainly,
um,
if you look at Eric and Brad,
I mean it's got more of a skew,
but what's nice is ideas can be parsed
in a way where as much as it is
embarrassing when you're put on the spot
and you're wrong,
no one's looking at twists the knife.
You know what I mean?
Everyone's kind of saying,
yeah,
I disagree with this.
[inaudible] disagree.
Have a tie disagreeableness,
but it's recycled.
Well,
it's
also based,
at least to some degree on trust.
You know,
if I can assume that you're different
than me,
temperamentally,
but that you're actually striving
towards the truth and we can have a
discussion and I certainly feel that
with Sam.
Yes.
I believe that.
I believe.
I believe that he's an honest person and
you know,
or I believe that he's dishonest as me,
let's say,
which is more to the point because well
maybe an honest person is too high a
barrier for anyone to actually achieve
given all of our faults,
but I don't believe there's any evidence
that he's striving with less intensity
towards the truth than I am.
The furthest right in the group is
clearly bad.
You know,
when to get back to that point.
It's like there's sort of three
approaches is a horrible human and he's
a hardcore old writer,
in which case if you believe that why
from a Sun Tzu perspective,
art of war,
would you not want to know your enemy
and figure it out?
Or He's somebody who has views and
ideologies.
I disagreed with him on a,
on a,
on a number of fronts,
but he's somebody who is it who is
interested in the truth and is willing
to admit when he has gone too far or not
gone too far.
That's the wrong phrase.
He's willing to admit mistakes that he
perceives that he's nate and is also
taking new information and it's like I'd
love to actually have a discussion with
him about something,
a discussion,
not a debate because he's a world class
innovator.
He would probably biliterate me but,
but an actual meaningful discussion
about some of the stuff where I see
there to be differences.
He's,
I think he might be in for that.
Like you and I have discussed the
possibility of finding high resolution
intelligent centrist Democrats and
getting some of these idw people to
interact with them.
So,
you know,
that looks like it's a real possibility
and be interesting to see what that
would do to the political discourse.
And I guess this is a step on that step
in that direction.
I talked to Bandon,
to Dave Rubin and to show our,
or to um,
to Sam and uh,
you know,
hypothetically there,
there are at least willing to look into
this as a possibility and it would be
very interesting as well.
Oh,
well,
it would also be very interesting to see
how this would play out with regards to
log form discourse because we need to
find politicians.
You know,
one of the things Joe told me when I was
talking to him,
Joe,
Joe Rogan,
when I was talking to him about his
three hour interviews,
I said,
well,
does that ever not work out for people?
And he says,
well yeah,
I've had guests on who just run out of
steam in about 45 minutes.
They don't have anything else to say.
And we don't need politicians who run
out of steam at 45 minutes.
We need people who can engage in intense
discussion for three hours without
running out of detail,
without running out of ideas,
a detailed grasp of the political realm.
And we need to be able to see that.
So we could move away from these six
minute CNN interviews and
yeah,
it's moving away from the tweets and the
nonsense,
which to my mind is inherently
polarizing.
It's like,
look at what this asshole hardcore lefty
get on a college campus or look at this
most egregious example of something over
here and I'm not saying those things
aren't important or that we don't have
to pay attention to them,
but the vast majority of people in
America right now me real nuts and bolts
solutions and corruption.
Maybe
there's a technological rule here,
so imagine that this is like we could
call this the Peterson principle.
Let's say the narrower the bandwidth,
the more likely polarized information
will be delivered over it.
I think it's great,
but I think we should call it the
principal.
You'll have to come up with a more
elegant formulation,
but it seems to me that that's highly
probable because if you have to compress
complex information into a very narrow
channel and and broadcast tv would would
certainly qualify.
And twitter of course even worse is that
you have to.
You have to radically oversimplify it,
right?
Because like I said,
I a lot of friends,
I mean across the gamut of political
orientations,
I read a lot of news and follow a lot of
people across the political orientation
all the way left to right or right or
very far left,
but I'm talking about within a
reasonable poles and it's,
it's just,
it's amazing to me how skewed it is.
If you turn on MSNBC and Fox News,
we're in two different worlds.
If you read the Huffington post and
drudge report and so it's very easy to
get.
Like I think I have more of awareness of
what the triggers are for conservatives
and what the triggers are for liberals,
but also the fact that these triggers
are getting this outsize era time
constantly.
Bio is condensed means of information
and I think that's where like the IB
dealt with you like there.
There's way more listeners to.
You guys didn't make any fucking sense
like the fact that you had 10,
two and a half hour lectures from the
psychological underpinnings of the Bible
and that more than two people watch.
That makes no sense.
And so there's a ton of people who are
really curious for more in depth
analysis is being met elsewhere and I
think that's where the polls have been
missing.
I think that that proverbial proverbial
lead a group of people who are,
who are being missed and you aren't
being discounted.
Yeah.
And
you know it's,
it's really important that we have the
more in depth conversations about it.
So that's our little conspiracy plant,
so to speak then is to take this to,
to,
to inquire if the people who've been
loosely grouped together as the idw are
willing to engage in serious discourse
with to begin with,
with centrist Democrats.
Doesn't have to be limited to that,
but I think that's a nice counter play
to.
For me,
it can even be Democrats who aren't
centrist or tilting even left of that,
who are willing to engage in civil
discourse and might even have like
different districts and states have
different notions and it might really
make sense for an aspect of the party of
further lab to test something in San
Francisco or New York and see what new
ideas come out of this.
Right?
It's just for me,
it can't be with moral condescension and
it can't be a purity tests,
you know,
you and I've talked so much about how
the left and the right get off track in
different ways.
The right gets very fascist.
You see them coming and it's,
it's,
you know,
fascistic overlay.
We know what that is.
Historically,
it's,
we'll go heavily towards voter
suppression.
There's a lot of issues that are very
highly problematic on that side of the
fence and when it gets so ethnocentric.
Exactly.
Or your sense,
right?
Yep.
Yeah.
And you know,
or,
or you know,
illegal or hardcore power grounding in a
way that's effective,
let's say.
And with the left,
the left,
you know,
cannibalizes and its purity tests and it
goes kind of crazy that way.
I think that we are seeing from the
Democrats now and awareness that the
real solutions need to be offered again.
Anticorruption is a huge thing that I'm
seeing Democrats start to tackle in a
very serious way.
Healthcare jobs,
education.
And it's really important that these
things get brought out.
And so for me,
it's like we can test things that are
further or further left and see it work
or don't work,
but we also need to do that from a
position that isn't morally
condescending and a position that's also
appreciative of different cultures and
different places around the country.
What's going to work in up in New York
isn't going to work in Alabama and
liberals are so good at.
I think it understanding and
appreciating other cultures,
you know,
like it's one of the things that is sort
of a trademark.
But it's interesting to me that,
that I think we have fallen down on our
understanding of different cultures
within the United States.
And so it's this very interesting
divide.
But like if it's foreign or perceived as
exotic,
it's all good.
But like we need a better understanding
of certain cultures.
Also.
Um,
you know,
Alabama,
Texas,
certainly as guilty of this too.
I mean the right treats.
Chicago is if it's some like horrible,
you know,
no man's land.
I'm not saying this is a problem,
only your belief.
But I'm saying we could really benefit
with conversations and talking to a lot
of candidates in Oklahoma,
in Orange County,
in Texas who have an understanding of
their constituents and what they want to
do is help them and to present a
reasonable alternative solutions to them
about real issues and not the bullshit
that everybody is engaging.
It's absolutely essential.
And if we,
if we offer all that and lose,
then tough luck.
We've got to make a better case.
We've got to make a better argument.
Like we screwed up.
We got to try harder and that way.
The other thing,
Jordan,
that's really heartening.
I'm seeing a lot of the actual
candidates as opposed to the noise,
is more and more of an emphasis on
personal accountability.
You know,
it's,
it's about helping people and creating
new opportunities for them economically,
but in a way that empowers them with the
freedom to sort of make their life or
make their mark if that's a freedom that
they can see.
It's about sort of trying to level a
baseline.
Like we talked about how healthcare can
be super helpful for business and for
entrepreneurial ventures.
We talked about why it's essential for
the robustness of communities,
but it's about setting the terms under
which people can be free to make choices
and to perform at a level that they want
to to build their whole future.
So it's not that it's a shift from sort
of us running ahead and and blocks for
people to us trying to lift the
constraint so that people can have
better choices for their,
for their families,
for their kids and their education
system for their own work so that they
can do better and make their own mark
and because a lot of what we're standing
on,
a lot of the successes that we're
standing on as a country are on the
shoulders of working men and women.
That's a lot of what's accounted for.
The things that we've done well and in
fact a lot of the world,
frankly.
A lot of the world is benefited
enormously from the working people in
United States.
You know,
in a way that I don't think gets nearly
enough recognition.
And so we
see the,
the accruing financial success of the
poor around the world.
Which is happening at a very rapid rate
is in part a consequence of the
sacrifice is made either willingly or
unwillingly by the American working
class over the last 30 years.
Absolutely.
Working class,
that's it.
It's competition with the world has been
opened up at the level of the working
class first and that's been unbelievably
beneficial to the rest of the world and
probably a pretty good medium to
longterm strategy because
the American working class,
it's like they have been built after the
winds for people around the globe,
like their heroes.
There's no,
there's no infantilizing of them in a
way that's derogatory and it's like it's
our job to make sure that they can have
choices for their future,
that they.
That they are free to compete,
at least with the same rules that
everybody else competes to differentiate
themselves because they've always kicked
mentioned.
It's an amazing,
amazing workforce and they've always
done well and it's like if people are
complaining about,
you know,
entitlements,
it's like we can also what your
corporate subsidies.
It's like it's not about one or the
other.
It's about the same rules that people
need to differentiate themselves and
it's about creating more freedom for
them to reach their accomplishments.
It seems to me that the Democrats would
have a lot more success and and and also
be able to generate a counter narrative
to the radicals on the left if they made
the assumption that there's all sorts of
good things about free market
capitalism,
but crony capitalism is not one of them
now and that's part of your emphasis on,
let's call it a regulation of
corruption,
so the free enterprise system works real
well except when it gets warped and
twisted and so we have to remove the
warping and twisting so that people do
have the opportunity to compete and to
cooperate as freely as possible and
that's in everyone's interests,
including radical capitalists because to
the degree that the system is corrupt
and that reflects badly on the system
and produces a tremendous amount of
opposition towards it.
If you can't win fairly,
what are you doing in the game?
Like it's to me,
it's a very tough argument.
That's like if you can't sign a pledge,
which,
which has been put forth,
it's called the disclose act.
There's a number of variations of it.
It's no dark money,
you know,
it's a strong stance against
interference by hostile actors.
It's no voter suppression.
It's getting universal healthcare,
universal voter registration.
There's a lot of stuff of like,
let's get everybody out voting,
let's lift the suppression and voter
intimidation,
and then when fair square and it's like,
for me it's like I want the right to
Wayne fairly and I want the right to
lose fairly if we make a better argument
than let's do it,
but you know,
it's also anti gerrymandering which is
really good and there's a lot of people
who vow to not participate in
gerrymandering and to also have it be
eager bipartisan committees or judges
who determine the boundaries.
It's really,
it's really quite an outrage that it's
not bipartisan committees.
It's ridiculous onto,
you know,
into a boxing ring and tell,
telling someone that we're going to
fight them,
but they can only step in certain areas
that you can go anywhere and they can
only hit you with the jab,
but you get to use your full battery
shots.
It's like man up,
right step into the arena if you think
you can wane and wind fair and square
and there's a.
there's a big emphasis,
I think it's not getting enough press
and Democrats cleaning up our side of
the aisle in a way that is accountable
and that is going to be clear and if
there's nobody who disagree with that,
I believe if you're a heart,
you're a republican and you want to,
when you should be aware that you can
win fairly and under the same rules and
that we can all agree on that.
Yup.
Well it would be nice if the Democrats
too could help everyone figuring out
figuring out what the problems actually
are.
Because right now mostly what we see in
the media is a discussion of pseudo
problems.
Exactly.
And so I'd like to see what,
what are the,
what are the real challenges that
confront us at the moment and what are
the proper solutions to those
challenges?
Yeah.
It's so funny because I feel like the,
the racial discourse,
a discourse around racism has gotten so
loaded and so complicated,
um,
since president trump has is run or has
taken office and it's,
I feel like all sides of the issue are,
there is nowhere you can stop without
being a landline.
And for me it's really important to boil
down to.
I went with a program called the five
that goes and runs an entrepreneurial
program in the prison system and it's
absolutely unbelievable how,
you know what I call the prison
industrial complex works,
the privatization of prisons.
And you can sidestep all the arguments
about who's doing what and who's
responsible.
African-Americans,
if you know who are up for drug charges,
the exact same drug charges as whites or
600 percent more likely to get like
that.
Just straight Scott.
That's not well,
they're doing more crime.
There's no argument to be had about that
there.
There are certain unbelievable biases of
how,
you know,
African Americans and people of color
are put into prison system,
which profits from them and which
they're doing a lot of work and
basically you know,
no wages.
It's very
problematic.
Anybody would agree with that across the
spectrum.
I think if you look at those numbers and
it's patently unfair if there's one
thing
we need to have an intelligent
discussion about drug policy that would
be a real scary,
the prison system and who exude towards
and the ways in which it is unfairly
implemented and that's a no shit major
crawl.
And if you,
if you discussed the actual hardcore
facts and if you could boil it down to
those things,
no one's going to disagree with that.
You know what Bjorn Lomborg did.
This is really interesting.
He's a,
he's a scandinavian.
You used to be an environmentalist.
He still is,
but he calls himself the skeptical
environmentalist now and I really liked
your Lumberg.
He wrote a great book called how to
spend $50,
million and then a few laters years
later,
75 billion to make the world a better
place.
A book,
I would highly recommend it.
This is what he did and this is really
nice procedural,
um,
achievement.
He looked at the UN.
I hope I got the story right.
It's a while since I,
since I read it over,
the UN puts out a lot of development
goals.
Say like,
I think they have 150 development goals,
something like that.
And that's too many goals.
You can't do 150 things.
And I worked on a UN committee for
awhile and we were trying to prioritize
the goals because you'd have to
prioritize things in order to accomplish
them.
And one of the things we discovered was
that you couldn't prioritize the goals
because every goal had its constituents
and they were outraged if any other goal
was prioritized over there.
And that was a terrible thing because,
well that's the tragedy of the Commons
because the goal is couldn't be
prioritized and they couldn't be.
They couldn't be accomplished
essentially.
So lumberg figured out a way around
this.
So his idea was this,
okay.
So there's a bunch of things that need
to be done because there's a bunch of
problems out there in the world and but
there's too many to simultaneously
address.
So we have to figure out where we're
going to start.
So what we're going to do is a cost
benefit analysis.
So we're going to concentrate on doing
as much good for the least amount of
money as we can.
Now it's going to be our initial
strategy because why not right?
Because money is a scarce resource and
it involves human labor and human
intelligence and all of that and so you
don't want to waste it.
But he didn't believe that he would be
capable of doing the prioritization.
So what he did was get 10 teams of
economists together,
some of which were headed by world class
economist.
People have won Nobel Prize and he had
them organized teams and then he had
them go through the development goals
and prioritize them and make an economic
case.
And so then you had 10 separate cases
and heres the rule.
You've got $50,
million dollars.
You can spend it on whatever you want,
but you have to justify it in terms of
cost benefit analysis,
Naf to choose from this list,
and so then he got each economist to
generate a list of their priorities.
Then he averaged across the lists and
came up with a final list of have both
problems,
which is a big deal,
right?
Because the first issue is what are the
problems that we need to solve?
Like you know,
you might think,
well,
what politicians should be generating
his answers.
It's like,
no,
that's not right.
If you're trying to solve a complex
problem,
instead of the complex problems,
the first thing you want to do is
formulate the problems property and then
you work towards towards defining what
the solutions might be.
So be really interesting to see if we
could have an intelligent political
conversation that would concentrate on,
on defining what the actual problems are
and it's not capitalism versus
socialism.
That's not a problem.
That's awesome.
Everyone gets to scream at each other
and then the superior and get it
immersed and getting retweets
without having to know anything about
anything.
Right,
and there's no actual motivation towards
trying to come up with solutions to the
vast majority of people who have,
who are dealing with real problems and
that's the part that pisses me off is
it's like it's this masturbatory venture
of discussing the overall culture and
you know,
if you turn on the news,
it's these little sound bites of the
most,
you know,
sort of tabloid nature of the furthest
extreme sense versus nuts and bolts
discussions of what actually makes
sense.
Okay.
So what we need to do,
let's say generally speaking,
is we've got to figure out what the
problem started.
Like what,
what are the,
what are the most serious problems that
currently confront us as a society.
That would be a nice start.
Like what are the 15 most most crucial
problems that confront us as we move
farther into the 21st century?
That's a hard.
That's a hard question and then I'm a
go.
No,
go ahead.
Well,
I mean the first thing for me,
looking at the system as political
corruption and I'm not eating that,
it,
it either party.
I mean,
I have my opinions about which party
does that more but neither one is
perfect and the average rating of
Congress right now is 15 percent.
I'm sorry,
18 percent is the providing of Congress,
which is better or works as a slightly
about syphilis.
It Ain't good and if you don't believe
that the people in government are
serving your needs and are are instead,
you know more interested in furthering
the big money donors over the interests
of people which has proven time and time
again.
That's a huge problem with trust is
eroded that the people representing you
are representing rich donors rather than
average Americans didn't seem to your
needs.
You can't get anywhere.
And I think that's part of what's
important and all those flags that
allowed Democrats are working on.
It's not.
It's a pledge to say here's what we,
here's what we will disclose and here's
ways that we will clean up our side of
the island.
And I think if it's essential,
it's essential that you start with your
own reflection of fixing the things that
you need to fix in order to make a
better argument.
For me,
corruption and governments and top of
this year.
But go ahead.
I was thinking more of a procedurally
no,
not so much in terms of what the
problems might be.
I mean,
one of the problems I see emerging,
well one of them would be this increase
in political polarization,
which I think is very,
very dangerous.
I think another potential problem on the
horizon is something like as our society
becomes more cognitively complex,
which is happening very,
very rapidly,
the of people,
the proportion of people who are likely
to be dispossessed as a consequence of,
um,
of,
of lesser ability to deal with that kind
of complexity,
that problem is going to increase.
And that's across the board and it isn't
obvious what to do about that.
I don't really buy guaranteed basic
income solutions in part because I don't
think that money is actually the
solution to the problem of what to do in
life.
Like money can stave off,
right?
In some ways it's the opposite.
If you lose a goal that you're striving
for,
that makes life tough.
Over conversation that I think should be
around table with Democrats and
Conservatives and Republicans to say
what's a furrow capitalist argument for
how we're going to train people and
bring them along.
Right?
What's,
what's uh,
what's,
uh,
you know,
a liberal argument for having concern
for people who don't have the same
advantages from the same background.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
the silicon valley types,
they tend to skew pretty heavily liberal
and that's because they're generally
creative and entrepreneurial,
but they're very rapidly building a
world in which people who are at the
lower end of the cognitive distribution
are going to be adrift.
Right.
And we need to fix that from both sides.
So rather than saying all or nothing,
right,
like tough lot capitalism,
free market,
forget it or you know,
we need to support every single person
in every single way.
That has to be the subject of
complicated in depth conversations with
people weighing in from a variety of
different political views.
It just has to be in order.
It's so complicated.
It's so complicated that we need,
we need opinions and brains from all
sides of the issue.
That's for sure.
We definitely might also need different
test cases,
those tough conversations,
you know,
like between someone who leans very
liberal and someone like Ben Shapiro,
you can think about those as stress
tests,
your damn stupid solution,
which you've put a lot of effort into
elaborating,
let's say,
can't withstand the stress of a single
argument with someone who disagrees with
you.
What the hell do you.
What makes you think that's going to
work when you implemented it in the real
world?
Obviously it's going to fail merely
because those people are going to object
to it independent of its objective
merits and so if it can't fly with your
opponents.
I mean I'm not talking about the fringe
opponents because nothing flies with the
fringe except what the fringe beliefs,
but
also think that the French is overly
represented and that's what's so hard.
Like when mark duplass apologize for
saying people should follow Ben Shapiro,
right?
There was an apology he put forth.
I haven't worked with with with deep
loss.
I've heard he's a terrific guy and I
think that is seen with sort of a
furtherance of,
of,
of an ending of polarization and
discourse.
I don't know who,
who are all those people who were
personally deeply wounded by him saying
that you should just follow somebody
whether you agree with him or not,
and I also don't know who the apology is
geared towards like who is he
apologizing to and if we have sort of a
mob ditties I mean the one thing I say a
lot and this is a specialist from
Hollywood,
is there's a huge and widening gap
between conversations that people are
having in public and what they really
believe in the sign of a creeping
totalitarianism that's really,
really dangerous and it's also from both
sides.
I'm not just saying that this is a
liberal value.
I think there's a lot more people who
have more complicated views that they
don't feel safe to articulate it because
fear of complete reputation slammer
room,
right?
Don't we'll be out of work.
It will be everything else and so I
don't.
It's very interesting thing,
may have a lot of sympathy for people
who set out and say something and then
sort of retreat and apologize because I
feel like the force of a mod response
from the French,
even if it's sort of pluralistic
ignorance,
right?
I mean 90 percent of people might agree
with you,
but if the tanner allowed and it's all
that you're seeing everywhere,
it has the power to reality.
Yep.
That's on mind control.
Colts function.
You know,
mind control is one of the first things
they do.
If they can get you off through complex,
there's privacy and everywhere that you
look,
if there's two versions,
they try and split me.
I went undercover in a mind control
calls to research one of my calls and
when you're there,
everything that I say that is cult Greg,
they're splitting Colt Greg from Greg,
Greg and everything that I saved,
like wow,
this is fun.
It's Sorta love bombing.
Everyone leans in its direct eye
contact,
sort of nonsexual touching.
Everyone's engaged.
But if I say,
you know,
this is weird,
I kind of miss being in contact with
someone of their friends.
It's the sort of windshield that
everyone's,
and it's what I think is happening,
but from a smaller percentage of people
that are really,
really loud and if you see it all of a
sudden it seems to be the reality would
be our sort of apologies that I believe
when a lot of people make the apologies,
they read flat.
To me it doesn't feel heartfelt and also
like let's say you really did screw up,
like part of what we need to do is screw
up.
Pardon me?
Think about things and say things and
overstaffed and go,
wow,
that was kind of his girl.
You know?
Oh,
what's a blanket apology to society
versus the individual stuff to say,
hey,
I forwarded this position.
I wish I had articulated it better.
I don't always relate myself perfectly.
Probably what I should've said rather
than,
and so sorry to have had a thought that
is isn't appropriate and we're seeing
this across the board.
I think it's really being part of what
needs to be done and this is something
we already talked about,
is to,
is to generate better dialogue.
Yeah.
It isn't like that and hope that the
mere fact that it's a much higher
quality is sufficient to attract people
to it in a way from this other nonsense.
Yes.
It's hard because as you said,
the shorter the span.
Like I have people who that,
who knows that we're good friends,
you know our work is time to tangle up.
We mentioned each other and our books.
We've known each other shit since I was
20 years old and people will say,
well he believes in course minority like
dismissed it.
It'll be one thing and it's like it's an
anthropological term or sociological
term with specific meeting takes one
google search to sort of prove that it's
not that Jordan Peterson is running
around like a world war two propaganda
poster,
like dragging ribbon off into the caves
of giving them,
giving them to useless men.
Right.
I mean,
but it's so disprovable,
but it's also so damning on a format
like twitter where you have 280
characters and so it's that.
It's that reputation thing where like if
you associate with you,
you should never be discussed again.
If you should follow a bunch of pure,
whether you agree with him or not,
you'll be bombarded in shamed until you
apologize for even saying that.
You'll do that and it's like,
look,
I've learned the most from my friends
who disagree with me the most.
I have a wide range of friends.
It's so funny,
but one of the stories that I tell after
president trump was elected.
I was in Vegas on a book tour and one of
my friends was a crusty old farmer and
sniper from the SPEC ops community.
He passed away recently,
but he was just a great friend and a
great guy and I did a lot of shooting
with him for the books and then a lot of
research and he wanted me to see his
ranch and we pull up to his ranch and he
has a tank parked in his front yard and
sticking out of the.
Out of the end of it.
He's a trump pence sign.
So at that exact moment,
my wife sends me a text and it's her and
my daughter at like one of the thousand
women marches and they just come up on
Miley Cyrus,
so they're like my daughter's pose.
Even miley Cyrus and the tech sort of
comes in and my buddy looks at me.
He goes,
what's that?
And I looked up at him,
I said nothing.
But then I showed him and we had a good
laugh about it in sort of this way that
it's like you need people around to have
a whole variety of things.
And one thing that's interesting with
him was around the time of the Muslim
ban.
And I was talking to him a lot about
that.
And I,
I'm,
I'm personally very posts the Muslim ban
for instance.
But there's,
there's a lot of reasons if you talk to
people in the military,
there's a lot of problems recruiting
translators now.
Like that has a negative effect that
ripple through the intelligence
community.
It's not good.
And you know,
and whether I've friends who were
vehement advocates of this,
but I'm arguing with them saying what is
the actual ground truth of how that is
affecting things.
And then there's all the people in the
military who were like,
this has been a total shit show.
It's really hurting our intelligence
efforts and our allies.
I feel like that's the level of the
discussion.
Or one of the other things for me that's
very relevant is,
you know,
I don't know if you know this,
but there's 15,000
Muslim physicians from the seven banned
Muslim countries in America and they
predominantly work in,
in rural red state districts.
They're providing the majority of,
not the majority of the.
Providing a ton of medical care to a lot
of people in red states.
And by the way,
those are the people.
If they fled Aleppo,
they hate Bishar Hassan and extremism
like this is,
this is,
this is exactly the sorts of people who
you want to have in these areas.
And if they're pulled out,
we're going to have a lot of rural areas
that more affluent physicians are not
going to have access to medical care
because more affluent positions or
people from America don't always want to
go to these regions.
There's a lot of like bigger recruiting
a physician,
so you have with people who are,
who are great sort of citizens and
representatives who hate extremism,
who are treating people in different
states.
And it's like,
that's really important.
And you pair that with the Intel picture
that I think is deeply problematic and
you have a sort of argument that isn't
just,
you should have more empathy for Muslims
and which then just deteriorates into,
well they're terrorists and like it just
devolves rather looking at sort of the
temperament of the people who were here
and you have to have conversations with
people from all sides of the,
uh,
like I had a lot of conversations with
people in the military who support it or
against it to kind of start to zero in
on what my position is.
Okay.
So the plan is something like this.
So we'll,
we've recorded this video.
I'm going to post it as a public
invitation to the intellectual dark web.
I think that's what I'll title it or
subtitling idea would be to bring on
people democrats at least to begin with
because that would sort of run counter
to the idw reputation,
let's say Democrats who are capable and
we're capable of and willing to engage
in long form discussions about co
complex high resolution issues and to
provide a more,
at least in part a more centrist
alternative to the radical leftists,
but also to bring on people with more
left leaning views to have them a try
their arguments out in a more,
in a more fully fledged manner.
Something like that.
Yeah,
I mean how does anyone lives,
like if someone's conservative not
moving,
they should know what the reasonable
virgin isn't.
The argument they're rejecting like good
for you.
Then you know all that.
They're seeing his reports of like
students gone wild on college campuses
and the craziness that I believe I
believe is a problem.
I mean you've certainly,
you've dealt with protests and you've
dealt with that sort of like brutal
groupthink and anti first amendment.
You know,
like sort of shutting down speech,
it's always tricky to talk about freedom
of speech and first amendment because
it's unclear,
always wear that lapses in being legal
or constitutional versus just people
articulating things loudly,
but I have no question that that's a
problem,
but I think that there's.
I think that it is over represented an
amplified by the media and by both sides
of the media.
Yeah.
So to see her topic and I think we
should get people in who are willing to
have conversations that are solutioning
here so that if people realize that,
see,
for me,
part of what my interest is in sort of
trying to transcend politics and getting
to a place where like I don't care if
you're republican or Democrat as much.
I care if you're offering real
solutions.
Yes.
Right.
Exactly.
This would be to figure out what the
problems are,
to see if we can come to some sort of
consensus about where are the challenges
that confront us really lie.
Right.
And if there's a Democrat running for
office who is very dark money embedded
in bold the donors,
and there's somebody who's a,
a cleaner,
a choice,
who's running,
who's a Republican,
it's like,
let's have that house,
you know,
it's,
this is,
this is about actually spring to figure
out solutions for,
for,
for people in terms of the level of
discourse that we can happen to
solutions that need to be offered.
Because while we're here talking about
all this stuff,
there's a lot of people's dealing with a
lot of real life problems.
I've started to introduce you to a
number of people.
You've met Sam and you met Dave Rubin.
Um,
you met Douglas Murray.
Briefly.
Who else?
Who else have I introduced you to?
Um,
a number of other peripheral people or
other crews.
But I think,
you know,
I,
there's a number of people I'd like to
talk to the viewpoint and the viewpoint
that is more aligned with my politics
represented.
So we should,
we should keep at it.
And I think that the aim for me,
there's a couple of aims.
I mean,
the aim is to sort of end polarizing
discourse,
raise the level of conversation that can
be had for actual solutions that we need
for actual people and sort of longterm
aim for me is just to,
to,
to eliminate the levels of corruption in
the government and that's crossed the
boards either side.
That's a longterm aim for me is like
who's willing to sign onto the disclose
act,
who's willing to say that they're going
to disclose all their donors?
Everyone we paid for an APP who's
willing to not take pac money is
individual candidates.
Um,
you know,
who's willing to stand up against
gerrymandering.
And that to me is party agnostic.
Whose on that?
Yup.
Okay.
Well sounds like a plan.
Alright.
Alright,
I'll start.
I'll start the ball rolling on my end.
I've got some people that I want you to
meet on the Republican end of the
distribution as well.
Great.
I'm happy
to meet with anyone who is reasonable
and willing to have discourse instead
the chest these?
Yup.
Okay,
good.
Good talking to you greg.