Well,
I'm speaking today with Dr Steven Hicks,
who's a professor of philosophy at in
the Department of Philosophy at Rockford
University in Illinois,
and Professor Hicks has written a book
that I found several books,
but he's written one in particular that
I want to talk to him about today called
explaining postmodernism skepticism and
socialism for Moose,
so to food code,
which was published fair,
why it fair while ago now in 2004,
but I think has become even more
pertinent and relevant today.
And I have talked a lot to my viewers
about your book and so let's talk about
postmodernism and its relationship with
new Marxism.
That's an so maybe you could tell our
viewers here a little bit more about
yourself and how you got interested in
this.
And
finished graduate school in philosophy
in the early nineties.
I'm originally from Canada,
born in Toronto.
Uh,
at that point a Pittsburgh and Indiana
had the two strongest philosophy of
science and logic programs.
And that's what I was interested in at
the time.
So on a professor recommendation,
I ended up at Indiana and it worked out
very nicely for me.
So most of my graduate work was actually
in epistemology philosophy of science,
logic,
some cognitive science issues as well.
So a lot of the ecosystem,
a lot of people and philosophical
linguistic issues that come up being
postmodernism.
Uh,
the groundwork was laid for that when I
finished Grad school teaching full time,
uh,
came to rutgers university is teaching
an honors program and the way that
program worked,
it was essentially a great books
program.
So it was like getting a second
education wonderfully.
But,
uh,
the way it was done was a,
each course was taught by two professors
to our honor students and so the
professors would be from different
departments,
so paired with literature,
professors,
history professors and so on.
And this was now the middle of nineties.
I started to hear about to thinkers.
I had not read,
I kind of heard about them,
but now I was reading them more closely
and finding that in history,
in literature and sociology and pro a
names like dairy dog who the others were
not omnipresent,
were huge names.
So I realized I had a,
have a gap in my education to fill.
So start reading a deeply in them,
uh,
my education in some ways was a broad in
the history of philosophy but narrow at
the graduate school level than I focused
mostly on annual American philosophy.
So my understanding of the continental
traditions was quite limited,
but by the time I got to the end of the
nineties,
uh,
I realized there was something
significant going on coming out of
continental philosophy and that's where
the book came out.
When you say significant,
do you mean what do you mean by that?
You mean intellectually do you mean
socially?
Politically,
there's lots of different variants of
significant
at that point,
intellectually this is still the 1990,
so postmodernism was not yet outside of
say are a,
a cultural wars.
But it was strongly an intellectual
force in that at that point,
a young phds coming out of sociology,
a literary criticism,
some subdisciplines in the law,
you're getting paid,
he's in the law,
historiography and so on.
And certainly in a departments in
philosophy still dominated by
continental,
traditional,
provocative,
uh,
that almost all of them are primarily
being schooled in what we now call
postmodern thinkers.
So the leading gurus are people like a
leotard from whom we get the label,
postmodern condition,
Fuko and,
and the others.
Maybe you could walk us through what you
learn because people are unfamiliar.
I mean,
you had,
you were advanced in your education,
including in philosophy and still
recognized your ignorance say with
regards to postmodern thinking.
And so that's obviously a condition
that's shared by a very large number of
people and postmodernism is one of those
words like existentialism that covers an
awful lot of territory and sober.
Maybe we could zero in on exactly what
that means and who these thinkers were,
Derrida,
Gluco,
and who you are and what you learned
about them.
Okay.
Yeah.
Fair enough.
Well,
all of the things you just named,
they think broadly,
they think strategically and they do
have a very strong historical
perspective on their disciplines and at
the same time they are trying to assess
where they think we are culturally,
politically,
socially,
and all of them are making a very,
uh,
dramatic claim that to some extent or in
some way modernism has either ended or
it has reached its major right or all of
the kind of the pack,
apologies and negative traits,
uh,
within the modern world are reaching a
culmination in their generation.
And so it's time for us to both
recognize that modernism has come to an
end,
that we need some sort of new
intellectual framework.
A post modern framework isn't
that they're criticizing what,
how would you carry that?
That's it.
That's the enlightenment values.
That's scientific rationalism.
How would you characterize it?
Exactly right.
Elements of it.
So of course there are some discipline
specific differences.
So literature,
people in philosophy,
people and the historians will use
modernism slightly differently.
But the idea of core is that if you look
at the mortem world,
essentially the world of the Middle Ages
saying that that was a itself broken up
by a series of revolutions,
the renaissance reformation and counter
reformation,
early scientific revolutions and all of
this is going on in a historic or short
chunks of time.
15 hundreds and 16 hundreds.
And so if you look at the both the
intellectual world and the social world,
uh,
comparing,
say the 14 hundreds with the 17 hundreds
culturally and intellectually you're in
a different universe actually at that
point.
So the features then of the,
of the modern world.
And now I'm going to use my
philosophical labels here are that we're
now natural listing,
right in our thinking that we were no
longer primarily supernatural mistake in
our thinking.
So we might still be open to the idea
that there's a god or some sort of
supernatural dimension like the way
deists are.
But first and foremost,
we're taking the natural world as a more
or less self contained self governing
world that operate supporting the cause
and effect.
And we're going to study it and its
terms,
but we're not seeing the natural world
as a derivative,
right?
Have a higher world or that everything
that happens in the natural world is a
part of God's plan.
And we read omens and so forth into
everything.
So metaphysically then where there's
been a revolution will naturalistic
epistemologically in terms of knowledge.
There also has been a revolution,
a how do we know the important truths
that require the beliefs that were
fundamentally going to commit our lives
to four by the time we become modern,
we,
uh,
we take experience seriously personal
experience.
We do that more rigorously and we're
developing and scientific method,
the way of organizing the data.
We're taking logic and all of the
sophisticated tools of rationality and
developing those increasingly.
And so our,
our,
our opposition then is either you know,
something because you can experience it
and verify it for yourself or we've done
the hard work of scientific method a and
as a result of what comes out of that,
that's what we can call knowledge or
best approximation to that.
So revolutionary.
Let me just say one more thing because
the prior intellectual framework,
right,
was much more intellectually
authoritarian in the framework,
right?
So you would accept in the Catholic
tradition the authority of the church,
right,
and who are you to question the
authority of the church and who are you
to mount empirical rational arguments
are against the authority of the church,
or you take the authority of scripture,
right?
Or you accept on faith that you've had a
mystical revelation of some sort.
So in all of those cases you have non
rational epistemologies that are
dominating intellectual discourse that
is all buying logs swept away by the,
in the,
in the modern world.
Okay.
So,
so prior to the emergence of the modern
world,
in the same people are dominated
essentially by their willingness to
adhere to a shared tradition.
And now shared tradition is somewhat
tyrannical enforced,
but there's no real alternative in terms
of epistemology,
let's say.
And then as the modern world emerges,
people discovered the technologies of
science and the value of rigorously
applied method and the comparison of
shared experiences.
And that makes us technologically,
technologically powerful and in a new
way and philosophically different from
what we were before.
Yes,
the assured tradition praise that,
uh,
that you added there,
that's an important one.
So I would say in the early modern
world,
there's not necessarily a skepticism
about assured traditions of students.
So it would be an acceptance of shared
conditions.
The idea is that you would not
uncritically accept your tradition,
that you will accept the tradition,
but only have two.
You've thought it through the major own
Independent.
Okay.
So you're elevated to the status of
someone who's capable of taking a stance
with regards to the,
to the tradition and assessing.
It's pretty sad.
So there's an elevation of the
individual and the critical intellect
alone along with the,
with the elaboration of the scientific
method.
Okay.
So then then we might know perhaps that
that's a tremendously effective
transformation,
although maybe it leads in a somewhat
nihilistic direction.
Metaphysically we can leave that to the
side,
but it's a very,
very successful revolution because by
the time,
at least the beginning of the 20th
century comes along.
There's this staggering.
And of course,
before that,
the industrial revolution,
there's this staggering transformation
of technology and technological and
conceptual power and then a stunning
increase in the standard of living and
that starts at about 1890 to really to
move exponentially in the eighties,
nineties,
or,
or at least to get to the really,
really steep part of the exit ex
exponential curve.
Okay.
So that seems to be going well.
So what is it that the postmodernists
are objecting to?
Precisely?
Well,
by the time,
just on those two issues,
um,
the metaphysical naturalism and then
the,
uh,
the elevation of critical empiricists
and a belief that we can through science
and,
uh,
even not necessarily a science,
the social scientists and so on,
come to understand powerful general
principles about humanity and social
systems.
Those two revolutions both are then
subjected to counter attacks.
Uh,
and again,
uh,
what happens in this case is there was a
revolution,
uh,
probably by the time we get to 1800,
the height of the enlightenment or the
beginnings of more powerful skeptical
traditions that they come to be
developed.
So the thinkers are starting to say
things like,
well,
you know,
if a scientific method is based on the
evidence of the senses that we,
uh,
we observed the natural world,
that's our first point of contact,
and then on the basis of that reform,
have distractions and we put those apps
integrated into a propositions and then
we take a propositions and put them in
networks that we call theories and so
on.
So we start to critically examine each
of the elements of scientific method and
over time,
uh,
weaknesses in the existing accounts of
how all of those rational operations
work come to be teased out.
And philosophy then starts to go down a
more skeptical path.
So if,
for example,
you take perception,
uh,
as fundamental as our,
you know,
the individual subjects,
first point of contact with the natural
world,
then you have to immediately deal with
issues of a perceptual illusions for the
possibility that people will have
hallucinations or that the way you
report your perceptual experience is at
odds with how I report my perceptual
experiences.
So we have all
tell me if I've got this right.
So with the dawning of the empirical
age,
let's say there's this idea that you can
derive valid information from sensor
data,
especially if you contrast that sense
data rigorously without others.
Okay.
So that's sort of the foundation for the
scientific method in some sense.
But then I think this is with manual
con,
there's an objection to that,
which is that while you can't make the
presupposition that that sense data
enters your cognitive apparatus,
your apparatus of understanding without
a prior restructuring,
it seems to me that that's where the
postmodernists really go after the
modernists.
It's that given that you have to have a,
a very complex perceptual structure that
modern people might say was instantiated
as a consequence of biological
evolution.
You can't make the case that what you're
receiving from the external world is
something like peer information.
It's always subject to some very
difficult to delimit degree to
interpretation.
And then you also have to take into
account the fact that about a
restructure and what it might mean for
your concept of objective reality.
And that's con.
I think if I've got that right.
Well,
the postmoderns,
we'll use both of those strategies,
the,
uh,
the strategy and the rationalist
strategy.
And what's important about con right is
that cloud is integrating,
right?
Both of those and by strategy.
So in the generations before Khan,
the,
uh,
the skeptical arguments about perception
by directed against the empiricists,
you just want to say everything is based
on observational data,
but then if you don't have good answers
about hallucinations and relativity and
illusions,
right,
and so forth,
and it seems like your structure,
intellectual structure,
whatever it comes to be,
it,
it's all based on probabilistic or
possibly faulty perceptual data than the
whole thing is a,
is a tottering mess.
And by the time we get to con,
the appearance is tradition is a largely
unable to respond to those kinds of
objections.
And so contract recognizing and saying,
all right,
we've been trying now for a couple of
centuries,
we haven't been able to do so
successfully,
uh,
we're not going to be able to do so.
Now.
You also nicely right,
emphasize that one of the other,
the other response.
So it had been on the rationalist solid,
which is to say,
well,
no,
you don't start with pure empirical data
instead that we do have perhaps some
innate,
a priori structures built into the human
mind,
how they got there.
Maybe they're put there by God,
maybe they're put there naturalistically
regular or whatever.
Uh,
but what enables us to have legitimate
knowledge,
right,
is that our empirical data comes in and
it is filtered and structured by these
preexisting right cognitive structures
as well.
The problem with that side of the line,
and this is also well worked out by the
time we get to the content,
is the same world.
If you're starting with inbuilt
cognitive structures and everything that
comes in so to speak,
goes through the structural machine and
you're aware of the outputs.
It goes.
That's what's presented to your mind.
Well,
how do you know that those inbuilt
structures I have anything to do with
the way reality actually is out there.
It seems.
I've been.
What you are stuck with is the end
result of a subjective processing and
there is no way for you,
so to speak,
to jump outside of your head or to
compare it to end result with the way
the world actually is our independently
of how your mind has structured the
awareness.
So once again,
you're struck stuck rather in a rather
subjective place and again,
the importance of contours and he's also
looking at this more rationalist
tradition and he's saying,
well look again,
we've been trying now for a couple of
centuries to work these things out here
from descartes who spinosa lightness in
the others and rationalism also has
reached a dead end.
So we're not going to be able to do so.
So conference in effect standing at the
end of these two traditions and saying,
you know,
uh,
the skeptics have it right on both
sides.
The empiricists and the rationalist
tradition fail.
There is no way for us to objectively
come to know and external reality
restructuring some sort of subjectivism.
Okay.
So I don't know now whether to talk a
little bit of Rote American pragmatic
approach to that or whether to maybe we
should go ahead and continue our
discussion of the postmodernist because
they're developing these claims.
Absolutely.
And some of the postmodernists who
describe themselves as neo pragmatist,
Richard Horton for example.
So yes,
that's exactly the direction it's worth
going.
Okay.
So my,
my understanding of that,
if I was going to defend the modernist
tradition,
let's say,
I would say that we,
we have instantiated within us an a
priority perceptual structure that's a
consequence of millions,
billions of years for that matter of
biological evolution.
And yet it is,
it has emerged in tandem with continual
correction of its presuppositions by,
by the selection process,
but it's still subject to error because
we have a very limited viewpoint as
specific individuals.
And we can,
we can,
not only are we limited,
but we also make,
you might say moral errors and I'll get
back to that cloud our judgment.
And so in an attempt to,
um,
expand our purview and rectify those
errors,
we do two things.
We test our hypothesis practically
against the world,
which is to say we say,
here's a theory of reality.
We acted out if the theory of reality is
sufficiently correct when we acted out,
we get what we want and then that's
sufficient proof for the validity of the
theory.
It's not absolute proof,
but it's sufficient proof.
And then the other thing we do,
and I think this has been paid attention
to much less except by thinkers such as
piaget,
is that we further constrain our
presumptions,
presuppositions about reality with the
necessity of constructing theories that
are also acceptable to people around us,
so they have to be integratable within
the,
the currently existing social contract,
and they have to be functionally
appropriate in the external world.
And that's a nice set of constraints.
And it seems to me that that at least in
some part goes along ways to answering
the objections to the,
to the limits of the scientific method
that had been discussed,
that were discussed and that you just
discussed that had been discussed
historically that you just summarized.
Uh,
I'm sympathetic too much of what you
went through.
The five point like a response to the
kinds of arguments that have been played
out,
but you're actually putting me in a
position then of the defending the
postmodern condition,
right,
about how it would undercut each of
those components.
So if you take for example,
a evolutionary epistemology and you give
a nice sketch of one standard
evolutionary epistemological framing,
which we said,
okay,
maybe we have these Infield,
a priority structures,
but we can rely upon them because here
we are standing at the long end of,
uh,
you know,
hundreds of thousands or millions of
years of evolution and they would not
have survived or enabled us to survive
had they not serve some sort of reliable
cognitive role in accurately
representing the way that it works with
the,
uh,
the postmodern.
Uh,
this is actually too early for the
postmodern.
Postmodern will agree with this is to
say all of that kind of begs the
question right in a very deep way
against the kind of skeptical objections
that we're raising.
Because in order to make that paragraph
long description of what evolutionary
epistemology is,
what I have to do is take for granted as
basic assumptions,
certain truth right about the world that
for example,
there is an external world,
right,
that we are biological creatures that we
have in built structures,
that those structures are evolutionarily
responsive and conditioning by changing
forces like and so forth,
and if you take those assumptions right
to be true,
then as a consequence or inclusion,
you can infer that therefore the
intellectual products that come out of
our cognitive processing or reliable
right in some way,
but where did you get those for premises
from?
How do you know?
Right?
That there was an extra in a world.
How do you know that we are biological
creatures?
How do you know for that evolution is
true with all of the historical
knowledge is necessary to reach the
conclusion that evolution is true.
All of that presupposes that we have
legitimate cognitive methods become to
understand the world,
but our having legitimate cognitive
processes understand the world.
That's exactly what we are arguing about
in the first place and you can't just
assume that right for the sake of coming
up with some premises that are then in
turn going to validate those cognitive
processes.
So something like that or say is there's
a,
there's a big circle,
a circular reasoning problem that the
evolutionary epistemology find some
crap.
Then now I think there are some
responses to that and this is just the
first back and forth,
right on that particular debate,
but that is the kind of response that
will be there.
So the third and fourth are keeping
track accurately is to say that we also
have a constraints,
right,
with respect to,
to ourselves,
uh,
that if we have a certain set of
hypotheses are certainly fatal theories
and we're testing them out,
uh,
we will accept those that give us what
we want.
That's sort of what I want.
So the street and I'm also necessarily
in a social situation.
So what you to do is check my results
against the,
uh,
the results of others.
Purely review,
experiment,
replication,
like and so forth.
Or we live in the same household.
Yes,
absolutely right.
More prosaically,
right?
A sharing our frameworks right with each
other,
right.
And so on.
And so if so to speak,
uh,
and this is the more pragmatist
orientation.
If we then say we have a theory or a set
of principles or guidelines or whatever,
and they do enable me successful,
you navigate the world or to get what I
want,
or they do enable me to navigate my
social world.
We get us what we want.
Then they're reliable crew or some sort
of a success label epistomological that
we're going.
Okay.
So let me ask you a question about this
is a place where I got honored and very
badly with a Sam Harris.
We were discussing metaphysical
presumption.
So you know,
and,
and I'm confused about this.
I would say to some degree conceptually
because I'm,
I'm an,
I'm a scientist and certainly operate
most of the time under the
presupposition of an independent
objective world.
But then I also have some difficulty
with the idea that objective truth.
It's that it's objective truth within
which all other truths are nested.
And that's something that Sam and and
the people that he represents in some
sense are very dead set on insisting.
Now,
it seems to me though that the crux of
the matter is something like the method
of proof and districts me is very
important because my theory is correct
enough if when I implemented,
I get what I want is not the same as the
claim.
My theory is true because it's in
accordance with some independently
existing objective world.
I mean both of those things can exist at
the same time,
but I think the more appropriate claim
to make with regards to human knowledge
is something like it's biological
functionality,
which is that your knowledge is of
sufficient accuracy,
which is about the best you can hope for
because of your fundamental ignorance.
If when you implemented it reliably
produces the results that are
commensurate say with your continued
existence.
Now it seems to me that that's a
reasonable claim from a Darwinian
perspective.
And it also seems to me that it's very
much in keeping with the claims of the
American pragmatists.
And I mean,
it's not like they were radical
postmodernists because they weren't,
but they were trying to solve this
problem to some degree of our
fundamental ignorance and our,
our inability to be certain about the
nature of the reality that surrounds us.
Okay.
Let's set aside a Sam Harris's a version
of this and focus on the pragmatist
Reggie tradition here.
So No,
you're absolutely right.
A William James,
John Dewey,
right?
And the others,
late 19th century,
early 20th century.
They are coming a century after the
content revolution after ideally ism,
uh,
and so forth.
And so they are very much trying to
solve this problem one way.
And this is a very American right sort
of things to say.
Look,
maybe the problem with philosophy is
that we have been to like intellectual
ising like cognition that we're not just
embodies.
Brains are disembodied minds that are
trying to kind of contemplate abstract
in some other realm.
Maybe what we need to do is understand
right?
The mind and cognition as a naturalistic
process and that the purpose of
knowledge is not to come up with these
pure and beautiful truths that are going
to be kind of museum pieces that we will
admire her,
but rather the purpose of knowledge is
functional.
The purpose of knowledge is to guide
action.
Uh,
and so they will then harking back to
the earlier they konijn traditional the
knowledge knowledge is not an end in
itself,
but as they can afford it.
A Francis Bacon,
a knowledge is power and by its fruits,
right?
So to speak,
you know it's worth.
And so what we then should do is to see
that the chest of crew is not like
whether it meets purely intellectual
standards of logic and mathematics,
but rather when we put it to practice
and then we act upon it,
we actually get good results or we get
the results we want or I get the results
I will become and more individualistic
form or more socialized,
right?
Because then we can get on.
That's ignorance in some sense.
So there's two things that are being
packaged here,
right?
One is to say that knowledge right is
functional and that part I think is
important.
I think it's a very nice correction or
the pragmatists are,
it's not original with them,
but they are re emphasizing that in the
19th century,
knowledge needs to be pushed to the
test.
Uh,
and uh,
it's ability to do,
enable us to,
uh,
to be pragmatic,
but so to speak in the real world is a
test.
Then there's a code to data as well.
And I think this is relevant to Thomas
Kuhn's discussion of scientific
revolutions because code is often read
as positing a sequence of,
in some sense discontinuous revolutions.
But if you,
if you and,
and,
and that the conceptual structure that
characterized one epoch,
let's say like the Medieval Lee Park was
so totally different and it's
presuppositions from the conceptions
that characterize the next.
He parked that,
that you can't even mediate between them
in some sense.
And now the reason I'm bringing this up
is because coon is at least read as
hypothesizing that there's not any
necessary progress when you make leaps
from one conceptual system to another.
But if you take this pragmatic approach,
the one that we've been outlining,
it seems to me that you can say,
well,
something like this,
your conceptions of the world are more
tool like than objective truth,
light and tools can have a greater or
lesser range of convenience.
And so if you come up with a really good
tool which would also be something that
would look objectively true,
generally speaking,
then that's something that you can use
in almost every situation and it will
never fail.
You and I would think of something like
Newtonian physics and in that regard,
or even more particularly quantum
mechanics because it's never failed us
and so it seems to me the pragmatic
approach in some sense allows you to
have your cake and eat it too.
You can pause it,
a hierarchy of truths,
moving towards an absolute truth even,
but also retain your belief in your own
ignorance and not have to beat the drum
too hard about the like what eternal
accuracy of your objective
presuppositions.
Okay.
Again,
I'm sympathetic.
I think with about 80 percent of that,
but let me put my skeptical hat back on
and say,
well,
how the postmoderns or the critics of
pragmatism for first generation
pragmatism will respond to that.
So if we then say,
right,
all of these,
uh,
cognitive results and to rephrase,
so we're going to assess all of our
cognitive,
uh,
results or cognitive hypotheses in terms
of their work with unity or they're
getting what I want or what we want.
Well,
then the big question we have to turn to
is to say,
well,
how do we judge whether something works
or say that it's good because I get what
I want.
We get what we want,
what is a want,
right?
And where do these wants come from and
why should we accept wants and desires
and,
uh,
achieving certain goals as our bottom
line,
so to speak.
Great.
Okay.
So that's right.
So you can start to question the
framework,
the framework within which you're
constructing the answer.
That's where I end at this point,
we're leading epistemology right
neutrally,
so to speak,
and moving into normative issues.
And so the whole status of normative,
uh,
goals and,
and then the means that are going to
enable us to reach,
reach rather those ends comes into play.
So if I want to say the it's important
thing is that I put it very baldly here,
right?
I get,
I want,
right?
And I'm going to assess intellectual
structures and beliefs and hypotheses in
terms of do they give me what I want?
Well,
that already sounds like a fairly,
uh,
normatively subjectivist standpoint.
Why should you take your wants as having
some sort of high status it,
everything has to be evaluated in terms
of a.
and then philosophically,
then we say,
well,
where'd wants come from?
And forces along anthropological,
psychological,
that set of literature a here,
what,
what's the relationship of our ones?
Are they based in biological drives or
the instinctual or they acquired or the
intellectual.
Do they have any relationship to our
rational capacities when I'm acting?
Should I act on my desires and my wants,
my console?
So poor.
So there's that whole tradition and we
have to have a sophisticated theory
about how all of that is going to work.
If we're going to say we'll solve all
these cognitive because the mechanical
issues in terms of once or the
satisfaction of desires or the
achievement of goals the way private
does want us to do,
and again,
uh,
it's fairly easy to,
to imagine what the skeptical you're
going to be,
right?
If it's a matter of what I want,
well,
isn't science supposed to be about
coming up with general truths,
uh,
or,
or maybe even universal cruise.
And if we're immediately going to
devolve it to whatever individuals want,
well then we're going to be in there
fairly scattered because that also opens
up a good point for a segue into the
potential link between new Marxism,
let's say,
and postmodernism,
because maybe you could say once you've
opened the door to an admission that you
can criticize the,
the idea of want as a social construct,
let's say.
Which is one of the things that you
intimated,
nor the only thing obviously.
Then you open the door to also making
the claim that,
that,
that social construct that governs the
wants that governs the truth can be
governed by power,
relationships.
Something like that.
And then by unfair power relationship so
you can spin off down that aisle,
which,
and,
and that's the other thing I really want
to talk to you about is because on the
one hand,
the postmodernists are following this
intellectual tradition of the critique
of,
of western thinking,
which is exactly in some sense what
philosophy should be doing,
but in another way they seemed
simultaneously to be introducing almost
by sleight of hand,
I kind of social critique that has its
origin more in political revolution and
class based theory.
And they do that.
They do that under the guise of pure
philosophy in some sense.
But with the intent and motivation of
something like justifying the social
revolution or continuing the Marxist,
the Marxist analysis of power
differential.
It can go both ways.
Yes,
it is possible that follow the road that
we've just been going down to say,
well,
you know,
if it's a matter about,
uh,
you know,
what works for you,
then that immediately starts to sound to
relativistic and subjectivist.
We don't have
an explanation or an answer rather to
all the Weirdos want to do strange
things because that's what they wanted
to.
So we might introduce as a corrective a
socializing right of the process.
So we might then say,
no,
it's not so much what you want as an
individual,
but rather what we want and we need to
achieve some sort of a consensus here.
So this is a slightly cartoon version
here,
but the difference between William James
who was more individualistic and John
Dewey in the next generation will
collect advisors things,
right a little bit more.
So then we have a corrective on all of
the individual Weirdos who knows what
their desires and goals,
right are going to be.
Right.
But anyway,
just to confront the same problem there
as soon as we start doing anthropology
because then if we say,
well,
if we relativize it to the social group
and when we start looking at different
social groups,
obviously different social groups have
dramatically different wants and needs
and desires and evolve very different
traditions.
And if it's a matter of saying what's
true is what works for the group,
uh,
there is then no sorta speak Uber Group,
right,
or,
or highest group of all groups that has
status overall of the others.
And if you do,
and this is the second point that you
said,
right?
Exactly right.
Uh,
then you say,
well,
no,
this group's norms and goals are better
than that group's goals,
or hey,
then you're into a,
what the critics are going to call
imperialism,
right?
Of,
uh,
of the,
of the Lgu,
inappropriate form,
right?
So that leaves us,
that leaves us with our current
political situation in some sense,
which is because that's been,
it's been,
that idea has been taken to what,
to a logical conclusion.
And that logical conclusion has now been
instantiated to a large degree as a,
as an intellectual and political
activist movement.
I would say that.
Sure,
absolutely.
So it can start as an intellectual
movement that we're trying to do some
hardcore epistemology,
right?
And we go through the empiricism,
the rationalist and the content
revolution.
And the pragmatists are right now,
we're in the second generation
pragmatism where we'd relativize
relative to various kinds of groups and
then we're just stuck in a kind of group
relativism and then the operational
principles socially then is going to be
that each group,
so to speak,
should stick to itself and not think
that it can impose its ideas and its
norms on any.
Any other group.
Right.
All groups so to speak,
are equal.
Yeah.
There was an equal claim to have an
equal claim to their formulation of the
truth.
The problem with the postmodern
conjunction with neo Marxism to me,
seems to be the idea,
the acceptance of idea,
that there's an intrinsic moral claim by
the dispossessed to the,
to the obtaining of status,
and that actually constitutes a higher
moral calling in and of itself.
So they're swallowing a moral claim that
it making it universal in some sense.
At the same time,
they criticize the idea of say general
narratives are universal moral claims.
Okay.
Now that's
also A.
Right.
So that's,
that's the other way rather than
starting with epistemology.
Right.
In ending up getting into a kind of
cultural relativism,
right?
You can start a course committed to a
certain normative framework,
regular certain ideological framework,
uh,
as Marxism is where you're very critical
part of one of those traditions.
And then the cultural relativism can be
right a part of that that you used to
criticize the tradition,
right?
Internal.
Now then we're explicitly into a not to
met an ethics and asking where do we get
our ethical principles off the ground or
where do they come from in the first
place,
but kind of a robust normative ethics
where people have committed commitments
rather to fairly strong ethical
principles and ethical ideals.
And this is where there was a debate
between say Nisha and mark's becomes
relevant and this is a late 19th century
right?
Debate.
So I suppose we say as both the Marxists
who will do is say there is no proof in
any objective sense.
And we said,
oh,
we have the subjectivity in relativity
regular very sorts and we have different
individuals in different groups and they
are in antagonistic conflict,
relationship with each other.
And that means there's not really going
to be any,
uh,
know rational and civil resolution of
these discussions with each other.
Instead,
it all comes down to power a sleight of
hand claim there too,
because why?
It has to come down to powers that seems
to introduce the necessary need.
Okay?
Yeah,
that's another thing.
We set that aside just for a moment,
uh,
but then we say,
okay,
so we have power,
right?
And one thing that we can say is,
while we don't think any one individual,
any one group has a better objective
claim to truth or better ideals,
it is nonetheless the case that some
individuals and groups have more power
than others.
And so then we have to make our
allegiance clear in this unequal power
struggle.
Are we on the side of those who have
more power or are we on the side of
those who have less power?
And that's where we get then a
Nietzschean and Marxian that fork in the
road,
right?
So the nutrients following nature will
say,
look,
uh,
it's all about power.
Uh,
then we can try on some crude
evolutionary thinking here.
It's only the exercise of power,
right by the stronger,
the fitter,
healthier,
and so forth that are willing to impose
their power on the weaker and use them
for their own ends that we as
individuals and groups are going to make
any sort of progress toward the next
best thing.
But whatever that is.
So in the power struggle,
there is no objective morality and
objective truth,
uh,
we just throw our lot in with the
stronger,
with the richer,
with the more powerful,
and they say whatever it is that they do
in order to advance themselves,
that's normative best that we can do
better.
Of course,
there's a long,
kind of aristocratic tradition,
right?
Uh,
innovative thinking that one can draw on
to support that.
And in a Marxist mattress rather,
of course it was on the other side of
that equation,
right?
Where their sympathies,
right initially are going to be say,
you know,
in any power struggle,
our kind of a prior or I commitments
that should always be to the weaker to
those on the losing end or the pistol,
those who suffer and so forth.
And it's always the rich and powerful
people who are oppressing and harming
them and so we throw our lot in with the
weaker and we're willing to use power
whatever amount of power we have on
behalf of the weaker.
And then when we're just into what I
think of as the major false alternative
that really has driven much of 20th
century with intellectual life.
Are you a nutrient or are you a Marxist?
Well,
okay,
so now we can get to the crux of the
matter here to some degree because to
even engage in that argument means to
accept the a priority position.
Which would you made quite rationally
compelling?
Let's say that its power,
its power because there's no other way
of differentiating between the claims of
different groups.
It's power.
That's the determining issue.
But yeah,
that that's something I really have a
problem with and,
and I think it's crucial importance
because first of all,
I think there's a big difference between
power.
There's a difference between power and
authority and competence.
Those are all not the same thing because
you might be willing to see greater
status to me in some domains,
if there are things I can do that you
value that you can't do,
and that's not power.
Exactly.
Power seems to be more than I'm willing
to use force to impose my interpretation
of the world to get my wants fulfilled
on you,
and it seems to me that were the
Marxists make a huge mistake.
Not that the Nietzsche ends aren't
making mistakes as well,
but for the Marxists make a huge mistake
is that they failed to properly
differentiate between hierarchies of
interpretation that are predicated on
tyrannical power and hierarchies of
authority,
confidence and mutual consent.
Because those and the other issue that
they failed to contend with,
and I believe this is a form of willful
blindness,
is that it isn't obviously the case that
every society is set up equally to only
fulfill the desires of the people who
are in principle situated at the
pinnacles of the hierarchies.
I actually don't think that that's
fundamentally characteristic of the
western tradition because it has a very
strong emphasis,
weirdly enough,
and this is how I think it extracts
itself out of the social socialized,
the conundrum that accepting a a
socialized version of truth presents to
you.
The West does two things.
It says we have a social contract that
constraints are views of the world and
our actions in it,
but that social contract is also
simultaneously subordinate to the idea
of the sovereignty of each individual
and so the social contract is bound to
serve the needs of each individual.
Not any privileged set of individuals.
Although sometimes it works out that way
and I don't believe that the postmodern
NSF contended with that properly with
their.
With their criticism of logo centers and
for example,
which was something that characterized
data.
Because I think that that because it
doesn't.
It never has seemed to me that what you
had with Stalinist Russia and and the
Marxist view of the world and what you
had on the side of the West was merely a
matter of a difference of opinion
between two equally valid socialized
modes of interpreting the world.
You know there's something wrong.
There's something more to the view of
the West.
Then what's in battle,
what's embodied in the conflict between
capitalism and socialism.
Because it could've just been a matter
of argumentation and opinion.
But I think that that's.
That's fault.
And I thought this way in part because
of piaget,
because piaget was interested in what
the intrinsic constraints.
We're on a social contract and he said,
and he was trying to address this issue
of the insufficiency of want as a,
as a,
as a tool to justify your claims to
truth.
And that's when he introduced the idea
of the equilibrated state.
So if you're sophisticated,
you have to put forward your want and
then need it in a way that will meet it
today and tomorrow and next month and
next year and in a decade.
So you have to iterate yourself across
time and you have to take all of the
iterations of yourself across time with
some degree of seriousness and then you
also have to do the same thing as you
extend yourself out into the social
community.
So it has to be what's good for me now
and repetitively into the future in a
manner that simultaneously good for you
now and simultaneously into the future.
And that starts to become an.
And he thought about that as the
playable game,
something like that.
The voluntarily playable game.
And there's something deep about that
because it includes the idea of
iteration,
you know,
iterated interpretations into the
equation,
which strikes me as like,
of crucial importance.
Okay.
Yeah.
Again,
I think by my count about six very
interesting subtopics built into that
and the latter part of a very nice
statement I think of kind of lightened
meant humanism where we're going to take
power seriously,
but we're going a constraint power in a
way that respects the individual and
simultaneously enables individuals to
form mutually beneficial social network
across time.
And so,
uh,
and uh,
I'm very sympathetic to a,
that overall right construction,
uh,
that comes out of them.
The first part,
which is a taxonomy,
right?
That you're offering about the nature of
power and that taxonomy does differ
significantly from both the Marxist and,
and the Nietzschean one I would say is,
you know,
I think it's better to take power right
more neutrally.
Um,
so there's a continuity with what the
physicists do.
My understanding there is a power or
just the,
the ability to get work done.
So it's a,
it's a tool and functionality,
right?
Language,
right power is what gets you from a to
B.
Great.
I love that description because it fits
very nicely in with the narrative
conceptualization of b,
because narratives seem to be
descriptions of something like how to
get from point a to point B,
right?
But it also doesn't say anything about
being in the status of be how we choose
where we should be going,
but what our ends are or what are our
goals are going.
So in that sense,
power is normatively neutral.
It's a means to an end.
Uh,
and that means that when we start to try
to evaluate the uses of power,
we're going to be evaluating power in
terms of the ends towards which is put
a,
if I can end with that pip position.
Yeah.
So now then we say,
okay,
well power comes in all kinds of
hormones,
right?
We're quite happy to say those
intellectual power or the ability to use
our minds to,
to address and solve certain problems
that there's muscular power will the
ability to move physical objects.
There's a social power people respect
you and are,
are willing to spend time with you and
divert resources to voluntarily and so
forth.
Uh,
there's military power,
political power,
and so we're going to have a whole set
of subspecies of power.
And what they all have in common is a,
in each of those domains,
there are goals and having the power
enables you to achieve your goals in
those domains.
Great.
And we shouldn't fall prey to the
illusion that there's necessarily any,
like,
what would you call it,
unifying matrix that makes all those
different forms of power.
Importantly,
similar except for the terminology you
know,
we,
and this is another thing that bothers
me about the both,
the Nietzschean in the Marxist Marxist
view,
is that there's this proclivity to
collapse these multiple modes of power
into power itself and that's not
reasonable because if it's reasonable to
note many of the forms of power that you
just described contend against one
another rather than mutually fortifying
one another.
It's like a.
it's like the balance of power in a.
In a polity like the American polity,
that's a deep point that you're making
a,
I think both the Marxists and the
Nietzschean to do ended up collapsing
power into a unitary type.
Alright,
that's when the steak,
but it's a mistake only if you deny
right?
As both the marshals and the Nietzschean
do that.
There is a deep individuality right
about a world.
So if you think by contrast,
right about the kind of individual human
rights respecting and lightening and
vision,
you're articulating that I agree with as
well.
For normatively,
that wants to devolve social power to
the individual or individuals with a
great deal of self responsibility and
control over their own domain.
Right?
So the speed and the idea then is that
if we're going to form social
relationships or any sort of social
interaction,
it has to be mutually respecting that I
have to respect your control over your
domain and you respect my control over
my domain,
but we agreed to share domains,
so to speak,
that voluntary.
Right?
And this is a place where I think the
post modernists are really open to you
might say conceptual assault is that you
know,
in order to have that freedom devolve
upon the individual in that manner,
it also means that the individual has to
take responsibility for acting as a
locus of power in world actual
responsibility and cannot conceive of
themselves or act in a manner that only
makes them an Avatar of a social
movement.
And I think that art of the preferred
anthony individualism of the radical
left is precisely predicated on that
refusal to take responsibility.
And I think that's also reflected in the
fact that by temperament,
they're low in trait conscientiousness,
so it's deep,
it's not merely an opinion,
it's an expression of something that's
even deeper than opinion
prayed.
Locus of responsibility,
locus of power,
locus of control.
You're right that the far left in
Marxist in Neo Marxists form does deny
that.
But you also find that in far right in
general,
right?
So this is a bit of cartoon,
To intellectual history,
right?
But then if you try to trace it to the
Marxist on the left and the nutrients on
the right,
both of them do denied that individuals
are locus Loci,
rather have responsibility by both of
them in their views of human nature have
strongly deterministic views for what we
call an individual.
Right?
According to both of them,
right?
It's just a vehicle through which right
outside forces are flowing,
so to speak.
Right?
Well,
you can also see that in some sense,
as a perverse consequence of the
scientific revolution because you're
still see this among modern scientists.
It's like,
okay,
what are the causal forces that regulate
human behavior?
Okay,
there's two primary sources,
mature slash biology and culture.
So it's the crude nature versus nurture,
debate being played out through them.
Yes.
Right.
So,
and that's in my opinion,
and I've derived this conclusion from
studying mythology mostly,
is that there's a missing third element
there,
which is whatever the active force,
whatever it is that constitutes the
active force of individual
consciousness,
right?
We don't have a good grounds right in
being an independent private initiator
of power instead of merely a responder
to other power forces,
right?
Or a vehicle through which those other
power forces operate.
So yeah,
the individualism,
right?
Uh,
that is built into enlightenment
humanism.
We start to see it developing in
renaissance humanism is to take
seriously,
right?
The notion that individuals have some
measure,
some significant measure of control over
their Fox,
over the actions,
the shape,
their own destiny,
and that is fundamental right to one
moral dignity as a human being.
And so that is going to be a live view
of human nature built into the ethics
fundamentally.
And then all of social relationships
have to be respectful of that
individuality.
And then consequently,
when we start to turn to political
theory,
or we thought knockabout very heavy duty
use of power such as the police and the
military,
uh,
we want to have a serious constraints on
government power to make sure that we
are respecting the individual
sovereignty.
Okay.
So here's something perverse to that,
that,
that emerges as a consequence of
something you pointed out earlier in the
conversation.
You know,
you mentioned that when modernism emerge
out of medieval Islam,
the two things happened and one was the
elaboration of the conceptual frames
that enabled us to deal with the
external world,
but the other was the elevation of the
individual to the status of valid critic
predicated on the idea that there was
something actually valid about
individual experience as such.
Now the problem there as far as I can
tell,
and maybe this is part of the reason
we're in this conundrum,
is that the,
the elaboration of the objective
scientific viewpoint let us left us with
the idea that it was either nature or
nurture that was the source of human
motive power.
But the missing element there is.
Well,
if that's the case,
then why grant to the individual to
begin with the role of independent
social critic?
Like on what grounds do you,
and it's like the,
it's like the resentment.
It's like a residual belief in something
like the autonomy of the soul.
You can't just sneak in and not justify
without,
without problems like the ones that we
have now.
That's well put and I think it's fair to
say that we still are in the infancy of
the psychological sciences.
You can speak to this better than I can,
but as someone in philosophy,
I think we're still at the beginnings
and we are still in the grip of early
and crude versions,
crude scientific understandings of how
cause and effect operators.
And so what we are starting with is very
mechanical,
uh,
understandings.
And we can understand how people that
are pushed around by biological forces.
We can understand to some extent now the
push around by the external,
physical and mechanical forces,
but we do not yet have a sophisticated
enough understanding of the human brain,
the human mind,
human psychology.
To understand how a volitional
consciousness can be a causal force
causal power in the world.
Right?
So that's perfectly put.
So in this,
I do a detailed analysis that some of
the people who watch,
we're familiar with this movie Pinocchio
and Un Occhio is got a very classic
mythological structure and it basically
introduces three elements of va,
so there's the element of being that's
associated with Japan and also the evil
tyrannical forces that are kind of
patriarchal in nature and that's sort of
the conceptualization of society.
I've been evolent element and a level at
the elements.
And then there's the introduction of
this other causal factor in it.
It's personified in the form of the blue
fairy in the blue fairy is a
manifestation of mother nature and she
animates the Nokia,
so Japan creates them and then sets up a
wish for his independence.
And then nature appears in the guise of
the blue fairy and and grants that wish.
So you have culture and nature
conspiring to produce.
I'm a puppet that could in fact
disentangle itself from its strength,
but the movie insists and it does this
on profound mythological grounds that
the puppet itself has a causal role to
play in it's own,
um,
what would you call its own capacity to
transcend the deterministic change that
it's being,
that,
that have the deterministic processes
that have given rise to it,
but that also enslaved it and you know,
in,
in all of our profound narratives,
I would say,
and this is part of the way that they
differ from the standard scientific
account.
There's always that third element.
There's always the autonomous individual
who is in some sense,
you know,
lifting himself up by his own bootstraps
and,
and I don't think it's a problem that
science is unable to account for that,
but it's a very big problem with
scientists who are unable to account for
that deny that it exists because they
can't explain it then becomes
extraordinarily dangerous,
right?
Once you stop looking,
uh,
you stopped crying,
right?
Then you're left with a,
an impoverished account.
So in a way,
there's a kind of Hubris right?
Built into the skepticism,
right?
It says,
you know,
I know that this is a problem that we
just can't solve that,
and so I'm not going to try.
I'll try anymore.
There's A.
There's a performative contradiction as
well,
which is much worth pointing out because
on the one hand,
the scientists might well claim as far
as I'm concerned from an epistomological
person perspective,
the only two causal forces are nature
and culture,
but then I'll go about my actions in the
normal world as an existential being,
acting in the world,
and I will swallow whole heartedly the
proposition that each individual is
responsible for his own actions because
that's how I constantly interact with
everyone in the world and I get very
irritated if they violate that
principle.
Right?
So how you live,
so to speak with your skepticism or with
your relativism in a way that doesn't
mean snarl you in the countries and
contradictions.
That's a.
that's a hard contract itself.
It does.
It does seem to be that I think it's
reasonable to point out that it's not
possible to find a person who acts as if
he or anyone else is biologically are
culturally determined.
We just don't behave that way in the
real world.
We act as if we're responsible for our
own actions and the consequences of
those actions.
So then we have a tension between what
our intellectual theories,
right are telling us and what are kind
of empirical data,
right was telling them.
So we don't yet have a way to put those
two together.
And then what you as an individual do in
response to that tension between theory
and practice.
Uh,
that's a whole other can of things to
explore.
Great.
To get the backup to our discussion
about power.
Um,
it's interesting that the way our
discussion right up to that point then
integrates,
right free thing.
So we started talking about proof,
uh,
and then we started talking about goals
and normative ends,
right in ideals.
And then we talk about power.
So there was already the big three
truth,
a ideals,
right and power.
I discussion about truth right?
Took us into a logical issues,
right in philosophy,
our discussion about ideals that takes
us into ethics and ethics issues.
Again,
also in philosophy or discussion of
power,
right?
Takes us in to issues about human
nature,
which traditionally,
but a branch of philosophy now,
smarter sub disciplines were doing so we
already have to have a theory of
epistemology,
theory of human nature,
a theory of efforts,
and we sometimes try to integrate those
and postmodernism is going to be an
integration,
right,
of certain views that develop in
divisions in all three of those areas.
So maybe one way to put it is this,
if you,
if you contrast it to again taking white
moment as our touchstone a since we're
both fans of the enlightenment because
they were fine with,
with power,
like knowledge is power and we want to
empower the individual,
right?
We want to eliminate slavery and
empower.
People want to eliminate or fashion
sexism and empower women.
So power.
Yeah.
We actually want to remove arbitrary and
unnecessary impediments to the
expression.
Yeah.
Proper power.
That's so there are legitimate uses of
power that are stopping and disempower
and right people.
So it's the double edge sword,
uh,
and as long as power is properly
directed or properly located,
right then we are confident that by and
large people individually and socially
we'll use their power to put together
useful lives,
build a successful economies and
societies and so forth.
So it was actually a very optimistic
right overall assessment about,
uh,
about,
about power,
but power right is then structured as a
means to an end.
And we want to empower people
cognitively teach them how to read,
teach them how to think,
right,
so that they themselves can understand
the truth and discover new truth.
But so power leads to true,
but we also then want people to be free
to,
uh,
to act on the basis of their,
their power.
Because then we think that if people are
respected as individual agents are going
to be happier,
uh,
and so they will achieve good goals and
they will mute workout,
share together,
fair will,
uh,
agreements and deals,
a kind of justice will,
the society will get better and better
and so forth.
So power is in the service of just
social relations.
And powers in the service of truth.
Great.
That's a great,
that's a great justification for the
enlightenment viewpoint.
And it seems,
I don't want to stop you from pursuing
that,
but it also seems to me that to the
degree that that's true,
a valid description of the enlightenment
aims and to the degree that that's
actually manifested itself in reality in
the state,
in the current state of human affairs,
that it's perhaps unwise of us to allow
our Marxist or are Nietzschean
presuppositions to take,
uh,
take two careless to swing at that
foundation.
Given that it's actually okay.
Absolutely right.
And that's why the enlightenment
articulation power is good.
If it's in the service of proof,
right?
Or power is good.
If it's in the service of justice and
you were fine and we're optimistic
enough about human beings cognitively
and morally,
that we think empowering them,
giving them lots of freedoms is going to
increase the net stocker approved and
it's going to increase the net stocker
justice.
So that entire enlightenment package is
precisely what the counter enlightenment
attacks and attack very fundamentally.
So that by the time we get to two,
three generations later to the
generations of marks and eat you,
it has been hollowed out.
So on the epistomological side,
right?
We don't believe,
right,
that there is such a thing as true
anymore.
So it's not the case that power is in
the search for truth because we don't
believe that human beings are capable of
getting any sort of objective proof
anymore.
So we're just left with power.
And also on the normative side,
we don't believe in dressed us right
anymore.
We don't believe that any sort of
normative principles or ethical ideals
can be objective.
We ground up.
And so then once again,
maybe we're left with subjective
designers,
right?
And so forth.
But we're just left again with power.
So Howard,
service approved power in the service of
justice that goes away.
All we are left with is power.
Sure.
Well we could mount a psychoanalytic
critique of that set of objections
because I could say,
okay,
here's some reasons.
Let's,
let's assume that you're doing something
simple
and and
let's assume you're doing something
simple and easy instead of complicated
and difficult with your objections,
and so here's the simple and easy
explanation you want to dispense with
the idea of justice and truth because
that lightens your existential lobe
because now there's nothing difficult
and noble that you have to strive for
and you want to reduce everything to
power because that justifies your use of
power in the pursuit of your immediate,
in pursuit of those immediate goals that
you no longer even have to justify it
because you don't have to make reference
to any higher standards of justice or
true,
and so I would say that's a deep
impulsive and resentful nihilism that's
manifesting itself as a glorious
intellectual critique.
Now I'm understanding as well that there
is the history of genuine intellectual
critique that you'd be laying out,
which is not trivial,
but those things have to be
differentiated.
You know,
it's certainly not reasonable either.
For those who claim that all there is is
power,
that they're not themselves motivated
equally by that power.
So in one way,
right?
What you could always say in the tech
philosophy is autobiographical,
in many cases were philosophers will put
their pronouncements in bird person
form.
I don't generalize form,
but if you always put it down to the
power or sort of person formulations
that can be profoundly self regulatory,
right?
So if you say for example,
human beings are Scamo,
where then you have some sort of
pessimistic already assessment of the
human condition,
a well built into that.
Then as the idea that I think if I
personally I am scum,
we're really doing is a,
is a,
is a first person confession and it's
always done in a legitimate move to
exempt yourself from the,
from the general principle,
right?
Everything just is to come back.
You are more likely topic,
your power relations and people imposing
their agendas on other people than what
you're saying is,
well,
my fundamental commitment is power and I
just want to impose my agenda on other
people.
So I think you're right that it can go
both ways.
It can of course be that you have people
who,
for whatever reason,
have a predisposition to nihilistic,
uh,
a more power seating and they,
when they become adults and
intellectual,
they latch onto theories,
uh,
that in indulgent that enabled them to
rationalize their predispositions.
Uh,
and so in many cases you are a lot of
postmodernism in some of the
manifestations is disingenuous,
right in that form that people don't
necessarily buy into the postmodern
philosophical framework,
but rather in kind of pragmatic form,
postmodernism as a set of tools is
useful for them to advance their own
personal and social agenda.
But whatever those happen to be because
they find it.
Okay.
So let's switch a little bit.
Let's switch over into that a little
bit.
And I found our discussion for what it's
worth,
I found her discussion extremely useful
on the philosophical and,
but now I would like to make it a bit
more personal.
So now you,
if you don't mind,
you've written this book and it's a
fairly punchy but say critique of
postmodernism and its alliance with neo
Marxism and,
and you've done a careful job of laying
out the historical development of that,
have both of those movements and their
alliance.
Um,
what,
what was your motivation for doing that
and what do you,
what have you experienced one as a
consequence of writing the book and to,
as a consequence of a professor who's in
the midst of a,
of an academic society that's basically
running on postmodern principles?
Yeah,
that's a good trio of questions there.
But my,
my motivation for writing the book was a
motivations plural.
A one is an intellectual exercise.
A year was a movement that was complex.
Many philosophical and cultural screens
were coming together and uh,
I enjoy the intellectual history very
much so.
It was a pleasure for me to,
to read back into the histories and the
cheese out over the lines of and how
things were packaged,
be packaged.
Uh,
so that the postmodern synthesis right
as it came together in the front of the
second,
third and 20th century,
right,
came,
came into being as a,
as a purely intellectual historical
enterprise,
found that fulfilling a partly also this
was a 19,
90,
late 19 nineties.
It's end of the Cold War.
Uh,
one of the things I had done,
not professionally but just out of
personal interest was read a lot of
political philosophy,
read a lot about the Cold War and the,
uh,
the intellectual developments and
political developments that have gone on
there.
So I had a very good say amateur working
knowledge before I started researching
the book about the history of Marxism
and history of the Cold War geopolitics
and sort of one of the big questions
that are on everyone's mind person in
the 19 nineties with the fall of the
Soviet Union.
The end of the Cold War is what's going
to happen next,
whether it's the new geo political
alignment going to be.
But then from my academic position,
uh,
the big question inside the intellectual
world is since far left politics had
been so prominent and that for
generations,
right?
Intellectuals inside the academic world
at large will given the benefit of the
doubt too far,
leftists experiments,
even going out of the way to be fellow
travelers and so forth that,
uh,
by the time you get to the end of the
cold war,
basically everybody except for a few
true believers is rethinking.
Right?
So what does this mean for not
necessarily left politics more broadly,
but certainly for our lab by politics.
Uh,
and so even the far right of the
leftists are recognizing that they're
going to have to come up with some sort
of a new strategy in order to remain
intellectually respectable and some sort
of a new strategy in order to become a
culturally and politically feasible.
So I didn't have a kind of a cultural,
political interest in what the thinking
was on the far left about what they're
going to do now that the Soviet Union
has collapsed and the whole world is
shifting more toward market liberalism
or to some sort of third way central is
loaded up on the beach.
So yes.
So you have a huge amount of empirical
data that you have to confront and uh,
uh,
yeah,
I think this is certainly going to be
part of the postmodern package,
but there was a lot of denial of the
relevance of Empiricism,
a lot of denial of the,
uh,
the relevance of logic and social
scientific statistical methods of
aggregating that data and which normally
the conclusions on the basis of that.
So we can understand the temptation on
the part of a lot of people to find
psychological devices that will enable
them to deny the gulag and various other
things
either are stacked viciously and get the
facts as even you would constrain them.
Are Stacking officiously in
contradiction to your theory.
It's time to mount an all out assault on
what constitutes a fact.
One strategy,
and that's again,
one of the sub strategies,
I think that postmodern postmodern
worldview,
so if you then have a loss suffers and
social scientists and the people who are
up to speed in their epistemology who
are telling you well know there are just
know different narratives that are out
there and there are no such things as
objective facts and logic was not
necessarily pointing in one direction.
There are poly logics or,
or,
or multiple frameworks.
Then,
uh,
if you have one framework that says no,
there are objective facts,
uh,
and,
and the logic is all going against your,
your version of political idealism.
It's to be very tempting for you to say,
well,
I can just dismiss that as just one
narrative way of constructing the
historical facts.
I can come up with a different narrative
that softens organized like all together
and certainly some of the bad faith
postmodernist who go down that road like
very much so.
In part that was my motivation for
writing the book part.
I did feel that I was in a good position
intellectually to do so because my,
my phd work had been in,
in logic,
philosophy of science systemology,
so it was up to speed on the entire
history of a log from the modern world
on blue things are the way things were
in the eighties and early nineties.
So I was reading the same people that
were already had,
I have to say I've learned an enormous
amount from reading Richard Rorty.
He's first rate even though I ended up
disagreeing fundamentally everything,
uh,
who goes phd also was in philosophy.
He also a phd in psychology.
There's another philosophy,
Phd Realtor,
another philosophy phd,
so not necessarily put myself on the
same stature right intellectually,
but,
uh,
all of the so to speak or first grade
educated,
any piss demolished,
so I know where they're coming from and
where all of that is going at the same
time.
Uh,
my,
uh,
my undergraduate and master's degree at
Grove,
just down the road from you,
uh,
in a,
in history of philosophy.
So a long standing passion for how
arguments and movements develop over
time.
Uh,
so,
uh,
I thought I had,
it was in a good position to see how
postmodernism have evolved out of
various other earlier movements that had
developed over time and I am enough of a
political animal to be interested in
political philosophy and I believe that
abstract philosophical theory when it
puts it,
gets put into practice,
make life and death practical
differences.
So the stakes are high.
Uh,
so it was motivated then to put it all
together.
How does the history and the philosophy
and the politics all come together in.
And so,
so I wrote the book now a yeah.
How it has affected me personally in an
academic life.
Well,
let me see.
I think in one way I think I was
fortunate that I had tenure by the time
the book was published and my university
is a vital,
larger tolerant case.
We have some,
some issues here,
but by and large my colleagues on a
reasonable decent people,
uh,
and uh,
I was able to get tenure on the strength
of my teaching abilities and my,
my publication.
Um,
so it wasn't that I was going to lose my
job right over this fracture.
First areas,
there's blow back.
I did have difficulty getting the book
published right in the first place.
Actually I finished writing the book by
the year 2000.
I had taken a sabbatical from 1999 to
2010.
I was not able to get the book published
until 2004.
And a reason for that was a number of
desk rejections.
You know,
the editor sends a form letter back for
very few of those,
but more seriously what happened three
times,
possibly four times,
I don't remember exactly now was that
would get past the,
uh,
the,
the editor at the press and then it
really sent out to two or three
reviewers.
And in each case what happened was I
would get split and poor I slipped a
review for at one would come back and
say,
yeah,
this is a really good book.
You've done his homework.
It's a good argument,
is a fresh argument.
Don't necessarily agree with all of it,
but this really ought to be out there
right as a book.
And then the other review or the other
two reviews on the other side would be a
equally savaging at this terrible book,
or he doesn't know his history of
philosophy.
He butchered the sat or act or the other
thing and I strongly recommend that you
don't like publishes books.
And then almost always in that
situation,
the,
uh,
the editor just said no.
So it wasn't until 2000 and I guess late
2003 a or few thousand for a scholar,
ged,
which was at a small press working out
of Arizona,
uh,
took the book on.
And I'm happy to say that to accurate
published.
It's an imprint consistently since then.
So remarkable.
Just remarkable how many book,
let alone an academic book and then
multiple translations and those
continue.
So,
so,
so I'm happy about that now to say the
scholar and the responses have been from
the moderate liberal,
also kind of traditional the one who
used the word necessarily traditional,
but the rational,
naturalistic liberal right thinkers,
uh,
conservatives and libertarians that
reviews have all been strong,
strongly positive or not received any
formal reviews from any of the
postmodern for or far left journals.
So I'm not sure what that means,
but there is a,
at least some level of unwillingness to
engage with might be a sign of respect.
Well,
there is one sign of respect that comes
out and that is that every,
let's say once a year,
so probably a dozen times since the book
has been published,
I've been asked by the editor of a
postmodern foreclose fellow traveler,
a critical theory type of journal to be
a second reviewer right on one of your
articles.
So I'm in their Rolodex,
so to speak.
We use the old fashioned label has that
when they are actually looking for
someone who's likely to give an
objective but critical respect
perspective on some articles to be
submitted to the journal once in a while
my name floats up and they'll send it
out to me.
So I'll just do the standard thing of
reading it and getting my mindset,
my professional opinion on that.
So I think when they are aware of me,
but there hasn't really been any direct
intellectual engagement.
Kind of sad.
When you set yourself up to write the
book,
were you thinking of writing a critique
of postmodernism or,
or were you thinking of conducting an
exploration of postmodernism?
Right now I'm working on the critique or
the,
the book ends,
uh,
I don't want to say abruptly because it
did set out the purpose of.
It does,
but it doesn't end with the door open,
right.
To say how then do we respond to a,
this is this dead end of counter
enlightenment thought or in
postmodernism are.
So we're at a point culture.
We were that the meaning of
postmodernism has now it's infected the
academy.
And we see problems there,
but it's also left the academy and so
for people outside the academy are
seeing results.
And so the big question is what do we do
next?
So,
so I am actively working on the sequel
to,
uh,
to explaining postmodernism now.
And I did go back and forth in the
writing.
My first purpose was to write a straight
diagnosis and intellectual history of
postmodernism.
And uh,
that's where I ended up leaving it
because in one sense this is a bit
artificial,
but I really liked 200 page books.
It's a kind of long enough for you to
get into a subject deeply enough and to
make a good point in integrated argument
and then stop.
And so I realized if I wrote the sequel
then it would be a 400 page book.
And I thought it was more important to
get this self contained intellectual
history of postmodernism out there.
So I brought things to a logical
conclusion right where I ended the book
and,
and now I'm working on
which the next one called just as a,
the working title of something.
And it changes every year,
every few months,
right?
Or,
or,
so sometimes I think about it,
the fate of the enlightenment or
something to do with the neo
enlightenment,
uh,
or it won't be this,
but post postmodernism or after
postmodernism something.
Yeah,
we've been struggling with terminology
as well.
Absolutely.
Talking about with such things.
And it's a very hard thing to do because
it's a,
as we've seen Phyllis philosophically,
right?
Postmodernism is multidimensional.
It's a metaphysical critique,
it's informative critique,
it's a political critique,
it's an epistemological right set of
views.
And so the alternative then also has to
be integrated philosophical.
There has to be an entire prosoft
package.
And so what,
uh,
what label is going to capture all of
that,
uh,
and at the same time make a connection
to postmodernism.
And also,
uh,
I'm,
I'm basically an optimistic positive
guy.
So I want something that,
that has a as a way forward.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
Make it a better place.
Right?
Right.
Exactly.
So,
look,
I think an hour and a half interview is
approximately the equivalent of a 200
page book.
So why don't we,
why don't we end with that and what I
would like to propose is that we have
another discussion in a couple of months
about what you're thinking about with
regards to what you're writing.
Now.
We've covered the intellectual
territory.
We've covered the historical territory
and done a reasonable reasonably good
job,
I think of both justifying posts,
postmodernism in this discussion and
also pointing out its pitfalls and
dangers.
We haven't outlined a much for an
alternative vision except making
tangential reference to the potency of
individual capacity.
That seems to be.
That would seem to be reasonable grounds
for the next discussion.
So
the next time we chat,
right talking about the current culture
war issues,
you know,
one of the things I'm very interested in
is younger people in particular who are
in the front lines in universities,
so to speak,
and they're surrounded in a bewildered
and angry and in some cases intimidated
by all of
the microaggressions and so forth and
the indoctrination of getting.
But I'm actually kind of glad that we
didn't talk about the political end of
it today because it enabled us to have a
conversation that was almost entirely
philosophical in nature and I really
think that's the right,
that's the right level of analysis
because the battle that's occurring in
our culture is actually occurring at a
philosophical level and there's other
levels as well.
But that's,
that's,
that's even more important than the
political level as far as I'm concerned.
Well said.
I agree 100 percent nicely.
Right.
Well it was a pleasure speaking with
you.
Is very much worthwhile or do you have a
remarkable capacity for tracking the
content of conversations and on point.
So that's quite amazing to see because
we did branch out and a lot of different
directions more or less similar
caneously it was quite helpful in
keeping the chorus on track that you
could so rapidly organized the,
you know,
it was almost like you're putting a
paragraph structure in the conversation,
ask occurred.
So that was something that was really
interesting to see.
So anyways,
it was a pleasure meeting you and thanks
very much for talking with me and I'll
obviously input recommend book like.
Sorry,
go ahead.
I want to say much respect for the work
you're doing.
Thanks for having me on your show.
Be Happy to talk again.
Great,
good.
We'll set that up right.
Thanks Jordan.
Bye.