Right,
no,
it
was like,
ha
ha ha,
please reasonable opposition.
It's best to let the unreasonable
opposition speak because they manifest
themselves as unreasonable and then
everyone can see it.
So that's part of the reason that you
want free speech because you want
people.
Oh
well,
at least the last,
the back
leg,
Dr Peterson.
No one's security can't help no matter
what their job,
no matter what they do,
they're wrong.
They're wrong.
Cause trouble for any students,
no matter who the students are,
what you're doing
there.
Just about horse take care of
themselves.
All right,
so I can tell you a little bit about why
I opposed to build seasick and there's a
variety of reasons.
I think the most,
isn't it?
It's the first piece of Canadian
legislation that's ever been put forward
but actually requires people to use the
particular center works.
Now there is other legislation that does
govern to some degree what you can't
say.
So for example,
you can't incite and crime and that's
perfectly logical,
reasonable restriction on free speech,
but we've never had a piece of
legislation ever that would require you
to use a certain kind of vocabulary and
regardless of what it is and the fact
that it happens to be about
transgendered terminology hypothetically
is almost beside the point as far as I'm
concerned,
it's all focused on this,
on a focused,
on this particular issue to focus on
some issue,
but this isn't the issue that's at the
bottom of it.
It's just that complex things manifest
themselves in very particular locations
and this just happens to be the location
that this is manifesting itself here.
Now the other thing that I really didn't
like it still don't like about bill cc
is the surrounding policies that are
basically part of what it's embedded in
that were produced by the Ontario Human
Rights Commission,
which I think is an appallingly
dangerous organization,
not at least because they're terribly
muddy thinkers.
One of the things,
one of the things that's happened,
but I think from a psychological
perspective,
is there anyone terrio soon likely in
Canada.
We're going to write into law an idea of
identity.
It's just radically insufficient.
So let me give you some examples.
So the way that bill see 16 is currently
coordinated.
If you take into account the surrounding
policy documents,
there's a.
there's a proposition embedded in the
law and that is that biological sex,
gender identity,
gender expression and sexual preference
vary independently and the fact of the
matter is that's not true and you can
demonstrate it very straightforwardly.
The first thing you observed is that
virtually everyone whose biological sex
is either male or female,
has a gender identity of male or female.
In fact,
the the people who go into that
category,
they exist.
There's no doubt about that,
but they're very small minority.
The reason I'm pointing out with the
minority because makes the claim that
those things very independently
and then you know to that most of the
people who have a binary biological sex
and the binary gender identity also
present themselves in a manner that's
the same as their gender identity in
their biological sex.
And so that's another indication of the
non independence of the three layers of
purported identity.
And finally,
you can see too that the vast majority
of people,
for example,
men who are biologically male,
who present themselves as male or who
identify as male present themselves at
male,
are also heterosexual.
Ninety five percent of the perhaps 98
percent of them depends on the
statistics,
but we don't want
those.
That event now,
I think he is on top
anyways.
The reason that I think that this is a
problem is because it's written into the
law and the law isn't the place where
you debate those sorts of things.
You don't instantiate a particular
philosophy into the law,
especially one that's predicated on what
I would say it's.
It's absolutely incoherent and not only
that,
like even if you're thinking about it
from the perspective of someone say
who's who's homosexual.
One of the arguments that people who are
gay very frequently used,
if there's actually the biological
underpinning to their homosexuality,
what we're going to dispense with that,
but what happens if we dispense with
that?
What happens if we dispense with the
idea that there's a biological
underpinnings of homosexuality that mean
that it can just be changed and what are
people gonna do with that piece of
information except trying to change it.
The people who are who've been fighting
for homosexual rights for the last 30
years very frequently made the case that
the reason that the rights were
necessary was because there was a
reality to the condition.
Well,
I'm not arguing for that or against it.
What saying is that the law,
the way it's currently constituted makes
arguments like that completely invalid.
It does the same thing with
transsexuality and which are we don't
know enough about to.
We don't know enough about it to
determine,
say it's its manner of causal origins
now it looks to me like,
like I think it's premature to exclude a
biological component and especially
because of what we know about how gender
identity and biological sex are
instantiated in utero.
So we know
it's an apple,
that
the standard human fetus has a female
morphology.
It doesn't matter whether take six weeks
and then it's transformed into a male
morphology
with testosterone.
Right,
so
the reason I tell them,
you
save your breath,
we got all night.
The reason that I'm telling you this is
because
there's no reason.
There's no reason whatsoever you can
presume that the laws are being put in
place to protect the people that these
laws are supposed to protect.
Anything that remotely
and as I mentioned when we were in the
hall,
talk to you about the letters that I've
received from sexual abuse,
terrifying about all of this.
The vast majority of them don't want to
be as invisible as everyone else wants
to be.
Noisily
by people who want to speak for them.
So
one of the things we really have to get
over in a serious idea that just because
you're talking to someone black or white
or color,
you're a member of a homogenous try and
get the opinion that they happened to
have the opinion that all those who are
like them,
there's nothing that's more racist than
that assumption
and I can predict everything that you
are and everything that you think.
Lots of terrible thing to believe and
it's awesome.
Patently untrue.
You know,
there's no reason to assume that any
group of people who don't fit into
traditional society for some rea or any
more homogenous in their general makeup
and your political views than any other
group.
In fact,
all evidence suggests precisely
so.
Another thing I really don't like about
it.
Talk
about why it's important to be able to
have this discussion.
Well,
I can tell.
I can tell you
these
tends to shut people down or being made
because you need to know this.
So
as far as I've been able to determine,
this kind of protest is an expression of
a philosophy that's grounded partly in
postmodernism.
Pardon me and Marxism.
The postmodern element is basically
this.
There was no such genuine individual
identity is this identity and you liked
it or not only have the interests of
your group and the whole world is
nothing but a battle ground between
groups of different interests.
There's no dialogue,
there's no parking between the groups.
It's just a power stage.
Combat has to take place,
and so the reason that speakers with
whom the radical postmodernists and the
Marxists don't agree or deny the
platform was because most people do not
believe from a philosophical position.
The dialogue can bring consensus and all
that's left.
If you forgo that particular principle,
this is only where it start.
You know the fact that you're all pretty
damn setting.
Thank God for that because if there were
enough fools in the crowd,
especially those who are intent on
violence,
this would turn out very differently.
We do not want to go down that pathway.
It's a big mistake.
We've been down that pathway many,
many years.
I would certainly not conformed to a
consensus that was against my belief
merely because it was a consensus in the
group is wrong.
The question was,
if there was a consensus against my
beliefs,
what are you going with them and answer
that would be well first it would depend
on what my conscience said.
What are we going to assume that the
consensus is correct?
The Nazis had a consensus,
right?
The individual has a conscience and you
have to know when the group is made a
mistake.
Jordan talked a lot in your personality
clause,
very confronting your shadow,
your shadow.
Do you find that people who care less
about what other people think and care
more about their conscience have
integrated their shadow maybe more than
people who care more about others?
Can you hear me at all?
So there was a question.
The question wise stemming from my
personality class,
I think that people are willing to abide
by their are those who have integrated
their shadow and I would say yes because
you have to be a bit of a monster to
stand up to the crowd,
right?
If you're too concerned with people to
you and if you're to avoid conflict,
then you're going to cave to pressure
and you don't want to do that because if
you let people stop you from moving
forward,
you just end up being something.
And if you have someone who stopped,
you've got no life in you and that's no
good.
So you have to get tough,
but you have to give tough in a way
that's controlled,
right?
It has to be controlled because
otherwise you're the puppet of your
worst impulses and that's a terrible
thing to be.
Pinocchio.
Other questions?
The question was,
we called the police and had them
removed.
Would've that been a failure?
I think the answer is no.
There's no reason to assume that this is
a bad thing.
It's noisy and it's annoying,
but that's fine.
You got to let things go to follow what
you believe to be true.
Don't worry about it,
and then let things happen and see what
happens because it's perfectly possible
that if you're trying to do the right
thing and you're trying to say that
whatever happens around you
and then it's a good thing.
So we'll see.
We'll have weeks after this event to
analyze its consequences and so far all
of those of you that are there to listen
to me talk,
you're peaceful and reasonable and you
got a chance to show that to hundreds of
thousands of people.
This is a good thing.
Not a bad thing.
How do we get these people to understand
the dialogue needs to consensus
cannot make people who don't listen,
listen,
they have to decide to listen,
but you do that by listening,
engage in dialogue and softened contract
consensus among you.
You live by example because there's no
getting through this.
It's an ideological war and the harder
you push against it,
don't worry about it,
but don't.
Don't get pushed around and don't let
people in
doctrinaire.
There's clearly a liberal left bias on
campuses.
The documentation is very clear.
If you go online and watch Jonathan
Heights' videos,
he explains it.
Partly.
The reason for that is that people are
higher in openness.
A trait are more likely to go to
university and into academia,
so there is some trait reasons,
but over the last 30 years he's become
overwhelmingly left wing.
Take your club.
You know you're not under the control of
the professors at university.
You're here to educate yourself.
Some professors will
help
yourself as you
want to know about
the peach.
Don't enroll in the
humanities paper
citations.
We also have no idea how widespread this
sort of thing is.
Maybe two or three percent,
very tiny minority,
but very well organized,
very noisy.
So the other thing you have to
organize yourself,
you
get your damn arguments together,
pushed back
against them.
You're pushing,
but that's you're
someone who's articulate
so that you learn how to
make
powerful and that's what universities
articulates.
So the question is,
I've made a good idea to let your
questionnaires,
what happened,
guide you.
I'm not going to happen
and you want to rely on.
You have to make sure that
I
apologize.
You're
speak to you properly.
Internal Guide,
post.
You have to be honest because otherwise
that's a terrible mistake.
So the reason that you don't lie
against
pathological,
if
you
can't trust yourself,
then you can have your political
or you can have nothing and neither of
those things are reasonable.
Replacements
went
really well.
Are
you
a
chance to talk to has
cut into video?
A
big fan,
big fan
out there is a chance to talk to him.