It's graduation is highly significant
for young people because it is a death
and a renewal at the same time.
I mean,
it's a good way of learning too about
life because you see when you graduate
at simultaneously,
you have attained the pinnacle of
something,
but by the same token,
it instantly transforms you into a
beginner at the next stage of your life.
When people say,
what do you want to be when they grow up
in our society,
they usually mean what career you're
going to pick.
It's really not the way the question
should be asked or conceptualize.
You should really think about what sort
of character you want to have.
I would say you should surround yourself
with people who are aiming up at,
who want the best for what's best in
you.
Unless you want people that will excuse
your pathologies and make weight for
your weakness and lead you down the path
of perdition,
so you're going to take care of
yourself.
You need to take care of your family.
You're going to take care of your
community.
You want to grow up and be a
responsible,
forthright and honest person.
It's the best way through life.
There could be a lot more to you than,
you know,
highly probable,
and you should act as if there is,
and then you should go out there and try
to do,
if not great things,
at least honest,
productive,
meaningful,
engaged,
and positive things.
That's what you should be aiming.
There's nothing in that except good.
Okay.