Have asked me some questions about the
exam.
There's not much to say.
Most of the descriptions listed on the
syllabus,
it be in this class.
Um,
my idol regard my exams is particularly
tricky.
So if you come to the lectures and done
the reading and he,
people generally do,
you know as well in this class as they
do in other classes,
maybe a little bit better.
So it's all multiple choice
and you won't run out of time.
So I don't,
that's about all there is to say.
There are sample questions posted on the
website so you can go there and see what
the questions are going to light.
Um,
I just select the dem random lead from
questions I've used before,
so they're representative of what you're
going to see.
So,
all right,
so
back to Sigmund Freud.
So I found a recording of Freud.
I think it's the only known recording.
It's from a BBC broadcast.
Um,
not too long before he died,
fall.
Play it.
You can listen along or we long because
he has a pretty heavy accent,
so it's somewhat difficult to
follow.
Ooh,
I don't remember
why
was
it
few introductory comments to this
lecture.
It's hard to imagine the degree to which
Freud re-introduce,
biological or introduced biological
ideas into the study of the human
psyche.
Because by the time Freud came along,
most of the formal thought about thought
and about the human,
uh,
human psychology was very influenced by
enlightenment ideas.
And so there was a
relatively widespread belief that people
were rational and scientific and
becoming increasingly more so.
And perhaps people were becoming
increasingly more so.
But Freud put the biology back in
psychology.
I mean,
he was a medical doctor and he was
trained as a neurologist and he was also
part of a,
I like burgeoning interest in placing
human beings firmly in that category of
the Animal Kingdom that was
characteristic of the late 19 hundreds,
particularly in relationship to Darwin
and was Freud who most particularly
established the fact that our
rationality is in some sense nested
inside our motivations and emotions and
our unconscious mind.
And
I think there's no doubt that those
claims are correct.
Um,
psychologists have always had an animus
towards Freud.
Um,
it's not exactly clear why he was a
psychiatrist.
He was a medical doctor.
So maybe that's part of it.
Maybe it's the distinction between the
different professions.
Um,
but I also have this proclivity to
believe that psychologists tend more
towards the type of person who's
convinced that the primary activities
that characterize human,
the human psyche are our rational
cognitive.
And,
and we certainly have fried to think in
large part for making a strong case that
that's not not true.
You'll encounter lots of psychologists
who
do their best in some sense to push
freud to one side and consider his
theories outdated and unproven.
And you know,
I don't really think that's fair,
partly because
the literature regarding psychoanalysis
as an effective treatment seems to
indicate quite clearly that it's as at
least as or more effective than other
psychotherapeutic schools.
And it's basically showed that since
outcome studies of cycle psychotherapy
have been conducted,
so that's three or four decades.
Hmm.
Um,
I don't know if there are gender
differences.
I'd actually different looked into that
with regards to outcome studies.
I don't think there's there
substantative so cause I've never heard
much made of them.
Now the other,
the other issues that Freud described,
for example,
that much of our psychological life is
unconscious
and much of it is motivated by what are
both implicit memory.
So memories we don't really realize that
we have anymore or basic biological
drives that seems to me to be
unquestioned.
Um,
30 years ago a little more than that,
psychologists rediscovered the
unconscious and they made a big fuss
about that.
But I have was well first at
psychoanalytic thinking by that time and
certainly didn't regard that as
particularly revolutionary because as
far as I could tell the psychoanalysts
had been there 60 years before.
In fact,
a lot of the experimental procedures
that psychologists use to examine the
unconscious are derived from the sorts
of Word Association studies,
Priming Studies in some sense that Carl
Young pioneer when he was still working
with Freud.
So we have a lot to thank Freud for.
And he also
introduced and developed the idea of
psychotherapy as something distinct from
medical treatment for mental disorders.
And you know,
I think there's room for a variety of
opinions about the overall social and
cultural utility of psychotherapy.
I've read interesting critiques making
the claim that it's reduced the
necessity for familial and friendship
ties,
for example,
as it's proliferated society,
but be that as it may all of the
psychotherapeutic fields that are
practically applied I think have freud
to thank for their founding.
So it seems a bit on the ungrateful side
to criticize him too harshly.
I've also found that Freud's
conceptualizations of certain pathways
to psychological pathology are
fundamentally correct and I'll discuss
those in a little bit more detail as we
proceed through today's lecture now
because the late 1900 is now a long time
ago.
It's useful to put Freud in his
historical context.
Um,
so this is partly history of psychology
I suppose,
but it also shed some light on how the
nature of psychiatric and psychological
disorders transform with time because
you know,
you tend to think of them as,
especially if you're more
scientifically oriented,
you tend to think of a disorder or an
illness as something that approximates a
scientific category.
But I think about illnesses,
diagnostic categories,
let's say is they're not precisely
scientific categories.
In fact,
they might not be scientific categories
at all.
They're informed by science sometimes.
And I would say increasingly as we
develop the diagnostics and statistics
manual,
which is the fundamental book that
outlands psychiatric and psychological
diagnosis,
particularly in North America,
but increasingly around the world,
science is being used to inform the
language that sits at the bottom of the
dimensions along which the pathologies
are defined.
So for example,
with regards to the personality
disorders,
there's increasing emphasis,
although not enough emphasis yet on
dimensional models such as the big five.
But you have to understand that medical
diagnostic categories serve a number of
purposes.
And you shouldn't get cynical about
this.
Often people start out by thinking about
diagnostic categories is scientific.
And then they soon find out that the
idea that their scientific can be
criticized on multiple different fronts
and quite severely.
Michel Foucault,
for example,
has done a lot of that.
Um,
and his works were regarded as
revolutionary by people who didn't know
anything about the history of
psychiatric disorders because most of
what he outlined was already known by
people who took the time to know,
hardly went through code line was the
fact that psychiatric diagnostic
categories like medical diagnostic
categories play a sociological and
political and economic role as well as a
scientific and treatment oriented role.
And that's part of it because as I
mentioned at the beginning of the
lecture series,
when you're attempting to move someone
from abnormality say,
or ill health towards normality or
health and the Noah's Ark precisely at
the same,
not precisely parallel lines there,
um,
you're doing a lot more than science.
You're also involved in athletics and
you can't help it.
And then,
you know,
you also have to think about why it is
that we have psychiatric diagnostic
categories,
for example.
And you know,
some of the critics of psychiatry,
especially in the 1960s,
regarded that as primarily an economic
or political movement that was designed
to categorize people who engaged in
abnormal behavior and to,
and to prevent them from exercising
their full rights.
In society.
No,
because it was thought of as a purely
oppressive
enterprise.
Now all you have to do is take a walk
around Toronto and see all the d
institutionalized schizophrenia ix
wandering around and enjoying their
freedom to understand that the
description of psychiatry as a purely
tyrannical rural pressive sociological
regime has a lot to account for because
those people were Ddd,
institutionalized in the late sixties
and early seventies and the institutions
have never been rebuilt.
And all that happened was that they were
dumped on the streets where they
generally stop taking your medication
and survived very poorly.
So even if psychiatry plays a
sociological and political and economic
role,
don't be thinking that,
that it validates it as an enterprise
just me and said it's a very complex
enterprise that has to span multiple
dimensions of,
it stands on many different
philosophical and scientific foundations
now,
psychiatric diagnostic categories and
the symptomatology that's associated
with them also transforms with time.
And that's kind of a strange thing,
especially if you think about
psychiatric ill health as a biological
phenomenon.
But the language transforms across time
too.
And it's grounded in biology.
And the truth of the matter is that
nothing that human beings do or
experience exists in a cultural vacuum.
So for example,
when I was young,
Carmen,
schizophrenia delusions,
especially for the paranoid
schizophrenia,
was that the TV was talking to them.
Now obviously they didn't have that
delusion in 1920 because there weren't
any televisions.
So by the time it was saying 1930 it
wouldn't be in the radio.
And now the most common focus of
paranoia is the internet.
And there's some reasons for that
because even if the TV wasn't spying on
you,
the Internet probably is.
So that's a simple example showing how
cultural transformation can change the
content and send the phenomenology
that's associated with a given
psychiatric disorder.
So you can take them to them as being
characterized by some combination of
biology,
biological pathology,
historical pathology,
pathology that's limited to the
individual's experience.
And then you can think of it that all as
nested inside a given cultural context,
which in itself may be pathological or
normative.
And so it's the interplay of all those
factors that makes understanding mental
illness and diagnostic categories are
very challenging enterprise,
especially when you also add to that the
necessity for social control,
which would be the political and
economic dimension,
and then also for intervention at the
individual level.
Because one of the things you want to
ask yourself as well,
what serves society better?
Society served better by putting people
who are completely unable of adopting
normative behavior and who may be
disruptive and frightening somewhere
where they cannot disturb the bulk of
the population.
So that's question number one.
The answer of that is all not.
Obviously that's a mistake.
Now,
it may be a mistake and it certainly
would be a mistake in some cases,
but you can't just simply say that it's
a mistake all the time because you want
to be able to walk around on the streets
relatively on harassed and free of fear
to not an unreasonable desire for a
civilized society.
Then the next question,
or maybe even the first question might
be,
well,
do these institutions help the
individuals with whom they're directly
interacted?
And then the right answer to that is
compared to what?
Because compared to perfect,
the answer is no,
but compared to no help whatsoever,
the answer is probably yes.
And so it's also worthwhile to be useful
in your,
or to be realistic in your expectations.
So for example,
most people who are schizophrenia don't
like to take their psychiatric
medication.
And the reason for that is because
antipsychotic medications,
which were only really popularized at
the end of the 1950s work on the
biological axis,
the dopaminergic system that produces
positive emotion.
And so if you take an anti psychotic,
it's going to flatten out your positive
emotion and demotivate,
motivate you and sort of take the color
out of your life.
And you can imagine that that's not very
music.
And then of course if you take them and
you start to feel better and maybe
you're feeling better for three or four
months or six months or a year,
you're going to be thinking,
well,
maybe I kept her and then you're going
to stop taking them.
So if you ask a schizophrenia very
frequently about their medication,
they'll say,
well,
they're not very happy to be taking it,
and they'd like to quit as soon as they
can.
But that does not necessarily mean that
the medication is not
okay
doing something that's beneficial.
It just means that the best they can
hope for is not very good.
And that doesn't point directly to a
flaw in the system that's dealing with
them.
It just points to the terrible nature of
the disease and it's fundamentally
intractable qualities.
Okay,
so back to front.
So that now a lot of what Freud saw was
sexual pathology.
Now you might ask yourself why.
Well,
the first thing we could point out is
that when Freud was alive,
society was very highly divided by
gender,
was divided by gender roles and man's
were authorities and women's were by and
large subordinate.
Although
that situation is more complex than a
simple reading of history might lead you
to conclude.
So for example,
if you read tolstoy's novels
characterizing Russian society in the
late 1900 you find out that among the
aristocratic women and after all only
the aristocrats have power,
there was plenty of power being
exercised.
The women essentially structured
society,
men were involved in politics and they
were involved in war,
but women were setting up the social
interactions that characterize the bulk
of of society
in their groups and in there and then
their own interactions.
So it's not clear who was doing what
when.
What is clear though is that in the
Victorian times,
sex was a lot more dangerous for women
than it is now and it's plenty dangerous
now.
A,
there was no reliable form of birth
control.
That's a big problem.
And B,
there was tremendous risk of syphilis
and selfless for all intensive purposes
was as bad or is as bad or worse than
aids.
Now what's controllable now,
but it wasn't controllable then.
And syphilis could also be passed on to
children and it was a neurological
disease that could take virtually any
form.
So it was a real terror for European
society.
And so the reason that's a Europe that
the victorians were sort of repressive
in sexual matters was because of the
environment demanded it.
And we know and more research has been
done on this recently.
It's fascinating research.
We know that as the rate of contagious
pathogen in the environment increases,
the degree to which is society becomes
authoritarian increases and very
rapidly.
In fact,
there's recent data showing that it was
a paper published just a few months ago
showing that the correlation between
infectious prevalence in a given
geographical locale and authoritarian
political views held by the individuals
in that locale approaches 0.7 which is
absolutely phenomenal.
It's such a high correlation that it,
it,
it almost eats up all of the
relationship.
And so as the risk of infectious disease
rises,
people become less and less tolerant in
there.
Um,
views on interpersonal behavior and a
lot of back scoring can be associated
with sexual behavior cause that's a very
good vector for the transmission of
disease.
We should remember that,
you know,
if we hadn't been so technologically
advanced in the 1980s,
well first of all,
age wouldn't have spread because it
spread because of air travel.
But apart from that you don't,
age could have taken us all out.
It was just luck of the draw and
technological power that enabled us to
keep it under control.
And you know,
there's no reason to assume that another
sexually transmissible play like age
won't come along.
So does that price promiscuity increases
the rate at which sexually transmissible
diseases are transmitted rises
exponentially.
Right.
And in a connected world,
that's bad news.
So my point is the Friday and the
victorians had their reasons to be
relatively repressive from a sexual
perspective.
Um,
there was another problem too,
which for women in particular,
which was that
yeah,
apart from the danger of pregnancy and
the danger of sexually transmitted
disease,
there was also the danger of the
destruction of their social reputation.
And so if a woman got a reputation for
um,
promiscuity at any level,
the probability that she was going to be
tossed out of her sociological niche
into some God awful life of prostitution
for example,
was really quite high.
So now,
so that sets up the sociological,
what would you call it?
This,
the sociological surround.
You don't repress something unless
engaging in it has high cost.
And certainly for the Victorian sexual
behavior was a high cost enterprise,
especially for the women.
And so freud,
given Freud's emphasis on biological
motivation
and given his,
his belief that section sexual drive was
a fundamentally,
what's one of the fundamental biological
motivations?
You can see that the stage is set for in
some sense for it,
no amount of conflict.
Now the conflict.
So I'm already there.
When you were a child,
say of 11 or 10
you exist in a world where the demand or
even the desire for engaging in sexual
behavior is low.
But as soon as puberty kicks in,
things changed dramatically.
Then the child was faced with a problem
of integrating the new demand that's
placed on them by the maturation of
their body into their personality and an
end to the social surround.
And that's no simple matter when there's
genuine conflicts between its expression
and other important considerations like
social propriety and health,
for example,
or maybe medium to longterm relationship
stability or maybe the provision of a
safe place to raise children,
et cetera.
So that's the situation that the
[inaudible] or the victorians found
themselves in.
Now,
Freud believed that many of the patients
that he saw,
the female patients had been sexually
abused or molested as children.
He wavered in that belief throughout his
life and has been called to task rather
severely for that by more current
critics.
But Freud was one of the first observers
of the extreme malleability of memory.
And he found it very difficult when he
was interacting with his clients,
especially the ones who are more
hysterical in,
in their essential orientation to
distinguish between memories that they
had made up or fantasies and things that
actually happened to them.
And until you encounter someone who's
memory structure is extremely incoherent
and chaotic,
it's almost impossible to realize to
what degree people can wonder around in
the world with no sense whatsoever of
what's happened to them.
So for example,
I had a client at one point who told me
that she thought she had been raped five
times.
And so the first thing you might know if
you heard a statement like that is that
the word thought is a very peculiar
insertion in that sentence because it's
not exactly all that straightforward to
understand how you would have any doubt
about that if it happened five times.
So she was a very strange woman,
and she was a person who was very much
like someone Freud would have described
in the late 19th century as a hysteric.
She had virtually no catalyzed identity.
She was,
as far as I could tell,
almost completely hollow in that none of
the things that have ever happened to
her see you have been processed beyond
the mere fact that they occurred and I
think that a big part of that was
because she didn't really ever have
anyone to talk to.
And one of the things that's emerged as
a consequence of Freud's work in part is
a realization of the degree to which
communication about your experiences is
advantageous or even necessary in the
maintenance of mental health.
Now,
Freud believed that
you needed to talk about experiences
that were particularly emotionally
significant part in it because it was
necessary to release or or ab react the
emotions that were associated with the
experience he called that Catharsis more
recent research,
particularly on like that and done by
James Pennebaker has indicated that it's
actually the articulation of those
experiences,
the verbalization and their
transformation into a coherent
representation that seems to be
beneficial for mental health rather than
the mere expression of it
motion.
But
just because Freud was only partially
right about why his method worked
doesn't mean he was wrong about the fact
that it did work.
Now this woman
was unemployed and had been for years,
although she dressed in a business suit
and she had talked her way into hosting
a cable television show in the town I
was working with in,
in the city I was working in.
That was a program about fostering the
entrepreneurial spirit even though she
was unemployed and it never started a
business in her life and she has also
talked her way on to a government board
that was charged with investigating the
development of a high speed rail lake in
southern Ontario even though she had
absolutely no experience whatsoever with
business or railways,
so she had a reasonably well developed
persona from a union perspective.
I asked her at one point to show me her
resume and she brought me in a binder.
You know those three ring binders that
was an inch and a half thick with those
little tab dividers that you use to
segregate different sections of your cv
and in which she had included a 20 page
description of her recent dreams and a
discussion or a list of all the novels
she read in the last 10 years.
She was completely
okay,
incapable of noting that every single
thing about that cv was inappropriate
even though she didn't suffer from any
formal thought disorder.
She,
she wasn't schizophrenia or a psychotic
in any way.
With regards to the rape statement,
she told me that what happened to her
frequently was that she would go to a
bar in her vague and ill defined way and
she'd have a few drinks or maybe more
than a few and then she'd end up back in
her place with some mat or at his place
and then that night they would have
sexual relations and then in the morning
she was unclear about whether or not
that was voluntary.
Now this was a fascinating case for me
because she outlined that story to be
in.
At this point,
I have become somewhat familiar with the
danger of therapists,
manipulation of patient memories because
therapists can implant,
so to speak,
memories in clients,
but it's very,
very complicated because when you're
dealing with someone who's as chaotic
and vague as this particular person was,
it's virtually impossible not to implant
memories just by talking about them.
So here's,
so I thought,
she told me the story and I thought,
okay,
I have a chance to reorganize this
woman's entire concept,
conception of her past sexual
experiences by uttering a variety of
sentences.
So I could have said,
well,
unless you give express consent to each
stage of the sexual transaction,
then you're clearly being victimized and
your claim that you may have been raped
five times could be transformed into the
claim that you work.
Or it could have said,
are you completely out of your mind?
If you go to a bar and a single's bar by
yourself and you have six or seven
drinks or however many drinks you had
and you bring someone home or go to
their place and you end up in bed with
them and that happens five times,
then probably you have something to do
with it.
And making a claim of rape is observed
and then you might ask yourself which of
those opposing interpretations are
correct and it doesn't matter because I
did tell her either of them because it
was up to her to sort out exactly what
had happened.
Now,
it's not that easy to believe that
people like that exist,
but they do.
And she was someone who had never
reflected on any of her experiences.
She had no real articulated identity.
And a big part of that was because she
was completely isolated.
And so when Freud got confused about
whether his client's memories of sexual
trauma in childhood were accurate or
inaccurate,
the reason that he got confused was
because he was frequently dealing with
people who were confused right down to
the bottom of their souls and who for
one reason or another had never been
able to engage in the process of
articulation that would've allowed them
to established a well establish a well
differentiated identity.
The
texted I'm showing you in these slides
is based department work by book by a
man named Henry Henri.
Actually Ellen [inaudible],
who is an existentialist,
was an existentialist psychologist,
psychiatrist who lived in Montreal and
he wrote a book called the discovery of
the,
and if you're interested in
psychoanalytic thought and the history
of psychoanalytic thought,
that's the best book that's ever been
written.
It's called the discovery of the
unconscious.
Now the other thing Alan Bridgej points
out,
cause I paraphrased his book here,
is that punishments for transgressions
in the Victorian Times,
we're also fairly draconian.
And that also sets up the situation for
conflict.
No.
If you're driven by something that's a
very strong drive and you're liable to
encounter tremendous trouble as a
consequence of engaging in it,
it's not a very easy thing for you to do
to figure out how to negotiate that
particular landscape.
Alabama Shay says,
psychoanalysis evidently belongs to that
unmasking trend.
The search for hidden unconscious
motivations characteristic of the 1880s
and nineties in Freud as a nature,
words and deeds are viewed as
manifestations of unconscious
motivations,
mainly of instincts and conflicts have
instincts for both men.
The unconscious is the wild realm of the
wild bruce instincts that cannot find
permissible outlets that derive from
earlier stages of the individual and of
mankind and that find expression in
passion,
dreams,
and mental illnesses.
Even the term id does s originates from
nature.
The dynamic concept of mind with the
notions of mental energy,
Quanta of latent or inhibited energy or
release of energy or transfer from one
drive to another is also to be found in
nature.
Before Freud nature conceived the mind
as a system of drives that can collide
or be fused into each other.
Okay,
this is from
okay.
The life and work of Sigmund Freud by
Jones,
who was Freud's biographer
talking about the process that
resulted in Freud's hypothesis about the
unconscious.
John says in the summer of 1897 freud
undertook his most heroic feat.
A psychoanalysis of his own unconscious
is something that's akin in some sense
to the initiatory routines that I've
described for you at the beginning of
this course.
It's hard for us nowadays to imagine how
momentous this achievement was,
that difficulty being the fate of most
pioneering exploits.
Yet the uniqueness of the feet remains
once done.
It has done forever
for no one again,
can be the first to explore those depths
and the long history of humanity.
The task has often been attempted
philosophers and writers from Salon to
Montana,
from juvenile to show up and hire.
Schopenhauer had essay to follow the
advice of the delphic oracle know
thyself,
but all had succumb to the effort.
Inner had borrowed advance there had
from time to time being flashes of
intuition to point the way,
but they'd always flickered out the
realm of the unconscious whose existence
was so often postulated,
remained dark,
and the words of Hair Clyde is still
stood,
stood.
The soul of man is a far country which
cannot be approached or explored.
Freud had no hell no one to assist the
undertaking in the slightest degree,
worse than this,
the very thing that drove him onwards,
he must've definitely divine however
much he tried to conceal it from himself
could only result it profoundly
affecting his relations,
perhaps even severing them with the one
being who he was so closely bound and
who had steadied his mental equilibrium.
It was daring bunch and risking much
what courage,
intellectual and moral must've be
needed,
but it was forthcoming.
Now obviously Jones is a real admirer of
Freud
and he believed that
Freud's hypothesis emerged from a
careful analysis from Freud's careful
analysis of his own fantasies and drives
an unconscious life.
Okay.
The Friday and model divides the human
psyche and in a variety of different
ways,
the simplest of which is conscious and
unconscious and elman bear.
He points out that by 1,904 functions of
the unconscious had been described.
There's the conservative,
so that's memory,
that's memory,
so in some manner that we don't really
understand
your psyche is the storehouse of
representations of experiences that
you've had prior to today.
Now some of those are recallable as the
stories that constitute your experience.
Those would be the sorts of things that
come up in your mind is images,
maybe dreamlike images or movie like
images or stories that you can
explicitly tell people about your past
experiences where you're the actor in
those experiences.
There's also the elements of memory that
enabled you to do things like to speak
and you don't have conscious access to
how it is that you know how to speak or
for example,
how it is that you know how to ride a
bike.
That's more implicit forms of memory.
So that unconscious contains the
information or the skills or the
circuitry that enables you to engage in
complex motor acts that you've learned
to do.
Does alluded the unconscious contains
habits.
Those are,
those are the more procedural elements
that I,
that I just described and dissociated
elements of the personality which may
lead a parasitic existence.
Now that's an interesting idea.
So part of that's predicated the notion
that I showed you this hierarchy before.
Yes,
you've seen this before,
right?
So now you can imagine that when you're
watching,
when you're interacting with maybe your
father,
your mother,
your sister,
your great aunt,
or that there are chunks of their
personality that you incorporate into
yourself sort of from whole cloth that
maybe you're doing that in the PS Yeti
incense by imitating them and,
and so the and and that you're,
you're being is full of these
hierarchies are sub hierarchies,
each of which is devoted towards a
single per purpose or maybe singular
collection of purposes.
And that you can switch back and forth
between being dominated by one of these
or the other.
And some of them are more straight
forward,
like the state of perception and action
that might characterize you if you're
simply angry or if you're simply
possessed by sexual desire.
But the more complicated ones would be
those that make those who know you say
you're acting just like your mother now
or you're acting just like your father
now and what that means in the sense
from the [inaudible] perspective,
and I think as well from the Piagetian
and perspective that you've incorporated
huge subsets of the habits and
perceptual scheme is that make up the
people who were closest to you in your
developmental history.
Now Freud would believe that those
things can motivate you on unconsciously
in that for example,
you might be living out your parents
unconscious dreams or maybe you're
living out your parents unconscious
dreams that you'd be a bad child.
That happens very frequently.
I've seen families,
for example,
where a daughter was born instead of a
son to the great dissatisfaction of the
mother,
and the consequence of that was that
that child was essentially demonized
from day one and to the degree to which
that was precisely unconscious behavior.
On the part of the mother was debatable,
but certainly if you asked her if she
was out to destroy her child with every
action she ever cooked,
she would say no.
But if you watched her carefully across
months,
you would see that that was precisely
what she was doing.
Now you might ask,
well,
why would someone develop an attitude
like that?
And this particular person,
the mother had grown up in a culture
where boys were more valued than girls,
certainly within the confines of a given
family,
and she'd already had daughter.
So was that her?
Was that the culture?
Was it something that she picked up for
whom parents,
God only knows,
but with this free floating spirit in a
sense that happened to inhabit her and
shaped the way that she was interacting
with the world without her really
understanding what she was doing at an
articulated level at all.
In fact,
if you ever more or less confronted her
with the evidence that she was doing
such a thing,
she did out solutely everything you
could possibly to refuse to take any
ownership for that whatsoever or to
articulate it or even to conceive that a
human being might be capable of such a
thing,
even though the situation to her and
family made a polling look like a
vacation.
Okay.
Creative.
The unconscious serves as the Matrix of
new ideas.
Well,
here's an idea.
Where do your thoughts come from?
Well,
you know,
you say you think them up.
Well,
you know,
as far as black sexplanations goal,
that's a prime one.
There's,
what do you mean you think of them off
young,
pointed out.
That's not even accurate.
It's more like they appear in your
experience more or less.
Unbidden you know,
it's funny thing because you can
concentrate and that seems to facilitate
the process of the generation of new
ideas at least sometimes.
But most of the time it just seems like
you're standing in a room by yourself in
the dark and the thought comes.
And where does it come from?
Well.
The psychoanalytic explanation for that,
which is more of a description is tall.
It comes from the unconscious.
That is the unconscious that's producing
those Mytho poetic,
the unconscious constructs,
narratives and fantasies that appear
mythic or roulette,
religious in nature.
So what that means at least in part is
that some of the dissociated fragments
of personality say that inhabit you and
guide your actions are so ancient,
partly because of their biological basis
and part of that because of the ancient
historical overlay on top of that,
that they take the form of great myths
and stories that look like they're
common to everyone in one form or
another.
So for it,
I think a good example of that might be
the degree to which you are possessed by
the rivalry with your sibling,
which is one of the oldest stories that
no,
the man,
the individual members of mankind tell
it to one another because it's such a
common experience and because the manner
in which that experience is going to
manifest itself has been shaped by
cultural representation.
Freud was also very much convinced that
the mind was a composite of
contradictory drives.
This is a very interesting proposition
and I think one that's true.
I think you can,
you can see it most particularly if you
consider the behavior of two year olds
and as I've already discussed with you,
if you watch a two year old,
they rapidly cycle from one intensely
motivated state to another.
And I think I'm reasonable way of
conceptualizing that is that much of the
underlying biology of the two year old
is already in place in terms of it's his
or her fundamental motivations.
Two year old can be hungry in a two year
old can be hot or colder,
uncomfortable in a variety of different
ways or feel pain or feel anxiety or
feel joy or feel exhilaration.
Your curiosity,
your surprise,
all that circuitry is there,
but it's not integrated at a higher
level into a functioning personality.
Because in part what the functioning
personality is is a collective agreement
among all those fundamental drives as to
which is going to take priority when and
under what conditions and the
integration of that with the entire
broader cultural meal.
You.
So,
for example,
by the time your two year old is for,
you would expect them to be able to rate
self regulate,
which means when they step into a
particular circumstance,
they should be able to determine which
of their motivational states is going to
be allowed to manifest itself.
We would think about that as a form of
learned inhibition,
even though it's really not,
it's more like the integration of those
motivated states into a higher order
game where each of them gets a chance to
express themselves,
but only in a particular order and only
under particular circumstances.
And then of course the four year old has
to have learned to do that in the
presence of other children and in the
presence of other adults.
So that that fundamental motivational
structures are integrated into a higher
order structure that allows everybody to
get along just fine and for everyone to
pursue the things that they need to
pursue.
And so
part of the reason you might think that
you have a cortex is so that you can
take the more fundamental elements of
your drives,
which you could think of as part of the
Friday and Ed,
which means it.
It's the thing that in you isn't you.
It's the things that you're subject to
from within.
The reason that you have a cortex in
many ways is so that you can figure out
how to integrate those complex states of
being that,
that keep you alive in some fundamental
sense into a society that's
characterized by hundreds or thousands
of other creatures trying to do the same
thing at the same time.
And so you can imagine that that
requires particular adaptation to the
particulars of this society and that and
the more general functions of the,
of the deep end.
So the unconscious is partly the end,
which is this collection of drives,
Freud concentrated mark mostly on the
sexual drives and the aggressive drives
because those are,
or instincts,
the sexual instincts and they're
aggressive instincts.
It's a better term that drive because
those are the most difficult to
integrate into the surrounding social
male you because sex for example is a
pretty selfish act.
It isn't an altruistic act in any
sentence and in some sense it's also a
zero sum game.
You're in competition with everyone else
for your success at that particular
game.
You can say the same thing about
aggression,
especially if you think about it in
relationship to dominance,
hierarchy striving because there are
very few positions in any given
dominance hierarchy that are at the talk
and so in some ways the competition is
zero sum and it's every person against
every other person,
but well that's happening.
You have to keep the dominance hierarchy
itself in place,
right?
Because there's no sense in destroying
the structure that you're trying to
climb and so fried points of considered
constantly that this is a very,
very difficult process of integration.
He also points out that in some sense,
the way that people solve that problem
is not by integrating.
What they do instead is rip press.
Now repression has two elements.
One might be,
and this is maybe more what's dealt with
by cognitive behavioral psychologist,
one form of repression is you just don't
develop the capacity.
So let's say
if you're a sophisticated child and
you're a fairly aggressive child,
then what you learned to do is to
integrate your aggression into the games
that you play with other people.
So maybe you turned into a very
competitive and skilled child,
and that doesn't mean precisely that
you've inhibited your aggression.
It means that you've developed it into
an unbelievably sophisticated set of
skills so that you can manifest it
within the games that people play
without blowing the games apart.
So you can be a competitive and skilled
player,
basketball player,
for example,
which can be extremely aggressive or a
hockey player or something like that.
But everyone still wants to play with
you.
So that means that the,
that the,
there's been no repression of the
aggression drive or limited,
it's just being integrated into all the
things that it could conceivably
informed.
The alternative to that would be,
well,
let's say your parents said you're never
to be angry with anyone under any
circumstances whatsoever because good
people never get nap.
Now lots of people believe that,
um,
identifying the aggression with evil
certainly,
or at least with the kinds of actions
that only people they despise engaging,
which generally means that their
capacity for aggression is still there
in a very nascent and underdeveloped
form,
but that they have absolutely no skills
whatsoever that would be useful for
integrating it into their lives.
So for example,
one manifestation of the integration of
aggression is,
let's say that you're negotiating for a
jaw.
It's an aggressive negotiation because
they want you cheat and you don't want
to be taken chiefly.
So if you're good at
drawing on your aggressive ability,
the first thing that you figure out is,
well,
how is it that I can say no in this
negotiation and meaning,
which is an aggressive act.
If you want something from me and I just
say no,
then at minimum I'm putting up a wall
that you don't get to cross.
And if you're negotiating with someone
and you can't do that,
you lose and then people walk all over
you.
And then what's going to happen to your
aggression is it's going to manifest
itself in resentment,
which is,
you know,
a very,
um,
unproductive form of aggression.
And then according to Freud,
I think this is a very accurate
observation.
That resentment is going to drive
leakages of aggressive behavior
everywhere.
So you'll come home from the negotiation
where you didn't get the salary that you
deserve,
that you know,
your husband or your wife will say some
little niggling thing that's under most
circumstances wouldn't bother anyone.
And poof,
there'll be a big fight,
which is not very helpful and maybe you
don't even know why it happens.
And that would be part of being
unconsciously motivated.
And this sort of thing happens all the
time.
It seems to especially happen with
things like aggression because if you
get picked on,
you know,
repeatedly during the day,
each time that happens,
the mechanisms will say they're the
defensive aggressive aggression
mechanisms that reside in the
hypothalamus.
They're sort of noting that you're
taking dominance hierarchy blows and
being pushed down that structure where
it's unsafe cause you don't want to be
at the bottom of the dominance hierarchy
and then that system is,
has a proclivity more and more to grab
your behavior and your perception and
react as it should because you don't
want to be pushed down the dominance
hierarchy.
And then if it's,
if enough darts have been thrown at you
for that a pay,
then someone will push you over
threshold and Poof,
all hell break loose,
but it's very unsophisticated his
behavior and it's likely to work at
cross purposes to the end.
That could be achieved if those impulses
were properly integrated into the
personality.
So from the [inaudible] perspective,
the answer would never be shy.
Don't be aggressive part of it because
you don't have that choice.
The answer would be if you're going to
be aggressive,
which you need to be,
because that protects you,
then be sophisticated about it and don't
pretend that it isn't there and people
do that all the time.
That's part of repression.
Part of what Freud described as
repression can ease Maura simply be
conceptualized just as self deception.
You tell yourself,
well,
I'm not that sort of person and the
truth of the matter is,
Oh yes you are,
and then there's a deeper truth
underneath that which is not only are
you but you should be,
and that applies on the dimension of
aggression and on the dimension of
sexuality.
Because another thing that you might
think about is,
well,
how many marriages break down because of
infidelity?
And then the answer to that is a
substantial proportion often because of
marriage cannot tolerate even one act of
infidelity mean if it's hidden,
that's one thing.
Maybe the marriage could still survive
even though you know it's on very
unstable ground at that point.
But if the act of infidelity is exposed
or admitted to,
then the contractual relationship at
that point becomes radically unclear.
It's very difficult to maintain a
marriage relationship after that.
Well,
you might ask yourself,
well,
how is it that you start such a thing
from happening and a psychoanalytic act,
a psychoanalytic answer would be,
well,
don't try to be too good in your
marriage.
And what,
what the Friday's would mean by that is,
well,
you don't want to be the sort of 1950s
couple
each of whom sleeps in a different bed.
Because even though that might
fulfill some restricted notions of
propriety and purity,
the probable probability that it will
satiate the more instinctive sexual
desires that necessarily manifest
themselves and more importantly,
that also make up part of what makes
life Dionysian and rich instead of just
rational adult.
Those things have to be integrated
inside the marriage and that means that
it's difficult.
I think this is often a difficult thing
for men to do because,
and maybe this is less true than it was,
but I doubt it
does a difference between the category
wife and the category mistress and the
wife's category is sort of the pure
category.
Maybe that's like mother or maybe it's
like sister or maybe it's like,
eh.
And then there's the mistress category,
which is more like stripper or a
prostitute or or temptress or something
like that.
And well,
if each category is completely separate
from the other,
then if you were in the merit married
category,
the mistress category is going to start
looking pretty attractive.
And so the trick is to get those things
integrated,
but that also means that the man and the
relationship has to foster the
development of the mistress and his wife
and often his moral propriety.
We'll stop that from happening or maybe
his jealousy because one of the things
that you see happening,
for example,
in in marriages,
if the wife starts to make yourself and
this,
this can also be reversed if the wife
starts to make herself look more
attractive,
perhaps to get in better physical shape,
to dress better,
to look more attractive and public to
the degree that the husband is insecure
and feeling inferior,
he'll interfere with that because he's
afraid of,
she gets more attractive.
Then she'll attract someone who will
take her away from him.
So he'll do everything he can to
unconsciously ensure the cheese is
oppressed and Downey as she can possibly
be so that at least she doesn't run away
from him screaming.
And that's a standard for the
unentangled weapon.
Something that's very characteristic of
many close relationships.
You see the same things often say
between parents and children where the
mother or the father are afraid that the
child will surpass them in some way or
leave them and that's the Friday and eat
apples situation.
If either parent is afraid that the
child will leave,
then the parents will do everything they
can to undermine every movement
whatsoever towards the child's
independence and keep them infantiles
and the infant title highs child becomes
dependent but unbelievably resentful as
they should because the parent is doing
everything they can unconsciously to
ensure that the best part of the child
is never allowed to develop.
And that's an unbelievably common
occurrence.
Freud believed that was characteristic
of most families and that was partly
because of the long developmental period
that children need in order to become
independent,
but more complexity.
It was because the dynamics between the
father and the mother may be impaired in
one fashion or another sexually or from
a perspective of communication or in any
of the ways that people can be
mismatched.
And maybe as well the couple's isolated,
somewhat friendless.
And so there are many things that I need
to be accruing to themselves in order
for the mice to be full and they're not
getting them.
And so then they turned to their
children for more attention than they
should,
for example.
And encourage their children to pay more
attention to them then they should.
And then from the Freudian perspective,
what happens is that the whole,
I'm conscious dynamic and fantasy
structure of the household becomes
extremely pathologized so that the,
so that what people are acting out so to
speak is this weird intermingling of
mother,
father,
child and lover,
where none of the roles aren't clearly
and were,
none of the roles are clearly
distinguished from one another.
It's a mess,
you know?
And that's a situation that's very much
facilitated by deceit on the part of the
parents because maybe the husband asks
the wife,
well,
are you happy deer?
And she says,
oh,
of course everything's always going well
in our house.
What she means is I'd like to take out a
knife and stab you 50 cartons of laundry
and sleep,
but she doesn't regard that as
inappropriate verbal statement.
Even though it might be something that
she's fantasizing about deeply,
you know,
for for hours a day,
but there's no way that's going to come
to light.
You know,
you,
you can see these sorts of things
happening if you pay attention to your
fantasy life from a Freudian perspective
because you'll see if you could catch
flashes of fantasy,
especially when you're frustrated or
disappointed or annoyed or something
hasn't gone your way,
you'll have little stories branch in
your mind.
And those are these underlying it like
this,
since systems that are trying to inform
your behavior,
but they're kind of one sided and single
minded and fantasies that they pop up
can be pathologically aggressive or say
pathologically sexual,
but they're,
they're attempting to make a case for a
motive being that needs to be integrated
into your personality.
Now the other thing that Freud's noted
was saying,
the less sexual you are as an integrated
personality,
the more sexuality will manifest itself,
has pathologized in your fantasy.
It's partly because in some sense it has
to scream very loudly to get your
attention,
but it's also because
if you refuse to allow something that's
alive,
healthy pal path of development,
it's not just going to go away.
If you put a potato in the cellar and
you put shine very dim light on it,
all you get are these white spindly
shoots that are hideous and and you
know,
and the polling.
But the thing is trying to live and the
same thing applies from the Freudian
perspective to the fundamental
instinctual motivations that drive human
beings.
It's like they can be deeply
pathologized to the degree that they're
not allowed to be properly expressed.
And then you can get more and more
dissociated from them so that it becomes
an increasing war between family sees
that are developing more and more to the
pathological side and the ego,
which is doing everything it can to
increasingly defend itself from those
realizations.
So
here's a cat,
a list.
This is a good list.
This is a very good list to think about.
Here are some of the voluntary
actions that people undertake in order
to ensure that the unconscious,
both as a repository of instinctual
motivation and as a repository of memory
becomes as pathological as possible.
And so one way of thinking about the
froggy and unconscious,
apart from the the element,
which is the instinct part,
this is more to do with the memory
element is,
well,
when people engage in something that's
pathological,
are they conscious of it?
And the Floridians would say,
well,
generally not.
But that doesn't mean they weren't
conscious of it when they first did it.
It's like the decision,
it's like the decision to lie is
conscious.
You may forget that you did it and only
be
moving forward through the consequences
of having engaged in it,
and the fact that you've made it
habitual and that there are consequences
may be something you forget and that
becomes unconscious.
But it doesn't mean you didn't know what
you were doing when you first did it.
And so here are some of the little nasty
tricks that people play on each other
and on themselves in order to ensure
that they don't accurately represent the
nature of their experience.
And you might ask yourself,
what is accurate representation mean?
Given that there's no way you can ever
have a coherent and complete
representation of anything that ever
happens to you.
And so one rule of thumb for that is
that what you've accurately represented,
something that's happened to you that
was negative in the past,
if you represented it such that you're
not going to do it again in the future.
Because the purpose of memory in large
part is to stop you from doing the same
stupid things that you've already done
again in the future.
It's not purely representational,
right?
It's adaptive.
And so if you're twisting and distorting
your memory so that they're more
acceptable to you from a conceptual
level,
but not developing in this direction
that would allow you to become
increasingly adaptive,
well then you're engaging,
you're likely engaging in one or more of
these processes,
repression,
well,
repression is that you just don't admit
it.
I think mostly what happens when people
repress is not so much that they
actively repressed.
It's not exactly that.
They do something and they remember it
and then they push it down.
It's that they do something and there
are some consequences and the
consequences are complex and maybe
they're motivated and then they just
don't think about it anymore because
it's easy not to think about something.
You just don't think about it.
It's easy.
So in some sense,
although this isn't a precisely Friday
an idea,
the default position is repression,
you know,
because most of the things that you do
are complex and they require
articulation and an ordered to
understand.
You can just avoid engaging in that and
then the nasty little situation will
remain sort of emotionally vaillant and
attempting to pop up in your memory
structure.
Those are the sorts of things that maybe
you remember that happened more than 18
months ago that still cause an emotional
response when you bring them to mind.
That's a good clue that there's
something there that you have not
articulated.
Sometimes it's because you don't want
to,
and sometimes it's just because he
can't,
you know,
you just,
you don't know how to make sense out of
the occurrence.
You know,
maybe you were bullied law when you were
13 it's still bothers you when you think
about it,
but you still haven't been able to
figure out exactly why
denied.
Well,
that's just outright,
you know when you're dealing with a
teenager and they're lying and you say,
are you lying?
And they say,
no.
Well that's the end of that reaction
formation.
Oh,
that was a sneaky when.
So Freud would observe that,
for example,
in sibling relationships where you know,
one sibling is extremely irritated at
the other,
but the way they cover that up to
themselves and other people is by
overdoing it in the other direction.
So no,
maybe a husband is having some serious
second thoughts about his wife and what
he does in order to stay unconscious of
that particular
bit of reality is act with excessive
care towards or whenever they go out.
Cause there's always a false and it's
about that.
I mean,
if your antenna are up at all,
that sort of thing,
actually
maybe it's worse for me because I've
seen this so often,
I'm sensitive to it,
that sort of thing.
Read,
it turns my stomach,
you know,
when you see this is saccharin falseness
with which people treat each other,
you know,
there's something gone,
awful brewing right underneath the
surface and neither of them will admit
to it,
you know,
a good fistfight would do them a lot of
good,
but instead they'll just karcher each
other to death with politeness for two
or three decades.
So displacement,
Laurie talked about that.
Well,
my boss yells at me,
I yell at my husband,
my husband yells at the baby,
the baby bites the cat.
It's sort of movement of the problem
down the dominance,
hierarchy,
identification.
Um,
you're bullied in school and so you
start bullying kids that are younger
than you.
Rationalization.
Oh,
this is a good one.
If your intelligence,
so all those of you,
you're all pretty intelligent.
If you want to be neurotic,
the best thing to do would be to turn
your intelligence to the,
to the function of rationalization so
that when you do something that is
clearly not in your best interest or
anyone else's,
then you want to meditate on how to
formulate a sequence of complex
explanations that make that pathological
behavior look positively altruistic and
then stick to that.
You know,
as hard as you can in every argument
that you ever have for the rest of your
life.
So that's a excellent use of
intelligence,
intellectual ization,
same sort of thing.
That's usually when you dress up your
neurosis with philosophy.
And so you often see that in people who
instead of addressing their own
personality,
pathologies,
blame them on,
you know,
the pathological cultural conditions and
try to foment revolutions of one type or
another because it's pretty clear that
they don't have the problem.
It's the whole society that has the
problem.
And if it would just reorganize itself
around them,
then everything would be fine.
And so a good example of this and the
Atlantic monthly,
several months ago where a woman who had
despite her best efforts,
in some sense not be married by the time
she was in her forties blamed the
structure.
Yeah.
The entire structure of Western
civilization for the continued failure
of her dating attempts.
Which,
you know,
that might be the case,
but I would say that before you jumped
to that conclusion,
you might give some consideration to the
fact that perhaps your integrally
involved in that failure sublimation.
Oh yes.
Well Freud regarded this as a real
driving force in culture per se.
So the quote is,
okay,
then I'll sculpt naked women.
So Freud believed that
instinctual motivations like sexuality
that weren't finding their expression in
the logical behavioral conclusion could
be the energy could be channeled,
so to speak,
in other sorts of pursuits.
And the sublimation,
yes,
explanation is really interesting.
One from an evolutionarily evolutionary
psychology perspective because you see
these weird things happening not only in
human beings but also an animals.
There's this animal verb,
colon,
bower bird.
You could look them up.
Bauer is b.
O.
W.
E.
R.
They're really cool burns.
And so the males make this,
they go on the ground and then they
sweep the ground with their wigs.
And then they built this really
complicated,
we've thing that's nest like,
and then they make little art pictures
in front of it.
So they take like red leaves and they
put them all in a pile and then they go
find some yellow leaves and they put
them in a pile and maybe a few rocks and
some seeds and some bottle caps.
And they make this really beautiful
display.
And then you know,
there's a bunch of them in one area that
do that.
And then the females come along and
they'd look at the artistic display and
they look at the little bird and they
look at the artistic display and maybe
they're happy and move in or maybe they
hop off to find some other bower birds,
little artistic production.
And the really nice,
like these are major league efforts,
especially given that birds make them.
If the bottom bird gets visited by three
or four females and uh,
you know,
the whole artistic thing isn't going
very well.
Let me erase the little thing they've
done with their,
with their wings and they tear apart the
little thing they've woven and then
they're all depressed and then they
started again.
And so,
and that's a good example of this
complex idea called sublimation because
obviously the bird is utilizing its
creative capacity to fill a sexual,
to fulfill a sexual instinct.
Now Fried would say the sexual instinct
is being channeled into the creative
production.
And it's actually relatively hard to
make a case against that.
If you're a Darwinian.
And we know for example,
that one of the things that makes human
beings attractive to one another is
creativity.
You know,
manifested say dress and all sorts of
other things.
And so,
you know what the question is,
is sexuality driving that at the
individual level,
which would be afraid and interpretation
or is it tangled up in an even more
deeply at a biological level?
And then the whole reason that people
are creative is so that we're attractive
to one another and so,
and that drives the species and it dries
rep production.
And so our creative endeavor is somehow
tangled up deeply with our,
with our reproductive desire.
And it's certainly not an unreasonable
proposition projection.
So you're arguing with someone when you
do think you guys do this all the time,
you're making me mad.
It's like you think about that.
That's a really interesting statement.
It's,
well,
you know it's true in a way,
right?
Cause now you're,
you're arguing with someone who's really
annoying and clearly they're making you
map.
On the other hand,
the only reason they're making you mad
just because you're accepting that you
know the structure within which the
argument is occurring and the fact that
they were able to elicit that sort of
response from you means that your
interpretation of circumstance plays a
causal role.
So that's a complex form of projection.
A simpler form of projection is,
well,
you just don't think about it at all.
It's like you're not touchy.
The other person's annoying and a lot of
arguments are actually about settling
that you're touching.
No,
you're annoying.
you're touchy.
No,
you're annoying.
It's like,
how do you ever settle that?
Well,
usually you start dishing out even
larger in salt,
you know,
not only are you annoying,
but you annoy lots of other people,
not just me know.
And that's,
it's a funny kind of projection because
I don't have to use,
we use it often isn't precisely clear
who started or who he is,
in fact at fault.
Anyways,
that's not a comprehensive listing of
Freudian Defense mechanisms,
but it's not a bad one.
Unconscious ideas are at the core of
psychological conflicts.
I can give you an example.
Let's do psychosomatic.
One sort of thing is extremely
complicated.
So I had a client once who,
she had a real fun time,
I'll change the story a little bit.
Um,
she was at a job that she had been
training yet for a long period of time
and she thought she was doing pretty
well,
but they fired her and then they packed
her up and put her on her bicycle to go
home the same day.
And then on the way home she drove her
bicycle down a ravine and and you know,
crashed into a tree.
So that's real fun.
That's a one two punch.
Right?
So first of all,
your job disappears and then how's your
just barely not recovering from that.
Then Bang,
you get hurt.
And she was quite hurt as a consequence
of the accident.
So
she had come to see me for,
was looked like post traumatic stress
disorder.
But there was a bit of a,
there was a bit of underlying thought
disorder.
There was sort of associated with it.
But to make a long story short,
one of the things that she did when she
came to see me when she was always like
this,
and um,
I found this very bothersome after a
while because of mirror,
I think it was mirroring.
So she'd come in here like this and that
would make me uncomfortable.
And one day I had,
I had mentioned this to her and she said
she was,
she thought she had hurt her arm and
maybe she had.
And so I started getting her to move her
arm little bit.
So she moved with like this and then
she'd move it like this and then she'd
move it like this and she was getting so
she could move it pretty well.
And then the next time she came in,
she was still like this and I got this
weird impulse and I said,
well,
come over,
just stand.
I've seen her for like years by this
point and said,
just stand wide my desk.
And so she stood like this and I sort of
pounded my fist down her spine and she
cried for like 45 minutes.
So that was pretty interesting.
I mean it was like light light and then
her shoulder was loose,
certain she could move her arm more.
And so then I kind of investigated that
and she said,
well she was afraid to move her arm
because she might damage it more.
And so then I looked into that and then
she told me a story about how one time
when she was five years old,
she got accidentally into a wagon and
gone down a hill and,
and cracked up at the bottom.
And then they put her in the hospital.
And then her parents weren't allowed to
see her for like a month and a half,
which is what hospitals used to do.
Cause they were sadistic and stupid.
And I left her with a permanent distrust
of institutions,
which was sort of associated with kind
of the paranoid edge of her post
traumatic stress disorder,
but also accounted for why she didn't
want to move her arm because she thought
if she moved it then that might hurt her
more and then she'd end up in the
hospital.
And so that's a good example of how
unconscious memories and conflicts,
part of the big conflict there for her
was she had a real problem with
institutions,
you know,
and a lot of that was politicized.
There was something wrong with all
institutions,
which is true but irrelevant.
Most cases,
you know,
because you still have to adapt to the
damn things.
But it had really hurt her adaptation
because she couldn't trust the
institutions.
And then if she ever got hurt
physically,
she couldn't move herself because she
was afraid she'd read damaged the body
part and then she did end up in an
institution.
So that's a good example.
Um,
incomprehensible distress.
See if I can come up with a good example
of that.
Oh,
I can give you a hallucination one.
This is a good one.
So I had a client one time who,
uh,
he was a schizophrenia.
I met him then,
not behavioral outpatient,
inpatient ward in Montreal.
And I,
um,
I was doing an Iq test with him and he
wasn't concentrating at all.
And so I said,
why are you concentrating?
And he was looking all distracted and he
said,
because the war between the battle
between good and evil and heaven is
going on in my head,
which I thought was the most interesting
reason for not concentrating.
I had ever heard of.
I spent some time like getting to know
him,
walking around with him for some hours
on the ward.
And even though he was paranoid,
he opened up to me after a while and I
asked him about how his illness had
developed and he had been,
he was the third son of a first
generation immigrant family.
And so,
you know,
there was a lot of ambition and the
family and his oldest brother was a
doctor.
And then the second oldest was a lawyer
or maybe the other way around.
And so he was taking a master's degree
in some behavioral science at Miguel and
he got behind.
And so he faked his research data and he
wrote up his thesis,
many hands and at the end.
And then that night he went home and
went to sleep and he woke up in the
middle of the night and the devil was
sitting on his bed at the end and that
was the beginning of his schizophrenia
illness.
And so that's the hallucination
manifestation of,
and I'm conscious moral conflict.
Well unconscious to some degree he knew
that he had done wrong.
Why he wasn't conscious of was exactly
how much damage that was going to do to
him.
Now you know when you could say,
well,
maybe he had a predisposition to
psychosis before he faked his data and
that was interfering with his
performance and that's why he got behind
him.
You know,
who knows?
These things are usually complex.
Lee Closet looped.
But Tom,
there was no doubting the phenomenology.
And when he said that he couldn't
concentrate on the Iq test because the
battle between good and evil,
it happened.
What's going on in his head?
He mentioned whatever that means.
And when he told me that he woke up and
saw the devil sitting at the foot of his
bed,
like that was a hallucination.
Well,
fair enough.
But that really doesn't explain it,
which is white people in mental
hospitals generally don't talk to
schizophrenia because they'll tell you
things that will curl your hair,
or he listened and they're very
difficult to make sense of it.
And that's partly why Freud noted at the
beginning of this lecture in the little
recording that I played for you,
that his ideas were met with
incomprehension and hostility and
continued to be met in that matter to
this day.
See you soon.
Okay.