Hello everyone.
Great.
You can see me.
Daniel says loud and clear,
so excellent.
Okay.
Okay,
well thanks guys for tuning in and,
and uh,
again for offering support for the
continued operation of my youtube
channel.
So,
um,
let's get going.
Um,
it's good to see all of you and so I've
got a set of questions here.
I'm,
I can see the,
the live stream as well,
the live chat,
so that's great.
Hm.
All right,
let's try this one.
What's an effective way to figure out
how to match your career with your
temperament?
How can you determine if a job is a good
fit or a terrible mistake?
Let's start with the first one.
What's a good way of,
oh,
what's an effective way to figure out
how to match your career with your
temperament?
Well,
the first thing you do,
obviously you have to do is to
understand your temperament to some
degree.
And so the best way to deal with that is
to,
uh,
get yourself assessed using a good,
big five instrument.
There's many of them online.
We're going to be setting up a website
within the next month that will enable
people to do use a tool that a student
of mine,
Colin de Young,
who's now a professor at the University
of Minnesota and I and some other
coauthors developed back in,
I think it was 2007 called the big five
aspects scale and it breaks the big five
down into 10 aspects and we'll have a
version of that online,
I hope by the end of July.
That's the plan that will enable people
to get a read of their temperament that
will tell them how extroverted they are,
how high they are,
a negative emotion or neuroticism,
how agreeable,
how conscientious in how open.
But it will break each of those traits
down into two aspects.
So extroversion breaks into enthusiasm
and assertiveness.
Neuroticism breaks into withdrawal and
volatility.
Agreeableness breaks down into
politeness and compassion,
conscientiousness into orderliness and
industrious and openness into openness
proper,
which is something like creativity and
interest in ideas.
And so the first thing you have to know
is what your temperament is.
The second thing you should probably
know,
and we'll probably add this
functionality to the system at at some
point,
is what your intelligence level is,
what your acu is.
Because the,
the higher your Iq,
the better suited you are for jobs.
Who's demands change rapidly and most.
So those are complex jobs and simple
jobs are the jobs where you can learn
something and then you can run it as an
algorithm.
You can just repeat it over and over.
And those,
those jobs of course becoming more and
more scarce.
So you need to know what your
temperament is and then you need to know
the temperamental demands of the job.
Now,
most jobs are,
are mastered with a combination of
intelligence and conscientiousness.
But the other temperamental factors play
a moderating role.
So for example,
um,
extroverted people tend to be
entertainer types and highly social.
And so if you're interested,
for example,
if you're extroverted,
then a career in sales is something that
you might consider a career that
involves a lot of public communication
and interaction with groups.
Whereas you're an introvert,
you're going to work,
you're going to want to work a lot more.
Um,
you're going to be suited to work on s
in a solitary manner a lot more.
If you're agreeable,
you're going to be suited for taking
care of people.
If you're disagreeable,
then you're a tough bargainer and a hard
negotiator.
And,
and Ah,
litigators,
for example,
lawyers are,
are,
uh,
often low in agreeableness.
So if you're conscientious,
well,
that tends to be a very good trait for
any kind of managerial and
administrative job.
And for,
for,
for simpler jobs as well.
Uh,
it's a great predictor of military
prowess.
For example.
Um,
if you're high in openness,
then you're going to want a creative
career and that might make you an
entrepreneur or musician or an artist of
that or something like that.
Um,
that's often very,
very difficult to monetize.
But,
um,
one of the funny things about openness
is that if you're high in openness,
it's not that helpful at the bottom of
hierarchies because you're basically
expected at the bottom of most
hierarchies to act more or less like a
functionary.
But it becomes of critical importance at
the top of hierarchy.
So it's a personality trait whose
utility can really kick in in the later
stages of your career because in really
complex positions where things are
changing dynamically,
you need to have a high intelligence and
you also need to be creative.
So how can you determine if a job is a
good fit or a terrible mistake?
Ha.
Well,
I would say you can tell if it's a
terrible mistake if you dread going and
also if you're working hard and doing
what you're supposed to and you're not
being rewarded for it or,
and there's no chance for advancement so
that,
those are good reasons to,
uh,
to leave.
Um,
so all right.
Truck playing says,
just wanted to tell you that you're the
first person to actually make me read
books.
I have a background in math and
engineering,
lots of formulas and equations.
Keep up your work.
Well,
good work truck plane.
There's some real utility in reading
books and I'm glad that you found the,
the,
I,
I'm glad that you figured out why it's
necessary to do that.
So that's,
that's uh,
that's,
I'm,
I'm very happy to hear that all of our
connor says it's definitely worth doing
the humanities.
It gives you a skillset you can apply
anywhere that's actually worth
elaborating on a little bit because I do
believe that classical humanities
education is at the core of the proper
university curriculum.
And you might say,
well,
what's the utility for example,
in studying philosophy and literature?
But that's not exactly the right way to
look at it.
The,
the utility of humanities education,
at least in principle,
is that it teaches you,
first of all,
how to be civilized and educated so that
you become aware of the major cultural
works that every educated person needs
to be aware of in order to operate
properly at a high level of
functionality in the world.
And what you'll find is that as you get
older and you climb hierarchies of
competence,
that broader and broader educational
familiarity is demanded of you.
But more importantly,
education in the humanities is designed
to teach you how to think and to speak
and to formulate arguments.
And because what you're doing in complex
positions almost always involves the
identification of problems and their
articulation so that you can frame the
problem,
then a description of a potential set of
solutions,
and then the communication of those set
of solutions to a wide variety of people
in a manner that can help them obtain a
consensus and work together,
they'll set those skills are absolutely
crucial when you're doing anything
that's a real difficulty.
And so the humanities education is
extraordinarily important as a,
as a consequence of that.
Um,
here's a question.
Piaget's final stage of morality.
It was he who can,
who you can create the rules.
Would you please provide an example of
what that means?
Um,
yeah,
I can,
I can.
It says,
uh,
I'm having trouble,
I can't get the rest of it,
but can you,
can you please provide an example of
what that means?
Well,
look at,
at a lower stage of Piaget and
development,
let's say where you're a child and
you've learned to play a game,
you're going to determine morality on
the basis of how well you as a player
adhere to the rules.
Now at the point of development above
that,
you start to understand that well,
the rules were actually a human creation
and in their original form.
And that what that means is that when
it's necessary,
the rules can be adjusted.
Think about the Harry Potter series.
I mean,
one of the things that characterizes
Harry and his friends is that there and
her mind,
he's a really good example of this is
that they're sufficiently disciplined.
I mean,
she happens to be really disciplined and
are perfectly capable of following the
rules,
but also make exceptions when that's
necessary.
And it's the fact that they can step
beyond the rules when that becomes
necessary.
That actually makes them the heroes of
the adventure.
Because it's very difficult to set up a
situation where you can always act
perfectly only by following the rules
because it's very difficult to delineate
out a rule set that sufficiently
comprehensive so it'll cover every
eventuality.
So that's the,
that's the upshot on that.
Um,
women have a tendency to prefer bad men
higher in dark triad traits.
How come?
The Bible describes mode of being as
associated with Nice guy traits,
which contradict that.
Okay,
well I take issue with both elements of
that.
Actually,
I don't believe that women do have a
tendency to prefer d bad men higher in
dark triad traits.
They may have a tendency to be more
erotically attracted to men who are
capable of manifesting,
um,
dominance and aggression.
I think that the evidence for that is
relatively clear and I don't think the
Bible at all,
this describes a mode of being as
associated with Nice guy traits.
Um,
I don't know that that may be how it's
classically taught,
for example,
because Christ is often presented,
especially in more simple minded,
very variants.
And I'm not being pejorative about that
precisely as the ultimate in Nice guys.
But I don't think that that's true at
all.
That's a reasonable characterization at
If you read the Gospel accounts because
he was someone who was certainly capable
of saying very,
very harsh things to people and was also
identified very strongly as a figure who
was capable of using judgment and
distinguishing between what was positive
and what was negative in that capacity
for judgment is something quite
different than than,
than the mere nice guy,
compassion that would be associated with
high levels of trait agreeableness.
So I think that um,
the,
the idea that the ideal that's put
forward in the biblical writings,
it's something like be harmless.
I think that's a real misreading of the
text.
And uh,
I also think that it's,
it's,
it's wrong because harmless and good are
not the same thing at all.
And in fact,
I think one of the best ways of
characterizing like a higher order
morality,
and this is something that needs you
talked about a fair bit is that,
and,
and young as well with regards to the
idea of integration of the shout,
it was that someone whose moral has the
capability for violence and the
capability for aggression built in and
add hand,
but is also someone who's perfectly
capable of controlling that in a
civilized manner.
And I think that,
um,
you know,
I'm speaking off the cuff here
obviously,
but I think that the,
the,
the attraction that some women have for
for the sort of men who are more likely
to misbehave,
uh,
to,
to act in a delinquent manner and so
forth is partly their desire to be
associated with men who have the
capacity for aggression.
Now,
the best of all possible worlds is when
that capacity for aggression is
civilized and held under control.
But,
so I would say that one of the things
that men should do as they mature is
transformed themselves into monsters,
but also become civilized at the same
time.
And that that's exactly what you see in
stories like beauty and the beast where
the,
the ideal man starts out as a beast and
ends up civilized.
He doesn't start out as a milk salt wimp
sort of character who you know,
who,
who poses no threat to anyone and then
becomes the hero.
That isn't how it works.
Although there are stories of that kind
of development.
So,
um,
which is the most accessible of Carl
Jung's books?
Oh,
well,
I wouldn't say any of them are
particularly accessible,
although modern man in search of a soul
is probably a good one to start with.
That's modern man in search of a,
of,
of a soul,
I think modern man in search of his
soul.
Anyways,
it's modern man in search of a soul.
I believe it's short and it's to the
point and,
and so that's a good introduction,
which has been the most impactful to me.
Probably I on a I o n which is the
second volume,
the second volume of volume nine of the
collected works,
which is an absolutely amazing,
terrifying book.
Um,
which describes it actually it,
it acts,
it,
it contains some of young's writings on
the psychology of astrology,
which are actually quite interesting
because he regarded astrology as a
millennia long as millennia,
long fantasizing on the part of the
collective human imagination.
And,
and spend a lot of time in analyzing the
content of that.
You might think about it as a dream that
was projected out into the cosmos.
So
what are your personal strategies for
consuming the news?
Hmm.
Well,
you know,
it's funny.
For years I haven't watched television
news for example,
and I don't read newspapers very often
either.
I tried to actually limit my exposure to
the news.
Um,
I read the economist,
I used to read Harper's magazine.
I used to read,
um,
the,
uh,
um,
Atlantic monthly as well.
I thought they were good periodicals all
the way.
Think both of them have collapsed quite
precipitously in recent years.
Harper's maybe not so much.
Um,
how do I walk the line between wanting
to be informed while avoiding the danger
of cluttering your mind?
Well,
the economist helps with that.
Um,
I think it's actually gone down hill to
some degree over recent years as well.
But I definitely tell my clinical
clients very frequently,
especially if they are depressed and
feeling overwhelmed to s to limit their
exposure to do Daily News,
particularly because if something's only
relevant the day that it's published,
you could make the case that it's not
relevant at all,
which is part of the reason why I like
the economist because it only comes out
every week or two weeks depending on
your subscription.
And so it can only cover things that
have enough importance to,
to be relevant over a timeframe that
exceeds a day.
So,
all right.
So let's see what we've got in the live
stream here.
MMM.
How do we revive interest in the good
mother archetype?
Well,
that's a good question.
Um,
I think it's a good question in part
because it isn't really obvious to me
that young women are narrow.
Society are told the truth about what
their lives are likely to be like.
You know,
they're,
um,
they're taught both explicitly and
implicitly that their primary interest
will be in the pursuit of a dynamic.
And there's some real problems with
that.
The first is that the proportion of
people who will have a dynamic career in
the technical sense is actually quite
low because most people have jobs and
not careers.
And even in those jobs that might be
regarded as careers,
much of the work that's done his job.
Like,
I mean,
the reason that people pay you to have a
job is often because you're required to
do things that you wouldn't do if you
weren't being paid.
And so
we,
we glamorize the role of career and
confuse jobs with careers and assume
that most people are going to end up
with high end careers.
And then we also assume that most
people,
even those who are qualified to have
high end careers are actually the sort
of people who would like to have high
end careers if they could.
And that's also often not true.
So for example,
I've worked very intensely with a large
population of female lawyers.
Uh,
usually,
usually partners at large law firms,
very,
very successful women,
usually very attractive,
very intelligent,
extraordinarily conscientious,
um,
and the sort of people who were
outstanding in high school and then
outstanding as undergraduates.
And then ace law school and then did
their articling perfectly and then,
uh,
became associates and then eventually
entered the partner stream in the large
law firm and then became partners.
And a huge proportion of them wake up
around 30,
somewhere between 30 and 32 and notice
they're 65 hour days and the incredibly
competitive environment that they happen
to be in.
And the fact that the demands of their
career are only going to accelerate as
they move forward.
I mean,
they're going to make a lot of money,
but the,
the demands on their time of their
career only going to accelerate as they
move forward and decide quite rapidly
that that's maybe not what they want.
And the reason for that is they also
would like to have a life.
They'd like to have a relationship that
they could attend to and they'd like to
have children.
And the truth of the simple truth of the
matter is,
is that it's very,
very difficult to have a truly high end
career and have an important
relationship and have children,
especially if there are two of you
trying to pursue that.
At the same time it's very difficult and
it's difficult to have a high end career
period.
And it's also difficult to have a fully
functional family.
Trying to combine those sorts of things
makes people who are,
I mean I've seen people do it,
but man,
they,
they push themselves right to their
limits and they usually have limits that
exceed the limits of typical people.
So one of the things we could do,
for example,
to revive interest in the good mother
archetype is to stop telling lies to
young women about what their life is
likely to be like.
Because my experience has been,
and you might think I'm old fashioned,
although I don't really think I am by
the way.
Um,
I think I'm actually quite current and I
pay a lot of attention to what's going
on around me.
And my experience has been
overwhelmingly that high caliber women
decide in their thirties that
relationship and family is the most
important thing in their life.
And I think the reason that the fact
that major law firms,
for example,
have a really difficult time holding on
to their high performing women,
even though they bend over backwards to
do that is actually an indication of
exactly that.
And this notion that it's a glass
ceiling in some sense that are stopping
women from advancing up the corporate
ladder,
I believe to be a truly erroneous as
well as dangerous.
And I,
I don't think there's really any,
any really any evidence to support that.
So,
alright.
Fraser Burns says highly creative
stupendously low in conscientiousness.
Am I do?
Um,
no,
you're not doomed.
And I think that openness and
conscientiousness are often at odds with
one another.
It isn't obvious to me how someone can
easily be highly creative and ordered
the,
for example,
because to be creative means to make
some disorder in the intermediary stages
of being a creative person.
I would say also that many creative
enterprises are not the sort of thing
that anybody who was sensible from the
perspective of being conscientious,
conscientious would ever pursue.
Like the the lifestyle of a musician for
example.
I would say though that if you're low in
conscientiousness and really high in
openness,
high in creativity is that you're going
to have,
you're going to be able to generate a
lot of creative ideas,
but you're going to have a hard time
implementing them.
You won't have the follow through and
you may have to really learn to
discipline yourself.
And I would say the simplest way to
start disciplining yourself is to use
something like Google calendar to
establish a schedule and stick to the
damn thing.
Like train yourself to get up at the
same time.
Train yourself to eat at the same time.
Train yourself to follow a schedule so
that you undertake the tasks that you
need to undertake each week on a regular
basis.
But,
but you can leave in that a little bit
so that it doesn't become intolerable by
using the schedule to design days that
you would want to have instead of just
days that you should have like a
schedule.
It doesn't have to be a tyrant.
The proper use of his schedule enables
you to have the maximum amount of
freedom while also maintaining the
responsibility necessary to stop your
life from auguring into the ground.
So if you're high in openness and and
in,
in all likelihood you're fairly
intelligent.
If that happens to be the case and
you're low in conscientiousness,
you might be able to get the best of
both worlds by learning to discipline
yourself.
But it's going to be a step by step
process.
And I would also say do something like
the future authoring program from self
authoring.com and even if you do it
badly,
because one of the things that will help
you discipline yourself is to have a
plan and a plan is this is the something
that all of you who are listening should
know is like,
I really recommend doing that future
authoring program because you,
you will not get what you want unless
you figure out what it is.
You won't be as much to use to yourself
and to the broader world unless you
develop a vision and implement it.
And,
and the best way to do that is to do it
seriously.
And,
and one of the best ways to do something
seriously is to write about it.
So,
um,
my goal is to be married and on my way
to starting a family within five years.
Is this a legitimate goal to have for
myself?
Well,
absolutely.
I mean,
All of these things can be made
conscious.
I mean,
you know,
we have this romantic belief,
I suppose that if you open yourself up
to opportunity than it will ferret you
out in your dreams will come true.
But that's kind of a naive way of
looking at the world.
And it's much more likely to be the case
that if you aim at something and,
and you aim carefully and thoughtfully,
that you're,
that you will orient yourself in a
manner that makes you aware of the
opportunities that will arise,
that will put you in that direction.
That's actually how your perceptual
systems work.
And so part of the reason that it's so
useful to Orient Yourself with regards
to a specific game is that your
perceptual systems then turn on to tell
you what's going to facilitate your
movement forward.
And also what's going to get in the way.
Now,
you don't want to be too single minded
about it because you can get obsessive
and you also want to maintain enough
flexibility in your aim so that you can
change them when necessary.
But there's absolutely nothing wrong
with deciding.
Not only,
you know,
over what period of,
during what timeframe you might want to
get married and when you want might want
to have children,
but what kind of partner you want to
have and what,
what sort of interests you would like to
share with them and to really specify
your life because it's much more likely
that it's going to be turned out in a
positive manner for you and everybody
else.
If you put some intelligent thought into
it,
just like it's the case that almost
everything is likely to turn out better
if you,
if you do that.
Um,
do you suggest homeschooling with the
state public schools are currently in?
No,
I don't suggest it.
I think homeschooling is an incredibly
difficult thing to pull off properly.
And I think that there,
I think that the number of people who
would do it badly far exceeds the number
of people who would do it well.
Having said that,
it's not like I think it's wrong and
it's also not like,
I think that there isn't increasing
reason for parents to consider that
because I do actually think there's
increasing reason for parents to
consider that because the postmodern neo
marxists have got their claws into the
education system and I think they're
doing everything they can.
And you can certainly see that in,
in,
in Canada and in Ontario where the
elementary teachers,
Federation of Ontario has published
there,
I think it's guideline curriculum.
It's something like that that's
basically a blueprint for transforming
kids into social justice oriented
individuals from kindergarten through
grade eight.
So it's not surprising that people want
to do that.
So,
um,
but I think that parental rights trumps
state rights in relationship to children
and it has to be that way even though
there's lots of bad parents.
The thing about bad parents is that the
state as parent is worse.
It's not like there are no bad parents,
but to assume that the state is going to
be a better parent on average than
parents who actually love their children
is a very bad idea.
So why is Jordan Peterson's Webcam a
thousand times better than all of my
favorite youtube.
Youtube is with millions of subscribers
because my son Julian,
who helps me with technical matters,
bought a Dlsr l camera dlsr camera for
me that happens to work extremely well
except the battery runs out about every
hour and 15 minutes and I have to change
it.
So,
um,
and I think there's,
there's,
it would be nice if I could actually
plug it in with an adapter,
but I think that that changes the
category of camera to video camera and
then there's tax implications or
something like that.
So I have the high quality camera and I
have to put up with the fact that the
battery dies.
So,
um,
how do I plan to buffer myself from the
deteriorating tier you're aiding side
effect of success?
That's a really good question actually.
Um,
I can tell you a bunch of answers to
that.
I mean,
the first is,
is that I have a sensible family,
a son and a daughter,
and soon to be a son in law and a
daughter in law as well,
who I like and who liked me.
And we get along really well and they're
really sensible people.
And so they help keep me,
my feet nailed to the ground.
And so does my wife because my wife is
also an extremely sensible person and
someone I really deeply trust.
And I'm also fortunate in that I have
parents who,
who play that role with me as well and a
sister and a brother in law.
Um,
and,
and my brother as well who helped me
stay
attuned to the potential dangers that
this widespread public exposure might
otherwise produce.
But so,
but the other issue,
so there's that,
I have advisors,
let's say,
who are on my side who tell me the truth
and we discussed what I'm doing all the
time to make sure that it's staying more
or less on track.
The other thing too is though,
you know,
I'm not exactly a young man anymore.
I'm 55.
And um,
I think a lot of the detrimental
elements of widespread public exposure
are things that would have been a lot
more harmful or that are a lot more
harmful to people when they're younger.
There's just a lot of things about being
in the public eye that don't have the
same cache to me that they might have
when I was a younger person or that they
would have to a younger person.
And I guess I would also say that I
don't really believe that I'm the sort
of person to let,
and I'm not trying to put myself on a
higher moral plane or anything with this
comment,
but I don't think I'm the kind of person
to let the sort of thing that's happened
over the last year or so really go to my
head.
And I think part of the reason for that
is it that I have a fairly pronounced
depressive temperament and so that I can
see the negative side of myself with,
with plenty painful clarity.
And,
um,
I'm also more concerned about the
possibility of making a catastrophic
mistake as I present my self publicly
than I am in what clambering up some
power louder I suppose in elevating
myself to a position at the top.
I'm just not that interested in that.
And so I think,
and I'm,
I'm also,
I think fairly aware of the dangers of,
of well let's say fame to the degree
that that's what's occurred to me.
Um,
I know the downside of that and it isn't
something that I'm interested in it,
I'm actually,
I know it's a strange thing but to think
about,
but I'm actually also rather private
person and,
and um,
although I'm,
I can't keep my mouth shut obviously,
and I'm,
I'm very talkative.
That's from being very high in openness,
even more than being high in
extroversion I think.
And uh,
but there isn't anything that comes
along with the dark side of fame,
let's say,
that I would find particularly
attractive.
You know,
I'm not really interested in partying
endlessly,
although I had my time doing that when I
was young.
I'm certainly not interested in,
um,
whatever additional attractiveness to
two females that my more well known the
fact that I'm more my well known might
provide to me that that just doesn't
interest me at all.
I'm very happy in my marriage and also
very aware of the catastrophes that lie
in directions of that sort of
temptation.
So,
um,
but,
but I also,
I think of all those explanations,
the one that's most relevant is my see,
I know that I'm walking a tight rope in
some sense and that it would be very
easy for me to make the kind of error
that would sink me.
Um,
and I'm,
I know that there are many people who
don't approve of what I'm doing who
would be very happy about that.
And so I think also living in a somewhat
constant state of existential terror
about the probability that this house of
cards could collapse is also something
that keeps me oriented in the humble
direction and
dwelling on this a little bit.
But it really is an interesting
question.
I am also,
I believe I also have trained myself so
that I orient myself mostly to
considering what I'm doing wrong and
what I couldn't be doing better than
what I'm doing right.
And so I'm always on the lookout in all
of the presentations I make four where I
didn't say things as clearly as I might
have been,
where I could have improved my delivery.
And so concentrating on where what I
have yet to attain is also a good way of
keeping whatever ego boost there might
be in more widespread public recognition
under control.
Having said that,
I'm very,
it's not like I'm ungrateful for the
fact that all this has happened.
It's actually an amazing thrill.
I mean,
things happen to me all the time that
are,
that are so overwhelmingly positive that
I can't believe it.
So last night for example,
I went to this restaurant called the
cake and I go there because I have a lot
of food allergies and they're actually
very careful with people who have food
allergies.
And,
uh,
the,
the waiter showed us to the table and he
knew who I was and he said that he had
been watching my videos and that he had
had four promotions.
I think that's what he's doing.
He said,
yeah,
four promotions in the last four months
at the cake.
And the reason for that was that he had
been watching my lectures and decided
that he was going to adopt a more
responsible attitude as an employee and
also do,
you know,
we'll start pushing the development of
his career at this,
at this restaurant.
And that had worked out brilliantly.
And like it was so positive because you
know it,
and I thought about it as a true victory
on his part because he took the
situation that he was actually in,
so a real situation and decided that he
was going to maximize the opportunity
that was there for him.
And you know,
there's nothing about that.
It's negative,
it's all positive and it's a personal
story.
And he shared it with me and I had some
small role in bringing that about.
And like that's just an absolute thrill
as far as I'm concerned.
Like every time someone writes me and
says,
I've been watching your videos and I've
just decided to sort out my life and to
aim higher and that's working,
it's just like,
it's such a thrill for me to be able to
provide that service for hundreds of
thousands of people.
It's like,
it's a,
it's an unbelievable privilege and I
hope I can figure out how to do it
better and better as I get more and more
practiced at it.
I mean,
that's really the aim.
And with my colleagues,
uh,
Daniel Higgins for example,
I have two business partner,
Daniel Higgins and,
and Robert Peale peale was my graduate
advisor and mcgill and Daniel Higgins
was one of my graduate students at
Harvard and we've been working on making
psychological interventions accessible
to people for about 20 years.
So they helped me develop the self
authoring suite for two.
For example,
we have a whole host of,
um,
psychological tools in development,
including a future authoring program for
high school students that we want to
bring to the broader general public.
And so this public exposure also gives
me the opportunity to,
to make what I know as a clinical
psychologist and as someone with some
specialization in technology,
especially through my partnerships,
make that accessible to perhaps millions
of people.
I mean,
God,
that's,
that's just an amazing opportunity.
And so
someone asks,
how do you find the self authoring
autobiography,
um,
outline?
Well,
you go to the self authoring.com it's
available there.
Um,
let's see.
MMM,
somewhat.
And at Adler says,
I have also done better in a lot of
things due to your kicks in the ass.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
that's great and that I'm thrilled to
hear that.
Um,
see,
part of it,
you see,
the thing about disciplining someone
let's say is that when you,
and I see this very clearly when I'm
talking to young people,
is that I really on the side of the
person that wants to do something
positive with their life to make their
own life better.
Because I think that's where you should
start.
You should start by making maximizing
the quality of your own life.
That's not a selfish thing.
Or if it is,
it's the right kind of selfishness and
that you should figure out how to do
that in a way that's of benefit to your
friends and your family and your
community.
And you should take that deadly
seriously.
And the reason you should do that is
because that just makes life better for
everyone and it re it reduces a fair bit
of the misery that would otherwise be
part and parcel of life.
And it makes everything function
smoothly.
And one of the things I'm really curious
about is what the world would be like if
everybody decided to do that.
Because human beings are really
remarkable creatures and we humble
ourselves very badly.
With deception and resentment and
revenge and the desire to make things
worse and arrogance and all those,
all those sins,
let's say that,
that,
that make us deviate from our True Path
and our true path should be something
like imagine the noblest aim,
then you can conceptualize and then
sacrifice your life to attempting to
attain it.
And there's nothing in that that isn't
good for everyone.
And so apart from the fact that it
requires a lot of responsibility,
I just can't see why everyone wouldn't
do that.
And when I'm talking to young people and
it was shaking my finger and saying,
you know,
grow the hell up and get mature and take
on some responsibility,
I'm not saying that because I'm an enemy
of the person,
I'm saying it because I'm the best
friend of the part of them that would
really like to walk in the light and,
and it's an invitation to walk in the
light and,
and it would be remarkable.
This is what we need to do as far as I'm
concerned,
not only in the West but in the world at
large,
but maybe in the West first is we have
to consciously decide that we're going
to do everything we can as individuals
to walk in the light and to regard that
as a noble and heroic endeavor and to
make that first and foremost in our
lives.
And that's what we should be educating
young people to do.
And they can do that.
And so I have dozens of people writing
to me and,
and talking to me all the time who are
saying the same thing they're saying,
look,
I've really been trying to get my act
together over the last six months.
I've been trying not to lie,
which is slightly different than trying
to tell the truth,
right?
It's a more humble goal to not lie
because you can tell when you're lying,
but you can't necessarily tell when
you're telling the truth.
And I,
I've been coming up with a plan and I've
been trying to discipline myself and
I've been cleaning up my room,
which is like a nice humble act that
that involves transforming chaos into
order.
And they write and say,
God,
things are just working out way better
for me.
It's like,
Whoa,
do it man.
That's just,
you keep that up for 15 years and you'll
be unbeatable.
And that's what we should be convincing
young people to be,
is to be unbeatable.
And not because that's what they should
do or because they're bad if they don't,
but because there's nothing better you
can possibly do with your limited and
you're limited and suffering bound life
than to aim high and,
and sacrifice yourself to the attainment
of those goals.
So that's,
uh,
being a highly creative woman,
I find myself fearful that having kids
will be spiritual suicide,
hindering my endeavors.
But I also don't want to have an
unfulfilled life.
Can I have a full life without kids?
Well,
yes,
I,
I suspect you can.
Although it's risky,
Maddie,
because it's really important for people
to have kids.
Because the thing is is that you get
older than 40,
and our culture is kind of dopey in that
regards.
It's underdeveloped.
We live as if we live as if we,
we only exist when we're young and we
don't.
It's like what are you going to do from
the ages of say 45 to 90 or 95?
You,
you need a family around you.
You need to see your children grow.
You need to have grandchildren.
It's a major part,
maybe the most important part of the
last half of life.
No,
you said being a highly creative woman,
I find myself fearful that having kids
will be spiritual suicide.
Well,
that's the part of your question that I
would really address because I would
say,
well,
don't let them be spiritual suicide.
You know,
it may be that there's a certain amount
of time that you need to take away from
the kids.
That,
and this is the case for parents in
general,
um,
so that you can pursue your own creative
endeavors.
It's children do not have to devour your
life.
In fact,
if you let them devour your life,
then you'll hate them and you mistreat
them.
And so what you want to do is to set
yourself up so that you can have
children and have a life and that's
better for the children.
And it's better for you.
Like children can be taught,
encouraged to spend a fair bit of time,
not when they're infants,
obviously,
but to spend a fair bit of time amusing
themselves.
And that's especially the case if you
have more than one child because they'll
mutually amuse one another.
It's actually easier in some ways to
have more than one child.
Because with one child,
you're constantly amusing the child.
But with two or three,
then they're off in their little,
you know,
club.
Especially if you can stop them from
developing sibling rivalry,
that's too intense and they can monitor
themselves.
So the trick is if you're a highly
creative woman is be disagreeable and
now so that you can carve yourself out
your own space so that you don't come to
resent your children.
You're afraid of that.
You're afraid that it looks like you're
afraid that if you,
if you give yourself to children,
there'll be nothing left for you.
And um,
you know,
that could happen if you have children
who have terrible health problems,
for example,
but you can't protect yourself against
those eventualities in life anyways.
But I would say your best bet is to be a
more selfish mother.
And believe me,
I've had more clients
who were ruined by mothers who were too
unselfish than I've had clients who were
ruined by mothers who were too selfish.
So you need to be there when the kids
need you,
but you shouldn't be there any more than
is necessarily.
So
let's see,
Adam Watson,
I feared having kids for the same
reason.
I'm a full time pro artist.
You make your own normal said my
therapist jp is speaking the truth.
Yeah,
well that's the,
oh,
that's the thing.
You know,
don't be thinking that you can't
organize your life when you have
children.
The thing about modern people is that
they're terrified of children,
they and this because they think they
regard children as if they're miniature
tyrants.
They can be of course,
because anyone will tyrannized over you
if you allow them to,
perhaps not anyone but virtually anyone.
Why not regulate your children's
behavior?
I wrote a chapter in my new book called,
uh,
don't let your children do anything that
makes you dislike them and that's like
really serious advice is like if you
allow your children to conduct
themselves around you in a manner that
makes you dislike them,
if you're being honest,
if you're paying attention to the shadow
side of yourself,
that can be aggressive and destructive,
then then if you allow your children to
do things that make you dislike them,
then they're going to,
they're having children is going to mess
up your life,
but you don't have to do that.
You're actually,
you actually have a tremendous amount of
control over the quality of your
relationship with your children and also
the manner in which you choose to
disperse your time.
And I mean you're,
you've got,
if you're willing to think it through
and be clear,
you can be in charge of your household.
The children don't have to be in charge
and it's not good for them to be in
charge anyways.
So people are afraid of children and
it's too bad because children are
absolutely wonderful.
I mean,
you have to be careful with them and
they get tired and they get hungry and
they get hot and,
and they don't have an attention span.
That's as long as an adult who has a
long attention span,
but they're great company and they're
unbelievably comical and they love you.
And like they,
they give back far more than they take
if you have an ounce of sense when
you're dealing with them.
So,
yeah.
so don't be afraid of children,
man.
You're,
you're the adult for God's sake.
You've got the upper hand and,
and if you have a partner,
you can rely on Walden.
You know,
you can both decide how it is that
you're going to run your household so
that you're actually thrilled to death,
that you have kids in that you have a
life.
So,
all right,
let's see.
When am I appearing on each three h
three November,
I believe.
November 3rd.
So I'm looking forward to that.
MMM.
Let's see.
How do you help someone with borderline
personality disorder?
That's Matthew Dodson.
Matthew,
you know,
I'd like to answer that question,
but it's so damn complicated that I
don't think I can manage it.
Um,
so instead of doing a bad job,
even though that's a very interesting
question,
I'm afraid I'm going to skip that.
MMM.
Let's look back at the pigeonhole panel
here.
Um,
okay.
Do you consider this,
okay,
some people have criticized my portrayal
of postmodernism.
In what ways would you claim you are a
fair or unfair in your assessment of its
core principles?
Well,
um,
I've done my best to,
to give it an evenhanded assessment.
MMM.
And
I think I'm unfair in that any rather
truncated criticism of a large body of
thought is liable to clip a few corners.
But I would say that I'm attempting to
provide a snapshot,
a relatively accurate but low resolution
snapshot of a certain kind of war id on
a war of ideas that's currently going on
in our culture.
And that's primarily centered in the
universities.
And I don't think my assessment of
postmodernism and its relationship with
neo Marxism is unfair in the least.
In fact,
I think that the danger that's presented
by that combination of ideological,
of ideological presumptions is more
dangerous than people are currently
aware of.
And that poses a larger threat to the
integrity of our culture then then I've
currently stated it's more widespread
than I thought.
For example,
when I first started,
um,
speaking out against postmodernism and
neo Marxism,
I didn't realize,
for example,
that the law schools had turned into,
it had turned into training grounds for
social justice activists.
I didn't realize that the legal system,
the legal training system had become
corrupt,
perhaps not to the same degrees as say
the faculties of education or social
work.
Certainly a long ways down that road.
And so I think I do believe that
postmodernism is an intellectually
bankrupt school of thought.
And I believe that its alliance with neo
Marxism borders on malevolent and it may
even go past the border into actual
malevolence because I don't understand
how anybody with an inkling of
historical sense can take a look at the
20th century.
And then dare put forward ideas that are
derived from Marxism as a,
as a,
as a treatment for any of society's
hypothetical disorders.
And it,
it's not to say that I don't leave that
there are,
that there are errors in,
in,
in western culture,
say for,
for whatever that's worth.
I mean,
individuals make more errors all the
time in groups make moral errors and
cultures make moral errors.
That isn't the issue.
The issue is how are we doing compared
to any reasonable alternatives.
Um,
what makes you think that it's,
it's appropriate to compare the
performance of western societies,
for example,
to some hypothetical utopia of your own
fictional imagining,
especially when we seen what sort of
utopias have emerged out of,
uh,
out of,
out of such imaginings.
And,
um,
what is it that you are offering people
as a concrete alternative than all I see
in postmodernism is destruction and
nihilism and always see in neo Marxism
is historical ignorance,
malevolence and misdiagnosis.
Well,
and in gratitude and arrogance,
I mean,
the list goes on and on.
So I don't feel that I've misrepresented
the postmodernists in the least.
And I find I regard like I've read a
fair bit of Foodco less of Derrida but
enough to get a pretty good sense of
what he's on about.
Like foucault is readable but more or
less obvious as far as I'm concerned.
And so he's a third rate thinker and
Derrida is just a troublemaker as far as
I'm concerned.
Although a very brilliant one.
And the idea that the postmodernist had
that there's an infinite number of ways
of interpreting any set of data,
let's say that's how actually happens to
be a true observation and a very
problematic one,
which is partly why it's,
it's so difficult,
for example,
to evolve a system that can,
that can visually perceive the world and
why about half our brain is devoted
towards that.
It's,
it's definitely the case that coming up
with a viable interpretation of the
world is a very difficult process.
But,
but that's about as far as the validity
of the postmodernist claims go.
After that,
it's like,
well,
yes,
there's a very large number of potential
interpretations of the world,
but there's a very small number have
actually viable interpretations and
that's really what's relevant.
And viability is constrained by all
sorts of,
of,
uh,
what would you call them?
Well,
let's call them constraints.
Yes.
Um,
you,
you have to interpret the world in a
manner that's commensurate with the
minimization of your own intolerable
suffering that puts very tight
constraints on which interpretations
you're allowed to bring forward.
You have to do that in a manner that's
iterable and repeatable across time.
You have to do that in a way that isn't
too objectionable other people,
or even better in a manner that makes
them want to cooperate and compete with
you so that,
you know,
a rising tide lifts all boats.
There's immense constraints on
organizing your perceptions in a manner
that is similar [inaudible] individually
and socially highly functional.
And the postmodernist Joseph just don't
grapple without at all.
They and,
and they're,
they're biologically ignorant beyond
belief and proud of that fact.
Anyways,
as you can tell,
I can hardly say enough things that
aren't good about postmodern neo
Marxists.
There's,
there's,
apart from the fact that they got the
initial observation right,
which is that there's a very,
there's almost an infinite number of
ways of interpreting a finite set of
data.
Everything else they've done is not only
intellectually bankrupt,
it's also morally reprehensible and I
think they're corrupting our culture and
I think they're,
they're,
they're hurting young people and they're
hurting them as well by getting them to
pay for being hurt,
which is really quite a malevolent,
um,
enterprise.
So I've got no,
what would you call,
I have absolutely no regrets about going
after the postmodern neo Marxists as
hard as I possibly can and I'm certainly
not done doing so.
So one of the things that's going to
happen,
for example,
in the next month or so,
I've been working with a programmer
who's,
who's volunteered his services and has
already produced this.
He's,
he's produced a website that enables
people to enter text that will then
classify the text as postmodern or non
postmodern.
And so you'll be able to enter course
descriptions from universities,
the course description,
the professor's name,
the discipline,
and the university.
It will tell you the degree to which the
description is postmodern and then you
can decide for yourself whether you want
to take that it become a social justice
warrior.
That's what you think your education
should be about or if you should avoid
that,
like the plague that it truly is.
And so my goal,
if I had to set a personal goal,
and this is the sort of thing maybe that
you guys are helping me do with my
continued support on Patrion,
is that I'd like to knock enrollment in
the postmodern disciplines down by 75%
over the next five years.
I think that,
I think I'm thinking about it from the
perspective of of nonviolent warfare.
It's that serious to me and that this
would be equivalent to cutting off the
supply chain.
It's like the,
the,
the postmodernists need a continual
influx of young impressionable minds in
order to continue their propagandistic
and society devouring efforts.
And I'm going to do absolutely
everything I can to cut that supply
chain off at the source hopefully,
and,
and reduce their enrollment to the zero
that would match their citation rate for
their publications.
So would I in my career as an academic
in order to enter politics as a
candidate for MP under Andrew Scheer's
leadership?
Uh,
no I don't think I would do that.
I mean I thought for Awhile I thought at
one point of running for the leadership
of the Liberal Party in Canada and then
I thought at another point in running
for the leadership of the Conservative
Party,
but both times I decided that what I was
doing as a academic,
and I would say as someone who's a
phyllis philosophy,
a philosophy,
a philosophy and science cheeses,
it's been a long day guys.
I'm starting to forget how to talk as a
philosophically and scientifically
minded psychologist was more useful than
anything I could likely do practically
in the political realm.
And I haven't seen any reason to change
that opinion as a consequence of the
events of the last eight months or so.
And so although I've always been
interested in
okay,
politics as a potential career route,
every time the opportunity has arisen
and I've had to make a choice between
continuing what I've been doing and
pursuing a political pathway,
I've always decided to continue doing
what I am doing.
And I think that's probably what I will
continue to do.
I actually think I can have more
influence doing what I'm doing,
that I could by doing anything else.
And that's partly because I suppose if I
thought there was anything else I could
be doing that was more useful,
I'd be doing that instead.
So that's the answer to that.
MMM.
What is the role of art in a healthy
culture is postmodernism as destructive
and in this domain as in politics?
Well,
let,
let's,
that's Michael Bamford.
Well,
what's the role of art in a healthy
culture?
While the artists articulate the,
the artists are the people who first
articulate the unknown.
And so the role of artists in a healthy
culture is to bring to public awareness
elements of being that have not yet
entered the,
the collective consciousness.
So you can imagine,
imagine that we're all living on an
island and many of us are in the center
of the island far enough away so that
maybe we can't even see the shoreline
and we can't see the ocean.
That's where our borders and,
but we're,
we're distant from the artists are right
on the edge and they're,
they're,
they're expanding the landscape.
They're there,
they're moving the culture forward.
That's where my metaphor fails.
I guess they're moving the culture
forward into the unknown.
And they do that by translating what is,
as of yet unimaginable,
but sensed into what is at least
imaginable and represented,
represented in image and,
and drama and literature.
And that's the precursor to its full
formulation in articulated philosophy
and thought.
And that's what artists do.
They're problem solvers.
They're problem detectors and problem
solvers.
That's what true artists do.
And they're always trying to solve
problems.
Like if you,
there's a great documentary that was
made about Picasso,
for example,
a painting.
And unfortunately,
I can't remember the name of it.
I think it was made in 1957 it's
available on youtube and it's in black
and white and Picasso is filmed making a
painting on a,
on a,
on a window so that you can see exactly
what it's doing and you can watch them
work with ideas.
He,
he paint something in and then he erases
that,
you know,
he paints over it.
Then he paints again and he paints over
it.
He moves the figures around on the
canvas.
It's,
it's a window pane as I said.
And you can see him working out visual,
you can see them working out problems
and solutions to problems using,
using his visual imagination and the
artistic product.
The painting is,
is the consequence of that rather than
the aim of it.
The aim is to formulate the problems and
to work out the solutions and the
artistic
product.
The painting is,
is the byproduct of that,
not the aim.
And so artists move us forward into the
unknown.
And you can see them doing that in
cities because it's the open people,
the artists who go into parts of the
cities that are,
have degenerated to some degree back
into chaos and then revitalize them and
they civilize them.
And then the less artistic people who,
who are more conventional move in and
you know,
that's when you get gentrification and
that sort of thing.
And that usually chases the artists out
and they go somewhere else cheap and
interesting and start the renewal
process again.
So the thing about artists,
and it's a hard thing to balance
property in our culture,
is that artists are unbelievably
productive economically,
but it's very,
very hard for them to monetize their
productivity.
So even though what they produce can be
of incalculable value,
um,
it's very difficult for them to get any
of the economic value that they're
produced actually directed towards them.
It's a major problem in,
and it's a major problem with trade
openness as a mode of being in the
world.
So it's postmodernism is destructive in
this realm as it is in politics.
Postmodernism is perhaps equally
destructive in all realms as far as I
can tell,
especially when it's allowed.
But with neo Marxism and those two
things,
there's no reason they should go hand in
hand.
You know,
because if you're a postmodernist,
there's absolutely no reason stemming
from your own philosophy that you should
ally yourself with a new Marxist
political outlook.
And the fact that those two things are
found together almost inevitably
indicates to me that postmodernism is
the handmaiden of the Neo Marxists
rather than the other way around.
So in in fact,
postmodernism is the intellectual front
that the Neo Marxists where or adopt to
hide from themselves and other people
their true motivations,
which are mostly driven by revenge and,
and resentment and,
and the desire to destroy and a hatred
for quality and a hatred for qualitative
distinctions,
which is dead.
It's death.
I mean with young people,
you want to say,
look,
there's not much to,
you're only 20 and you're kind of
useless.
But that's because you're only 20 you
know,
that doesn't mean you're not full of
potential.
That potential needs to manifest itself
so that you can turn into something
that's it's of,
of,
of world beating significance.
But in order to tell a young person that
credibly you have to say,
look,
there are true qualitative distinctions
between things and you're just getting
started.
There are highlights that you can ascend
to that are genuinely high,
which also means they're above where you
are now,
but that gives your life the fact that
there are those things to pursue,
gives your life deep meaning and
significance and gives your struggle.
Nobility and validity and the
postmodernist,
Neil Marxist as far as I'm concerned,
are absolute enemies of qualitative
distinctions and so what they do is
destroy everyone's ambition.
It's like we're all already as valuable
as we're going to get.
It's like,
okay,
well fine,
that's good.
We don't have to feel bad about
ourselves,
but what the hell are we going to do?
What are we going to orient ourselves
towards?
What we want is multiple hierarchies,
multiple steep hierarchies of competence
that are open in,
in fair competition to everyone.
And if we don't have enough hierarchies
of competence for everyone,
then you know it's up to the creative
people to produce some new ones.
It's not like we'll necessarily run out.
So.
All right.
Have you ever had to tell someone that
they are best suited to a subservient
slash blue collar lifestyle because they
don't have any semblance of brilliance?
Okay.
Well I want to take issue with the
formulation of that question,
although I think it's a perfectly
reasonable question.
That's Gen Swan.
Don't be thinking that a blue collar
lifestyle is necessarily subservient.
I mean,
first of all,
you can be a trades person and now it's
a really good career choice as far as
I'm concerned.
It's very,
very valuable.
I mean,
you know,
good plumbers are rare and good
carpenters are rare and good bricklayers
are rare and they're so useful.
I mean,
I do a lot of renovation work.
I've done an awful lot of renovation
work on all the places that I've,
I've lived in and I've learned to do a
fair bit of construction and automotive
body work and all those sorts of things.
And I really liked doing it.
And you know,
there's,
they're blue collar life is not
necessarily subservient at all because
you can be master of your trades domain
and be unbelievably economically useful
and productive and creative and
independent and autonomous.
And so there's,
there's nothing necessarily subservient
about that.
Um,
now,
you know,
if you're thinking more about,
about,
let's say life at the low end of a
restaurant,
but even there,
if you're a conscientious person and
you're careful and you,
and you're awake and you treat the
people around you well and you do your
job properly,
there's also room for advancement in the
private sphere.
There's no reason to assume whatsoever
that merely because you don't have the
intellectual horsepower to work well in
the ABS,
in the,
in the domain of rapidly shifting
abstractions that your life has to be of
secondary quality or,
or,
or opportunity.
I don't see that at all.
And,
and there is endless opportunity in the
trades and,
and like in,
in Toronto for example,
there's a chronic shortage of,
and there's always a shortage of
qualified people for every occupation.
So,
um,
if I have to tell someone that they're
best suited to a blue collar lifestyle,
I wouldn't feel bad about it.
I might say to them,
well,
look,
you know,
um,
you,
you know,
let's assume you're talking to someone
who has an Iq of a hundred,
which is the Iq of the average high
school graduate.
You might say,
well,
look,
you know,
um,
less you're super conscientious,
uh,
career in something like law is probably
not your best bet because you're going
to be competing with people who have iqs
that are like 30 points higher than
yours,
or 25 points higher than yours.
And if you really work yourself to
death,
you might be able to main maintain
competitiveness in that domain,
but you're going to be working at a
powerful disadvantage because the people
that you're competing with,
for example,
are going to be way faster than you
verbally.
They're gonna be able to read faster and
to reason verbally faster,
and,
and all of that.
And it might be better to pick up,
uh,
an ambition.
It's more in keeping with the quality of
your temperament and your intelligence
to,
to put it bluntly so that you can be,
but that doesn't mean that your success
has to be limited.
And it,
it also doesn't mean that I'm in ve
elevating intelligence to do a platform
of the ultimate moral ideal because the
relationship between intelligence and
moral ideal is zero.
There is no relationship between them at
all.
Intelligence is,
uh,
is our capacity,
let's say that can be put to ill use
just as well as to good use.
And there's nothing intrinsically better
about smart people.
They might be more useful for certain
things if they're oriented towards the
good,
but,
um,
there's absolutely,
there's no shortage of opportunity in
the working class end of the end of the
world.
And I can certainly understand often why
people might prefer that too.
To the endless,
my asthma,
you might say chaotic Miasma of complex
abstract jobs.
One of the problems with those sorts of
jobs is that you're never done.
It never finished.
There's always more work than you can
possibly do.
So all right,
so that's a good one.
Let's see here.
MMM.
I feel sensitive to meme culture.
Slash irony.
It seems hard to act out honesty when
every facet of human behavior has turned
into a meme.
So I worried people's natural reaction
will be to mock or scoff.
Well,
you know,
I've been the target of my fair share of
memes,
um,
perhaps more than my fair share.
And I actually find it extremely,
I'm really happy about it.
And part of the reason for that
involves some of the elements of our
earlier discussion.
People were saying,
well,
how do you plan to keep your feet on the
ground,
say,
given your new phone public,
um,
pr profile.
And I see the,
the meme culture as part of the
corrective.
I mean,
there's a great role for satire and
irony and all of the elements of comedy
to,
to act as a corrective.
And I mean,
I've been fortunate because most of the
memes that have been directed my way
have been done with good humor.
I'm lucky because for some reason the
ratio of positive attention I received
from the general public,
let's say,
is compared to the ratio to the amount
of negative reactions I'm receiving is
very disproportionate.
I receiving almost all positive
reactions.
So,
you know,
I'm in the fortunate position of being
able to allow for long with it.
But,
um,
I don't think that there's any reason to
assume that irony and satire have to
become cruel and scoffing.
They can be done with a light touch and
they can be done in a manner that keeps
everybody awake and make sure that no
one is above
okay.
Both criticism and,
and,
and humor that they're now,
that sort of thing can become cynical
very rapidly,
but it degenerate as soon as it becomes
cynical.
You see this with satirical shows,
you know,
like,
I really liked the simpsons,
the first 13 seasons in particular,
and like it,
it was one of the very rare,
true satires on American television.
And it never degenerated into cynicism
in part because although it comedically
critiqued almost every element of
American life,
it was also,
it also had a set of messages that were
very positive.
So for example,
the Simpson family was an
extraordinarily coherent nuclear family
unit and for whatever homer's faults
might've been,
and they were myriad,
he was always there as a reliable and
trustworthy a father to his family,
despite his,
you know,
somewhat limited abilities,
both ethically and intellectually.
He was there when it counted.
And that stopped that show from
degenerating into cynicism.
And I also think the same boat,
the trailer park boys,
which is a show that I have a fair bit
of partiality four,
despite its,
it's endless profanity and,
and an absurdity,
it has the same underlying structure is
that the characters are bound together
by genuine affection.
And there's something about that that
that makes the satirical message,
um,
both positive and deeply acceptable as
far as I'm concerned.
So
I know lots of laughs.
Jordan watches trailer park boys.
I don't just watch it.
I really like it.
I really get a kick out of it.
I don't know how many of you are trailer
Park Boys Aficionados?
Probably not that many because it is a
pretty rough schilt.
But um,
the conky episode,
that's gotta be one of the,
the high,
that's one of the highest.
That's the,
the highest reach of Canadian comedy as
far as I'm concerned.
That episode just absolutely floored me.
It was so,
it was so surreal and so observed that,
um,
alright.
Let's see here.
What are,
is your advice for someone who lives
with chronic pain?
Wow,
that's a tough one.
How can I discipline myself mentally in
order to be productive when I feel awful
all of the time?
What coping methods cannot use?
Look,
the first thing I would say,
this is a question posed by shivers,
is like,
if you're suffering chronic pain,
one of the things you can do is try not
to judge yourself too harshly.
Man,
that's really rough.
And why don't you start by assuming that
if you're having a hard time
disciplining yourself,
that it's actually a consequence of the
chronic pain rather than a moral fault.
You know,
like I've dealt with lots of people
who've had terrible chronic health
problems and you know,
you,
you want to push yourself because you
don't want to end up in a situation
where the disease condition is taking
more away from you than it absolutely
has to.
So you attempt to impose minimal
disciplinary structures on yourself too
to push the illness back as much as you
can.
But if you're in chronic pain,
I would say,
um,
you need to find someone that you can
trust to talk to so that they can help
you plan.
And you need to be able to delineate out
what your limitations are in a manner
that they can understand so that you can
jointly focus on how to make productive
use and high quality use of the time
that you can actually spend outside of
merely suffering.
The other thing that I would ask you
about is,
are you sure that your medication
regimen regimen is adjusted optimally?
Because antidepressants,
for example,
can be very effective long term
medication for chronic pain,
especially,
uh,
drugs like Celexa w.
So,
I don't know if you use an
antidepressant in your attempts to
manage your chronic pain,
but that's something I would definitely
recommend.
And there was a lot of pharmaceutical
treatment and you know,
you may have run the gamut already.
I know lots of people who have chronic
pain have done that,
but,
and also stimulants,
like the adhd medications,
um,
can also be helpful in the management of
pain because stimulant medication,
um,
has an analgesic properties.
So you might want to consult a number of
specialists about your medication
regimen to see that you're medicated to
the optimal degree.
But I would definitely recommend
antidepressants and also find and,
and talking to someone,
find someone you can trust so that you
can talk to him about your genuine
limitations and how you might transcend
them.
And,
and also see if you can not torture
yourself with guilt because you aren't
able to live the productive life that
someone who's free of chronic pain
might.
I mean,
it can be unbelievably debilitating.
So mostly a while.
So I'm very sorry to hear that that's
plaguing you.
And,
and,
uh,
when you say,
how can I discipline myself?
I'm sorry,
I'm afraid I've lost the question.
You said,
how can I discipline myself at
something?
Like how can I discipline myself when
I'm in chronic pain?
It's like,
well,
I think a more appropriate question
might be how can you ensure you that you
treat yourself with the appropriate
compassion if you happen to be living
with severe chronic pain and maybe the
disciplinary element should be
secondary.
It's something like that.
So
I'm getting tired guy,
so I'm probably gonna stop at nine.
I'm going to stop at nine 30 because I'm
going to start becoming incoherent if I
don't.
So just to give you a warning,
we're going to,
we're going to run this for 15 more
minutes.
So is joining the military a respectable
path for my life.
While I would say it would likely depend
on how you conduct yourself as a soldier
it and also what your alternatives are.
But I wouldn't,
so I wouldn't say yes without
reservation,
but I certainly wouldn't say no without
reservation.
I think joining the military can be a
respectable pathway for your life.
I mean,
it's obviously a complex pathway,
but,
um,
it's,
it's not like the military isn't a
necessity.
And so if there's something in you that
tilts you in that direction,
then,
um,
perhaps that's courage in Utah.
That's certainly possible.
So,
um,
let's see.
Let's go back to the pigeon hole thing
here.
Becoming a truthful person involves
dealing with the guilt of past lives.
Is it better to come clean about old
lies even if they will ruin lives or
forgive yourself and focus on living
truthfully in the present and future?
Uh,
that's a,
that's a really good question.
Um,
I would say that there,
there are
telling the truth doesn't mean saying
everything about everything all the
time.
It's a lot more complicated than that.
First of all,
you have a right to privacy.
And second,
like,
here's an example.
This is a tricky one,
but I think it would address your
question.
Imagine that you've had an affair,
you have a happy marriage,
but you had an affair and maybe you had
an affair three years ago and maybe it
was,
you know,
a couple of weeks or a couple of months
or maybe it was even only one night and
it's driving you crazy,
you're guilty about it and you feel that
you should confess.
And I would say,
well the first question is have you
learned your lesson?
And the lesson should be you've
processed what you've done and decreased
the probability that you will do it
again to something as closely
approximating zero as possible.
And then you have to ask yourself what
makes you think that you have any right
to confess?
Because then what you would do is take
the original transgression,
which was quite severe and hurt someone
very badly revealing it.
And you might say,
well you pat yourself on the back for
being a truthful person about it.
But I would say you've already
sacrificed the right.
You have to be truthful about that.
And,
and I know I'm over simplifying it
because the only way to not oversimplify
is such a thing is to use a real example
and not a hypothetical example,
but I think many times the moral thing
to do is to take your guilty secrets to
the grave.
And maybe you can talk about them with a
therapist or you can talk about them
with someone that you really trust,
who will maintain confidentiality.
But,
um,
you don't come clean about old lives.
You're not coming clean about old lies
generally,
if that will ruin lives.
And I don't think you,
you forgive yourself precisely and focus
on living truthfully in the future.
You focus on living truthfully in the
future.
And perhaps you don't forgive yourself.
Exactly.
That doesn't mean you pound yourself
into the ground with guilt.
But if you have done things in the past
that were reprehensible and that would
destroy lives,
if we're brought to light,
then you should.
I think that generally speaking,
you should do everything you can to
limit the spread of damage as you
attempt to move truthfully into the
future.
So,
um,
you've said that a marriage must be
based on trust and transparency and
being shackled together.
How,
and for how long should you get to know
someone?
How does set a foundation?
Oh,
well,
you know,
there's no,
there's no simple answer to that.
Um,
hello.
I think that you should know someone
well enough so that you can
so that you know if you can negotiate
with them and so that you have started
to formulate a vision of your joint
future that you can both
look forward to with enthusiasm and
confidence.
So,
and of course that's going to depend to
some degree on your level of maturity,
but that means you've considered such
things as,
do you have a sufficient number of joint
interests and are you oriented in the
same direction with regards to how
you're going to handle your joint
careers and the possibility of children
and that the manner in which you're
going to interact with your in laws and
you have to start thinking about,
you have to start
considering your life together from the
perspective of practicality and
economics,
I would say.
So it can't just be that massive erotic
attraction that's associated with with
love.
Although I think that's extraordinarily
important and you're unbelievably
fortunate if you have that and you
should do everything you can to maintain
it,
which and at that takes effort that
takes real effort and will,
but you need to ally that with with
maturity and intelligence and the
maturity and intelligence is,
okay,
we're going to put our lives together.
What's
that going to look like at the level of
detail?
How are we going to handle our finances?
Where are we going to live?
Um,
what are our joint plans going to be?
It's et cetera.
One of the things that my business
partners and I plan to do in,
in,
what would you say that in a as an
analog to the self authoring suite is
that we want to develop an online
program to help people negotiate their
relationships and,
and so it would actually provide an
answer to this question in a more
comprehensive manner is that you imagine
that if you want to set up a household
with someone,
then there's a lot of things that you
need to get straight.
And you either do that by bringing your
unconscious assumptions to bear on the
situation and perhaps clashing where
they don't match or you sit down like a
conscious and aware and articulate
couple and start to negotiate what your
joint responsibilities are going to be.
And so that would be well,
who's responsible for the meals and when
and what are you going to eat and who's
going to get groceries and who's going
to pay the bills and who's going to do
which part of what household chores
there are to do and how is that going to
be laid out?
Fair.
And so you should get to know,
you should get to know the person that
you're with well enough so that you can
start discussing the real practical
issues of life and determine whether or
not you're capable of of negotiating
that.
And I don't think that necessarily means
that you should live together because
the evidence is actually quite strong.
At least the last time I looked at
people who live together are more rather
than less likely to be divorced.
Now that might be,
that might have nothing to do with the
actual act of living together.
It might be that people who are more
likely to get divorced or also those who
are more likely to merely live together.
But I don't think that's a great
solution for reasons I won't get to go
get into now.
And with regards to being shackled
together is that,
that's a complicated one.
And,
and I learned this at least in part from
reading Carl Young and the idea there is
that unless you've really made a
commitment to someone like a lifetime
commitment and that that's a serious
commitment,
one that you're not going to back out
of,
you're not going to take the
relationship with the seriousness that's
necessary to make it have the highest
possible quality and sustainability
across the course of your life.
And it's really important that it is of
that high quality and sustainability
because the relationship,
especially when it starts to produce
children,
is a,
a machine,
let's say a machine that you jointly
operate that adds immensely to the
quality of your life and the depth of
your life.
I mean you,
you have the rope and strand of your
life and your partner has the strands in
the rope of his or her life.
And then those are tied together to make
a stronger rope.
And then that unites you across time.
And then you undertake massive
adventures together.
And some of that is the establishment of
a household and the establishment of
joint careers and
the maintenance of each other's mental
and physical health and the maintenance
of a high quality sexual life and all of
that.
Very,
very challenging to do all of that.
And then the joint production end and
care of children,
which,
which sets you up properly for the last
half of your life.
So like,
I'm 55 now,
you know,
and um,
both my kids just got engaged in the
last month,
so that's pretty bloody amazing.
And they're both setting up households
and um,
and there are stepping into adulthood
and I'm fortunate enough to have them in
the city that I live in.
So Hooray for me,
that's so bloody,
uh,
fortunate that I can hardly believe it.
I mean,
we've helped them out and tried to make
it.
Um,
what would you say to make the
possibility of their living here be
something that's viable?
But I'm absolutely thrilled that they're
going to be around and I'm looking
forward immensely to having
grandchildren and like,
what else are you going to do when
you're 55,
you know,
when you're going to be 55,
it's going to,
I might have 40 more years.
Like,
what am I going to do with those years?
Well,
so I have a good marriage,
thank God for that.
And that's partly due to the outstanding
moral quality of my life.
My wife,
who I'm also extraordinarily attracted
to.
And,
uh,
you know,
we've built a life together and we've
had kids together and we're happy with
our kids.
And we had plenty of,
of struggle with our kids because one of
our children,
my daughter had serious,
serious health problems,
which she seems to have managed to
resolve partly as a consequence of her
own brilliance.
Um,
but you know,
we've set ourselves up now so that our
children are respectable and mature
young adults.
So thank God for that.
And they've got partners who we both
really like,
and they're going to have children and
well,
Hooray.
You know,
that means that this next part of my
life is going to be something that I can
advance into with a,
with a fair bit of hope and,
and,
and excitement.
And the idea of having little kids
around again,
it's thrilling because I really liked
the little kids.
They're really,
really fun.
And so th the shackled together is more
like,
it's a,
it's,
it's such a,
I may have even said that,
but it's such a cynical way of looking
at it.
It's more like what you've produced is
an unbreakable bond between two beings
and that that makes both of them,
both of them better in every way.
If it's based on,
if it's a relationship that's based on
trust and genuine communication,
it's very difficult thing to attain
because you have to be willing to tell
the truth.
And the truth is terror generally a
horrible thing,
you know?
I mean,
it's easy to tell truth when everyone
wants to hear what you have to say,
but it's very difficult to tell the
truth when no one wants to hear it,
least of all yourself.
And so marriage gets a very bad rap in
our culture and Sodas,
child rearing.
And I think that's absolute catastrophe
because really being in a longterm
relationship,
a marriage let's say,
and having children,
that's two thirds of your life.
Even if you're a highly career oriented
person,
that's two thirds of your life.
And I'm a highly career oriented and
my family has been unbelievably
important to me and has also been
something that's enabled me to be very
effective in my career because my house
has been a sanctuary for me.
And thank God for that,
especially over or many times in my
life,
but especially over the last year.
So
you should,
you should get to know someone long
enough to know that you two can
negotiate,
tell the truth with each other,
communicate and negotiate.
Because the most important part of a
relationship is the fact that you can
tell each other the truth and negotiate.
So how does it feel to be viewed as a
father figure by many people who grew up
without one?
Well,
um,
I think it's an unbelievable honor.
How's that?
And that is really what I think as it
gets a tremendous honor and I'm doing
absolutely everything I can to be worthy
of that.
And I would like to say to all the
people out there who grew up without a
father,
that's really too bad because you need a
father there to encourage you.
That's what fathers do is they
encourage,
they help make you courageous.
And if I can help people develop the
capacity to be courageous and to learn
to tell the truth and to be responsible,
then that's great.
I,
I can't imagine a better outcome for me.
And so if people are willing to help me
play that role and to use what I've been
teaching to guide them in that manner,
then hooray.
I couldn't possibly imagine a better
outcome than that.
So
how do you formulate good questions?
Giving that a well,
given that a well oriented question
seems often more critical than the
answer?
That's a great question by the way.
Um,
a lot of what you do to formulate good
questions is listen.
Like,
if you're engaged in dialogue with
someone and you really listen to what
they're saying,
the all you have to do is notice when
you don't understand what they're saying
and then ask them for clarification.
And that's the case when you're dealing
with the w the factual world as well,
you know,
um,
what you do to formulate good questions.
It is admit your own ignorance to
yourself and then tried to articulate
that ignorance as clearly and simply as
you possibly can.
And so I do that all the time when I'm
in my clinical sessions with people
because there'll be telling me the story
of their life years ago perhaps,
or maybe events over the last few weeks
or whatever.
And they'll tell me the story and,
and all detect elements of it that I
don't understand or that are unclear or
that seem self contradictory.
And so then I'll just ask,
it says,
well,
I don't,
I don't understand what you're saying
there.
You said this as far as I can tell,
but that wasn't clear.
What exactly do you mean?
And so a huge,
and,
and get them to articulate it.
And maybe I'll say,
well,
you said this now,
but you said this,
you know,
10 minutes ago.
And as far as I can tell,
those two things are opposites.
And so how do you,
how do you bridge the gap between those
things?
And,
but the critical issue with regards to
good questions is that you admit to
yourself your own ignorance and you're
not embarrassed
about it.
Like there's nothing wrong with being
ignorant.
Well that's not true.
It's a terrible thing to be ignorant,
but it's inevitable.
But it's not a moral flaw.
It's just unfortunate.
The moral flaw is in refusing to admit
to it.
And so,
you know,
the students who do really well in
classes are the ones who ask basic
questions.
They put up their hand and say,
look,
you know,
everyone else here seems to understand
this,
but this is a point that I really don't
get.
And you know,
rarely a person asks a question like
that and they haven't been listening and
they haven't been paying attention and
they're just being annoying.
But most of the time people who do that
have been paying attention and they're
asking a question that everyone else in
the room would also like to ask but is
embarrassed to do so.
So,
um,
all right.
You said that positive emotion comes
from moving towards a goal,
but also that friends and family are
crucial,
critical to a fulfilling life.
Are both of these hitting the same
neural circuits?
I would say no,
not precisely.
The,
the positive emotion that comes from
moving towards a goal looks to me to be
primarily dopaminergic.
And the,
the positive emotion that's associated
with friends and family,
I think is much more associated with the
opiate system.
And some of the best work on that was
done by Jaak Panksepp,
j a,
k,
Panksepp,
Epp.
And he wrote a book called affective
neuroscience and a variety of very,
very good scientific papers and laid
some of the initial groundwork for
understanding the relationship between
the functioning of the endogenous opiate
systems and social bonding.
So no,
I don't think they're the same.
They're,
they share overlap because the opiate
circuits can activate the dopaminergic
circuits.
Um,
but,
but there,
there are definitely differences in the
system that,
that,
that seeks out goals.
And that's the system that Panksepp
actually called the seeking system.
That's the dopaminergic system and the
more affiliate of systems.
So there are definitely overlapping but
separate neural circuits.
And so,
um,
I have to take away from your
interpretations,
but for a skeptic,
how do you know that your analysis of
Biblical stories are true?
Well,
that's a great question,
but the issue there is what,
what you mean by true?
I would say there are functional because
I'm a pragmatist and I mean that
technically I believe that our
conceptual structures are tools to help
us orient ourselves in the world.
And so the issue for me is,
are the interpretations that I'm making
of the biblical stories,
useful functional tools for people to
use to operate in the world?
And how can I demonstrate that their
canonical interpretations of the Bible?
Well,
I can't demonstrate that.
What I can say is that people can listen
to them and make their own judgment
about whether or not they're useful and
valid,
which I think is a better way of
thinking about it then then true.
Because truth in literature and
mythology is a very tricky concept.
And especially in a book like the Bible,
which as I pointed out in the first
Biblical lecture is the first truly
hyperlinked text where every,
almost every verse interacts with almost
every other verse.
And so it's an end.
It's endlessly deep and there's an
endless number in some sense of valid
interpretations that could come forth
from it.
But,
um,
okay,
there's more to the answer to that
question,
but I can't go into it for now because
I'm,
well,
we're running out of time and I'm
running out of energy.
In fact,
it is nine 30 and so,
um,
and so,
and my daughter has just showed up in my
wife has told me that.
So I think I'm actually going to take
this opportunity to bow out and to say
once again,
thank you.
Um,
this is my wife by the way.
I might as well what
I was watching the video and I thought
she was still in the room.
The video is lagged.
So I was actually interacting with a
ghost there for a minute.
Um,
I wanted to thank you all again for
supporting me.
Um,
I also want to say I know that for you
patrons that have been supporting me for
at the $200 level,
I know that I promise to give you
producer credit on the biblical videos
and I haven't forgotten that.
I just haven't done it yet because I
would like to say because I'd been doing
a bunch of other things and I do
actually believe that's true,
but I haven't forgotten and I still want
to do it.
And I think it is important and you have
been crucial to the production of these,
this series,
all of you patrion supporters.
And I'm hoping that I can continue to
put the support that you've been
offering me to,
to ever better use.
And hopefully you can also help guide me
in doing that in these q and a's because
it gives us a chance to,
uh,
to communicate.
So,
um,
well,
so I'm going to say good night and
thanks a lot to all of you and we'll see
you in a month.
Um,
get your act together,
all of you,
and do what you can,
man.
It'd be a wonderful thing to see.
And if enough people start doing that,
maybe we can turn this whole mess
around.
That'd be lovely.
And maybe it won't take that many people
to start it,
so that'd be a good goal.
So good night.