Hi everyone.
So here we are for the first q and a for
2018.
Um,
there's 514 questions lined up.
I don't think I'm going to get to all of
them.
So it's been a busy time since the last
time I did a q and.
A.
Um,
some of you probably know about the,
when Lindsay Shepherd a at Wilfrid
laurier university where a teaching
assistant was brought in front of a
tribunal,
uh,
because she had the temerity to play a
video where I was discussing bill see 16
on a public television show.
Um,
that's been quite the national and
interval national scandal I would say.
And so I made a bit of a video about
that today,
which I haven't launched yet.
Uh,
contains a message to junior high and
high school students.
I'm recommending to them that they,
well,
I guess you'll have to watch the video.
Um,
I didn't mean to make it a cliffhanger
like that,
but then as soon as I said that I
thought better of it and thought maybe
I'll just wait.
But anyways,
let's take a look here.
Steve a has the first question,
how can we know the difference between
unhealthy repression and healthy self
restraint of sexuality?
Well,
I would say,
you know,
part of what constitutes ethics,
let's say first of all,
let's start,
let's think about ethics to begin with.
So what's the point of conducting your
life ethically?
The answer to that isn't so that you
follow the proper rules precisely the,
the answer to that is so that you
balance your life so that it says
productive and meaningful as it can
possibly be.
And that would be productive and
meaningful for you with any luck,
but also for people around you that
would even be better.
And,
and for you now and next week and into
the future.
So it's sort of a variation of the
philosopher Emmanuel counts moral
dictum,
which was act such that your action
becomes a moral,
a universal,
something like that.
Although I think that it's,
it's better phrased across time and
across people like that.
Um,
so when you're thinking about an ethic
that has to do with any fundamental
motivation like sexuality,
you have to think about it in the
context of the rest of your life.
Um,
the,
the question is whether or not,
what,
what did I say?
What,
what did I read at one point that I
really liked with regards to sexuality?
Okay.
Who's in control?
That's the,
is it you or is it the sexuality that's
in control is have you integrated your
sexual life into the rest of your life
so that the whole thing makes a
harmonious balance?
And Are you in charge or is it in
charge,
so to speak?
Because if you're not in charge with
that harmonious balance,
then things are going to waver wildly
out of control and you're going to find
yourself in dreadful trouble.
That happens whenever any given driver
me really any given value predominates
to the exclusion of all else.
Now,
it seems to me that sexuality is best
handled within the confines of a
relationship.
Um,
that's the classic ethical solution to
the problem.
It's because sexuality brings with it a
tremendous amount of responsibility.
Now,
people don't like to think that,
especially people who I would say are
low in conscientiousness,
let's say are high in impulsivity.
It's easy for people to believe in,
what would you call it?
Casual sex,
which is not something that I think
exists because I don't think you can
divorce sex from its sociological or
political or economic or psychological
consequences.
And I would say the endless scandals
that have plagued the United States in
particular in the last year with regards
to sexual behavior are proof positive
that there's no such thing as casual
sex.
I think the reason for that is that the
consequences of sex are too dramatic.
It's not just pregnancy and disease,
let's say,
which are both,
uh,
as dramatic as consequences can be in
life,
but also the fact that
there's no disentangling sexual behavior
from emotional behavior.
Or maybe you could say even worse if you
try to disentangle your sexual behavior
from your emotional behavior,
then I think what happens is that you
end up cold and cynical.
I mean,
if you're,
let's say if you're a a cereal,
if you're us,
uh,
if you have a lot of one night stands
and a lot of casual partners,
then first of all there's not much
discrimination between one partner and
the other.
And so in some sense you're in a loop
and just repeating the same act over and
over,
but you can't,
there's nothing deep about it.
There's nothing that,
that enables you to establish a
relationship with another person.
And I think that that's a,
I think that you corrupt your soul in
that way and that you hurt yourself
across time and of course you're going
to hurt other people as well.
So I'm not a big admirer of the casual
sex idea.
I think it's a demented adolescents
fantasy.
Uh,
fundamentally it just doesn't work out
in the real world.
Now,
healthy self restraint.
Well,
with regards to sexuality,
it's the same with everything else is
that there's,
there's the necessity to forego
immediate gratification for the purpose
of medium to longterm thriving,
let's say.
So if your sexuality is integrated in an
ethic that encompasses the rest of your
life,
and if it serves that ethic,
then I would say it's properly
restrained.
If it's unhealthily repressed,
well then you're angry and bitter and
resentful and cursing the opposite sex
or perhaps the same sex.
If you happen to be gay for failing to
recognize your particular form of
sexual,
uh,
what would you call attractiveness?
I think resentment and anger are good
indication that there's something wrong
with the manner in which your sexuality
is restraint.
So I hope hopefully that's a decent
answer,
Trev moocs as why are dragons in western
culture bringers of death and
destruction that must be slain while in
the east.
They're portant of good fortune to be
revered.
Well,
I,
that's a great question by the way.
Um,
the,
the Dragon,
I already defined the dragon at some
point,
partly from a book I read a while back
on dragons as a tree cat,
snake bird.
The idea in the book was that the Dragon
was a images stick representation of the
class of all predators,
which means also might be why dragons
also breathe fire because fire was
undoubtedly a common destructive agent
in our evolutionary past,
but the dragon is the most primordial
sim symbol of that which lurks beyond,
which is known.
In fact,
it's even more primordial that that
because it even is that which lurks
beyond what is unknown in some sense.
Remember Don Rumsfeld,
unknown,
unknown unknowns.
Well,
that's basically the drag it.
There are some unknowns that pop up that
you can master right away and you could
kind of think of those as known
unknowns,
but unknown unknown's are those things
that pop up that you don't know about.
You didn't even,
you had no idea whatsoever that they
even existed anyways.
What's the character of an unknown?
Unknown?
Well,
part of it's terrifying because it can,
it can.
It can do you in,
right,
but part of it's also positive and
because it,
anything that's truly unknown brings it
with a tremendous amount of new
possibility.
That's why dragons hoard gold or why
they also heard princesses or guard
princesses hoard,
I would say is the right word.
So I don't think the dragon in the West
is a fully negative symbol because the
dragon has gold associated with it or
virgin.
The reason for that is that the hero who
confronts the Dragon gets the Virgin.
And that hasn't changed.
That's,
that's a story as old as time.
And I don't think it'll ever change as
long as there are human beings.
Now why the Chinese put stress on the
positive side and the West put stress on
the negative side is difficult to say.
I might say because the Chinese got
organized so early,
I have a sneaking suspicion that it was
easier for them to see a little bit of
chaos is something positive,
something necessary and positive as a
counterbalance to tremendous
organizational weight of their state.
Um,
that's the best,
best answer that I've been able to
formulate.
Um,
so,
so anyways,
the dragon is a very complex and
ambivalence symbol.
It,
it combines everything into one symbol,
positive and negative.
And then you can stress the positive or
you can stress the negative.
You could also say to some degree that
whether a dragon is positive or negative
depends to some degree on the manner in
which you approach it.
Because the psychological reality is
that dragons approached voluntarily,
well,
small are most likely to be positive and
that's a really good thing to know in
your life.
Uh,
it's a good reason.
It's a good rule of thumb to help you
stop avoiding things that you shouldn't
avoid so that they don't grow and
magnified beyond your capacity to deal
with them.
You often mentioned disciplining
children so they behave.
What is your advice for making them
behave without resorting to corporal
punishment?
Well,
first of all,
it depends on what you mean by corporal
punishment.
Um,
timeout could be regarded as corporal
punishment.
It also depends very much on the age of
the child.
Um,
at say a two year old,
well,
in my new book,
by the way,
I have a chapter in there called don't
let your children do anything that makes
you dislike them.
And the reason that I wrote a chapter
about that is because people who let
their children do things that make them
dislike them,
end up disliking them.
And because there's a huge power
differential,
generally speaking between adults and
children,
if you end up disliking your children
because they're not behaving well,
they're behaving disgracefully say,
or they're,
or they're challenging your position in
the authority hierarchy to regularly
something you won't put up with.
By the way,
even if you think you will,
it's necessary to get your disciplinary
routine straight.
So the first thing I would say is figure
out what the rules are.
There shouldn't be too many.
Um,
for two year olds,
basically they have to know what no
means.
And they also have to learn as they
approached three not to kick,
hit bite or steel essentially.
Now it's easy to train a two year old,
but no means you can actually start with
a child that's only 13 months old at
child that can cry,
let's say that or that can crawl.
Let's say that you have a child is
starting to crawl and wants to explore
the house.
So the first thing you do,
if you have any sense is try to get rid
of most things that the child could
cause a tremendous amount of trouble
with,
uh,
to,
to the things or to the child so that
it's reasonably safe.
Um,
and then the child is going to want to
want to crawl around and get into
everything.
And so,
but maybe there are things you don't
want him or her to get into.
Like maybe there's a uh,
oh,
what would we say?
Maybe there's a tablecloth and on top of
the tablecloth there's a plant or maybe
there's some plants on the floor and
when the child is crawling and goes off
to do something that he or she
shouldn't,
um,
you can just grab his leg and you know,
gently but firmly and say no.
And the child will keep trying to move
forward because they're stubborn little
blighters and you can continue to say
no.
And if you persist with saying no,
then the child will eventually give up
and sort of go limp.
Now,
now and often the child will cry when
you do that.
And of course that might make you feel
guilty,
but what that means is that you've
effectively brought to behavior to a
halt.
And if you do that 10 times,
you've got to watch your child and don't
stop them from exploring things that
they need to explore it.
You want to use this sort of thing with
judiciously.
You can grab them by the leg and say,
no,
no.
And wait until they give up.
Usually they'll cry and then you can let
them go.
And then soon after you do that about 10
times soon.
Then if you just say no with the same
tone of voice,
the child will generally,
what happens,
the child will immediately cry and then
stop.
And then after about 10 repeats of no
without having the lake grabbed,
then no,
we'll just produce stopping of the
behavior.
And that's unbelievably useful because
as soon as your,
you train your child to understand what
no means,
then they really have free reign of the
house in some sense with relative
minimal supervision from you.
First of all,
they can learn what things they're not
supposed to get into.
And it's amazing how fast children can
learn that and how fast they can
generalize to the class of things that
they shouldn't get into.
Like you don't have to teach them every
single thing.
They can generalize very rapidly.
That's not much different than thinking,
but also once they are capable of
understanding what no means,
you have an extremely potent means of
helping them regulate their behavior
with a minimum of intervention.
So that's unbelievably useful.
So now let's say you have a two year old
who's pretty contentious and two year
olds are pretty contentious.
Some of them in particular because both
5% of two year olds,
most of them are male,
are quite aggressive by temperament.
And those are the ones that if you put
with other two year olds will frequently
kick hit,
bite or steel.
Not all kids are like that,
but some are.
Most of them gets socialized out of that
by the time they about four.
Now let's say you have an at two,
they also start to experiment with
saying no,
uh,
back.
And also with misbehaving,
although they can do that even younger
than that.
So if you have a two year old who's
particularly rambunctious and who
decides he isn't going to listen to you,
we use he in this example because it's
boys that are more likely to misbehave
and not or not listen.
You can,
you can pick them up and you know by the
arms.
Now you got to get your attitude right
because you don't want to be stupid.
You don't want to let your kid make you
mad,
especially when they're really little
because you're really big and you can
hurt them and so you gotta,
you gotta have a clue.
That's why you want to get the rules of
discipline in order.
The minimum rules of discipline and why
you want to have a strategy,
but let's say your two or two year old
is insisting upon doing something that
you don't want him to do,
like inserting a fork into an electrical
outlet and you just can't have that and
so you can say no.
Hopefully you've already done the no
training that I recommended.
And then if that doesn't work,
what I recommend doing is picking the
child up by the arms and then putting
them on the steps.
Say,
look,
you sit there until you're ready to
listen.
Now,
um,
are usually the child will sit there and
then the rule has to be something like
you can get up as soon as you ready to
be a civilized human being again and you
can refer to yourself,
your own attitude during a process like
that.
Because if the child does comply and
sits on the steps and then comes and
says,
I'm ready to be good,
and you like them again and you to be
honest about this,
then you can tell that he's honest in
his decision to rejoin the civilized
world.
Now sometimes if you put a two year old
that's particularly rambunctious on the
staircase,
that as soon as you let go of their
arms,
they'll run off and that can be a game
or it can just be an act of defiance.
And in that case,
then you go get them and he put him back
on the steps and you do that several
times if necessary.
And if that,
that becomes a game,
then you sit on the step and you hold
him by the arms.
Remember no anger cause he's just too,
for God's sake,
you know,
you don't have to be angry is put them
on the steps and hold them and say,
look,
I'm not letting you go until you sit
there and behave.
And so if you hold them for a while,
he'll squirm and look away and so forth.
But you can get it as a tension if
you're a little bit stubborn,
you hold him there and say you're going
to sit there until I decide that you can
leave.
And so you hold them and he'll squirm
and,
but you can outwait them if your
patient,
but you gotta make the time.
And then eventually he'll stop squirming
and you can let him go.
And then you can sit there and watch
him.
And when you think he's,
you know,
decided that he's going to be a
civilized creature,
then you can say that's good and you can
give them a pat on the head and you can
say,
let's go back and do what we're doing.
And the rule has to be,
you see that the punishment not only has
to bring the behavior to haul in the
most merciful manner possible,
but it's still effective.
But it also has to satisfy your need for
order and justice so that you don't
carry resentment and irritation about
the child's misbehavior forward with
you.
Because you don't want to kid yourself
about what sort of Nice person you are.
You're not nearly as nice a person as
you think.
And no one likes to be,
um,
brought down the authority hierarchy by
a recalcitrant two year old.
So in almost all circumstances,
those processes will suffice.
Um,
there's other disciplinary strategies
that you can use to that are more
positive.
I mean,
one of the things that you can do,
for example,
if you're,
let's say you want to get your child to
go to bed,
which is a really good idea,
you should set a stable bedtime for your
child.
And I would say if they're under four,
it should be around or seven or
something like that because you want to
have a life and you want to have a life
with your wife so that you don't end up
hating your child.
And so one of the things you can do if
you want to train your child to go to
bed at eight,
so maybe he's not going to bed until 10
right now and you want to fix that.
So you say,
okay,
go to the grocery store or a little
convenience store and buy 10 little
gifts and it can be cheap.
Kids don't care,
they're not very bright,
you know you can fool them.
So by 10 little things that you think
your kid would like and wrap them up and
then put them up on a shelf where he can
see them but can't get out them.
Then you say,
look kid,
I'm going to put you to bed at nine 30
tonight and uh,
if you don't get out of bed then I'm
going to give you one of these.
I'm going to give you one of these gifts
in the morning.
So,
or if the,
or you can do it another way too.
If the child is always giving you a
rough time about getting ready for bed
and going to bed,
you can say,
look,
if you're,
if you put on your pajamas without
fussing and you climb into bed,
then I'll give you one of these little
gifts.
And so then if that works,
then the child can have a little gift
and he's in bed at nine 30 and then you
can make it nine and then you can make
it eight 30 and then you can make it
eight and those are called,
that's called success of approximation,
right?
You hit the target,
you specify the target that you want the
child to achieve and then use small
rewards not too often in order to attain
that goal.
And those are unbelievably effective
strategies and they can actually be
pretty fun.
But I would say the advice to not let
your child do anything that makes you
dislike them is really,
really useful.
Um,
you want to talk this over with your
partner too so that you have your
disciplinary strategies and your rules
talked out so that you don't work at
cross purposes to one another.
So,
okay,
so that's probably good enough for that.
Can we take the biblical,
Andrew Wells asks,
can we take the biblical story seriously
enough with us without also keeping
biblical traditions?
What's the psychological impact of group
gathering church going?
I think we could take the biblical
stories seriously enough,
but I don't think that it's particularly
easy.
Um,
the traditions bind the community
gather.
Now I'm saying that and I don't go to
church,
you know,
and the reason I don't go to church is
because while it drives me crazy to
speak,
frankly,
I haven't been able to sit in a
situation like that ever since I was
well ever.
Really.
That's really the truth of it ever.
Um,
I'm not convinced that that's a good
thing because I do believe,
and I've had good conversations about
this with Jonathan Patio,
I do believe that communal return to the
source of the community's ethics is
actually a necessary thing.
And maybe I'm atoning for my past sins
by doing these biblical lectures at the
moment,
which is something that's communal.
So,
and then because there's also something
about going where a bunch of other
people are to reaffirm your commitment
to,
to the good that you're also all aiming
at,
that's,
that's got some power in it.
And,
and I don't think that that's something
that we should forgo.
I think it's dangerous.
I mean,
look,
even if you're cynical about church,
and I guess I would put myself in that
category,
it's,
it's certainly the case that communal
church going in the 1950s say,
provided the average person with at
least an hour a week where they were
contemplating,
no matter how poorly the purpose of
ethics in life and,
and the idea of a higher purpose in a
higher meaning in life.
And you gotta think that spending an
hour a week thinking about that is
better than never doing it at all.
So I don't know how to,
that tradition can be revivified in a
meaningful way,
but I think it's,
I really do think it's a catastrophe
that we've lost it because we don't have
a center,
an ethical center that holds our
community together.
And the consequence of that is that
we're fragmenting quite badly.
So
Edwin Raj Kumar says,
I was wondering what your thoughts are
on meditation and if you practice it
yourself.
Well,
that's a good question.
I think I practice it a lot and look,
when I listened to someone,
or even when I listened to myself,
but let's say when I listened to someone
in my clinical practice,
I think I do it in a meditative way in
that I sit and listen and I wait for
thoughts to appear rather than
voluntarily thinking.
So I clear my mind.
I try to keep my agenda's off the table,
my agendas,
whatever they are,
except that I want the best for my
client in this hour and the best say by
their definition.
And mine jointly decided because that's
all part of discussion and then I
listened very carefully and I wait for
the reactions that occur within me and
then I share them.
And I think that's a meditative
exercise.
I think it's different than voluntary
thinking.
It's like,
you know there's a statement in the new
testament that says a knock and the door
will open asking you will receive.
Now
that's a meditative,
that's a,
that's a call to a meditative mode of
existence.
It's like,
well often what I do for example,
if I want to solve a problem is I,
if I have a problem with my own behavior
or maybe I'm having problems in my
family is all go sit on a bed or a chair
and they'll think,
okay,
I would like an answer to this.
I would like to know what the answer to
this and I'm willing to accept whatever
answer is appropriate and cause usually
you get an answer that you don't like.
Right?
If it's a real answer,
it's not something that you're going to
be all that happy about and then
magically so to speak and answer
appears.
And I think that's a meditative practice
and
the meditative practice is part to clear
your mind of your proximal concerns and
to concentrate more deeply on what might
be regarded as eternally true and to
open yourself up for a revelation in
relationship to what is eternally true.
And I found that incredibly effective
and I think that you can live like that.
Um,
you just have to abandon your proximal
pursuits.
Now in my new book,
again,
I wrote a chapter about that called do
what is meaningful and what not,
what is expedient and it's a bit of a
meditation on the sermon on the mount,
I would say because of the essential
message in the sermon on the Mount,
which is the foundational document of
Western civilization as far as I'm
concerned,
essentially,
is that you should orient yourself
ultimately towards the highest good that
you can conceive.
And I've tried to formulate that and I
mentioned earlier in this q and a that
the highest good that you can conceive,
it should be something like what would
be good for you now and good for you
tomorrow and next week and next month
and next year.
So good for you and all the future use
that might exist.
And also at the same time,
good for your family and good for the
community,
you know,
conceptualize narrowly and broadly and
good now for your family and the
community and then also into the future.
So it's something like that.
It's,
it's a balance of goods that stretches
across time and you,
you have to decide if that's what you
really want.
And my sense would be you haven't gotten
anything better to aim at and that you
should aim at.
The best thing that you can aim at for a
whole bunch of reasons.
One is if you don't aim at something,
you're certainly not going to attain it.
And if you're going to aim at something,
why not aim for the best thing that you
can think of?
And if you do aim for the best thing
that you can think of and you make any
progress whatsoever,
it's extremely exciting.
And if you do aim for the best thing you
can take up and you make some progress,
then it's very life affirming and
validating and that sort of quells your
anxiety and your existential pain.
And so he get yourself properly oriented
and,
and the sermon on the mount basically
suggest that you do that by orienting
yourself towards God.
And for the psychological purposes,
we could conceptualize God as the
highest good that you can conceive of
and then you concentrate on the day.
And so you can get up in the morning and
you can think,
well,
I want the best possible thing to
happen.
And so what is it that I should do to
serve that?
And if you ask that genuinely,
and that's an a meditative way,
I will say you get an answer to that
right away.
Now the problem is is that it's usually
an answer that involves some kind of
sacrifice.
It means that instead of doing what you
would like to do impulsively right now,
you're more likely to have to go do
something.
You know,
that you've been avoiding.
And that's difficult.
But if you do that,
then you'll have some,
you know,
you can also leave in your day with some
pleasure,
uh,
to reward yourself for doing something
difficult.
But if you,
if you live that way,
then I think that your,
your house stays clean and your family
stays organized and the state doesn't
rock and all that.
And all that's extremely,
extremely good.
So anonymous says,
how do I deal with the fact that I'm a
pedophile and should I tell my family
and friends it?
Um,
I can't answer the second part of that.
Should I tell my family and friends
because I don't know your family and
friends and I don't know how you would
go about telling them.
So I can't make a piece of,
I can't make any advice about that or I
can't offer you any advice about that.
Um,
I would say that if you have the
opportunity,
you should probably go speak to a
counselor or priest or someone that you
trust
because you're going to have to figure
out how to deal with that and,
but you should also maybe,
and that's about the best I can do with
that.
I'm not an expert in the treatment of
pedophilia.
And so I can't offer you any great
clinical wisdom,
but I would say that you need a plan.
You need to plan and you have to,
and I would include in that plan the
absolutely catastrophic consequences of
not regulating that behavior properly.
And you should really think it through
because that pedophilic impulse,
let's say could lead you into seven
different sorts of hell.
You and whoever you happen to tangle up
in it.
And you might want to avoid severn diff.
You might want to avoid seven different,
seven different forms of hell.
And in order to do that,
given the proclivity that you described,
then you're going to have to have a
plan.
Now look,
lots of people have impulses that they
have a hard time controlling.
You know,
alcoholics can't drink alcohol and
cocaine addicts can't take cocaine and
most people can't what manifest on
trammeled sexual behavior.
And so it certainly within the capacity
of human beings to regulate impulses
that aren't in there or other's best
interests.
So I wouldn't regard it as a hopeless
pursuit.
But it does seem to me that it's
something that you might want to talk to
someone you trust about because it's,
it's a complicated issue and it's a
proclivity that's likely to lead you in
a direction that would be,
let's call it sub optimal.
I was wondering what you thought of
Santa Clause,
if it's a healthy thing for parents to
practice,
what's the psychological impact of lying
to your child?
Look,
I think the,
I think lying is the wrong way of
thinking about this.
Santa Claus is a game.
It's a game of pretend and children play
games of pretend all the time,
you know,
so I don't see any harm in it at all.
Now,
you know,
you don't want to prolong that belief
beyond its natural end point.
But it's a,
it's a massive game and it's a lovely
game.
And I don't believe that there's
anything harmful in it in the least.
So now what's the psychological impact
lying to your child?
Let's we can think about that more
generally.
Don't lie to your children.
Don't lie.
Period.
Lying is a really bad idea.
It's a really bad idea.
Um,
it never works.
You might think it works,
but that's only because you're blind to
the consequences and probably willfully
blind.
Plus it's a terrible weight.
You know,
if you,
if you don't lie,
there's a lot fewer things to keep track
of.
Your life is a lot more pristine and
crystally and,
and then things that you,
that come your way maybe you deserve in
some small measure and it's a bad idea
to lie now,
but I don't think it's a bad idea to
play pretend games with your children.
I think that's okay.
You once mentioned you were planning on
making an Iq test available alongside
the big five aspects scale.
One,
is that in the works?
Yes.
We have an Iq test that we use for
business testing.
Um,
although we haven't made it available
publicly yet.
It is in the works but not for a while
what we're doing instead.
And that's because it has to be,
well there's a bunch of work we still
have to do on it to generate the reports
so that they're going to be truly usable
to people.
Now that I would say it's about three or
four months work is necessary to do
that.
Um,
what we are doing right now with the big
five aspects scale though,
so that's that understand myself.com is
producing a dyad version and so we're
working on the boyfriend girlfriend
version right now.
So what that'll mean is that when you go
there and you do your personality test
and your girlfriend say,
does her personality test,
that you'll both be able to generate a
dual report that describes the
similarities and differences between you
and your partner and where you're likely
to see eye to eye on things and where
you're likely to defer and what that's
going to mean and what you might want to
do about it if you know what you might
be able to do about it.
And this we're hoping this will be
really useful because temperamental
differences are a lot of the reason that
people have a hard time getting along
that and complete inability whatsoever
to state what they actually want and to
negotiate,
which has a completely different issue.
I want to build a program to help people
negotiate too at some point in the
future.
That's part of our future plan.
But the next development plan is to,
well there's two of them is to get the
high school version of the self
authoring program up and running and
that my program or keeps promising it in
two weeks and I,
these things always take longer than
expected but I'm sure we'll get it out
in the first quarter of 2018 and then
also the dyad version of the big five
aspects scale.
Uh,
that should be out in the first quarter
of 2018 as well.
And then I'm not sure if the Iq test
will be next on the development track.
See,
one of the things we'd like to do with
understand myself is to expand it out
into a career,
um,
planning process.
Because look at it this way.
You know,
if you have an Iq of a hundred,
which is the average Iq,
so that would place you sort of in the
middle of the average high school class.
Being a lawyer is probably not a great
career choice for you unless you're
unbelievably conscientious because
you're going to be competing with people
who have a verbal facility say and a
problem solving capacity that far
exceeds yours.
And you're going to have to work like
mad too to just be reasonably competent.
And so what seems to be more logical is
to take a good look at your intellectual
prowess as given cause it's,
it's very powerfully biologically
influenced and to pick a domain of,
of career that you could excel in.
Because why not pick a domain that you
can excel?
And there's lots of different things
that you can be.
And so you want to consult your
temperament.
So if you're agreeable,
then you probably want to work with
people.
And if you're disagreeable,
you probably want to work with things.
And if you're extroverted,
you want to have a job that involves
sales and social activity.
And if you're introverted,
you want to work alone.
And if you're open,
you need to do something creative and
entrepreneurial and so on.
So we have to consult your temperament
to see where you would be properly
slotted.
And then you have to consider your
intelligence so that you can find a
niche where you're most likely to excel
and those niches exists.
So,
um,
we'd like to combine the Iq test with
the big five aspects scale so that we
can give people reasonable career
advice.
It's been a longterm goal.
And so those are all on the table and I
have good program team working on them,
but they're very complicated things and
they take a lot of time and we don't
want to make a mistake and all of that.
So,
but maybe the couple's version and the
high school version of the couple's
version of the personality test and high
school version of the self authoring in
this quarter and maybe maybe the career
counseling version of the big five
aspects scale in the next year.
That would be lovely.
Um,
that's probably overly optimistic for
the second part,
but
you often give advice to young adults to
help them avoid some of the pitfalls of
life.
Any advice for those of us who are 40
plus who have already faltered?
Look first,
Graham,
this is Graham.
Everybody who is 40 pluses has already
faulted.
But,
but I'm presuming that you mean faltered
in a manner that appears to you to be
above out above the average,
right?
Well,
what I would really recommend is I think
that you should,
if you haven't already,
you should go do the future authoring
program and maybe the past authoring
program too,
because you should figure out exactly
how you faltered.
Like what exactly did you do wrong by
your own buy your own analysis,
right?
I'm not saying,
well what social rules did you break?
Although that's not a bad initial
guideline.
It's like,
so in the self authoring suite,
there's a past authoring module and it
asks you to break your life I to 70
parks and then to consider the
emotionally significant or practically
significant events within each epoch and
detail out there,
emotional nature and their consequences.
And so on.
And one of the things you might want to
figure out is,
well,
when you say that you faltered,
like what do you mean exactly?
And I mean,
exactly go over your life with a fine
tooth comb.
This is what Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn did
by the way,
in the ghoulag before he wrote the Gulag
archipelago,
he went over his life and said,
okay,
well like where did I go wrong?
What did I squander?
What mistakes did I make and what did I
do right?
So that you can orient yourself now and
then you want to think,
and this is why we built the future
authoring program.
Well look,
you got 40 years left,
man.
So what do you want them to be like?
So what do you want to aim at?
You know,
at least how are you going to minimize
the misery if,
if,
if nothing else.
And so you need a plan.
And then what you need to do is to
figure out how to work day to day so
that you incrementally approach that
plan.
So I have another chapter in this new
book,
um,
called compare yourself to who you were
yesterday rather than to who someone
else's today.
That's really a useful psychological
stance for someone who's 30 and over in
particular took 20 year olds can still
kinda compare themselves to other 20
year olds because all 20 year olds in
some way are the same,
but 40 year olds are really different
from each other and sore 30 year olds
for that matter.
So you might think,
okay,
well
here's a,
here's a meditative strategy for for
ceasing to falter.
You could wake up in the morning or you
could do this at night before you go to
bed and you could think,
okay,
look,
I want to structure my day to moral so
that when I,
when I'm done with the day,
my life is in slightly better order than
it was when I woke up this morning.
Just slightly better because incremental
progress is massively,
massively effective because it bears a
exponential fruit.
I just like a bank account,
um,
compounds,
incremental progress compounds with
time.
So you can get up in the morning and you
could think,
okay,
there's some things in my life that I
could put in order today.
They're usually things you don't want to
do.
As I mentioned earlier,
what could I do today that would help
put my life in order that I would do?
You have to ask yourself.
You can't tell yourself.
You have to ask yourself what would you
do?
And then maybe you have to say,
well,
or maybe you have to say,
under what conditions would I be willing
to do something to put my life in
further ordered today?
What little reward would I need to give
myself?
And these have to be questions you can
like take out the whip and boss yourself
around because you'll find that you're a
terrible master and a worst slave.
And so you can get along ways if you
look low enough.
One of the things Carl Jung said,
which I really liked,
was that modern people don't see God
because they don't look low enough.
They don't have the humility.
Now you said that you have already
faulted.
So it sounds like you've got the
humility already intact.
So I would say think about what you
want.
Think about what you know around you
isn't set right cause you'll know,
make a list of things that are around
you that aren't right.
And then start thinking about small
things you can do,
like trivial things that even a fool
like yourself could manage that would
orient you in the right direction and
help straighten out your life and try
that for a year before you decide that
you're a failure.
You know?
Because you'll find that if you put that
into practice for a year,
that things will be a lot better.
And like I said,
you got 40 years left so you're not,
you're not done yet.
And so,
okay.
The other thing I would say too is,
yeah,
it isn't exactly that.
I would say forgive yourself because you
know,
that's just a cliche.
But I would say that once you've
decided,
once you what you've done wrong and
you've put into practice some,
some strategies to rectify that,
that don't,
you don't have to beat yourself any more
than is necessary for you to learn.
Which is a good rule of thumb with
regards to treating yourself and also to
treating other people.
So
I don't think my wife loves are
internationally adopted daughter and she
won't go to counseling with me.
My house is filled with tyranny and
anger.
Any advice?
Anonymous.
Wow.
Okay.
That's a loaded,
that's a set of loaded questions,
man.
I don't think my wife loves are
internationally adopted daughter.
Well,
the first question would be why not?
But she in on the adoption,
for example,
was it partly her decision?
Here's a possibility.
Maybe you could ask your under what
conditions,
ask her more specifically why she
doesn't like you're internationally
adopted daughter.
It's too vague.
I don't think my wife loves are
internationally adopted daughter.
Break it down.
Maybe it's something like there are 15
things about our life with our
internationally adopted daughter that my
wife does not appreciate.
Now,
maybe some of those things are the way
that the daughter behaves.
I don't know how old she is or anything
else about her and
differentiate your problem.
It's too vague.
You'll never solve it this way because
loves isn't the right word.
See if you can write down 30 reasons why
your wife is annoyed about your current
situation.
Um,
and maybe you'll have to differentiate
each of those 30 into 10 more,
right?
Maybe there's 300 reasons.
And then see if you can start asking her
about fixing some of the reasons that
you differentiate it.
Because obviously you can't go up to her
and say you have to start loving are
internationally adopted daughter.
That's just not going to work.
And you already know that.
Um,
but if you break that down into the 20
reasons why she doesn't like your
daughter,
then maybe you can figure out a way that
some progress might be made on one of
those problems.
And maybe if you take that approach for
a whole year,
then she'll go from like,
she'll at least hit neutral or something
like that.
Um,
that's the best I can do.
Given that I only have three sentences
to go on.
So differentiate the problem and then
solve the smaller problems.
You have talked about the difference
between intelligence and wisdom.
Jason Clark,
you have talked about the difference
between intelligence and wisdom.
Saying,
EH,
intelligence isn't a shortcut to wisdom.
Well,
let's,
let's point something else out,
man.
Stupidity isn't a shortcut to wisdom
either.
What is your definition of wisdom?
Okay,
well,
there's the Old Testament view.
That's the fear of God is the beginning
of wisdom.
That's a good one.
I think wisdom is in part the
willingness to come to terms the
knowledge of your own capacity for
malevolence.
That's wisdom.
The the desire to rectify that,
the wish to set the world on a pathway
that leads it closer to have and farther
away from hell.
That's wisdom.
The humility to know that there's more
things that you don't know then that you
know and that you should be open to what
you don't know when people inform you of
it because it's better to learn that it
is to walk nose first into a wall or
blind folded off a cliff.
The knowledge that you don't have the
right to be a judge of being without
having given it your utmost.
That's wisdom,
wisdom.
What else?
The knowledge.
Wisdom is also the knowledge that hell
is real enough so that you should do
everything you can to avoid either
inhabiting it or producing it.
That's what I learned from,
uh,
from psychological analysis of the
history of the 20th.
Hell's real enough and,
and you,
you're,
you're duty bound.
Let's say your honor bound,
you're ethically bound to do the
opposite of whatever produces those
hellish circumstances.
Amy Pellegrini says,
why is self sabotage such a future
feature in human life?
You know what?
I have a chapter about that in my new
book too.
Um,
which chapter is it now?
I think it's it.
I can't always match the content with
the chapter title.
Oddly enough.
I think it's the chapter about picking
friends that are good for you.
See?
Oh yes,
I have it right here.
And I didn't set that up by the way it,
I genuinely did remember,
make friends with the people
who wants the best for you.
Was that it?
No.
Treat yourself like someone you were
responsible for helping.
There we go.
MMM.
Why are self sabotage such a feature?
Okay,
here's a couple of reasons.
The first is,
is that there's a lot of responsibility
with success,
right?
So if you,
if you say yes to things and you do a
good job and,
and you bear a large burden,
then you have to carry it.
And a lot of that might be success.
But you know,
failure is a lot easier than success.
Plus you can complain about it and whine
about it and be a victim and you know,
garner all sorts of Kudos from yourself
and others that way.
So there's that.
It's just failure to adopt
responsibility.
But then I would say too,
there's also revenge on,
on the self and God,
that's partly why I liked the Cain and
Abel story so much.
Once I sort of figured out what it
meant.
Um,
people have a hard time not having,
yeah,
the kind of contempt that borders on
self hatred for the cells.
Partly because you know,
we are fragile and mortal creatures and
prone to error and malevolence.
And we know that of ourselves better
than anyone else.
Okay?
Because we know that we're prone to
punish ourselves and to think ill of
ourselves.
And you know,
one of the things I learned from young
was that the injunction to do unto your
neighbor as you would have him do unto
you was an equation rather than,
um,
a statement about how to be nice to
people and that you have an ethical
obligation to treat yourself as if
you're some a person of value.
Even if you don't really feel that,
that you owe yourself the,
that you owe yourself the same treatment
that you would give someone that you
cared for in love.
Now it's a really hard thing to learn,
you know,
cause you kind of have to detach
yourself from your knowledge of all your
insufficiencies and your flaws and treat
yourself with dignity and respect.
At least the dignity and respect.
Do someone who's faulty that could
conceivably learn.
And that's a very difficult ethical
lesson to learn.
It's,
it's easier to beat yourself continually
on the hip,
back of the head with a club and to feel
it's justified given how much you know
about how wretched and useless you are.
So,
so let's say there's two reasons,
um,
one is that you don't want the
responsibility,
so it's not really self sabotage,
it's just avoidance of responsibility
and consequence failure.
And the second is [inaudible].
Yeah,
punishment,
self punishment.
That seems only just given what you know
about all your pathology and,
and an error and,
and insufficiencies.
So I would say that that's the big two
there.
Any advice for a grieving parent who
lost a child unexpectedly?
Yeah.
Well one,
I wouldn't say make sure that you turn
to the people that you have left at you
love.
The second I would say is don't be
guilty about grieving.
You know,
and if you have friends you could tell
them,
you could let them do something nice for
you because they would like that.
You could figure out something they
could do that would be nice that you
would appreciate and let them do it
because you know other people are going
to grieve at some point in the future
too.
And maybe they'll be able to ask you for
help if you do that.
And then,
well I would,
the next thing I would say is give
yourself time.
You know,
it takes a year,
maybe longer to adapt to adjust even
reasonably to such a catastrophic loss.
And then I would say try not to allow
that terrible wound to make you bitter
because then not only will you have lost
your child and grieve,
but you'll be bitter and then you'll be
resentful and then you'll be hateful.
And that'll be like a terrible,
that'll add insult to injury.
So that's too bad.
Are there ever situations where you
should hold your tongue and not speak
what you believe?
Yeah.
You most of the time?
Look,
it's really a tricky thing to figure out
when to say what you have to say.
But I can give you a couple of rules of
thumb.
It's a general question name and I can't
list all the situations,
but I can give you some strategic
advice.
So for example,
if someone is,
um,
has said rude things to you,
for example,
says a rude thing to you,
maybe you shouldn't respond immediately
even though you're very irritated
because maybe that's just an impulsive
response and one that you'll regret when
you make an anger that you'll,
and so I would say when you're dealing
with someone and you want to chastise
them,
then you should wait for them to cin
three times,
right?
So the first time they're rude to you,
you think,
oh,
well they're probably having a bad day,
or I misunderstood,
or I'm,
I'm rude sometimes too.
And you know,
I'll just let it go.
But you don't forget and you don't
pretend it didn't happen.
And then it happens again and you think,
well,
that could still be fluke.
That could still be,
that could still be situational.
So maybe I'll just hold my damn tongue,
but I'll remember that.
I'll remember.
And then the third time they do it,
then you think,
no,
three times.
That's a pattern.
And so then you can go to them and you
can say,
look,
this happened.
And then maybe they did die.
And you say,
well yeah,
you can deny it,
but then this happened and maybe they
denied.
And you can say,
wow,
you can deny that.
But then this happened
and you know,
three times the charm.
And that's a time when you should stand
up for yourself and say what you have to
say.
Look,
you have to put yourself in a position
where you can say what you have to say.
You have to think it through.
You have to have a plan.
And you can't just launch yourself off
the edge of a cliff and hope that God's
going to catch you on the way down.
And I'm saying,
you know,
it's definitely the case that if you
have something to say,
like if you're being oppressed at work,
if you've got some,
you know,
horrible tyrant as a boss,
or,
or maybe that's happening to you in your
marriage,
or maybe you're the horrible tyrant,
God only knows.
There's things that have to be said,
but that doesn't mean you can just blurt
them out.
You have to have a plan.
You have to figure out what you want to
say.
You have to make it as minimally
troublesome as possible.
You have to have the goal that you want
in mind,
and you have to have a backup plan like
this,
the sort of thing that you're talking
about.
You know,
where you need to say something that's
like a little war.
You don't want to walk into that unarmed
and unprepared.
And now that doesn't mean that you
should,
that means that you should set up your
life so that you're firmly enough
anchored in a variety of different ways
so that you can say what you need to say
without dying as a consequence.
So
you,
Josh Gates.
Oh good.
Josh asked me an easy question.
Young suggested that the Christian Myth
failed to articulate Christ descended
into hell and that this resulted in the
mass shadow projection of the West.
Thoughts?
Yeah.
Well,
I'm going to refer to my book again.
I talk about this and rule seven,
pursue what is meaningful,
not what is expedient.
In that Chapter I discussed there's this
idea in Christianity that Christ took
the sins of the world onto himself and I
think that's very much related to the
idea of descent into hell.
They're not exactly the same thing,
but I,
but I'm going to address the first one
and it will shed light on the second.
Okay,
so what does it mean that the Messiah is
archetype lead the figure who takes the
sins of the world onto himself?
What it means practically speaking or
psychologically speaking.
And I've tried this with some of my
clients who were very naive.
It means to read the history of the
world as if you were the perpetrator of
the evils that you read about instead of
the victim or the noble intervener.
You know,
I talked to somebody the other day about
the movie Schindler's list,
and Schindler was this German
industrialist who saved a very large
number of Jews that were in danger of
well in danger of,
of,
of the final solution.
And one of the things he said was,
well,
you know,
when people watch Schindler's list,
they always think they'd be schindler
and on if they don't think they'd be
schindler,
maybe they think they'd be the Jewish
victim of the Nazis,
but they almost never think that they'd
be the Nazi persecutor.
And that's a big mistake because when
you read about history,
then you're reading about you,
even if the you is the perpetrator.
And unless you understand that,
then someone else has to be the
perpetrator.
And if someone else had is the
perpetrator,
well then you have a devil that you can
chase.
And you know,
maybe you've identified the devil
properly because you know,
now and then it's like John Wayne gacy
or Ted Bundy or someone like that.
And you've actually,
you know,
you've identified a perpetrator,
but so often,
far too often,
yeah.
The best way to constrain the
malevolence outside is to constrain the
malevolence within.
And so if you don't have a locale for
the evil of the world and you have to
externalize it because the evil of the
world certainly exists now,
it's a better solution to
okay,
assume that you're
fully capable of the terrible things
that people have been capable of throat,
the history of humanity,
and to contend with that genuinely.
And there's massive advantages to that.
I mean,
first of all,
it can actually produce and remarkable
increment and self esteem because you
know,
if you're just a rabbit and you freeze
whenever a wolf looks at you,
then you're just a frozen rabbit and
that's not so good.
You're just a scared rabbit.
But maybe you learn one day that you're
not a rabbit that you like,
you're actually quite the damn monster
and you've got teeth and you could
really use them in an underhanded and
horrible way.
This is why people like anti hero movies
so much hay because they go and see the
villains,
the mafia guys in these tough guys and
they antiheroes that populate our
imagination and think,
oh yeah,
well I'd really read it like to be
someone like that.
And the thing is,
is that being useless and weak,
it's better to be a monster then to be
useless and weak.
And that's because being useless and
week makes you a worst monster then a
monster.
That's why it's not like being a monster
is good,
but week use,
this monster is the worst kind of
monster because that's the sort of
monster,
little jumpy in the dark and sink its
teeth into the back of your neck instead
of confronting you forthrightly in the
alley.
And so if you start to see yourself as
the perpetrator of historical
malevolence,
you know,
if you can imagine yourself as an
Auschwitz camp guard,
if you see yourself as,
as the,
the vicious villain of the human story,
then all of a sudden you've got a lot
more respect for yourself and you can
unlock that internal monster and that
internal monster.
And then maybe you can tame the damn
thing or at least bring it,
bring it into some sort of partnership
with yourself.
And then when someone pushes you around,
you can let a little bit of that out in
your eyes just a little bit and you can
say,
ah,
it would be better for you.
And for me if you didn't continue to do
that.
And you can actually mean it.
And then actually it will start because
if you let a little bit of that out when
you tell someone to stop,
the probability that they'll stop is
extremely high.
And then just a tiny like vision of the
monster you could become is enough to
keep order in your house.
Hey,
and maybe in your state.
And so the mass shadow projection of the
West,
well,
you know,
here's another thing.
So one of the things the Christians
figured out was that,
um,
the snake in the garden of Eden was also
Satan.
Ah,
I can't get into that.
It's too complicated.
You'll have to read chapter seven if you
want a full explication of that idea.
I that's as good an answer as to the
question does.
I can manage tonight.
I spent all day,
let's see,
all day I got up at seven and I worked
all day till five on this video I told
you about.
So I made about 400 and it's or
something like that.
So I'm a little bit on the burnt outside
tonight.
So
let's see.
Let's take a couple of questions from
the live chat and it's zooming along
here.
So,
um,
how should one deal with recurring self
pity and why is it so gripping?
Well,
it can be gripping for a variety of
reasons.
It can be gripping because you are,
let's see,
because you are high in neuroticism.
That's a possibility.
And A,
and why is it so gripping?
Well,
that's another potential reason.
It's hard for me to say.
Um,
let's see.
I have a,
another chapter like that.
What's it called there?
Um,
yeah,
again,
it's rule to treat yourself like someone
you were responsible for helping.
Well,
why the hell wouldn't you pity yourself?
I mean,
people are,
life is tragic.
Everything ends in death.
Everything that you have will be taken
away from you.
You're weak and breakable and prone to
fits of impulsivity and malevolence.
How could you not have self pity?
Well,
that's really the answer,
but,
but the next answer is,
yeah,
well,
despite that it's not good enough.
You have to rise above all that even
though you have every reason for it.
That's the thing that's so paradoxical
is you have to rise above it even though
you have every reason for it.
And part of the reason you have to rise
above it is because if you don't,
it makes everything worse.
You and everything else and being
itself.
And so it's gripping because well,
it does grip you,
you know,
malevolence and tragedy and
vulnerability and mortality.
They're gripping.
And I would say,
well,
you have to find something that's even
more gripping than that.
And I would say the most,
the thing that's most gripping,
the only thing that's more gripping than
that in true and truth is to live a good
life,
to live the best life you possibly can
to live a life that's so noble that all
of those things are justifiable.
Uri l three 33 he says,
jp thinks he is a monster.
L U.
L I didn't know what l u l means,
but I don't actually think I'm a
monster.
There's a difference between thinking
you're a monster and knowing you're a
monster.
All right?
Foglight says,
I love this guy.
Well thank you.
Foglight I would probably love you too
if I knew you.
Let's see
who's that?
Santa's Christ says I'm a monster.
Roar.
Good.
Well that's a good start,
man.
That's a good start.
Practice that roar.
Um,
and get good at it because there'll be
times when you need it.
So,
okay,
Dj chronic says,
I let myself be that week monster for so
long.
Yeah,
well maybe you know what it's like man
down in your basement fantasizing about
revenge.
That's no bloody fun.
But you know,
this is something now for an adler new
too.
He's worth reading those fantasies of
revenge.
You know,
they have the seeds within them.
You knew this as well.
The seeds within them of the new you.
You can let those,
you can let those fantasies.
What would you say?
Manifest themselves and see what seeds
of potential future development or
harbored within them.
That's also extremely useful.
Okay.
Ethan for Gal says,
how do you boost your confidence?
Talking to people and get rid of the
paranoid that people hate you and don't
like you and think you're trash.
That's how I feel.
Okay,
well the first thing is,
um,
let me tell you a little bit about
courage.
No,
a little bit about trust.
Sorry.
When you're a naive person,
you trust people because you think that
people are good and then maybe someone
comes along and hurts you and you think,
oh no,
people aren't good.
I can't trust anyone.
And then maybe you're paranoid.
You think that people hate you and don't
like you and think you're trash and so
forth.
You don't trust people.
Then you figure out,
Jesus,
this whole knock,
trusting people isn't working out very
well because now I can't get anywhere.
And,
and if I ever do meet someone who's
trustworthy and I don't trust them,
then they're not going to get an
opportunity to show me that they're
trustworthy.
And so then what happens is that you
replace naive trust with courageous
trust and you put yourself out there
despite the fact that people might hate
you and don't like you and think you're
trash.
You know?
So
the other thing I would say that's more
practical,
Ethan,
I think you'd find that you only think
that when you run away,
my suspicions are if you went out and
talked to people,
like you'd have to have something to
talk about,
you know,
but if you went out and talked to
people,
you'd find that those thoughts only
bothered you for about 10 to 15 minutes
and then you would get over them.
You know,
a lot of that's a high neuroticism and,
and that's,
uh,
that in the big five aspect scale,
that's withdrawal.
You're experiencing a lot of withdrawal
related negative emotions,
anticipatory anxiety.
And the best way to overcome that is to
not avoid.
So if you find yourself avoiding social
situations,
then you have to formulate a plan to
stop doing that.
And then over time your confidence will
be boosted.
Let's see here.
That guy.
Yes.
When I watched those movies,
I always liked the bad guys.
I knew they were evil,
but they just seem cool.
Yeah.
Well the thing is there's nothing cool
and there's also nothing good about
naive harmlessness.
You know,
this is one of the things I really liked
about,
about learning.
What I learned from you.
It's like,
okay,
naive harmlessness is
okay.
It's worse than monstrosity because the
problem is if you're naive and harmless,
then someone else has to be the monster
and that's not good because you are the
monster.
So,
so the bad guys are cool because they're
cooler than the people who think they're
good,
but who are just cowardly and naive.
That's why.
That's why people like bad guys in
movies.
So
David Jackson,
what are your thoughts on Sophia's
citizenship status?
That's the robot.
I believe that the Saudi,
the Saudi Arabians made into a citizen
here.
I've got a thought.
Wouldn't it be nice if the Saudis
actually let their women be citizens?
That's what I,
that's my thoughts.
So I don't think that the rest of the
world is in any position to take any
lessons.
On what whatsoever on what constitutes
citizenship from the Saudis.
That's my feeling about that.
I'm,
I'm not a fan of Saudi Arabian culture.
I'm not a fan of the way that they treat
their women.
I'm not a fan of the way that they
disseminate Wahhabi propaganda into the
west.
I'm not a fan of the way that they,
they despise work and,
and I'm not a fan of the Saudi Arabians
and the fact that they,
granted Sophia citizenship status is a
publicity stunt of the worst form as far
as I'm concerned.
So
hello,
Dr. Peterson.
Do you ever fear that your psychological
reading of the Bible is wrong?
While I'm sure it's wrong in some ways
even Satan can use scripture for his own
purpose.
What if you're just using the word for
your own gate?
Well,
then God helped me.
I guess that's,
that's what I would say.
What if I'm just using the word for my
own gain?
I guess it would depend on what you
think of is gain.
I am using it for my own gain,
but I would say that I've aligned my own
game with the gain of others.
And that's made my own game.
It's a weird thing,
right?
Because if I'm see that way I can have
my cake and eat it too.
I can do what I think is best for me,
but at the same time I can do what is
best for others and I've also defined
what is best for me as what is
simultaneously best for others.
And I believe that.
I truly believe that.
I think I'm fully convinced of that
because I've thought it through.
So
that's my answer to that.
Ellen Wilson,
how do I tell my half brother 14 and 17
their father didn't leave three years
ago,
but that we kicked him out because he's
a pedophile.
Who targeted my sister?
The older one is autistic.
I'm tired of lying.
Jesus.
Ellen,
that's a rough one.
I can't tell you I can't help you.
It's too,
I'd need to know way more details.
I can imagine you're tired of lying.
The 14 year old might be a little young.
I Dunno ellen.
It's too complicated.
I can't,
I can't come up with a good ex.
Good answer for you.
I'm sorry.
I,
I'd have to know more details in order
not to botch the job.
Okay.
Let's see here.
I'm a British conservative millennial
training to be a school teacher.
How can I protect children age five to
11 from postmodernism,
which is everywhere in school.
God,
that's a good question.
That's free at Hana.
That was the main video I was making
today was about that.
Teach them what you believe to be true,
right?
Formulate for yourself a philosophy of
education or a serious one.
Write it down,
right?
You can think about it as a mission
statement,
but write it down.
Spend some time on it,
man,
because you're devoting your whole life
to that.
Figuring out what kind of teacher you
want to be and come up with articulated
reasons why you're going to be that sort
of teacher and then do it come hell or
high water.
You know,
like often there's kids out there that
only have to run into one good adult and
that will set them on the proper course
to the life.
And you could be that one good adult.
So I would say learn everything you
count about paws postmodernism.
So you're a master of it.
Decide what sort of teacher you want to
be,
implement that and and you'll,
you'll be a bulwark against that kind of
catastrophic foolishness and,
and help many,
many people.
If the right to identify with certain
arguments has to be earned.
How does one earn it?
How do we truthfully discuss ideas
for which we have not earned it?
That's been wood.
If the right to identify with certain
arguments has to be earned,
how does one earn it?
Well,
I think you start by feeling out
physiologically what arguments you do
have the right to make and when,
and that's that meditative consultation
practice that we talked about earlier.
You have to
pay attention to your words and see if
when you utter them they put you in a
solid place.
That's the line between chaos and order
as far as I'm concerned.
And you can test continually that the
extensibility of your arguments by doing
so you can,
you can implement more and more
sophisticated arguments as you get
better and better at finding that place
to stand and take on larger and larger
problems.
I guess that's the other part of it is,
you know,
how do you earn the right to,
to,
to an argument,
to a position,
pick a small problem,
one that you think you could solve,
but that's a little more than you can
chew.
You know that bite off a little more
than you can chew but not too much.
And then see if you can be successful at
solving it.
And then that'll strengthen and put
things in order a little bit.
And then that will entitle you to the
use of certain arguments and those
arguments we related to what you've just
done.
And then as soon as you've done that,
you'll be a little stronger and more put
together and then you can take on a
little bit bigger problem and fix that.
And then the same thing will happen.
And you just keep doing that.
It's like progressive weightlifting and
that,
and you,
you can't truthfully discuss ideas that
you haven't yet earned.
You can't,
you have to be quiet,
you have to listen or you have to think
about something else.
You have to do something else.
There's lots to do.
You know,
you don't have to engage in arguments
that you don't have any right to engage
in when there's all sorts of things you
can engage in right in front of you that
would fully engage you,
that would be very useful in that you
could contribute to,
you know,
I really liked this idea of incremental
improvement.
It's soul,
it's such a good idea.
You look around,
like I have this room that I'm in right
now and it's kind of messy.
I know I tell people to keep their room
clean and I'd been trying to clean up
this room since like last January,
but I guess because so much chaos has
been generated
around me in some sense that some of
it's flooded into this room.
The rest of the house is in really good
order,
but the residual chaos is still in this
room.
But when I come in here,
you know,
I,
I try to spend five minutes to clean up
a bit of correspondence or something and
I'm,
I'm definitely making progress.
The room is in much better shape than it
was.
Um,
don't underestimate the utility of
incremental improvement and you
strengthen yourself by doing that.
And then you can talk about the things
that you've actually done,
you know,
in detail in the kind of detail that
would convince someone who is skeptical
and knowledgeable that you are someone
who knew what they were talking about.
And then if you do that over 10 years,
like you'll,
you'll be solid.
Your,
the,
the breadth of argumentation that you'll
have at your fingertips will vastly
improve.
I'm a female student in stem and I feel
bombarded by all the feminist groups
trying to infantilize me.
How do I prevent them from turning me
into an adult child?
You know,
one of the things that's really useful
to do in university is to pick your peer
group.
When I went to university,
like I,
I made new friends in university and
that was really useful.
So I had my personal friends and they
were people who were trying to aim at
something better than what they had,
something better than what they had
left.
And that was a real relief to me.
I wrote about that in my new book too.
Um,
called make friends with people who want
the best for you.
That's rule three.
Um,
but I also realized that when you went
to university,
you picked your peers and in the stem
fields is what you should do is pick
some great scientists and those could be
people that you just read books about.
Pick some great scientists,
man or some great engineers.
There's some great mathematicians,
cause I don't know where you are in the
stem fields.
Pick some,
pick a hero or two or three and then
make those of your peers right and don't
pay any attention to all the noise and
Ruckus that you hear around you.
It's all nonsense anyways.
Partly what should happen when you go to
university is that you should be
introduced to great people and those can
be great people of the past.
They,
their spirits still live on in their
work,
in their books and you can pick them as
peers and ignore all that idiot
political nonsense.
Well you straighten yourself out and
learn to be great at what you do.
Develop a philosophy of greatness.
And that will keep the social justice
warriors at bay.
What books are we read to our young
children?
Well,
it depends on how young,
really young.
There's this book called how to teach
your child to read in a hundred easy
lessons,
all type that.
Um,
no,
I've done something technical.
It's called how to teach.
I mean something technically poor your
child to read in 100 easy lessons.
That is an excellent book because you
can actually teach your child to read it
in a hundred easy lessons.
Very smart,
very,
very smart book.
Very well developed psychologically
older kids.
I really liked the Harry Potter books.
I think that rolling nailed the
mythological structure.
Um,
what else?
I mean I'm in collaboration with my
daughter.
I'm putting together a reading list for
young people for,
for kids and young adults.
So I guess I'll have to answer it that
way.
[inaudible]
I can't bring it to mind and I can't
bring it to mind.
Okay.
Daniel,
how to be a good partner to someone
suffering from depression?
That's a tough one,
man.
It's very hard to live with someone
who's suffering from depression.
We helping without enabling and pushing
without being too judgmental?
Well,
again,
the devil's in the details.
Is the person seeing a counselor because
if they're depressed,
then they need to talk to someone.
Have they tried antidepressants?
Because if they're depressed,
they should try antidepressants
and they should be strongly encouraged
to do so.
And maybe that encouragement should even
border on a demand because depression is
just,
it's terrible.
It's terrible for the person who's
experiencing it,
like unalterably terrible.
Um,
and it's terrible for the person who is
living with the person who has
depression.
And so it's incumbent on the person who
has depression to do everything they
possibly can in order to set it
straight.
And it's hard.
But you know,
there's lots of potential treatments for
depression that have some efficacy in
antidepressants.
Really do work wonders on people.
You could try five hydroxy tryptamine
too.
You could look that up.
Five htp,
it's usually three times a hundred
milligrams.
Um,
and you can,
if you try that,
sometimes you can find out if
antidepressants will work for you
without having to resort to the
antidepressants.
Um,
you can also help the depressed person
make a plan in the morning.
That can be really useful or maybe a
plan the night before if they're just
not in any shape to do it in the
morning,
to sit down and say,
okay,
well you have to get through tomorrow.
And that's another good,
that's another good piece of advice.
And so in rule 12,
I talk about that sometimes in
relationship to depression,
real 12 is pet a cat when you encounter
one on the street and it's a bit of a
meditation about what to do when your
life is in absolute crisis.
But,
um,
one of the things you can do with
someone who's depressed is narrow.
And this is what I discuss in this
chapter is narrowed their timeframe.
You know,
maybe a depressed person can't think a
week ahead,
but maybe they can think about tomorrow
and you can sit down and say,
okay,
well you have to get through tomorrow.
And so how are we going to structure
tomorrow?
So that will be okay.
And so that you'll be able to sleep
reasonably soundly when you go to bed
tomorrow night.
And then tomorrow night we'll do the
same thing and helping someone come up
with a daily plan can be,
now they might object and squawk and
complain about it,
but you should be.
Um,
I would say relatively persistent about
that and you can say,
look,
let's just try it for a week.
And if they say no,
then you say,
well let's try it for one day.
You know,
Christ,
the person's got to be pretty
unreasonable if they let's plan for 10
minutes just for tomorrow and see if
that's helpful.
You know,
if the person objects,
you can keep cutting the magnitude of
what you're asking down until you
finally get a bit of a,
a bit of an agreement from them.
But helping someone depressed plan can
help a lot
you up.
You said you don't go to church because
the pastors are lying most of the time.
What do you mean by lying in this
instance?
I don't,
my experience has been that they don't
believe what they're saying.
That's what it sounds like to me.
That's what I mean by lying.
They say these things and they tell
people to believe them.
But they don't believe them themselves
and so,
and they're actually not listening to
them.
They're not listening to what they're
saying.
That's the thing that I've always had
this experience in church and there's
lots of other reasons I don't go to
church and a lot of them have to do with
me,
not with the insufficiency of church,
but you know,
a lot of the scriptural writing's really
have really hit me and I do understand
some of them,
I think to some degree and it's,
it's kind of painful to hear them
utilized by people who are doing it.
Formulaically or
okay.
Without conviction or even worse knowing
full well that they don't believe what
they're saying.
And so that's what I mean by lying.
My first ever girlfriend of three months
is pregnant and keeping the baby.
She said I can walk away or marry her.
No in between.
I don't love her.
What do I do?
Well,
I guess you have to figure out what you
want.
Like maybe you could sit down and write
out what you would like in terms of your
relationship with this child.
You know you've got a child coming.
That's really something that's someone
that could actually like you,
you know,
maybe you could write down and you could
sit down and write out and offer,
here's what I could offer to this child.
Here's what I would like to offer to
this child.
Think about it because you know,
maybe you want to have a relationship
with this person.
You know,
that person might be around when you're
like 70 so there's somebody you could
have a relationship with the rest for
the rest of your life.
What do you want that person to think
about?
You know,
you don't love her mother,
that that's a real complication.
And you know,
I would say,
well that's a real complication.
So you're in quite the fix,
but you could decide what you're willing
to offer and then you could and do it in
detail,
right?
Not just,
well,
I'd like to help.
It's like,
Jesus,
that's not helpful either way past,
I'd like to help,
you know,
here's the amount of money I'd like to
contribute.
Here's an amount of time I would like to
spend with the child.
Here's an amount of time I would spend
babysitting,
like make differentiated,
make a real plan.
Like,
like you're someone with a clue and
offer that to your girlfriend and see
what she says and give her some time to
think about it,
you know,
because maybe this could be a blessing
instead of a curse.
So she said I can walk away or marry
her.
No inbetween.
Well,
that's what she says,
but you know,
maybe if you made her a concrete offer,
she'd be willing to reconsider.
Often like a new mother can really use
help with the baby could really use help
with the baby.
So even just being a babysitter,
if you were like committed to it and
made the real offer like you'd thought
about it.
How about,
think about it for a whole week.
It's like,
okay,
here comes this baby.
If I was being a civilized,
useful person,
but I don't love the mother,
um,
then what should I do?
Well,
you're going to have to ask yourself a
lot of questions and maybe talk to some
people that you trust,
but,
um,
it's a problem we're solving because it
might be,
you know,
it's a relationship you could have the
rest of your life and,
and if you don't have it,
there's going to be a hole in your life.
You're always gonna wonder what the Hell
is going on with that person.
So,
okay,
we are expecting our first eight,
Evan says,
we are expecting our first child in me,
a daughter,
and he's specific.
Any advice specific to raising
daughters?
Well,
congratulations first.
So that's great.
Um,
okay.
Let's see.
I'm just thinking about my daughter and
specific advice.
I would say don't be afraid to support
her masculine and feminine sides,
you know?
And so the feminine side is you'll find
little girls.
No,
not all little girls because some are
more masculine than others.
But let's say you have a more feminine
little girl.
She's going to like to dress up,
but she's going to like to put on
jewelry.
It's amazing how much of that stuff
seems to be implicit or a neat,
you know,
and that can be really supported.
But then by the same token,
it's nice to wrestle with your little
girl kids and little kids really like
rough and tumble play into and to,
you know,
encourage her to be courageous and
forthright.
And so if you're lucky you can,
you can support her in both elements of
her personality and that would be a
really good thing to do.
So
don't let her wrap.
Are you around her little finger either?
That's another thing too.
Were there any lectures or lectures
series that you found helpful to you?
This Nathan,
like yours have been to so many?
Well,
Nathan,
you know,
I would say not really.
Um,
although,
you know,
when I went,
I went to this little college called
Grand Prairie Regional College.
It was way the hell up in northern
Alberta and um,
there's only 600 people that went,
it was an adjunct of the University of
Alberta.
It's still exists.
It's really lovely building.
Um,
and we had professors there,
an English professor and a political
science professor in biology,
professor,
philosophy professor,
people that I still remember little
seminars and they,
we got deeply into the material and I
really,
it really helped me a lot.
This English professor really taught me
to write to because he just slashed my
essays to ribbons.
I was really upset the first time I got
a bad grade because I'd always got good
grades and my papers in high school,
even though they were dreadful.
Um,
you know,
I was verbally intelligent enough to be
able to compose an essay that was better
than most with very little effort and
with very little quality.
And so that was very influential to me.
And I did a lot of reading under the
tutelage of those professors in these
tiny little courses in my first year.
But mostly what's been helpful to me
have been books.
And you know,
I read Nietzsche,
I didn't read all of nature,
but I'll read all that was easily,
easily accessible,
published works of nature in sequential
order in the order in which they were
written when I was in my twenties and I
read everything that young had published
it when I was in my twenties and um,
and,
and well and the same with a wide
variety of other authors.
And so those were like lecture series
and they were,
I was unbelievably useful to me.
I put some of those books on my reading
this.
So,
um,
could you please tell us your second
ghost story as mentioned on h three h
three podcast.
God Nicholas,
if you asked me that at the next q and a
and people voted up then I'll tell the
story but I can't right now cause it's a
long story and I'm just about out of
voice and brain and time.
And that's,
so I'm going to answer two more
questions I think,
and then I'm going to stop because I
really am running out of,
um,
words.
Let's see.
Okay.
Kay.
He says,
have you read much Thomas Soul?
In many ways,
he filled your societal role for the
last generation from a different
academic perspective.
I'm just reading his book right now.
Um,
it's,
what is it,
white.
Okay.
Black,
red Nixon,
white liberals.
Is that right?
Black rednecks and white liberals.
Okay.
Yeah.
I,
I'm,
I'm still making my mind up about it.
It's quite a radical idea.
I mean in that book,
so claims that black urban culture is
actually a derivative of southern
cracker culture and that that in turn is
a derivative of a rather dysfunctional
highland dysfunctional British culture.
What would you call rural called British
rural culture from a couple of hundred
years ago?
Um,
I'm still thinking it through.
I find the book really interesting and
it wouldn't surprise me if it was true,
but it's quite original.
The thesis is quite original.
So I'm,
I'm working my way through that right
now and I don't have anything much more
intelligent to say than that.
Can you share with us your reading
habits?
Max says,
I'm sorry,
I'm skipping over some questions,
but I have to answer some easier ones
because I'm out of the capacity to
answer difficult ones.
Oh,
I answered this one instead.
If you could talk to Donald Trump for a
day,
what would you try to say or convinced
him about?
I don't think I would try to convince
them about things.
I don't actually try to convince people
about things.
I don't think
I tried to ask them.
I'd ask him a whole bunch of questions.
I try to figure out how we thought
because I'm really curious about that.
I'd ask him all sorts of questions,
ask,
see if I could find out what he was up
to.
I'd like to know what he's aiming at.
I'd like to know why he think he became
president,
what he did right,
what he did wrong,
what,
what he dreads,
like what he would consider a
catastrophic failure,
where he thinks his biggest weaknesses
are,
what he'd like to leave as a,
as a legacy.
Um,
okay.
That would be fascinating.
But see,
I find generally speaking,
it's much more interesting to ask people
questions,
especially people like that than ever to
try to convince them of things.
Because the thing is,
I already know what I know,
but I have no idea what he knows or what
he's like.
And so it'd be amazing to be able to
talk to them.
And so I have a bit of that opportunity
now in Canada because I've been speaking
to a lot of political figures in Canada.
I'm going to have that opportunity in
Europe,
but a lot of,
a lot of what you want to do when you
meet people as asked them questions
because you know,
they'll tell you all sorts of things you
don't know.
And um,
that's also an entry point to a really
good conversation is to ask questions.
So that's what I would do.
I'd ask questions like mad until he
chased me away.
So
one more.
Daniel,
shall I like this question?
How would you give a speech to soldiers
entering the army about responsibility?
I will command at Basic Training Unit
and address young soldiers advice.
Daniel,
what I would do is you can take about
this,
you could ask them to complete the
future authoring program.
I think that would be a really good
idea.
But if you don't want to do that,
but you should ask them to like get them
to sit down for 90 minutes or an hour or
even I would use the future authoring
program cause it's just easier.
But ask them what sort of soldiers they
want to be in three to five years.
If they could put themselves together
and be the best military and serve the
purpose that they enrolled in the
military for in the best possible
manner,
what would they look like as their own
future ideal?
They have to think it through.
So,
and then the other thing you can ask
them,
and this is also part of the future
authoring program is like what would
your life look like three to five years
down the road?
If you fail in your,
in your desire to,
to become a proper soldier.
What sort of hell are you courting by
failing to take on the responsibility.
And if you can get them to think that
through,
you know,
the probability that they'll do a good
job will vastly increase,
really vastly increase.
Lots of young people have never thought
about who it is that they could be if
they started to be the person they could
be.
And so getting them to think about that
write about it would be extremely
important.
So what I would do first of all is get
them to do the writing and the thinking
and then give the speech.
And maybe once they've done it,
you know,
you could ask them if they'd be willing
to share with you some of what they've
written.
I wouldn't make that mandatory because
then they might not be able to write
about it honestly.
So that's how it would go about it.
So.
Okay.
Well I'm done.
So,
um,
thank you very much for tuning in and
thank you all for your support and um,
keep,
what else?
I hope that
I have lots of plans for 2018 and I
would like to keep you all in the loop.
And so all posts a lot of those.
Oh yes.
I should tell you this.
I'm going to be giving some public
talks,
a bunch of them.
So I'm going to be in the following
places in January,
February and March.
Um,
I'll try to say them in order.
I'm going to be in London and then I'm
going to be in Amsterdam and then I'm
going to be in New York,
Los Angeles,
San Francisco,
maybe Oakland.
Then I'm going to be in a bunch of
cities across Canada,
in major cities,
Winnipeg,
Edmonton,
Ottawa,
Calgary,
maybe this little town,
grand prairie that I went to college in
Vancouver.
And then I'm going to go down to
Australia and I'm going to go to
Melbourne and Sydney and Brisbane.
And so I'll post
the dates on my website very soon.
I'm still making the arrangements.
And so if you want to come and listen to
me talk,
then you'll have the opportunity to do
so and so.
Okay.
So I have to say good night.
And so good night to all of you.
And,
uh,
what would I like to close with?
Well,
I'm glad you're tuning in and I hope
that you're using the information that
you're finding as a consequence of
tuning in to put your lives together,
because it would really be good in 2018
if a whole bunch of people did
everything they could to put their lives
together because then maybe we could
avoid this idiot catastrophe that we
seem to be dreadfully sliding towards.
And so that would be lovely if we could
just not do that.
So until next time,
bye bye.