This is our first,
uh,
a hangout google hangout.
I hope the first of many you are Jordan
Peterson,
that professor of psychology at the
University of Toronto and I'm Wodek
Szemberg a producer within the agenda,
uh,
at Tvo and today we are going to be
speaking about a book that you are
beginning to work on,
right?
It's your,
it's your second book.
Um,
and tell us first a bit about,
uh,
the first book that you written and how
long it took you to write that one.
Well,
I wrote a book called maps of meaning
the architecture of beliefs back in.
It was published in 1999 and now it took
me 15 years to write and I wrote three
hours a day basically for almost that
whole time.
So it took a long time and it's
correspondingly difficult to read.
Obviously.
Obviously you are not trying to spend 15
years writing a.
The next one,
the title was the book's title is 42
wide,
42.
Well,
it was partly,
um,
what would,
what do you call that?
Um,
well fluke isn't exactly the right word,
but it's the only one I can think up at
the moment.
I started experimenting with a website
called Quora.
Quora is a relatively new site where
anyone can post any question and anyone
can post any answer.
Um,
and then the answers are voted on by the
target population who's interested in
the question.
And so I wrote 45 or 50 answers to
different questions and one of them was
a list of rules for living.
The question was,
does anyone have a good list of rules
for living?
And so I thought I'd take a crack at
that and I wrote 40,
turned out that I wrote 41 rules for
living and it became quite popular on
Quora.
It got something in the neighborhood or
has accrued something in the
neighborhood of 500 up folds,
which puts it in the top.
One or two percent of all the thousands
of answers that have been posted on
quora.
And lots of my other answers have
nowhere near that kind of,
you know,
popular success.
And then I was thinking about the list
and I remembered that there was a book
written by Adam so long while back
called hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy,
Douglas Adams,
and in that book a computer,
a super computer in the future is asked
the question,
what's the answer to life,
the universe and everything and the
answer that the computer spits out
after,
if I remember correctly,
several thousand years of computation
was 42.
And I believe the computer also comments
that that is the correct answer,
but that the people who are going to
receive at aren't smart enough to
understand it.
So I thought,
well,
one more answer that gives me 42 and
then that would be a funny,
a bit of serendipity.
That's the,
that's the word I was looking for.
You remember which one was the second to
rule that you came up with?
Wait,
remember clones?
No,
I could find out but I don't remember.
Okay.
So,
so let me ask you this question.
Why,
why is it that a 10th amendments and not
sufficient for us to live by and why?
Why do we need a,
a fresh list of rules that will guide
our life's choices?
Well,
the first thing is,
is that if you,
if you actually look in the Old
Testament where the 10 commandments are
listed,
you'll find that there are far more than
talent.
The tanner,
I suppose,
what might be regarded as the most
crucial rule.
So even back when the 10 commandments
were formulated,
10 rules wasn't it?
But there's also something about the way
people think that makes them quite happy
about lists,
numbered lists,
you know,
when you see this very frequently,
the seven habits of successful people
and,
and so forth.
Then once the list is numbered,
it sort of tiny and it seems well
organized and it's sort of a,
did.
It implies that it's comprehensible and
somewhat comprehensive.
And I mean,
I think that was part of the
attractiveness of this particular
answer.
So other than that,
I can't really say,
and I guess people are looking for
simplicity,
right?
And 43 is quite a few,
but
I must say,
I must say that I was a bit taken aback
by some of them,
uh,
by virtue of the fact that they seem to
rather a lacking in,
in,
in importance,
others say,
seem to naturally possess a,
as in be truthful.
I mean,
that's a great role that seems to,
seems to have all the bells and whistles
of,
of truth to live by that here are some
others which seem to not to be at the
same caliber.
And this is,
these are the ones I want to talk to you
about today.
Uh,
hopefully we'll get another chance to
talk about this.
We'll say they're on.
So we will talk about the important of
as quote unquote a.
So here's one of them,
uh,
number 14,
try to make one room in your house as
beautiful as possible.
Why is that important?
Well,
because if you want to improve things on
a medium to large scale,
let's say,
so that would be important.
It's really useful to doing so on a
small scale.
So you actually learn how to do it.
And No,
it isn't that easy to make a single room
beautiful.
It's,
it's hard and it's hard.
Plus it's the knowledge you generate
doing that is also generalizable because
fixing up one thing is a lot like fixing
up another thing.
There's a lot of commonality between the
attempts to improve one thing and
another thing and you can start locally
like with the room and the first thing
you find out is that it's not trivial to
try to make a single room beautiful and
that you learn an awful lot about beauty
and you learn an awful lot about paying
attention and you learn an awful lot
about how you could make what you
already have much better than it is
merely by paying attention to it.
And you know,
I shouldn't really say merely because
paying attention to things,
there's almost everything.
And also you get to practice doing
something that's hypothetically an
improvement on something that's actually
your own.
You're not putting anyone else at any
risk.
And the benefits of that are also are
also quite remarkable because then you
have a space around you that's beautiful
and you get to benefit from whatever it
is that beauty is.
Beauty is deep and people are afraid of
it too,
which is another thing that makes it
difficult and challenging is I believe
the favorite color that Canadians have.
Canadians for decorator purposes is a
beige and you know,
there's a reason for that.
And the reason is you can't go wrong
with beige,
but the problem with that is you can go
right with it either.
And so trying to make something
beautiful demands that you step out of
the ordinary and that's frightening and
it's really useful to try to do.
So
I've been,
I've been to your home,
it will not be a secret to those who,
uh,
familiar with you and the frequency with
which you have been on,
on the agenda and big ideas that we know
each other quite well.
Um,
tell me which of your rooms in your
house,
so you deem to be the most beautiful
one?
Well,
I have a front room.
It's a small room.
Um,
because I live in a quite a small place
because I lived downtown,
I have a front room which is a living
room I suppose.
Um,
and it,
it,
it's about 12 by 12 and it's,
it has a beautiful fireplace and a
marble tiled and the cover,
it's a gas fireplace.
The cover is a cover that,
okay.
Was part of the original house before we
redid it and it's made out of like a
bronze tinted cast iron.
And then in that room there are probably
15 paintings of different sizes.
I'm ranging from like monumental,
could,
one of them's about seven by nine and
then there's several others in there,
believe it or not often or approximately
that size.
And there's this sculpture and um,
and some paintings by a famous Mexican
artists.
And,
and you know,
you might think,
well that's,
that's would be prohibitively expensive
to,
for someone to attempt,
but it's actually not because you can
buy paintings at a very reasonable price
if you learn how to find them.
I find most of them on Ebay as it turns
out.
And I'd found some unbelievable
paintings on Ebay.
I've had to look a lot.
I probably looked at,
I tried to calculate it the other day.
I've looked at two or 300 paintings a
day for 10 years,
so that's about $6,000
a months or about 75 to $100,000
a year.
So that's a million paintings in a,
in 10 years.
I'm curious,
how long does it take you to know,
to know where the painting is worthy of
interest?
That's a good question.
It could take as little as,
oh,
it's less than half a second.
It's probably more like a fifth of a
second.
Probably.
Most of them are so bad.
It's just absolutely unbelievable and,
but,
but the,
the ones that aren't,
they kind of pop out and,
and then I put them in a group a day.
I opened a new tab and look and save it
for later consideration and make a
small,
you know,
I,
I call,
I told them very,
very radically and so.
But I mean it's really been very,
it's been very interesting to try to do
this not only to the,
to the room,
but to the whole house.
And,
and I mean I have 36 colors in my house
and I had a friend of mine who's from
Montreal,
helped me initially.
He's a portrait painter and he helped me
initially pick the colors and you know,
one of the questions is,
well,
what does that do when you do something
like that?
And I mean one of the things that's been
quite interesting is it always gives me
an excuse to invite interesting people
over to my house because I have
something interesting to show them.
And so it's made it easier for me too.
It's been,
it's made it easier for me to make
certain kinds of social arrangements
with people.
I'm also,
and this is something I thought about a
lot when I had my kids,
I mean they're often university now,
but when they were little,
you know,
it struck me that it would be useful to
have them surrounded by
productions of high quality because
they,
they tell you about production of high
quality and artistic production tells
you something like a painting for
example of something.
Most of the paintings,
I have a relatively representational,
although not all of them because there's
lots of different dimensions of beauty,
but a representational painting that's
beautiful,
have something normal because some of
the paintings that I have are of working
people.
For example,
what the patient tells you is,
although you don't notice it because you
don't have the time,
you're surrounded by things that are
worthy of great attention.
And here's an example.
Here's a portrait of a working man,
maybe a coal miner that some artists who
is talented spent 250 hours on just
getting the face right.
And so what that reminds you of,
even though you don't know it when you
look at it,
is that everything that you glance at is
worth 250 hours of study.
It's just you don't have the time and
you forget about it because you have to,
but the world is full of things that are
absolutely remarkable,
deeply remarkable.
And what an artist does is tell you that
all the time.
And so when you have those things around
you are,
you have beautiful things around you.
It's a constant reminder that behind the
necessary shallowness of your perception
is the kind of depth that you need to
make contact with in order to sustain
your faith in life and in humanity.
It's not a trivial thing.
It's a really important thing and you
can see this.
Just one more comment on this like
although it's harder for conservative
people to appreciate this because by
temperament they're not as aesthetically
I'm committed,
I would say are interested.
You know,
one of the things we should remember is
that Europe has become a magnet for
tourists all over the world and it draws
billions and billions of dollars a year
of revenue from other countries because
people come from all over to look at
impractical,
so to speak.
Beautiful things.
Well,
it turns out they're not practical at
all.
They're so practical that you just.
The fact that they're beautiful is
probably an indication that they're more
practical than anything else you could
possibly imagine because your
appreciation for beauty,
beauty I think is probably it's a
facility that you have of noting what's
valuable beyond the mundane.
So John,
let's move on.
Let's continue with talking about things
that are to be appreciated and will.
Number 37 is pat.
Sorry,
pat kept when you encountered one on
this treat,
why?
Why is that an essential
important part of,
of,
of a good life?
Well,
you know,
it's,
I suppose it's in the same category and
I guess this is rather evident of stop
and smell the roses,
although obviously that's degenerated
into something of a cliche,
but I mean it's easy to become so
obsessed with your particular goal that
you don't notice what's around you when
it's happening and a catcher,
a good break from that as far as I'm
concerned because they'll poke their
little heads out and kind of take a look
at you because they're interested in
maybe having a momentary pleasurable
interaction and there seems to be very
little harm in doing it and it takes you
out of your.
It takes you out of one timeframe,
which is often a goal oriented and
practical timeframe which are obviously
necessary timeframes and helps you
concentrate on the moment and attending
to the moment.
Well,
it's,
it's analogous to the same thing.
We just discussed with regards to
surrounding yourself with beauty,
it's hard for people to pay enough
attention to the moment and when an
opportunity presents itself to you where
you could immerse yourself in something
that's,
that's of high quality for no cost.
No,
there's no,
there's no downside to it.
So well,
a good rule of thumb is like engage in
every opportunity you possibly have for
peaceful pleasure.
That's that as is of no cost to anyone
and there's lots of opportunities like
that around and people start noticing
them like we're wired out.
So we stopped noticing things that are
working and there's a reason for that.
It's practical,
but the problem is,
is that you forget about everything that
surrounds you that's working really well
in that and that is pleasurable.
Can,
can you give me some other examples of a
pleasurable activities that have that,
uh,
that quality that they take you out of?
Well,
the,
the ordinary humdrum,
uh,
the purposeful pursuit of things.
Yeah.
Well,
I think hot showers are good example of
that.
I mean,
think about a hot shower.
It's like almost everyone in North
America is so rich that they have a
personal hot spring in their house.
It's like,
that's a good deal.
That's such a good deal.
It's,
it's so impossible and so unlikely and
people take it for granted.
Although,
well,
yes and no because they sing in the
shower and lots of people say they have
their best ideas in the shower and it's
like,
it's really useful to remember when
you're in the shower that hey,
aren't you king of the universe with
your hot spring inside your house and
what a great deal that is.
And lots of things are like that and we
forget about them and it's,
it's the curse of human beings to forget
about things because we're kind of
cognitively limited and we're always
attending to problems and so you have to
sort of stop yourself now and then and
think,
okay,
well,
wow,
isn't it great that this works?
I also think the same thing about cars
because I,
I'm firmly convinced that if the
automobile was invented today,
there's no bloody way it would be
illegal for people to drive.
I mean,
when we left,
you know,
at the risk of being sexist in ages,
we let little old ladies pilot,
you know,
3,500
pounds of hurdling metal down barrier
lined highways with thousands and
hundreds of other people around that
could be run over and no one even
notices that that's an absolute miracle,
that that's,
that,
that you can do that and that it's not
illegal.
I just,
every time I think that it just makes my
jaw drop because it violates every
principle of common sense you could
possibly imagine.
And plus it's so much fun and cars
worked so well.
They're so good.
Like I have an old car,
it's a,
it's a Hyundai Sonata from 19,
from 2004,
you know,
so it's getting to be an old car.
The bloody thing is perfect,
you know,
it's got a top speed of about 140 miles
an hour.
It's smooth as silk has a great sound
system and I can zoom around like a mad
dog and the authorities are,
don't bother themselves with that.
Yeah.
Go on the record here and,
and much support you in admiration of
the fact that we have achieved as a,
as a conscious realization,
something,
something on parallel which is,
which is to allow individuals to,
uh,
drive potentially killing machines in a
way in which in which,
uh,
the killing does not happen for the most
part,
does not happen and it happens.
It's not intentional and that it somehow
it does embody and amazing or that that
fact of driving a mass suggests that we
have,
will be able to create a cartoon in
which,
uh,
the principles of freedom and older able
to exist in an amazing fashion.
It is,
it's amazing.
I mean,
you know,
that if we invented a new technology
that killed as many people a year is
audible,
there's no,
there's no way we disseminated.
There isn't a chance,
but for some reason automobiles have
have sneaked through that and it even
more amazing.
They sneak through that so well that
even totalitarian states can't stop
them.
And so the first thing your basic
dictator does is buy a Mercedes.
It's like he's screwed right off the bat
as soon as he buys the Mercedes because
what he's announcing is that personal
mobility trumps everything and it's
only country in which the leadership has
managed to maintain a,
a control over who's allowed to drive or
not North Korea,
sorry,
Arabia bit too because they're not so
thrilled about having their women drive,
which is a sad commentary on Saudi
Arabia.
Um,
let us move on and,
and I want to raise another rule that
really surprised me.
Rule number 37,
38 a do not bother children when they're
skateboarding.
It's always been a source of amazement
to me.
The way that institutions,
businesses,
governments treat skateboarders.
It's like,
first of all,
if you ever sit and watch a group of
adolescent,
if they're usually boys,
not always skateboard,
it's,
you can't help but be struck with
amazement about how brave they are.
Like outside of the St George Building
here,
the kids will jump up on the metal
railing that goes down on the steps,
on the cement steps.
They'll jump up on that with your
skateboard and try to write it down.
It's like they fall off,
they fall off,
right onto the cement and with the sharp
edges and you know,
they all,
their friends laugh and they lay there
and lose their breath and they gasp and
Moan and then,
you know,
two minutes later they're up throwing it
again.
It's like,
it's so brave and they're so good at it.
And,
and it's harmless.
Yeah,
they might get hurt,
but that's hardly the point,
you know,
I mean,
you can't be encased in Styrofoam.
It's a pathetic way live.
And those kids are brave and they're
trying to master something really
difficult and all they get is grief.
So for example,
outside my,
the building I work in here,
there are some,
some cement containers.
They're quite long and they lined the
street,
there are trees in them and uh,
the skateboarders like to jump up on
them and,
and of zip along the edge with their
skateboard.
And um,
what the university has done about that
is put all these metal,
um,
they're a little metal strips along the
edge of the containers.
So the skateboarders can't do that.
And it just irritates me because first
of all,
the metal strips or as ugly as sin,
they looked like they were put up by,
by a totalitarian state.
And second,
it's like,
leave the damn kids alone.
Let them play.
That's what they're doing.
They're playing and kids need to play.
So and that skateboarders,
they're not let them skate board.
They're not drinking.
They're not like they're not doing
anything delinquent.
They're out there trying to master their
bodies and to be brave.
And,
and there's,
I think that irritates people who won't
do that.
They look at those kids and there's the
part of them that's,
that's not right.
Things.
Oh,
those little rats.
It's like,
no,
they're not a little wrapped.
They're brave.
And what they're doing is remarkable.
It's like gymnastics,
except they're not on a nice rubber
floor.
They're on cement.
They're brave.
What is the principle that the defendant
here as there,
is it important to have a correlation of
bravery,
of physical bravery,
or is that it?
The importance of understanding and
accepting that that good good life
involves a certain degree of risk.
I think it's the good life also requires
a certain amount of ability to admire
those people who take risks and plus
they're not doing any harm.
Now,
you know,
someone might object,
well,
what about liability?
But my,
my,
my experience with liability is,
is that as soon as someone talks about
liability,
you better be skeptical of their motives
because they're using their liability
argument to abdicate their
responsibility for participating in the
necessary dangers of a civilized state.
The whole liability thing that's a,
that's a weasel his way out as far as
I'm concerned.
So
is this the reason why you have the main
point of this,
uh,
and formulated to the rule of the way
you have is,
is it because you have a sense that,
uh,
that we increasingly subject to a kind
of the cautionary principle that the
seminar society is preoccupied with too
much risk and,
and,
and that,
and the counselors asked to be in ways
which are,
uh,
not too risky.
Yeah,
I think that's part of it.
I also think,
I think the other part of the two is
that,
you know,
like I said,
most of the time these skateboarders are
boys and they're like adolescent boys
state and I think that admiration for
the sorts of things they're doing,
which is a kind of,
in a sense,
it's reckless,
reckless,
masculine courage that's sorely lacking
in our society.
And you know,
people might object at,
that's my opinion.
But I'll tell you,
I talk about this a fair bit in my
classes,
like my class this week.
I showed the students a couple of clips
from the lion king when Simba,
the lion king is growing up and trying
to become braids.
And um,
you know,
I have my students,
the boys in particular,
the young men coming up to me constantly
saying that,
you know,
they,
they just see no appreciation whatsoever
for what used to be termed masculine
virtues anywhere in society.
And they're like,
they're,
it's not good for the.
I mean,
that one of them wrote me a letter this
week stating exactly that,
you know,
they're hurt by it and,
and there's a resentment towards it.
And I see it really expressed in that
attitude towards skateboard.
Is this like,
what's wrong with those kids are fine.
They're plus.
Plus.
The other thing I know is that play kids
have to play.
It's not playing isn't what,
what do you call it?
It's not of secondary importance.
Human beings have a place circuit.
It's,
it's part of being a mammal.
And one of the ways that human beings
organize themselves at the highest level
of moral virtue is through play.
You know,
when those kids,
the kids that are skateboarding in their
groups,
you know,
they're evaluating each other for
courage and bravery and they're watching
each other perform difficult physical
app.
So they're extending their limits and
it's,
you should be happy about that.
And if you just sit down and watch them
for 10 minutes,
it's,
it's like warranty.
Like I said,
it's like watching gymnastics.
It's goal as far as I'm concerned,
goes skateboarders.
Uh,
Jordan,
we have now a half an hour.
I think this went very well for the
first time out.
I hope to be able to talk to you again.
We have only managed to talk about the
three other rules.
They are 42 on a on an all,
so we've got 39 to go.
Plenty of material to talk about in the
future,
so thank you and until next time,
great.
Nice talking to you.