We are the Democrats
since 18,
28.
Our great party has played a major role
in participating in the political
process that is produced what is
arguably the greatest republic the world
has ever seen.
We've produced generation after
generation of leaders who despite their
faults,
have helped establish and maintain a
country that is served in the main,
has a beacon of light and hope to the
desperate masses of the world,
yearning in those immemorial words to
breathe free
over those nearly 200 years.
We have all worked together despite our
differences to produce a society we're
desperate.
Want is a rarity.
We're hardworking men and women can
produce a better future for themselves
and their children and where the
arbitrary disadvantages that have in the
past held so many of us back and
deprived others of our genuine talents
have in good faith,
being continually reduced and minimized.
Nothing is perfect and neither is our
country,
but we have built together a stable,
secure,
exciting,
dynamic community and can all in
consequence look forward to an even
better tomorrow.
But we as Democrats have faltered in our
duty in recent years.
We have allowed the discourse within our
ranks to become increasingly dominated
by a tiny,
well organized and disruptive minority
who have insisted ever more stridently
that our culture is a tyrannical
destructive patriarchy and that we are
not sovereign,
responsible individual citizens capable
of negotiating a shared and prosperous
piece,
but oppressive or oppressed minority
group members defined above all by our
sex,
race,
ethnicity,
and sexual preference.
We have failed as well to oppose the
profoundly anti American claim.
That free speech is merely the means by
which the powerful protect their
interests and we have abandoned are
invaluable commitment to and contract
with the American working class who
toiled mightily and often under
conditions of extreme deprivation to
perform the backbreaking labor,
so necessary to the creation of our
stellar country.
In doing so,
we betrayed and insulted our primary
constituency and we squandered the
opportunity to elect the first woman to
the position of the presidency of the
United States.
Then instead of taking responsibility
for our well-deserved failure and loss,
we insisted upon vilifying those who
defeated us appropriately and honestly
in the honorable democratic process.
We're sorry,
we promised to return to the priorities
that made our party great.
We promise to build and revitalize the
vital infrastructure who's construction
employees are tradespeople and whose use
is available to all.
We promise to insist that our schools
and those who conduct the research upon
which their methods are founded,
abandoned they're divisive,
videology,
and teach our children the knowledge and
skills necessary to make them
respectable,
mature,
productive,
reliable citizens.
We promise and have already taken
productive steps to reduce the
inevitable corruption that tends to take
hold of even the greatest and most alert
of states where the Democrats,
we did not uphold our responsibility to
the American people and were justly and
properly sorry for that.
We promised to clean our house.
We promise to draw divisions between the
key and time honored principles that
unite us all and the divisive identity
politics that is threatening to reduce
this to an ignoble squabbling and
dangerously polarized tribalism
where the Democrats,
we hope you'll forgive us and we promise
by the sacred social compact defined by
our unalienable individual rights to act
responsibly and carefully and do better
together.
Long may our great country prosper.