Okay.
Welcome to the waking up podcast.
This is Sam Harris.
Okay,
well today back by popular demand,
I have Jordan Peterson.
Jordan is a clinical psychologist and
professor at the University of Toronto.
He formerly taught at Harvard University
and he is published articles on drug
abuse and alcoholism and aggression,
but he has made a special focus on
tyranny and a of late,
he has,
I've been fighting a pitched battle
against political correctness up in
Canada and he's attracted a lot of
support and criticism on that front.
As I said last time around,
he is far and away the most requested
guests I've ever had and we did a
podcast about four or so episodes back
entitled what is true podcast number 62
and that to the disappointment of
everyone was a fairly brutal slog
through differing conceptions of
epistemology.
You've ever the phrase bogged down
applied to a podcast.
I it applied there.
Some people enjoyed it,
but most of you didn't.
Okay.
But as I say in the conversation today
with Jordan,
I did a poll online and 30,000 of you
responded and 81% wanted us to try again
because there was much more to talk
about and as it turns out there was,
we had a much better conversation this
time around.
It was very collegial and if you have
anything to say about it,
feel free to reach out to Jordan and me
on twitter or make noise wherever you
want.
And now I bring you Jordan Peterson.
I am back here with Jordan Peterson.
Jordan,
thanks for coming back on the podcast.
My pleasure.
Let's just take a moment to bring people
up to speed.
While we can assume many of heard our
previous effort at this all won't have.
So we did a podcast a little over a
month ago.
It was podcasts 62 I believe on my list
and it went fairly haywire.
We intended to speak about many things
but got bogged down on the question of
what it means to say that a proposition
is true.
And I considered this actually a very
interesting problem in philosophy,
but it seemed to me that we got stuck at
a point that wasn't very interesting and
many of our listeners felt the same.
And at the time I didn't let the
conversation proceed to other topics
because I felt that it would just be
pointless.
I knew you wanted to talk about things
like the validity of religious faith and
he jungian archetypes and many other
controversial things.
And I felt if we couldn't agree on what
separates fact from fantasy,
we would just be doomed to talk past one
another.
I think it's,
it's still possible we are doomed to
talk past one another,
but we ran a,
a twitter poll after our first podcast
and despite all the complaints I
received about our conversation,
81% of people wanted us to make a second
attempt.
I think 30,000 people answered that
pole.
So it was a considerable number of
people.
I decided we should give our people what
most of them claim to want and um,
we'll just see how it goes because I
don't want us to fight the same battle
all over again.
I think listeners who are curious about
how that last conversation went can
listen to it and I'm sure the topic of
truth and falsity will come up.
But if it does,
I think the best thing to do is kind of
flag it on the fly and move on.
And I think this will be an exercise in
seeing just how much can profitably be
said across differing epistemologies.
Would that warning about the various
road hazards?
Uh,
I think we should just see where we wind
up and I,
I think it could be someplace
interesting because you and I appeared
share many of the same concerns.
I think we both find the question of how
to live in this world to be the most
important one.
And I think we're equally concerned
about some of the very well subscribed
answers to that question that are
obviously wrong.
And so I think we should just do our
best to,
to make sense.
And see where it goes.
Well,
I hope so too.
That seems right.
I mean,
you place a tremendous emphasis on moral
necessity of the spoken truth and that's
certainly something that I'm in accord
with.
And you're also concerned with ethics in
relationship to the alleviation of
suffering from,
from what I've been able to understand
from what I,
from what I've read of your writings and
your also very much concerned with the
relationship between scientific fact and
value.
And so we do share this intense concern
about the same domain and I think for
many of the same reasons and I think
that you're an outstanding exponent of
your particular position and that makes
you an excellent person to talk about
these things with.
I was actually going to start with a bit
of an apology because I listened to our
talk twice trying to figure out where it
went off the rails.
It actually went okay for the first hour
and then we got bogged down in the truth
issue.
And I think I made a couple of strategic
errors,
which I hope not to repeat.
The first one was that,
um,
I started the conversation by more or
less accusing you of being
insufficiently Darwinian and that was
designed to be,
I thought playful and provocative.
But when I listened to our conversation
again,
I thought that that wasn't very wise
strategic move.
That was one mistake I made in the
second mistake I made was that I had
just read a number of things that you
had written and I told you a lot about
what you thought instead of letting you
say it.
And I was doing that partly,
well partly because there is an argument
to be had here and I suppose partly
because I was nervous but also partly to
demonstrate that I had actually
familiarized myself with what you had
read and I want to do indicate or what
you had written and I wanted to indicate
to you that I was taking it seriously.
But I'm going to try to not be the least
bit provocative in that manner during
this conversation because I really do
think that we have something important
to talk about.
And I think that that's why so many
people actually want to listen to us
talk.
So anyways,
hopefully we get bogged down just in the
interest of completing that bit of
housekeeping.
I don't think the first was an error at
all.
I mean to say that I'm being
insufficiently Darwinian is provocative
and I don't take it in the least bit
personally.
We just didn't find a path through that
particular thesis that we could Converge
On.
As far as the second point telling me
what I think in advance of our actually
hitting that topic.
I think that is,
that's the almost certainly a mistake
with me or,
or anyone.
And that's fine that you did that
postmortem and I,
and I agree with that bit.
So let's just start with a clean slate
here and I think kind of a natural
starting point would be to ask you,
and again,
I've heard a few of the things you've
said on this topic,
but I'll just let you invent yourself a
new however it strikes you.
What is the relationship in your view
between science and religion?
Well,
I think that religious systems are
descriptions of how people ought to act.
And I think that the way that I think
that those rows in a cause I
evolutionary manner.
And so imagine,
imagine the,
the dominance hierarchy structure of a
chimpanzee troop or a wolf pack.
Okay.
So we'll,
we'll use the,
the wolf idea first and then switch if
it's okay to the chimpanzee idea.
Hmm.
So as a consequence of the behavioral
actions and interactions among social
animals,
you could think of something as a,
something that might be described as a
procedural covenant arising and that
would be the animals knowledge of the
structure of the dominance hierarchy,
which is kind of ill named.
But we'll use that for now so that
there's a,
there's a hierarchy of,
of,
of rank and every animal in the social
community understands that hierarchy of
rank.
That's essentially the culture of the,
of the,
of the troop or the or the pack.
And there's an implicit recognition of
the value of each individual within
that,
that troop or pack such that,
for example,
two wolves
square off in a dominance dispute.
Of course they puff themselves up to
make to make themselves look large and
they growl at each other and they engage
in throws,
just threatening displays and generally
speaking the wolf that ha that has the
lowest threshold for anxiety.
Activation will capitulate first
generally without much more than the the
pose of a fight and rollover and expose
his neck and then the dominant wolf will
not deign to tear it out basically and
you could think of the wolves acting out
what you would describe propositionally
as respect for each individual's value
and then in the chimp troops,
friends to walls.
Research has indicated for example that
if the dominant Turkey is only based on
brute force and that chimp out the top
who's generally male is there because
he's a barbarian dictator,
let's say.
Then he's very likely to be taken out by
two male chimps,
three quarters his power who are much
better at social bonding and who made a
very tight compact between one another
and and so that the chimp troop that's
based on a tyranny is unstable.
What de Waal indicated was that the
chimp tropes that tend to be more stable
are run by dominant males who actually
are very good at social bonding and
reciprocity and who pay a fair bit of
attention to the females and infants in
the troop.
So the dominants isn't power so much as
as it might as you might think of as
good politics.
And so if there's an emergent ethic
that,
and I truly believe it's emergent ethic
that's very similar to what piaget
described as emerging among children
when they play games,
that not only specifies the nature of
the social contract,
let's say,
but also is structured as if the
individuals within the social contract
have some implicit value.
So imagine that as human beings diverged
away from their chimpanzee progenitors
there,
you know,
the common ancestor we have with
chimpanzees,
we already started to act out this
ethic.
It was coded in our procedures to speak
technically because we have a procedural
memory.
And then as we develop cortically,
we watch each other and,
and ourselves very,
very intently.
And once we develop language,
we were able to start encapsulating that
procedural ethic first in stories and
that story.
Those stories were partly about what a
very well structured procedural ethic
might be and how it might go wrong,
but also about how an individual within
that procedural ethic should be treated
and should act.
And the storytelling,
which was the mapping of that procedure
was the birthplace of the image and
story basis of religious ideation as far
as I can tell.
So that's the basic thesis.
It's like Piaget's notion that children
when they first come together to learn a
game,
if they're,
if they're young enough,
they can play the game when they're
together,
but if you take them out of the game and
ask them individually about the rules,
they give widely disparate accounts so
they've got the procedure in place,
but they haven't got the episodic
representation.
Technically speaking,
it's only in,
it's only once they become more
linguistically sophisticated that they
can actually come up with a coherent
representation of the rules.
And then it's only later when they start
to construe themselves,
not merely as followers of the rules,
but also as originators of the rules.
And that's akin to the recognition of,
I would say,
constructive individuality in
relationship to the state.
And so I see these things as very,
very,
very deeply biologically predicated.
Where's the concept of an archetype come
into this picture?
Well,
okay,
imagine this,
Sam,
you tell me what you think about this.
So you know how if you,
if you have a,
can I tell you just a two minutes story?
So,
okay.
So one time I was at the hockey rink
with my son and he was playing,
he was young,
he was about 12,
and they were playing his championship
game in this little league that they
had.
And,
uh,
my son was pretty good hockey player,
but there was a kid on the team who was
better than him who was kind of the
star,
but he was,
uh,
he was a diva,
you know,
and even though he would score goals and
all of that,
he wouldn't pass and he wouldn't,
he wasn't facilitating the development
of any of the other team members.
And so anyways,
we watched this game and it was very
close.
It was a very exciting game.
And in the final few minutes of the last
period,
the other team scored and my son's team
and this,
this stars team lost.
And so then the kids went off the ice
and that,
and the diva kid smashed his hockey
stick on the cement and started to
complain bitterly about how unfair the
game is.
And then his,
his idiot father came running up to him
and told him how unfair the raffing had
be and how,
and how it was stolen from them and how
catastrophic all of that was.
And I thought it was one of the most
highness displays of poor parenting that
I'd ever seen.
Now.
So there's,
there's a,
there's a moral of that story.
So his kid was very good at playing
hockey,
but he wasn't very good at being a good
player.
And so,
you know,
you always tell your kids,
doesn't matter whether you win or lose
it,
it matters how you play the game.
And of course you don't know what that
means and neither does the kid.
And it's often a mystery to the kid what
that means because obviously you're
trying to win.
But,
but imagine it this way.
Imagine that human beings,
that the goal of human life isn't to win
the game.
The goal of human life in some sense is
to win the set of all possible games.
And in order to win the set of all
possible games,
you don't need to win any particular
game.
You have to play in a manner that
ensures that you will be invited to play
more and more games.
And so when you tell your children to be
good sports to play properly,
what you mean is play to win,
but play to win in such a way that
people on your team are happy to play
with you and people on the other teams
are happy to play with you and so that
you keep getting invite,
getting invited to games.
Now if you think of each game as a,
as a,
uh,
small hierarchy of value or dominance,
then obviously the appropriate thing is
to move up the hierarchy.
But that's what animals do is they move
up to in their specific hierarchy.
But because human beings are capable of
abstraction,
we've been able to conceptualize the
hierarchy as such rather than any
specific one.
And then also to characterize a mode of
being that is most likely to move you up
the hierarchy no matter what that
hierarchy is.
And as far as I can tell,
that's the archetype of the hero.
The hero is the person who's most likely
to move up any given dominance hierarchy
at any time in any place.
And the hero is also,
and then so that the nature of that
archetipal hero first was acted out.
It was,
it was laid out in procedure and then it
was acted out and then it was described.
But it's also,
it's multidimensional.
It's not only he who plays to be invited
to play again,
but also he who goes out into the great
unknown to face chaos and the dangers
there,
but to gather what's valuable as a
consequence and to bring it back to the
community.
And that's the,
that's the basis of the Dragon Myth
archetype,
which is of course plays out in art and
literature throat.
While throughout recorded history,
the oldest story we have,
which is the Enuma elish from
Mesopotamia,
is a,
a story about Marduk who's the culture
hero and also the,
the highest God in the Mesopotamian
Pantheon.
He confronts the Dragon of chaos,
cuts her into pieces and makes the
world,
in fact,
one of his names was nam,
I can't remember the name unfortunately,
but it meant he who creates ingenious
things as a consequence of the combat
was tie a Matt who's the dragon of
chaos.
So he cuts off,
he counts up to the unknown into pieces
and makes ingenious things out of them.
And it's a perfect description of,
of the human archetype.
It's the fact that we are hyper
exploratory and that we use our capacity
to explore the dangerous unknown,
to gather the treasure that lies there
and then to distribute it to the
community.
So,
and that,
in terms of the evolution of that
archetype,
Sam,
think about it this way.
Okay.
Again,
you could tell me what you,
what you think about this.
So we know that roughly speaking,
that human females mate across and up
dominance hierarchies,
whereas chimpanzee females are
nonselective majors,
the dominant chimps,
males will chase away the subordinate
chimps from that female's in estrus.
And so they're more likely to have
offspring.
Okay.
The females will mate with anyone,
whereas human females are very selective
and they have hidden ovulation and they
mate across and up dominance
hierarchies.
So imagine the woman once the man who's
most capable of rising up the set of all
dominance hierarchies.
So what happens is she outsources that
problem to the computational capacity of
the male hierarchy.
And she let's the man fight it out among
themselves,
compete and cooperate to determine who
the best man is.
He's provided with the majority of the
meeting opportunities.
And so that's how the extended religious
phenotype manifests itself in
evolutionary space,
which was something that you and Richard
Dawkins,
we're wondering about the last time that
you talked,
like it's not psychopathy,
which was in some sense,
you know,
you were thinking about the charismatic
liar,
but really what's being selected for is
the,
the consciousness because that's the
right way of thinking about it.
That's best able to rise across the set
of all dominance hierarchies and females
are selecting very hard for that,
which is at least in part why we've had
this tremendously expanded cortical
capacity.
Well,
let me see if I can wade into this
picture and find places of agreement and
disagreement for clarity sake.
I think it's useful to distinguish
between two different intellectual
projects here with respect to values and
morality and the question of just how to
live in this world,
which is aren't at least nominal
starting point first.
There's the,
the description of how we got here,
right?
And this captures all of evolutionary
psychology and much of what you just
began to say about
selection pressures with respect to
dominance hierarchies and you know,
the kind of heroic male mate female apes
will find attractive and all that.
Then you can add religion to that as
perhaps an extended phenotype or the
possibility of group selection pressure.
We are more religious tribes have a way
of organizing themselves in a more
durable way than,
than less religious tribes.
And therefore we have,
there's something Ian,
our evolutionary history that has
selected for religiosity,
say an overarching story that unites
non-kin in a way that is more energizing
than some other story.
You know,
I don't really have much of a dog in
that fight.
I think some of that as plausible.
Some of it isn't.
I think group selection though you
haven't mentioned it,
is working to some degree in the,
in the background of this way of talking
about religion in evolutionary terms.
And at the moment I happen to be
convinced that group selection is
implausible and based on some bad
analogies.
But again,
this is not,
this doesn't strike me as important for
this conversation or for really for
anything that I've written about the
relationship between morality and
science or facts and values because I
view this problem of describing how we
got here,
how is it that apes like ourselves have
the moral attitudes and concerns that we
have?
That's a distinct project which was
quite separate from the question of
deciding how we should live now given
what we are and given the opportunities
available to us and given the way in
which are continually flying the perch
that has been prepared for us by
evolution with our technology and with
our institutions and with our new moral
norms that have absolutely nothing to do
with ancient selection pressures.
And this is even true in a religious
context.
So you have in many religions,
perhaps even most,
you have certain ideals that could never
have been selected for because they are
the antithesis of anything that would
offer an adaptive advantage.
Celibacy,
for instance,
anyone who was committed to celibacy in
our ancient past by definition,
didn't breed.
You could say that they might've helped
their kin,
but still celibacy is not an ideal that
you can make much Darwinian sense of and
yet you can have the most committed
adherence of any faith tending toward a
life of celibacy.
At the very least,
promiscuity is taboo in most religious
traditions.
Now I'm not taking a position that
that's a good thing or a bad thing.
I'm just saying that this is where
evolution is no longer relevant to a
discussion of how people should live and
as I think I said in in a blog response
to some of the things you said after our
first podcast,
if you want it to just take a jeans I
view of how human beings should live,
especially how men should live.
Well then you,
you would conclude that given current
opportunities,
every man should be passionately
committed to doing more or less nothing
but donate his sperm to a sperm bank
because then he would could father
possibly tens of thousands of
offspring for whom he would have no
financial or emotional responsibility.
From a Darwinian perspective,
that should be every guy's deepest
dream.
You should just get up in the morning
with just a commitment to that project
unlike any other,
they could be discovered in life.
So we have motives and norms and
concerns that don't narrowly track a
gene level analysis of what we should be
doing.
So I just put that out there.
I think the more interesting
conversation is not to talk about how
apes like ourselves could have gotten
religion,
but to talk about what we should do
given the way the world is now and what
we seem to know about it through
science.
Well that,
that's fine.
I just want to make a couple of comments
about that.
I mean,
the hypotheses that I'm proposing is
certainly not dependent on groups
election,
so we can leave that one aside.
As far as I'm,
I know,
I think the jury's out on the ultimate
validity of the idea of group selection,
but I'm not interested in going down
that rabbit hole because it doesn't
matter to me one way or another.
It really how that's resolved with
regards to
the potential validity of evolutionarily
derived motivations to the present day,
I think.
I think that's more complicated.
So
the first thing I would say is that
I believe there has been a central march
forward with this set of very productive
ideas as human beings have evolved their
morality,
but those have spun off
counterproductive,
evolutionary dead ends,
like everything doesn't,
it's possible,
for example,
that celibacy is one of those with
regards to the donation to sperm bank
idea.
I mean that's essentially the mosquito
away of propagation,
right?
And that's it's our versus k,
is that the,
is that the correct terminology?
I don't remember it correctly.
But there's two fundamentally different
strategies,
extreme strategies for propagating
yourself in the world.
And one is to disseminate
yourself as widely as possible
and let the offspring live or die as
they may,
which would be the sperm bank approach.
And then there's the other one,
which is high investment in children,
which is maybe take it to its extreme in
human beings.
And so we're tilt to them a lot more
towards that.
And so you can't really imagine a human
being being motivated to take the
mosquito approach because that's really
not built into us.
But,
but that isn't to say that he sexual
morality,
that's part and parcel of our being,
which seems to 10 relatively strongly
towards monogamy for example,
as marriage is a human universal,
although there are variations of it.
Hmm.
We're still very much tilted towards the
high investment in single offspring
patterns.
So let me just clarify one point I,
I certainly am not saying that you can't
see the thumbprint of evolution in more
or less everything we do,
you obviously can and as you point out,
are sexual morality and our commitment
to monogamy,
all of that is amenable to being
interpreted in evolutionary terms.
No doubt those stories are valid and
interesting to understand.
My point is is that we are in the
process of repudiating and struggling to
outgrow most of what evolution has
prepared us to want and care about and
fear tribalism,
xenophobia,
and the list is long.
But we want,
we want to get out of our tribal
violence program and all the rest.
Dress that because you see most of the
evolutionary psychologists that I've
encountered have what I consider the
misbegotten notion that our primary
period of evolutionary determination was
on me,
African Veldt and my viewpoint I would
say spans broader time spans than that.
So I'm starting from the presupposition
that the most permanent things are the
most real which,
which I think is a reasonable,
a reasonable starting point.
I have a reason for saying that because
what I've enabled to understand by
delving deeply into the grammatical
structure underneath mythology is that
the,
the religious landscape actually
describes that which is most permanent
[inaudible] what shape human
evolutionary history.
And I mean way back,
I mean 350 million years back before
trees,
before flowers,
back when we shared,
when we shared a common ancestor with
crustaceans.
And so one of the most permanent
features of the biological landscape is
the existence of the dominance
hierarchy.
And that's roughly portrayed in
religious mythology as culture or
explored territory or the known.
And it's,
it's usually given me the character,
a logical representation of the great
father.
And there's a positive one and a
negative one as the dominance hierarchy
can support you in your development or
crushed you completely.
So the dominance hierarchy is one major
selection mechanism and it's known
territory there.
There's another major selection
mechanism,
which is roughly speaking mother nature,
and that's that which exists outside of
explored territory.
And it's generally being kept
conceptualized as feminine,
which I think the reason for that is
because the unknown,
it's the unknown,
cognitively speaking or territorial
speaking,
that gives rise to new forms,
but it's also more importantly that
female human beings.
So the feminine plays a very vicious
role in the selection process.
Um,
you may know and probably do that you
have twice as many female ancestors as
male ancestors.
So as far as human beings are concerned,
the feminine is a bottleneck through
which genes must pass,
so to speak.
And it's a very narrow and,
and choosy marble next.
So it has a positive element and a
negative element.
So roughly it's the same thing Sam
that's represented in the Dow is dnd
Yang Symbol.
Because that Yin Yang symbol basically
is predicated on the idea that being is
partly the known or the interpretive
structure that's brought to bear on the
situation.
And so that's the White Paisley.
It's a serpent to actually,
and the unknown,
which is the Black Paisley or a serpent,
and the two are interchangeable and out
of them arises meaning.
So the idea behind the Taoist symbol is
that you should have one foot in what
you know and one foot in you in what you
don't know.
And that's the place where information
flow is maximized.
And that's the same thing as occupying
the position of the hero who confronts
the unknown and generates new
information.
And those,
those evolutionary realities remain
absolutely unchanged.
The idea that every place you go,
there's something you know and an
interpretive framework that you bring to
bear.
So there's a cultural element and
everywhere you go or are,
there's something that transcends that
knowledge,
but you have to deal with.
And everywhere you go,
you're there.
And so that's the,
so the three basic archetypical
characters of mythology or the
individual positive and negative
culture,
positive and negative and nature,
positive and negative.
We haven't outgrown that in the least w
it's exactly the same problem it's
always been.
And as far as I can tell,
it's exactly the same set of problems
that always will be.
And that's partly why these archetypal
stories can't be,
cannot be transcended and they cannot
be,
um,
ignore,
ignored.
They pop up off of their own accord.
Look,
I'll give you an example.
One question.
Pardon?
How
is any of that religious though I
understand how,
you know,
thinking of the individual versus the
cosmos gives us a kind of narrative
structure,
right?
You have your protagonist and you have
all of the things that can happen to him
or not and all of the things that he can
want or not.
And it's very easy to conceive of any
human life or the life of a whole
civilization in terms of stories like
that.
But how does this bring religion into
the picture?
Okay,
well I'm okay.
Approach that from two perspectives.
The first perspective I presume is one
that you might find interesting given
your your interest in spirituality.
So it's certainly capable for people to
experience deeply a sense of meaning.
Don't chick sent a highly talked about
that as flow,
which I think is a rather trivial way of
dealing with it,
but at least it's one that people can
directly understand.
But I would say you can understand when
you're doing something meaningful
because you're deeply engaged it and you
also have a sense in some sense of
standing outside of time cause you don't
know.
There's times flow and it also feels
worthwhile and that the sacrifices that
you have made to enable yourself to do
that,
we're justified.
And so I would say because the ultimate
domains of reality are in fact chaos and
order or known and unknown,
that when you straddle those two
properly and maximize information flow,
you feel a deep sense of intrinsic
meaning.
And that's the output of the entire
structure of your consciousness telling
you that you're in the right place at
the right time with regards to
furthering your capacity to thrive and,
and move forward.
The question you're a Jordan,
wouldn't you grant that there are
pathological experiences of meaning,
meaning that is actually based on a
misconception or or divorced from the
truth,
which can be no less intoxicating to the
person who's finding something
meaningful.
Sam,
I think that's a great question.
One of the things that really,
really disturbed me when I was first
working out these ideas was exactly that
question because like I've read an awful
lot about extraordinarily pathological
people,
you know,
serial killers and people who were
malevolent right to their core.
And that's exactly the question I asked.
Because you know with serial killers for
example,
especially the sexual Predator types,
they seem to have to live on the edge of
their pathology in order to continue to
be rewarded by it.
You know,
they have to keep extending their
pathology into the unknown to keep
getting that rush.
And then of course there's the situation
with schizophrenia where the underlying
mechanisms that produce the sense of
meaning actually go astray.
That's especially the case say with
paranoid schizophrenia.
But you see that's,
that's partly why I think I developed a
viewpoint that's similar to yours with
regards to the necessity of stating the
truth or at least attempting very hard
not to say what you believe to be false.
Because as far as I can tell,
at least under most circumstances,
okay.
That meaning orienting system,
which is actually the extended orienting
reflex,
technically speaking,
neuropsychologically speaking,
I think that you pathologize the
underlying mechanisms if you speak
deceitfully because you build,
you build pathological micro machines,
so to speak,
into the architecture of your physiology
and then your underlying the underlying
systems,
much more fundamental say limbic systems
for the sake of,
for lack of a better term,
they start producing pathological output
and take you down extraordinarily
dangerous roads.
So if you're going to let your intrinsic
sense of meaning serve as a guide life,
then you have to ally yourself with the
commitment to speak the truth or at
least not to engage in deceit because
otherwise you will do exactly what you
said and pathologize yourself and then
well,
and then all hell will break loose in
your life.
And in the life of others,
rigorously honest,
but still mistaken,
right?
I mean,
you could have a belief system or b
raised in a culture that has a belief
system that is completely illogical or
out of touch with reality.
You could not know it.
The dishonesty doesn't have to be local
to your own brain.
You could just be confused.
Right.
Well,
I think this is partly why I was more
insistent than I should have been in our
last discussion about a particular idea
about truth.
I mean,
because I would say there's the truth
that's associated with being in
possession of a set of accurate facts,
but there's a more enacted truth or
embodied truth,
which is the consistent attempt to go
beyond what you know.
And so that would be the,
the necessity of living in humility or
in ignorance.
And so that what you're doing when
you're discussing with someone or when
you're acting in the world is not so
much attempting to prove that what you
already know is completely right and
correct,
but attempting to understand very
carefully where you're in error and
learning everything you can to correct
that.
And you see that ideas also deeply
rooted in in religious mythology.
So for example,
the the finger of Horus,
who's the Egyptian Aye and who's also a
fall camp.
Horace is an I and a fall can because
falcons can see better than any other
animal,
including human beings,
even though we can see very well and
he's an eye because the eye with the
open irs signifies paying attention.
And Horace who's a messianic figure in
some sense for the ancient Egyptians,
had his eyes open to the corruption of
the state,
which was symbolized by a day.
And he named Seth set,
who later became Satan in,
in,
in the developmental pathway of this set
of ideas.
And Horace who lived in truth so to
speak,
was able to keep his eyes open and
understand the corrupt nature of his
society and his uncle,
his uncle was seth.
And to put that right again,
and so there's the,
there's the idea that lived truth can
rescue you from pathological untruth and
that might be more or factual.
If you're a scientist operating in a
truthful manner,
you update Archaic,
Archaic,
empirical representations.
If you're a,
what would you call it?
More culture hero type of person,
then what you're doing is updating
archaic and blind
representations of the proper moral
pathway forward,
which can never be encapsulated
completely in a set of rules.
So that's partly why.
That's partly why,
for example,
in in,
in the line of Christian thought,
Moses couldn't reach the promised land
because his morality was bounded by
rules.
And it's not possible to reach the
proper motive being by only acting out
rules because rules the same rules
aren't applicable in every situation.
I mean,
I could tell you the Christian story in
a way that you might find interesting
and about 10 minutes if,
if you,
if you would like me to do that and
let's hold off on Christianity.
I want to get there because I know
that's the,
the system of thinking you find most
interesting in this area.
And so I would like to talk about that.
Okay.
My issue is that it seems to me that
this kind of language game of,
you know,
talking about ancient stories and the
way in which they seem to cash out some
of the pre-scientific intuitions and
moral norms of any group of people as
though there's a validity to the whole
picture when you talk that way that I,
I just see that that's kind of
unconstrained by anything.
I think you can do that with anything,
with any system of beliefs.
You can find the people,
which from my point of view are living
in some form of radical error,
which is to say that virtually
everything they think is true almost
certainly isn't.
And the way they're treating one another
is terrible on the basis of those
misconceptions and they're never going
to get anywhere worth going.
Right?
So a modern example of that is something
like isis or the Taliban,
but there's some ancient examples or you
know,
older examples that are in some cases
even easier to understand because we
have no affinity for them.
So do you know the,
the Dobo people,
the anthropologist Ruth Benedict wrote
about them?
I,
I wrote about them for a few pages in my
book.
The moral landscape.
Yeah.
I write about them in your book
actually.
Yeah.
So for listeners who didn't read the
book or can't remember,
I mean the dove to get my vote for
perhaps the most tragically confused
people who have ever lived,
and this is just kind of a hot house
version of radical confusion,
which you wouldn't believe it would be
possible,
but for the fact that some
anthropologists wrote about it.
But so this was a culture that was
completely obsessed with malicious
sorcery and their primary interest,
every person's primary interest was to
cast spells on other members of the
tribe in an attempt to sicken or kill
them in the hopes of magically stealing
their possessions and especially their
crops.
It was like a continuous,
magical war of all against all in this
way.
And,
and they believed that magic had to be
consciously applied to everything.
They literally thought that gravity had
to be supplemented by magic so that if
you didn't cast the right spells,
your vegetables would just rise out of
the ground and disappear.
And they thought every interaction of
this sort and every outcome for people
with zero sum so that if one man
succeeded in growing more vegetables
than his neighbor,
his success,
his surplus of vegetables must have been
stolen from one of his neighbors through
sorcery.
Even the farmer who got lucky in this
way,
w with a surplus would have believed
that he succeeded for this reason,
that he actually magically stole his
neighbor's crop.
So to have a good harvest was a crime by
everyone's estimation.
Even the person who it was a lucky
harvester.
And it seems to me that you could play
this same game with the dope boo.
I mean you could talk about archetypes,
you could talk about whatever stories
ancient or otherwise that they were
using to justify this,
this view of life.
You could find some evolutionary way of
kind of threading the needle of how what
they were doing was a response to the
the ancient imperative of dominance
hierarchies.
You know,
you could give some sympathetic
construal of the whole enterprise in
terms of myth and archetype and meaning.
But clearly this was like a kind of
strange basin of attraction that you'd
be very lucky never to have found as a
tribe or as a culture.
And we're very lucky not to be stuck in
some similar place there.
There's another detail here,
which is especially horrible because the
dove who felt that magic became more
powerful the closer you were to somebody
so that the people who are closest to
them in life,
their spouses or their children,
or the people who are most likely to
destroy them,
would there be magical powers?
Well,
that's actually true,
Sam.
Yes.
But yeah,
so again,
you,
you could,
you could connect it to some kind of
story that makes sense.
So you could go to Greek mythology and,
and Shakespeare and,
and spin a yarn about it.
But clearly this underlying belief in
magic was one,
it's almost certainly not true,
but to,
it was creating a truly toxic moral
environment for these people.
And so yeah,
I just put that out there as an example
of something that one would never want
to spend a lot of time trying to justify
this worldview by reference to stories
ancient or otherwise.
Yeah,
well,
I mean there's actually a technical
solution to the problem that you're
posing.
I mean,
part of the,
the problem is how do you know if what
you're looking at is a genuine thing or
an artifact of your imagination.
And you know that Paul Meehl and,
and his,
his,
uh,
has colleague crunk back basically
addressed that back in the 1950s with a
very solid piece of methodological work
that every psychologist either does or
should know about.
They were the inventors of the multi
multitrack multi-method construct
validation process,
which is a
pretty awful jumble of words.
But basically it means something like in
order to specify whether or not
something exists.
You have use multiple methods to detect
it and that their reports should co-vary
positively.
And so of course,
we do exactly that with our five senses.
You know,
just because you can see something
doesn't mean it's there.
But if you can see it and hear it well,
you're a little bit more certain.
When I wrote my book maps of meaning,
I was very acutely aware of that.
And it's certainly a criticism that has
been leveled against people like Carl
Young,
mostly,
uh,
tragically enough by the postmodernists
of course,
who don't believe in any sort of
overarching narrative and who have their
own form of Dogan like pathology,
uh,
distributed well widely among them.
So what I did was refused to take a
presupposition as acceptable unless I
could find its manifestation at at least
four levels of evidence simultaneously.
So for example,
in,
in my book,
I start out with a neuropsychological
account on account of the fundamental
neuropsychological processes that enable
us to make sense out of the world,
primarily relying on the work done early
work done by the Russian
neuropsychologists,
Luria and soak aloft.
And Vinod Cordova who did a lot of early
work on the orienting reflects in the
hippocampus.
That was then sort of combined with
modern cybernetic theory by Jeffrey
Gray,
who was hands Isaac student.
And Jeffrey Gray's work has had
tremendous impact over the last,
especially over the last 10 years in in
psychology in general.
He wrote his book in 1982 but it was a
very,
very difficult book.
I think it had,
it must have had between 1500 and 3000
references.
And Jeffrey Gray was exactly the sort of
person who would have read every single
one of them.
And he outlined on cybernetic
information processing model of human
neuropsychological function that
actually lays extraordinarily nicely on
top of the architectural world that I,
that I've been working on outlining.
And I also wanted to ensure that it was
in keeping with the kind of
observational animal studies that people
like Jane Goodall and Frans de Waal do.
Ethology,
I wanted to make sure that it was in
keeping with the ecological data as well
as the broader literature on
evolutionary psychology and biology.
And so when I say that there's these
patterns that exist that you can extract
out of out of mythology,
I'm saying that knowing full well that
you can find concordance for the
processes described by those archetypal
stories in at least four different
scientific disciplines,
simile,
tanium and according to chronback and
meals methodology.
That's the most effective possible way
of validating a construct when,
when it might be susceptible that to the
kind of contamination by imagination
that you're referring to.
I don't know what to make of that claim
generically,
I think.
I think we should talk about your view
of Christianity at some point soon to
see if we can talk about specifics,
but I just want to take a generic
starting point,
which for me is more accessible and I
think more illuminating.
It certainly describes the divide
between science and religion that
resonates with me and I think it
connects nicely to the way you were
describing kind of our primal
circumstance of being an individual or a
tribe standing in the face of mute and
often hostile nature and trying to
figure out what's going on and how to
live within it.
I think that really is the primal
circumstance.
This is why I think of religion as you
know,
as a kind of failed science as a kind of
first attempt to tell a story about
what's going on.
That gives us some power over it.
But it's a bad attempt because we didn't
develop any kind of methodology at that
point to differentiate fact from
fiction.
Take the case.
Every parent will be familiar with
standing helplessly over your sick child
wondering what's wrong.
Let's say your child throws up and has a
fever and you don't know what's wrong
with him or her.
And this is obviously one of the more,
the more ancient moments for any person.
And there's a,
you know,
obvious evolutionary reasons why we
would be concerned about this.
And so this is quite Darwinian to care
what's happening to your,
your infant.
But today this primitive uncertainty and
helplessness and fear is bracketed by a
basic understanding of the processes in
the world that can affect a human body.
And there's obviously enough to worry
about there to drive almost any parent
crazy.
But one thing that is no longer on the
menu is the evil eye.
When your child gets sick,
no part of your mind,
if you're saying is now devoted to the
question of whether or not you should go
burn your neighbor as a witch because
she might've tasked a malicious glance
at your child.
Right?
But as you know,
that was not always so,
and in fact,
in Africa,
people are still murdering their
neighbors for the crime of witchcraft.
So the problem from my point of view is
twofold.
One is that we know that there's a path
forward to rule out things like
witchcraft and the evil eye,
and that this path is science and
rationality.
Generally.
The other problem is that you could
still play this game by resort to
ancient stories and finding some
connection between those stories and
evolution.
You could play a game of dignifying a
belief in magic.
In this case,
you know,
the evil eye specifically along union
lines or archetype aligns or something.
You could be sympathetic with this
picture.
But my point,
what would be the point of that mean
given the obvious harms that we no
longer need commit based on disavowing
this ancient ignorance,
why would one spend any time at all
trying to make sense of admittedly
ancient concern about sympathetic magic,
right?
Sympathetic magic is dangerous bullshit.
That's basically all I think we need to
know about it now.
And yet you could spend a lifetime,
you could be reading not only young,
but you know,
sketchy or people like Alistair Crowley
and lfs Levy and all that.
You know,
the history of hermeticism and you could
open it and you know,
manly palmer halls,
the secret teachings of all ages and,
and just get deep into that stuff.
The tradition of Western magic,
right?
It seems to me to be almost by
definition,
a colossal waste of time and actually,
yeah,
unnecessary to preserve anything that we
care about at this moment in history.
Okay.
Well,
I don't think that we have to have an
argument about the,
the,
the utility of moving forward on the
scientific front.
I mean I consider myself a scientist and
I don't,
I don't feel that it's necessary to
justify to the audience that's likely to
be listening to this,
the utility of the scientific approach.
I would say that that the,
there are,
there's great purpose in looking at
these ancient stories in the same way
Sam as there's great purpose and utility
in reading fiction.
So,
and I,
and I don't mean that in a derogatory
manner.
One of the things that I thought about
after our last discussion because I went
and did some investigation into
definitions of truth,
um,
some serious investigation so that I was
more prepared the next time that we
talked.
But one of the questions that I wanted
to ask you,
for example,
given your emphasis on the,
on truth as embedded in fact and also
the ability of moral truth to reveal
itself from a set of facts is here's the
sentence for you and perhaps you can
tell me what you make of it.
There is great truth revealed in
Dostoevsky,
tolstoy and Shakespeare.
Do you agree with that or disagree
because there's no fact in any of that.
And there are certainly no scientific
data now.
Do you think that that,
that those great works of Literature,
which are I would say more or less
universally regarded as valuable,
do they?
How would you,
this is where we,
why we got stuck on the issue of truth.
You see?
I would say that those stories,
there's more truth than Dostoyevsky's
fiction.
Then there is in a single person's life.
I don't know if I'd go quite that far,
but yes,
I will totally agree with you that
there's a lot of truth in fiction.
I don't think that's at all why we got
bogged down in our previous discussion
about truth.
How would you characterize that truth
though?
Because it's certainly not factual by by
any stretch of the imagination.
It's,
it's some sort of,
let me stretch our imaginations there.
I think there's a wide variety of facts
that are at the very least illustrated
in fiction.
The reason why fiction is compelling to
us is that it does map on credibly to
our experience of the world or what we
can imagined to be valid human
experiences.
Yup.
If it were radically strange,
which is to say if it all seemed
preposterous.
That's the definition of an unsuccessful
work of fiction in so far as certain
kinds of fiction push those boundaries
and certain kinds of magical realism or
science fiction,
which begins to seem basically like
tennis without the net where there's
just no,
there are no rules that make it
interesting.
The sweet spot,
at least in in my mind for fiction is
something that has enough verisimilitude
to be credible and yet it's a heightened
reality,
which makes it much more interesting.
Then just finding out what happened to
an ordinary person on an ordinary day.
Right.
Okay,
so with that,
let's,
let's take that idea of heightened
reality because I could make,
imagine that this is the case.
Imagine that I took Dostoevsky and
tolstoy and Shakespeare for,
they'll do for the time being and I
distilled out what made them great
fiction and I extracted a work of Metta
fiction from them.
That would be archetipal he religious.
The thing about religion for me,
again,
I know there are people who would
dispute this.
I just don't find this.
These claims,
credible religion becomes religion for
me.
When you begin to assert
that certain things are true,
specifically other worldly things,
the survival of the conscious mind after
death or the real existence of invisible
agents,
which you can propitiate or fail to
propitiate.
Yeah,
who have their eye on you,
right?
They care how you live.
They care whether you masturbate a care,
whether you pray to them and in what
terms you do and if you get any of that
stuff wrong,
you will suffer for it.
You are in relationship to these things.
There are some people who who have
relaxed their standards of commitment.
Two revealed religions so much that they
don't really answer to that description,
but most religious people most of the
time,
certainly most Christians and Muslims,
I believe otherworldly and supernatural
and superstitious things,
which are I would argue indirect
contradiction,
too.
Reasonable things.
They might believe about how the cosmos
works.
Okay.
Okay,
so I'm going to take a specific example
from what you said and address it.
You were talking about the propitiation
of supernatural beings.
I'm going to,
if you don't mind,
tell you the story of,
and Abel in a way that you probably
haven't heard it.
It's only a paragraph long.
This story,
and I want to set it up first.
So Kate,
enable our types from a classical
religious interpretation standpoint and
there that you might think about them as
foreshadowing the emergence of the idea
of Christ and Satan.
So they're the,
they're the idea of the hostile brothers
and that idea pops up in fiction all the
time.
It's,
it's a,
it's a constant,
it's an archetype.
It's man against his soul,
say,
or man against his darker nature.
Um,
that that's the basic plot idea.
So now Cain and Abel in Genesis are
actually the first to actual human
beings because God or Adam and eve are
made by God.
So somehow they're not exactly human
play along with me for a minute,
I know this isn't literally true sound,
so I'm not trying to claim that it is,
but cain and enabled are the first two
human beings that are born into the
world instead of paradise.
And cain is a,
uh,
an agriculturalist and Abel is a
shepherd.
And of course that shepherds the
meckel's much later in through
Christianity and also in the story of
King David,
partly because if you are going to be a
shepherd back then,
man,
you are one tough dude because you had
slingshots and sticks and their reliance
after your sheep.
So you know,
you weren't little boy blue in pastoral,
Victorian England,
you are one tough character.
So to be a shepherd was no joke.
Anyways,
Cain and Abel are making their way
through life and Cain is having a very
rough time.
Things aren't going his way at all.
Whereas able,
everything goes his way.
All the women love him,
his flocks increased.
He's,
he's successful in the story.
Also intimate that not only is he
successful,
but everyone likes him and understands
why he's successful.
Whereas Cain is kind of bitter and
nothing he ever does works out.
And so they both make sacrifices to God.
And I'll tell you,
Sam,
when I started to understand what the
discovery of sacrifice meant,
it just about blew me out of my room
because I realized that in the discovery
of sacrifice,
in the acting,
out of sacrifice,
we had information pertaining to the
earliest human discovery that you could
let something of value go in the present
and reap a reward in the future,
which is a staggering realization.
It's actually the discover of the
future,
discovery of the future.
Now people had to act these things out
and then represent them in stories
before they could understand them
psychologically.
So cain and Abel make sacrifices.
And the idea is that to keep Yahuah
happy,
the patriarchal spirit happy,
you have to sacrifice something of true
value.
It has to be a real genuine sacrifice or
you or you won't reap the future rewards
and what,
and everyone knows what that means to
them because I asked my students all the
time what their parents sacrificed to
send them to university.
And they all understand that perfectly
well.
And what's happened is their parents
have made a bargain with the present,
which is that they will forego certain
kinds of gratification so that they are
even their children can reap a reward.
They're making a bargain with the
structure of reality.
Now that was personified or
anthropomorphize depending on on which
terminology wanna use early when people
were still starting starting to work
these things out,
but that didn't destroy the essential
validity of the idea.
Now the story goes,
Abel sacrifices were valid.
The story implies that although it's a
bit ambivalent,
you never know if Cain is doing a bad
job of sacrificing or if y'all was just
being a son of a bitch and torturing
him,
which of course is a classic problem
existentially because you don't know in
your life when you fail,
if it's because you'd be doing things
wrong and not making the correct
sacrifices so to speak,
or that fate is just treating you
harshly and unjustly.
But the story into mates that cane is
making errors in his sacrifices,
whatever,
things don't go well for Cain and Abel
continues to to flourish.
So Kane is very unhappy with this.
And one day he decides to have it out
with the creator of being,
which you know,
is a pretty ballsy thing to do,
let's say.
And so he goes and has a chat with God,
and I've got this description of their
conversation from looking at multiple
translations of the original text.
And he basically confronts cio and he
says,
you know,
what kind of stupid university have you
put together here?
Um,
this being that you've created this
fundamentally flawed.
I'm out there breaking myself and half
trying to make everything work and
nothing ever works out for me.
And then there's that damnable who he
doesn't,
he already has to lift a finger and you
know,
women flocked to him and his camels
increase.
It's like,
it's unjust.
It's,
it's unjust and inappropriate,
and you should be called to task for it.
And so that's the eternal story of
people complaining about the fundamental
tragedy and evil of being.
So it's pretty good argument.
So God says to kick k and he says,
look,
you know,
that's a pretty good argument,
but here's how I look at it.
You're like a man who's inside the house
and at the door of the house there's
this predatory cap that sexually aroused
and it's,
it's sin.
It's missing the mark because that's
what sin means.
It means to miss the Bullseye.
And you have invited it into your house,
this corruption and sin.
You've invited it into your house
voluntarily so that it can have its way
with you sexually.
So that,
and you've,
you've intertwined yourself with it
creatively and brought something
horrible forth
and you're suffering there,
therefore can be laid at your feet and
you have no reason to call me on the
structure of my creation.
And so of course,
that's the last thing that cain wants to
hear because he doesn't want to
understand that he's at fault for making
the wrong sacrifices.
So he trots on out of there and the
story says that his countenance falls
and that he's raw,
which is to say almost nothing at all.
And he decides that he's going to serve
God a good one and wander off and
destroy his ideal,
God's ideal,
but also canes,
all no ideal.
So we kills his brother and leaves him
dead.
And that's the story of mankind.
And then it's worth Sam.
Because what happens after that is that
cane gives rise to descendants and in
his first or so generation of
descendants,
if you bother or annoy them,
they kill seven of you,
not one.
And if you bother his descendants,
descendants,
they kill 49 of you,
not seven.
And then his ultimate descendant or one
of his ultimate descendants is tubal
cane and tubal cane.
Uh,
historically speaking or,
or traditionally speaking,
is the first person who makes weapons of
war.
And so the idea there is that the deceit
and jealousy and resentment of the
individual propagates through society
until war emerges.
And then the next story is the flood to
reactions to this Jordan one is that
obviously you,
some stories are interesting and are
written for a reason and those reasons
are interesting and I've already granted
you that in fiction,
that it can be a lot of truth in
fiction,
a lot of human truth,
which is distilled there.
And one of his virtues is that when you
read somebody like Dostoyevsky or
tolstoy or Shakespeare,
you can run an emulation,
other people's lived experience.
You can essentially live other lives
that are,
that you would never live personally and
learn the lessons of those lives,
though you're never going to murder some
old woman in her flat.
You can watch roscommon the cough do it
and experience a plausible psychological
arc that follows from that.
So I'm not discounting the value of
stories,
it all,
but it seems to me that what you're
doing is overlooking in your discussion
of Cain and Abel and the the archetype
of propitiating a god,
you're overlooking the obvious ground
truth and its consequences here.
And then telling a story,
which is fairly unconstrained by any
rules.
The obvious ground truth for me is
people thought they were in relationship
to a deity who could become angry and
who had to be propitiated.
And this led to some very direct and
appalling consequences
for millennia.
The most extreme beans,
human sacrifice from which we graduated
too.
Animal sacrifice,
at least in the Judeochristian tradition
and human sacrifice was real.
And it's virtually a cultural universal
and yes,
so there's some archetypal story you can
tell about it,
but it was perhaps the most barbarous
symptom of human ignorance about the
weather,
about disease,
about good and bad luck about
agriculture,
about everything that we have ever given
rise to and we are quite happy to have
outgrown it and when whenever we find a
culture that is practicing something
like human sacrifice based on it,
a notion of propitiating invisible
deities,
we see these people as dangerously
confused and that and any child born
into the company of of such adults is an
unlucky one who has to be rescued now.
Right.
I mean the year is 2017 as you were
talking,
I was reminded of something I wrote in
the end of faith,
my first book and an end note that was
kind of pitch to the Joseph Campbell use
of mythology of which you are showing
some affinity even though his name
hasn't come up.
And I just want to read this to you
because this is,
I believe this counterpoint to this way
of talking about mythology and stories
and archetypes is still valid place is
still what I think.
I went into a bookstore.
I walked into the cookbook section of a
barnes and noble and with my eyes
closed,
just ran my hand down the shelf and
grabbed a book,
opened it at random and looked at the
first recipe I saw and the book turned
out to be a book called a taste of
Hawaii new cooking from the crossroads
of the Pacific.
So here is what I wrote in this end note
in the end of faith and they're in,
I discovered an as yet uncelebrated
mystical treatise.
While it appears to be a recipe for walk
seared fish and shrimp cakes with Ogo
tomato relish,
we need only study as list of
ingredients to know that we are in the
presence of an unrivaled spiritual
intelligence.
Then I list the ingredients,
right?
So there's one snapper fillet cubed,
three teaspoons of chopped scallions,
salt and freshly ground pepper,
as long list of ingredients.
And then I go through with a
[inaudible],
a mystical interpretation of this
recipe.
I'll just give you a few sentences to
give you a sense of,
it
sounds like you're getting dangerously
close to paranoid schizophrenia
thing.
I mean this is obviously crazy cause I
know how I did this,
but this is as valid sounding or so I
would argue as most of what is produced
in this genre.
So when I say the snapper fillet of
course is the individual himself,
you and I,
a wash in the sea of existence.
And here we find it cubed,
which is to say that our situation must
be remedied in all three dimensions of
body,
mind and spirit.
A have three teaspoons of chopped
scallions.
This further partakes of the cubic
symmetry suggesting that that which we
need add to each level of our being by
way of antidote comes likewise in equal
proportions.
The import of the is clear.
The body,
mind and spirit need to be tended with
the same care,
salt and freshly ground black pepper.
Well here we have the perennial
invocation of opposites,
the white and black aspects of our
nature.
Both good and evil must be understood if
we would fulfill the recipe of spiritual
life.
Nothing after all can be excluded from
the human experience.
It seems to be a tantric text.
What has more salt and pepper come to us
in the form of grains,
which is to say that the good and bad
qualities are born at the tiniest
actions and that's we're not in good or
evil in general,
but only by virtue of innumerable
moments which color the stream of our
beans by force of reputation.
Then there's a dash of Cayenne pepper
clearly of being of such robust color
and flavor.
It's signifies the spiritual influence
of an enlightened add Dept.
I go on and on and this is all bullshit
because it's meant to be bullshit.
I mean,
again,
this is a random text that I'm giving a
high falutin spiritual interpretation
of,
but my point is you can do this with
anything and religions have been doing
this for millennia with specific books,
which even by the merits of fiction for
the most part I'm,
there's some exceptions here.
I'll grant you that.
There's some bits of the Bible stand
comparison with the rest of world
literature,
but much of it doesn't.
Right.
Most of these books are profoundly
mediocre.
The Koran is as mediocre a book as I've
ever seen on any subject.
Our grant that may be the Arabic is
beautiful.
I don't read Arabic,
but the content of the book isn't,
and this is true of most religious
writing and the,
the fact that most people most of the
time have found profound meaning in much
of this work is not proof otherwise.
I mean,
again,
if you found me a culture that was doing
what I just did too,
a recipe in a cookbook,
the fact that they had gone generation
after generation and namor heard of that
interpretation wouldn't prove anything.
That's the problem I'm having here.
Yeah.
Well that's good.
I mean what you wrote is very funny too.
You know,
it's very much reminiscent of new age
thinking.
I would say.
What's the problem with new age thinking
that in your view?
Well,
I don't think it's constrained and
exactly in the manner that you said.
I mean,
I mentioned that what I've been trying
to do,
well,
working my way through the Merck,
let's say,
well,
if you're analyzing scientific
literature,
you have to separate the wheat from the
chaff and like 95% of it is chaff unless
it's social psychology,
in which case 99% of it is chat,
but it's chat.
There's a lot of it.
You have to be discriminating and your
interpretation in the scientific
literature just as another and in other
literary domains.
It's certainly the case that we aren't
as good at distinguishing what
constitutes quality in the fictional
domain from what constitutes outright
falls to a den and delusion,
let's say.
Um,
any d I used the example of paranoid
schizophrenia very specifically there
because paranoid
who tend to be among the more
intelligent people who are cursed with
schizophrenia take a set of axioms and
then weave a compelling story that's
logically coherent if you grant the
validity of the axioms.
And so the kind of merch that you were
describing it and I think that that
characterizes in particular new age
thinking is is an ever present danger.
Not so much of religious thinking
though,
Sam.
It's a,
it's an ever present danger of human
imaginativeness.
You know,
we can produce representations of the
world that grip onto the world in many
ways,
but then we have to subject them to
intense criticism and that's why for
example,
we both share a belief that the last
thing we want to do in our society has
put any restrictions whatsoever on the
human,
a right to criticize religious
presuppositions.
I think that's an absolute catastrophe
and I'm certainly not claiming for a
second that every possible religious
interpretation is correct.
That's,
that's clearly no more than every
possible work of fiction is of quality.
But the quality issue really is a
stickler because it's very,
as we,
as we've already discussed,
it's,
it's sufficiently evident that there's
such a thing as great literature to be
somewhat self evident that there's truth
embedded in that even though we don't
precisely know how to define it.
You know,
now the postmodernists would take an
opposing view to that.
They would say,
well,
there's no truth in literature
whatsoever.
It's all a matter of interpretation,
which is an,
it can in some sense to the objection
that you're raising and that's all I
have to say.
That's a profound objection,
but I don't,
I believe that it throws the baby out
with the bath water.
So,
so what I've been trying to do is
discriminate my way through the,
the wealth of past wisdom that has been
bequeathed to us and to find patterns
and then to verify them using other
techniques.
Now some of the techniques are,
you know,
you can,
you can also debate what constitutes an
acceptable methodological technique.
But one of,
there are existential techniques as well
and I think you rely on them to some
degree when you're talking about the
necessity of speaking the truth.
Because I would say I've put what I've
learned from the analysis I've conducted
into action in my,
in my own life,
which,
which has changed dramatically as a
consequence and only for the better in
the life of my family about which I
could say the same thing about the
teaching that I've done to my students
and I've been regarded for 30 years as
teaching courses at good universities
that have been regarded by a vast
majority of the students is absolutely
life transforming and so and there is a
massive hunger.
It's almost,
it's almost insatiable for more
sophisticated understanding of these
archetypal stories.
Now,
you know,
you talked about human sacrifice and I
would say,
well obviously
that was a catastrophic and barbaric
epoch in human developmental history and
who would want to go back to that.
But I would say what we've done to that
is not so much invalidated as supplanted
with a psychological understanding in
that we can sacrifice what we hold dear,
that's holding us back and move forward
into the future.
Or,
or you could say on an even and even
more super ordinance sense,
it's reasonable for a person to
sacrifice themselves to what they hold
as the highest value.
And that's an idea that's built
extraordinarily deeply into the
substructure of Christianity.
And it's very much what you're,
in my opinion,
when you tell people that they should
abandoned,
let's say they're impulsive desires and
their instrumental longings and do
nothing but tell the truth in some sense
from my perspective,
what you're telling them is to give up
their selfish individual being and
sacrifice themselves to the truth.
To me that like I truly believe that
that's the central message of
Christianity.
It's the central message of the
Prophetic tradition in Judaism as well
because the people who spoke truth to
power in the old testament were
generally very unpopular for doing so.
So I know it's a problem separating the
wheat from the chaff and I think you did
a great job of satirizing that in,
in what you wrote,
but that doesn't help us solve the
problem of the fact that there is value
in great fiction.
I don't view that as a problem.
I think it's obvious that there's,
there's value in it,
but it's not the value of telling you
how the cosmos works or what is likely
to happen in the future.
Right.
It's a different kind of value.
It's not a surrogate for a scientific
theory about anything.
Right?
Apps,
that's what religion does with it.
Well,
that I would say that that's fine.
I've got no disagreement with you.
There is thing about the fundamentalists
say the Christian fundamentalists who
insist upon a literal understanding of
the biblical stories is that they don't
know what literal means and actually
they're,
they're better scientists in some sense
then the scientists themselves,
because the scientist would never say
that the stories in genesis are
scientific,
but the fundamentalists implicitly
assuming that only scientific fact can
be true attempt constantly to force
these stories into a scientific
framework where they do not belong.
Right,
but again,
the because the stories are believed to
be,
we're talking specifically about the
Judeo Christian tradition because
they're believed to be revealed truth,
right?
I mean these are not stories written by
human beings.
These are the word of God in some form.
These are not held to be stories.
These are held to be records of things
that have actually happened.
So their history books on one level and
when they talk about what will happen
when they're obviously given to
prophesy,
they are an indication of what will
happen if you believe God is talking to
you and,
and,
and that's where the whole thing becomes
so pathological from an intellectual
point of view.
I agree with you.
This is partly why I've spent so much
time studying nature.
I mean in the,
in the late 1900 and each of basically
diagnosed Christianity,
he said that it had produced a
tremendous longing for the truth,
which was then used against the dogmatic
elements of Christianity,
which is destroyed.
But some of it's,
I would say some of it is,
is intense philosophical confusion.
It's like there's a kind of,
let's call it wisdom in fiction if we
don't want to call it truth because you
know,
obviously calling it truth brings up the
fact issue.
Let's call it wisdom.
The wisdom is clearly there,
but to consider it as a representation
of the factual world is not only a
mistake but also a dangerous mistake and
it's a self defeating mistake.
You know,
it's,
it's partly why the fundamentalists who
insist upon the equivalents of the
stories in Genesis and scientific theory
do their own creed,
a tremendous disservice.
And there they're bound to lose because
the Bible as science is weak and
sciences,
science is strong and so there's no,
there's no hope there for people who are
trying to push fundamentalist Christian
stories as literally true.
So we can agree on that.
What I'm trying to do,
while I would say what I'm trying to do
with mythological languages,
I'm trying to raise my father out of the
belly of the beast,
out of the belly of the whale.
It in the depths of the ocean because
there's,
there's living truth in our traditions.
Obscured is that is by human ignorance
and inability to conceive.
Even that doesn't mean that it can be
left behind.
It can't be,
it has to be brought forward and updated
and give a new site,
which by the way is exactly what happens
in the Egyptian stories because horace,
that I have attention goes down into the
underworld and rescues the god of
tradition.
Oh Cyrus and gives him sight.
And that's exactly what I'm trying to
do.
And I think I've been successful at it.
And so yes,
the interpretation problem is a major
one,
but that's something that would be
devil's everything.
Absolutely everything.
The other issue here though is that
there's a,
this is another thing that puts religion
in general,
an uneasy relationship with science.
There's a radical provincialism entailed
in endorsing any specific religion.
So for instance,
if Christianity is right in any sense,
well then all other religions are wrong.
When you look at what Christianity and
tail.
So at a minimum,
it suggests that Jesus was the Messiah,
right?
So the Jews are wrong.
Jesus was divine and resurrected.
So the Muslims are wrong.
There's only one God.
So the Hindus are wrong,
right?
So even if you want to relax the
literalism there,
you're still sending some fairly sharp
elbows toward the other religions.
Well look,
this is,
this is again,
I think to give the devil his dude.
This is exactly the point that
postmodernists like Derrida have put
out,
have put forward and very powerfully,
you know,
they say,
well look,
if you accept a value system as
paramount,
then you invalidate all other value
systems and you exclude everyone who
isn't succeeding in depth value system.
And their answer is,
well,
we'll just dissolve all the value
systems.
Well that's a completely insane answered
because you can't even focus on an
object in the absence of a value system
technically speaking,
because you're always focusing on things
of value,
right?
And so the fact that the conflict that
you described is an emergent consequence
of value systems is a terrible problem
and we don't know how to solve it.
Although I think the solution
paradoxically enough is actually
embedded to some degree in Christianity.
And the reason for that is because
Christianity makes the group's
subordinate to the individual.
And it also hypothesizes that the
highest moral virtue that a person
should uphold is that of the truth and
the truth speaks chaos into order in the
most beneficial possible way and that
that's the fundamental ethical duty.
But why make this a matter of allegiance
to Christianity?
Why not just take what is useful in any
tradition?
You just mentioned Nietzsche,
right?
So you found some of his work useful.
There's no tradition of allegiance to
Nietzsche.
You don't,
you don't have to worry about whether or
not you are sufficiently Nietzschean in
order to use his wisdom.
You just take from him and so far as
it's useful,
why not do the same thing with
Christianity?
Why?
Why waste any time wondering whether or
not you are a Christian or telling
people that you are or not?
Why not get out of the religion business
and use everything that is useful in
human culture?
However it comes to you in a way that's
nondenominational.
Well,
we thought could be achieved.
That would be absolutely wonderful.
I,
I would say the first problem with that
is that,
or the historical problem with that is
that the kind of truth that have emerged
out of this lengthy,
mythological process,
this lengthy,
imaginative,
mythological process,
we're first encapsulated inside the
stories and the images.
They weren't articulated philosophical
or psychological truth out of the kind
that we're speaking.
Look,
you can,
you can think about this like the
relationship between Dostoyevsky and
Nicha.
So Dostoyevsky and nature were very
similar in many ways philosophically,
but Dostoyevsky wasn't a philosopher.
He was a storyteller.
Implicit in his stories was Nietzschean
philosophy.
Even though paradoxically enough,
Dostoyevsky was a Christian.
The storyteller's get there before the
philosophers and you know,
you're saying now that the philosophers
have got there,
maybe we don't have to pledge allegiance
to a canonical version of the story.
And that could be the case.
In fact,
you see,
partly nature criticized Christianity
for all the reasons that you just
criticized Christianity or any other
creed.
Devin,
a devastating manner.
Although he was also extraordinarily
grateful to Christianity because he
believed it had disciplined the European
mind and that that period of discipline
was necessary.
A period where everything was
interpreted under the rubric of a single
interpretation because that taught
concentration.
But nature said,
well,
now we're beyond that and we're going to
have to become gods of our own accord in
order to withstand the consequences.
And then of course,
that turned out to be very problematic
for reasons that to also prophesied
because he said that the West would
degenerate both into nihilism and into
totalitarianism,
and that millions of people would die as
a consequence of the death of God.
And that's Dostoyevsky prophesied
exactly the same thing in the devils.
And it's exactly what happened.
And I don't believe that we can get past
the Scylla and Charybdis of nihilism and
totalitarianism without going back to
the past to find what it has to offer us
to bring it forward in an articulated
manner.
And of course,
that's precisely why I think the
discussion that I'm having with you is
important because I think that's what
we're doing,
right?
But there are two ways of going back to
the past.
You exemplify both of them.
You are going back talking about people
like nature,
right?
And you can throw the rest of philosophy
and world literature into that Bin,
but then it sounds like you are also
tempted to go back in what appears to be
a different category of effort,
which is the religious one,
which is at you.
You're holding to one side,
certain arguably fiction writers and
philosophers as being something other
than fiction writers and philosophers
and treating certain texts as something
other than mere products of the human
mind.
And you have a lot of company,
right?
This is what every religious person
does,
but why not treat Jesus the same way you
would treat socrates?
Well,
that's a,
that's a good start.
I think that socrates and Jesus had an
awful lot in common,
but the thing about socrates is that
he's primarily a historical figure,
whereas Christ may have been a
historical figure.
I think that the simplest assumption is
that someone of that description
existed,
but he's also a mythological character
and the mythologies unbelievably deep
and what it is in some sense is it is
the human imagination is attempt to
construct a representation of the
perfect man.
And so Christ is the perfect map.
Now,
you may say,
well,
we don't know what that means.
You can say that Jesus was the perfect
man.
I didn't say that.
I didn't say,
I said that Christ is the perfect man,
that it's different.
Because I'm speaking at the mythological
level is that whatever human beings can
imagine as perfect in terms of the
manner in which an individual could
conduct himself,
acts would Christ represents.
I'm not claiming for a moment that that
manifested itself in history.
That's a different claim and we can talk
about that claim to,
but I would say it didn't even manifest
itself in the Bible.
If you're going to write a story about
the perfect man,
a fiction of the perfect man,
you wouldn't write it the way the New
Testament is written.
And you would get Jesus to do things
that he didn't do and not do things that
he did do.
And he would say things that he didn't
say.
He can get a lot more perfect than what
you see.
And in Matthew,
mark,
Luke,
and John.
Okay.
So let,
let me,
let me tell you why briefly,
why that story's architect will be
perfect.
Okay.
So,
so here's the reason.
It's because as has been agreed upon by
the sages of the ages,
let's say the fundamental reality of
life is suffering and,
and finitude.
And you can layer on top of that from an
existential perspective,
malevolence and injustice,
and that's the law of human beings.
And so here's an archetypal story.
The most perfect,
innocent,
sinless person possible is betrayed by
his friends,
his countrymen,
and the foreigners simultaneously for no
crime whatsoever in the most torturous
possible way,
and also abandoned by the creator of
being himself.
And he accepts that all voluntarily.
You see,
the reason it's an archetypal story is
because you can't get beyond that.
You see it,
it hits a limit.
It's the limit of tragedy.
And so that's where the perfection lies.
Now the issue is,
well,
what does that mean?
And here's what it means.
We can go incrementally here because I
don't even buy that.
It's the limit of tragedy.
I mean,
first of all,
the thing is anchored to a belief in
human sacrifice.
This is what is so weird about
Christianity from my point of view is
that this is not a religion that
disavows human sacrifice.
This is a religion.
It claims that human sacrifice is real
and important,
but there was only one that was in fact
necessary and effective,
and that is the sacrifice of Jesus.
Well,
that's the Protestant and the Catholic
interpretation.
It's not so clear with the Orthodox
Christians,
they don't really,
they by the aversion of Christianity,
that's more and stress is more each
individual's moral obligation to do the
same thing.
I don't know enough about Orthodox
belief to dispute that,
but most western Christians have
unacknowledged at the core of their
belief system,
this assertion of the validity of human
sacrifice.
Right,
which is insanity.
Well,
I did the sat.
If you think about sacrifice in the way
that we talked about it
early,
that's not the way it's thought about.
Even in the Bible,
he had to die for our sins,
right?
He is the scapegoat.
He is the only effective scape goat and
he's a hero.
He's perfect in your terms because he
took this on voluntarily.
We need to go back to what you were just
saying.
This is not the ultimate tragedy because
he did take it on voluntarily.
It's more tragic if someone really get
screwed by the cosmos.
Oh yes,
you're right about that.
But the,
the part,
the fact that he took on voluntarily is
actually the part of this story that
involves the transcendence of the
tragedy.
Because the,
the,
the story there,
and this is a very old story,
it's far older than Christianity.
The story is that the best way to,
to transcend the,
the bitterness of life is to accept it
completely.
Hmm.
Including including betrayal at the
hands of your friends,
including betrayal at the hands of your
countrymen and,
and the foreigners to,
to allow that to be acceptable,
to take it on voluntarily and not to be
bitter about it like cain cause you get
murderous when you're bitter.
So I can go with you there.
But now if that is what you find
compelling in this story,
I could just offer for your examination.
Another example,
another story,
another tradition,
which in its details is basically
irreconcilable with Christianity,
but it's also well subscribed.
It's the Buddha and Buddhism,
right?
The Buddha is another example of the
perfect man.
He does give you a similar rationale to
the one you just gave for radical
acceptance of the vicissitudes of life.
And yet he's far more articulate.
I'm here now,
we're talking about the historical
Buddha who predated Jesus by five
centuries,
but who seems to have said much more
that is psychologically perspicacious.
And he talks exactly on that point about
the nature of acceptance,
what psychologically is accomplished
when you do,
except your experience to moment and the
barriers to doing that and the way in
which you should structure your life.
So as to be able to do that more and
more moment by moment.
And he presented a methodology of
meditation that is even today,
almost perfectly designed.
If you're going to talk about the oldest
tradition of Buddhism,
the Teravata,
it's almost perfectly designed for
export into a secular context.
So you can take whole sections of the
Pali Canon and if you just filter out
some of the needless repetition and some
of the phrasiology that treats the
Buddha like the perfect world conquering
hero who Buddhists believe him to be and
you just look at what is being said,
it's almost a perfectly secular recipe
for training your mind in essentially a
course of growth toward the kind of
acceptance you are talking about.
Again,
I'm not urging you to be a Buddhist,
I'm just saying this is an example that
is non Christian that does much of what
you are claiming Christianity
perhaps
uniquely does.
It invites a non mythological
relationship to it.
Well only if you strip the methodology
away from it and I think actually that
you make a mistake with that.
A person makes a mistake with Buddhism
if they do that,
you see,
because there's also a longing for
religious experience that's part of the
human soul and for example,
that's why people smoke marijuana and
why they take psychedelic drugs
and why they meditate.
But again,
I would argue,
and this is what I argue in my book,
Waking Up,
you can have the most esoteric
experiences are classically interpreted
as religious or mystical or spiritual
without believing anything on
insufficient evidence and certainly
without structuring your,
your interpretation of these experiences
along classically a religious dogmatic
lines or even Joseph Cam bellion
mythological lines.
You can essentially be a scientist of
introspection and you can use drugs to
do that.
You can use new technology to do that.
You can use ancient techniques of
meditation to do that.
You could even do something which is
seems to partake of delusional thinking.
To do that and just notice the outcome.
I mean there are practices like in
Tibetan Buddhism,
there's something called Deity practice
where you imagine yourself to be a deity
or a Bodhisattva and the practice of
imagining yourself to be that is not the
same thing as becoming delusional and
thinking you are that
that's exactly the same thing as the
mystical imitation of Christ.
It's exactly the same idea.
So you could do that with Christ.
You could do it with Batman.
You could say to someone who's shy and
who doesn't like to go to parties
because they just don't like each
subsequent encounter with a stranger
that they,
where they have to overcome their
shyness and their inability to make
small talk and all the rest of shyness
is a psychological problem that
virtually everyone has to some degree or
another.
And perhaps one way to overcome it is to
walk into a party just trying on the
idea that you are Batman,
right?
That you're Bruce Wayne,
That you have this all of these secret
abilities or your Jason Bourne or some
powerful character who
that's exactly it
is capable of great things,
but we know as a total fiction.
So now does that have any psychological
consequence?
And if so,
why?
I think there's no question can have a
psychological consequences and can be
useful to do that.
The crucial thing there is that you can
play with those kind of Schema without
diluting yourself.
Like if at any point in that adventure
someone tapped you on the shoulder and
said,
but do you really think you are Batman?
You would say no.
Now,
the problem is when you meet the guy who
really thinks he's Batman,
that's where you're,
you cross over into dangerously divisive
and unsupported ideas about the nature
of reality and religion.
It's really the only game in town when
you want to dignify those ideas,
generation after generation and protect
them from criticism.
That's why the scientific attitude of
speaking honestly about facts,
heaps smashing into religion uniquely.
It doesn't smash into fiction,
doesn't smash into Dostoevsky.
It smashes into Jesus,
right?
Because of what most people are doing
with Jesus.
Yes.
Well,
okay,
so right,
no arguments there.
Let me,
let me,
uh,
all for you.
Uh,
an elaboration of your idea.
So let's say no kid wants to be Batman.
While that's right,
because that's why he's reading the
comics and that's why he's going to the
billion dollar marvel movies that are DC
movies that portray these superheroes
out on the screen.
It's because the kid is acting them out.
Imagination is trying on an ideal.
So let's say,
well,
maybe you start with a pro wrestler
because you're,
you know,
you're not that conceptually
sophisticated.
And then maybe you move to Batman and
then maybe move from Batman to thor in
the marvel cartoons and narrow you're
in,
you're in the domain of quats
identities.
And then maybe you get a little bit more
sophisticated than that and you try on
Jesus or Buddha and then you ask
yourself,
well,
what would happen to the world if you
tried those on completely?
And that's the real question,
that that's where the historical element
and the mythological element meat,
I mean there's obviously a hierarchy of
rank among individuals and some people
have a much more positive impact on the
world through their actions than others.
And there's an,
there's,
there's some hypothetical ultimate limit
to that.
If you were the best person you could
possibly be in every possible way,
just exactly how much good could you
bring into the world.
And at what point would you be a bought
of sap?
Fuck,
that's something Buddhist sask
themselves all the time.
Wait,
would you be an incarnation of Christ?
Something that isn't just mythological
or imaginative or delusional.
It's a partial because if the ideal
recedes as you approach it,
but there's a reality underneath which
is better,
people are better and worse,
people are worse.
And there's archetipal limits to both of
those.
So these are,
these are very complicated things.
They're not,
they're,
they're fiction in the sense.
But I would think about the more as
metaphysician there,
there,
what happens when you distill fiction
into whatever centrally true about
fiction.
And it's really,
really true.
Well,
I would grant you,
and again,
this is the topic of my book,
Waking Up,
that there are possibilities on the
positive end of human psychology that
very few people actualize for any
significant amount of time.
And people glimpse them in their best
moments in life.
They have peak experiences,
whether on drugs or,
you know,
after some crisis or they've been
fasting or they have moments where they
feel as good as they have ever felt.
They feel as in touch as they ever will
with just the sheer profundity of
slamming into the present moment and
finding it totally captivating and
worthy of their attention.
They're not looking elsewhere for
anything.
They have become identical to the
feeling of being and found it to be in
some basic sense.
Perfect.
Now that's available to us as human
beings and there's not much of a
scientific story to tell about it at the
moment.
It's not arrived at by understanding
more about the universe scientifically,
so it is in some sense orthogonal to all
of science,
but
right.
My point is that it doesn't require
delusion either.
It doesn't require belief in anything on
insufficient evidence.
It doesn't require that we,
I believe certain books were revealed by
the creator of the universe and others
weren't.
You can get rid of 90% of what people
are doing in the name of religion and
spirituality and mysticism and still
fine.
This project captivating.
The 10% that you retained perhaps is
when you hear these stories about people
like Buddha and Jesus and all of the
people who have made heroic efforts to
be like them.
Historically Christian,
contemplative and Buddhist monks and all
the rest.
You can find in the biographies and
pseudo biographies of these people,
some evidence that transforming the
human mind as possible.
And you can find that evidence in your
own life if you have the right
experiences.
And you can see that human consciousness
is perturbed,
bubble and plastic,
and you need not be who you were
yesterday.
And so when you're talking about
becoming your best self or becoming more
and more like the best selves that have
ever existed,
are you talk about transcending the self
itself as an illusion,
right?
All of this stuff is worth thinking
about and paying attention to.
And there is a there there.
I'm not doubting that for a second what
I'm insisting upon.
However,
is that right?
We need never step off the razor's edge
of real honesty and conceptual integrity
even for a moment in order to walk in
that direction.
And that's,
as you said,
most new agers see no problem in
indulging any kind of happy talk about
the significance of crystals or whatever
it is they're connected to.
And that's where it becomes startlingly
unscientific.
And that's where he's someone like
Deepak Chopra and I can't agree about
how talk about things because the moment
we start,
he hits me with,
you know,
you close your eyes and you feel at one
with the universe that proves that you
proceeded the Big Bang.
Your consciousness was there before the
big bang.
Now of course it proves nothing of the
kind.
That's where he becomes a pseudo
scientists.
And so what I'm arguing for is that we
just remain attentive.
Two honest talk about what we know about
reality even while we have deep
experiences and seek them out by
whatever means.
And again,
I will grant you that there are means
what amount to a kind of internal
costume party where you can think in
terms of myth.
If you said to me,
Sam,
I want you to think of the rest of your
day in terms of the hero archetype.
What are you doing today to slay the
dragon and bring back that hoarded
wealth to your community?
That's a pattern of thought.
I have no question.
Could have some utility.
Yeah,
right.
Well that's what we were doing today.
So,
right.
But again,
the crucial bit is that in doing that,
I'm not making claims to knowledge about
the ethereal existence of archetypes.
There's no,
you know,
Akashic record or collective
unconscious.
Yeah.
I'm not making claims that kind at all.
In order to find this way of thinking
useful.
I'm not aligning myself with any
provincial tradition of mythmaking I e
or religion and claiming that my
religion is better than others,
which is,
you know,
as we see every time we open the
newspaper,
a divisive game that we have to figure
out some way of unraveling.
Right.
We do and mean your emphasis on
clearheaded thinking.
I mean this is part of the reason why I
wanted to talk to you.
I mean certainly one of the things that
you demonstrated the first time we
talked was your capacity for clearheaded
thinking.
I mean you're,
you're crazily incisive and laser
focused and you know,
those are extraordinarily useful
attributes and that's partly why I
thought it would be so useful for us to
have a conversation.
I'm an advocate of critical thinking.
We have to get this right.
Having said that,
the abandonment of all value structures,
which is say the postmodernist
perspective isn't a way forward because
it leads to,
it leads to a situation where people are
going to be unconsciously possessed by
far more foolish ideas.
Then they left behind them.
You're certainly not getting that in me.
I'm not advocating that we abandoned
value structure is there the contrary,
the value
that we should have in hand perhaps
before any other is the one you
referenced earlier,
which is honesty on every level because
it's the only thing when you're talking
about honest speech,
it's the only thing that that allows us
to course correct collectively is the
only thing.
If you're going to lie to me,
then you are denying me your view of
reality and in so far as you have a view
that can be useful to me.
We're now playing a game that is not at
all optimized for course correction and
so as a,
as a society we need to be,
and this is where you are,
defensive free speech comes in and has
been so useful.
We have to be committed to defending
free speech.
However,
impolitic or unpopular or even wrong
because defending that is the only
barrier to in the limit violence because
the only way we can influence one
another short of physical violence is
through speech,
through communicating ideas.
And the moment you say certain ideas
can't be communicated,
you create a circumstance where people
have no alternative but to go hands on
you.
But again,
I'm not,
there's nothing in me that is echoing a
postmodern relinquishment of a sense
that there are right and wrong answers
to the contrary.
I understand that and I'm certainly not
assuming that you are in that camp or
that you think that way.
It's quite clear to me that you don't
say I'm getting tired.
I kind of to just say one more thing.
Sure.
Okay.
With you.
Well,
it has to do with this course correction
idea,
so I'm going to perhaps leave you with
another architectural idea that you can
show on if you want.
So there's an idea that's paramount in
Christianity,
which is a creed I understand better
than most,
mostly as a consequence of my
educational history.
But the idea,
there's a very weird idea and not in
that is that at the beginning of time
God spoke order out of chaos.
The chaos was like a potential and that
it was the act of speaking truthfully
that brought forth the proper kind of
order and that was the paradise will
order that Adam and eve in habit.
And so there's this deep idea lurking in
there that was drawn from many sources
that this spoken truth is what
transforms chaotic potential into
habitable orders.
And then weirdly enough,
what happened with that idea over the
period of about 3000 years as
Christianity emerged from Judaism was
that by the time Christianity emerged,
there was an insistence that Christ was
the word that God used at the beginning
of time to extract habitable order from
chaos.
And so the idea there,
it's,
it's one of the most brilliant ideas of
mankind is that by speaking the truth,
you've faced the chaos of potential and
bring forth the most benevolent possible
type of ordered combined with that
course that you're describing.
And I think that's the central idea of
the West.
No.
You can find that idea echoed in other
areas like in Buddhism for example,
and in other religions for that matter,
but I believe that it reached it's
highest in logistics development at
least as far as I can tell in the west.
And that's also why we have societies
that are predicated on the sacredness,
so to speak of the spoken truth.
Yeah.
The question of why we value the spoken
truth to the degree that we do is an
interesting one.
I think it's largely,
yes it is.
It has as much to do with a reaction
against western religion by science and
philosophy as it does with anything that
came from western religion,
but I think it,
you know,
it,
it is something that is unraveling in
the strangest of places now.
So it's in so far as you and I can make
common cause defending the necessity of
protecting free speech across the board,
however unpopular.
I think practically speaking,
that's an extraordinarily useful thing
to do.
Yes,
well that's the best way at the moment
that we can slay our respective dragons.
Well listen Jordan,
it's a pleasure to talk to a second
time.
I hope people found something of value
in it.
You would never imagine we disagreed as
much as we did the first time around.
If you only heard this second
conversation.
Yeah,
well sometimes it's sometimes some,
some stupid persistence is useful and
you know,
I think the rabbit hole we went down,
it was an interesting one.
Even though it was painful and perhaps
luck,
it was productive because it got us to
the second conversation.
Hurray for that.
And like if you,
if you
feel inclined at some point to speak in
the future with me,
we'll see how people respond to this.
But you know,
I found the conversation very useful and
harrain for that.
Yeah,
well listen,
so I will invite people to respond yet
again as I did the first time.
I think you and I both pay attention to
twitter.
At least I pay attention to twitter
really exclusively in terms of social
media.
So yeah,
me too.
Pretty much twitter is a good place to
make noise at us.
We have these kinds of conversations for
you guys.
This is,
I said the first time around this you
Jordan,
where my most requested guest vibe,
a factor of,
I don't know what,
but it was remarkable how many people
wanted us to talk.
So we've now done it a second time.
And um,
listen,
it's a pleasure and I wish you the best
of luck with your entanglements with
crazy bureaucracies and everything else
here doing because you're,
you are on the front lines of a certain
kind of culture war and it can't be
easy.
I know it must be stressful and I just
wish you the best with all of it.
Thanks Sam.
Much appreciated.
Good talking with you.
If you enjoyed this podcast,
there are several ways you can support
it.
You can leave reviews on itunes or
stitcher or wherever you happen to
listen to it.
You can share it on social media with
your friends.
You can discuss it on your own blog or
podcast,
or you can support it
directly@samharris.org forward slash
support.