So I think the best way to continue to
walk you through the,
the,
the thinkers that we're planning to
cover is to do that with examples.
Some they stick better and they're more
interesting and it's very difficult to
understand you outside of a narrative
context.
And so I'm going to walk you through the
lion king today.
How many of you have seen the lion king?
Yes.
So how many of you haven't?
Right.
Okay.
So,
so you obviously were raised in a box
somewhere out in the middle of the
field.
So anyways,
you know,
it's,
it's an amazingly popular animated
movie.
I think it was the most highest grossing
animated movie ever made until frozen,
which I actually absolutely detested.
But the lion king,
the lion king is actually consciously
influenced by archetypes as well as
unconsciously influenced by them.
So it's a bit of a cheat,
I would say in some sense.
But it doesn't,
I don't,
for the purposes that we're using it
for,
I think it's just fine.
And so I'm partly,
what you might think about is that it's
its relationship to archetipal themes
that made it so overwhelmingly popular.
Same being the case with say books and
movies like Harry Potter or the entire
Marvel series.
The Marvel series is quite interesting.
I know somebody who wrote for Batman and
for Wolverine,
I know Batman isn't a marvel comic,
but one of the things that he told me
that was quite interesting was that once
these characters take off and establish
a life of their own,
they have a backstory and which becomes
part of the mythology that's
collectively held by the readers.
And if you,
you can invent an alternative universe
where you can muck about with the
backstory,
but otherwise you better stick with it.
Or the readers are going to write you
and tell you that you've got the story
wrong.
And so there's a bit of a collaboration
between the writers and the readers
after these things take on a life of
their own.
And so,
and of course the,
they,
they tend to,
the comic books in particular tend to
tend towards mythological themes very,
very rapidly.
And so anyways,
um,
Carl Young was a fascinating person.
I think you can read his biography,
autobiography slash,
biography,
which is called memories,
dreams and reflections,
which in many ways I think is an
unfortunate book because it's usually
the only book that people read that that
is more or less by young but,
and it is more popularly at popularly
accessible,
which is probably a good thing,
but it's also,
uh,
it's not as rigorous as his other books.
And so,
um,
the problem with someone like young as
you kind of have to read them as much as
you can in the original because
interpreting him is not a very
straightforward forward matter.
Um,
he was a very visionary person by which
I mean he had an incredible visual
imagination and he used that a lot.
He used it in his therapy practice.
I believe that most of his therapy
clients were high in trade openness.
Um,
I have lot of clients who are high in
trait openness.
They kind of seek me out because I'm
high in trade openness and you know,
they watch my videos and that sort of
thing and they're interested in what I'm
doing.
And many of them are are astute dreamers
and prolific dreamers.
And many open people in my experience
have archetipal dreams.
Whereas people who are lower and
openness,
they either don't dream at all or they
don't remember their dreams as much or
they're not interested in them and
they're not interested in the
mythological underpinnings of them.
So I've,
I've taught psychology roughly speaking
to many different types of people,
including lawyers and lawyers and
physicians and they tend to be higher in
trait conscientiousness then in
openness.
And they're much more interested in the
practical applications of psychology and
maybe the big five theories than they
are in the narrative underpinnings.
And you know,
people say that when they went to union,
they had union dreams,
but I don't.
And then when they went to Freud,
they had Friday and dreams.
And I don't really believe that's
exactly true.
I think it was a matter of selection
bias,
a priori selection bias on the part of
the people who were likely to go see
either of those two.
And so,
but I've been struck by some clients in
particular how unbelievably continually
they can generate deep archetypal dreams
with a really coherent narrative
structure.
It's really phenomenal.
And how revealing those dreams are
problem with archetipal dreams is that
they're not really personal,
right?
So if you're looking for a personal way
out of a situation and archetipal dream
doesn't help you that much because it
gives you the general pattern rather
than a specific solution to your
problem.
But a good dream will do both at once.
Anyways.
A young was an astute student of
Freud's,
uh,
we'll cover freud next.
Although generally in personality
courses the,
the order is reversed Freud first and
then you can because of their temporal
of the temporal order of their thought.
But,
um,
I think it's better to start with young
because it's,
it's as if you,
Freud excavated into the basement and
then young excavated into many,
many floors underneath the basement of
the mind.
And so from,
if you're transitioning from an archaic
understanding of archaic modes of
thinking towards Freud,
it's better to go through yield because
young is,
I think,
I think Freud in theory is a subset of
union theory.
Fundamentally just like Newtonian
physics is a subset of Einsteinian
physics and I think that Freud knew that
even to some degree,
although he was very much opposed to any
sort of religious thinking,
mythological religious thinking,
I would say he was a real 19th century
materialist and he didn't like the fact
that humans work started to delve into
religious themes in a manner that
actually in some sense validated those
themes.
And so that's actually why they split.
They split when you published a book
called symbols of transformation,
human was also a deep student of nature.
Nature wrote a book called [inaudible],
which is kind of an old testament
revelation,
poetry kind of book.
It's a strange one and I wouldn't
recommend if you want to read Nietzsche
that you start with that one,
but most people do.
But you get a seminar on thus spake
Sarah through Sta,
which is about,
I've got this wrong,
it's somewhere between 700 and 1100
pages long and it only covers the first
third of the book and thus spake Sarah
Theaster is actually quite a short book
and so well,
so you can imagine how much you had to
know about Nicha to derive that many
words out of that few words and nature
was a,
well,
an absolute absolute genius and young
was actually trying to answer the
question that Nietzsche posed
fundamentally,
which is why part of the reason why it's
incorrect historically to consider him a
freud and he was so niche.
It basically stated,
let's say explicitly that scientific
empiricism slash rationalism had
resulted in the death of the
mythological tradition of the west,
roughly speaking.
That's niche comment on the death of
God.
And in that comment he also said that
the fact that God was dead was going to
produce tremendous ideational and social
historical upheavals that would result
in the deaths of millions of people that
that he didn't say all that in one
place.
It's,
it's spread between,
part of it's in will to power and I
can't remember the source of the other
one.
Some of it's referenced in [inaudible],
but Nietzsche believed that in order to
overcome that collapse of traditional
values with the idea,
say of God as its cornerstone,
people would have to become creatures
that could produce their own values as a
replacement,
that we would have to become capable of
generating autonomous values and young.
But,
but that's easier said than done because
trying to impose a set of values on
yourself is very difficult because
you're not very cooperative and you know
that if you try to get yourself to do
something that you don't want to do or
that's hard,
you just won't do it.
And so it's not like you can just invent
your own values and then go along with
that.
That just doesn't work.
And so what young and the Floridians
did,
Freud first I would say,
was to start looking into looking into
people's fantasies,
autonomous fantasies,
unconscious fantasies to see if they
could to,
and and discovered that values bubbled
up of their own accord into those
fantasies.
And you can imagine,
for example,
if you've become enamored of someone
that you might start fantasizing about
them.
And if you read off the fantasy,
then you can tell what you're after and
what you're up to.
And so the motivational force composes
the fantasy and fried was more
interested,
not in a personal sense.
So in,
in so far as your fantasies might reveal
your personal history.
So for example,
if you have a burst of negative emotion
in a clinical session,
there'll be a fantasy that goes along
with that and an association of ideas
that,
that kind of manifest themselves of
their own accord.
And they're not necessarily coherent,
logical third link by emotion.
That's the free association technique in
Freudian Psychology.
And they also might manifest themselves
in dreams and fantasies.
And so Freud started doing the analysis
of these spontaneous,
let's call them fantasies and Ewan
linked that more Freud did this first
with the depaul oedipal complex,
but then you linked up spontaneous
fantasies and dreams with,
with myth,
mythology and fantasy across history.
And of course piaget did the same thing
from a completely different standpoint.
So,
and that a lot of that's embedded in
this movie,
so we might as well just walk through
it.
So,
ah,
the first question might be,
well,
why is a lion and king,
right?
And because that'd be,
it makes sense to people that aligned
could be a king.
And of course a lion is an apex
predator.
And so,
which means it's at the top of the food
chain,
roughly speaking.
And it's sort of golden like the sun.
So that's also useful.
And you know,
it has that main that makes it look
majestic.
And of course it's very physically
powerful and it's,
it's,
and,
and it's intimidating.
And so it's something that you run away
from as well.
Right?
Or you're awestruck by the fact that,
you know,
it's like snail king just doesn't make
any sense.
Right?
But Lion King,
that works.
And you got to think about those things
because it's not self evident why a lion
would work as a king,
but a,
but a snail wouldn't.
But it fits in with your metaphorical
understanding of the way the world works
much better.
And so the lion king makes sense and
well,
and when things like that that aren't
rationally self evident makes sense.
You have to ask yourself in what
metaphorical context do they make sense?
So you have the lion king.
Now the movie opens with a sunrise and
the sunrise is equivalent to the dawn of
consciousness.
So that in many archaic stories,
the son was a hero like horace,
if I remember correctly,
was a solar king
Apollo in particular,
but Apollo Greek Greek myth.
The idea was that the sun was,
this was the,
uh,
the hero,
the hero who illuminated the sky in the
day.
And so here are wisdom and illumination
and enlightenment are all tangled
together metaphorically.
And then at night what would happen
would be that son would fight with the,
with the dragon of darkness basically or
with evil all night and then rise again
victorious in the morning.
And so it's a death and rebirth.
The minutes,
very,
very cold,
very common mythological theme.
And the reason the sun is associated
with consciousness as far as I can tell,
is that we're not nocturnal creatures,
right?
We are awake during the day and we're
very,
very visual.
Half our brain is devoted to visual
processing and to be a lightened and
illuminated means to develop,
to move towards a higher state of
consciousness.
And we naturally use light symbolism to,
to represent that,
you know,
like the light bulb on the top of
someone's head.
You know,
you don't say I was in dark.
And when you learn something new,
and so again,
that fits into this underlying
metaphorical substrate that that's I
think deeply biologically grounded,
but also sociology,
socially grounded.
So it's a new day,
it's the start of a new day.
And a day day actually means like
French.
Your Nae Means Day,
the day trek in some sense.
And how to comport yourself during the
day is the fundamental question.
And the day is the canonical unit of
time.
And so you have to know how to comport
yourself during the day.
And part of that,
a journey from consciousness into
unconsciousness.
And that's,
and that return.
So like a Paulo,
you,
you've,
you descend into unconsciousness and
then reemerge.
And of course that's not metaphorical at
all.
That's exactly what you do.
You descend into the underworld of
darkness and dreams and strange things
happened out there.
And so,
and then you awake.
If you're fortunate or unfortunate,
depending on your state of mind,
you will wake in the morning and it's a
new day,
right?
And so the dream world seems to help you
sort out your thoughts.
By the way,
if you keep people awake for an extended
period of time,
then they,
uh,
they,
they lose their minds essentially.
The dream,
the unconsciousness and the dream state
seem absolutely critical.
And the maintenance of mental health,
although people don't exactly understand
why it looks like dreams might help you
forget because forgetting is really
important.
You just can't wait.
You just can't remember everything that
happened to you get so damn cluttered
that,
that you'd,
you'd fall apart.
And so you reduce things to the just,
and when you're doing that,
you pack them.
It's like you compress them in some
sense.
You pack them into a smaller space and
get rid of everything that isn't
relevant.
And the dream seems to now be part of
that.
It also seems to be a place where you
deeply encode learning that might've
been done that day,
which is something that Freud actually
noted in his interpretation of dreams,
which is a great book.
If you're ever going to read a book that
Freud wrote,
the interpretation of dreams is the
proper one to read in my estimation.
It's a brilliant book and it laid the
groundwork for a lot of what you did.
So anyways,
that's how the movie starts and the
animals come out into the light.
And that's,
that's a metaphor for the dawning of
consciousness to come out into the light
where you can see.
And so this is a baby giraffe and babies
emerge into the light,
roughly speaking.
And that's,
that's like I said,
that that's a representation of,
of the emergence or expansion of
consciousness.
And so this is how the movie starts.
It starts with very expansive music as
well,
celebratory music.
And that's to indicate to you to set the
tone for the movie,
but also to indicate to you that you're
about to watch something of import.
And the opening scene is actually a real
scene of genius in my estimation.
The animators did a great job and it
goes along very nicely with the music.
And so you see this lit place and then
you see this rock pride rock,
I believe it's called in the middle of
it,
and it's the center.
It's the center.
It's like the spot that's marked by a
cathedral,
which is an x or across,
and you're right in the middle of that.
And so it's the center of the light.
That's another way of thinking about it.
Or it's the center of the territory or
it's the home or it's the fire in the in
the wilderness or it's the tree in the
center where you live.
It's all of those things at once.
It's inhabited territory with you at the
center and the,
the rock represents tradition because
people tend to inscribe their traditions
on rock right or two to build them into
rock like the pyramid.
So you could think about that as a
pyramid,
as an Egyptian pyramid,
and it's the right way to think about
it.
You could also think about it as a
dominance hierarchy with the apex
Predator at the top.
And that's the line.
So it makes sense that the lion would be
in the light on the rock.
That's a pyramid in the middle of the
territory.
Right?
That makes sense to people
psychologically.
So because that's what the state is,
the state is a hierarchy with with
something at the top that occupies a
space that has been illuminated and made
safe by consciousness.
That's what the state is.
And that's all represented right away in
this movie.
And all the animals come to to observe
what's happening in the pyramid and at
the top because they need to know what
happens as at the top,
partly to organize their world.
That's the pyramid,
but also to see how the organizational
principle works.
And that's why they're all gathering.
And so they're gathering in the light in
the morning to observe something new
that's going to be born that's of
significant importance.
And that's the birth of the hero and
this little bird here Zazu right?
It's the zoo is like horus,
the Egyptian God who was a falcon.
And an eye at the same time.
He is the king's eye in this king's
eyes,
in this movie,
right?
He flies up above outside of the pyramid
so he can see everything that goes on
and reports to the king.
And so partly what that indicates is
that the thing that's at the top of the
pyramid needs to be an eye.
And that's partly why you see an eye on
the top of the pyramid on the back of
the American dollar bill.
It's exactly the same idea.
Or if you look at the Washington
Monument,
which is a pyramid at the top,
you see that it's capped with aluminum
and you think,
well,
why aluminum?
And the answer to that was it was the
most expensive metal at that time.
And so the notion is,
is that at the top of the pyramid,
there's something that actually doesn't
belong in the pyramid.
It's something that goes up above the
pyramid and can see everything.
And so you could think about it this
way,
is that you're going to be in a lot of
pyramids in your life,
dominance hierarchies,
and different states and families.
And all of that and they'll arrange
themselves into a hierarchy and there'll
be something at the top.
And the top is the thing that can do
well across hierarchies.
So it's not stuck in any one pyramid at
10 it's partly associated with vision
and the ability to see a long,
long distance also to see what you don't
want to see and to report that back to
the king.
And so the king,
fundamentally,
as far as you guys are concerned from a
psychological perspective,
that's your Super Ego.
That's the Freudian perspective.
Or it might be the moral system by which
you comport yourself,
but your eyes are the thing that updates
that,
right?
You need it to Orient Yourself in the
world.
You need it to Orient Yourself among
other people,
but your eye and your capacity to pay
attention,
especially to what you don't want to pay
attention to is the thing that
continually updates that model.
Exactly as piaget laid out with
children.
So,
and all of that's packed into the
imagery in the first,
you know,
few minutes of this movie.
And that's actually why it really relies
on imagery.
Why this isn't just a lecture by a
psychologist.
You know when you go to see the movie,
it's because the images,
they say a picture is worth a thousand
words,
but,
and there's thousands of pictures in
this movie obviously,
but maybe a picture is worth more words
than you can actually use to describe
it.
If the picture is is profound enough.
And we have many,
many pictures like that and he deeply
picture is virtually inexhaustible in
terms of its semantically with regards
to its explanation.
Images are very,
very dense.
So anyways,
the animals all gathered.
Now the animals are also,
he had representations from the Freud in
perspective and the Ed is the part of
your psyche from the Freudian
perspective,
that's animalistic and,
and,
and full of,
of,
of implicit drives,
sexual and aggressive in particular as
far as Freud was concerned.
And that's because those two drives say
unlike thirst or hunger are much more
difficult to integrate into proper
social being and tend to be excluded and
left unconscious.
And so a lot of Friday and psychology,
and I would say psychology in general is
focused on the integration of sexual
impulses and aggressive impulses into
the psyche.
I would also add to that anxiety because
anxiety is also a major problem.
Anxiety and negative emotion that's pain
like is also a major problem for people.
And so the animals represent those ed
like impulses that have to be organized
hierarchically before you can become an
integrated being in precisely the piaget
had manner,
right?
Because Piaget would say,
well,
the child comes into the world with
reflexes and maybe a more modern
psychologists would also con concentrate
on the implicit motivations.
And those have to be organized inside
the child into some kind of hierarchy of
unity before the child can organize him
or herself into the broader unity of the
state.
And that's basically what's being
represented here.
And so,
so Zazu the eyes of the king comes to
checkout the king,
and that's what's his name?
What's the king's name?
Mufasa.
Yeah.
And he is,
he had a very regal looking person,
a lion,
and he stands up straight and tall.
And that means that he's high in
Serotonin because Saratonin governs
posture reflection.
And if so,
if you're dominant and near the top of
hierarchies,
you tend to expand so that you look
bigger than than you could if you shrunk
down.
And so if you're low dominant person,
you wander around like this so that you
look small and weak and you don't pose a
threat to anybody.
But if you're at the top,
you expand yourself so that you can
command the space.
And that's why he has that particular
kind of regal posture.
And if you look at his facial
expression,
you see that it's quite severe.
He like he's,
he's capable of kindness,
but he's also harsh and judgmental.
And that's what society is like.
That's what the superego is like.
And what that means is that he's
integrated his aggression.
And I've seen this happen in my clinical
clients when they come in and they're
too agreeable,
they look like Simba looks later in the
movie when he's an adolescent and he's
sort of like a deer in headlights.
Everything is coming in and nothing is
coming out.
But when the person integrates their
shadow and gets the aggressive part of
themselves integrated into their
personality,
their faces hardened.
And if you look at people,
you can tell because the people who are
too agreeable,
look childlike and innocent and the
people who will,
a hyper aggressive person will look mean
and cruel.
But
let's see if that's good.
That's still working.
So,
uh,
but I've seen people's face changes,
change face change in the course of
therapy,
men and women.
So,
and what happens is they start to look
more mature and it's more like they're,
they're judging the world as well as
interacting with it properly.
Once they integrate that more
disagreeable part of it,
it's very,
very necessary.
And that's part of the incorporation of
the union shadow or the incorporation of
the unconscious from a Freudian
perspective,
but old Musap Musafa there,
he's already got that,
he's already got that covered.
So,
and he's capable.
Like obviously he can smile and he's
fully capable of the full range of
expressions,
but he's a tough looking character.
And now this they'll baboon here who's
supposed to be basically just a fool.
When the story was first written,
he turned into what's essentially a
sharman across time.
And so he represents the self from the
union perspective.
Now the self is everything you could be
across time.
So you imagine that there's you and
there's the potential inside you,
whatever that is,
you know,
and potential is an interesting idea
because it's represents something that
isn't yet real yet we act like it's real
because people will say to you,
you should live up to your potential.
And that potential is partly what you
could be if you interacted with the
world in a manner that would gain you
the most information,
right?
Because you build yourself out of the
information in the [inaudible] sense.
But it's deeper than that too,
because we know that if you take
yourself and you put yourself in a new
environment,
new genes turn on in your nervous
system,
they encode for new proteins.
And so you're full of biological
potential.
That won't be realized unless you move
yourself around in the world into
different challenging circumstances.
And that'll turn on different circuits.
So it's not merely that you're
incorporating information from the
outside world in the constructivist
sense,
it's that by exposing yourself to
different environments,
you put different physiological demands
on,
on yourself,
all the way down to the genetic level.
And that manifests new elements of you.
And so one of the things that happens to
people,
and this is a very common cultural
notion,
is that you should go on a pilgrimage at
some point to somewhere central in that
would be say like the Rock and the pride
rock and the lion king because you take
yourself out of your dopey little
village and that's just the little
bounded you that everyone knows and that
isn't very expanded.
And then you go somewhere dark and
dangerous to the central place.
And while you do that,
you have adventures and they toughen you
and pull more out of you.
And like partly because you're becoming
informed,
which means information,
it means you're becoming more organized
at every level of analysis.
But there's also more of you too.
And so that's a very classic idea.
And then in cathedrals in Europe,
especially at charter,
there's a big maze on the floor,
a circular maize,
which is a symbolic representation of
the pilgrimage for people who couldn't
do it.
And so it's a huge circle divided into
quadrants,
which is a union Mandela.
And you enter the maize at one point and
then you have to walk through the entire
maze north,
east,
west,
and south before you get to the center.
And the center is symbolized by a flower
that's carved in stone.
It looks like this.
It's big.
This means,
hey,
it's,
it's large so that you can walk it and
that's a symbolic pilgrimage.
It takes you to the center.
That's the center of the Cross because
it tended cathedral.
And that's the point of acceptance,
of voluntary suffering.
That's what that means.
And so you walk through,
you can call that a circum ambulation.
You go to all the quarters of the world
to find yourself.
And so
well the self is,
is the baboon in this particular,
in this pr,
I think he's a mandrill actually in this
particular representation.
And he lives in the tree.
He lives in the tree of life.
It's a bale,
Bab tree,
and this particular,
so he's the spirit that inhabits the
tree of life and he's the eternal wise
man.
That's a way of thinking.
So is the king,
but he's,
he's sort of a superordinate king or an
outside king in some sense.
He's the repository of ancient wisdom.
And the king is the manner in which that
wisdom is currently being acted out in
the world.
And so their friends,
and that means that the king,
he's a good king because if they,
if the king was a bad king,
he would be alienated from himself and
that would make him shallow and one
dimensional.
And that would make him a bad ruler.
No union with the traditions of the
past.
To be a good ruler,
you have to rescue your father from the
underworld and integrate that.
And of course that's a main theme in
this entire movie.
So
hey,
a new mystery to solve.
Okay,
so the hero was born and that's what the
rising sun represents.
And everybody goes,
oh,
isn't that cute?
And the reason for that is because
you're biologically wired,
especially if you're agreeable to
respond with caretaking activity to cute
to cuteness and cuteness is button,
nose,
big eyes,
small mouth,
roundhead symmetry and helpless
movements.
And you'll respond to that across the
entire class of Mammalian,
of Mammalian creatures,
even maybe down to lizards.
You know,
isn't that cute?
It's no,
it's a lizard.
But you know,
so,
so that's an archetype as well.
That's the archetype of the vulnerable
hero at bore,
the vulnerable hero,
newly born.
And that should invoke a desire mostly
on the part of males to encourage and
mostly on the part of females to neuro
to nurture.
But males and females are quite cross
wired among human beings.
And so there's encouragement from the
women.
And there's also near nurturing from the
man.
And of course those,
those curves in some sense overlap.
So there's more nurturing males and more
encouraging females.
But that's roughly the archetype.
And so he looks cute and everybody goes
on.
And that's because the animators nailed
that.
They,
the essential features of cuteness and
he's also in the light,
right?
And so then the Sharman mandrill
basically baptizes him.
That's essentially what he's doing.
And he uses something that's symbolic of
the sun,
which is this ripe fruit and fruits are
symbolic of the sun because of course
they need the sun to ripen and they're
round like the sun.
And so,
and people know that they need light.
But and,
and so anyways,
the animators make a relationship
between the fruit that the Shaman is
going to break and the sun.
And so he's also being baptized into the
sun and that means that he's being
baptized into the light or that he's
being transformed into a hero.
And so then everyone's happy and that's
basically,
you know,
the divine father in the divine mother
and the divine son and the self who's
taking care of that.
And there's a union between the baby and
the wise old man because the baby is all
the potential that's realized in the
self.
And there's an old idea that the way to
full maturity is to find what you lost
as a child had regain it.
It's a brilliant idea.
And that,
that,
that echoes through miss all over the
world.
And that means you have to regain your
capacity once you're disciplined and you
know how to do something,
you have to regain your capacity for
play and sort of for wide eyed wonder.
And that's maybe the child like part of
your spirit and the reintegration of
that child,
like part with the adult grownup part
revivified as the adult grownup part and
allows the child to manifest itself in a
disciplined way in the world.
And so that's all being hinted that
there.
And then they show the Sharman shows the
baby,
the newborn hero to the crowded.
It's very cool what happens in the
movie,
all the animals spontaneously,
Neil,
and I can give you an example of that
kind of spontaneous action in a crowd.
So imagine you're watching a
gymnastics performance,
right?
And it's like at a high level world
class performance and someone comes out
there and they do this routine that's
just dead letter perfect.
You know,
and they stop and everybody claps like
mad,
right?
And it's perfect.
And so then the next contestant comes
out and they're basically in real
trouble because you know,
this person just got 9.7 out of 10 and
it was perfect.
So how do you beat perfect.
And so will they come out there and then
you watch them and you're right on the
edge of your seat because what you see
them do is something extraordinarily
disciplined just like the last person to
yet.
But they push themselves into that zone
that's just beyond their discipline
capacity.
And you can tell every second you're
watching it that they're that close to
disaster.
And so you're right on the edge of your
seat and,
and you know that they're doing a high
wire act without a net.
And so when they finally land
triumphantly,
you'll all stand up and clap
spontaneously.
And it's because you've just witnessed
someone who's a master at playing a
game,
who's also a master at improving how to
play that game at the same time.
And people love that more than anything
to see that it's just absolutely
overwhelming cause it's a testament to
the human spirit and you'll respond
automatically and unconsciously to that.
And that's why that's an analogy to why
the animals all spontaneously bow when
now what happens is they sh he shows the
lion king and the sun breaks and shines
on that the hero at the same time.
So there's this concordance between an
earthly event and as so called heavenly
event and human would call that
synchronous.
That's his idea of synchronicity where
something important subjectively is also
signified by something that appears in
narrative keeping with that in the
outside world.
And it's one of the most controversial
elements of his theory,
but I've experienced a variety of
synchronous events and they often happen
in therapy,
especially around dreams,
but they're very hard to communicate
because they're so specific to the
context in which it occurs.
They're very difficult to explain.
So anyways,
it's the syncronous event that make
drops all the animals to their knees.
So there's the sun coming out and
there's shining on them and all the
primates go mad for that.
And that's of course exactly what we do
when we applaud and then we switched to
scar.
Now scar is Mufasa's brother evil
brother.
The king always has an evil brother and
so does the hero.
The hero always has an adversary and the
reason for that is the king always has
an evil brother and that means that the
state always has it.
Tyrannical element.
And the tyrannical element exists for
two reasons.
One is the state deteriorates of its own
accord and that's an entropy
observation.
What that means is that the state is a
construction of the past,
right?
But the present isn't the same as the
past.
And to the degree that the past is
mismatched with the demands of the
present,
then it's,
then it's a tyrannical,
it's malfunctioning.
And so it's,
it's a continual problem with the state.
It's always two steps behind the
environment.
And so then that means that the
awareness of living people has to update
the state.
And so elliot and Murcia,
Eliana,
who's a great historian of religions,
looked at flood stories from all over
the world because there are flood
stories from all over the world,
partly because there are floods all over
the world.
But that there's a psychological reason
too.
So you imagine that New Orleans was
wiped out by a hurricane,
right?
A flood,
and you say,
well,
that was an act of God,
but then you think,
wait a second,
wait a second.
They knew those damn dikes weren't going
to hold.
They knew they weren't built strong
enough.
They took the money that was allocated
to the dikes and spent it badly.
And that was willful blindness.
And so you could say that it was God who
caused the flood,
so to speak,
metaphorically.
But you could also say that it was the
degeneration of the state and the
willful blindness of the politicians
that caused the flood in Holland.
They build the dikes to withstand the
worst storm in 10,000 years in the use
other than us.
They built them to withstand the worst
storm in a hundred years.
And they knew that that was
insufficient.
And so the flood,
if there's a flood,
while you can say,
well,
that's an act of nature,
but you can also say,
just wait a sec.
Maybe if there was a flood,
because we looked the other way and
because our systems are out of date,
and that's why in flood stories there's,
there's a continual theme,
which is the people get wiped out by the
flood because God judges them harshly
for their senility and they're willful
blindness.
And it's a story that's very much,
you'll have a flood in your life,
right?
It'll be a flood of chaos and you will
find a of one form or another.
And you'll find when you investigate the
causes of the flood that some of it will
be,
and sometimes this is the case,
it's just random.
You just got singled out,
you got a terrible disease and that's
the end of you,
or something like that.
But there'll be other situations where
the flood comes and you're surrounded by
chaos and you'll look into it.
You'll think,
I knew this was coming.
I knew I wasn't paying attention.
I knew I hadn't sorted things out.
And the consequences of that will have
cascaded and wiped you out.
And then you're in real trouble because
not only did you get wiped out,
but you also know it's your fault.
And that is not a good thing that makes
you bitter and resentful and murderous
would not happen.
So anyways,
scar is scarred,
right?
So what that implies is he's had a
pretty rough life and he's kind of
skinny and he said he was born in the
low end of the gene pool.
And so he has reasons to be resentful.
He's also hyper intelligent and
rational.
And it's one of the things you see very
commonly about the evil adversary of the
state or of the individuals,
often intelligent and hyper rational.
And the best commentator on that was
probably John Milton in paradise lost
because that's how he represents Lucifer
or Satan,
who's the spirit of rationality and
enlightenment.
Strangely enough,
hence Lucifer,
the bringer of light.
And the reason for that,
as far as I can tell them,
this is something that Milton figured
out when he compiled all these ancient
stories about evil and tried to make
them coherent,
was that the problem with irrationality
with rationality is that it tends to
fall in love with its own productions,
right?
And so then it comes up with a theory
and it makes that a totality and then it
won't let go.
So the rational mind has a totalitarian
element and we know that to some degree
because that kind of rationality seems
more left hemisphere focused and the
left hemisphere tends to impose
structured order on the world and be
updated by the right hemisphere.
And the right hemisphere generally
updates it with negative information and
with fantasy.
And so the left hemisphere will impose a
coherent structure on the world,
which is really necessary for you to
live in it.
But the problem is there's a tension
between coherence and completeness.
And that's partly why you need two
hemispheres.
You need one to represent the world and
you need one to keep track of the
exceptions and to feed those slowly into
the representational system so that it
so that it can stay updated without
collapsing into complete chaos.
So anyways,
scar and he's,
he's got this like droopy mouth in this
whiny,
arrogant voice and he feels hard done by
and he's resentful and,
and in,
in classic hero stories are stories of
the state as well.
The,
so this is an Egyptian take on it.
Oh,
Cyrus was,
was the god of the state and who later
became Satan,
that name became Satan.
Has It transformed through Coptic
Christianity?
Oh,
cyrus had a brother named set and set.
He didn't pay attention to set enough
attention.
Instead was always scheming,
scheming to overthrow the kingdom,
just like scar is.
And the Egyptians said straightforwardly
that the reason that oh cyrus got
overthrown by sad,
he got chopped into pieces and his
pieces distributed throughout the state
in the mythological representation.
And those pieces were actually the
provinces of Egypt,
technically speaking.
So,
and,
and that's what the Egyptians thought.
So that's quite cool.
But the Egyptian said explicitly that
the reason that ocirus got overthrown by
set was because he was willfully blind,
old,
senile,
and willfully blind.
Same idea as the flood myth.
You don't see that quite here because
Mufasa is sort of on to set or to scar,
but scar is more treacherous than Mo.
Fasa believes and he gets that.
He gets at who Fossa by going through
his son.
Bye Bye.
By playing on the,
on the impulsivity and juvenile
qualities of his son.
And so obviously there's some antagonism
between these two as you can see by
their facial expressions there.
And there's the good example of scar.
You know,
he's got that droopy kind of whiny
malevolent face and that malevolent
voice that Jeremy Irons pulls it off so
incredibly well.
And he's,
he's always skulking,
he's a creature of the night.
He always skulks around.
He's not a creature of the day in any
sense of the word.
And you know,
obviously Mufasa is golden,
like the sun and scars dark like the
night.
That's another thing,
another clue.
Another hint.
Okay,
there's the tree.
That's the tree of life.
We already talked about that.
I think that represents the multiple
levels at which you exist
simultaneously,
all the way from the Subatomic,
all the way up to the cosmic,
so to speak.
And that's a different kind of
dimension.
And that's the,
that's the place that the self inhabits
and it can kind of move up and down
those dimensions.
But anyways,
that the Sharman lives inside that tree.
And,
and I was our first introduction to him,
basically,
but he's the spirit of the ancient tree.
That's another way of thinking about a
very,
very common element in stories,
right?
The spirit of the ancient tree.
And so,
all right,
so now,
uh,
Mufasa has taken,
taken Simba up to the top of the
pyramid,
right?
So that's the,
the aluminum place,
let's say,
or the place of the eye where you can
really see a long ways and he's
explaining to him what his kingdom is
going to be.
And you see the sun of course appears at
that to begin with.
And that's another hint about being at
the top.
That's the illuminated part of the
pyramid.
And so they're up there talking.
And what Mufasa tells Simba is that his
kingdom is every place the light has
touched.
And that's so brilliant.
So one of the things you'll notice if
you move into a new apartment,
you're like a cat.
Cats don't like changing houses and they
have to zoom around in every corner to
see exactly what the hell is going on
there before they calm down.
They need to know they can hide and
where the potential dangers are.
And what you'll find if you move into a
new place that you will not be
comfortable there until you've
investigated,
potentially cleaned and repaired every
single square inch of it,
the more attention you pay to it,
the more it will become yours.
And that's far more than mirror,
like material ownership,
which is also relevant.
But in order to feel comfortable
somewhere and to dominate that place,
to be in meshed in that place,
you have to attend to it.
You have to shine light on every corner
and you have to do that with yourself
and with your relationships as well.
And so anyways,
Mufasa tells Simba that his kingdom is
everything that the light shines on.
And that's exactly right.
And then there's a metaphor there too,
which is that what you've shown light
on,
which is what you've come to understand
and master is surrounded by an other
world of all the things that you don't
understand.
And some of those would be natural
things and some of them would be
tyrannical things.
And some of those would be things you
don't want to know about yourself,
but they're outside of where you've
managed to shine the light.
And so that's exactly what Mufasa tells
Simba.
He says,
we live in this pyramid,
we're at the top.
There's a domain of light around it
that's explored territory.
Outside of that,
there's explore unexplored territory.
And that's partly the unconscious
because you fill it with fantasy and
it's partly what you just don't know.
And then move fossa tells Simba and it's
sort of like God telling Adam and Eve in
the garden of Eden not to eat the apple.
Mufasa tells Simba there's this outside
place that's dark,
that's not part of your kingdom and you
should not go there.
And that's really interesting because
Simba doesn't even know about that place
yet.
And so Mufasa is doing something very
contradictory there.
It's like telling them that it exists
and heightening his curiosity,
but also saying that he should go there
almost ensuring that that's exactly what
Simba is going to do.
You See this in the Pinocchio Movie to
where Pinocchio is planning to jump into
the ocean to go get uh,
Japan from the underworld and he's
following his conscience is along with
them.
Jimminy cricket and the cricket is
warning him about all the dangers that
he'll face down there and telling him
that he will be fish food personally.
And while he's doing that,
Pinocchio ties a knot around his donkey
tail around rock so he can sink and the
little cricket helps them tie the
naughts.
So while he's warning them about the
adventure he's going to undertake,
at the same time,
he's encouraging to do it.
And there's that paradoxical thing,
which is that if you go outside what you
know,
it will cause a fall because it'll
damage your knowledge structures and
you'll go down into chaos and that can
really destroy you.
So you shouldn't do it.
But by the same token,
if you do do it and you do it
successfully,
then the new you that arises can be
stronger and more complete than the
previous youth.
So you should do it and you shouldn't do
it.
And that's anyone sensible says,
look,
don't bother.
Right,
but sensible isn't enough.
That's the thing.
You have to also be not sensible enough
in order to live.
And your typical hero and potter's a
really good example is always a rule
breaker always.
But he,
you know,
the rules he breaks are like there's
judiciousness behind the rule.
Breaking the hero breaks a rule in the
service of a higher good,
but he's still breaking the rules.
And that's what puts him outside the
boundary of the social of the social
establishment.
So
now at this point,
Simba also gets introduced to scar and
that,
that has two meanings.
One is that scar is the tyrannical
element of the state.
And so as a child,
when you're being socialized,
you encounter the tyranny of the state
and one of the best,
you can't,
there's no way around it.
One of the best examples of that is that
children are always running around
having fun and they're really bubbly
and,
and impulsive and joyous and playful.
And that causes a lot of trouble because
positive emotion is very disruptive.
They'll run around and break things,
they'll hurt themselves and they'll get
into trouble.
And so you're always saying,
calm down,
sit down,
behave,
don't do that.
And it's not because they're crying or
angry,
it's because they're so damn happy and
impulsive that no one could stand them.
And so and so that's a tyranny.
It's like that.
The state puts,
puts pressure on you to regulate your
emotions,
positive,
negative and positive,
and it crushes you.
It crushes the life out of you,
a lot of it.
And so you end up,
you know,
your age and you're all mopey because
the whole,
especially because you've been forced to
sit down in school for like 17 years,
you're all mopey and it's no wonder,
you know,
you've had the spirit taken out of you
by the process of discipline,
but without that you'd be completely
useless.
So it's another one of those
paradoxical,
you know,
gifts.
And,
and catastrophes that you encounter as
you move through life.
So anyways,
Simba,
look at how happy he is.
You know,
I mean,
he doesn't know a damn thing.
He's so naive.
You can tell by,
oh look,
it's so my uncle scar.
It's like,
you know,
and this is not a guy you smile at
clearly,
but he's all positive emotion and joy
and enthusiasm.
And that's not good because that means
this character can take serious
advantage of it.
And that's exactly what he does.
And so scarp pretends to be on his side,
which is what a good pedophile always
does,
by the way.
And so,
you know,
you,
you take advantage of the child's
trusting nature and openness in order to
exploit them.
And that's,
that's what horrible people do that all
the time,
including the parents of children and
other children themselves.
So,
you know,
there's this false,
I've been looking at,
the animators are so damn brilliant,
hey,
look at that expression,
really like,
you know,
you just look at that and you think,
well,
that's just a facial expression.
But of course it's not.
Some damn animators worked a really hard
to get that.
They're really observant and they
distill the facial looks,
look how big the face is,
right?
It covers the whole head and,
and they,
they've got the eyebrow lifts proper and
they've got this horrible sanctimonious
smile and the tilt of the head then,
you know,
and he sort of crushing him while he's
hugging them at the same time.
Really,
really.
And you know,
it took a lot of thought for every
single one of these frames to be put
together.
Right.
There's a tremendous amount of cognitive
effort that went that.
So none of this is accidental.
Yeah.
Well that pretty much says everything.
It's like,
I hate that kid could hardly wait until
he's gone and didn't die.
Pull one over on them.
You know,
it's a real testament to an adult's
genius when he can fool a kid.
So then Simba encounters the anima.
That's the anima,
the Union Anima and the Anima is the
feminine counterpart in the soul.
And she,
well yeah,
you could tell what she does to him,
right?
Because she's got this super silly
ascend and what would you say?
Judgemental and Teasey look on her face
and she's really tried to put him down
and it's working like bad.
He's not very happy about that at all.
And she's the thing,
this is what the enema does,
the soul,
she's the thing that teaches the
exploratory hero that,
that it's not everything it could be.
Right.
And that's part of this can be read
multiple ways,
but it's part of the eternal tendency of
women to make men self conscious by
their sexual subjectivity.
That's part of it because that makes men
self conscious like nothing else.
And it's also perhaps being one of the
phenomena that's produced the
evolutionary arms race in this,
in this sex,
is it among human beings that's caused
our rapid cortical expansion and our,
our,
our quick movement away from chimpanzees
who aren't selective majors by the way.
So look at him.
Jesus,
he just want to slap him,
right?
He's uh,
he's the son of a king,
so he's very,
very privileged and he confuses his
privilege with competence.
Richard,
of course all of you do because you are
all sons of the king,
which is why you can sit here in the
university and you confuse your
privilege with competence as well
because it's not,
has nothing to do with any of you that
the lights are on and it's place is so
peaceful.
Right?
But you take that for granted and it can
make you false and arrogant like,
like Jesus.
That's just so sad.
You look at that kid,
you think he's,
he's in for real trouble,
man.
He thinks he knows everything.
And of course that he has a wrestling
match with,
what's her name?
What's it,
was it Nala?
Yeah,
it has a wrestling match with knowledge.
She just pins him every time.
Right.
Gotcha.
Again,
pinned the again and that's basically
right.
One of the things that happens with men
when they meet a woman who they really
desire and admires,
they project an ideal onto her
immediately.
That's an anima projection.
And then that Adam,
a projection judges them and they act
all inferior and stupid.
And it's partly because they are,
that's why.
And so then they go down in defeat
constantly to this thing that they're
projecting,
which at least has some concordance with
the actual woman,
but not that much.
So,
okay,
they keep wrestling and then they're on
the fringe of the kingdom.
This wrestling match between this pairs
of opposites takes them to the edge of
the kingdom and they end up in the
elephants' graveyard.
Right?
And,
and there's,
there's bones everywhere.
And so now they're out into the Kingdom
of death.
And what that means is that these two
kids,
as they've grown up,
encountered death,
right?
They go outside the light and it's very,
very shocking for them.
They're very curious about it.
Obviously they go to explore the
skeletons and all of that,
even though they were not to,
but their curiosity,
they can't stay away from death.
There are too curious about it.
And so they develop knowledge of death
and that.
And then of course out there in the
dead,
lounds is where the hyenas are.
And that's exactly right.
Cause Hyenas are scavengers,
right?
And they can break bones with their
teeth.
They're really,
really quite the animal.
And you know,
you kind of have a shudder of repugnance
when you see those things.
And I think it's partly,
I mean,
we shared an evolutionary landscape with
the ancestors of hyenas for a very,
very long time.
And like vultures too,
you know,
you couldn't imagine something that
would be more well designed to look like
it was a horrible thing than a vulture.
Right.
And there's this weird concordance and
crows and ravens are like that to carry
an eaters.
You know,
eagles are kind of an exception,
but they look just as creepy as they
are,
which is really quite interesting.
And of course hyenas fall into that
category and they laugh too,
which is,
you know,
really you,
you also have to laugh really with all
these other things you have going for
you.
And anyways,
the hyenas and hyenas are enemies of
lions and they can take lions down their
tough things.
And you know,
they're not one hyena obviously,
but a bunch of hyenas can give a line
and pretty damn rough time.
And so,
and these little lines are really no
match for the hyenas.
And so they get threatened very,
very rapidly.
And one of the hygienists,
of course,
it's just completely out of its mind.
And one of the things that's really
interesting and you see this with the
muppets too,
there was often a puppet that was like a
crazy puppet and its eyes would move in
different directions.
You know,
and one of the things that happens with
people who are schizophrenia as they
show involuntary eye movements,
and it's because you have a brain center
that controls your eyes voluntarily and
you have another one that controls them
in voluntarily.
So you can see that look ahead and try
to move your eyes smoothly back and
forth.
You can't do it.
You'll see that they jerk,
hey,
but if you watch,
put a finger in front of your face and
then do this,
they'll move perfectly smoothly.
And that's because you're using
different eye control centers,
one voluntary and one more involuntary.
And the involuntary one is actually more
sophisticated.
And so in schizophrenia,
the involuntary eye control centers tend
to disrupt the voluntary eye control
centers.
And that's likely part of the
hallucinatory process,
you know,
because you have the ego in the
schizophrenia that's being disrupted by
processes underneath fantasies and that
sort of thing that looks like it's
reflected in involuntary eye movements,
like,
like dream movements.
So anyways,
so much for the crazy hyena and they're
in real trouble now the kings I who's
supposed to be keeping an eye on this
and we're supposed to be watching Simba
is trying to intervene,
but I mean look at him,
he's like delicious little bird.
And so that's not working out very well
anyways.
And then you see this immediate
juxtaposition of the domain of death and
the hyenas with hell,
right?
And everyone looks at that and they
think,
well,
they,
they know exactly what that means.
It's no surprise to anyone that that
happens.
And I suppose that's partly because on
the velt where we evolved in large part,
but not by no means all part fire was an
ever present danger in the grasslands.
Right.
And so,
and so,
uh,
that's a good,
that's a good example of hail.
So,
Huh.
Well
I guess that's it.
We'll do some more of this when we meet
on Tuesday.
Bye.