All right.
Welcome back.
So the next four lectures are also
oriented towards discussion of primarily
clinical theories of psychology and
psychopathology.
We're going to talk about lines of
thinking that in some ways run parallel
to those of the site ground lists
because the thinkers we're going to
discuss now and with a few small
exceptions,
well all of them,
all of the thinkers we're going to
discuss in the next four lectures were
either influenced heavily by Freud,
human adler or
word themselves,
thinkers who influenced Freud in me up.
So there's an intellectual continuity
stretching over with,
with people who are deeply educated and
who are very thoughtful.
There's intellectual continuity ideas,
stretching over exceptional spans of
time.
And so it's exactly the sort of thing
that you would,
that sort of relationship is exactly
what you'd imagined.
Um,
Roger has had a variety of influences,
so let's say Freud and Jung and Adler,
but he was also very much influenced by
phenomenological ideas and the
phenomenologists app were,
and our phenomenologies a brand of
philosophy and
which I'll explain more deeply.
And the other primary domain of
influence on Rogers was Christianity
likely.
And,
and then
Christianity also via probably northern
European culture as far as I can tell.
The reason I'm,
I'm talking specifically about
Christianity in relationship to rogers
is because as a young man,
he was a fundamentalist Christian and he
was a seminarian.
So we had,
he was quite oriented towards
mainline Protestant Christianity.
But when he was in university,
he had a crisis of belief,
I suppose,
when he was even going to go to China as
a missionary at one point.
Um,
but he had a crisis of belief in
university because he'd also been
scientifically trained.
His father was a farmer who used rather
advanced farming techniques.
And so rogers was trained to think
scientifically from a very young age and
he experienced the conflict between his
religious belief and his scientific
presuppositions quite intensely.
And in that battle is formal Christian
belief was the loser.
However,
his thinking is very much influenced by
fundamentalist Protestant
presuppositions.
And,
uh,
the effect of those all described as we
walked through Roger's thinking.
Now
it's important to understand the
philosophical underpinnings of a global
personality or psychology theory because
every theory is set within a set of
assumptions,
things that you have to assume to be
true in order to proceed with the theory
and like the axioms in,
in,
uh,
in classical geometry,
you can't prove the axiom that you have
to accept them.
Once you accept the axioms,
then you can move forward and use the
whole system.
I think the reason that systems have to
have axioms,
which are items,
elements of belief is because every
system is incomplete,
right?
It doesn't cover the entire world.
And so in some sense you need a place to
dispense with your ignorance.
And the way you do that is by making
assumptions.
We're going to act as if the following
is true and then you can proceed with a
partial theory and you'll have some
success with it.
But it's useful to understand the
presuppositions because they'd orients
you properly towards the theory.
Now Rogers is a phenomenologist and
phenomenology is a brand of philosophy,
which I believe started with Edmund
Husserl but was probably made most
influential by his student Martin
Heidegger.
Now heidegger
was,
there was a philosopher,
I suppose something somewhat like Nicha
and that he was very much his thinking
around,
very much counter to what you might
describe as general academic philosophy.
Um,
for example,
heidegger believed that ever since the
time of Plato,
which is when people think philosophy
began more or less western philosophy
had taken an erroneous direction.
It had become too concerned with the
nature of structures of thought and not
concerned enough about the nature of
being.
And so you can determine those two
things being as how things are and
thought of course is how you represent
things.
And one of heidegger's
missions was to reestablish being as the
central
reality of philosophy.
Now that begs a question,
which is what is being well
to conceptualize reality as being is not
to conceptualize it the same way that
you conceptualize it
in terms of modern Western thought.
Because one of the presuppositions at
the basis of modern Western thought is
that the most intelligent way to divide
up the world is in terms of subjective
and objective experience or subjective
and subjective experience and object of
world.
So the fundamental scientific
presupposition you might say is that
there is an objective world.
It's the real thing.
You come to that by performing certain
procedures,
documenting them,
describe them,
the outcome of those procedures,
documenting them and then allowing other
people to do the same thing,
operating under the presupposition that
if they experience the same outcome from
the procedures,
then what they're experiencing is real.
That's basically the scientific method,
right?
Method results.
You detailed the method,
which is how you act on the world.
You'd get the results,
you compare them maybe across multiple
observations that you do and then other
people do multiple observations that
you've come up with that with a
consensus,
but it's a method bound consensus and
then of course you abstract out general
principles from that and it works very
powerfully,
right?
Make no mistake about it.
The objective,
the idea that there was an objective
external world and that that's the best
way to conceptualize reality is an
unbelievably powerful tool.
Now,
whether or not it's an accurate
description of reality,
that's a much more difficult question
and it's partly a matter of definition
actually,
you know,
it's the case that there are different
forms of geometry.
You might know this,
you can start from the presupposition
that reality has a three dimensional
structure and then you're basically
within the realm of Euclidean geometry.
But you can also start with the
presupposition that reality has a four
dimensional structure and that kind of
geometry was invented in the late 18
hundreds and it turned out to be the
perfect geometry to describe the
universe that Einstein conceptualized
when he came up with his great theories
in,
in the second decade there abouts of the
20th century.
So it's interesting because you can
start from different assumptions,
build tools on the basis of those
assumptions and sometimes you find out
that those tools work very well.
Indeed.
Now it's not that easy to think of flaws
in the subjective experience,
objective world conceptualization.
And that's partly for,
as for us as modern people,
it forms the basis of so much of what we
think that we just think about it as
axiomatic.
It's just true.
It doesn't bear any question,
but I'm going to offer you a couple of
examples of why it might bear some
questioning and you can,
you can think about,
you can think about it.
The first problem is is that the
classical scientific view of the world
has a very difficult time accounting for
certain things.
So for example,
these are called quality a often by
people who were interested in
consciousness.
So knowing the wavelength of light
doesn't seem to tell you much about the
subjective experience of color.
You know,
we experienced for example,
in a non continuous fashion,
right?
Cause we see discrete colors like you'd
see in a rainbolt.
I mean they shade into each other to
some degree,
but it's not like they go from light red
to dark red in the continuum.
There's clear demarcations of color.
While that's because of the way your
brain is wired.
You know,
it seems like over the course of
evolution,
what we've learned is that parsing up
that wavelength fragment in terms of
categories which would be the different
colors that we see has substantial
practical utility.
Now what are the things you might ask
is,
well,
do those colors exist?
Well,
objectively they don't seem to exist as
colors.
Partly because of the,
the wavelengths that we see are actually
continuous.
So when one color shades into another,
there's no radical transformation in
wave lake length.
It's a continuum,
but we see it categorically.
Okay,
so is that real or not?
Or The colors we see real or not?
Well,
that's a good question.
Um,
you can't get a collective experience of
pain.
Like you can get a collective experience
of the blackboard,
but pain seems to be something that's
limited to subjective perception,
but it's very difficult.
No one acts as if pain isn't real.
I mean,
I would say that
of all the things that you might
consider real,
we act as if pain is the most real
thing.
You certainly can't argue yourself out
of it.
For example.
It seems like a fundamental element of
experience.
Okay,
so that's two places.
We also have no account in the
subjective objective,
what breakup bifurcation of the world.
We have no explanation whatsoever for
consciousness.
That seems like a big problem,
right,
because you could make a case that
there's no being without consciousness.
Like is there something if there's no
one there to perceive it.
By the way,
that is not the same question as if a
tree falls in the forest and there's no
one there to hear it.
Does it make a sound?
It's not the same question.
It sounds superficially the same,
but this is a much more complex question
because we don't know.
For example,
if we don't know the relationship
between time and consciousness,
like we have a certain perception of
time.
We have a certain temporal realm within
which we exist.
Our refresh rate for our vision for
example,
is about 60 hertz,
which is why you can see computer
screens flicker or if they have a reflex
rate that's slower than that.
So 60 hertz to us looks continuous,
but you know,
there's a lot of microseconds in a
second for a computer,
especially a fast process it computer
that can do maybe a trillion operations
per second if it was watching,
so to speak a movie,
it would just see a picture still
picture that was there forever and then
another still picture that was there
forever and like it wouldn't have the
impression of continuous movement.
So there's this weird subjective element
to time.
It's very difficult to understand.
And then here's a more,
here's a more complex criticism of the
subject object idea.
I thought about this for a long time.
So the best example I know of it is I
read this book a while back written by a
kgb officer and it was published after
the fall of the,
you know,
the wall and the Soviet Empire.
And this KGB officer claimed that he had
worked in a biological warfare unit in
the Soviet Union and the purpose of the
biological warfare unit was to turn
infectious diseases into aerosols so
that they can be sprayed on enemy
populations.
And so they were working on two things,
developing a very,
very silent infection.
And so if you're willing to infection is
one that's very severe but also very
transmissible cause those things are
separate.
And then also one that could survive
being aerosolized because it turns out
that that's quite difficult,
which we should all be very thankful
about.
And one of the projects they were
working on was uh,
an attempt to cross Ebola with smallpox.
Now he bulla is,
you all know about Ebola,
I presume it's uh,
it's very,
very fatal although they've learned ways
to treat it now and maybe have a
vaccine.
But at that time it was very,
very fatal and a small smallpox is
incredibly contagious.
And so they were hoping they could
develop something that you said it was
very,
very contagious and very,
very deadly and that you could spray on
civilian populations.
Now you know,
here,
here's where it gets tricky.
It gets tricky here because
how you answered this question
inevitably lead inevitably depends on
how you define truth and truth is
actually something you have to define
before you can have a conversation about
it,
which is a kind of a strange thing
anyways.
You can make a case that determining how
to cross Ebola with small parks and
aerosolize.
It is a perfectly valid scientific
question
and because science is value free,
it's very difficult to make an argument
that that's any worse experiment than
any other kind of experiment or any
other kind of investigation.
And you could also imagine,
even if you didn't go to the
aerosolization stage,
that positive things might come out of
it.
Maybe you'd end up with a more detailed
understanding of DNA or something as a
consequence of the investigation that
would have positive consequences.
But it still seems
that the idea of doing scientific
research across Ebola,
smallpox,
there seems to be something wrong about
that.
And it's maybe that sense of wrongness
as well that can't be captured with
inside,
inside scientific models.
And so
one of the things that you claimed him
and Rogers and the is that in some sense
is that the scientific reality has to be
encapsulated within a,
an ethical reality rather than the other
way around.
Now Rogers would say,
you know that feeling you have when you
hear about someone crossing Ebola with
smallpox,
that feeling you have in your body,
that's a real thing.
That feeling and that that's part of
being
now
for the phenomenologists being is
actually,
it's complicated
to define and it's hard to understand,
but what the phenomenologists do,
we start with a different set of
assumptions.
They don't assume that the best way to
approach reality is to break it up into
the subjective and the object they
presume instead that the way that you
should approach reality is by assuming
that all of your experiences real,
all of it.
Now,
that doesn't mean there are different
categories of experience,
you know,
because you could still say a dream and
the experience you have walked dreaming
of walking down the street and walking
down the street are still different
things and the phenomenologists would
say,
yes,
you can keep your categorical
distinctions in tact,
but you have to say that they're both
real.
Now
this is an assumption and I told you why
the assumptions generating part of the
reason the assumption has generated the
alternative assumption is because there
are problems that emerge with the set of
assumptions that make up the scientific
worldview.
Now,
it's not that surprising that the
scientific worldview can't encompass the
subjective because the scientific world
view was actually established by,
by Bacon and descartes safe and by well
by other thinkers of that time it was
set up to exclude the subjective from
the conceptualization of objective
reality.
So you can't really criticize science
because he does that.
But you can say the fact that this
objective is excluded is a fault or at
least an incompleteness.
And that incompleteness sometimes has
extraordinary,
extraordinarily serious consequences
that you can't just dismiss because you
might say,
well,
had the Russians being the Soviet being
successful in crossing Ebola with small
pox and aerosolizing it,
then we might all be dead.
And then you might think that any theory
that leads everyone to be dead might
reasonably crypt be criticized for its
assumption to universal truth.
Now you can debate that,
but,
and,
and rightly so,
but all I'm pointing out is there are
reasons to go at this from another
approach.
Now,
it was Roger's basic assumption that,
okay,
you are more likely to be properly
oriented in life if you adopted a
phenomenal logical approach to your
experience and to break up reality in
that manner.
So let me give you an example.
When I,
when my daughter was about three,
she have nightmare and she came running
into
her parent's bedroom and
she told me her dream and she was all
upset by it.
She might've even been younger than
three at that point,
had she and dreamed that there was a
clear stream and that it was quite
beautiful and that there was garbage
littering the bottom of it.
Now by that time,
you know,
she kids are quite sophisticated in
their ability to categorize.
You know,
by that time she'd already learned the
difference between kid and adult things.
And you think that's a bloody complex
form of discrimination,
you know,
because like what objective features do
adult things sharing common that
differentiates them from kid things?
You,
you can't actually come up with a set of
objective criteria that allows that
distinction to be made.
But kids,
by the time they're three years,
got a pretty clear grasp of that.
So they can come up with very
sophisticated classifications,
um,
about the same time.
But one of my friends had a two year old
who went outside their house one day and
look down the street and there were a
couple of garbage cans knocked over and
the kid said,
oh,
and you know that's also extremely
sophisticated because you think,
you know the a whole street is a very
complex visual set of visual stimuli.
And to be able to glance at that and
then to know that something is out of
place and then to make an utterance
solid to draw people's attention to it,
is it ridiculously sophisticated
cognitive out?
And my daughter was doing the same thing
within the context of her dream.
So she was upset about this.
Now it's quite interesting because you'd
think,
well,
why would someone who was three be upset
about the fact that a stream beautiful,
clear stream was but had garbage in it?
You know,
it's,
it's a really,
it's like innate environmentalism or
something like that and concerned for
the environment.
And that could easily be the case.
You know what I mean?
If we followed our environment up
continually during our evolutionary
history that was likely to have very
negative consequences.
Even birds clean their own nest and so
do with bees and you know they keep
their hives clean and all of that.
So it could be a very primordial
instinct.
Anyway,
she came in with the stream and she was
quite upset and then you think,
well there's a couple of things you
could do about that.
You could say it's just a dream,
don't worry about it,
go back to sleep.
But you know,
that's a philosophical statement,
right?
And it's,
it's,
it's a misleading one.
Or You could argue that it was
misleading one because what does,
it's just a dream mean.
Well it means that it's certainly not
something to take.
Like you would take serious take
something that occurred during the day.
Seriously,
it's a mirror like a fantasy.
But with the definition of fantasy being
some fundamentally useless
act of what the play,
I suppose that you can ignore with no
consequences.
And not only that,
but you should ignore it.
And you know,
that's,
that's not necessarily true because
then you're making the case or you might
be making the case that you don't have
to pay attention to products of your
imagination.
That seems like a pretty dopey thing to
tell a child given a,
that anything creative that you ever
produced is going to come out of your
imagination and be the way that you set
goals and plans for your future is by
imagining them dreaming about them.
Right?
Everyone knows what it means to pursue a
dream.
And you know,
you might say,
well,
if you're depressed,
it means all your dreams have
disappeared.
It's like so maybe you shouldn't be
telling your child that it's just a
dream and so you can go,
you can ignore it and go back to sleep.
You know,
you don't know exactly what you're doing
when you,
when you do that,
you're certainly not paying attention to
the child's experience because it's,
she did have that image you had.
It did make her upset.
And those are facts.
And as far as people like Rogers would
be concerned,
those are facts about reality.
Are there elements of reality?
And they should be dealt with as such.
So I told her to close her eyes and to
bring the dream image at inner
imagination,
which she could do very well.
And then to imagine that she had some
rubber boots on and that she could go
into the stream and pick out the garbage
and put it in the garbage bag and that
there was a garbage can nearby and she
could put it in the garbage can.
And so we went through that and that
calmed her down and then she went back
to bed.
And then you might say,
well,
what?
What am I doing doing that?
Because you might say,
well,
that's just a fantasy.
Just like the dream.
And because they're just fantasies,
neither of them have anything to do with
reality.
But you know that again,
that's not very sophisticated way of
thinking because the dream presented my
daughter with a problem.
Or You could even say a class of
problems and the class of problems,
it includes all of those things that
people do too.
And I and other animals,
of course,
all the ways that the environment can be
defiled.
Well that actually is an existential
problem.
And then you might say,
well,
what should you do about it now?
So that might be,
well,
maybe you should do something about it
in so far as you can do something about
it,
because then you're conceptualizing
yourself as an active agent and not just
a passive victim or a passive recipient
of the problem.
You could actually do something about it
and that's a way different messages.
Then it's just a dream.
You can ignore it and go back to sleep.
You know what?
You've maybe you shouldn't actually tell
your child to be ignoring reality and go
back to sleep.
Maybe you should be telling them to wake
up and see reality as clearly as they
possibly can and not ignore any of it,
including their fantasies in their
dreams.
And that doesn't mean that they're
fantasies have the same reality as the
reality that you experience with
everyone else.
But the fact that it's not the same
reality that you experienced with
everyone else doesn't mean it's not
reality.
Now Rogers would claim for example,
that to ignore a private experience,
yeah,
warps you fundamentally.
So
here's the basic outlines of his view of
the world.
So there,
there's first of all,
you exist within a phenomenological
field now phenomenon,
phenomenon and comes from the Greek word
famous thigh and famous thigh means to
shine forth.
And so phenomena are those things that
shine forth for you.
Now the way to understand that is to
imagine that you're reading a book and
maybe a passage of it really strikes you
as meaningful.
Well then you might say,
well,
why?
There's lots of passages in the book.
If someone else was reading the book,
it's not obvious that the same passage
would strike them.
And then you might say,
well,
is that a consequence of the structure
of you as as a,
as a,
as an interpreter of the book?
Or is it a consequence of the contents
of the book?
And the answer to that is you actually
can't tell because
the book is neither the thing that's
printed nor the reader.
The book is the interaction between the
reader and and the book.
And that interaction is actually unique
for each person,
even though there might be some
commonalities across people because
otherwise he wouldn't even be able to
talk about a book.
Well,
regardless when you're interacting with
something,
some things announced themselves on your
field of consciousness and other things
don't.
And so the phenomenologists would say,
well,
some things shine forth for you.
Well,
other things don't.
It's a little bit like
one of Ewing's ideas about the
development of the self.
Don't believe that
if you follow the things that announced
themselves to you as meaningful,
that they would take you through a
descent to begin with where you would
encounter things you were afraid of or
terrified of and disgusted by and wanted
to avoid.
And then the consequences of that would
be that you did incorporate a lot of new
material into your personality.
And the consequence of that would be
you'd be reborn roughly speaking as a
stronger person.
And then if you just kept doing that all
the time for the rest of your life in
small and large ways that you'd become
more and more and more fully
differentiated and developed.
And he would have said that the,
the ultimate potential target of that
kind of development was what he
described as the self.
The south is a multifaceted
conceptualization,
so that's not all there is to it,
but the self from the union perspective
is who you could be if you could be who
you most deeply are.
If you didn't shy away from anything,
if you,
if you accurately encountered and then
integrated,
even in a phd,
Rdm sense your experience.
Now that's,
that's exactly the same idea that Rogers
had.
He believed that
there's a phenomenal field and it's full
of experience.
All of your experience manifests itself
as the phenomenal field is quite
interesting because if it means also
that other people are part of your
phenomenal field,
part of your experience,
and then that within that field there's
a circumscribed area that he described
as the self that's different than the
union itself.
So it's somewhat terminal,
logically confusing.
Rogers self is more like Freud's ego,
but rogers would define the self as
those aspects of the phenomenal logical
field that you,
that you call I,
I felt like
I've had clients who tended to talk in
the third person about their emotions or
they would say the body,
they wouldn't say I maybe they're
describing cutting themselves and they'd
say,
well
the body needed to be cut.
And
what Rogers would say about that was
that
person existed in the phenomenological
field and part of that phenomenal
logical field was demarcated by the
self,
but the self hadn't expanded to
incorporate as much of that
phenomenological field as it should
have.
The other concept he had was the con.
Another concept he had was the concept
of the organism.
Now you could think of the self as what
you identify with it and then you can
think of the organism as all those
things that are unique to you that you
might identify with the eye.
Now it's tricky because imagine that you
get angry during the fight with some
argument and they say you're angry and
you say,
no,
I'm not lost.
Like,
what exactly are you doing there?
The other person,
we're going to assume the other person
is right for the sake of this argument.
They can clearly see that you're angry,
but you're not
allowing
the organism organismic manifestation of
motivational state or emotion to be
incorporated with those things that you
identify with.
Rogers would call that in grows.
And he believed that in congruence was
roughly equivalent to psychopathology.
So that part of your goal was to,
was for the organism to respond
appropriately to the broader
phenomenological field.
Now we can talk about what appropriately
means,
but we won't do that yet.
And then what the south was supposed to
do was accurately symbolically represent
organismic responses to the broader
phenomenological field.
So now you can see that there are
similarities between that concept and
say Freud's idea of the ego and the ID.
No,
cause the Ed was this sort of external
thing and that was the home of
motivational land,
emotional forces that couldn't be easily
integrated into the ego and for partly
because the Superego said,
for example,
that they were wrong.
And so there is this,
these sets of phenomena you know,
that all of the different clinicians are
talking about,
but all of them are talking about it
starting from different initial
presuppositions and it's like
a group of people in the room shining a
flashlight on a very complex object.
You know,
they're all standing in a slightly
different position.
The complex object is the same thing,
but you can only see parts of it.
And so you need both couple different
ways of looking at things so that you
can come up with a cohesive and coherent
account of something that's actually
beyond your understanding.
Because of course not only kit,
can you not accurately symbolically
represent the phenomenal logical world,
the entire domain of your being.
You can't accurately represent even the
organismic,
the aspect of that field that's related
to the organismic you.
There's this part of you on top that you
identify with,
I roughly speaking,
and it's trying to model a mortal of
something very complex.
And of course that's extraordinarily
difficult.
Now why is it doing that?
That's the central mystery of
consciousness.
You know there's this problem that
consciousness researchers always
referred to.
It's an annoyingly termed,
I think it's called the Zombie problem.
And the Zombie problem is the why is
consciousness unnecessary?
Like why is it necessary for something
complex like a human being to actually
have awareness and self awareness?
Why couldn't it just wander through the
world reacting in predetermined
deterministic fashion?
Zombie like no awareness robot.
Like let's say what's consciousness for
Rogers doesn't really discuss that.
And so we won't at the moment,
although I think there are some
reasonable ideas.
Consciousness,
for example,
I was used to generalize between certain
phenomena anyways,
regardless,
there's the self,
the organism in the broader
phenomenological field.
Let's say you go into a
pub bar
and you're,
you've been there many times and so you
know the people in there,
you know where to sit,
you know what's going to happen.
You met friends there.
You might say that your organism
exists
at least in part as a very accurate
model of that broader,
phenomenal,
logical world.
And then inside that
you're aware of your knowledge,
the bar.
And so
if your organism is properly adapted to
the broader phenomenological field,
when you go into the bar or other
familiar place,
things that you expect and want happen
instead of things that you neither
expect nor one.
And you could say,
well perhaps that's a reasonable
definition of adaptation though.
This isn't biological or evolutionary
adaptation,
right?
This is personal lab application there.
They're similar in some ways,
but importantly different.
I mean you can be adapted to an
environment without that in any way
having any effect whatsoever on your
evolutionary adaptiveness.
So
okay,
now if you're,
maybe you're not very well organismic
Lee adapted to the environment,
you have a more love it.
And because of that,
when you go somewhere familiar,
people don't like you as much as you
think they do and you're not nearly as
much of a master of that situation as
you think you are.
And what are the consequences of that?
So that would mean that your self
representation is too rigid and
simplistic and full of defenses to
notice the discrepancy between your
organism and the broader environment
that's pathological.
And the way that's going to be marked is
first by anxiety.
You know,
maybe you tell a joke,
there's some people sitting around you
to tell the joke and you see people kind
of,
you know,
making that face and maybe rolling their
eyes.
It's like,
well that's not exactly,
you might think,
well they're joking,
you know,
they're just,
they're just teasing me.
Well maybe they're not.
Maybe they're damn sickie or stupid
stories and you've told them 50 times
and you're not very funny.
And they'd rather you work in the bar at
all.
And it may be that you'll actually
notice that,
but you don't necessarily notice it in a
symbolically fully symbolically
developed.
Now what that would mean is maybe you
start feeling anxiety and Roger's
identify as different levels of feeling.
It might start with this subception and
to sub seed something,
which is a word that I guess comes from
general semantics,
is to
have the event affect the way that
you're interacting with the world in
ways that you don't necessarily notice.
So it's sort of equivalent to the idea
of subliminal when you're talking about
advertising,
a message is flashed out unit Stokley
changes the way that you're interacting
with the world.
But you don't notice that that,
and that happens to people all the time.
I mean it's actually a part of our
normal cognitive structure.
And when you walk into this room,
the room tells you all sorts of things
about how to behave and you don't notice
that the room is telling you those
things because you know what it's
telling you so well that you just acted
out.
You don't need to go through all the
complex processes of actually perceiving
and thinking about it.
And so Roger's point is that you can
detect things organismic Lee that will
affect the nature of your experience
without necessarily either even
perceiving that or definitely not
symbolically representing it.
Now maybe the social discomfort that's
inherit in the situation rises up to the
level of perception that's not
symbolization yet.
And then you might think,
well what does it feel like to be
anxious?
Well that,
and I'm not asking what are the
objective markers of being anxious cause
we actually don't know those.
We know we can kind of infer them.
Sometimes people's heart rate goes up
but sometimes it decelerates and then
there are facial expressions that are
associated with anxiety.
But you have to use those to infer.
If you get anxious,
I don't feel your anxiety,
I have to infer it.
But if you get anxious,
you feel your anxiety and so then the
question might be,
well what does it mean to feel anxious?
Well
that's a hard question and the reason
it's a hard question is because you
never have to answer it because if you
tell someone I felt anxious,
then they refer to their own feelings of
anxiety and then they know what you
mean.
And you never have to come up with an
explanation of what it feels like.
The feeling this,
the,
the idea that the feeling is an element
of experience is something that we just
take for granted.
You know,
I got angry today.
Everybody nods or maybe I tell a little
story.
I didn't say,
well,
you know,
I go out on the bus and I was missing
like 2 cents.
And I asked the bus driver if he would
let me get on the bus and he didn't.
And not really annoyed me because I take
that bus every day and the driver knows
me and I got angry and everybody nod.
And the reason they know od is what
partly because they can imagine that
that's how they would have reacted in
that situation.
But even more importantly,
they accept the reality of angry as a
response and they know what it feels
like.
So,
but explaining it,
that's a much more difficult thing.
So the point is is that you can have
experiences that you know of.
First of all,
you can have experiences that you don't
know that would be the sub sieved
experiences.
Then you can have experiences that you
perceive,
but that you haven't symbolically
represented.
And those might be emotional or
motivational experiences.
And then you can have experiences that
you have symbolically represented in a
way that that captures their just
accurately in a way that's reflective of
your adaptation or lack thereof.
To the broader phenomenological world
and Rogers would say that ladder state
is preferable.
You know how to act or you know that you
didn't act properly and you know how to
fix it,
which is almost as good and you
represent that accurately.
Now you might imagine that you could
concentrate on the mismatch between
organismic responses and the
environment.
That's what behavior therapist really
do.
They say,
well,
how are you acting and what are the
consequences?
But that isn't really where Roger's
goes.
Rogers is more psychoanalytic then the
behavior therapists and what he seems to
be primarily concerned of is about is
whether or not your self representation
is an accurate representation of of how
your organism is responding.
In some sense for Rogers,
the organism takes the place of God.
It's more or less omniscient.
So your organism is going to tell you
the truth in every situation and it's up
to you whether or not you're going to
pay attention to that and make sense of
it or whether you're going to engage in
any of the different kinds of
shenanigans that you might engage in to
stop yourself from going through the
complex process of symbolization.
Because you might say,
well,
you're back in the bar and you might
say,
well,
you notice the anxiety and then you
know,
different ways of symbolizing it come to
mind.
These people are all people are all just
jerks.
And then another thing comes to mind is,
well maybe nobody likes me.
And then maybe another idea that's
associated with symbolization comes to
mind,
which is,
well,
maybe there's elements of my social
behavior that I should adjust.
And I presume that if Roger's was having
a conversation with one of his clients,
he would assume that that was the most,
that was the most fruitful potential
step towards accurate symbolization.
Now Roger's felt that anxiety emerged
when the south concept was not
accurately symbolically representing the
organisms experiences.
And so that would be in some sense if
you're a house divided within yourself,
then your pathological from a Rogerian
perspective,
and you can think about that in some
sense as a move away from necessary
simplicity
mean
if your self concept is set up property,
it doesn't contain contradictory and
misleading bits of information.
Everything works seamlessly together.
And so what that would mean is that you
think about something,
you act it out and it works.
And then that's an indication that the
organization between say these different
three different levels of being is,
while the right word is ice to morphine,
each represents the other with
sufficient accuracy.
And so that means that you're congruent
and if you're congruent,
then the world is treating you not only
in the manner that you want to be
treated,
but also in the manner that's most
likely
two
further your actions in the world as an
organism.
And so that's partly why Rogers believed
that the organism had wisdom because
it's natural proclivity was to operate
in the world effectively and to expand
its competence.
At the same time
I was self actualized person because
that's one of Roger's phrases is someone
who self concept accurately represents
their organismic
Ba.
Now Rogers was primarily a clinician as
well
and his theories were derived from his
clinical experience
and his theories informed his clinical
practice and Roger's invented or
developed when he believed to be a new
kind of therapy and he called that
client centered therapy.
Now you've probably heard about student
centered education in Rogers.
I ideas have had a tremendous amount of
influence,
certainly not at least in educational
psychology also in conflict reduction of
various sorts.
Yeah.
You start with Rogers initial
assumptions,
which is first of all that you should
regard your experience as real second
that your organism will give you
accurate information about the totality
of experience
and third,
that your self concept should accurately
encompass your actual experience.
There are implications of that theory
for therapy.
And one of the implications is that you
can figure out what you should do if you
want to because your organism
will tell you or at least hint at you
about which directions are correct and
which directions are.
And if you follow those,
then you're going to naturally gravitate
towards a state of being where you're
more and more accurately represented by
yourself,
but also that
your representation and your organism
are going to act more effectively in the
world.
They're not bumping up against each
other all the time and you know,
there no one even conflict anymore.
And so that's the goal of the self
actualized person if therapy
in part is the art of furthering that
process of self actualization.
Now Rogers,
yeah,
Rogers was opposed to
diagnosis because he felt that it didn't
sufficiently
represent the
vital minutia of the client's individual
experience.
And I think that's,
I think that his plane was extremely
important.
No,
because
medicine psychiatry tends to declassify
everything
and you might say,
well,
are the psychiatric diagnostic
classifications real?
And then answer that is it depends on
what you mean by real anyway.
Think,
well that's an annoying answer,
but it is.
It is still the answer.
And so I could say if I was being
cynical,
although I don't really think it's a
cynical response,
if I was willing to sound cynical,
that the only reason that psychiatrists
diagnose their clients is so that
insurance companies can pay the bills.
And I actually believe that that's more
true than the claim that the psychiatric
diagnostic categories accurately
actually capture the essence of the
person's problems.
In my clinical experience,
classification
has had almost a zero utility.
And the reason for that is because it's
too low resolution.
It doesn't capture the individual
property.
Because the thing about a client
clinical client is that it's precisely
their individuality.
That's the fundamental issue.
It's like they have to make their way
through the world in their body and
their in their time and their position
in culture with their advantages and
disadvantages.
And that requires
our unique,
a solution that's unique in many ways.
And one that's also personal.
And Rogers also wasn't a particularly
great fan of the psychoanalysts tendency
to look for the causes of present
behavior in past events.
So he didn't,
he didn't regard fishing in the past as
a useful,
necessarily useful expedition or as a
necessary expedition.
Although if issues of the past came up
in therapy,
he was perfectly willing to,
to,
to deal with them.
He didn't accept except the Freudian in
theory that the fundamental cause of
psychopathology was saying traumatic
past experience.
Right
now this gives Rogerian therapy a
particular flavor.
You could also call it non directive
therapy.
Now if you're a behavior therapist,
you might actively strategize with your
client about what they're going to do in
the next week and then once they've
established their goals,
you might offer some hints about what
strategies they could use to monitor
themselves and to attain those goals and
maybe you'll even have them keep track
of it.
Roger's generally speaking,
wouldn't do something that directed and
in fact he strove not to unduly
influence the client's decisions about
important future of.
And in that way he was quite similar to
Freud because Freud would sit behind,
would sit.
So the client would be laying on a couch
and Freud would set so that the client
is patient actually couldn't see him and
then he would listen to the person free
associate,
which in some sense means that they
would ramble on.
And he was attempting by doing that to
facilitate the self realization of
their,
of their own memories.
If things happen to you in your past and
they still cars you emotion,
let's say they're more than 18 months
old for the sake of argument,
Freud would assume that if you kind of
wandered around that memory somewhat
haphazardly and in an in an association
will weigh the way conversations
naturally unfold,
that you would bring things to light and
that would allow certain kinds of
emotional expression and that,
and in fact in itself would be curative.
But for,
I didn't want to with your fear with
that process or guide it to any great
degree.
And so rogers was like that.
He,
he wanted you to make your own
decisions.
So he believed that the therapeutic
endeavor required
could not,
could not occur unless certain
conditions were met
and the conditions were
willingness to tell the truth.
So
when we're not,
when a client comes to see me,
one of the first things I tell them is,
you can tell me anything you want.
Although you're perfectly within your
rights to maintain your privacy.
You can tell me anything that you want,
but tell me the truth as much as clearly
as you can.
Because if you don't,
there isn't,
I don't know what's going on with you.
And there's not a possibility,
not any possibility at all that I can,
that this process will be useful if
we're talking about things that don't
exist.
So one precondition is the person is
willing to come and see you because that
means they want to transform.
The second precondition is that they're
going to communicate with you.
And communication means they're going to
do their best to tell the truth.
But the therapist takes the same
vow in a sense.
And so one of the things that I tell my
clients is that I will never let them do
anything that makes me resent them.
So if I'm asked to step out of my way
for some reason to take an additional
session or maybe to meet them somewhere
and I do it,
they can be assured that there won't be
a price that will be extracted from them
later for interfering with the smooth
flow of my day.
So,
and the other thing that I do,
and I've learned this from Rogers and
from the other people I've read,
is that I listen to people talk and then
sometimes something will occur to me and
I don't think about it as I thought
something because I'm actually somewhat
a follower of Nick Nietzsche's dictum,
which is that the fact that you think is
no proof that the fact that you
experienced thoughts is no proof that
you thought.
They just appear.
Well,
you don't think that you think up your
dreams,
right?
You have your dreams.
There you are in band.
They're the dreams.
Are you having them?
Well,
it doesn't seem like it.
It seems like you're experiencing this
in some sense the same way experienced
the external world.
You know what voluntary creating them.
Well why do you think anything different
about your thoughts?
And that's a very useful thing to
realize by the way.
Because otherwise you think your your
thoughts and then if you have negative
thoughts while then you assume that
they're true and they're not true just
because you think them,
they're just thoughts and maybe they're
true and maybe they're useful and maybe
they're not.
So stepping back from them a little bit
is incredibly,
it's like Buddhist detachment in a
sense.
It's an incredibly useful thing to do.
I mean that's another thing that's
really characteristic of modern people
because especially if they're smart,
they think,
they think first of all,
and second they think that the things
they think are true and neither of those
things are necessarily true.
And abandoning your belief in the makes
you
much less rigid and much more able to
expand your preconceptions or even
radically change them when the
circumstances demand them.
So
the person has to be
wanting to change in principal in a
positive direction.
They have to be willing to tell the
truth.
Then the next element of Rogerian
psychotherapy is something that he
called
unconditional positive regard
and unconditional positive regard.
And the Rogerian tradition is something
like radical acceptance.
It's actually a hallmark of modern child
rearing techniques.
You should wholeheartedly accept all
aspects of the person's being.
Now,
Rogers believed that are positive,
that partly because he also believed in,
what was it called,
conditions of worth.
Here's a condition of worth.
I don't like you when you act like that.
So you imagine you might tell a child
that,
I don't like you when you act like that,
and maybe you tell them that about a
bunch of things that they do,
but maybe those are integral parts of
the child's Ba and by making your lack
of acceptance,
no,
you make it impossible for the child to
incorporate those aspects of his
organism organismal experience into his
self concept.
You can see echoes of the Super Ego
Eagle idea there.
And so rogers would say,
well,
if someone comes into psychotherapy and
experiences unconditional positive
regard,
that means that they'll be able to
reveal those elements up there.
Organismic experienced that have been
rejected and say by the social world and
themselves
experienced them and then potentially
incorporate them within the self concept
and that that's going to be a good thing
because rogers is a great believer in
the natural inevitability of positive
transformation.
If if you set that up as your goal,
he also believes that that should be
your goal and that it's actually your
natural goal.
If for example,
you haven't been subjected to arbitrary
conditions of worth.
Yeah.
Now I'm going to read you something that
Rodger's road,
which is quite interesting and I think I
found it extremely effective.
Oh yes.
That's another thing I should mention.
There is one other important assumption
in the idea of self actualization.
The other thing that Roger's tried to
ensure that his clients develop was
autonomy and independence.
Now for Rogers,
there was very little difference between
the move towards autonomy and in any and
personal independence and the process of
self actualization.
Now,
given that we're looking back at Roger's
work 50 years later,
you might ask yourself is if
autonomy and independence is a necessary
precondition for psychological health
because you could make the case that
productive interdependence
and more communal orientation is equally
healthy,
but that's not a Rogerian
presupposition.
So
his ideal is the fully functioning
individual.
So here's his hypothesis with regards to
psychotherapy,
assuming a minimal mutual willingness to
be in contact and to receive
communications,
we may say that the greater the
communicated congruence of experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual,
the more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same qualities,
mutually accurate understanding of the
communication's improved psychological
adjustment and functioning in both
parties and mutual satisfaction in the
relationship.
Okay,
so let's unpack that.
Assuming a minimal mutual willingness to
be in contact and to receive
communication.
Well,
the first thing you might say is that
it's pretty much though the hallmark of
a relationship,
right?
Because if you're not in contact,
while clearly you don't have a
relationship,
and if you are in contact but you're not
communicating,
you probably don't have a relationship.
Yeah.
All right.
So,
and you know,
that also begs the question of exactly
what a relationship is for,
and that's something that's very much
worth considering because people don't
really usually know what a relationship
is for.
They certainly know that as a general
rule,
they're going to pursue them,
but they don't really have any idea,
in some sense,
what the optimal state is or what the
desired finance state should be.
You know,
of course the desired final state 50
years ago was marriage,
but
I don't,
it's certainly the case now that most
people who are couples aren't married.
Now you might ask yourself,
well,
what's the utility of a relationship and
what's the utility of a longterm
relationship?
While the Rogerian answer to that would
be
the more based on trust,
the relationship is,
the more likely that you're going to be
in contact and to receive
communications.
And then as a consequence of that,
you're going to
become better and better at representing
your organismal experience within your
self concept.
And that's going to facilitate your
movement towards self awareness and self
actualization.
It's a two brains are better than one
idea.
So we say,
well,
we established a relationship.
Okay.
And the goal of our relationship is to
make things better.
And we,
we make a presupposition that the way
you make things better is by telling the
truth as you see it.
So remember,
this is a phenomenological theory.
And so the truth that Rogers is talking
about isn't objective truth.
And I suspect that that,
at least in part because establishing an
objective truth within the confines of a
relationship is I think it's technically
impossible.
And we talked about that before because
each interaction between the members of
a couple or people in any relationship
is contaminated in a sense by all of the
other interactions they've ever had.
Plus everything they bring to bear on
the situation.
And there's just no untangling that
objective.
You know?
What did you mean when you said that?
That.
Well,
God,
you know,
you can argue about that for,
to the point of divorce and for 10 years
afterwards,
you know,
without ever coming to a satisfactory
conclusion.
All right?
The grade greater,
the communicated congruence of
experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual,
the more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same quality.
Okay?
So here's the idea.
You go see a psychotherapist or a jury
psychotherapist,
and at least in principle,
this is someone who's mastered or is it
tempting to master these basic modes of
being?
So what they're going to do is they'll
tell you,
I'm going to tell you the truth as I see
it.
And so the way I see that happening in
psychotherapy is that when someone comes
to see me,
I listened to them.
And that means that I'm not distracted
by anything else.
I'm not thinking about anything else.
I'm not thinking about what I'm going to
say next.
I'm not thinking about the things I have
to do today.
I'm not thinking about the last time I
saw this person.
I'm not allowing my attention to wander
away from the person and then I'm
watching them
and listening to them at the same time
and those are the same things because to
really listen to someone,
you also have to watch them because then
you sub c perhaps or perceive all the
nonverbal elements of communication that
go along well,
partly with voice tone,
but a with I direction and partly with
very subtle transformations of facial
gesture.
So sometimes,
for example,
I see on my clients that they'll all of
a sudden turn into a child.
It's very interesting.
It's like there'll be recounting some
experience.
It's like fixation from a Freudian
perspective.
There'll be,
there'll be describing some experience
from the,
from the distant past and for a second
there expression will approximate who
they were when they were six years old.
It's really,
it's really something remarkable to see
and you can see these things if you
really pay attention and then as they
talk,
I'm watching what's happening inside me
as I listened to their words and all
sorts of things will happen.
Sometimes I'll get an image or sometimes
I'll get a memory of something we talked
about before or sometimes I'll notice
that what they're saying right now is
different than something they said five
minutes ago.
And so then I'll say,
wait a sec.
No,
I'm trying to understand what you're
telling me and I noticed that you just
said this and it seems to imply this,
but then you know a couple of minutes
ago when we were talking about that,
then you said this and I don't see how
those two things are the same and I'm
not doing that because I want them to
rectify the paradox.
I'm doing that because I want to
understand what they are saying.
And if someone says 80 u and then they
say be,
you don't know what they're saying.
And so the question is for
clarification,
there's no other direction than that.
And then maybe,
you know,
I'll have little image,
like the sort of a fragment of a dream
and I'll say,
wait a second with what you just said
when you said what you just said,
this is what I experienced.
And then maybe we'll talk for awhile
about what that might mean.
And,
and I'll,
I can say to them what,
so for example,
sometimes,
sometimes people will come to my office
and they do all sorts of strange things.
Like I had one client who had
psychosomatic epilepsy and one of the
first times I saw her,
she had a seizure in my office.
And,
uh,
I was watching her and it didn't really
matter to me that she was having a
seizure.
And I thought that's pretty weird
because normally when someone's having a
seizure,
it's like you get affected
by it,
right?
I mean there's,
there's,
there's sensations that emerge in your
mid section and there's thoughts of
emergency and,
and you know,
cause your body in some sense is
mimicking their body,
which is what your body does all the
time when you're talking to people.
And that produces a sense of urgency.
And I just sort of watched her have the
seizure and I thought,
oh,
it's not real.
It's not real seizures.
But she was very good at it and you
know,
as far as she was concerned,
she couldn't tell if the seizures were
real or not.
And sometimes if you have cycle genic
epilepsy,
you've had an epileptic seizure at one
point that was genuine.
Well it's very exceptionally complicated
and it's not easy to develop psychogenic
epilepsy,
but
she had developed it and part of the
reason was
that she thought that she was toying
with the idea at that existence as a
psychiatric patient would require less
effort and responsibility and so she got
tangled up at one point with one of the
mental hospitals and they diagnosed her
with paranoid schizophrenia,
which is not something I would recommend
it,
especially if you don't actually have it
because once you've got the diagnosis,
well are you really going to know that
you what's going to happen?
Hey,
you do something like that.
You have a psychogenic epileptic seizure
and a variety of other symptoms there.
The consequence of a very complex
complex in in union terms,
there is a secondary motivation and
Friday in terms you go through with the
whole routine,
then you end up in a psych hospital and
you see four experts and they tell you a
paranoid schizophrenia.
Do you really think you're going to not
believe that or at least 10% of you is
going to believe it.
You're going to wonder after that.
And if another 20 people tell you that
and you're put on medication,
which you could easily be,
then a year later while you might still
not have paranoid schizophrenia but you
are not going to be doing very well.
So
well that's a good example of what
happens when your self concept and
you're organismic valuing systems aren't
working carefully in tandem
anyway.
So someone might be telling me a story
that's,
you know,
like a story,
a story about something terrible that
happened to them and like I'll just be
sitting there like a brick wall.
It's like you're not effecting me.
And sometimes don't tell people that.
It's like,
I don't know why,
but you know,
that's a pretty terrible story.
But I'm having no emotional response to
it at all.
Do you have any reason you have any idea
why that might be?
Well then maybe we'll,
you know,
often people aren't very happy when you
tell them that and that's fine.
They can be unhappy with that.
That's perfectly okay.
But the thing is now they know that
there's at least one person that they've
communicated with who's actually telling
them the truth,
who is actually not affected by their
story.
Because look,
if someone sits down beside you and they
tell you a terrible story,
the probability that you're going to
tell them that that had no effect on you
is basically zero because really rude
not to be negatively affected by someone
who's telling you a very sad story.
But if you're negatively affected by it,
I just know a true,
you're not doing them any good at all.
All you're doing is providing them with
evidence to maintain what could easily
become a delusion if they worked on it
long enough.
By contrast.
Sometimes people will come into my
office and they'll tell me something
that just seems trivial and it make me
tear up.
So which means I can actually feel
emotions.
It'll make me tear up,
but it's just something they just
barely,
they barely alluded to.
You know,
I've got a client a while back told me
that we had had a session family session
where I had suggested to some of the
members of this person's family that
things might go better for them and
their child,
who was one of my clients,
if for the next two weeks,
what they practice doing was watching
each other's behavior during the day and
finding one thing that they could make a
positive comment about.
Now,
and this isn't a game,
like if you play it as a game,
then it isn't going to work.
If you're going to do this properly,
what you do is you watch and then you
notice when the person does something
that actually makes you feel positively
towards them and then you tell them you
did this.
It has to be specific.
It can't be at the end of the day.
While you were pretty good today.
It's like,
no,
that's not going to work and you have to
notice something they actually did.
It's usually something trivial,
like,
um,
I really appreciate the fact that you
took your dirty dinner plate off the
table and rinsed it off and put it in
the dishwasher.
It's like,
you think that's so damn trivial.
It's hardly worth commenting on.
It's like,
no,
no.
It's not at all.
That's exactly the sort of specific
thing that you comment on.
If it did in fact make you happy.
You know,
when you can think about that in
behavioral terms,
you could say,
well,
if you don't,
if you want someone to do something that
you like,
you should tell them when they do things
that you like,
so that they know what you like.
But of course that means that you're
putting yourself on the line too,
right?
Because if the person knows what you
like,
then they can withhold it from you.
And so you're not going to do that
unless you trust them.
You're really not.
So you know,
you might be in a relationship,
you might be in a marriage where never
once during the whole bloody marriage.
Do you ever tell the other person what
actually makes you happy?
It's like that's,
that's stupid by the way.
So like if you want to have a really
miserable time of it,
that's an excellent way to start.
You could also add to that the
presumption that if they really loved
you,
they know what you liked,
which is also what
your partners no smarter than you
generally speaking and you don't have a
clue what it's going to make them happy.
So I don't know why you'd expect them
to,
especially if they're male,
while you'd expect them to return the
favor.
So then you teach them,
you know,
like probably take four years.
It's like I like when you do this and
then of course they won't.
So you might have to mention it again in
a month.
You might think,
well,
it's going to take 18 months to train
this person at least,
I mean,
they're smart,
they're smarter than a dog,
but not much smarter.
So you have to be,
you have to use repetition and you have
to be judicious about it.
And if you do that,
and now that person is also doing that
to you and you both know that you're
doing that and you're both trying to
make things better than you're going to
communicate about it.
And then with any luck,
things will get better.
But that means you actually have to want
things to get better.
And that's part of the problem of
course,
because not everybody wants things to
get better.
And there's a part of everyone that
would be just as happy if they didn't
get better.
So anyways,
Roger's idea is that if you
communicate properly with the person
that you're in the relationship with,
that you can model proper being in some
sense,
and that at least you can attempt
tomorrow it.
And then as you attempt it,
you'll get better and better at it.
And as you get better at it,
the other person will get better at it.
But that works too.
So I had a client who was very anxious
person.
So when the person first came to see me
and they couldn't even talk on the
phone,
and now they're doing,
they're acting publicly,
they're acting in public.
And that's been the consequence of about
seven years of,
I would say Rogerian conversations were
almost all that I did was listen,
now the uncover,
I don't quite get the unconditional
positive regard thing,
although I know white rodgers said it
and his idea that arbitrary conditions
of worth can make someone pathological
or true,
but
I think a more nuanced sense of
unconditional positive regard is what
happens when you watch the person and
they tell you something and as they're
telling it to you,
you can see a little part of them sort
of come alive and that often happens
when their face loses a fair bit of its
rigidity and you can see more of what
they were like when they were a child,
sort of peeping through.
So their face sort of opens up.
You can think a hot that was really good
for that person.
Whatever they've been telling me that
they'd be doing that was right on the
right track.
And then you can say,
look,
I noticed that when you talked about
this,
you know,
your,
your face for the ox do,
you didn't look as anxious.
You were smiling,
you know,
and it was a genuine smile.
And for like a second or two there you
looked like you were doing well and you
were happy.
It's like,
let's do a bunch more of that because
you know,
if you see in someone that they're
capable of experiencing that,
then you could help them experience that
more.
And that's the purpose of a longterm
relationship
is that
you have your weaknesses and
inadequacies and you can't think the
think yourself out of them by yourself,
partly because they colored the way that
you think.
And so you need somebody else to bang
yourself up against to contend with so
that all the knots in your soul can get
ironed out and you're doing the same
thing for the other person.
And then both of you are on an upward
spiral.
And in some sense that's the core theory
of Rogerian psychotherapy.
It's like genuine,
honest communication can heal people and
genuinely disown his communication can
make them pathological.
And
in some sense,
I think Roger's got closer to the truth.
If you invert Rogers presupposition,
that's as close to the truth as any
psychotherapist is gone to see makes
people pathological.
And that's true.
A lot of,
and you'll notice this as well,
a lot of what you're doing in
psychotherapy and in any genuine
relationship is a moral endeavor.
You're trying to make things better,
and if the other person is deceiving
themselves or lying or failing to become
aware of things that they should become
aware of,
they're going to get bent and twisted
out of shape and then they're not going
to be congruent,
congruent with their body or with the
broader world,
and then they're going to suffer and
then that will cascade.
Then all sorts of things will start to
happen.
And you know,
that's the past to perdition and an
involuntary trip to the underworld.
When we meet again,
I think I'll show you a little clip of
Rogerian psychotherapy because a woman
in the 1950s agreed to be filmed,
which had a dramatic effect on her life,
by the way.
But,
um,
it,
it presented,
provides a nice
real world illustration of what Rogers
is doing when he's trying to listen.