So the last time we met,
we talked about a Greek myth,
I believe.
Is that correct?
We talked about horace and Isis and.
Okay,
good.
So I want to talk to you about this
symbol today,
which reminds me.
There's another slide that I need to use
to do that.
Hmm.
This took me a long time to sort out.
It looks to me like Ms Dot lg uses to
classic myth and the symbols that are
associated with classic myth use two
different symbols to represent the
unknown and one of them as far as I can
tell,
represents the absolute unknown.
And so that would be things that.
It's a complicated conceptual category.
All these are because otherwise they
would be articulated and explicit
categories instead of images stick and
artistic categories and so they're
trying to.
The symbols express a very large variety
of things that are difficult to
formulate into an explicit set.
Now,
one of the theories that young had about
symbols,
which I really like.
It's different than the Freudian idea.
Now.
Freud believed that your mind produced
symbols to represent content that you
repressed.
Basically.
Maybe it does that from time to time,
but you thought of the symbol in a
different way.
He thought of it as something that
floated up from the depths so to speak.
I actually think that's the right way of
thinking about it.
Like a dream.
Now,
we don't really know much about
consciousness.
It's proved very elusive to scientific
study and we don't really know much
about the process by which the
understanding of very complex concepts
comes about.
What we've started to take that apart to
some degree in the class,
you're often confronted with things that
you don't understand and can't control
and it's necessary to categorize those
because you have to figure out how to
deal with them and we've already
established the proposition that most
human categories that are,
that are fundamental art associated with
action rather than than representation.
Or you could think in some sense that
the action is the representation,
right?
Which which would mean you might say,
well,
what's a monster where we could even do
something simpler.
We can say what's a chair?
And I could say,
well,
a chair,
it could be a beanbag and a chair.
It could be a stump and that you might
ask,
well,
a chair in a beanbag and a stump have
virtually nothing in common apart from
the fact that they're both made out of
matter.
They're very dissimilar entities and yet
you can encapsulate them under the same
headache and the reason for that is
because you can sit on and so the
categories are actually predicated on
the use and we've talked about the idea
that we categorize things as as tools or
or that we categorize them in
relationship to their
there
implication for action.
Now
there were mammalian creatures around
between 60 and 220 million years ago.
This is very long time.
It's,
it's long enough for those mammals to
have been overlapping with dinosaurs
quite nicely.
And you know,
our early ancestors were quite small and
easily preyed upon and then are later.
Ancestors were tree dwelling primates
and then they were ground dwelling
primates and now we're city dwelling
primates,
you know,
and there was a tremendously long period
where we were preyed on things that came
in from the outside.
That's one way of looking about looking
at it and from this perspective,
a monster is something that's predatory
and that comes out from outside and that
something you don't expect and that
inhabits unexplored territory and
something that you don't understand.
It's all of those things at once
and then
do to the degree that the psyche is
transpersonal,
which means to the degree that your mind
is capable,
excuse me,
the concepts so that your mind uses to
organize the world are an expression of
a heritable structure.
Then
it's reasonable to propose that you have
an inbuilt representation of something
like the Predator,
but it's more complicated in human
beings.
Now you might say,
well,
is there any evidence for that?
Because it,
you know,
Young's ideas of archetypes of the
collective unconscious has never really
been accepted by general psychologists.
A lot of biological psychologists are
interested in it by the way,
because they're much more familiar with
the idea of built in instinct and action
pattern and instincts and action
patterns that are built in can be
unbelievably complicated and we do know,
for example,
that rats that are never exposed to a
cat in their life will still panic if
you waft cat older over their domicile.
So rats do not like the smell of cats
and they don't have to learn that for a
long time.
Psychologists believe that you learn
theory through conditioning and then
there was an idea that there were
prepared,
that there are certain fears were
prepared so you could learn them more
easily.
So for example,
if I wanted to condition a fear response
to you and I showed you a picture of a
snake and associated with a small
electric shock compared to fy associated
with a picture,
say of a,
a daisy or even a pistol,
which is also a dangerous thing.
Obviously you're going to learn to be
conditioned to the snake much faster.
So that's sorta the weak version of
prepared categorization,
but they're stronger versions of
prepared categorization to and I
actually think they're correct and I
can't see why they wouldn't be the
stronger version is that no,
you don't have your,
your,
your apprehension,
you're alert,
apprehension,
the alert,
apprehension that you would devote
towards something like a predatory
reptile is not something that you need
to learn at all.
You already know how to do it.
And
I wouldn't say that that's been proven
beyond a shadow of a doubt,
but,
but we do know that chimpanzees react
with fear to a variety of stimuli that
they didn't necessarily come into
contact with during their developmental
periods.
So for example,
chimpanzees don't like bodies of
chimpanzees that don't move.
So if you bring on,
and that's the tie is champion to a
group of chimps in a zoo.
Say the chimps are not happy about that
at all.
They also don't like snakes.
They don't like even plastic snakes and
they don't like snakes.
Even if they've never seen a snake.
And if they see a snake when and they
never have,
they'll get the hell away from the
snake,
but then they'll turn around and look at
it and look at it and look at it and
look at it.
And in the wild they do something
similar.
So if a,
if a chimp comes across a snake,
a big snake say it has a particular
noise,
it makes,
which is called a snake Ra.
And I guess that's a representation of
the noise that the chimp makes.
But what happens when the chimp makes
that noise is all the other chimps will
come running and they'll look at the
snake.
They're sort of enraptured by the snake,
I think is the right way to think about
it.
I think they're in all of the snake to
tell you the truth.
Um,
you might take,
well,
chimpanzees can't feel all.
It's like,
well,
don't be so sure you're a modified
chimpanzee and you can feel all and.
But there's more to this story than
that.
You ever listened to a piece of music
that makes the hair on the back of your
neck stand up or a shiver run through
you?
Is that a familiar experience to people?
Has Anybody not had that experience?
Okay.
You're the only person in the whole
room,
Huh?
Okay.
Well,
maybe,
maybe whatever.
Whatever.
The shiver.
The Shiver is a consequence of pillow
erection,
and what that means is that when you
have that feeling,
you're doing the same thing that a cat
does when it puffs out,
and the reason that the cat does that is
to look big and the reason it wants to
look big is because it sees something
that is inspiring and that's partly.
It's an admixture mixture of terror
around and
fascination.
Yes.
That's.
That's the right way of thinking about
buddy.
What's interesting about the pilot where
reaction response in human beings is
it's often manifested to something of
great beauty or great excitement,
you know,
so anyways that,
that,
that reaction is so old.
My point is that reaction is so old that
we still have hangovers,
biological hangovers from it,
so to speak.
From the time when it was actually
useful for us to puff up our for and
that was a long time ago and so I don't
think it's unreasonable to presuppose
the chimpanzees can feel something like,
aw,
now I would also like to point out that
our can be felt to a variety of
different things.
So I think that what a low ranking chimp
feels to a very high ranking chimp is
also something akin to all the reason I
think that is,
well first because of how low ranking
chimps act around high ranking chimps,
the act subordinate,
but also because there has been studies,
there have been studies with monkeys and
I think these were done with Vervets,
although I'm not precisely sure of the
breed.
They showed vervets troop.
They took vervets from a troop and they
showed verve.
It's pictures of the low ranking.
I told you this,
the low ranking vervets,
and they showed pictures that verve.
It's pictures of the high ranking
vervets and the verbiage preferred to
gaze at the high ranking vervets.
And so the vervets were the high ranking
vervets were the target of their
retention now.
Yes.
Perfect,
they knew them,
but there might also be something about
them physically.
I don't know the answer to that.
I mean,
we know that human beings can
hypothetically can look at,
are an array of middle aged men and pick
out the ceos without knowing them.
They can do it at better than chance
now.
They're not exactly sure what cues are
being used or maybe they are and I just
don't know the literature well enough
that,
that might be,
that might be part of it.
Um,
so we do pick up cues,
dominance that are,
I think their innate wide jaws.
One of them,
you know,
and there's weird variations on this
too,
so I can tell you,
for example,
if you show women pictures of the same
man and you vary the jaw width.
When the women are ovulating,
they liked the guy with the thick jaw,
heavy jaw.
And when they're not,
when they're completely opposite to
ovulating,
they liked the guy with the thinner jaw.
And so,
I mean,
I think this is part of the reason that
women have trouble with men now
actually,
because I think that from a sexual
perspective,
they might be more wired to be
attractive to men who produce monstrous
sons,
but you know,
like powerful,
attractive sons because from an
evolutionary perspective,
you're much more likely to get a
grandchild or to speak,
to speak in a more Darwinian sense.
You're more likely to pass on your genes
if you have a son who's successful at
attracting mates.
And there's no reason to assume that the
man who will produce sons that's more
more capable of attracting mates is
going to be the sort of man a that will
treat you right or b won't fool around
because basically you're gambling in
some sense that your son will have the
opportunity to fool around because
that's your best bet.
In terms of moving your genetic material
forward,
why is it that white job,
it
dominance testosterone?
Has it been shown that people with live
jobs are actually more.
Yes,
its teeth we bite.
So a heavy more muscular jaw,
like people don't anymore,
but chimpanzees certainly bite.
Yeah,
they are.
They are.
Wider face is one of the markers
actually.
Yeah.
So these are,
you know,
I wouldn't say they're overwhelmingly
powerful effects,
but they're detectable.
No.
So know it also goes along,
I think with some things like preference
for symmetry because you know there's a
higher probability that an asymmetrical
person has had something go wrong with
them at some point in their biological
development.
So people find it symmetrical people
more attractive and that that's true
even for for creatures like butterflies.
So there are butterflies that will not
meet with another butterfly even if
they're asymmetrical by almost an
unmeasurable amount is they're very,
very attuned to it.
I think what this symbol stands for as
far as I can tell is that,
which exists beyond our comprehension
and that's,
that's different than something unknown.
It's different in some ways.
Anyways.
You remember the,
remember the hierarchy diagram I showed
you,
I showed you that over and over,
right with the little,
you know,
the high resolution actions at the
bottom and then the really low
resolution actions at the top.
So maybe you can think about it this
way.
So the unknown seems to be able to be
represented by this serpent reptile
predatory symbol.
It also seems to be able to be
represented by the negative feminine and
it also seems to be represented by the
positive feminine.
And so Mandy,
if you think about that hierarchy,
what happens is that the trivial
novelties you know that you encountered
whenever you do something wrong,
that's only a small mistake.
Those trivial novelties,
maybe their best symbolized by the
positive mother because they're not
going to blow you into pieces just
because you know,
because you've encountered a small error
and you'll learn something from it and
it won't be very costly.
You might even be interested in it.
And then I think as you go higher up the
hierarchy,
it's likely that the positive mother
representation is gonna Shade into the
negative mother representation.
Because what's happening is if you get
hint at a high level of abstraction,
is that it's going to start to demolish
larger and larger proportions of your
personality structure.
And then maybe at the very top.
The thing that would demolish that is,
is this.
It's this for the same reason that this
is the thing that would eat you if you
went to a far away from your tribe or
this is the thing that would eat you if
you move too far away from the fire or
if you fell out of the tree,
you know,
or the thing that would slither along
the branches and swallow.
You maybe swallow your offspring
millions of years ago.
Now you might think,
well,
is there any reason to presuppose that
those experiences left traces on us?
Well,
I think,
I actually think that the propositions
that psychologist started with,
and this happens very frequently,
are backwards.
I think the onus is on people to prove
that our minds aren't structured by our
biological and evolutionary past.
Rather than that they are.
I mean,
the whole bloody physiology is
structured.
The entire,
you know,
the body in which the mind,
the body,
the mind and habits is structured by
evolutionary processes.
Um,
you know,
we know that there are certain sets of
pretty formulaic cues that men and women
use to evaluate each other.
And those don't seem to be learned in
any important way,
although learning can modify them,
we know that,
you know,
we,
we don't,
we're not born able to speak a language,
but we are born able to babble the full
names of all languages,
so I don't know if you know that,
but when a baby's laying in their crib
and they're babbling,
they're capable of babbling virtually
every noise human beings used in all of
their languages.
And then what happens is that they lose
the ability to babble all the names that
aren't used in that language.
And then it's very difficult often for
an adult either learn to hear or to say
those full needs.
So.
So babies are obviously born prepared to
learn the language and it's not like we
actually teach them to speak.
Right.
You know,
we might make minor corrections now and
then and tell them how to say a word,
but most of the time they just pick it
up by observing.
And they do it very rapidly and they're
incredibly good at it.
So clearly that's biologically prepared
because no other animal does it and you
can't get other animals to do it really,
except maybe parrots,
African gray parrots turn out to be
extraordinary language users.
Um,
but other animals,
you don't get very far with them.
You might get to the word level or maybe
to the simple sentence level,
you know,
when people have claimed that chimps
have got up to the three year old level,
but about obviously you're pushing a
rock up a steep hill.
It's not,
it's not a straightforward thing for an
animal to pick up language like a human
being just,
you know,
you just drop them in there and Poof,
away they go.
So obviously there's something about us
that's prepared for that.
And of course we can talk and I don't
know if you know this,
but our whole breathing apparatus is
oddly designed to allow us to talk and
we can control our breathing very well.
Um,
compared to most animals,
we can hold our breath and we can
exhale.
And it actually,
that modification actually makes this
slightly more prone to choking when we
eat.
Because most animals can't do that,
but because of the peculiar way our
throat and our,
um,
are,
I don't remember the name of it
unfortunately.
Yeah.
And brachial brachial tubes,
the way their throat,
I guess.
No,
that's wrong.
Yes,
yes.
The way those are arranged that they
kind of conflict with each other now and
then.
And that can't happen in animals.
So not only are we prepared mentally to
speak,
but we're too to learn language,
but we're prepared physiologically to
speak.
And that means we have tremendous
control over our tongue and we have
tremendous control over our lips and our
breathing and all of those things.
So it's kind of hard to believe,
you know,
that we'd have this whole physiology
that's evolved to be devoted to language
without having a biological substrate
for language somehow as part of our
biological mental makeup.
And you know,
with regards to the relationships
between the sexes,
I mean sex is very old.
Sexual differentiation is exceptionally
old.
The probability that we're not evolved
to that is zero.
So.
So I'm going to show you another
picture.
I want to tell you a little bit about
this one first,
I guess,
so this symbol means a lot of things go
well.
First of all,
it's a dragon.
It's a serpent,
so it's a snake,
but it's.
It's it.
It's also a lizard.
It's a predatory thing and it's.
It can breathe fire.
That's one of the characteristics of a
dragon and fire is a transformative
substance and it's a very mysterious
substance.
And one of the things you might note
about fires,
what happens when you're sitting around
a campfire?
What do you look at the fire?
Right?
You can't not look at a fire.
It's like a baby.
If there's a baby in the room,
a two year old,
you're gonna.
Look at that two year old.
You can't keep your eyes off.
It's like a flickering TV and fires like
that for people.
We can't keep her demise off it and I
think the reason for that was that we're
all descended from the first creature
who decided that he was going to play
around with fire far more.
You know,
he probably came home with his furl
burnt off when he was an adolescent,
you know,
and his mother said,
are you out there playing with fire
again?
It's like,
yeah,
I can't help it,
you know,
is a mutation that made it impossible
for that creature to become accustomed
to fire,
was fascinated by it.
And you know,
once we had fire there was no stopping
us.
So the probability that we're all
descended from arsonist apes is
extremely high.
What's that?
Yes.
No,
no doubt.
No doubt.
Insane fire wielding chimpanzees.
That's our ancestors.
So,
so,
and fire is a transformative substance,
right?
It's,
it's,
it's strange.
It's this strange mode of material.
If you put something into it,
it turns into something else,
which is very,
very cool.
And you know,
which is also an extraordinarily useful
as it turns out.
So the fire fire is a fire,
is not only a transformative phenomenon,
but it can be used to represent other
transformative phenomena.
So the dragon is something that's
innately attractive for a whole variety
of reasons.
It can breathe fire.
It's very predatory.
It's also,
it's also an infinite creature.
And that's why it has its tail in it's
mouth,
it's self contained,
it needs nothing else.
It's,
and this is where the symbols starts to
stretch beyond the representation of the
Predator to the representation of the
unknown.
As such,
you know,
so one of the things you might wonder if
you're a human being is,
well,
what is the unknown like?
And you might think,
well why do you have to understand that?
And the answer is because it's horrible.
Things come leaping out of the unknown
all the time.
And so then you might ask,
well,
is it better to figure out how to deal
with each of those horrible things?
Or is it better to learn how to deal
with the source of all those terrible
things,
which would be the unknown itself.
Now you remember ty and Matt in the
Mesopotamian myth when she went to war
against Marduk,
she was sort of in the background and
created all sorts of monsters.
And then they all went to battle against
Murdoch.
So I'm going to tell you a dream that my
nephew had and I think this is a good
way of representing what this symbol
means and remember human beings abstract
and so what we're trying to do is to
look at singular phenomena and abstract
out what's common across them so that we
can learn to deal with the common things
so that we can apply it to the entire
set of those things instead of having
to.
And you know,
we,
we know in some sense possibly that
human beings can do this and animals
can't.
And so I went and heard Temple grandin
speak at one point and I don't know if
you know who temple grandin is,
but she's probably the most accomplished
autistic professor and she has.
She has built,
when she was a small child,
she learned that if she built this
enclosure that Kinda tightened in on
her,
that it would calm her down.
And she,
she applied the thing she learned that
would calm her down to calming down
cattle when they're being,
when they're being held in pens prior to
being slaughtered.
And so she's redesigned all the cattle
handling facilities or many of the
candle cattle handling,
handling facilities in the United States
to keep the animals calm and one of the
things she's designed is this kind of
spiral enclosure so the cows can't see
what's in front of them basically.
And it's fenced in because if,
if cows are going down a,
a,
an enclosed area like an alley and
there's a coke can lying in the middle
of it,
they'll all stop and look at the coke
can or they'd stop and look at a
briefcase there,
kind of freaked out by these things.
And if they're walking down a enclosure
and it's open and there's a windmill or
something spinning off to the side,
they'll stop and look at that too.
Now Temple Grandin and thinks that she
thinks like an animal,
which is why she thinks that she can
figure out how animals think.
And one of the things she said,
I remember her,
her,
her presentation,
she said,
okay.
So if I say to you,
church,
what do you see in your mind?
Just anybody.
Tell me what?
What's the.
What's the prototypical church?
How,
how,
what,
how would it appear?
Yeah.
Okay.
Does that seem reasonable to people?
What?
What led?
What popped into your mind when I said
that?
Church bells.
Okay.
Stained glass.
Now when temple grandin thinks of
church,
she doesn't think of church she thinks
of at Church.
She can't abstract out the commonalities
across churches and she thinks that's
partly why autistic people have a hard
time learning language because for an
autistic person there aren't.
There isn't the prototypical church.
There are just churches and she thinks
that's how animals see.
They see the particulars.
They don't see the abstracted universals
that unite the particulars.
And of course that makes sense if you
think about it and you know one way of
thinking about that too is that until
you can abstract out the,
the common era commonalities across a
class of phenomena,
and maybe you have to do that in an
image,
you can talk because you can't use the
word church unless what you do when you
receive the word church is apply it to a
class of phenomena.
You know,
that may have very little in common from
a visual perspective.
I mean just think about how different a
given church looks from different
angles.
Now,
I don't know if you knew about the
autistic.
They're artistic Savannah's who can draw
like mad and so you can see some of
these people on Youtube.
I mean one guy is just.
Absolutely.
He's so amazing.
It's just staggers the imagination
making fly them across the city and the
helicopter and then he can go home and
they own this huge piece of paper.
Draw the whole city.
He can.
It only has to see it for about an hour
and he can draw the windows and like
everything and their artistic people who
can figure out how many windows are on a
building with one glance.
They don't see things the same way we
do.
They don't see the abstractions and
animals don't seem to either.
And the reason I'm telling you that is
because you got to understand the
process of abstraction before you can
understand what symbols mean.
Now,
what young believer that assembled did
was exactly what I just described,
which was that there's a class of
phenomena that were struggling to
understand and the way that we build our
first representations of it is an image,
just like you had the image of a church
and then you,
you can,
you can label that image with a word and
then you can use the word Madel evoke
the image and that will evoke the class
of phenomena.
But part of the reason that that normal
so to speak,
human beings can't draw is because when
they draw,
they draw here or glyphic.
So think about,
you know,
you think a child's drawing of a person
is very primitive,
you know,
had stick,
stick,
stick.
Maybe they put little circles on the
feet or something and you think,
wow,
that's pretty primitive.
It's like,
that's wrong.
That's really,
really sophisticated.
It's ridiculously sophisticated that a,
that a child can figure out how to
scheme and ties a person with like five
sticks in a circle and then Maine,
they know that it's a person and that
you do too.
That's amazing.
That's not primitive now,
the autistic savant,
they,
they seem to draw.
They seem to be able to draw.
So Dan accurately because they don't see
the abstraction,
they just see the particularities.
So another really interesting phenomena
that goes along with autistic drawing is
sometimes you'll see,
remember this girl who could draw horses
like mad,
she lost the ability later when she
picked up language,
but she could start with any part of the
horse.
She could start by drawing the tail,
you know,
which is not how a normal person would
draw a horse at all.
You know,
first of all you'd sort of centered on
the paper and then you maybe you'd
sketch it in and like it's work.
You just don't start somewhere and like
draw out a whole horse.
And her horse drawings were like
Michelangelo Quality.
They're remarkable.
So,
so this symbol,
I think this is the symbol that people
were using or that are,
that we use to represent the ultimate
unknown.
And the ultimate unknown is a very
difficult thing to represent.
And so this symbol is making a case and
the case is,
well,
it's something like fire because it's a
transformative substance and it's
something like a predatory reptiles
because it lurks in places where you
don't expect it to look and it can
consume you and not an end.
It's also something like a spirit or a
bird of the air because it has wings and
and why that is.
Well,
maybe that's because things come
swooping down that you don't expect.
I mean there's lots of pr primates,
small primates that are attacked fairly
frequently by predatory birds.
And so the error is another place where
the unknown can emerge,
but the air is also sort of the place of
spirit and the ground is sort of the
place of matter.
And so this symbol here is a
representation of the conjoined union of
spirit and matter.
And I'll talk about that a bit later
because that's a very,
very complicated idea.
And okay,
now I'm going to tell you my nephew's
dream.
So he,
he was about five and he was having
nightmares and during the day and night
terrors.
So He'd wake up screaming and when
people ask them what the problem was,
he didn't know which is quite common
with night terrors with children,
but you know,
you can kind of infer that he was having
terrible visions at night.
Okay.
So anyways,
during the day he was running around
with a plastic night hat and a and a
sword and a playing night and you know,
and you might think,
well why would he play night?
It's like,
well it's,
I don't know exactly why it would play
night,
but you know,
he'd watched Disney cartoons and that
sort of thing and he'd been exposed to a
fair bit of media.
So his little brain was picking up
archetypes in some sense and he was
acting them out trying to figure out
what they meant and you know,
he's a pretty smart kid and
when you went to bed he'd put the sword
and the little night hat beside it and
then,
you know,
regardless he,
he was having night terrors now there
were,
there were some problems in his family
at that point and a divorce happened
relatively soon after.
So there were things lurking under the
surface around him and he was also
preparing to go to kindergarten,
which is definitely,
you know,
when you take a step out into the
broader world,
whatever that happens to be.
So he was surrounded by unknown things.
Um,
so
one night when I was there,
he had night terrors and he came to sit
at the table with his family and my
family and um,
I asked him if he dreamed about anything
and he said he got very intense and he
said yes,
I was out in this field and I was
surrounded by these little dwarfs that
were just only came up to my knees and
they didn't have any arms and they,
they,
they had a huge beak like this and they
were covered with hair and Greece and on
the top of their head there was a cross
shaved in them and they had big,
strong feet and legs.
And when I was walking around,
these things would jump at me and bite
me with their beaks.
With the breakfast table got very quiet
when he said that.
As you might imagine,
it's pretty horrifying vision really,
you know,
and uh,
and you know,
you can think,
well that's why he's waking up
screaming.
It's like,
you know,
little
peak dwarfs are like gnawing on him at
night.
It's like that's a reason to be freaked
out.
So I said,
what could you do about that?
And now you see that.
That's an interesting question because
you know,
you often think that when you ask
someone a question,
they provide you with the answer,
but it's not exactly right because when
you ask them a question you also provide
them with the seed of an answer and you
can't help that,
which is why it's very difficult not to
lead witnesses in a trial.
And it's also very difficult to
interview children because every time
you ask them a question,
you're inevitably hinting about what you
want the answer to be.
But I was doing that on purpose and what
I was telling him was it's
hypothetically possible that a creature
like you could do something about that.
And if such a creature could do
something about that,
what would it do?
So I was introducing really what I was
doing was introducing the idea of the
hero to them.
It's like you're beset on all sides by
monstrous enemies.
What's the appropriate response?
Well,
I do know if you have a client who has
nightmares,
you can get them to envision the
nightmare.
So you say sit down,
close your eyes,
bring the images back to mind.
And some people are really good at this.
I think my experience has been that
women are better at than men and women
are somewhat more open than men on the
openness dimension.
Maybe that's why they like fiction
better to.
But anyways,
because women like fiction and men like
nonfiction,
roughly speaking,
I mean there's lots of overlap,
but if you have a client who has a
nightmare and you have them bring it to
mind,
you can get them to change the ending.
But it has to be some in some cause I
realistic manner.
So I had a client once who she had two
fears at the same time.
She was afraid of mice.
She was particularly afraid of mice
running upper leg,
which they will do,
but she was also afraid of being
attacked and raped in the cabin that she
had that was north of this was Montreal,
north of Montreal.
So there was a Friday and connection
between the most fear and the fear.
We treated her mouse phobia with
exposure.
I took her to mcgill and where the rat
labs were and you know,
first of all she just kind of peered in
the rats and then she got closer and you
know,
we just did graduated exposure and find
me.
She picked up a rat and petted and all
the same day by the way.
And so that was quite.
She was quite happy about that.
Direct behavior,
behavioral treatment exposure.
Right.
And then with the,
with the whole cabin thing,
what we did was,
first of all suggest that you get a
decent lock and maybe an alarm because
she was up there alone and you know what
the hell part of her fear might've been
predicated on an observation that she
was at risk.
That was higher than it might be
appropriate to me.
I didn't know,
but you might as well err on the side of
conservatism and then maybe she could
bring a dog up there that might be
helpful too.
So that was the practical addressing of
the problem,
but she had these dreams where some guy
would break in the window and you know,
rape her and so we had her bring the,
bring the dream to mind and then we'd
armed her with various things.
So one thing was a bath and another
thing was some rope and another thing
was a can of ovens spray.
And so when the guy jumped in,
she sprayed him with the ovens spray and
hit him with the baton and tied him up
and she was like,
so she visualized this quite intently
and she was pretty damn happy about the
whole visualization,
you know?
Um,
and I think it was because it put her in
the role of,
of,
you know,
person able to defend herself rather
than in the role of helpless victim.
Anyways,
that was the end of your nightmare.
So that's not actually very uncommon.
I had another client who she was walking
down a beach in her dream and on the
beach above the dunes.
There was this man who had a big Boa
constrictor and he was showing it to the
crowd and she just walked on by and uh,
she was facing a variety of very
difficult things.
And I said,
well,
you know,
all those other people were curious
about looking at the snake.
Maybe you could look at the snake.
And she said,
well,
I think that the person who's handling
the snake is a,
is a charlatan and a phony.
And I didn't want to have anything to do
with it.
So I said,
well,
let's,
let's play with the dream of bath.
And so
she closed her eyes and we went into it
and I said,
now I want you to go up there and just
take,
take a look at the snake.
Get closer.
She says,
I'm afraid that the crowd will make me
touch the snake.
So that's interesting because what that
meant was she was afraid that if she
associated with people that she would be
forced by peer pressure to engage in
things that she was afraid of doing.
So she was,
she was afraid of the crowd and it's
attitude.
And I said,
okay,
well if people ask you to do that,
you just tell them that you know,
thanks very much,
but I'm not comfortable with that.
It's enough me to look at the snake and
you know,
probably they'll back off.
And so she did that and they backed off
and so then she was watching and this is
an act active imagination,
you would call this act of imagination.
She was watching the guy handled the
snake and she said you can,
because the fantasy was continuing like
a daydream.
And she said,
well,
he's not a charlatan and all he knows
how to handle these,
these snakes.
And he's out here on the beach to show
other people how to handle snakes
safely.
And he's actually a good guy.
And I thought,
well,
that's pretty damn interesting because a
snake handler,
like a snake handler is an architectural
Messiah,
fundamentally.
So.
So I told you those stories back to my
back,
to my little nephew now.
Alright?
So beat things jumping on him.
I said,
well,
what could you do about that?
And he,
he kind of perked up,
which is an interesting postural
adjustment take because he was sort of
like this before.
And then he perked up and his eyes got
kinda bright.
So he's excited about this idea.
And I think that was activation of the
approach systems,
right?
Rather than,
uh,
the,
the freezing and retreat systems,
we sits up,
his eyes get bright,
he's excited.
He says,
I would take my sort and I would get my
dad.
Oh,
sorry,
I'm missing one key element.
After he told us about the beat
monsters,
he said there's a dragon behind them and
the dragon is puffing out,
smoke and fire.
And every time it pops,
puffs out,
smoke and fire,
the smoke turns into the beaked dwarfs.
And so it's a big problem,
right?
Because you got all these big dwarfs
around and you're gonna be fighting them
off hypothetically,
but there's an infinite supply of beak
dwarfs because there's a dragon behind
it that is like puffing up all the beat
big door.
So what the hell are you going to do
about that?
And I knew that that was like a hydro
story.
It's an old story.
A Hydra is this multi-headed snake and
if you cut off one head,
seven more heads grow.
It's like that's a problem.
It's a problem.
Apparently you're supposed to drop a
very large rock on hydro because cutting
the heads off it isn't going to be
helpful.
And you know,
there's,
it doesn't take a tremendous amount of
imagination to notice that.
What that story means is that sometimes
when you solve a problem,
you bring on seven more problems.
Right?
And that's actually life because very
few things that we provide solutions to
don't generate a host of new problems.
You know,
like the car is a really good example of
that,
you know,
because we like to think that the car is
the thing to get from one place to
another end.
But it could turn out that what a car
actually is,
is a,
an entity that transformed cities and
also the atmosphere,
right?
So,
or maybe it's the assembly line that's
not just an assembly line.
Maybe this assembly line is the thing
that transformed cities by making cars
and also fills the atmosphere with
carbon dioxide.
And then we all die,
right?
That's a big problem.
So at least hypothetically,
it's a big problem.
So.
So it's not.
It's always the case in life that when
you move forward in one direction,
and even if you solve a problem that
doesn't mean you solved the problem of
problems and that the best solution to a
problem isn't the solution to a problem.
The best solution to a problem is the
solution to the problem of problems,
right?
It's a category how best to face the
world if the world is composed of
problems.
All right,
so here's this dragon.
Now,
that's when I said,
what could you do about that?
And he said,
I would,
I would take my sword and I'd go get my
dad,
and then I go jump on the dragon's head.
And then I poked both of the sides out
with the sword and then I'd go right
down its throat to where the firebox was
and I'd cut off a piece of the firebox
and I'd make a shield.
And I thought,
wait,
go.
Perfect.
Right?
Because what he did was so perfect.
First of all,
I went right to the source of the
problem,
right?
Right to the heart of the matter,
right down the dragons throat.
Perfect.
And then the best part about it was
though that was that he cut a piece of
the firebox off so that he could use
that as a shield.
It's so brilliant.
And the reason it's brilliant,
it's brilliant on multiple levels,
but the first reason it's brilliant and
the most important one is that it is
possible that if you confront a dragon,
that you will obtain a shield.
And that that's like the story of
humanity,
right?
If we face down our predators,
if we confront the unknown instead of
running away,
if we explore and voluntarily it turns
out that every time we encounter a
problem we can extract out a solution
and that solution might be a solution
for all sorts of things rather than just
a solution for that problem.
And so we've had to learn that the
problem is,
uh,
is,
is also the place that generates
solutions.
So there's nothing more informative than
a problem.
Now the problem is that a problem might
kill you.
That's a problem.
But so it's not like we have been able
to make the problem disappeared,
but we've come up with a pretty damn
good way of dealing with them.
It's like confront the damn problem and
figure it out.
And what do we do?
We,
what do we do?
Then from that,
what are we extracting?
Well,
he extracted out a shield and of course
that would protect them from the fire
because it was made out of the firebox
like good work kid.
When we confront a problem,
what we extract out his information and
we use the information,
we use the information we build with it,
we learn new things about it,
and so you can conceive of a problem as
a place of information.
Now it's,
it's more,
it's worse.
It's worse than that.
If that's not sufficient
conceptualization because it's a place
of information that has this nature.
You know you,
you can't get it.
You can't just turn it into an abstract
issue because the place of information
is also the place of horrible predatory
matter.
Spirit,
reptile.
It's,
it's all tangled together in one thing.
We use the systems that we've evolved to
identify rapidly identify predatory
reptiles,
but predators of all sorts,
but predatory reptiles for the point of
this argument,
once we became capable of abstraction,
we use the same damn system to represent
problems.
Abstract problems,
you know,
because we know how evolution works.
It's a conservative business.
Once you lay the platform for one kind
of perception or cognition and then you
transform that,
you,
you increase its power and generalized
ability.
You have to build it on the same
platform.
You know,
it's like that continuous generation of
new versions of windows,
you've already got the infrastructure in
place.
You can't just demolish everything
completely and build it from scratch.
You know,
we have the same body plan as reptiles
and mammals and birds and whales and not
fish,
but you know,
that's,
that's a pretty wide range of things
that basically have the same skeleton we
do.
So evolution is a very conservative
process.
Now my nephew intuited that if you
confronted the heart of the problem,
you could extract out something that
would protect you from the problem
itself.
And that's what human beings do,
right?
We're always on the frontier.
Some of us are on the frontier
and the front,
there's always a frontier.
You know,
we conceptualize the frontier as the
place where our knowledge.
And so there are journals called
frontiers of neurology and we also think
about that as the cutting edge.
Right?
That's well,
what's it cutting into?
Well,
it's cutting into a mat.
That's one way of thinking about it.
It's,
it's sort of a variant of Plato's idea
that you cut nature at the joints.
There's a knife like element to it as
well in that,
and that's partly because of course you
do use a knife to cut things up so that
you can figure out what they are.
You know,
it's,
it's the symbols are as grounded in
reality as they can possibly be.
They're not as young pointed out,
the symbols aren't trying to make things
hard.
They're trying to make things we don't
understand easy and the so the symbol
stands when you get out to the frontier
is all you've got when you look past the
frontiers into the abyss is the symbol
and the symbol is created by the parts
of your mind that are capable of sort of
groping blindly in the darkness and
formulating monstrous representations of
what might be there as first pass
approximations of what it is,
and then of course you.
You refine that and you refine that and
you refine that and at some point gets
so refined that you can articulate it
and you can lay it down in a
mathematical theory and you can control
it.
But to begin with,
it starts like that.
It starts like that.
Now there is a matter of spirit element
here and there's an informational
elements,
so I think the best way to approach that
is to think about it from a p,
a jetty and perspective.
Now Piaget was a constructivist,
so this is how he thought.
Children learn things.
They would run through a routine that
they've mastered.
They started out with just basic
reflexes,
so there were things they could do as
soon as they're born.
For example,
they can,
they can take in milk and that also
helps them establish an initial
relationship with the mother and their
eyes are roughly focused in so far as
they're focused at all about the same
distance that the mother's face would be
from their eyes if they're breastfeeding
and they're capable of some movements
and their tongue in their mouth or
pretty wired up and they get control
over their eyes relatively quickly.
So,
and then they start to experiment with
these reflexes.
You know,
they can kind of fling their arms around
because they're,
they myelinate from the center outward.
So they start out on differentiated
basically and then they differentiate
outward and become more and more
articulated,
and they learn to experiment with their
basic reflexes and modify them and you
know,
it's like,
think about when,
when you,
when you're first learning to dance,
you kind of clunk around,
you know,
you lose,
you use low resolution movements and
those are often by the way,
controlled more by your right
hemisphere.
Once they become high resolution and an
extremely skilled movements,
they start to be more controlled by your
left hemisphere.
So you started,
you sort of start out like Frankenstein,
you know,
and you end up like Nuria have,
if you're,
if you're fortunate.
So although you probably don't,
you probably stay more like Frankenstein
or at least I do.
So
now what Piaget pointed out was that now
you want to remember that piaget was
mostly interested in figuring out how
people figured out things.
That was his primary goal.
And underneath that,
by the way,
was the goal of uniting science with
religion,
which is something that hardly anybody
knows about piaget.
But he stated it bluntly and actually
wrote a novel about it anyways,
so he was curious about how people
figured out things and so his notion was
that a child would be lumping along with
it's sort of low resolution,
psychomotor Schema and it would do
something that it didn't expect.
Now,
I don't know how many of you are really
familiar with babies,
but they have a remarkable startle
response.
Say so if you have a relatively new baby
and you blow on it,
it just goes like this,
you know,
it's really,
it's really amazing.
And it as a full body startle,
you know,
it's quite cool.
So they're very capable of being
surprised by things.
And so,
you know,
maybe laying in their crib and they're
looking at a,
a mobile up there.
If you buy your child immobile,
by the way,
it should be black and white and you
shouldn't hang the damn things this way.
Right?
Because the child actually is gonna.
He's looking up so people by their
children,
mobiles all the time and from the
child's perspective,
they just looked like lines hanging in
the air.
It's like,
no,
they're supposed to be facing down,
so keep that in mind.
So anyways,
the baby's lying in the crib,
you know,
and it's looking at things and sort of
moving around in like,
like this because it hasn't got great
control of itself.
Sorry about that.
And maybe it wax the mobile,
you know,
so it's pretty,
it goes wax the mobile,
it goes like this.
It's like that was not what it expected.
And then from Piaget's perspective what
would happen is the job would try to do
that again because it was interesting.
So in some sense the first interaction
with the mobile was quasi random,
you know,
because it doesn't really know what it's
doing,
but then maybe it's foot kick the mobile
and something interesting happened.
So then the child tries to see if it can
organize itself to give that thing a
kick again and then maybe it'll practice
that.
You know,
what kids are like,
man,
they will obsessively practice
something.
So when my daughter was young,
probably 18 months old,
we gave her these Disney books and they
were,
were hard back.
There were only about this big and maybe
10 pages and there was like five of them
that fit in the little box.
Well,
it turned out not to be so easy to put
them in the box and so she probably
spent,
Oh God,
40 hours picking up a little hard cover
thing and putting it in the box and then
picking up another and getting them all
in and then shake them all out and then
she'd do it again and you might think,
well,
what was she doing?
Well,
she was sharpening up her putting things
into things ability,
which is a pretty good ability because
you're going to be doing a lot of that
throughout your entire life and so by
practicing that's.
That's how she built up that,
that particular subset of transferable
skills.
Okay,
so then you might think,
well exactly.
What was that box of books for her?
How would you conceptualize it?
No,
because if you look at it,
you say,
well that's a box of books.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's a box of books for you,
but for her it was something else.
It was a.
It was a phenomena that enabled her to
extract out information about how to
organize her motor activity and so,
you know,
so then I could say,
well to the degree you think it's a
book,
a box of books,
you're just blinded by your own
presuppositions.
It was far more than that for her.
And it's quite interesting.
You see this with kids all the time,
you know,
you buy them,
you buy them a,
a toy for one purpose,
you know,
you buy them a big toy and then they
play in the box.
So.
So you know,
when it was interesting when we had
little kids because they would go around
and they do weird things with things all
the time.
So we got milk and milk bottles at that
point in the milk bottles had these like
foil wrappers on them and my daughter
would always use those as sons in her
little house drawings and show she'd be.
She'd walk around and take things that
we'd already categorized as a certain
kind of thing and she'd do something
completely different with it.
That's,
that's in part lack of latent
inhibition.
The fact that she hadn't categorized
that thing meant that it was polyvalent.
There is many things that you could do
with it instead of the thing that you do
once you categorize it.
So Piaget basically conceptualized the
unexpected event as a source of new to
things as a source of new matter,
roughly speaking and as a source of new
spirit.
Roughly speaking,
why?
Well,
first of all,
the novel thing would attract your
attention and then second,
as you're interacting with it,
you're doing two things just like
Marduk,
so this little baby in the crib.
It's like by whacking the things with
his hands,
it starts to conceptualize their
function as a defined and categorized
entity,
right?
Because you get a sense of,
I mean,
imagine,
imagine this,
like let's say your eyes are closed and
you have a basketball and there's a
pillar in a room and you're trying to
figure out what's in the room and all
you can use as the basketball,
but you can move around.
You could bounce the basketball off that
pillar a lot and sooner or later you
develop a visual image of it,
right?
It's a low resolution investigative
tool,
a basketball,
but you could still use it if you're
bouncing off it,
so to speak.
You can build up a representation of it.
And so from the Piagetian perspective,
that's how a child builds up the
representation of the world.
That's how it creates the world.
It creates the material world for itself
that way,
by banging up against it.
And,
and at the same time,
it's learning how to bang up against it
in ever better ways.
So the unknown,
which is the thing that attracts the
child's attention,
can be best conceptual.
Imagine this,
here's another.
So the child is surprised by a mobile
that it kicks.
The child is surprised when it drops a,
uh,
a clump of baby food on the floor.
The child is surprised when a glass of
water tilts over.
The Charlie's surprised when he pulls
the dog's tail on the dog barks,
you know,
the child surprised all the time.
Okay,
so then the question is,
what is the similarity between all of
those surprising events?
If you had to categorize the category of
all surprising events,
what would that category look like?
Well,
you might think,
well that's,
you know,
that's not an appropriate category.
It's like,
wow,
it's not clear that that's not an
appropriate category because the
category of all surprising events is
exactly the category of the unknown as
such.
And as I said before,
it's better to know how to deal with the
unknown as such,
then it is to deal with,
to know,
to deal with specific aspects of the
unknown.
And that's exactly what was expressed in
my nephew's dream,
right?
He wasn't going to fight off the little
doors,
there was no point in it.
He had to go to the thing that was the
source of the trouble and fight that.
And you know,
that's how people are.
That's what our most archetipal stories
are about.
So some of you are star trek fans
perhaps.
Um,
what's the motto of Star Trek?
It's to boldly go where no one has gone
before,
right?
And everybody's pretty happy about that,
you know,
and it's very,
very basic archetipal story.
But it does encapsulate the human
relationship with reality.
It's not,
we,
we think of reality that way.
We think of the known and unknown and we
think of there being a boundary between
the known and the unknown and we think
about being on the edge of that boundary
and looking over and that's the,
that's the architect of exploratory
behavior.
Now the serpent symbol is even deeper
than that because the serpent symbol
represents the world before it's even
been categorized.
It's like what's there when there's no
one there.
That's what this symbol represents.
It's the ultimate in the unknown.
It's the source of all things and so
it's infinite and self contained and
it's matter and spirit at the same time.
And partly it's infinite because you
never run out of an unknown things and
it's um,
it's eternal because you never run out
of unknown things.
And,
and it's mattered because when you
interact with it,
you,
you conjure up the material world,
so to speak,
and all sorts of different ways.
You know,
sometimes by actually crafting material
things and other times by merely
defining the material of the space that
you're in,
but you also extract information out of
it to build yourself out of because you
might say,
well,
where do you come from?
Well,
part of it is there you are,
you have a biological structure.
But obviously we think of nurture.
You're extracting information from the
environment all the time.
Now you might say,
well how do you do that?
And I think there's,
there's a variety of ways.
One is,
you know,
Piaget would say,
well you mimic the world with your motor
apparatus apparatus.
Hi,
you're.
So for example,
when you look at the can,
this is part of looking at the can,
the can is a graspable object.
That's the can,
that's how you define it.
So this is like the can.
And so that's a pattern in so far as
it's stable in space across time,
it's a pattern and you can match that
pattern.
And so it's a transfer of the pattern
here to a transfer to the,
to the pattern here.
And that's,
that's the use of information.
Information is information.
It's,
it's,
there's something,
there's lots of different definitions of
information by the way,
but,
but the information that we think of as
information is that that you can gather,
that you can then use,
you incorporate it,
and then it's in you,
and then you can use it.
So in so far as you're constantly
adjusting to the external world and its
demands,
you're,
you're reproducing the pattern of the
external world in your body.
That's one form of representation that's
a,
that's an informed representation.
And then you abstract out of that to
make your abstract representations.
But the point is you're pulling the
information out of it.
So the unknown is the ultimate source of
information and it can be very,
very dangerous,
but it doesn't matter because it's less
he.
The human supposition is that the
unknown is there and it's dangerous,
but the best thing you can do with it is
confronted voluntarily.
When it makes itself manifest,
when you're prepared,
that's your best bet.
And that's,
that's,
that's our archetype.
Fundamentally,
that's our bat on reality.
You know,
evolutionary biologists say that we
occupied the cognitive niche.
Well,
I'm trying to do that.
It's okay.
I will.
That's what this next bit is about.
So.
So your question is perfectly timed.
Okay.
So now I want to show you this image
that I forgot to put it in here.
There we go.
Okay,
so I'm going to walk you through this
diagram.
So in the middle is an anomaly.
Now I want to tell you a little bit
about.
So normally it's the unexpected that
emerges when you're,
when you're laying down a routine on the
world,
you,
you want the world to do something,
but it does something else.
We talked about that a lot.
What does it do that something else?
Here's a way of thinking about it.
So
the word phenomenon phenomenon comes
from a Greek word famous thigh and that
word means to shine forth.
So when the normally is something that
shines forth and you might say,
well what does that mean to me?
And I would say,
well you can watch for this.
Like all you have to do is watch in the
next week,
watch the things that attract your
attention because they will.
There are things that will automatically
attract your attention.
You get interested in them,
you know,
or they catch the corner of your eye and
you,
you have to look at them.
I mean,
and those are the things that are
shining forth in some sense and the idea
that they're shining forth is actually
quite an accurate idea because here's
the way of looking at your perception.
So you know,
I mentioned that my little daughter
would take all these foil things,
make sense out of them.
She was always making one weird thing
out of something that we'd already
categorized.
So here's something to think about.
What do you see when you look at the
world?
And the answer is mostly you see your
memory
because you're not smart enough to
actually see the world.
It's too damn complicated.
So you spent a lot of time seeing the
world and so you've built up all these
representations of the world and so now
when you see the world,
you use the representations because why
the hell wouldn't you?
It's so hard to look at the world.
So once you learn to do it,
you're going to use what you've learned
and then what you see is what you've
learned.
You don't see the world,
and so I could all even say that as long
as things are going your way,
you never see the world.
You only see your representations of the
world.
And so then you might say,
well,
what's behind that representation?
Well,
what's behind the representation is the
thing that shines forth.
Now
I think people experience this when they
take hallucinogenic drugs because I
think what the hallucinogenic drugs do
in part is stopped them from seeing
their memories and then they see they
see the unknown as such more.
Although you can never see the unknown
as such,
but everything that's,
that's no longer hyper attractive than
new and fresh and vital revitalizes.
That's what Huxley reported in the doors
of perception.
And we know that if you're,
we know that if you're predisposed to a
stimulus and the stimulus means nothing,
so first of all,
something pops up and it attracts your
attention,
but then you see it again and again and
again and again and again and again and
again.
You habituate to it and then it no
longer has any effect on you.
It becomes invisible.
I really believe that you habituate,
I think it's the wrong word.
You habituate.
If it's the kind of stimuli that your
spinal cord could process,
you know.
So if you take a snail and it comes out
of its shell and you tap it,
it'll go into a shell and then it'll
come out.
You tap it and go into a shell and will
You keep doing that.
Sooner or later you can tap the snail
and it won't go into its shell.
And the reason is,
is that the snail has figured out that
tap does not imply an event that would
require a snail to pull into its shell.
Now it hasn't done that because it's all
reflex,
but in people we still have those simple
reflexes that can just habituate,
but then we have much more complex
models of the world that we have to
actively engage in constructing and also
once we construct those,
they can stop us from reacting to the
stimulus.
Now think about it.
Here you are in this room.
Look at everything around you,
which you can't do by the way,
but look at everything around you.
How many of those things are you
reacting to?
And the answer is none really,
so I bet I could take half of you out of
this room.
I can take all of the order of this room
and half of you wouldn't know what color
the room is.
Well,
right and right as long now because
that's all of a sudden.
Then it shines forth.
It's like,
oh,
now that has meaning.
Again,
you wouldn't know what color those sound
absorbing panels on the backer.
You probably wouldn't even know that
there's those are there.
You wouldn't know the color of the floor
or the design on the floor.
You might not even know the color of the
chairs and and why would that be?
It's because,
well,
why is it,
why wouldn't you know those things that
you've been exposed to so often,
and part of the answer to that is,
and this is an interesting way of
thinking about it,
it doesn't matter.
Well then you might think,
well,
what does matter mean?
Because matters a weird word,
right?
Because things are made out of matter,
But you can also think that things are
made out of what matters
and it's actually more accurate to think
of things as being made out of what
matters.
And what happens when you build a model
of what matters is that most of it stops
mattering.
And that's okay because you know you
don't want to be overwhelmed by
everything all the time.
Mean maybe that's a paradise ul or maybe
a hellish experience,
but it kind of makes you nonfunctional.
There's just not enough of you to
process everything all the time.
So you zero everything out by building a
model of it and the mortal says you this
is zero.
It's irrelevant.
It has no bearing whatsoever on what
you're trying to accomplish in this time
and place,
and it ceases to draw your attention
now.
Then you think,
wait a sec.
Not Everything has ceased to draw my
attention
now.
That's a strange thing.
You remember that little thing that
Harry potter used to chase around when
he was playing quidditch?
That's the unknown by the way.
That's actually a symbol of the unknown.
It's called the winged chaos and I had
no idea how the hell j Dot k dot rowling
knew about the weighing the chaos or the
round chaos is another way of,
of describing because if you put round
chaos into Google,
the only thing you get is my website.
Now.
It's something I took from us,
but it's pretty damn old obscure.
But apparently she studied lot of
alchemy before she wrote Harry Potter
and that knowledge consciously or not
made it into.
She's pretty damn smart.
So it's ad,
but she's creative,
you know?
So if you're creative,
there's always a dance between your
consciousness and your unconscious mind
at creative dance.
Things emerge and you play with them.
But,
and the emerge and then you play with
them,
like the writers,
I know their characters come alive for
them and they may just write down what
the characters are likely to do.
You know,
when there's going to be some conscious
direction.
But it's this dance between
unconsciousness and consciousness that
really makes up creativity.
But anyways,
you know,
in the Harry Potter quidditch game,
what happens when Harry gets the little
ball,
right?
Right,
right.
So there's really two games going on at
the same time,
right?
There's the game,
everyone else's playing.
And then there's the game that the
seeker is playing and when the seeker
wins,
everyone wins.
That's the rule and quidditch.
And that's the rule.
When the seeker wins,
everyone wins.
That's the rule.
And that's an archetype too.
So,
and the chaos,
the thing that Harry's chasing,
that's the coolest thing because that
was the alchemical representation of
matter,
and it was a container and it contained.
It's like the dragon in some sense,
it contained matter and spirit.
And if you caught it,
then you could inculcate the matter or
the spirit and utilize the matter.
Now,
back to what attracts your attention.
I hate to say this,
but because what attracts your attention
is the same thing that Harry's chasing
in the quidditch games.
It's the same thing now.
It's the category of what attracts your
attention.
Now,
young was very interested in this.
He thought that what attracted your
attention was a consequence of the
manifestation of the higher self.
The self is what he called it.
The self is what you are,
the ego is what you think you are,
and it might also.
That's close enough.
The self is what you actually are.
Well,
you have no idea what you actually are
because you don't know very much about
yourself and you're really,
really,
really complicated and there's lots of
things going on that you have no idea
about.
And the world is a really strange place
and the self is also the thing that you
are now and the thing that you were and
all of the things that you could
potentially become.
And that's a strange idea.
So maybe you guys can help me think
about this.
You know,
because I'd been thinking for a long
time about these sorts of things,
so there's that.
You might say,
well,
is the unknown?
Is that a reasonable representation of
the unknown?
As such,
the unknown as such is the place from
which matter and spirit emerges.
Okay,
now you think,
well,
no,
I'm saying that's the best definition of
reality.
That's the best definition.
Or we're gonna.
We're gonna.
Make that proposition.
You'd say,
well,
no,
that's not right.
The best definition of reality is
material reality,
material reality.
You can decompose it down to the
elemental and this and the atomic level
and that's objective reality and
everything else is a secondary
manifestation of that and that's the
modern worldview.
Although we don't and can't factor
consciousness into that,
but whatever.
It's a pretty powerful view.
It's enabled us to get a lot of places.
So then if you're going to offer a
counter position,
and by the way,
although it took me probably 30 years to
figure this out,
there are many other people who have
made this case.
So heidegger,
for example,
made the case that I'm making in young
made the case that I'm making all the
white knew that um,
so other people have wandered down this
path fundamentally.
So it's not as idiosyncratic,
as strange as you might think.
What do you see?
What is it that you are facing when you
face the future?
Now there's,
there's a variety of ways of thinking
about that,
but let's think about how you act and
how you think.
When you think about confronting the
future,
I would say,
well,
you see the future as a field of
possibilities,
right?
You do.
That's what you do.
You see the future as a field of
possibilities and you use your faculty
of imagination to map potential routes
through that sea of potentiality because
you imagined that you could be a.
or you could be be,
you could be a plumber,
you could be a lawyer,
you could be a supermodel,
you could be a nerd.
Like there's all,
there's this,
there's all of these possibilities that
lie open to you and some of them are
more at hand than others in in that you
could get from here to there very
rapidly.
So for example,
if you want it to go get a drink of
water in the next 10 seconds,
you could probably make that reality
manifest itself,
but if you want it to be a billionaire
then it's going to take a fair bit of
maneuvering to make that reality
manifest itself.
So some are,
some are there and some are far,
but you act as if what's your,
what you're up against this possibility
and then what you also act out is that
your,
the thing that can transform itself in
response to the transformations of that
possibility and everyone believes that
even though they don't notice it.
And so your parents say live up to your
potential.
What in the world is that your potential
now?
It's weird.
It seems to me it's weird like it's hard
to measure.
I mean,
if I gave you guys an Iq test,
that would be some clunky way of
measuring part of your potential,
but it's not even easy for us to measure
potential.
Then you think,
well,
what is this stuff that we call
potential?
Is it?
It's not the way things are.
It's the way they could be and they it.
It seems to be that they could be a
whole bunch of ways,
not just one,
and so what seems to happen is that this
field of potential collapses into a
single league actuality as we interact
with it.
Now,
I should also point out that there are
models propagated mostly by John Wheeler
and his school.
He's,
he's a quantum physicist and his
hypothesis,
he calls his hypothesis it from bit that
being a piece of information.
He believes that the ground of reality
is basically something that's best
conceptualized as information and that
when consciousness interacts with it,
whatever consciousness happens to be,
it transforms itself from potential to
actuality.
It snaps into place and there is weird
corollaries to this.
So here,
here's a weird.
Here's a bloody weird thing.
This is from wheeler,
so let's say you go outside and you look
at a distant galaxy.
It's maybe who knows how far it is away.
It doesn't really matter.
3 million light years away.
You look at it in a Photon,
hits your retina.
Wheeler claims that that photon couldn't
have left that star 30 million years ago
unless you're.
I was there now to perceive it.
Now that's a bloody weird thing to say
and if you don't believe me,
you can look it up.
I mean,
I wouldn't say something like that
unless I was reasonably sure that that
is in fact what he would say we learned
believes that the quantum wave form,
which is in,
I think it's something like this horizon
of potentials doesn't become realized
until it's interacted with by something
that's conscious.
Now,
not everybody believes wheeler,
but the physicist who don't believe
wheeler believe something that's even
weirder.
They believe that every time a quantum
event,
so if you go down far enough into the
subatomic realm,
you get to events that are no longer
divisible basically.
So a quantum event,
for example,
would be the bouncing of an electron
from one shell atomic shell to a lower
shell,
in which case,
if I remember correctly,
it emits a photon.
So the bounces a quantum event,
the electron goes from here to here,
but it doesn't pass through the
intervening space.
However that happens and then it
releases a photon and the photon is a
quantum event.
And so things are quantum because at
some point you can't break them down any
further.
So your,
your computer screen is quantized right?
Because if you get the resolution of
higher high enough,
you can see the singular pixels that
it's made out of.
And that's it.
You can't go any farther than that.
So these other physicists believe that
every time there's a quantum event that
could go one way or could go another,
that a new universe is created in which
if it goes one way here it goes the
other way in that new universe.
And so there's like infinite numbers of
infinitely branching universes and you
might say,
well where are those?
And the answer is they don't know.
They can't really detect them in some
sense and then you might say,
well,
that's a hell of a theory.
To explain something simple by all you
do is posit an infinite number of
infinite universes and Poof,
you solved your problem.
It's hardly an outcomes razor solution
and then you might say,
well why even bother with that theory?
And part of the answer is,
well,
there are people that are working very
hard on quantum computer computation and
quantum computation
involves the use of these things that I
don't comprehend it all called cubits q.
You be its.
And a cubit is a state of matter.
That could be a variety of different
states but isn't any of those yet and
you can use those cubits to compute.
But the simplest way of saying what
you're doing when you're doing quantum
computation is that you're using the
universes that are pretty close to ours
to do your computations in so that you
can get a lot more done in a lot shorter
time because you're doing some things in
this universe and you're doing some
other things in a bunch of other
universities.
And so that's a lot more efficient and
you might think,
well sure,
but quantum computation does work.
Now there's even a company that has
manufactured what they claim is a
quantum computer,
although you can do quantum computations
at very local levels that's been
demonstrated.
No one doubts that it's published in
journals like science and nature.
This actually happens.
There is a company that claims that they
produced a commercial quantum computer
and people aren't sure if that's true or
not for again,
for reasons I don't understand,
but the computer is capable of doing
certain kinds of calculations much
faster than a normal computer camp.
So that's all pretty damn weird,
that's for sure.
Now it seems to me,
and I wrote a paper with my graduate
students about this and you know,
we were stretching our knowledge to the
right to the end of our limits.
We were trying to unite the theory of
anxiety with,
with thermodynamics basically.
And we published this paper in a journal
called Psych Review,
which is a very good journal,
but it's very hard to publish in psych
review.
It's the only paper I've ever published
there.
And,
uh,
we're basically proposed that when you
get anxious,
what you see in front of you,
what you perceive in front of you,
you can't actually see it with your
eyes.
It's more like you perceive with your
body or your body perceives it.
What you see unfolding in front of you
is a large and indeterminant space of
potential world,
roughly speaking.
And that the reason you get anxious is
because all of a sudden there's all
those potential worlds you have to deal
with and you didn't think that you were
going to have to deal with any of them.
So you might say,
well,
when does that happen to you?
And I would say,
okay,
so it's 20 below and you're late for
class and you jump in your car and it's
snowing like mad and you drive two miles
and all of a sudden your car stops.
And then you might say,
well,
what is it that you're sitting in now?
And you will say,
well obviously I'm sitting in a car.
It's like.
And it's by no means obvious that what
you're sitting in is now a car.
It couldn't be a tomb if it's called
enough and even if it's not a tube,
you're not where you expected to be.
You're not where you want to be and it
isn't exactly clear where you are and so
that your body is going to get all.
Uh,
I just saw a dinosaur like,
and it's an apprehension.
It's a,
it's a perception.
It's a perception that the map that you
were using to map your environment to
define all the objects and to define
your relationship to those objects no
longer fits the territory.
And so then you might say,
well,
if your map doesn't fit the territory,
then what the hell is the territory?
And the answer to that is many things,
many of which you cannot control.
Now you know,
you might get lucky and all that has to
happen is that somebody comes and tells
you how long it takes you to a mechanic,
but even now it's going to rattle your
chains because,
well,
if your car breaks down,
how do you feel about having to take it
to a mechanic?
Well,
mostly you don't feel good about it.
Why?
It's like,
well,
you don't know if the mechanic will find
the damn problem.
You don't know if you might have to get
a new car,
you don't know if you can trust the
mechanic to tell you whether you need a
new car.
Maybe it's a $2 part and like he offers
to put a whole new motor in and then you
have to deal with them or you have to
find a place to take it.
You have to assess whether or not the
sharp is honest,
so it's like a whole can of snakes and
part of that kind of snakes is,
can I,
is it the case that the mechanic to who
might take this car is the thing that he
presents himself as now in an honest
transaction,
that problem never comes up because you
just assume that the person in front of
you is two dimensional and that you can
assume that they're identical with what
they say.
Right?
That's an honest transaction.
So then you're not dealing with a kind
of snakes.
You're dealing with a few words,
but if it's not an honest transaction,
it's like what kind of snakes?
So maybe someone stops to help you on
the side of the road and you think,
well,
that a good thing or is that a bad thing
because the person who's approaching you
in the snow storm,
when it's isolated is also a can of
snakes.
And then there's the other snakes that
come out like,
well,
you weren't going to get to class and so
maybe you have an exam,
and so then there's the whole,
well,
what happens if I miss this exam and
maybe that'll,
you know,
I won't do so well in this course,
and then I have to go talk to the
professor and it's going to be a big
mess,
et cetera.
And so I would say that what happens
when your car stops on the way to school
is that everything around you turns into
a massive snakes.
Now obviously that's a symbol,
right?
Because if it's not,
they're not real snakes,
but they're not your damn car either.
And you might to the degree that you
confuse what you're sitting in with a
car,
all you're going to be be as irritated
and upset because it's going to
manifest.
None of the features of a car,
because a car isn't a block of metal
with four tires on it,
a car is something you can ignore.
Well,
it takes you from point a to point B and
as soon as it isn't doing that,
it is the car.
It's some bloody chunk of metal with all
sorts of parts that you don't understand
that a bunch of people you don't know
anything about are going to have to
manipulate before it will turn back into
a car,
at your expense and the day that you
proposed,
which you had all mapped out,
was quite simple.
Poof.
All of a sudden it's not that day at all
and God only knows what sort of day it's
going to be.
You know,
it's a.
it's a perfect setup for a movie.
These things happen all the time.
You know what?
Someone's car breaks down on a dark,
lonely road and you know God only knows
who comes out of the shadows to help.
It's a classic setup for horror movie,
so the question is,
where are you when you don't know where
you are?
I would say you're as close to reality
is every as you're ever going to get
when you are where you don't know where
you are and it's a bit much to take and
so people do everything they can all the
time to make sure that the amount of
reality that they have to come into
contact with is the limited filtered and
control
and we do that a bunch of different
ways.
We do that by organizing our beliefs in
a certain way.
That's terror management theory
fundamentally,
right?
Is that we organize our beliefs to
shield ourselves from the reality of
death,
but we also organize our societies and
our interpersonal relationships in such
a way that were shielded from death and
so that we don't kill each other and
that has nothing to do with the utility
of our beliefs and keeping the fear of
death at bay.
That's something that keeps the lights
on and keeps this room warm.
When it's minus 20 outside,
you think,
well,
here we are in this room and everyone
knows what this room is,
but it's not the same room.
If someone pulls out a pistol,
it is really not the same place and
insofar as you think it's the same
place,
all that means is you're in real trouble
because it is not the same place,
so things can shift and change on you
all the time and in fact to some degree
that's what time is doing.
Okay.
Now
you remember though,
oh,
Cyrus Horace Story.
Right?
Okay.
So there's no.
Cyrus and ozharvest is like.
He's like the way things are now.
There's a problem with that.
He's like the map.
There's a problem with that is because
the territories are always moving around
and so your map is never quite uptodate
and so you can't rely on no cyrus,
you know that if you have one of those
google gps now and then they've taken me
to the,
to the middle of parking lots,
you know,
because the map thinks there's something
there that isn't there and it's.
There's nothing there.
Maybe it's not updated.
It wasn't google.
It was the thing that I was using in my
car because Google tends not to do that.
But anyways,
when the map isn't an accurate
representation of the territory and
accurate pragmatic representation of the
territory,
then you can't navigate in it and you're
going to end up places that you don't
understand.
So the map gets out of date as the
territory changes.
So Oh,
cyrus isn't good enough.
The old map never works.
It kind of works,
and so you need horace because horace is
the thing that updates the map.
It's like he's attending to those
things.
He's attending to those locales where
the map is no longer valid and updating
it.
Now,
back to the idea about the things that
attract your attention.
It was either been swagger or boss and
unfortunately I don't remember which
because I always confuse the two
existential phenomenal logical
psychologists and one of them,
and I think it was been swinger,
said that reality shines forth and the
other one said,
no,
no.
You lay a structure on reality and the
structure is what allows things to shine
forth and it doesn't matter because you
can just put those two theories
together.
There's something shining in the
background and you have a map that's a
filter and now and then there's a little
hole in the map and you can see the
things that are shining through.
Those are the things that attract your
interest.
Now imagine that you have a part of your
brain that likes the map and just
follows it,
and I would say that's the automatized
part of you,
right?
That's the part that's running on
algorithms.
So when you know a territory,
when you're driving home,
the hundredth time,
you hardly have to pay attention at all
because he paid attention 100 times
before you know the route.
You can rely on your preexistent skills
they're built into you.
Literally.
You've built neurological models of,
of the landscape and the reaction.
So here's an example.
You know before you can be a London taxi
cab driver,
you bloody,
you have to take a test.
It takes like four years of study.
You have to know the city and London's a
big city.
It isn't that.
You just have to know how to navigate
and it.
You actually have to sort of memorize
the whole damn city and so they've done
scanning studies on people who've done
the London cab training process and what
they find is that from the beginning of
the four year,
three year,
whatever it is,
training period to the end,
their hippocampus grow.
So while why?
Well,
cause they have a big map.
It's a bloody big map.
It's all of London,
you know.
So the reason I'm saying that is you
don't want to be thinking that when
you've learned a route that you've just
updated your psyche.
You know what I mean?
It's not just your abstract conscious
mind that knows something.
You've built the damn thing right into
your body.
You've built neuro structures that are,
that correspond in some manner,
some minimal manner to the territory
itself.
And so then you can just run on
automatic and you want to run on
automatic because you know,
I bet you've experienced this.
You go somewhere for the first time it,
it's much longer the first time.
Then it is the third time.
Have you had.
Has that,
have you experienced that as.
How common is that experience?
To put up your hands if you've
experienced that.
Okay.
As people not experienced that.
Okay,
so I think the reason that is is that
you're doing a lot more neural.
There's a lot more neural events going
on when you're doing it the first time
and part of your time perception is how
many neural events are occurring per
fragment of time and so if a lot of them
are happening per fragment of time,
the time is going to seem longer.
If hardly any of them are happening.
It's like you hardly even notice the
time and why should you?
There's no point in it.
You run,
you're running on automatized machinery,
so I'll say,
well that's so cyrus.
Then you have another piece of machinery
that's Horus.
That's the thing that attends to those
things that the map hasn't covered and I
would say this is a union idea of
primarily,
although of course you extracted it out
from all these ancient stories where
things shine through the map is what
attracts your attention and that tells
you whether or not you know it.
The map has a hole there.
You should fix it now as you fix the
hole in the map,
you also fix yourself because you're
building yourself out of information.
Now,
corollary of that is you have a map of
the past,
your past and there's holes in it
everywhere and you can tell where those
holes are because you can't forget about
them,
so the whole might be you got bullied in
grade three and you were traumatized.
It's like that's a hole in the map
because you're still that person.
Unless you've repaired the hole,
you're still that person and that's
never going to stop shining through for
you unless you go back there and repair
it,
and what that also means is imagine that
that whole what shines through is is
horror in part.
It's hard on you,
but it's also information.
It's information and information.
There would be,
how the hell do you deal with a bully?
And so maybe you go back and you think
about that.
You really think through it and you
think,
well,
how did I get bullied and why did I get
bullied?
And exactly what it is about human
nature that allows someone to be
malevolent like that and what should a
person do to defend themselves against
that possibility and how can I become
that person.
It's like poof.
Whole fixed and what that means in some
senses that you've extracted out the
residual information from that
occurrence that you hadn't been able to
or refuse to process when you first had
the experience.
Now in your brain being no stupid thing
is it's really concerned about this map.
It cares about the map and we're things
shine through because it doesn't want
you falling through holes and so every
place that what you don't know shines
through is either something you have to
attend to now or something you can't
forget and what you do when you forget
something,
you don't actually forget it.
You learn that it doesn't mean anything
anymore because you've mastered it.
That's what it is to forget.
A traumatized person can't forget
because they haven't mastered the
territory that constitutes the locale of
the trauma.
You know?
So you might say,
well,
let's say you're a soldier and you did
something seriously brutal in
Afghanistan or Vietnam,
like seriously brutal and you can't
forget it.
What do you do about that?
Well,
you know,
I've dealt with people who have been
traumatized in one way or another,
or sometimes by things they've done in
sometimes by things that have happened
to them.
Um,
in order for people to deal with a
traumatic event that involves
malevolence,
they have to develop a theory of good
and evil
because it's the evil in the malevolence
that traumatizes them.
And I,
I think I've told you already,
I had two clients who suffered post
traumatic stress disorder because of the
way someone looked at them once.
It was only one time the person looked
at them,
the other,
it was repeated.
This is a person who been bullied and it
took me a while to figure out that she
had posttraumatic stress disorder,
but she kept talking about the look on
his face.
What was an archetypal look?
Right?
It's the luck of pure evil in so far as
someone can manifest that look,
it's like you can manifest that look,
you know,
and if you're a soldier and you
manifested that spirit,
that might be enough to knock out part
of your consciousness,
right?
That's what happens to horace when he
encounters seth.
It's like,
oh,
eyes open.
You encountered something like that.
You lose an eye.
You pay a price,
right?
It can damage you because it's so deep
and terrible.
One of the things you said about human
beings and as such,
and this is the adversarial part of the
person there a heroic side and there's
an adversarial side,
and he said all of your moral flaws,
your moral flaws are like.
They're like,
hmm,
there's an abyss underneath.
That's what.
That's where the image of hell comes
from.
Everything you do that's wrong.
Morally wrong is associated with the
abyss.
If you look into it deeply enough,
one of the things young thought was that
if you,
and this is also the same with the
phenomenologists by the way,
and it's also the same with Viktor
Frankl and I believe it's also the same
with Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn when he
wrote about how to stand up against
totalitarian states.
It's like you have to maintain an honest
relationship with the things that
attract your attention.
You can't ignore them if you ignore
them.
Well,
what happens what?
We've already figured that out and you
don't fix the holes in your map and then
whenever you wander on that territory
going to fall right through and when you
fall through,
then you're going to think,
oh my God,
the world's cursed.
Look at all these terrible things that
are happening to me.
It's like,
yeah,
well if you weren't wandering around
with a self imposed degenerative map,
then maybe it wouldn't fall into the
pits.
And that's a very interesting
proposition.
You know,
because one of the propositions is if
you read the terror management
theorists,
say those guys think that you gotta have
a psychological theory that's pretty
coherent and integral in order to
protect yourself against death,
anxiety,
and even though in the final analysis
that theory is false,
it's insufficient,
it's there as a defense like a Friday
and defense.
Okay,
and if,
if not that then you have to
conceptualize yourself as a hero because
that boosts your ego,
makes you feel good about yourself,
and you can find temporary relief in the
delusional fantasy that there's
something special in heroic about you.
Okay?
That's a materialist interpretation of
archetypal reality and it's a powerful
one.
That was Ernest Becker and Becker was a
smart guy and he took Friday and theory
to its ultimate limit.
He never read young adult and was a big
mistake.
Giving has a different proposition.
It's really,
really different.
His proposition is if you extract out
all the information that's available to
you by paying attention to the
disjunction between the territory and
the map,
so if you let your.
If you let what shines forth guide you
and you explore it,
then you'll extract out enough
information from that process of
exploration so that you can build
yourself into something so strong that
you're actually just no longer afraid of
death and there's nothing false about
that.
See the backer and the Friday instinct,
that's impossible.
They think,
you know,
basically you're a,
you're a sand sculpture in a hurricane.
We don't know what people are and we
don't know how tough they can be and
people can be unbelievably tough.
You know what I mean?
You think about people for God's sake.
It's like my sister in law works in
Palliative Care,
you know,
that's kind of rough.
Everybody she works with is gonna.
Like they're gonna die in three weeks.
She knows it.
She diluted about it,
you know,
I don't think so.
I talked to her like she seems to be
quite aware and also quite happy when
her life is going well,
you know,
because she sees all the time.
What happens if it doesn't go well?
It's like whole damn bottom falls out.
It's like if,
if you have a little joke that I was
telling myself about,
this is like,
how can you tell when you're having a
good day and answered that is there
isn't a crocodile attached to your leg
and that's about the right attitude.
And you know,
if you're dealing with something like
palliative care,
that's basically how you think all the
time.
Oh,
he had a rough day at school.
That's not so bad.
At least there isn't a crocodile
attached to your leg.
You know?
And I also think that that's what
happens to adolescents in cultures where
they undergo a really profound
initiation.
You know,
they're taken out of there.
It's usually happens with the boys.
And I think that's because mother nature
benefit blesses women with their own
automatic initiation.
Um,
they take the boys out from their
mothers often their mothers are all
crying and unhappy about this and some
of that's ritual and some of it's true
because they're going to lose their
child and they take the kids out the
boys out and they like,
they just scare them to death.
You know,
they burry them,
they put them in,
they put them in a cave.
I don't know if you've ever been in a
cave with the lights off,
but I can tell you a cave is very dark
and you can imagine.
Imagine sitting in a cave for two days.
Okay?
Now you might say,
well,
what's in that cave?
And the answer to that is who knows?
Right?
Spiders,
snakes,
whatever,
cave monsters,
whatever.
But I can tell you one thing that's in
that cave and that's your imagination,
and believe me,
you're going to confront that sucker
with two days inside a cave.
You're going to wonder,
well,
are they ever going to come back and get
me?
I'd be wondering that.
It's like,
what if the roof caves in?
What if this is an evil trick?
And then you think,
well,
what are,
what are all the things that could be in
that cave?
Well,
whatever is really in that cave is,
is certainly not going to be any more
horrible than the things that you might
imagine could be in that cave.
So you know,
in some sense and initiation like that
is a confrontation with the ultimate
horrific limits of imagination and my
suspicion is if you get through that,
I mean and there's more to the initial
initiation ceremony then that because
you also get inculcated with the tribes
customs and beliefs at the same time,
you know,
so you're stripped bare in some sense in
that rebuilt as an adult.
I think part of what that initiation
does is show you the difference between
things you should be worried about and
things you shouldn't be worried about.
And it isn't clear to me that you can
have your nervous system calibrated
properly until you've taken yourself
right to the edge because then you know
what's frightening and what isn't.
And there's every reason to believe that
we have no idea how courageous people
can be.
You know,
they can be insanely ridiculously
courageous.
And I think palliative care work is a
good example of that,
you know,
caring for the dying.
That's,
you know,
I think that people who work in funeral
homes are like that.
They,
they seem to manage it.
You know,
I mean,
I've talked to people who work in
funeral homes.
I said,
well,
like how the hell can you stand doing
this?
They say,
well,
it really makes me appreciative of my
life.
Isn't that interesting?
Like the things that shine forth can you
shine towards some reality shining forth
from the structure that kind of covers
of reality.
So I kind of see that as like our social
work world.
Do you think humans can discern between
kind of that shallow social,
um,
social things that interest us from what
reality actually is?
Things that shine from reality?
Well,
you know what,
that diagram I showed you with the
stacks,
there's a square,
it has a little dragon on it.
Then there's a disc that's the great
mother.
Then there's another disc that's the
great father,
and then there's a disk inside.
That's the hero.
Those are,
those are,
it's a map of the waste.
Things shine through fourth to some
degree,
you know,
because I think the background is
illuminated.
The background of things is illuminated,
so to speak.
And then we place what is essentially a
social structure on top of that.
Part of that's conceptual and perceptual
and part of it's actually out in the
world,
so you know,
when we're all sitting here just sitting
here,
you know,
we're all keeping the tremendous
potential that we all have for one thing
or another.
We're all keeping that under really
tight control and we're all doing it in
exactly the same way.
So basically the polite way to act in a
situation like this is as if you're
something that can be safely ignored.
Now the thing is,
you have a map of the social world,
just like you have a map of the natural
world,
there is the social world and you have a
map of it and there is the natural world
and you have a map in it of it.
So the thing is,
novelty in the social world can also
shine forth.
Now here's here are you out?
You see what you think about this?
So,
so let's say you fall in love with
someone,
okay?
And you think the clearly that's a
delusional state because while it fades
usually,
and uh,
you know,
often what happens in a relationship,
is that,
right?
The person who sort of illuminated that,
that would be the effect they have on
you when you're infatuated or when
you're in love and then you know,
you learn all the ways that they don't
quite match that maybe or you habituate
to them or you know,
the relationship accumulates a
tremendous number of errors and then
that disappears and you think,
well that was just like,
that's an instinct and you're the victim
of it.
You have to fall in love like that.
You have to be stupid like that because
otherwise men and women wouldn't be
attracted to each other.
And that would be the end of it,
but it.
But it's an illusion.
Maybe it's a chemically induced
delusion.
Okay,
that's one way of looking at it.
But here's another way of looking at it.
Now I'm going to switch it a little bit.
It's one thing your,
the women in the class will particularly
experienced this,
although men can experience it too,
but I think it's something that's
particularly granted to women.
So let's say you see someone else's
baby.
Okay,
well most women and some men are quite
interested in babies.
You know,
so they'll go up,
they like to interact with them,
they're,
they're attracted to baby so,
but being attracted to someone else's
baby is nothing like seeing your own
baby.
Like those are like those are
cataclysmically different experiences
and I think the reason for that is the
only baby you can actually see as your
own
for everyone else's baby.
You just see your representation of a
baby and the real baby shines through a
little bit but not very much.
But what you're blessed with,
if you have a child,
and I think this probably is a
consequence of a biochemical
transformation,
is that the memory structures that you
would use to process that child as a
known object disappear and all you see
is the baby.
It's like that's the same idea as the
archetypal infant.
You know,
the architectural holy child,
you know,
and it's certainly possible that each
infant is an architecturally holy child,
but the only person that can see that is
the mother.
And then you might say,
well,
is that true?
Is that an architect holy child?
Well,
one answer that might be it depends on
how you treat it,
you know,
if you treat it as if it's an
architecturally holy child,
then it has a pretty good chance of
developing into one
so and so.
Then let's,
let's switch that a bit and think about
a relationship that you would have with
someone when you fall in love.
One possibility is that you're diluted.
The other possibility is you get the
chance briefly to see what that person
could be like if you interacted with
them in the most perfect way you could,
so it's like a glimpse.
It's like a glimpse into a potential
extraordinarily positive future,
so they visioned emerges and then it
shuts,
and then it's up to you to build it,
to make it happen,
to take what you've seen in transform it
into reality.
Now that doesn't mean I don't think that
people can be diluted about
their partner.
I think they're diluted about their
partners all the time.
I think part of the reason for that is
that we build corrupt maps and we do it
on purpose and to the degree that you've
built a corrupt map,
then the things that shine forth aren't
even going to be in the right place.
So one of the corollaries,
and we're going to talk about this a lot
near the end of the class,
that is if you're going to follow the
things that shine forth,
you better make sure you're not looking
at the world with flawed machinery
because my suspicions are that for
someone like Jeffrey Dahmer,
for example,
the things that Sean fourth,
we're not exactly the things that you
would like to follow.
You know who Jeffrey Dahmer was?
Oh,
he was a brutal serial murderer.
Yeah.
He was.
And you know,
in in many situations like that when
someone is oriented towards
extraordinarily brutal crimes,
the brutality of the crime increases
with time.
The brutality of the crime increases.
It starts with.
It often starts with the torture of
animals and then it proceeds and there's
no stopping it.
Like God only knows where it would go
and I mean it.
It's bad enough.
So one character like that,
John Wayne Gacy,
he was a clown.
He was quite the character when they
finally caught him,
he asked to be killed.
So you know,
the shine forth thing,
is it kind of a tricky business because
you know,
there's a line in the old testament or
the new testament that says something
like,
test the spirits to be sure to be
certain that they are from God.
It's something like that.
But you know,
if you're looking at things in a crooked
way,
what shines forth might not be the thing
that's best for you.
So there's this like there's this
parallelism.
So if you're going to take the risk of
having a life that's governed by
meaning,
let's say you bloody well better,
make sure that you're not lying to
yourself because all that will happen
then is that you'll follow a blind
person and you'll both fall into a pit.
Okay?
So let's take a break.