Hello.
So you've lined up a very large number
of questions today.
So a couple of things.
First of all,
I have a number of
youtube videos and podcasts lined up.
One with Steven Pinker,
author of enlightenment.
Now one was Warren Farrell who wrote a
very interesting book called the boy
crisis and also a previous book called
why men earn more,
um,
one with an animator named Nina Paley,
uh,
one with a young guy named Charlie Kirk
who has organized a large number of
campus youth groups,
more on the conservative end of things
and associated with freewill.
So all those will be coming out in the
next month and a half,
I would say.
And so thank you for your continued
support.
It makes all of this possible.
And uh,
I'm also going on tour.
I presume some of you know that if you
go to Jordan beat peterson.com and you
look up events,
you can see where it's about 40 cities
listed so far.
Most of them are in us and a couple in
Europe,
Iceland,
the UK.
Um,
but we're announcing we're going to
announce 10 Canadian cities here in the
next week as well.
So that's all what's going to be
happening with me in the next two
months.
So I'll be on the road with my wife that
whole time,
sometimes in a plane,
you know,
just commercial travel,
sometimes in a motorhome,
depending on where we're going and how,
so I'm looking forward to seeing you if
you come out to the events.
I've been enjoying them quite a bit.
It's good to be able to talk to so many
people.
So,
um,
12 rules for life as sold about a
million copies now.
So that's really quite something.
And I think we've sold foreign rights in
43 countries,
so it'll come out in not quite that many
languages,
but just about over the next year and a
half,
something like that.
So.
All right,
so you,
let's get at it here.
Hopefully I could warm up and get my
brain going and,
and answer some questions.
The first one,
343 people have voted this one up.
Um,
could you please discuss freewill and
Sam Harris's and others' ideas of it's
non nonexistence.
Well that's a good complicated question
to kick things off.
So I want to tell you a little bit about
how to conceptualize freewill.
I think first because it's obvious that
we don't have infinite free will are our
choice,
our choices are constrained in all sorts
of ways.
And I think part of the reason that
there's a,
a continual discussion about freewill
and the philosophical and the
philosophical literature is because
just conceptualizing the issue properly
is extraordinarily difficult.
So I like to think about it at least in
part,
the way that you think about a game.
You know,
if you're playing a game,
obviously the game has rules.
So if it's a chess game or a basketball
game,
then there are things that you can do in
and things that you can't do.
And but,
and so it,
it's a,
it's a closed world in some sense.
But the fact that there are things you
can't do when you play a game also seem
to open up a universe of possibilities
for things that you can do.
So chess obviously constraints you to a
board and to a certain number of men and
to a certain pattern of rules.
But the strange thing is,
is that when you put in those rules,
because rules sound like limits,
they sound always like things you can't
do.
But when you set up a constrained world
like that and you lay out a system of
rules,
what you do is open up an infinity of,
of a near infinity of possibilities.
Same with music.
You know,
music has rules obviously,
and,
and if you follow the rules,
then you can make an infinite variety of
music.
And so,
and so there's a,
there's a very interesting dynamic
that's hard to understand between
constraint and possibility.
And there's a deep idea that's
associated with that that I read in some
Jewish commentary on,
on the biblical stories that I,
I read a long time ago.
I'm talking about the relationship
between God and man.
And the idea was that God,
imagine,
uh,
being with the classical attributes of
God,
omniscience,
omnipotence and omnipresence,
all seeing,
all knowing and all powerful.
What is it being like that lack,
and obviously the answer is nothing,
right?
Because by definition those three traits
provide for absence of limitation.
But then that's exactly what's lacking
is limitation.
And there's some strange connection
between limitation and,
and I was saying say limitation that
that's rule governed as I mentioned
before,
and the opening up of possibility.
So it isn't necessarily the case that
now determine determinism and limitation
aren't exactly the same thing,
but they're analogous and they need to
be discussed together.
Okay,
so now,
so that's the first thing is that our,
whatever our free choice is,
it isn't limited,
it's or it's limited.
It's deeply limited.
Now here's another thing.
If I take my arm and I go like this,
see,
I'll do that again.
Now you see there's a movement like that
and then my hand stopped just before my,
my other hand.
Now it takes a certain amount of time
for the neural messages to go from my
brain to my arm and back.
And the time it takes my hand to go like
this and stop is actually shorter than
the time it takes a message to get to my
brain and back.
So what that means is that when I,
when I planned this movement,
which is called a ballistic movement,
it's called a ballistic movement.
It's like a bullet.
Once you let it go,
it's gone.
There's no calling back.
I've actually organized the neurological
and muscular sequences that enabled that
action before it's implemented.
I set all that up and then it's released
and the whole thing cascades.
And so once the action has been
released,
let's say,
then I don't really have any freewill
because I can't stop it now.
So,
so you think about that,
it looks like there's a temporal
gradient with regards to freewill.
Is that as you look out into the future
meet perhaps the farther out you look
into the future,
um,
the farther down the road,
let's say the more free your choices
are,
but the closer they get to
implementation,
the more they become deterministic
governed by standard cause a processes
and there's some transition point where
they change from being what we would
describe as choice that we haven't got
to free choice yet,
but at least to choice.
There's some transition point between
now and ballistic movement.
Here's another way of thinking about it.
Like we know for example,
that people who are expert at playing
the piano look ahead of where they're
playing and,
and they're doing the same thing.
They're watching the notes,
they're seeing where they're going,
but,
and then their disinhibiting,
the automated structures that enable
them to play what they've practiced so
thoroughly.
They're disinhibited.
Those structures.
And then they go automatically.
And then what happens if you make a
mistake is that consciousness notes the
error and then unpacks the motor
sequences that have been practiced and
then you read,
practice them and sequence them again
until they become automatic.
And deterministic.
So there's choice in that you're reading
ahead,
but there's no choice in that.
Once you've read ahead in disinhibited,
the auctions,
then they run ballistically.
And then you can think about the same
thing that's happening when you're
driving in a car.
You don't look right in front of you
when you're driving a car because
whatever is right in front of you,
if you're going 40 miles an hour,
whatever you've already run over,
you look a quarter of a mile down the
road.
And that gives you the opportunity to
see what's coming.
And to set up a sequence of increasingly
automated movements that culminate in
whatever it is that you're doing while
you're driving.
And so there's a gradation from choice
to determinism,
a temporal gradation.
And,
and I,
I don't often see that addressed when
people talk about free will.
And now Sam's issue with freewill is
that if you get someone to do something
like lift their finger and you,
and you scan their brains using a
variety of techniques while they're
doing that,
what you'll see is that there's an
action potential that emerge and you ask
them to voluntarily move their fingers.
So they're doing it,
let's say by free choice,
there's an action potential that you
can,
that you can read off the brain that
occurs before the person either moves
their finger or let's say decides to
move their finger.
And that occurs quite a bit before the
feeling of volunteerism or that
voluntary act.
And so that's been read by Benjamin
Libet who did the experiments,
um,
as indication that even the feeling of
voluntary choices determined.
But I don't think that that's a very
useful way of addressing the issue
because the issue of when you lift your
finger in up again is it requires
pre-programming to disinhibit.
Like you know how to do this right?
You don't have to learn to do that.
So you have a little automated circuit
that does this sort of thing.
All these finger movements and
everything,
you can see babies practicing them and
they develop automated circuitry that
tends to be posterior left hemisphere in
order to run those,
those automated processes out.
And what you're basically doing when you
decide to do something that's a routine
that you've already practiced or,
or made out of sub routines that you've
already practiced is disinhibiting them.
And the,
the degree to which you might regard
that as free exactly is unclear as are
the temporal limitations.
So I don't think that limits experiments
demonstrate conclusively that there's no
such thing as free will even though
there are action potentials that
indicate that there is brain activity
signaling,
even the onset of a voluntary choice,
um,
voluntary choice early.
Now,
um,
another thing that we might look at in
relationship to that is,
um,
yeah,
so we can look at it phenomenologically
and we could also look at it in,
in,
in relationship to how people treat one
another.
So phenomenologically it seems clear
that we have free choice and it isn't
obvious to me why we have consciousness
if free choice isn't real.
Cause consciousness looks to me like a
mechanism that deals with potential
before it's transformed into actuality,
let's say.
And,
and I think consciousness is also the,
the faculty,
so to speak,
or a manifestation of the faculty that
enables us to preprogram deterministic
actions.
So again,
let's think about someone playing the
piano.
They're practicing,
you know,
after you repeat and you repeat your,
your finger movements,
if you're playing the piano,
any complex motor skill is like that.
You have to repeat it and repeat it and
repeat it and repeat it.
And you're using consciousness to
program it,
to sequence the motor movements and to
pay attention to them.
That all seems voluntary and it involves
the activation of a tremendous amount of
your brain.
Because if you're doing something new,
a lot of your brain is activated.
And then as you practice it,
the amount of brain that's activated
decreases.
It shifts from right to left.
And then it shifts from frontal to
posterior and a smaller and smaller
area.
So what's happening is that
consciousness is creating little
machines in the back of your head that
do things in an automated manner.
And
the,
the volume that consciousness looks like
consciousness appears and feels that
would be the phenomenological and as if
it's doing that voluntarily and it is
associated with a different pattern of
brain activity.
And so,
okay,
so there's that,
there's the fund long phenomenological
reality of voluntary choice and effort
as well.
Cause conscious programming of that sort
is also effortful.
It doesn't seem to run deterministically
like a clock does.
And then finally,
there's also,
and I don't know what you think about
this with regards to evidence,
but what constitutes evidence is not
always that easy to determine even in
the scientific domain.
So imagine,
think about how we think about ourselves
and other people and how we treat
ourselves and other people.
You could imagine that you're like a
clock running down and that's like a
deterministic model.
But people aren't,
clocks were dissipative structures.
A clock is something that runs downhill.
But human beings,
you can look up dissipative structure.
I think that was an idea that was first
formulated by the physicist.
Schrodinger we,
we're,
we're not,
we're not clocks by any stretch of the
imagination.
And we take energy in and we disperse
energy and,
and we were anti entropic in an in a
temporary sense.
So that makes us and and so and life is
as well shorting a wrote about that in a
book called what is life and
we don't what we seem to do,
this is how it looks to me.
We don't contend with the present and
we're not driven by the past.
Instead what we see in front of us is a
landscape of possibility and my wilder
moments,
I think that's associated with the
physical idea of multiple universes.
But that's in my wilder moments.
It's just a speculation.
And so what we see in front of us is an
array of potential universes.
And those are the universes that we
could bring about as a consequence of
our actions and it,
and we make choices to the right or the
left.
There's a lot of mythological
speculation about that sort of idea to
in an ethical sense,
cause we decide what sort of reality
that we want to bring into being.
And so we encounter potential like God
did at the beginning of time when he
made order out of chaos.
Chaos is this chaotic potential.
We confront chaotic potential with our
consciousness and we cast that into
reality and that now then you think,
well is that really the case?
Well that's hard to say because there
are limits to our knowledge about
consciousness and about reality.
But if you treat yourself like you're a
free moral agent with choice and that
you can determine the course of your
life,
then you seem to get along better with
yourself and to be less anxious and to
be more productive.
And if you treat other people like that,
that they're free agents that are making
voluntary choices about how reality is
going to come into being and you reward
them when they do it properly and you
punish them,
uh,
or otherwise discipline them when they
don't,
when they do it badly,
then your relationships with them seem
to work.
And then if we predicate our society on
the presupposition that each individual
human being is capable of doing just
that,
then we seem to have extremely
functional societies.
And so,
and this is something that Sam Harris
has been taken to task for many times,
is if you dispense with the idea of free
will,
how is it you organize your relationship
to yourself,
your interactions with your family and
your relationships with the broader
social community?
It's a very complicated issue.
So I believe strongly that we have free
will,
that we're responsible for our choices.
Those choices are constrained in many,
many ways.
I think there's a gradient of freewill
from free out into the future to
increasingly constrained as the present
manifest itself to deterministic in the
moment when,
when in the moment of action we,
and you might think that we entered the
realm of deterministic causality at the
moment of action,
something like that.
That's how it looks to me.
So.
Well,
so at this rate we're going to answer
about five questions so that,
but that was a very,
very hard one.
So anyways,
I hope that's helpful.
Maelstrom.
Who is apparently chaos given the name
asks me,
am I chaos or am I order?
Well,
that's a good question.
I would say a lot of the time I'm chaos,
but I do everything I can to put things
in order.
Um,
but I'm going to answer that in a deeper
way.
I would say,
because first of all,
everything and everyone is chaos and
order at the same time.
And I don't mean that in a trait sense.
I mean in a technical sense,
which is order.
Technically speaking in my way of
viewing the world is order is that
domain you inhabit when what you're
doing produces the results that you want
to have happen.
That's a pragmatic perspective from,
from a philosophical perspective,
it's derived at least in part or as
analogous to the pragmatism of people
like,
um,
cs purse and William James,
the American pr,
the early American pragmatists.
Um,
and there's a great book on all that if
you're interested,
called the metaphysical club.
Um,
so order is where you are when what
you're doing is producing the results
that you intended and that validates
what you're doing.
By the way,
that that's a pragmatic form of truth.
Your theory is accurate when if you
enact it,
then the results that you intend emerge.
That's the definition of truth from a
pragmatic perspective to have very
powerful definition and it's very much
associated with the Darwinian notion of
truth.
So that's worth,
that's worth looking into.
Now obviously there are times when you
implement a plan and a and at world
conception that goes along with that
plan and what you wanted didn't happen.
And so then the domain of chaos comes
up,
the domain of the unpredictable and
unexpected and you have to contend with
it.
And sometimes when you are acting,
you do perverse things and things that
that surprise you and then things don't
work out well for you.
Or,
or maybe you get a surprise and maybe
sometimes that might even be positive.
And that's because the chaos within you
as manifested itself and you've done
something that exceeds the bounds of
your understanding.
And you know,
that can happen to people so badly that
they developed post traumatic stress,
post traumatic stress disorder.
Sometimes soldiers,
especially naive young soldiers,
will go on a battlefield and watched
themselves do something they can't
imagine they're capable of doing and
then they have permanent post traumatic
stress disorder.
So there's a chaos within that can
manifest itself,
that can disrupt whatever order you are.
Um,
and you know that minor ways because
everybody's always running around doing
things that aren't good for them,
that they know they shouldn't do and
that they can't control.
And so there's a chaotic and an orderly
aspect to everything,
to the individual,
to the family,
to the social world,
to the natural world.
It's chaos and order at every level of
analysis simultaneously,
which is why the Dallas think of the
world is made out of Yin and Yang,
which is essentially
analogous to the idea of order and
chaos.
And now,
but then there's another element too.
So your order and your chaos and w the
place that you live,
the environment is order and chaos as
well.
But you're also the process that
mediates between the two.
And what that means is you're the forest
that confronts chaos and cast it into
order.
We talked about that in the freewill
discussion.
That's the basis for the dragon math,
or at least part of it,
the hero myth.
You're the forest that confronts chaos
and transforms it into habitable order.
And there's an idea that if you do that
using truthful speech,
it's probably the deepest idea in the
Bible.
If you confront chaos and the unknown
using truthful speech,
then the order that you produce is good.
So that also means that your chaos and
order and the process that intermediates
between them,
and that's really the basis of the hero
myth.
So part of that is the hero story and
the Dragon Myth.
Go Out,
confront the drag and get the gold,
bring it back,
share it with the community.
And the dragon is a representation of
that which dwells beyond the confines of
the safe and habitable space,
right?
It's an image of a predator.
That's part of what it is.
Although it's way more complicated than
that.
And you're also the forest that
confronts order when it becomes too
tyrannical and restructures it back to
chaos and then restructures the chaos
back into more beneficial order,
which is what you do.
For example,
if you have an argument with someone
that you settle,
right?
Cause the argument takes the orderly,
um,
relation that you have with that person
and then produces a chaotic interlude,
which is all the pain that's associated
with the argument.
And that's a dissolution into what
Murcia Ellie Audi called pre cosmic gone
to chaos.
And out of that,
a new order can emerge.
And so the best way to construe yourself
is not as chaos or as order,
but as the process that mediates between
the,
and that's the basis for the ethos of
the West is that the human being is best
represented as the individual and the
individual is that attentive and
communicative entity that is continually
capable of mediating properly between
chaos and order.
Now this is a deep idea.
You could read maps of meaning if you
would like.
The audio version of that is coming out
June 12th,
by the way.
And I will make a video detailing the
relationship between maps of meaning and
12 rules of life.
But you can construe yourself,
you should construe yourself as the
process that mediates between chaos and
order.
And you should aim to be the process
that does that properly using truthful
communication because that's how you
keep the elements of existence properly
balanced.
And you might say,
yeah,
but is that real?
Well,
if you read maps of meaning,
there's a section on neuropsychology
that's also buttressed by a book written
by Ian Mcgilchrist called the master and
his emissary that lays out the
relationship between the right and left
hand Miss Hemisphere.
Now it's quite strange that we have a
right and left hemisphere.
It's almost as if we have two
consciousnesses dwelling in our,
in our,
in our being.
Um,
and they're quite separable.
If you cut the Corpus callosum that
unites the two,
then the two hemispheres will act
independently to some degree.
You can communicate with each of them
somewhat independently.
So they actually view the world quite
differently.
And that that hemisphere distinction is
not only they're in human beings,
but also an animals along way down the
phylogenetic chain.
Now,
I made the claim partly because I was
reading a man named El Conan Goldberg,
who was a student of Alexander Luria,
the most brilliant neuro psychologist of
the 20th century.
And,
and Goldberg made the case that,
um,
the left hemisphere is specialized for,
for what's known.
And the right hemisphere is specialized
for anomaly and [inaudible]
Rameshchandra and who's a famous
neurologist.
I'm an MD in,
in California,
has also made it very similar claim
based on his analysis of brain damaged
individuals.
But Goldberg's case was the left
hemisphere is specialized for what you
know,
how to do.
And the right hemisphere is specialized
for response to what's unknown and that
maps onto this order chaos dimension,
right,
and the right hemisphere.
Now,
um,
mcgilchrist in his book,
the master and his emissary has pointed
out quite clearly that the left
hemisphere has a tyrannical tendency,
which Rameshchandra and also viewed in
his brain damaged patients by the way,
and that the left hemisphere is always
trying to impose.
It's logical and restricted order on the
world.
And to make the world fit into that.
Now it has to do that.
There's reasons for that.
Part of the reason is,
is that if your theory you've worked on
for 10 years makes one prediction era,
you shouldn't throw the whole damn thing
out.
You should doubt the prediction error,
right?
Cause you never know when your data is
actually data or is just another kind of
theory.
We can't get into that at the moment.
Now,
um,
mcgilchrist makes it very strong case
and I think in a more elaborated case
than I made in maps of meaning.
But it's the same argument fundamentally
that the right hemisphere is concerned
with reaction to anomaly.
And so,
so what happens in some senses something
unexpected happens that's the domain of
chaos.
And that stops you in your tracks,
it freezes you.
And that's a Predator response.
A prey response.
Actually,
you're frozen,
the unknown has manifested itself.
You're not in order anymore.
You don't know where you are and you
don't know what to do.
And so,
and you can't just shut down like a
computer does.
You freeze instead.
And then what happens is that the
ancient mechanisms that have helped our
ancestors for tens of millions of years
or perhaps longer than that,
react to that which lurks beyond the
confines of the unknown kick in.
And you start,
first of all that's motoric.
So you freeze and then you cautiously
start to explore and then it's
imagistic.
You start making imaginal
representations,
metaphoric representations,
dramatic representations of what might
constitute the unknown.
And then those representations are
practiced and implemented in the world
and they become more and more fine
grained and automatized.
And as that happens,
the locale that they're represented in
the brain shifts from right to left.
So,
so,
so the reason I'm telling you all this
is because you know,
this is where the metaphysical and the
physical unite,
and this is the sort of argument that I
was trying to make to Sam Harris and
hopefully we'll be able to continue
doing that because I'm going to meet him
three times in the next few months.
Is that the,
the Yin Yang idea,
the chaos order ideas,
metaphorical in some sense to say that
the world is made up of order and chaos
doesn't sound like an empirical
statement,
but strangely enough,
the world to which our brains are
adapted is actually the world of chaos
and order.
You can think about it as unexplored,
unexplored territory too.
That's another,
that's another,
you know,
take on it.
And so then you think from a Darwinian
perspective,
think about it this way.
From a Darwinian perspective,
there's an,
there's an an axiomatic presupposition,
and that is reality is that which
selects,
okay,
reality is the force that selects over
evolutionary time.
And so the forest that selects over
evolutionary time has selected for
hemispheric specialization,
bilateral hemispheric specialization,
which indicates the two different modes
of looking at the world are necessary
for survival,
right?
So that's real.
And so the idea that the world is made
out of chaos and order is perhaps the
most real idea.
Now,
here's something else cool that's
associated with that.
And this is an antidote to nihilism.
I also think it's an antidote to two.
What would you call 'em?
Ideological,
ideological possession.
So when you encounter something unknown,
you orient towards it and that's an
involuntary response.
You could even think about it as a
deterministic response.
It's part of what orients you very
rapidly towards predators.
So they don't kill you before you have a
chance to respond.
Okay,
so you react because the normalist thing
is meaningful,
it's intrinsically meaningful.
And the reaction is first terror with
perhaps an overlay of disgust and second
curiosity.
And it's terrorist so that you freeze
and remained paralyzed.
You turn to stone.
When you look at the basilisk or the
snake or the Gorgon,
you turned to stone,
you're paralyzed like a prey animal.
And that's so the prey Predator can't
see you at least in part.
And there's other elements of the
orienting reflects that are associated
with Predator avoidance.
And then if nothing additionally
terrible happens,
you start to thaw out and you start to
explore and you do that with image first
and then pr and then practice the
appropriate behaviors and then,
and then automate those.
Now look,
here's the thing that's cool.
So that orienting reflects to the
unknown is it's an admixture of threat,
fear and curiosity,
incentive reward.
So negative emotions and positive
emotions now,
and it's dose dependent.
The larger the anomaly,
which means the larger the map,
it blows out when it manifests itself.
Think of the difference between being
irritated at your marital partner
because they,
you know,
um,
Oh,
who knows?
Because they were late to pick you up
for work compared to how irritated you
would be if you found out they were
having an affair.
Difference in size of a,
normally the first one disrupts a tiny
little part of your space,
time orientation,
and the second one demolishes your past,
present,
and future.
And the larger the disruption,
the more negative emotion,
obviously.
And so,
so there's this weird interplay between
negative and positive emotion in the
response to a normally and,
but it's deeply meaningful,
even if it's even if it paralyzes you,
even if it's terrifying,
it's meaningful.
And then that transforms perhaps into
intense curiosity and you start to
explore.
Now the phenomena of meaning is a
manifestation of the complex orienting
reflex.
And so you're wired so that you're not
just order and you're not just chaos,
your order continually confronting chaos
so that the order remains updated.
And you might say,
well,
how do you know how much chaos you
should confront in order to keep the
order continually updated?
And the answer is meaning.
See,
something is meaningful.
The reason that something is meaningful
is because you're getting a deep
instinctual signal that you're
encountering a normally at a rate that
doesn't exceed your capability.
That's also the rate at which you can
keep yourself updated optimally.
And so meaning isn't epit phenomenal and
it's,
and it isn't.
It isn't some kind of delusion that
rationality can and should overcome to
say,
well,
everything's meaningless.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
Meaning is the most fundamental instinct
for adaptation.
And so that's partly why in 12 rules for
life.
I said one of the rules,
um,
I think it's rule seven is do what is
meaningful,
not what is expedient because meaning is
a really good guide to longterm
adaptation.
And so then,
and the other thing about meaning,
which is what happens when you get the
balance between chaos and order,
right?
Is that meaning is the antidote to
despair.
And so if you,
and there's all sorts of reasons in life
to be desperate.
And so if you immerse yourself in
meaning,
you can learn to do that.
You can learn to do that.
You can make that goal your highest
goal.
And so then the highest goal would be to
be the sort of mythological hero,
let's say,
to embody and incarnate and imitate the
mythological hero,
like the imitation of Christ,
which is what you're called to do.
If you happen to be Christian,
that means that you live in meaning.
And that meaning is the antidote to the
suffering of life that would otherwise
make you brutal and vengeful and unhappy
and miserable.
And like that,
that young guy who just mowed down 12
people in Toronto,
these are real things.
You lose your sense of meaning.
You end up in hell and inhale,
you do all sorts of terrible things.
These are,
these are dreadful realities and it
isn't as if they're not grounded in the
appropriate science.
So anyways,
that was also a very complicated
question began in a longterm
relationship.
We are considering kids.
What are your thoughts about gay people
raising children?
Um,
I think the devil's in the details to
tell you the truth.
When,
if I was ever talking to any individuals
about that,
that's it.
The question is,
well,
how would you raise them?
I mean,
you have problems,
right?
If you're both of the same sex,
then you're going to have the problem of
how to provide the proper model for,
you know,
let's say you have a boy and a girl.
Um,
we know this is indisputable and this is
something I've talked to Warren Farrell
about kids in intacct,
heterosexual families where the father
is present,
do way better on multiple indices than
kids who are,
are part of single parent families.
Now that doesn't mean that there are no
single parents who do a good job,
right?
That's not the same bloody claim.
Those are different claims.
But on average kid,
not only do kids where fathers are
present do better,
but societies or even even local
societies where there are more fathers
present do better not only for the kids
that they're fathering but the kids in
the neighborhood,
whether lots of intact families with
fathers do better.
And so I believe quite firmly that the
nuclear family is the smallest viable
human unit,
father,
mother,
child,
smallest viable unit.
And if you fragment it below that,
then you end up paying.
Now that that doesn't mean that there
are way,
there aren't ways that you can operate
in smaller unit or a different unit
effectively.
But you have to contend with the fact
that it's necessary for pe,
for kids to have models for both sexes.
And that means that means accepting that
the sexes are different even though
there's a fair overlap between the mix
epting that they're different and that
both sexes play their role.
It looks like what fathers do.
And I talked to Warren Farrell a lot
about this,
and I'm going to release this video this
month about what fathers do and a lot of
what they do is rough and tumble play
with the kids,
which kids really,
really,
really like.
And it's really important as Jaak
Panksepp a great effect of
neuroscientists laid out in his studies
on routes.
He discovered the place circuitry and
fathers.
This is something feral told me,
which was extraordinarily interesting,
is that fathers used the joy of the
possibility of play as a scaffold to
help children learn to delay
gratification.
So imagine a father spends a bunch of
time playing with his kids and they're
having a great old time.
They're wrestling around and pushing
each other's limits to find out where
they are and learning the physiological
dance that goes along with direct
contact,
direct,
exciting contact,
learning what hurts and what doesn't and
what constitutes fair play and what
isn't and how everybody can play and
still enjoy the game and how excited you
could get before it's too much and how
much you should wine and how much you
shouldn't and when you can.
Object to being hurt,
all of that at a deeply embodied level.
The kids love that.
They'll line up for that.
And panksepp demonstrated very clearly
that rats will work to play and that
routes play fair and they learned to
play fair because of iterated play
bouts.
And that if you don't let juvenile male
rats play,
then their prefrontal cortex is don't
develop and they get attention deficit
disorder or the equivalent in rats.
And then you can treat that with rental
it.
And so this is all very vital material.
Now if you're going to,
if you,
if you're gay,
let's say there's two,
two men or two women,
then you have the problem of what you're
going to do for the Contra Sexual,
um,
target.
And you can say,
well,
it doesn't matter because there's no
differences between men and women.
And you can gerrymander the damn
question that way and avoid you're
remorseful responsibility.
Or you can face it squarely and say,
look,
you've decided to step outside of the
cultural norm and to organize a
nonstandard relationship,
which puts a tremendous rented
responsibility on you.
And then you have to figure out how you
can provide for your children what it is
that they would get in the classic
minimal human unit.
So,
and more power to you.
I hope you can do a good job of it.
You know,
I think there's room in the world for,
for a diverse range of approaches to
complex life problems,
like,
like having kids and finding a partner.
But that doesn't mean you get to bury
your head in the sand about the absolute
realities of life.
And the fact that there are biological
differences between men and women to
deny that is reprehensible in my
estimation and besides the empirical
doubt at the scientific data are crystal
clear.
So and so.
Okay.
Carl Jung says that everything
unconscious is projected into reality.
How do you know if you are perceiving
reality accurately or are just
projecting?
Great.
Yeah.
Well,
that's partly why I'm a pragmatist.
there's a bunch of ways.
Um,
there's a bunch of ways that,
you know,
pain tells you
if you make a mistake and you hurt
yourself while then you're stupid theory
was wrong,
right?
That's what the pain says.
You're stupid theory was wrong.
And that's a pragmatic,
you see,
that's another indication of pragmatic
theory of truth.
You lay out.
Look,
when you look at the world,
you look at the world with a set of
presuppositions.
I outlined that in chapter 10 in in
rules,
in 12 rules for life called be precise
in your speech.
It indicates that when you look at the
world,
you look at it through a value
structure.
You can't help that because you're
always aiming at something in the world
and you're always aiming at something
you want and you're trying to get it.
And so that means that you look at the
world through a value structure.
Now the question is whether or not that
value structure is valid,
and that's a very complicated question.
Okay,
so how do you know if it's valid?
Number one,
you lay it out and you act it out.
You,
you implement it perceptually and then
you act it out.
And if you get what you wanted,
what the theory predicted,
that's another way of thinking about it,
but wanted is a better way of thinking
about it.
Then the fact that that behavioral
routine and perceptual structure
produced the intended result validates
it as a tool for obtaining that result.
And that's a form of truth.
Now,
it might be the only form of truth,
although I'm not convinced of that
completely.
But it might be,
it's a very complicated question.
Now,
how do you know if you're stupid theory
is wrong.
Okay?
A,
it fails and you're hurt.
Pain tells you,
you pragmatically,
your theory was wrong.
So that's why you should pay attention
to your own pain because your suffering
is indication that you still have things
to learn.
And maybe the suffering of other people
is also that,
um,
maybe something unexpected or
unpredictable happens when you're laying
out your plan and then the anomalous
manifest itself,
the unexpected or chaos.
And then you get anxious.
Well,
anxiety is an indication that your plan,
your Arrow didn't fly too.
It's mark,
so you aimed wrong.
And that might mean a small error,
you know,
maybe a tiny adjustment of your bowl or
it might mean you just don't know what
the hell you're doing at all and
everything is lost.
And so anxiety tells you if your theory
is wrong and then,
and then other people tell you that.
And that's why you want to surround
yourself with other people because you
distribute your cognitive resources.
Ew,
you,
you distribute your problems to the
cognitive resources of the social group.
That's what we do when we price things,
right?
Everyone votes on the price of something
because it's so difficult because the
price of something has to be established
in relationship to the price of
everything else.
And that's always in flux.
And so it's computationally impossible
problem.
And so we outsource it to the market,
which is the free cognitive decision of,
of millions of people.
And that's how we determine price.
And so one of the things you do to make
sure that you're not any stupider than
you have to be blind,
ignorant,
biased,
and all of that is you surround yourself
with other people and you try to treat
them well enough so that they can
tolerate you.
And then every time that you do
something stupid because one of your
theories is it is vague or incomplete or
wrong or biased or you're willfully
blind,
then they slap you on the side of the
head.
They ignore you because you're boring.
They don't laugh at your jokes because
they're stupid.
They,
they,
they are irritated at your auctions
because you're not taking your own
longterm interests or the interests of
other people into account.
And so you have pain,
you have anxiety,
you have the reward of success that
that's,
that's a positive indicator that your
theory is okay and then you have the
reactions of everyone else and if you're
clued in,
you pay attention to all of those things
and you try to update your,
your order,
which is your perceptions.
You try to update your order constantly
as a consequence of being humble in the
face of your errors,
which is why humility is the
precondition for learning and why it's
one of the highest moral virtues.
So
and perceiving reality accurately.
You don't really perceive reality and
you don't really perceive accurately.
You perceive small portions of reality,
extraordinarily limited in space.
And time and accurately means well
enough so that when you do what you're
doing,
it works.
That's why I'm a pragmatist.
I mean,
not only,
you know,
I mean there's lots of other
philosophical streams that have
influenced my thought.
Existentialism,
Phenomenal Log,
phenomenology,
dimension to others.
Um,
but the thing is you can't perceive
reality accurately because you don't
know everything.
So,
and you're full of biases and you're
ignorant as hell.
And so the best you can do is perceive
small bits of reality well enough so
that you can more or less get what you
need in a relatively short period of
time without screwing yourself up too
badly in the medium to longterm.
That's pretty much what you've got.
And that doesn't mean truth is
impossible,
just means that it's very,
very complicated to decide what truth
is.
And because the question is what is
truth for someone whose knowledge is
limited,
right?
Because obviously because your knowledge
is limited and you don't know everything
saying some fundamental way,
you're ignorant or wrong about
everything.
But that doesn't help because you still
have to act in the world.
So there are bounded truths,
there are bounded truths and so,
all right,
if past experiences shape us,
oh no,
I missed one.
You cite a tired brain foggy thinking as
the reason to stop answering questions
or giving a talk.
How do you combat this well working or
writing daily?
Um,
well I eat a big breakfast relatively
soon on waking.
That really helps.
If any of you out there are anxious and
many of you no doubt are,
there'll be a large number of you who
are anxious and don't eat breakfast and
there'll be a whole bunch of you out
there who think,
well I don't eat breakfast.
It isn't necessary.
It's like that's wrong.
It's necessary.
You fasted all night.
If you load yourself cognitively or
physiologically in the morning,
your brain stressed will produce,
will encourage your body to produce
insulin.
It will take all the blood sugar out of
your blood and then you're done for the
day and then you'll be anxious.
And another lot of the rest of you too,
you'll find if you're anxious,
try this.
It's really,
really interesting experiment.
The next time you anxious,
go eat something,
eat like eat some protein and fat would
be best.
You could have cheese and crackers.
I'm not a big fan of carbohydrates but
whatever.
Eat whatever you're willing to eat but
make it solid.
Don't eat a peanut butter or don't need
a like a chocolate bar or something
sweet.
Eat something substantial,
a piece of meat,
a piece of cheese,
some peanut butter,
something like that and then wait 10
minutes and see if you're less anxious
and try that for like two weeks every
time you get anxious,
eat something because then you can find
out if you're anxious,
if you're anxiety is linked to low blood
sugar and it's very likely that it is,
especially if you also get irritable and
foggy and your thinking and so,
and the best way to treat that as far as
I've been able to tell,
and there's a decent literature on this,
is to make sure that you eat a big
breakfast and you might say,
well,
I'm not hungry in the morning.
It's like,
who the hell cares if you're hungry?
I didn't say enjoy your breakfast.
I said,
eat it.
That's not the same thing.
You know,
there's lots of things that you need to
do that you don't enjoy to begin with.
You'll get hungry in six months and then
you'll start to enjoy it.
So that's a massive difference.
I take small naps quite frequently.
If I'm wiped out,
you know,
I'll go have a nap for 10 minutes or 15
minutes and then that helps quite a lot.
Um,
I try to wake up fairly regular,
a lot on a fairly regular schedule.
That's another thing I would really
recommend for people whose lives are in
disarray and who are anxious.
Try to fix your wake time,
sleep going when you sleep,
that's not so important.
So you can still stay up late and have
fun and all that.
But getting up in the morning is really
helpful.
Okay.
So,
um,
you know,
and you,
you also have to figure out how much you
can work or write.
I can't write for more than about Max.
My sustainable maximum for writing is
three hours a day.
And if I push it past that,
then especially if I'm editing,
I,
I make mistakes.
When I'm editing.
So that's counterproductive and I can't
sustain it across time.
And so I don't really think you can do
more than about three hours of extremely
intense intellectual work a day.
Although if you have a nap,
you can stretch that.
But I think at least I end up paying for
it across time.
So nap,
make sure you eat,
um,
and make sure you eat protein and fat
and not carbohydrates because
carbohydrates are basically poisonous.
Um,
that's about,
that's about and make sure that you get
enough sleep.
So that's,
that's how I combat it and try to make
myself hyper efficient,
which is also a really interesting thing
to try.
You know,
I was talking to my agents at CAA,
creative artists agency in La and I just
hired a publicist to help me manage
media in a more intelligent manner.
And we're trying to think about our
overarching philosophy.
You know,
and I first proposed to the CA guys that
are overarching philosophy would be
something like,
cause you need an overarching philosophy
under which you nest all your specific
actions.
It was something like to educate as many
people as possible.
In the shortest period of time,
which seems like a really good goal,
like why the hell not do that?
But then we broadened out a little bit
this week which was to try to do as much
good as possible,
as efficiently as possible and that
efficiency thing is really fun.
If you guys who are listening are out
for a challenge,
like one of the things that you can,
I think this heightens the meaning in
your life is to try to do difficult
things,
right?
Aim High,
don't name Sadam High,
you can't manage it and make sure you
break down your aims into reasonably
attainable sub goals,
but you want to aim high and then you
want to see how hyper efficient you can
get.
That's a great thing to do in your early
twenties is to see,
okay,
like discipline yourself.
You think,
okay,
how much work can I do if I load myself
right to the maximum,
how far do I,
how far can I work?
How hard can I work until I exhaust
myself?
And then you back off obviously because
the optimal amount of working productive
engagement,
let's say,
is that which is sustainable across
decades.
So you have to,
you have to learn that,
but you don't learn that without
stretching yourself to your limits to
begin with.
And you know,
if your life isn't everything it could
be,
and if you're suffering from an excess
of meaninglessness,
well it means you're not oriented in the
world of chaos and order properly.
It's like you could learn to discipline
yourself,
look,
figure out what,
figure out what it is that you need to
do and that you want to do and then see
how efficient you can get.
Because one of the things that's quite
fun is to figure out if you have a task.
I always tell my graduate students this,
if they're doing an experiment too,
if you have a task that you have to do,
it's really interesting to spend a few
minutes,
sometimes hours,
depending on how long the task is.
See if you can figure out how to do it
from,
from five to 10 times faster.
It means you'll have to rearrange the
way you think about it,
but you can often do it.
And that's how extremely productive
people get.
So hyper efficient,
you know,
sometimes it means you have to delegate.
It means sometimes it means you have to
bring other people aboard.
That's delegation as well I suppose.
Um,
but there's a lot of preconceptions that
you hold about who you are and who the
world is that you could dispense with
that would make you a way more efficient
actor in the world.
And so,
all right,
so there,
that's that.
If past experiences shape us from the
moment of birth,
how can an action be ever said to be the
result of freewill rather than the
accumulation of past influences?
Well,
it is in large part the accumulation of
past influences because that's
knowledge.
But I addressed that,
I would say already pretty thoroughly in
my discussion of freewill.
Your,
your freewill isn't absolute.
I mean,
what are you a genie?
Even a genie is constrained inside a
lamp,
you know,
so there's,
there's no action without constraint.
There's no action without limitation.
So it's,
it's,
it's just not conceptualized well and
all of your choices are constrained,
not least by the fact that you have to
keep yourself alive.
So even just because there are
limitations that emerge,
say as a consequence of the accumulation
of past influences doesn't mean that you
aren't,
that you don't still have a massive
domain of freedom.
So what is your opinion of attachment
based therapy and do you think that
therapy is at risk of encouraging people
to wallow in self pity?
And I'm not going to talk about
attachment based therapy cause I don't
know enough about it to provide an
intelligent critique,
but I can answer the second part of the
question.
Do I think that therapy risks
encouraging people to wallow in self
pity?
Not if it's done by a competent
therapist.
If you're a therapist is encouraging you
to wallow in self pity,
then it's time to get the hell out of
there.
You've got a therapist who thinks that
they're supposed to offer you a safe
space.
That's not helpful.
Look,
what do you do as a therapist?
You Act as a strategic counselor.
So let's imagine someone comes to see
me.
So there's two big mysteries,
right?
What's wrong and what,
what would look better,
what's wrong and,
and how,
what would it cure look like?
And I don't know.
And so if you're a therapist,
the first thing you want to do is figure
out that you don't know what's wrong
with this person.
And probably neither do they.
And you also don't know what's right for
them.
And so then you start talking to the
person to try to solve that problem.
It's like,
okay,
you've come to see me because something
isn't right in your life.
What is it?
And so then the person has to talk and
talk and talk.
And you have to ask them questions to
find out because you know,
maybe they're depressed,
maybe they're anxious,
maybe they came from a terrible family.
Um,
maybe they're really hard on themselves
and things are actually going better
than they think.
Like you have no idea what's wrong with
them.
You're ignorant,
you're ignorant.
And so are they.
And so you say,
look,
you can tell me anything as long try to
tell the truth because otherwise we're
just not going to get anywhere because
we're trying to deal with reality here.
So tell me the truth.
I'm not going to be judgemental in any
stupid sense.
I'm going to judge like mad cause I want
to help you do things right.
So I'm going to be,
I'm going to be judging like mad,
but I'm not going to throw you out
because of the things you say.
You're going to have to wander all over
weird territory to explain your problem
because you don't even know what it is.
So you have to listen a lot.
And the first thing you want to figure
it out is okay,
what's wrong here?
And the personal tell you a hundred
things that might be wrong and that
there is quite painful to listen too
often.
You know,
they'll tell you about their past and
their present.
I don't mean painful in that it's not
engaging or that it's not worthwhile.
I mean people whose lives have a lot of
pain in them.
So it's painful to partake in that.
So they'll tell you like a hundred
things that might be wrong and then you
do an analysis with them and you think,
well,
okay,
how many of those things really probably
aren't a problem?
The first thing that happens is if you
let a person talk about,
let's say they tell you about a hundred
problems,
the first thing you find out is that 90
of them aren't real problems.
And the person just figures that out as
they talked them through.
So they say,
well that's linked to this and maybe
that's not really a problem.
That's not as bad as I thought it
wasn't.
We can probably ignore that.
It's like they have a handful of cards
that aren't organized and they don't
know what to do with them.
There's too many cards.
And so you say,
look,
lay your cards on the table,
all of them.
This is also what you do when you're
listening to someone you're intimate
with and they're trying to solve a
problem and you have to be patient to do
this cause they're all upset about
something.
Right.
And you don't know what it is,
and maybe they're upset about you and
maybe they're upset about themselves and
they're not handling it very well,
and they're impulsive and,
and volatile and hard on you.
And you say,
all right,
Christ,
I'm going to listen to you.
It's like,
what's your stupid problem?
And then they lay out their problem,
right?
The problem space.
And you have to listen and not jump in
there too quickly with a dam solution
because what the hell do you know?
So you listened to them,
lay out the problem space,
they lay their cards on the table.
Then you say,
well,
we don't have to pay attention to this
and we don't have to pay attention to
this.
We don't have to pay attention to this.
And that's the cutting the dragon of
chaos down to size.
That's what it is.
You look at the dragon of chaos and it
starts to shrink.
Okay?
So,
and that's because by looking at it,
you indicate to the dragon that you're
bigger than you thought you were and
that you're bigger than it thought you
were.
And that's very,
very useful.
So anyways,
you lay out your cards and then you
start to organize them.
It's like,
well actually I only have 10 problems.
All right.
So then you think,
well,
how can we break those problems down
into manageable sub problems?
And how can you go about addressing
them?
That can be very complicated.
I hate my job.
Well,
do you have an alternative?
No.
Well,
why not?
I don't have a resume.
I hate being interviewed.
I'm afraid to make a resume.
I lost up my education.
Um,
I don't have any options.
It's like,
yeah,
that's a lot of problems man.
And that's,
you know,
those are strategic problems.
So then you have to figure out how to
help the PR person strategize and then
implement the strategies.
And so the next step is,
okay,
now we know your problems.
If you could have a solution like that
would be the opposite of the problem.
What might a solution looked like?
Same issue.
It's like,
well,
there's lots of solutions.
I don't know what to do with my life.
I don't know what job to have.
I don't know what person to,
um,
uh,
establish a long term intimate
relationship with,
I don't know what I would like to do
with my family.
I don't know how to use my time outside
of work.
I don't know how to resist temptation
like drug and alcohol abuse.
I don't know.
Um,
I don't know how to take care of myself
mentally and physically.
All of these complicated problems.
It's like,
okay,
let's sketch out a potential solution.
If you could have what you wanted.
So that would be a cure.
What would that look like?
We formalize this by the way,
in the future authoring process.
So if you do the future authoring
program,
which is part of the self authoring
suite,
it will guide you through doing this.
And it's unbelievably useful to do that
cause you're not going to hit what you
don't aim at.
So,
so then you,
you have the person lay out,
okay,
well where are we headed?
It's a map.
Now we know where we are and it's a
problem.
Now we have to figure out where we're
headed.
And so,
and then finally,
once we figure out where we're headed,
we have to figure out how to get there.
We have to make the map.
It's got a beginning place,
it's got an in place.
Now we have to map out the terrain.
So like,
well I didn't finish my degree or maybe
I didn't go to college or maybe I didn't
finish high school.
It's like,
well,
do you need a different job?
Yes.
Do you need a high school diploma to get
that?
Yes.
What steps do you have to take to get a
high school diploma?
Um,
maybe you have to start with one course,
right?
Okay.
Where do you find the course?
You'd go look it up online.
What things make you afraid to go back
to school?
Which of those things are stopping you?
How are you going to overcome those
fears?
So you take the large scale vision,
which is the place you're headed to in
the future.
That's the cure.
And then you break it down into the
strategic elements that are necessary to
be implemented on a day to day basis.
And you do that so that they're
difficult.
But attainable.
And then the person,
if they're not difficult,
then they're not worth attaining.
Obviously.
Obviously you're not pushing yourself
and you want the person not only to
develop in the direction they're
supposed to develop,
but you want to get them better at
developing.
So you want to push them just like you
do with kids or yourself if you have any
sense.
And so we'll break it down into small,
implementable daily processes and then
you review those with your,
with your client.
None of that's wallowing in self pity,
man.
Quite the contrary,
quite the contrary.
So,
so psychotherapy is get your story
together.
Who are you,
where you're going,
where are you going?
What's your strategy?
How are you going to learn to overcome
the frightening and unexpected things
that are going to pop up at you when you
implement that strategy?
So in those can be some of those things
can be the natural world.
I'm afraid of death,
I'm afraid of illness,
I'm afraid of insanity.
And some of those can be the social
world.
I'm afraid of my boss.
I'm afraid of my wife,
I'm afraid of my friends.
I'm afraid of being humiliated.
I'm afraid that people won't like me.
Those are the two big classes of fears,
right?
Fear of the Great Mother Nature,
fear of the great father culture.
And if you're really afraid,
you get to have both those fears at the
same time.
So there's nothing about that that's
wallowing in self pity.
Quite the contrary.
It's a bad therapist that does that.
They're not there to make,
to feel sorry for you.
They are there to be on the side of the
part of you that's aiming up and to
encourage you and to allow you to have a
space where you can lay out your
thoughts using your free speech to think
where you can lay out your thoughts
about what's wrong with you and how that
might be set right.
Has nothing to do with wallowing in self
pity.
I don't want to calculate high
resolution utopia for myself,
only to have it squandered by fortune.
How do I ensure the meaning I
experienced a self determined?
Well you can't because there's an
arbitrary element to existence.
So it is going to be squandered to some
degree by fortune,
but that's,
that's not the point.
What are you going to do?
Just sit back on your laurels and wait
for things to roll over you.
So what you do,
look,
the hero myth basically says,
go out there,
confront the drag,
get the gold,
share it with the community and,
and live properly.
Or it says the alternative.
He has faced the tyrant.
Enter the desert as a consequence
because everything falls apart.
Recast,
structure,
find the promise land.
Those are the two elements to the hero
myth and you might,
and that's divine.
It's the closest thing to divine that we
know.
You might say,
well,
what happens if you follow the divine
path?
And the answer might be,
well,
everything turns out perfectly because
God is on your side.
It's like,
no,
that isn't what happens because things
don't turn out perfectly.
It's your best bet.
It's your best strategy,
right?
That's the thing.
And you know,
dragons wouldn't be dragons if they
couldn't eat you.
And so,
but that's okay.
That's okay.
And this is something I found so useful
about the biblical stories,
especially about the abrahamic stories,
which I didn't know that well until I
lectured about them last year.
You know,
God calls people to the adventure of
their lives.
And so you could say in part,
God is that force within you,
which calls you to the adventure of your
life.
And it says,
get away from your family.
Get away from your blind and unconscious
comfort and get the hell out there in
the world.
Well,
God calls Abraham out from his father's
where he stayed far too long and from
his kin where it's secure and like the
first thing he encounters is a famine.
And then he encounters a tyranny
inhabited by people who want to steal
his wife.
It's like you think,
well,
Keith Abraham,
he should have just stayed in bed and
ignored God obviously.
Well,
that isn't how it is.
It's like we're built for struggle.
US human beings,
you're not after the bubbles of blessed
that does Dsq described in,
in notes from underground.
We're built to contend with the world.
We're built to contend with reality.
You want to challenge and the best way
that you can take on a challenge because
it challenged,
fortifies you.
So you don't want to be secure.
You want to be strong and you get strong
by taking on optimal challenges.
And so you lay out your destiny in the
world and you take the slings and arrows
of fate and you make yourself stronger
while you're doing so.
And you might fail and fortune might do
you in.
But it's your best bet.
And you know,
people have also people if that
extracted unbelievable successes out of
catastrophic failures.
And so,
and I'm not saying that in a naive way,
I know perfectly well what happens to
people.
You know,
you're doing fine in life and then you
get cancer and then six months later
your debt and all the heroism in the
world isn't going to save you at that
point.
But that's not the point.
That's not the point.
Life is bounded by mortality,
but that doesn't mean that you don't get
out there and contend and you develop by
contending and you minimize the net
amount of suffering in the world.
And that's something,
man,
that's something to do.
So it's,
it's,
it beats laying in your basement and
getting bitter and then doing the
terrible things that bitter people do.
So you can't ensure that the meaning you
experience his self determined,
but you can play your role to the best
of your ability and that will be good
enough and that will be good enough.
That meaning the meaning that you all
find in then in that I believe is
sufficient to be sustaining and perhaps
even sustaining through the flood.
So it isn't that you can avoid
catastrophe,
it's that you can prepare yourself to
deal with it honorably when it arrives.
That's what you've got.
I have very high order lead ness and low
industriousness.
23rd I have very high orderliness,
90th percentile,
low industriousness,
23rd percentile.
What can I do to remedy this and get a
higher industriousness?
Okay,
first of all,
that's not that low.
Okay,
we've got to think about percentiles
here for a minute.
Cause they're not percentages.
They're different.
So if you're at the 23rd percentile and
there were four people in a room,
you'd be the least industrious of four
of them and that kind of puts you in the
average range.
It's not that big of deal.
Um,
there's problems with it and we'll get
to that,
although you may,
maybe you're high in openness to it
anyways,
I won't get into that
low would be fifth percentile because
that makes you one in 20 or second
percentile cause that makes you one in
50.
It's kind of like interesting to v
visualize a fairly large high school
class and then to think of yourself as
situated in there.
If you're the least industrious person
out of 50,
that's going to be a problem.
You better be smart or have some other
things going for you because you're
going to have a hard time being diligent
enough to be successful.
Okay.
Having said that,
so and maybe first percentile makes you
one in a hundred and 0.0 0.1%.
It makes you one in a thousand.
So you got to think about percentiles
property.
Um,
so having said that,
let's say you're not very high and
industriousness,
what should you do?
A,
make a damn plan.
Okay,
you need a plan for your life.
And I would say use the future authoring
program because that will help you make
a plan or make a plan on your own.
That's fine.
Or make a plan because you talk to
someone.
But you know,
we put the future authoring program
together to help people develop a vision
of where they could be a counter vision
to scare the hell out of them by helping
them think through how catastrophic
things could become if they let all
their stupidities get the upper hand and
then a second part of the program that
helps you make a strategy.
And we know the future authoring program
helps people,
young men in particular who are doing
worse.
By the way,
in academic situations,
it increases the probability that they
will stay in college and university by
between 25 and 50%.
So make a damn plant and make when you
want.
Like don't make a plan.
That is what you should do even though
it will be what you should do.
Make a plan that outlines a future so
that you could sit back and say,
look,
if I had that future,
then all the horrible things that are
going to happen to me are going to be
worthwhile.
That's what you want.
Do you want to think this game is worth
playing despite its tragedy?
That's what you've got in life and now
for meaning to serve as an antidote to
tragedy.
All right now and then you generate a
strategy and then the other thing you
should do if you're not very
industrious,
industrious is disciplined yourself and
so what do you do with that?
Eat three times a day at regular meal
times.
That's a good thing to practice because
that starts to put some stability into
your life.
Get up at the same time.
I would highly recommend all those young
people out there who are listening like
you want to get a jump on life,
get the hell out of bed in the morning.
You know,
as I've got older,
I've got up earlier and earlier now.
That's partly because you don't need as
much sleep,
but it's also partly because I've got
more and more disciplined.
Like get up early in the morning and get
your things done,
man.
Learn to get up at six in the morning
and you'll be one deadly creature,
especially if you can get to work.
You'll have half your damn day down by
the time other people haul their story
houses out of bed.
And so that's a massive,
massive advantage.
Look will pharrel Warren Farrell,
not the comedian Warren Farrell,
the author.
He outlined data in why men earn more,
which is a book I would recommend,
by the way,
showing that if you work 13% longer
hours,
you make 40% more money and it's
nonlinear.
So you think,
why is that?
Well,
imagine you had 10 employees and one of
them works and extra 10% it's not much.
Well,
how often is that person going to be
promoted,
assuming you have a clue as a boss,
it's like you're going to look at the 10
people and you gotta think,
well,
that guy's always here like 45 minutes
early.
It's like,
why don't we give him the promotion,
obviously,
right?
So these tied these small edges that you
can manage like that work an extra 10%
extra,
13% have non-proportional payoffs.
That's part of the parade.
Oh distribution.
So get,
get your sleep cycle organized.
So you get up in the morning,
learn how to do it.
No excuses.
I'm too tired in the morning.
I don't like mornings.
Who Cares?
That's not relevant.
It's like discipline yourself so you can
manage it.
Schedule your meals cause that's a good
disciplinary routine.
And then learn to use a calendar like
Google calendar.
Most of you,
many of you out there do not use a
calendar.
Okay?
A calendar is not a prison and it's not
a tyrant,
not if you use it properly.
A calendar keeps anxiety at bay.
It makes sure that you do what you need
to do,
which is important because otherwise you
fall behind.
But if you use it property though,
it's also helps you plan what you want
to do.
So I could say,
well Leo,
your damn calendar and designed the days
you would like to have.
That's what your calendar is.
Ha is four.
So you can put in all sorts of things in
there you want to do and that would be
good for you.
And that's a really good,
a really good way to start being more
industrious,
make a plan.
You need a plan for three years,
you need a plan for the next year,
you need to plan for the next six
months,
you need to plan for the next three
months.
You need a plan for the week,
you need a plan for the day,
you need to plan for the hour,
all of that,
all of that.
I make lists constantly of what I have
to do and they're like daily,
weekly,
monthly,
yearly.
Right now I can't look out more than
about six months,
you know,
cause my life is too complicated and
chaotic.
But,
but you need a vision of who you could
be,
what character you could have three to
five years out.
You can't go much farther than that
because life is too unpredictable.
I think to make vision,
that's longer term than that subject
too.
There's too much chance associated with
it to spend a lot of time on.
Maybe you can stretch it to five years
and in rare cases you can have a 10 year
goal,
but it has to be pretty low resolution.
But you want plans at all those levels
of resolution.
You want to write the things down and
what,
because what are you gonna do?
You're gonna Stumble around and get,
get what you need.
You're going to stumble around and be
useful to other people.
And it's useful to be useful to other
people.
You know,
they want to work with you,
then they want to do things with you.
They want to have you around,
they trust you,
they open up opportunities for you.
And if you stumble around,
like you're blind,
you're not gonna get anywhere and then
you're going to suffer and then you're
going to be bitter and then you're going
to be cruel.
So that's a bay.
That's hell.
That's a bad outcome.
So unless you want that,
don't aim for it.
And or,
or aim for the opposite because that's
how you get out of it.
So
physical attractiveness is extensively
studied in departments of psychology.
How big of a determinant of success is
it apart from Iq or any of the other big
five traits?
Um,
that's tough.
One because physical attractiveness is a
very complex trait.
Um,
it's also,
for example,
it's a marker of health and of course
health is a mar is a prerequisite for
success.
So,
um,
I you can't take attractiveness as a
unitary dimension and measure it
sufficiently accurately.
Wait,
I should back up on that.
No one that I know of has taken physical
attractiveness as a unitary concept,
measured it accurately and then pitted
against Iq and the big five to see if
it,
to what degree it adds incremental
validity to the prediction of longterm
success,
but physical,
but,
and so I can't give you a technical
answer.
You know,
I can say,
well,
in a complex job over the long run Iq
accounts for maybe 20% of the variance
in success leaving 80% therefore random
events and,
and the big five traits and connection
networks and,
and family background and all those
other things,
gender perhaps that all the other things
that determine success,
physical a true,
we know that physical,
that people who are physically
attractive though are given the benefit
of doubt by other people.
They,
they benefit from the positive halo
effect.
And the positive halo effect is the
propensity of people to assume good
things about someone.
If there is one outstanding thing about
them that's easily evident,
that's good.
And so if you're,
if you're,
if you stand up straight with your
shoulders back,
so that's rule one and 12 rules for
life,
then people are going to see you as more
attractive.
If you're symmetrical,
you're more attractive.
If you're thin but not too thin,
Wow.
And then there's like good skin and good
teeth and good heroin and all of those
things in proper proportions and youth.
And there's a whole slew of things that,
that,
that feed into that if you are
characterized by a plethora of those
features,
then people are also going to assume
that you're more competent and more and
more,
more worth having around let's say.
But the problem is,
is that you are,
so separating out the attractiveness
from the things the attractiveness are,
is correlated with is very hard.
That's why you have to do multivariate
analysis.
That's multivariable analysis in any
complex social science because a lot of
these traits overlap.
So,
but you know,
you can,
there's,
there's some,
some things you can do about that.
Postural adjustment is helpful to work
out with weights.
That's extraordinarily helpful that that
increases,
improves your posture and makes you more
confident and,
and,
and at,
and you can dress reasonably well and
intelligently and,
um,
all of those things too,
to help yourself capitalize on whatever
attractiveness you can muster.
So
what is your view on psychological
egoism?
If we're all ultimately acting out of
self interest,
then does altruism have any merit?
I don't think the questions well post
and that's,
it's one of those questions that leads
into a philosophical,
a dead end because it's not well post
you.
There isn't any such thing as self
interest.
It's not the right way to think about it
because you're not alone.
And so this is why like piaget,
John Piaget cause he thought about this
intelligently look first of all who self
interest you meet.
Do you mean your immediate self interest
in the next second.
So that would be impulsive pleasure.
We're all acting for the gaining of
impulsive pleasure and to hell with
everything else.
Well obviously that's a stupid way to
behave because everyone knows that
because you can do impulsive,
short term gratifying things like snort
cocaine now and you can keep doing that
and it pay off real,
real well in the extremely short term
and they'll just auger you into the
ground in the medium to long term.
So if you're acting in your own self
interest,
let's take that apart over what period
of time.
Okay.
Your self interest in the next second.
You're self interest in the next hour.
Like,
if you're impulsive and you want to
gratify an impulse,
you're obviously acting in your self
interest in the next second or the next
two seconds or the next minute.
But you know,
you'll pay for that.
Maybe you punch someone or you slap
someone cause you're so angry and they,
you know,
and they knock you for a loop and then
they charge you with assault.
You know,
so well it was great in your self
interest in the second,
but like future,
remember that simpsons episode,
homer drank a quarter manet's and vodka
and margin,
all his kids were telling him not to and
he said,
well that's a problem for future homer.
I sure don't envy that guy.
It's like,
which is one of the best Simpson's lines
ever,
I think.
And well that's it.
Exactly.
It's like,
well there isn't just you.
There's,
there's now you and there's tonight you
and there's tomorrow morning you,
that's the one that'll have the hangover
by the way.
And there's next week you and next month
and next year you and old you.
And so if you're going to act in your
self interest,
you have to take that collective of use
across time into account when you make
your decision.
And now here's the cool thing about
that.
So then that say,
well that would be acting in your self
interest writ large,
right across times pounds.
But the thing is future you and someone
else that you have to live with right
now that's not,
you are pretty much the same people.
And so if you're going to act in your
self interest and you have other people
around you,
then you also want to act in their self
interest because otherwise they won't
like you,
they won't cooperate with you and they
won't compete with you in a reasonable
manner.
And so that's going to be a catastrophe.
And so you want to act out what's good
for you now and what's good for you next
month and next year,
and you want to do that in a way that's
good for you and your family and your
community right now,
next week and next year,
and you're going to take all those
things into account at the same time.
That's an equivalent rated game from
[inaudible] perspective,
and it was his idea that that
constituted the basis for proper moral
judgment and it's a brilliant idea.
It's a brilliant idea.
And so that's your true self interest.
There's no difference between your
interest in the interest of others,
not in any fundamental sense,
even your enemies,
which is why you're enjoying to treat
your enemy as if he was yourself,
because he is,
you know,
and you think,
well,
you should wish,
you should wish your enemies well.
Well,
why?
it isn't that you hope they get a bigger
house than you.
It's that.
Let's say you're,
you're being pursued and tormented by
someone who's truly reprehensible.
That person is,
they have a miserable life,
man.
In all likelihood.
Let's say they're truly malevolent,
you know they live in hell and what you
might hope for them is that they could
figure out how to get out of there cause
it's not good for them and it's not good
for anyone else think,
well even your enemies,
it's like wouldn't it be good if they
could get their act together and stop
being so unnecessarily malevolent?
And that's in your self interest.
So the idea that your self interest is
somehow opposed to other people's or
that if you maximize yourself interest,
you're not operating in the best
interest of other people is predicated
on a poor idea of what constitutes
yourself interest.
Cause you're not separate in any real
sense from other people.
You maybe not separate from everything
in some real sense.
You know,
I mean young,
young in his book mysterium [inaudible]
he had this idea,
I'm going to go through it real quick.
It's a complicated idea that this is how
you put yourself together.
The first thing you do is you,
you join your emotions and your,
and your rationality.
So that,
so that your mind and your emotions are
one thing he called that the first
conjunction.
Um,
so that your motivations and your
emotions and the way that you think
about the world are all acting in the
same direction.
Okay?
So that's the first conjunction.
And you get your act together that way.
So that would mean incorporation of
aggression and sexuality from a Freudian
perspective,
those parts of you that are difficult to
integrate come to be integrated into one
thing.
So you can use your anger when you need
to and you have your sexuality under
control.
It doesn't have you,
but you know how to use it.
And it's a power for you.
Um,
and,
and you're properly assertive in all of
those things.
And so you build yourself into one
psychological unit and then you embody
that.
So that's the second conjunction.
The second conjunction is take your
mind,
emotion,
motivation,
unity,
and acted out,
acted out in the world so that there's
no distinction between you and what you
do between you and the way you think
about the world and your philosophy and
how you act.
That makes you a second kind of unity.
And then the final conjunction,
which is the most difficult one,
is to stop thinking that the world is
different than you are.
This is why I ask people to clean up the
rooms just like your room is you,
it's you.
And so you go in there and you clean up
your room,
your cleaning you up to the same way
you're developing discipline,
you're putting yourself in order,
you're developing a vision of the
future.
You're figuring out how to dress,
you're figuring out how to take care of
your things.
You're interacting with the micro cosmos
that you have in front of you and
learning how to balance chaos and order.
There's no difference between you and
what's around you.
And that's a very difficult thing to
understand.
And so you want to act in a way that's
good for you.
But good for everything else at the same
time and that's,
that's a high moral virtue and that,
so there is there.
Okay,
that's the right way of thinking about
the relationship between psychological
egoism and altruism.
It's like if you're,
as you move towards a broader
conceptualization of things,
you start to understand that there is no
selfish selfish.
There is no selfish self interest isn't
how life works.
Like if you're married to someone for
example,
and you're stuck with them for the next
50 years,
it's like you can't win an argument with
them.
You can make peace because there you
man,
there you,
there are a huge part of your
experience.
You have to treat that person as if they
are you.
And then if it's not,
it isn't like,
well I'm going to treat you well because
you're me.
It's not because people don't treat
themselves very well.
Often it's way more complicated than
that.
You just,
you don't want to defeat your wife man,
because then you live with a defeated
wife and if you think she isn't going to
take revenge on you,
then you're,
you're not very bright.
So you want to listen to what she has to
say and you want to listen to her
problems and you want to help her solve
them because she's you and you want to
do the same with your kids and then you
want to do the same with the people
around you if you can do it.
So and so the whole idea of like,
well we're basically wired to be
selfish.
Well we are when we're not very wise and
we act impulsively.
But as your view of the world broadens,
you start to understand that this is why
in the Buddhist philosophy,
no Buddha attained nirvana.
So that meant he could stay in union
with the gods so to speak.
He,
he attained the highest form of,
of subjective experience with might be
but which might be something like
totally immersion in bliss and meaning.
But he rejected it because he went back
into the world to help other people
attain nirvana or at least to move
towards it because he realized that
there was no individual redemption
without the redemption of all.
And you,
if you don't understand that,
then you're just not very wise.
And so you're trying to be a force for
good in the world.
And that doesn't mean just good for you.
That's just,
it's just blind because there isn't any
isolated you that isn't how things are,
that is now realities lays itself out.
So what is your current thinking on
Orthodox Christianity?
The Orthodox Christians like me,
I don't know why,
but I think I have some idea,
I guess.
Um,
I've got a lot of letters from religious
people,
a lot of lot from,
from Muslims,
from Jews,
uh,
from Orthodox Jews in particular,
strangely enough,
um,
from Christian monks,
monks.
Um,
but a lot from Orthodox Christians.
And I think the reason for that,
as far as I can tell is that the
Orthodox look at Christianity from a
slightly different angle than the
Protestants and the Catholics.
And I'm not putting down the Protestants
and the Catholics,
they have a perspective,
a reason for their viewpoint.
But what's happened in the west,
I think,
and this is a dreadful over
simplification,
so please forgive me,
is that the West has viewed Christianity
more as a set of beliefs that are
analogous in some sense to a cognitive
theory of the world.
So to be a Christian in the West,
you have to accept that Christ died for
your sins and that you're redeemed.
So you have to accept Christ as your
redeemer.
And that really means to state that you
believe a set of propositions about
Christ,
that he was the son of God and that his
death and resurrection,
his sacrifice redeemed mankind and that,
and then you partake in that redemption
by laying out that co that accordance
with a set of facts,
let's say.
I don't,
I understand why that's how it's worked
out,
but I think there's a big risk in that.
And I don't think the Orthodox fell into
that to the same degree.
Their idea more,
and this is their products in
protestantism and Catholicism to,
it's there,
but it's,
it's given more secondary,
more implicit emphasis.
And I think that's a problem,
especially in the modern world.
There are Orthodox would say as near as
I can tell that you should pick up your
Damn Cross and stumble up the hill.
That's your job,
right?
And the cross is the x where everyone is
located.
You're right at the center of reality,
your suffering and dying and being
reborn all the time at the center of
reality,
as you transform and you have to accept
that and embrace it,
you have,
and that's very,
very hard thing to do because it means
to embrace all your flaws and the flaws
of reality and the tragedy of existence
and your death and the sum total of
human evil,
all of that unbelievably demanding
requirement.
But you do what you can to do that.
And then not only do you pick up your
cross so to speak,
but you stumble up hill towards the city
of God.
Do you stumble up towards what's good
and that's your destiny and that's where
meaning is to be had.
And the Orthodox lay that out quite
well.
That's your goal is the imitation of
Christ and Christ is the logos.
This is the Christian story.
Christ is the logos that God uses,
that the beginning of time to transform
pre cosmic gone chaos into habitable
order,
truthful speech.
So that's the thing,
you're,
you're the fact that you're capable of
uttering truthful speech is an
indication that you shouldered your
cross and are stumbling up hill.
A very coherent theory.
And the Orthodox I think have done a
very good job of keeping that idea at
the forefront of their,
of their belief.
And so that's what I think about
Orthodox Christianity.
Do I have any thoughts on the Myers
Briggs personality test?
Yes.
It's old.
It isn't psychometrically valid.
It wasn't derived by factor analytic
techniques.
It should be replaced by the big five or
the big five aspect scale,
which you can use if you go to
understand myself.
Dot Com we put it online for people to
use and to generate a personality
report.
Um,
Myers and briggs attempted to make a
questionnaire predicated on union
presuppositions and perhaps they did a
fine job for the 1930s,
but that was a long time ago and there
weren't any powerful computational
devices of the kind that were necessary
to sort out the structure of personality
properly,
which we've managed to do since about
1960 onward.
So now the Myers Briggs is a perfectly
useful tool if what you want to do is
get people to talk about the fact that
there are individual differences in
personality and corporations love it
because no one gets offended by it
because everyone wins.
But if you want a personality tests that
actually tells you who you are that's
valid and reliable,
then you use the big five.
And,
and that's that.
And so I would say the Myers Briggs
should be relegated to the dustbins of
the past because it's a defunct and
archaic instrument and it's no longer
properly valid.
And so,
um,
that's that.
Yeah.
How can women who waited too long to
have children find meaning in their
lives once they realized their mistake?
How can we cope with the regret?
Jesus.
That's a hard question.
Well,
you know,
there are other avenues to meaning,
right?
I mean
that's,
that's the first thing to realize is
that there are,
there's intimate relationship,
there's familial relationships that
aren't in accordance with children.
There's other people that you can serve.
There are other children that you can
serve.
So what you have to do,
because intimate relationships are so
important,
and I'm including that close familial,
I'm not talking about sexual
relationships,
I'm talking about very close social
relationships.
The thing about having children,
if you're lucky,
is that you have a relationship there of
a depth that you don't get anywhere else
with the possible exception of your
parents and siblings and your partner.
But there's something about the child
relationship that's even more
fundamental because the thing about
having a child is that if you have any
sense,
as soon as you have a child,
you are no longer the most important
person,
right?
You're no longer the person that you
have primary responsibility for.
It's now your child.
And that produces a psychological
transformation and it produces a
relationship of a depth that can't be
easily duplicated elsewhere.
But it's not like that's the only thing
that there is to do in life.
You know,
there,
there are other relationships and I
would say what you do is you foster them
to the degree that that's possible and
maybe you could find other kids to
serve.
You know,
there's always the possibility of
volunteering for hospitals or,
or,
or working in places where children need
service.
So that's a possibility as well.
And so you've,
you know,
there are,
there are a variety of sources of
meaning in people's lives and they're,
they're not unlimited.
You know,
there's career,
there's education,
there's what you do that's meaningful,
meaningfully engages you outside of
work.
There's your social relations,
your friends and so forth.
And so maybe you have five lakes lakes
to stand on and you missed one cause he
didn't have kids.
Or maybe you missed too because kids are
a big deal.
But that doesn't mean the rest of them
aren't accessible to you.
And so you optimize your functioning
along the dimensions that are left to
you.
And then I would also say maybe you try
to forgive yourself a little bit.
You know,
like it's very difficult to go through
life without,
without regrets,
without making mistakes.
You know,
when you can't beat yourself to death
for it because then everyone would beat
themselves to death all the time.
And so you think,
well that's,
that's I've,
I'm,
I'm too soon old and too late wise to
use an old cliche and you think,
well that's the lot of mankind.
We learn things too late often and
that's too bad and you forgive yourself
because you're stupid and you don't know
what you're doing and you're unwise just
like everyone else.
And maybe you're somewhat capable of
learning if you're careful.
And then you go out and you try to
foster relations and do good in the
world to the degree that you can outside
of the necessity of,
of children.
And maybe you have nephews,
nieces and can lavish some attention on
them and find your substitute where you
can.
But I would say to forgive yourself is a
big part of that.
It's like people make mistakes,
big mistakes.
And the people that I've watched through
life that have been successful,
it's not like they didn't make mistakes
because everyone makes mistakes and they
do things they regret and they miss
opportunities and it's a bloody
catastrophe.
But they treat themselves with some
degree of mercy along with the justice.
It's like,
yeah,
well I screwed up there and I'm going to
try to learn and I'm not going to do it
again,
but I'm not going to beat myself to
death so that I can't get up again.
And so you do what you can to forgive
yourself.
You know,
it's a confusing time to live in in many
ways because we have the birth control
pill now and that means reproduction has
now become voluntary.
Well,
when's a good time to reproduce?
never,
because who would ever think about doing
that?
It's so ridiculously irrational and
complicated and the burden of
responsibility is so insanely high and
you never secure enough to,
to have the proper place to bring
children into the world and you have to
get your career going and your and your
intimate relationship.
And maybe you have some struggle doing
that.
And one day you wake up and it's a bit
late.
It's like,
yeah,
well you're a product of your time and
one of the prices that we're going to
pay for having birth control for having
reliable contraception is that some
people are going to make the wrong
decision with regards to having
children.
And then you view yourself as a product
of your time.
And that's a catastrophe,
you know,
because to be a product of your time is
in some ways a catastrophe.
So,
but there's other things to do in life
and,
and augering yourself into the ground
with regret and,
and,
and self recrimination is not useful.
Right?
I mean,
you have to learn your lesson,
you have to take your lumps,
all of that,
but have some mercy.
You know?
That's it.
You have said that the only moral
absolute is always to tell the truth.
What if you have anne frank in the attic
and the Gestapo at your on your
doorstep,
then I would say that there has been a
lot of lies that have got you to that
point.
So you may be in a situation where
you're damned if you turn right and
you're damned if you turn left.
And what that means is you made a lot of
mistakes along the way.
You know,
so if the totalitarians or knocking at
your door,
if the totalitarians or knocking on
everyone's door,
that means everyone should have spoke up
a lot sooner.
And then they wouldn't end up in a
situation where the Gestapo was out the
door and Anne Frank was in the owl is it
was in the attic.
So you now and then you end up in a
situation where you've made so many
mistakes that all you've got is hell
around you.
And that was certainly the case in
Amsterdam say,
or and in,
in when the Nazis came in on,
I mean the Dutch are now admirable
people and I know they were invaded by
the Nazis and that was a terrible thing.
But many,
many,
many people made many terrible moral
errors for all of that to occur.
And you have to be awake and do
everything you can to make sure your
society doesn't.
This is the answer.
You be away.
Can you make sure everything you society
does doesn't lead to the point where the
Gestapo at your doorstep and you have
Anne Frank in the attic,
it's a little late to be thinking.
Then I would say,
well I have confidence in an opinion
when it could be wrong.
Well partly because it could be right.
You know what?
That's why it's better to think about
opinions as tools,
you know or maybe to dispense with
opinions altogether because who cares
about your stupid opinion but what you
want is tools to work in the world and
you think,
well I have a tool and it might work.
So like let's say that you're going into
negotiate with someone while you're your
tool kit is your conceptual,
the conceptual structure and the habits
that you have that enable you to
construe the situation and to conduct
the negotiation.
Well,
you have to have confidence that your,
that your tool kit is appropriate or you
wouldn't go out there and test it and
you'd say,
well,
I might be wrong.
It's like,
yeah,
but you're not going to learn if you're
wrong.
Unless you go out there and test it.
So you have to have provisional.
Okay
look,
let's say that you're um,
well let's say that you're using a
hammer to hammer in a nail and you
think,
well,
am I going to hit the nail?
Well you aim at the nail and you hit it
and you watch.
And if you didn't hit it quite right,
then you aim a little different.
You know,
so you have enough confidence to swing
the hammer.
But that doesn't mean you're not paying
attention to the outcome.
So you want to have confident,
and maybe this is the best answer,
you don't want to have confidence in the
opinion.
Exactly.
You want it how you want to believe in
the necessity of moving forward in the
world with your limited tool kit.
And also
you want to make the the vow.
Let's say that as you implement your
tools in the world,
that you're going to pay attention to
what happens and you're going to modify
them as necessary as you move along.
That's the adoption of the hero myth
again,
cause that's,
you know,
let's say your opinion is a little
screwy and so you laid out in the world
and you get responses that aren't
positive.
It's like you think,
oh,
okay,
well that didn't work out quite right.
I'll go retool my opinion.
And so you,
you move out into the world,
not as a collection of opinions,
but as a collection of tools and as the
process that can re cast those tools.
And then you think,
well,
it's not so much that I have confidence
in my opinions.
I have,
I know that they're necessary to express
them because sometimes the work and if
they don't work then I can learn.
And that's,
and that's the recipe for forthright
action in the world.
Okay.
Our daughter entered her life at 24 due
to depression.
If someone is determined to end their
life,
how can one change their mind?
Oh,
first of all,
I'm very sorry about that.
That's a terrible thing.
Look,
I had this friend
her,
sorry.
There's been a lot of depression in our
family.
So it's a question that cuts close to
the bone.
Okay.
Anyways,
I had this friend,
a friend of my parents and her grand
daughter committed suicide,
you know,
she was just beating herself up about
what could have I done,
what could have I done differently?
This is the problem with suicide leaves
everybody behind thinking,
Oh my God,
what could've I done?
I could have treated the person better.
I could have listened.
I could've been there.
It's like,
and she was just beating yourself up
about this really feeling that she
wasn't a useful person,
that she'd failed as a grandmother.
She's a really good person,
you know?
And so I went for a walk with her and I
said,
she's married and she likes her husband
and he's a really good guy.
And I said,
look,
you're,
you're blaming yourself for the,
for your granddaughter,
suicide.
It's like,
are you blaming your husband?
Are you sitting him down and telling him
what to use?
Useless bastard.
He was as a grandfather because his
grand daughter committed suicide and how
he failed completely.
She said,
no,
I'd never do that.
So I said,
well,
don't do it to yourself.
No people.
Depression was a terrible thing and
many,
many things cause it and we don't
understand.
We understand some of them,
but lots of them,
we don't understand it all.
You know,
sometimes people get depressed because
they're really sick.
We know that depression could be an
inflammatory disease,
it might be associated with audio,
immune dysfunction.
There's lots of reasons that people get
depressed and depressed.
People can go places that are so dark,
you just cannot imagine it.
And it isn't necessarily the case that
you can always rescue someone,
you know,
and but,
but drowning yourself in the aftermath
of a suicide is not helpful.
So there's a,
there's a good room for self forgiveness
there.
You know,
I mean maybe you did some things you
shouldn't have done that were
reprehensible in all of that,
but you don't want to beat yourself up.
Remember the presumption of innocence,
right?
Innocent until proven guilty and you
have to apply that to yourself.
I don't think.
I think there are times when people are
so depressed there,
there isn't anything that anyone can do.
You know when the depressed person
thinks,
and this is probably the worst part of
it,
the depressed person thinks
everywhere I look,
it's nothing but catastrophe and
there's,
I can't see any way out of it.
I can't see any path forward whatsoever.
And then they think as well,
and maybe it's the combination of these
two thoughts that that really make
people suicidal.
It's like it's hopeless.
It isn't going to get any better.
No matter where I turn.
There's no escape.
The suffering is unbearable and I have
absolutely no use whatsoever.
Do anyone.
It would be better for everyone if I was
just gone because I'm going,
if I'm not so much of a burden now that
it's going to destroy their life,
then I'm going to be that much of a
burden in the future.
And so it's hard to imagine what that's
like for people,
but it's dreadful and there's lots of
ways you get there and so
you can listen to people.
You can desperately encouraged them to
seek the help they need.
You know,
like I've,
I've seen antidepressants work miracles
on very,
very many people now.
They don't work for everyone and they're
not a panacea,
but you know,
they have side effects and all of that.
But one of the side effects of untreated
depression is that you kill yourself and
there is no recovery from that.
And the are,
the probability is actually rather high.
So you can go to war with them about
antidepressants.
If the person can't get out of their
depression and their,
and their suicidal,
it's like,
what did they have to lose one month on
antidepressants?
They'll know,
oh,
they might have to experiment longer
because it would depend on,
you know,
some people respond better to some
classes of antidepressants than the
others.
Um,
it's worth having a war with someone if
they're in dire straits and they won't
do everything they can to get better.
ECT works.
Electric convulsive therapy works for
intractable depression.
It's a terrible thing to contemplate,
but the modern versions of ect aren't
one flew over the cuckoo's nest.
And again,
it's like there's no coming back from
death.
So look,
it isn't clear.
You can't rescue everyone.
People get sick and they die,
and sometimes the way they die,
it looks like it's depression.
Depression is a multifaceted phenomena.
You can be there for them.
You can listen,
you can watch,
you can intervene,
you can try to understand,
you can hold them accountable.
You can do all of those things but that,
but everyone has their own destiny,
you know,
and you're not omnipotent.
And so sometimes it catastrophe occurs
like your daughters and
then,
and then you should try to drag the
least amount of misery forward that you
can
once you recover from your grief.
Yup.
I'm going to answer one more question.
Due to a recent incident.
My company is making me undergo implicit
bias training.
How should I come to terms with my
possible firing when I refuse?
Look,
there's no sense in burning yourself at
the steak.
You know,
if you're going to take a principled
stance on something at work and you're
going to refuse,
you have to get your tools in order.
You have to get your quiver full of
arrows.
You know,
what the hell good is it going to be for
you just to get fired?
I maybe have a family that depends on
you.
That's not helpful.
That doesn't mean I think you should be
weak because you have a family.
You should be stronger.
I would say.
Is your resume in order?
Is Your CV in order?
Is it updated?
Have you sent out other job
applications?
Are you prepared?
Do you have a lateral move?
Like this is a war,
not a battle.
And you don't want to lose.
And so set yourself up and then make
your case.
And when you make your case,
don't apologize,
but don't do it carelessly.
You know you,
you need a lateral move because
otherwise you're too exposed.
So,
and if you're going to refuse,
have your arguments at at hand,
you know,
have them in writing.
Make sure that you share them with the
appropriate people.
Don't make unnecessary enemies
and do yourself the least amount of harm
possible.
Now look,
having said that,
you know,
so you're going to,
you're going to pay,
you're either going to pay and you're
going to go do implicit bias training
and you're going to sell a bit of your
soul to do that.
Are you going to pay because you're
going to refuse and you're going to take
that price.
So you got priced to pay both ways.
If you're going to refuse,
do it intelligently,
do it programmatically.
Do it philosophically.
Do it strategically,
right?
Stupid martyrdom is just stupid
martyrdom.
It's not helpful.
So there may be people you need to talk
to.
There may need to be more than one of
you,
you know,
so you may need to make contact with the
press.
Like you got to be strategic about this.
You got to be intelligent about it.
You don't want to just let yourself in
fire and out of protest because maybe
there'll just be a pile of ashes that
people sweep up and go on with their
idiocy.
So,
all right,
everyone.
Okay.
Nice talking with you all.
Thank you for the questions.
Um,
come and see me if you want.
If you go to Jordan Peterson,
Jordan B.
Peterson Dotcom,
you can see the upcoming events.
Um,
they've gone,
they've been going real well.
I'll talk about my book and about all
the other things that I'm thinking
about,
or not all of them,
but some of the other things that I'm
thinking about am I tried to make every
talk different.
Um,
even though,
you know,
the outline is the same cause I'm
talking about my book.
Um,
I guess that's about it.
Thank you for all the patrons support.
I know it's been a little while since
this last q and a.
Um,
that's life,
I guess at the moment.
Um,
and I'll try to do one within the next
month.
I'm on the road law.
They'll probably do it with my laptop.
So,
um,
what should I say in closing?
Get your act together much as you can.
There's things to do in the world and it
would be good if everyone was out there
doing them with see how we could beat
this old globe back into some reasonable
shape or into better shape than it's
ever been.
That would be lovely thing to do.
So
goodbye for now.