So last time
we talked a little bit about
the state of the world of belief I
suppose by the end of the 19th century.
And I talked to you a little bit about
Nietzsche and Dostoevsky and
Kierkegaard,
um,
a
very large number of the clinical
theories that we're going to be
discussing for another two lectures
after this one have been influenced by
philosophers.
And that's partly why I'm also talking
to you about the philosophers.
Um,
it's almost as if in some sense the
great philosophers have our tap directly
into the lower strata of the park are
our cultural systems of meaning as they
move forward in time and they can
outline what those structures are and
also describe their weaknesses and their
strengths and their likely
transformations moving forward.
You know,
I mean obviously people can be behind
the times and just as it's just as
probable that some people are ahead of
the times.
And we would assume,
if you're thinking about it,
say from a big five trait perspective,
that the people who are ahead of the
times often are very,
very intelligent and very,
very open.
And of course that's a pretty good
definition of a philosopher.
So
Nietzsche and Dostoevsky,
I think more than any other two
thinkers,
had their finger on the pulse of the
transmutation of cultural systems of
meaning in the at the end of the 19th
century.
And they were both very concerned about
the fact that
the systems of meaning within which
Western civilization at least had taken
shape,
had been fragmented for a variety of
reasons.
The most important of which was likely
the rise of the scientific world view.
And as I detailed to you in the last
lecture,
both Dostoyevsky and Nichi believed that
that had left modern people.
Because I think in the early 20th
century it was Western people.
But now I think it's reasonable to say
that it's modern people in a state of
their,
their cultural discontinuity,
that things,
belief systems,
but also technological systems now have
transformed the world so radically that
the conflict between modernism and
traditional forms of belief is acutely
felt everywhere.
It's certainly,
I think one of the forces that have
given rise to the battle between Islamic
fundamentalism and modernism because
it's more of that than a battle of
Islamic fundamentalism against the
Western world.
And the problem fundamentally is,
is that people typically exist within
cultural constructs that are very,
very ancient and that have,
that are grounded in,
in evolved systems of meaning that that
are even deeper than the ones that are
articulated and explicit.
And when there's a period of very,
very rapid cognitive and technological
change than the integrity of those
systems starts to,
it starts to become questionable from an
explicit perspective,
but it also starts to become
insufficient from a practical
perspective.
So one example that you might give some
consideration to is the fact of the
introduction of the birth control pill.
For example,
no one,
if you listen to politically minded
people,
they make the case that the
emancipation of women was essentially a
political matter.
But I don't think that that's a very
reasonable way of looking at it at all.
Of course,
the things,
everything feeds back onto itself and
there are multiple causal pathways to
any end.
The radical element in the emancipation
of women was of course the development
of efficient forms of contraception,
most particularly the birth control
pill.
And it's the case that as soon as you
educate women anywhere in the world,
not only does economic productivity rise
dramatically,
in fact,
it's actually the best predictor of
increase in economic predict
productivity in a modernizing state is
the granting of rights to women.
Now,
whether it's directly because of the
granting of rights to women or because
of the existence of an underlying belief
structure that allows the concept of
right to expand quite rapidly,
it's very difficult to be sure of.
But in any case that exists.
And then of course the other thing that
happens is that women stop having
children unbelievably rapidly.
So for example,
I think,
I believe it's Iran
where this has been most market over the
last two generations.
So from family sizes far greater than
replacement,
two family sizes,
well below replacement in basically one
or two generations.
It's a massive transformation and it's
not necessarily something that anyone
expected.
It's part of the sequence of forces that
are
rapidly allowing our population to reach
a peak and then either stabilize or
decline.
I don't know how many of you know this,
but the projections are that there'll be
9 billion people on the earth within 30
to 50 years.
And that'll be our peak population after
that,
it will fall rapidly.
And you know,
you can see that sort of thing happening
right now all over the western world.
And it's happening a lot in China and
it's happening in Japan where you know,
there are more older people than there
are younger people because the younger
people aren't having enough children to
actually replace the population.
So the probability that we'll peak at
about 9 billion and then start to fall,
it's not certain,
but that's what the best projections
seemed to indicate now.
Oh,
so what happens anyways with in periods
of very rapid technological and and
cognitive transformation,
because those things go together,
that the,
the certainties upon which people base
their interpretation of the world and
even more importantly base their
judgments about how to act start to
become uncertain.
So,
for example,
if you introduced the birth control pill
into a population and you put,
um,
women's reproductive faculties under
their own voluntary choice,
then you radically transform virtually
all of societies.
Fundamental social structures,
not least marriage and marriage of
course,
is being regarded classically as the
foundation of civilization.
And of course,
increasingly there are more people who
aren't married then there are people who
are married now.
It's very difficult to know what to make
of that because of course there's no
setting the clock back and
it's not even clear that you would want
to set back the clock if you could.
But expecting cultural constructs,
which take centuries or maybe even
thousands or maybe even tens of
thousands of years to develop,
to keep up with change of that magnitude
is it's not possible.
You know what I mean?
And you guys face technological
transformations that are earth
shattering on an almost yearly basis and
you hardly even notice it.
I mean,
tinder is a good example of that.
You know,
I don't know if you know,
but tinder has produced quite a spike in
sexually transmitted diseases.
But you know,
it's a radical technology because it's
the first technology that's ever been
invented that enables men to find
partners with no fear,
with virtually no fear of rejection.
And of course that's been a limiting
factor for,
that's been a defining feature of the
interactions between men and women ever
since history began.
And so these things are occurring at an
extraordinary rate and of course it's,
it's not reasonable to expect are more
slower moving cultural constructs to
keep up with them.
And that's partly because as well that,
you know,
people talk for example,
about the divisive nature of religion.
You,
you often hear people who are critics of
formal religion in particular talk about
the fact that religion,
underwire underlies a tremendous amount
of destruction and warfare and conflict.
And you know,
first of all,
it isn't religion that does that.
By the way,
it's tribalism.
Tribalism characterizes even
chimpanzees.
And I don't think chimpanzees go to war
with each other for religious reasons.
So,
you know,
the religious groupings of mankind are
our large scale manifestations of the
same phenomena that produce dominance,
hierarchies in the wild.
And of course large scale religions
unite people within the religion just as
much as they divide people on the
outside of it.
So part of the accumulation of religious
tradition across time is a process that
allows thousands and 10 thousands and
even millions of people to exist within
the same hierarchy of values and exist
relatively peacefully.
As a consequence.
Now I'm saying relatively peacefully,
you know,
a hundred years ago it was thought that
pre let's say let's say archaic people.
So those would be people who are still
living a fairly isolated tribal life in
small groups pre,
you know,
basically operating at the level of
stone age technology.
Let's say.
The idea was there was a very popular
idea for a long time that those cultures
were um,
communistic and violence free.
And that's wrong.
They're not violence for you at all.
If you track the homicide rates in stone
age,
culture is they're way,
way higher than they are in civilized
cultures,
like orders of magnitude higher.
And there's a variety of reasons for
that.
But I'm just telling you that because
you want to dispense with the idea that
along with complex civilizations and
this fred say of unifying religious
beliefs,
there was an increase,
an increase in baseline violence because
there's just no evidence for that at
all.
Now the problem with these large scale
belief systems is they're not very fast.
And part of the reason for that is that
in order for a large scale belief system
to,
uh,
manifest itself in any reasonable form,
it has to be predicated on the mutual
agreement of the people within whom,
within,
who operate within its embrace.
You know?
So for,
for Toronto to exist as a city has a
peaceful city,
basically what has to happen is that the
vast majority of us have to agree that
the rules that govern the city and the
social interactions within the city are
useful.
And just,
and because if you don't agree with
that,
then splinter movements of all sorts
start to occur and people become more
revolutionary in their modes of action.
And then they become more violent than
the whole system starts to break down.
So it's not easy to establish a
collective norm because people have to
agree to it.
And you can imagine that hammering out
agreement with anything,
with even a small agreement that affects
many,
many people is a process that takes a
tremendous amount of time.
And people can argue forever about the
smallest alterations in the systems that
regulate our behavior.
Now,
you know,
some of you might be familiar with the
terror management theories.
How many of you have heard of terror
management theory?
Okay,
well,
the terror management theories are
predicated on the idea that our belief
systems protect us from our fear of
death.
Now exactly how they do that isn't
specified particularly well in the
terror management theories.
But the originator of the theory,
whose name was Ernest Becker,
who was a sociologist by the way on a
Friday.
And,
um,
believe that cultural systems enabled us
to attribute beliefs to our actions,
finite and infinite,
so that we could consider ourselves in
relationship to mortality.
And in some sense,
hide from the truth of the,
a tune of our existence.
Now,
one of the things the terror management
theorists don't really give any credence
to is the fact that belief systems are
not only systems of belief,
there's systems of action regulation,
right?
So we've talked about the Piagetian
notion of a game.
The game exists first as something that
everyone can play and only later as
something that people represent.
And as social cultures the same way a
cultural,
a culture regulates the way that you
interact with each other and what you
expect from each other,
and how you can fulfill your mutual,
your needs in,
in relationship to one another.
And then it's represented.
And the representation might help you
find meaning in your life.
But the fact of the initial social
contract,
which is the phenomena that regulates
your interpersonal behavior,
doesn't protect you from the fear of
death.
It protects you from dying.
And,
and that's a very important thing to
note.
I mean,
you know,
all of you know,
of course it's very cold out today.
And yet here you are in this classroom
where it's renal ridiculously
comfortable,
you know,
by classroom standards and of course by
standards around the world.
And you're not freezing to death in
here.
And that's not your belief that's
protecting you.
It's the fact that you're embedded in
this insanely complicated system of
cultural interactions.
And it just so happens that you get to
sit here and listen to a lecture.
Well,
there's thousands of people beating
around many of them outside in the cold,
making sure that the power grid,
for example,
that keeps this place warm,
is properly maintained and functional,
which takes a tremendous amount of work.
So when in during periods of rapid
transformation,
it's hard for the social contract to
adjust itself so that everyone knows how
to behave in relationship to one
another.
But then it's also very difficult for
the description of that.
So the articulated norms that constitute
a society,
it's very difficult them to transform
rapidly enough so that they can keep
track of the,
of the changes and help people decide
what they should do.
So let me give you an example.
So I had a client a while back who had
been raised as the fundamentalist
Christian and she was very,
um,
she had been socialized and had come to
believe that
sex before marriage was wrong,
but the probability that she was going
to get married before she was 27 or 28
was low for a whole variety of reasons.
And so then she faced this conundrum and
it was an interesting conundrum,
my perspective because you know,
I think that in a well-regulated psyche,
sexuality is integrated into the
personality so that it's so that it
plays its role in the,
what would you call in Nepal or the of
the south.
It's integrated properly inside.
And so it's under moral control,
roughly speaking because it serves its
own function plus the function of
keeping the person well situated in the
present and developing property in the
future and maintaining proper
relationships with everyone around them.
But it was quite obvious to me that a
lot of the constraints that had been
placed on her behavior as a consequence
of her relatively rigid belief,
we're actually interfering with her
development as a person.
You know?
And so one of the things we had to
puzzle out was,
well,
exactly what are the moral guidelines
that you should use to regulate your
sexual behavior outside of marriage if
you're not planning to be married for
maybe until your late twenties well,
you know,
good luck trying to figure that out.
Like it's a really,
it's a really,
really,
really complicated question.
And it's certainly not obvious that any
one person can figure out the answer to
that in a single lifetime.
You know,
even if they thought if nothing else,
especially because of the landscape
itself is transforming as you're
attempting to adjust to it.
You know,
and we eventually concluded,
although it was a very individual
solution,
we eventually concluded that there were
things that she had forbidden herself to
do,
that we're stopping her from
establishing any kind of longterm
relationship at all.
And that that was interfering with their
development,
you know,
as a mature person.
And that the morality that she had used
to structure her behavior appeared to be
counterproductive,
at least,
you know,
in some,
in some areas.
So it's one thing to,
you know,
to,
to regulate sexuality in the hopes of
marriage.
When you get married,
when you're,
you know,
19 or 20 or 21 it's a completely
different thing when it's perhaps not
going to happen until you're in your
late twenties so now need shit talked a
lot and Dostoyevsky talked a lot about
the collapse of meaning systems in the
late 19th century and you know,
that was followed by a river,
very,
very rapid period.
Technological transformation like that
really kicked in in the late 18 hundreds
which was the,
you know,
the,
well,
was it the height of the industrial
revolution,
particularly in England.
And there were modern technologies being
thrust out of the industrial revolution,
like mad,
like the automobile or near playing in
the electric light and recording devices
and all of the things that we're still
elaborating on now.
And then of course,
apart from the collapse of classic say
Christian belief and the introduction of
all these new technologies when world
war one hit,
the entire monarchical structure of the
Western world collapsed.
And that also occurred say with regards
to the Ottoman Empire.
And that was partly what led to the
creation of the modern Middle East.
And of course we're still,
that still hasn't been sorted out to any
great degree at all.
So the monarchical structures collapsed.
These ancient civilizations,
the Russians underwent their revolution
and we're,
you know,
and were transformed into communists and
then after World War One,
the,
the stress between the potential
different ways of structuring societies
after the monarchical societies had
collapsed was almost unbearable and
people didn't really know what to do.
No.
Yeah.
What happened at the end of niches
period and m Dostoyevsky's period was
that the question that both of those
people,
what no
most important question,
both of those people ask became the
central focus of the development of
philosophical ideas of ethics in the
20th century.
So you could think about those as that
has a kind of a post religious ethic.
Now,
the reason I'm telling you this is
because among other things is because a
lot of what cycle analytic or
psychotherapeutic treatment is about,
it's about ethics.
And that can't be stressed too much
because ethics is about how you see the
world and how you behave.
And so even behaviorists who are
technically embedded in the scientific
world are still pregnant,
practical ethicist.
Because what they're consistently doing
with their clients is breaking down
whatever the problems are that are
causing the misery,
breaking them down into sub problems and
trying to figure out solutions that
improve their quality of life,
like practical,
implementable solutions that improve
their quality of life,
not only now,
but as they propagate into the future.
And that is not a scientific issue.
It's a how to live issue.
So the entire history of the 20th
century,
in some sense,
political,
economic and psychological was a
sequence of attempts to answer the
question when your fundamental systems
of ethics collapse,
how is it that you should live
okay
now Nisha said very clearly that
there'll be two to the collapse of these
systems and one would be nihilism,
the belief and nothing at all,
which he also regarded as a form of
escape from responsibility.
So it's a logical consequence of the
breakdown of classical belief systems,
but it's also a a cop out and it's the
kind of cop out that dusty Husky
explored very deeply in his small
resilient novel notes from underground,
which describes a person who's basically
slipped and intellect intelligent person
and an irresponsible person who's
basically slipped into a pit of
meaninglessness where he experienced his
hatred and resentment and the desire for
revenge and all of the sorts of things
that would afflict someone in the
underworld who's got nothing to hold
them together.
And then of course,
nature also talked about the likelihood
that people would turn to totalitarian
belief systems such and he particularly
discussed communism as a replacement for
religious belief.
I can give you a Canadian example of
that.
So I heard a Gallup pollster one time,
I was at a conference in Ottawa.
It's the only time I've ever heard this.
And I think it's an amazing,
it's an amazing fact.
They were looking at the probability
that people would be separatists in
Quebec.
And if you are a lapsed Catholic,
the probability that you will be a
separate as was increased 10 times.
And the reason for that is,
you know,
Catholicism fell apart in Quebec in the
late 1950s it was one of the last places
in the Western world,
roughly speaking,
where the,
the feudal in some sense structures of
Catholicism had maintained themselves
right up to that point right up to the
1950s late 1950s and that collapsed
precipitously,
just like belief in Christianity had in
Russia,
you know,
in the late say 1880s and what happened
in Quebec was,
well first of all,
the birth rate plummeted.
I mean I did genetic research in Quebec
and in the 1950s and before that it was
very typical to see families of nine to
13 children.
And of course by now Quebec has the
lowest birth rate.
I believe in the Western world,
it's way below replacement.
Everybody bailed out of the church,
nobody gets married.
And if you were a separate,
as if you were a lapsed Catholic,
you are 10 times more likely to be a
separate list.
All that meant was that with Catholicism
fell apart,
you know,
people who still needed to have very
structured belief systems just turned to
nationalism as a natural alternative.
You know,
and that's part of what,
that's part of what accounted for the,
the rigidity and utopian,
uh,
the utopian,
the Utopian nature of the Quebec
movement towards independence.
You know,
I remember talking to one of my
callings,
very,
very intelligent person.
And uh,
you know,
I asked him because at that point they
were predicting that if Quebec
separated,
the Canadian dollar would fall to 40
cents,
45 cents us something like that and be
complete economic catastrophe.
I said,
well,
you know,
the,
the predictions are that if Canada
separates and first of all or Quebec
separates and no one would know how to
do that is the Canadian economy will
collapse.
And of course that will collapse the
Quebec economy too.
And he,
he,
he didn't deny that.
He said,
yeah,
but it would be worth it.
And I thought,
well,
there's just no way of having a
conversation under those circumstances.
Because from my perspective,
total,
you know,
severe economic collapse is a good
reason not to do something.
But if you believe that the pope,
the future potential is such that that's
justified,
then well there's no arguing with you.
It's just something that you've decided.
And that's the end of that.
And when I lived in Quebec,
as I did for a long time,
I learned very quickly never to have a
discussion about politics with anyone
who was a separate,
just because it was just absolutely
counterproductive.
You know,
they had axioms of belief that were
movable.
Like the future will be good enough so
that no matter what price we pay in the
present,
that will be justified.
It's like,
well that's not an idea.
Right?
It's a statement of faith.
And you saw a doctor the same thing
happening,
not with the same principles.
I'm not saying that,
but you saw the same thing happening
from a psychological perspective in
Russia when the Communists,
you know,
when the communists really started to
become active in the 1920s when any
matter of horror whatsoever was fully
justifiable because it was going to
bring about some future state that was
basically equivalent to paradise.
So anyways,
so,
and then you know,
Dostoyevsky pursued the idea of nihilism
even farther because Dostoyevsky was
certainly someone who was willing to go
to the ends of an argument.
And one of the things he proclaimed was
that if there was no god than anything
was permitted.
And his basic hypothesis was,
well as if there's no all ultimate
arbiter of values,
if there's no transcendent arbiter of
values,
then you're radically free.
Now the existentialists would say,
well,
you could use that radical freedom to
find meaning in your life.
But one of the things Dostoyevsky
realized was that you could use that
radical freedom for anything that you
wanted.
And so in his book,
crime and punishment,
for example,
he explores the actions and beliefs of a
student named Rascal Nacog and risk
called Nicole is a starving student.
He's a law student and he doesn't have
enough to eat.
So of course he's,
his cognition is a little bit on the
adult side because he's going through
periods of starvation and drunkenness.
So it's not like he's thinking that
clearly he wants to become a law
students so that it can help society.
And he finds out that his sister is
basically willing to enter into a
loveless marriage and more or less
prostitute herself so that she can
generate enough money to share with her
mother so that they can fund his
continuation through law school.
And he thinks that wouldn't be a very
good deal.
At the same time,
he's indebted a pawn broker who everyone
hates,
who is an absolutely miserable person in
every possible way.
And Dostoevsky sets up the situation
like that.
So the pawn broker has a niece,
if I remember correctly,
who she basically in slaves and miss
treats and she squat squirrels away all
sorts of money but never does anything
with it,
lives in absolute poverty.
And anyways,
he considers her the sort of person
without whom the world would be a better
place.
So having all of these things co
occurring in his imagination,
he decides that because there are no
ultimate arbiters of value,
that all morality is essentially
cowardice,
which is kind of the reverse of what
needs to concluded.
See,
said most people were cowardly and
justified that with their morality,
but responding to cough took the other
idea,
which is,
well,
why do I have to obey any rules at all
if there's no ultimate source for any of
these rules,
it's just convention and cowardice.
And if I have enough strength,
then I can leave outside of that
framework and I can do whatever I want.
So he decides to kill the pawnbroker,
which he does and quite successfully.
And not only that,
he gets away with it and that's about
the first third of crime and punishment.
And the rest of the book is that the
discussion of the manner in which he
comes unglued as a consequence of having
performed this act.
And it's,
it's a brilliant,
it's absolutely brilliant study of the
way that a value system holds you
together even in ways that you don't
know.
And then if you step outside of that
and,
and violate your relationship to it in
some really intense way,
then there's going to be catastrophic
psychological consequences that will
echo through your whole being.
You know,
we know that this is more than theory
because many people,
soldiers in particular who developed
post traumatic stress disorder,
developed post traumatic stress disorder
when they observe themselves doing
something that they regard as
tremendously cruel or vicious or
immoral.
You know,
when they're in the situation where,
you know,
uh,
acting that acting in that manner is
highly probable.
It's a war situation is usually very
intense and you know,
they don't have a lot of time to make
decisions and God only knows,
you know,
what the specifics are of the particular
event.
But many,
many people come to be so shattered by
observing themselves do things they
can't believe that a human being would
be capable of doing that.
They never recovered.
And it's partly because you know,
they violate their,
their ethical,
the ethical structure that holds them
together holds older ideas and their,
their plans and their perceptions and
their interactions with other people.
That's a unified field in some sense.
And if you violate it and it fragments,
then you're left absolutely fragmented.
Then that's,
that's not,
that's not even a psychological
observation.
It's a psychophysiological observation.
You can stress yourself so badly,
raise your stress level so high that
your brain starts to become damaged by
the stress hormones.
And you know,
so it's,
it's not just a psychological state,
it's,
it's damage to the core of your being in
some sense.
Now,
the collapse of these belief systems and
their destabilization was well thought
through by these thinkers by the end of
the 19th century.
And then w we have the technological
transformations and the,
and the sociological and political
transformations of the early part of the
20th century.
That leaves everyone in a state of
confusion in some sense.
Like in Germany in the 1920s of course
the Germans had gone through this
terrible period of trench warfare.
So they're all,
their men were brutalized,
some of them had been on the front for
months and that was in the trenches.
And then,
you know,
their political system had collapsed and
they put a week weekly rooted democracy
in place.
And then the economic system collapsed
in Germany,
went through a period of hyperinflation.
So that money,
the value of their money basically
dropped to zero.
And so that meant that if you were 65
years old and had saved up your whole
life to have enough money to retire and
we're a good citizen,
you know,
and,
and prudent and careful,
every single thing you ever own
disappeared.
And so at the same time,
you know,
the communist revolution had taken place
in Soviet Russia and there was great
concern within Germany that the same
thing was likely to happen there.
And certainly that the communists were
always pushing for that because they had
the common term,
which is the international communist
movement,
which was devoted towards the
stabilizing,
you know,
non communist governments and,
and producing the preconditions for the
revolution.
So it wasn't,
wasn't like it was just paranoia.
It was a real threat.
And it was out of all that mess that
came,
the emergence of the fascists and the
Nazis.
And it's not that,
you know,
it's,
it's not that surprising because chaos
breeds the desire for order.
And so that was what,
that was one direction that people could
go,
you know,
instead of following an abstract
Messiah,
let's say,
the sort of of idea that was embedded in
classical Christianity,
they realized the new Messiah not was
Hitler.
And that certainly didn't seem to be any
improvement,
you know,
because Hitler was really a messiah of
destruction and fire and you know,
the World War II who killed about 120
million people.
And of course it left Germany in
absolute ruins.
And Hitler killed himself in his bunker
underneath Berlin while it was burning.
And the Russians were advancing into
the,
you know,
into Germany and they were not happy.
You didn't want to be a German national.
Well,
the Soviets were advancing towards you
after your con,
after your country to invaded.
There's push them back halfway across
the Soviet Union,
you know,
and produced a tremendous amount of
damage and distress.
It was an situation,
you know,
and uh,
the Messiah is that the,
that the Russians turned to Lenin and
Stalin were barbaric and brutal be on
comprehension.
You know,
and it's,
it's a strange thing,
you know,
we're not very well educated in what
happened in this,
in the Soviet Union in the 20th century.
We know far more about what happened in
Germany,
say with the Holocaust.
And you know,
it's very important that people should
know about that.
But there were tens of millions of
people brutally destroyed in the Soviet
Union.
And you know,
partly because they were murdered by
people who were,
at least in principle,
motivated by left wing Utopian visions.
We seem to,
our education system seems to regard
that as somehow more forgivable,
which it certainly isn't.
So,
you know,
the whole,
the whole generate second or
alternatives to religious belief issue
didn't seem to work out very well.
And then the nihilism alternative,
well that has its own problems.
You know,
one problem is the sort of dusty Esky
talked about,
you know,
and you see the kids who go up and
shoot,
shoot up high schools and,
and exploded in rage.
You know,
they're often people who feel that they
have no meaning in their life,
that life itself was contemptible and
that suffering is too extreme and that
they're,
they bear the brunt of unfair reality.
And you know,
they develop unbelievably dark and,
and destructive theories of,
of revenge and may ham over sometimes
over the period of years.
And then they go up in the world and lay
those things out.
And it's not like they're thinking is
irrational,
you know,
it's coherent.
It's just predicated on principles that
you might not agree with such as,
you know,
the principle that everyone that I don't
like deserves to die.
But you know,
in the absence of a really formal way of
demonstrating that such thoughts are not
only immoral but wrong,
you know,
in some absolute sense it's very
difficult to come up with ways of
defending ourselves against those two
extremes.
You know,
the extremes of destructive vitalism and
the extremes of ideological possession.
Now,
nature started to work out some,
some solutions to this.
And I just started to touch on those at
the end of the last lecture.
Um,
you know,
Dostoyevsky solution was a return to
Christianity fundamentally,
and it's revivification.
And that was the same tack that
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn attempted to lay
out and also tolstoy in Russia.
You know,
and,
and I'll talk to you about that a little
bit more in the next lecture,
dusty or niches idea was that people
would have to,
he said,
you know,
when his quote about the death of God
that people would have to become light,
God's just to be able to tolerate the
consequences of this dismemberment of
the previous civilization.
And he believed,
well,
his thinking on this,
I would say is,
is somewhat fragmentary.
I mean,
nature was a great critic of
Christianity,
institutionalized Christianity,
and a great diagnostician.
He could say what was rotten at the core
of western civilization will say modern
civilization.
But when it came to actually describing
what to do about it,
well,
he didn't live that long,
you know,
he died a fairly young man.
There's actually a video of nature in
the mental hospital online.
I just found it the other night.
I have no idea that he was ever a
captured on video.
But there's video from movie from 1899
showing him in the mental hospital where
he ended up in his early forties so he
talked about the development of the,
of the being.
He called the over man,
which is often translated as super band.
And his idea was that people would have
to take onto themselves the,
the,
the burden of creating new systems of
meaning and new morality's that were
suited to them,
that they would have to create new
values.
Now,
young took niches,
diagnosis very,
very seriously.
And you can,
you can certainly say that Ewan was as
much influenced by niche as he was by
Freud.
And I would say in some ways he was
influenced more because one of the
things that yoga was trying to do was to
identify where the lost values had gone.
So the Nietzsche and idea is that it's
possible for human beings to create
their own values.
Now there's a problem with that and
there's a variety of problems with that.
And one is that it's,
it doesn't seem exactly true in that,
you know,
and,
and a lot of the existentialists who
followed feature like John Paul Sartre,
for example,
believed in the radical freedom of human
beings that we were,
we were doomed to be free in a sense.
And that was absolutely necessary for us
to conjure up our own meanings and
values because fundamentally we faced
the void.
And you know,
life was nasty,
brutish and short to use hobbs terms.
And that we had to be able to confront
that and live despite it.
And well,
there's a variety of problems with that
solution.
The first one is,
well,
if you come up with your system of
values,
there's no reason.
And I come up with mine,
there's no reason to assume that they're
going to be sufficiently integratable so
that we don't have to fight each other
to the death.
That's a big problem.
So you know,
you'd have every single person with
their own system of beliefs.
Well,
fine extent.
How do you know that?
In a sense,
that's a structured kind of
philosophical anarchy.
Well,
okay,
maybe that's good if you happen to live
alone on an island,
but if you're stuck with all these other
people,
then that becomes a very difficult thing
to,
and I think it's partly for that reason
that Sartre famously said,
hell is other people,
you know?
Because he thought of the other in some
sense that which was not him as an
oppressive force that stopped him from
manifesting his destiny in the way that
would it be best for him?
Well,
you know,
hell might be other people,
but that doesn't mean that,
first of all,
that's a very one sided way of looking
at things because of course hell is
other people.
Hell is you two.
And you know,
hell is nature.
There's lots of places you can find
hell.
But by the same token,
you know,
the most meaningful elements of people's
lives are often their social
relationships.
And you can't lay everything at the door
of pathological society.
You know,
and we shouldn't forget as well that
Sartre didn't,
uh,
what come up with any reasonable
critique of the communists until the
late 1960s.
But,
you know,
but,
and that was a little late.
People with any sense,
like George Orwell had figured out that
the whole Soviet experiment had become
radically murderous by the early 1940s.
And so starcher pr,
you know,
proposed radical freedom as a,
as a,
as the existential response to the
unveiling of no meaning.
But when it came right down to it,
he couldn't resist identification with a
totalitarian structure.
So I don't see any reason why we should
really pay any attention to what he had
to say.
So now there's another problem with the
idea that people should create their own
values.
And that is that it's not so simple.
You know?
And the problem seems to be is that you
don't obey yourself very well.
You know,
you can say,
well,
here's my code.
I'm going to live by it.
So,
and we let's do that simply to begin
with.
You say,
well,
I'm going to study very hard and do well
at my classes just for the sake of
argument that you know,
but you don't,
you know,
you procrastinate and you have a paper
you're supposed to read and you know
you're supposed to read it and you need
to read it for reasons that are even
hypothetically important to you.
But there's no damn way you could get
yourself to sit down and read it.
Your attention wanders and you go to do
three or four stupid things and you feel
terrible about it.
Like you feel like you're betraying
yourself.
And maybe this is a continual pattern in
your life,
but one of the things you find out is
that you don't get to create your own
damn values because for some reason
you're not in charge of yourself.
And of course,
that's where the psychoanalytic ideas
start to come from.
You know,
Freud notices.
This is in the aftermath of nature,
that you're not the master of your own
psyche.
You know that there's,
there's many sub use inside of you and
they don't all want the same thing.
And so the idea that you can generate
your own meaning is very,
it's,
it's insufficiently developed idea
because there's a lot of meaning making
generators residing within you.
And not only do they not all point in
the same direction,
which is a huge problem,
but they don't even necessarily,
they don't necessarily lay themselves
out in some integrated fashion across
time and they don't necessarily operate
together in a way that's going to enable
you to find your place with other people
and in society.
So you know,
make your own meaning.
Well,
which part of you,
you don't,
you're not a unified thing.
So that's a big problem.
And then all these other problems just
remain unaddressed completely.
Well,
one answer to that,
and this is the answer that the more
radical existentialist took as well.
Society has to be reconfigured.
But you know,
we kind of know where that leads to when
people are doing radical societal
reconfiguration,
at least as far as we've been able to
tell.
Most of the time,
that's an absolute murderous
catastrophe.
So,
you know,
it's reasonable.
It seems reasonable to me to presume
that,
that those experiments have already been
run.
All right,
so now une,
like Dostoyevsky was very interested in
returning to sources of meaning from
which he believed that our original
religious ideas had emerged.
And this is partly his notion of the
collective unconscious.
So,
you know,
part of the radical critique of
religious systems is predicated on the
idea that there's something like
conscious beliefs.
You know,
they're articulated beliefs that you
could lay out in a credo,
but,
but that's not right.
It doesn't seem to be correct at all.
And Neat.
She actually knew this.
He knew that a lot of our social
institutions had emerged from the bottom
up and had only become articulated after
they'd been embodied in,
danced out.
Essentially,
you know,
you,
you are a tribal group learns how to
organize itself over thousands and
thousands of years of trial and error
and pushing against each other and so
forth.
And they come into that tribal grouping
with a biological substrate and there
are sociological and political
interactions are constrained by all of
those things.
And then maybe they come up with a
description of that over time,
the self description and an articulated
representation.
And that's the religious system.
It's not that the religious system is
thought up first as a system of
metaphysical presuppositions,
images and dreams,
then turn it into rules then imposed on
the population who then obeys it.
And generally speaking,
when people criticized,
um,
formal religion,
they criticized it.
Assuming that that's how it had
developed,
you know,
and that's kind of a Marxist idea,
for example,
that religion is the opiate of the
masses and that,
you know,
the religious structures were laid out
so that a small elite could control the
population.
Now,
you know,
in virtually every domain,
a small elite emerges that dominates the
population.
I don't care what domain you look at.
So mark's is accurate in that way in
that,
you know,
there's always a power imbalance between
elite minority and a non elite majority.
But to say that that's the cause of all
the systems that people interact with it
as well.
And it's,
it's,
I'm sophisticated beyond belief.
What it does is it takes phenomena that
are complex beyond comprehension and
reduce them to one thing.
It's not helpful.
Like,
you know,
here's an example.
MMM.
If you,
if you sampled popular songs on the,
on Youtube,
let's say you made a graph of how
popular songs were,
what you find is that about 10 songs at
any given time are played.
Half of all the songs played at any
given time are going to be one of 10
songs.
Well,
and then what,
the other thing you'd find is that half
of all songs played are played by one or
more of 10 musicians.
And that's true.
No matter,
you know,
if you look all the way from the 1930s
to now,
if you look at popular music,
you see the same thing.
Almost everything that almost everyone
listens to is created by very few
people.
And then there's millions of musicians,
but you've never heard of most of them.
And you'll never hear a song.
For most,
it's a small minority.
And what you see as in any field of
creative production,
this happens.
A small elite emerges and dominates the
entire landscape.
Now,
you know,
it's kind of,
it would be kind of ridiculous to assume
that the 10 most popular singers and
musicians that are currently operative
word,
those who gave rise to the system that
allowed them to thrive.
I mean,
obviously that's a dopey idea and it's,
it's,
it's no more an intelligent idea of when
you look at any other domain where
there's tremendous variation and the
emergence of an elite,
it's a very common phenomenon.
It happens,
as I said,
it happens anywhere.
There's creative production.
And so that's why 1% of the people,
you know,
roughly half,
50% of the money,
it's no different than in other creative
domains.
Now we'll talk later in the course about
why that happens,
but to think it's because those people
set up the system.
So that they could thrive as well.
There's an element of that obviously,
because once you're rich,
you're going to prefer political
policies that help you stay rich.
But that doesn't mean that you set up
the whole damn system that made you rich
to begin with.
Plastics,
not the same people over any reasonable
span of time.
So the 1% of people who have most of the
money,
it's always 1% but it's not the same
people.
You know,
each in individuals tend to hold on to
money for very short periods of time and
big companies don't last very long.
You know,
they,
they last on average about 30,
35 40 years and that's it.
Then they disappeared.
So when it's,
because you know,
the economic landscape is just churning
like Mac,
it's very difficult for a company to,
you know,
there's not that many big steam coach
companies anymore,
you know,
and,
and nobody makes zeppelins and nobody
makes typewriters.
And you know what I mean?
It's things move quick.
And just because you dominated the
landscape at one particular moment
doesn't mean you're going to be able to
do it that the nest.
So,
all right,
so the create your own meaning thing is
a rough one.
And then there's another problem too,
which is what makes you think you have
enough time?
You know,
lots of times people come to me and they
have relationship problems and part of
the problem is,
is that they've set their relationships
up outside of social norms and they do
that.
And also they'll say something to me,
something like,
well,
we're not going to get married because
marriage is just a piece of paper,
which is really a stupid thing to say.
Like it's an incredibly stupid thing to
say.
But underneath that there's this idea
that they want to remain free of social
constraints so that they can negotiate
their own way.
Like if you're giving them credit for,
you know,
wanting freedom instead of just escaping
responsibility.
But the problem with that is it's like,
okay,
good luck.
Try it.
I don't know why.
You would assume that you have enough
time in the 30 or 40 years that you're
going to be pursuing relationships to
actually figure out how they should run.
You don't have a hope of that.
And it's worse too,
because very,
very few people can negotiate,
you know?
Because the,
here's the way it works.
New.
Either adhere to the social order or you
stand outside of it.
As soon as you stand outside of it,
you're in a chaotic place because
there's no guidelines.
And then you either live chaotically
because there's no guidelines or you
start to formulate order.
But to do that,
you have to know what you want and you
have to know how to express it.
And then you have to figure out what
your partner wants and help them express
it.
And then you have to negotiate a
solution.
Well,
I would say one in 20 people know how to
negotiate.
It's really,
really difficult.
If you mean,
just think of the steps.
First of all,
you have to know what you want and then
you have to admit it to yourself.
Well,
yeah,
right.
Like,
you can't,
you're not even going to get to the
first one in all likelihood.
What do you want?
A lot of what you want can't be
articulated even,
you know,
I'll give you an example.
So there's a great study done a while
back on prediction of,
of,
of a relationship longevity.
Okay.
So here was the question.
Um,
how many negative interactions do you
have to have per set of positive?
Sorry?
How many positive interactions per
negative interaction do you have to have
with your partner in order for the
relationship to remain stable?
Okay,
so let's say you have one negative
interaction to every one positive
interaction.
Okay.
Or maybe have 10 negatives to every
positive.
Then you can imagine a different
situation where you have a hundred
positive to one naked,
right?
Spanning the whole potential continue.
And you use that to predict relationship
satisfaction and longevity.
Well,
you might think,
well God,
obviously a hundred positive to one
negative is where is the preferable
ratio.
And so it's those people who,
you know,
their relationship is nothing but
constant compliments and bliss.
They're the ones who last.
It's not true.
What you see is that there's a,
there's a,
an optimal,
an optimal ratio domain.
If it falls below five to one,
positive to negative,
then your relationship falls apart.
It's too negative.
And it's partly because people feel
negative emotion more than they feel
positive emotion because you can be hurt
more than you can be pleased.
And so one that's only five to one is to
punishing and people won't,
won't stay in.
But if you get above 11 to one,
it gets not punishing enough.
And you think,
well,
what does that mean exactly?
Well,
what do you want in a relationship?
While you think bliss,
it's like that isn't what you want.
As it turns out,
it's more like he wants someone to
contend with,
you know,
you don't want to push over.
You don't want everything just to be
easy.
You know?
And this is the sort of,
um,
the sort of phenomena that kierkegaard
was talking about when he talked about
deciding to make things more difficult
for people because that's what they
need.
You know,
you know this perfectly well because if
you go out with someone and they worship
you and they don't on your every word
and there's nothing but positive
feedback coming from them,
you lose respect for them almost an
instantly and you go wander off and find
someone who's more interesting.
And part of the reason for that I think
is that you want the person that you're
with to challenge you so that not only
do you do reasonably well data gate day
together,
you know,
so that you can coexist in the same
space with a reasonable amount of pace.
But you also want there to be enough
tension in the relationship so that
you're both involved in a process of
mutual transformation.
Well try specifying that in an
articulated way.
You know,
good luck,
you know?
And it also explains strange things
about people like the fact that they'll
stay in pretty negative relationships.
Like what the hell are you doing there?
If you had articulated it two years ago
and you said,
well,
I want to be with someone,
I'm miserable with half the time,
of course you're never going to say
that.
But it could easily be that that's what
you're after.
So well,
so,
alright,
now heidegger is another philosopher who
was attempting in some sense to solve
the problems that were laid out by
Nietzsche and Dostoevsky.
And the way that heidegger heidegger
began to resolve them was by taking a
radically new lockout philosophy itself.
And
he was,
he was one of the prime
phenomenologists.
And I told you a while back that the
phenomenologists decided to re
constitute Western philosophy.
So that was focusing on being instead of
knowledge.
And so the hardest thing to grasp about
the phenomenologists is what exactly
they meant by being.
And so I'll give you a,
I'll give you a overview of that.
So that's where the term dad sign comes
from.
And that's a German term and it means
being there.
And so right now you're encapsulated in
a dad side and the design is the
totality of your experience.
And that experience would be an
experience of the extended world,
the natural world,
and then the social world.
And then inside that the world of your
subjective experience.
And that constitutes be it.
And the phenomenologists make the case.
They're not playing this subject object
gate and they're standing outside of the
division between subject and object.
That's part of the scientific world
view.
So it's a real paradigm shift in that
you can't use the rules from the old way
of looking at things inside the new way
of looking at things.
You have to start with new
presuppositions.
So we might say,
well one of the things that you're going
to do if you look at things
phenomenologically is to assume that
everything that you experience is real.
So,
so then we would say that there's no
attempt in that phenomenological world
to reduce pain to something material.
Pain stands as stands itself as a
phenomena.
So does anxiety.
So does joy.
All the things that that scientists have
consciousness call quallies,
which are viewed by them as qualities of
the objective world aren't viewed that
way by the phenomenologists.
They just say those are primary elements
of being.
So it's a very interesting way of
looking at things because it kind of
allows you to reclaim the validity of
your own experience.
You can no longer say,
well,
that's only subjective,
and that doesn't mean that everything
you play him subjectively is true
objectively or for other people.
What it does mean is that everything
that you experience subjectively is
real.
Now that doesn't mean you have to not
think about it or take it apart or
categorize it properly.
You still have to do all of those
things,
but you're,
you're put into a place where there's no
need to deny the reality of your own
experience or to subordinate it to
something else.
So for example,
if I'm doing dream analysis with
someone,
which I do often,
if people dream,
because dreams as young pointed out are
there,
they,
they're,
they're manifestations of being,
you don't come up with them,
they appear to you.
They sort of appear out of nowhere in
some sense.
They manifest themselves,
they do it strangely.
And I think the reason for that is that
they contain unarticulated thought.
But if you can get a handle on them and
assess them,
then sometimes they can tell you things
that there's no other way you can figure
out.
And what's really cool about them is
that they're,
they have the same impersonality as
phenomena in the,
like the broader world of experience
have,
you know,
you don't ever think about the truth of
a chair.
It's just there.
And dreams are like that.
They're just there.
And if you can untangle what they have
to,
what they indicate,
then you can get a take on your own
experience that's not
altered by any of your local subjective
wishes and desires.
I hate to use the word subjective in
this sort of context.
So phenomenology is the study of being
now,
now and in being,
there are a variety of aspects.
So one aspect,
I never remember the names of these,
but I'll get it here right away.
Oh yes.
Uh,
heidegger broke the world of experience
being into three basic categories.
There was the unwelcomed,
which I think is basically the world
beyond culture and the individual.
There's the mid dwelt and that's the
world that we share with everyone else.
So that's roughly the social world and
the social structures.
And then there's the eigen value,
which is that domain of experience
that's unique to you that other people
can't partake in.
So those are the elements of being,
as far as the phenomenologists were
concerned.
And in those domains of being different
experiences manifest themselves.
We talked about some of the ones that
would be manifestations of the,
I can belt
scientists would call those things
emotional or motivational states.
Normally people think of them as
feelings.
I would say.
I feel that's,
I feel such and such.
And those are experiences that that
manifest themselves to you or that you
have,
depending on how you look at it,
that are indicative of the manner in
which you should act in relationship to
being.
Now,
one of,
part of the reason that this is relevant
to psychotherapy in particular,
it was because of the,
the,
uh,
the phenomenologists were very
interested in the manifestation of
meaning.
So you could say,
well,
nihilism is the absence of meaning and
totalitarianism is the fixed headedness
of meaning,
right?
If you're a totalitarian,
what you do is say,
all exist in relationship to this
structure.
It's almost as if from the
phenomenologists would say you're trying
to reduce the,
the weld,
which is the natural world,
the Mip Weld,
which is the social world and the Eigen
belt,
which is your own world.
You're trying to reduce all of that to
the Midwest so that everything falls
under an explanation that's granted to
you by some higher authority.
And,
and then of course the nihilists art are
having none of that.
They see,
they,
they use their eigen felt,
I would say their own world to
invalidate meaning in any domain.
Now the phenomenologists would say,
well,
it's a mistake to use your rationality
to undermine the,
the,
the sense,
the manifestation of meaning.
And I can give you an example of that.
So let's say you're a good nihilist and
you think that maybe you're going to go
do something difficult,
like put yourself through university,
and then you think in a relatively
depressed state of mind,
maybe you encounter some obstacles of
one form or another,
and you think,
oh,
to hell with this.
Who's,
what difference does it make anyways?
Who cares if I go and get my degree?
You know,
none of this knowledge is particularly
relevant or meaningful and who the hell
is going to know the difference in a
million years?
And so you think,
well,
that's a perfectly rational,
um,
dismissal because who is going to know
in a million years?
Or let's say,
well,
even if you could make a case that
someone might know there might be some
effects left of you in a million years,
then we'll just multiply it by 100,000
and go to a trillion years.
So here you are,
you're this little tiny speck on a
slight,
you'd made your speck in the middle of a
galaxy that has god only knows how many
billion stars.
And then there's a billion of those
galaxies.
Although there's way more than that and
they're spread across this tremendous
expansive time.
And in the face of all that,
who cares what you do?
Well,
what a phenomenologist would say is,
okay,
let's look at how meaning manifests
itself when you alter your own
private world in a variety of manners.
So let's say you're trying to do
something,
maybe you're working in a,
maybe you're working as a volunteer in a
hospital helping sick kids,
you know,
you're reading to them so that they're
distracted from their pain and you say,
well,
in the trillion years,
who's going to know the difference?
And so they think,
well,
it's meaningless to do this.
And the phenomenologists would say,
if the frame of reference that you're
using,
like if you're,
if you're imposing,
if you're transforming the way you're
being manifested itself so that it
becomes meaningless and absurd,
then you should try experiencing it in a
different manner.
So it's d c because a rationalist in
some sense,
the phenomenologists say a rationalist
can't deal with the argument.
What difference is it going to make an a
trillion years?
And here you are,
a little dust speck among all these
other dust specs.
It's ultimately meaningless.
A phenomenologist would say
maximize the meaning.
That's the,
that's the marker of truth.
And it's so,
it's a completely different way of
thinking about it.
So he,
he would say,
for example,
that if you're going to a hospital and
you're reading to sick children,
that the frame of reference that you
should use,
the way that you allow that experience
to manifest itself should be such that
the experience manifests itself so that
it's as meaningful as possible rather
than is meaning less.
The idea being that just because you can
twist your own experience so that
certain elements of your being become
meaningless does not mean that that's
right.
The fact that it becomes meaningless
actually means that it's wrong because
you think you see,
it all depends on what you allow to be
primary,
and this is the phenomenologists point.
If you allow your strict rationality,
it'd be primary.
Then if it can attack something and
destroy it,
then that thing is worthy of being
attacked and destroyed it.
But if you flip it around and you say,
well,
what you should be doing is allowing,
is interacting with your experience or
allowing your experience to manifest
itself in a manner that situates you
most meaningfully in the here and now.
Whatever framework you're using to do
that,
that works is right.
What's a completely different way of
looking at things?
And it's a real,
it's a real escape from the pathology of
rationalism,
you know,
because it isn't obvious that what you
think should take priority.
Now the phenomenologists would go
farther than that.
They would say that,
and this is something.
So here's a way of thinking about it.
So been swinging your seven.
What we perceive our first and foremost,
Vince Wanger was a psychiatrist who was
very much influenced.
It's why your advice where the people
we're going to talk about mostly were
very much influenced by it.
Gary and ideas,
they say,
what do we perceive our first and
foremost,
not impressions of tastes,
tone,
smell,
or touch.
Not even things or objects,
but meanings.
Okay,
so the idea for the phenomenologists is
that what being is made out of this
meaning it isn't that the objective
world is made out of things.
It's the being is made out of meaning.
Now,
some of those meetings can be positive
and some of them can be negative and
some of them can be neutral.
But the constituent elements of being
the fundamental constituent element of
being as mean.
And then there was an argument between
bins,
swagger and boss about how that meaning
manifest itself.
So been swagger would say that you endow
meaning on the world.
So that's kind of a nichey and idea that
you create your own values so that you
have within you something he called an a
priori ontological structure.
It's a world designed or a matrix of
meaning that determines how the world
manifests itself to you.
Now the easiest way to think about that
is that you know you're thrown into a
particular time and place.
That's another existentialist idea.
And that's part of the absurdity of your
life is that you're here.
Now in this particular context and
situation,
it's something you have to contend with.
And that's true for everyone.
There arbitrary preconditions to
everyone's Ba.
And one of those arbitrary preconditions
is the structure through which you look
at the world.
And that structure enables some things
to be highlighted in some things to be
ignored.
And so the way that meaning manifests
itself is a reflection of this,
a priori ontological structure.
And the primary mode of being so there
can't be being,
which is say your experience for the
sake of our argument,
without the structure that consists of
the,
that that you consist of.
And so that's a given and it's,
it's the action of that structure that
determines the meaning of things.
Now boss would say exactly the opposite.
He would say that's the wrong way of
looking at it.
You should look at the totality of your
existence,
which is partly the broad natural world,
the cultural world,
and your own world.
And you should note that meaning arises
in different places of its own accord.
You can't,
you can't reduce it to the action,
say of this ontological,
a priori ontological structure.
And so one example would be,
well,
what about the meaning of things you
don't understand?
Well,
it's hard to understand how the meaning
of things you don't understand can be
attributed to what you understand.
The meaning seems to be there to begin
with.
So here's an example.
You're,
you're,
you have a relationship with someone and
you discover that they have an affair.
Well,
the discovery of the affair is going to
be something that's meaningful.
Now you don't know what the meaning is.
You're going to interpret it to begin
with,
likely very negatively,
except to the degree that part of you
would like to escape out of the
relationship,
right?
Because sometimes if you're a betrayed,
you're happy about it because it's time
for that to be overweight.
But in any case,
there are things that you can encounter
that you don't understand,
that are meaningful in and of
themselves.
So I think that you actually can't
separate your structure from the
structure of everything.
They're always interacting and meaning
emerges out of the interplay of those.
So here's another way of thinking about
it.
You're reading a book.
The book is meaningful.
Where's the meaning?
Is it in your head?
Is it in the book?
While it's very difficult to say,
right,
because obviously there's a subjective
element to it.
There's an element that's unique to you,
but just as obviously that meaning
wouldn't manifest itself if it wasn't
for the book.
And of course the book wouldn't be
meaningful if you end the book weren't
embedded in this complex structure.
And so the meaning is an emergent
property.
The meaning is an emergent property of
the interplay of all of the elements of
being.
It's a very interesting way of looking
at things.
So you have all these elements of PA and
their dance produces meaning of one form
or another.
Now you might say if you are a
phenomenologist that some of that
meaning is going to be life sustaining
and some of it is going to be life
destroying.
And the phenomenologists would say from
a clinical perspective that you're,
if you're,
if you are,
if you exist in a system of meaning,
revelations that are life destroying,
that you should turn your attention away
from them towards meetings that are life
affirming.
And you know,
one of the things that's quite
interesting about the phenomenological
perspective is that you can experiment
with it quite easily.
So I could say to you,
for example,
a couple of phenomenological
experiments,
one would be for the next two weeks,
you want to detach yourself in some
sense so that you're a curious observer
of your being.
You're not necessarily trying to direct
it,
you know you're just trying to let it
unfold.
And then what you might want to watch
for is when the meaning that manifests
itself as,
as things flow around you is clearly
meaning of the life affirming tight.
Now you'll see that you know,
it depends on how well situated you are
in some sense because if you're,
if you're surrounded by,
if your experiential field is primarily
negative,
these are going to be relatively rare
events,
but they will still not be nonexistent.
They might only happen for a few seconds
or a few minutes every day or every two
days.
But so say,
okay,
you notice that all of a sudden you're
in a place where things are the way you
would like them to be.
So you could say you're in a place where
being is manifesting itself as
acceptable.
Okay,
so that's a place where nihilism is not
appropriate.
It doesn't apply because of the quality
of the experience is such that it's life
affirming.
You have to notice that it's something
that happens and then you might ask
yourself law,
okay,
what are the preconditions that enabled
that?
What are the preconditions that enabled
all of the different sub elements of
being to work harmoniously together at
that time in place so that that was the
meaning that emerged.
And then the next question might be how
would it be possible for me to allow
that to happen more frequently?
And so you can tilt yourself towards
life affirming meetings in a way from,
from say meanings that are associated
with despair of nihilism.
But you do that partly,
it's almost like you're navigating in a
boat.
In fact,
I think you are.
I think you're navigating to find the
line between order and chaos because
that's where the meaning is.
That's exactly where the meaning is and
you can feel it like it's a place and
that's the other thing that phenomenal
just to trying to get across these
things are real.
They're not secondary manifestations of
some deeper reality.
They are reality itself.
I also think,
and we'll talk about this more when we
get to the neuropsychological portion of
the course,
that your brain is actually set up first
and foremost to detect meaning.
You detect meaning before you detect
objects.
And it's partly because you have to
detect meaning so that you know what to
do when something happens very rapidly.
And there are times when you have to
figure out what to do before you have
enough time to even see what's there.
You just don't have the time.
So you know,
part of the question is,
well what exactly do you mean by
meaning?
You know,
I think meaning is significance for
behavior or significance for the
structure that governs behavior.
But those are very,
very basic fundamental perceptions
there.
They're not.
You see the object and then you derive
the meaning.
It's exactly the opposite.
In many cases you perceive the meaning
and derive the object and there's plenty
of neurophysiological evidence for that.
For example,
you have lots of,
you know,
your retina is a pattern detector and
the retinal information is transmitted
to your brain alone,
the optic nerve,
the optic nerve branches,
and it goes lots of places in your body.
Some of it maps right onto your spinal
cord so that your eyes can make your
body move.
Some of it maps onto your Amygdala so
that what you perceive are the meanings
of facial expressions without even
perceiving the face.
So you can have people who have
blindsight a damaged visual Cortex,
you can show them angry faces,
which they say they can't see,
but they'll respond to them electro
physiologically,
it as if they're being exposed to
something negative.
And it's because of the retinal pattern
is manifesting itself right onto the
system.
That maps one form of meaning.
So you can clearly have meaning without,
without object perception.
And so the idea that you derive the
meaning from the object,
you see the thing and then you attribute
meaning to the thing that's,
that's right.
At some levels of analysis.
But it's wrong in many other levels of
analysis.
And so
the other thing I think that you can try
that's phenomenologically informed.
This is quite an interesting trick.
It can really,
it's really hard on any of those.
Be careful if you try this.
So what another thing you could try for
two weeks is to watch what you say.
You got to detach yourself.
Again,
you have to remove the belief that your
thoughts and you are the same thing.
And then you have to watch mostly what
you say.
And then you have to see,
and this is something that Rogers would
also be an advocate of.
You have to see if what you say it makes
you feel what you have to see if what
you say improves the quality of your
being or makes it worse.
And you know,
if you start believing in what you say
and watch what the consequences are
instead,
how it manifests itself in terms of a
transformation of being,
then you can also learn how to only say
things that improve the quality of
being.
Well,
that's a good thing if you can manage
it,
but,
but it's,
it's,
it's terrifying in some sense because
one of the things that you'll find is
that hardly anything that you say does
that most of it's neutral,
but a fair bit of it has exactly the
opposite consequences.
It makes things worse.
So
I think I mentioned that the word
phenomenon,
that's where the phenomenology,
the term phenomenology comes from.
Obviously the term phenomena means is
from the Greek word famous thigh and
famous thigh means to shine forth.
And so the phenomenologies
phenomenologists argument is that like
being is made up of meanings that shine
forth for you and that those different
meanings attract you there.
They're like,
they're like guideposts that you can
follow.
So you know,
one of the,
I've noticed this for example,
in relationship to reading,
so I'll be reading a complex text and
some passage will really strike me.
So it manifests itself is meaningful.
Why is that?
Well,
you know,
one of the phenomenologists which would
be being been swagger,
we'd say,
well,
it's because of the way that I'm
structured.
But boss would say,
well no,
it's a dance that's occurring within the
structure of everything.
And the consequence of that is the
manifestation manifestation of this
meaning.
Well what I've found is that I can
follow threads of meaning through books.
You know that it's like it's something
that's guiding me,
that sense of meaning.
And often if I find something within a
book that's meaningful,
then I'll read the other things that
that person wrote and all see that some
of the people that they read have
meaningful things to say and then I can
branch out that network and it's,
it's following a pathway that's laid out
for you in some sense that's laid out
for you in the world.
And you know,
the phenomenological idea is that if you
follow that pathway,
then what happens is being becomes more
and more integrated around you and those
experiences of,
of intrinsic meaning start to multiply
and increase in intensity.
And you know,
if you're able to do that over a long
period of time,
then you can get more and more of the
totality of your being,
revealing the kind of meanings that stop
you from being either nihilistic or
totalitarian.
And so,
well,
that's the basic,
that's the fundamental theory of
phenomenological psychotherapy.
You know,
we might first say,
well,
you know,
you're depressed and anxious and your
life isn't going very well.
What keeps you afloat?
It's an,
it's something to observe.
And then we might say,
well,
are there ways that we can expand that
small area that's keeping you afloat so
that it starts to occupied more and more
of your experience and push back the
parts that are either neutral or
negative.
And you know,
it's,
uh,
it's in large part a consequence of
attention and willingness to first of
all,
treat things as if they're meaning is
real.
And then second,
to allow that reality to transform the
way that you experience things in the
future.
See you Thursday.