Hello Am I Korean readers main fund,
my publisher.
I'm sitting here in Maui,
Hawaii,
taking a bit of a break from my tour and
I just received word that sales of 12
rules for life and Korea are approaching
the hundred thousand mark.
So I'm extremely gratified to hear that.
Um,
I'm a great admirer of South Korean
culture.
I think that what you,
you're people have managed in the last
40 years is nothing short of a miracle.
And I'm filled with admiration for your
accomplishments.
I would really hope that the 12 rules
for life can help your people,
young,
and old alike,
and encourage them to develop a
compelling vision for their life and to
take on the sort of responsibility that
you've been pastors at managing and to
speak honestly and forthrightly and to
live knowably and to bury your suffering
properly and to help make the world a
better and less of place.
And so,
um,
thank you for all your support so far
and I hope at some point to be able to
come to your country and perhaps talk to
you.
Thanks very much Dr. Jordan Peterson.
Bye Bye.