All right,
so we're going to leap out of the
psychoanalytic domain now and start
talking about at form of approach to
personality and its transformations
that's predicated on a different set of
different philosophical assumptions.
And it's a bit tricky to navigate this
because
it requires the adoption of a different
frame of mind.
And of course that's the case with all
the theorists that we're going to be
discussing.
Um,
phenomenology probably had its most
thorough explication
in the philosophy of Martin heidegger
and heidegger was actually trying to
reconstruct western philosophy from the
bottom up.
He thought that we had been pursuing an
improper pathway conceptually,
really ever since the time of the
ancient Greeks.
[inaudible]
back around the turn of the century,
the previous century,
that from the 19th to the 20th century,
a new form of geometry was invented and
that geometry was predicated on
different axioms than Euclidean
geometry.
Now,
people had thought for thousands of
years that the world was properly
described by Euclidean geometry.
And you know,
when you employ a system like Euclidean
geometry,
you have,
there's axioms that you have to accept
and they're like the rules of the game.
And once you accept the axioms then you
can go ahead and play the game.
But there are other forms of geometry
invented and in the,
in the later part of the 19th century.
And it turned out that those forms with
different axioms actually described the
world better than the Euclidean forums.
So sorta like the transformation from
Newton to Einstein.
This was the transformation from Euclid
to say,
I think I've got his name right,
Reman,
r,
I,
e,
m,
a,N ,
n who developed a new form of geometry.
And it turned out to be just the
geometry that Einstein needed when he
was putting his theories forward.
And the reason I'm telling you that is
because
you can think of systems that have
different axioms as,
as different tools,
same idea that piaget was trying to
express when he talked about how
children's cognitive representations
underwent
staged transformations so that they were
starting to apply new principles.
Not only a new way of looking at the
world,
but they were fundamentally retooling
their presumptions about how the world
operated.
And heidegger tried to do the same thing
with philosophy.
And so,
and it's tricky to figure out exactly
what he was talking about,
but,
but I'll,
I'll give it a shot and then we can move
forward with Rogers.
So since the dawn of the scientific
world and likely before that,
we have tended to believe that we are
subjects in a world of objects.
And that's obviously a very useful way
to view the world.
And you can tell that because
formalizing that in the form of science
has enabled us to extend control over
the world in ways that we were not able
to before,
um,
to formulate the idea of an objective
truth has been extraordinary useful
maneuver.
And so the idea roughly is that
everyone's perceptions can be
contaminated by their own biases and
their own fantasies.
That subjective biases and fantasies and
you can overcome that by stringently
specifying the conditions under which an
observation takes place.
So that would be an experimental method.
Having multiple people view the
consequences separately.
Have them detail out what the
consequences are and then look for
commonalities across them.
And you think,
well,
the common leds across the set of
observations constituted description of
the objective world.
And that's been insanely powerful.
Um,
crazily powerful.
I mean,
that's not all there is to the
scientific method,
but it's a big part of it.
Now,
there is an emergent problem with that.
Perhaps it's complicated,
but one of the emergent problems with
that is maybe a consequence of stripping
the subjectivity out of the world.
So what science does is consider
anything subjective as a form of bias or
error in the observation and then get
rid of it.
And so what you're left with when you
formulate the scientific world is a
world that stripped of subjectivity.
Now the problem with that is that you're
a subject.
And so when you strip the world of its
subjectivity,
that sort of leaves you isolated,
like an isolated being with no necessary
connection to objective reality in the
midst of a set of impersonal fact.
And that seems to have psychological
consequences.
And the psychological consequences are
that,
well,
for example,
I think it's easier to develop a
nihilistic sense of being.
For example,
if you believe that the world is nothing
but objects and that you're
fundamentally an object among many and
not a particularly important one at
that.
So there are psychological consequences
to adopting the scientific worldview.
Prior to the emergence of the scientific
worldview,
people were more embedded in what you
might think about as a mythological
landscape.
You know,
where every element of being had it's
place in something that approximated a
master plan or at least a meaningful
plan.
And so the idea of the meaning fullness
of life was not necessarily such a
pressing intellectual concern.
And then,
well,
and so we don't know the full extent of
that.
I mean I've talked to you a little bit
about niches.
Idea is expressed at the end of the 19th
century about the death of God and his
prognostication that the collapse of
classic systems of meaning would open up
people to possession by nihilism and
also by potentially totalitarian
political systems.
And that seems to have been what
happened now.
Heidegger was very concerned about that
among other things,
and so he decided to reconsider reality
from the bottom up and so what he did
was generate an alternative set of
axioms.
He said,
he said something like,
well,
what if we decide to make reality?
Everything that we experience,
forget about the subject object divide.
One of the other problems with the
subject object divide for example,
is accounting for consciousness,
right?
Because it's a problem that science
really hasn't got any distance with at
all.
As far as I can tell.
I mean,
people have been trying to crack the
secret of consciousness obviously for a
very long time,
but they've been trying to do it
formally and using scientific methods at
least for the last 50 years,
and my sense of that is that they've got
absolutely nowhere.
Maybe that's a bit unfair.
We're better at representing how
conscious experiences manifest
themselves in the brain.
But we're certainly no better at
understanding how it is that we
experience things.
And that's the problem of Kalia,
that that's how the philosophers
describe it.
And quality is the quality of your
experience.
Like the,
the fact of pain for example,
in the pain you feel is by no means
identical at least as far as you're
concerned to some pattern of
neurological activity.
Right?
It's pain.
It seems to be a fundamental reality of
something.
In fact,
I think pain is the fundamental reality.
I think it's the only thing that people
will never deny but and so,
so there are these aspects of your
existence that are subjective,
like your experience of color and your
experience of beauty and just your
experience of things or maybe just your
experience and your experience plays a
in role in the structure of being
itself.
Cause you might ask,
well what would there be if there was
nothing conscious and you could say,
well
what would there be if there was nothing
conscious of being?
Well,
it's a tricky question because it
depends on your a priori axioms,
but it's not obvious what there would
be.
In the absence of a conscious observer.
There wouldn't obviously be any duration
between things.
It would be very difficult to specify
things in terms of size.
There wouldn't be any of the qualities
that we experience that we experience
are being as having cause color doesn't
seem to be an intrinsic part of the
world.
Smell doesn't seem to be intrinsic part
of the world.
It's very difficult.
The more you think about it,
you'd find the more difficult it is to
determine exactly what their would be if
there was no one to observe it.
And that's not the tree in the forest
idea.
Precisely.
It's not so much if a tree falls in the
forest and there's no one to hear it,
does it make a sound?
Because that's more a matter of the
definition of sound than anything else.
This is more like if there's a tree in
the forest and there isn't anyone,
is there a tree?
And that's a whole different question.
Anyway,
so what heidegger did,
partly because he was not pleased,
I suppose with the metaphysical
consequences of the scientific worldview
and also perhaps because he wasn't very
happy about our ability to account for
consciousness.
He decided to see what would happen if
he played a different kind of game.
And you can do that in an intellectual
discussion.
You know,
you can say,
well,
here's the set of axioms out of which
assistant will emerge.
Like here's a set of rules out of which
a game would emerge.
Same idea.
What if we start with a different set of
rules?
Let's see what we can do if we do that.
You kind of do that when you play one
video game rather than another,
you know their little worlds that pop
out there.
There's different,
there's a different underlying structure
and then you can go inside that world
and experiment with it and see what,
what comes out of it.
So heidegger decided to say,
okay,
what we're going to do instead is we're
going to assume that everything we
experience is real.
We're going to make our field of
experience itself reality.
And so that would mean from heidegger's
point of view that everything about
the being that manifests itself to you
is to be regarded as equally real.
So then you think,
well that makes pain a fundamental
reality that makes it anxiety,
a fundamental reality.
It makes beauty and color fundamental
realities.
They're not self-evidently reduceable to
anything else which they would be,
which they are in this scientific from
the scientific perspective because you
have to think about them as
manifestations of some more fundamental
underlying material reality.
And I guess that's another problem with
the subject object model and the
material model.
When you aggregate Adam's,
when you arrange them in certain forms
and when they manifest themselves as
certain molecules and then in more
complex structures,
they seem to take on all sorts of
qualities that you couldn't predict if
you just knew about the sub atomic
particles in the atoms themselves.
And so of course they're what are called
emergent properties.
And you say,
well you can
observe hydrogen and you can observe
oxygen,
but that doesn't make itself evident for
you to be able to predict the properties
of water.
And of course that's a much simpler
problem.
All things considered.
Then the problem of figuring you out
here,
this crazily complex aggregate of these
hypothetical hypothetically simple
entities,
but it isn't obvious how their elemental
properties can combine to produce you.
It's not obvious at all.
It's certainly not obvious how a
material that's supposed to be dead
matter so to speak can can manifest
consciousness no matter how complex Lee,
it's arranged.
So
the phenomenologists,
heidegger leading them were attempted to
produce a philosophical model of being,
and we'll talk more specifically about
the phenomenologists after we're done
with Rogers,
but he's,
he fits in that philosophical framework.
And
one of the things that I've thought,
this is a bit of a tangent,
but I'll move back to the moral
afterwards.
See,
I really liked the psycho analyst and I
liked the idea that you have a psyche
that's inside of you and that that is
structured in partly consciously and in
part conch unconsciously.
There's something about that that's
really cool and I've learned a lot from
the psychoanalyst,
but you know there is a funny
consequence of thinking the way they
think.
And you do think the way they think,
even if you don't know it,
like we tend to think that a lot of us
has inside our head.
You know,
that's the psyche model basically,
but the more I've practiced as a
clinical psychologist,
the last,
I've actually been convinced that that's
true.
So I could say,
well,
let's say I want to know about your
personality.
We think,
well,
I want to know you.
I want to know about your subjectivity.
I didn't want to know what's inside of
you,
but that isn't actually what you do want
to know.
If you're doing clinical work,
say with someone you want to know,
did they have any friends?
That's really important because if
you're miserable and anxious and badly
placed in life and misbehaving,
one of the reasons that all of that can
occur is because you don't have any
friends.
You don't know anyone,
and that's not something that's you.
It's it's you localized in a broader
sphere.
And then you might say,
well,
do you have a job and well,
let's talk about the job.
Do you actually make enough money with
your job?
Is it satisfying for you in any way?
Are you bullied all the time?
When you're at work?
Does it provoke anxiety?
Is it a career that allows you to go
somewhere?
Are you overworked?
Well,
but let's start with just the first
question.
Do you have a job?
Well,
if the answer to that is it,
no,
you have a serious problem and that
would enough might be to depress you and
make you anxious and hopeless and
nihilistic and all of those things.
And you could say,
well,
you're not reacting very well to not
having a job.
But that's kind of a foolish objection.
Even though some of it might be true.
One problem is,
is that you're not reacting very well to
not having a job.
But another problem is that you don't
have a job and that actually constitutes
a problem,
right?
You don't get to eat.
You don't have a place to live.
So those aren't psychological problems.
Precisely.
Even though a psychological problem
could make it worse.
Well,
are you as educated as you should be?
That's another question.
How do you handle drugs and alcohol?
Are they taking you down a bad pathway,
you know?
Um,
what about intimate relationships?
Do you have one?
Do you have a plan for one or they,
is that a never ending series of
catastrophes or something that you avoid
completely.
That's a big problem.
And maybe people don't,
aren't attracted to you for one reason
or another.
And you could think about that as a
psychological problem,
but it's an interpersonal problem.
And the degree to which that's a
psychological problem is,
is certainly an specified when you first
begin to talk to somebody.
What about your family?
Do you have a family?
Cause it's hard to be in the world all
by yourself.
That's for sure.
It makes things a lot more stressful.
Even though having a family can also be
extraordinarily stressful.
You don't,
do you have plans to have children?
How are you doing with your parents?
Do you get along with your siblings?
You know,
all of that.
All of that to me is more fundamental.
And it's outside of you.
Those are elements of your experience
more broadly conceptualized more than
they are objects of your psychology or
of your internal experience.
You know,
it's sort of like
while a person is,
uh,
is it is a creature that exists at
multiple levels of analysis,
right?
Something might go wrong with you at a
cellular level,
so maybe you're born with a genetic
abnormality so something's wrong with
you molecularly or you have something
wrong with a major Oregon.
Or maybe there's something wrong with
you psychologically or maybe you're in a
pathological family or maybe you're
stuck in a pathological social system
and,
and figuring out what's why you're
suffering means going up and down those
different levels.
Trying to specify the appropriate level
for analysis and also the appropriate
level for intervention.
And for me as a,
as I've said,
even though I'm a great admirer of the
psychoanalysts and I do things like
dream analysis,
which I really find you an incredibly
useful and enlightening the first,
the fundamental level of analysis is,
well what's your experience structured
like?
Exactly.
And that isn't localized in you.
Now the behaviorists do that too because
it's one of the things I really liked
about the behavioral approach to
psychotherapy.
It's very,
very concrete and practical.
It's like they'll say,
well,
there are certain things that you need
to have in order to live properly and
maybe you don't have the skills or the
wherewithal where with all to accumulate
them and we'll break them down into tiny
little pieces and you'll practice.
So for example,
with someone who doesn't have any
friends,
then you do a micro analysis of their
social skills say and maybe an analysis
of the kinds of anxiety that are
stopping them from going out and meeting
people.
And then you address those things
practically one by one.
You try to get the person to have some
friends.
He tried to figure out how they can
establish an intimate relationship.
You see if you can help them sort out
their family,
you do what you can about their
employment.
And a lot of that's only tangentially
related to really in some sense to the
structure of their psyche.
But one of the things you'll see if you
work as a clinician or as a counselor is
that most of the time people come and
see you because they have problems,
not because they have psychological
problems and those things are not that
easy to distinguish.
You know,
it's sort of the psychoanalytic idea
sort of like,
well if you just start your act
together,
everything would work out for you.
It's like,
yeah,
there's some truth in that,
but,
but you know,
if you're 55 years old and you've just
been laid off work
and maybe through no fault of your own,
it isn't obvious how much getting your
act together is going to help you find
another job.
Because the actual problem that you're
facing me have relatively little to do
with you.
And that would especially be the case if
you're maybe on the bottom half of the
intelligence distribution for example.
And so it isn't as easy for you just to
go out and pick up new skills at the
drop of a hat,
you know?
And that gets harder as you get older
because your Iq actually declines quite
substantially as you get older.
That that working or the the fluid
intelligence part anyways,
exercise can keep that at bay by the
way.
It's the best way to keep that at bay.
So anyways,
you can think from the phenomenological
viewpoint of your experience as a whole
instead of you being a subject in an
objective world.
And so here's another way of of here's
something that's quite useful.
Young talked about this because he was
moving towards a phenomenological
perspective later in his life.
The last book he wrote was called
mysterium [inaudible] and he talked
about three conjunctions that needed to
take place in order for someone to be
well constituted psychologically.
And you know how piaget talked about
learning that you could not only follow
rules but that you could make rules for
new games as sort of the highest level
of moral development.
I would say young extended the Piagetian
moral continuum up past
what piaget had envisioned.
Now he didn't,
he didn't do that cause he wasn't trying
to extend Piaget's model.
But,
but you can think about it the same way.
It's not easy to come up with a moral
motive being say,
that transcends the ability to make
rules for new games.
That's damn smart,
man.
That's,
that's,
that's a major home run by piaget as far
as I'm concerned.
But Young said something like this said,
look,
when you're going through the process of
psychological integration,
here's a way of conceptualizing it.
And he thought about this as
symbolically as male female pairings.
Because as I've tried to point out the
most,
one of the most fundamental character
categories that are mythological
imagination uses to structure the world
is the category of masculine and
feminine.
And it moves that around.
You know,
it's,
it's a fundamental metaphor.
So you can move that around anywhere.
And so young thought,
well one of the things that you're
trying to do is to get your thoughts and
your emotions integrated.
And so,
you know,
the Classic Enlightenment Viewpoint,
roughly speaking,
is something like passion is the enemy
of reason,
right?
And so to the degree that your rational,
it's sort of a Friday viewpoint.
It's cause he got your emotions under
control and there's some truth in that,
but not enough truth.
I like the Piagetian idea better,
which is that,
no,
no that isn't what happens.
What happens if,
if you're playing the proper game is
that you integrate your emotions
underneath.
You're thinking something like that.
So they're all working in the same
direction,
you know?
So for example,
you can make your anxiety work against
you or for you.
And one of the ways I did,
I made a program called the future
authoring program that I think helps
people do that.
Because one of the things you see when
you're talking to people and they're
trying to solve problems is that they're
afraid to face the problem.
And so then their anxiety is working
against them.
And you can think about it as a,
as antagonistic to rationality.
But then I could say,
well why don't you think for a while
about what your life would be like if
you didn't face this problem?
Because if you think that through,
if you have a problem and you really
think through what the consequences are
going to be in three to five years of
not facing it,
then you're going to get more afraid of
then facing it.
And that's great because then your
anxiety instead of standing in front of
you,
instead of you having a dragon that's
guarding the path in front of you,
where you have one chasing you down the
path from behind,
that's a lot more useful.
And so,
you know,
that's just a minimal example of the
utility of getting your emotions and
your,
and your thoughts aligned the same way.
The same thing happens with aggression.
You know,
one of the most common reasons that
people come and seek psychotherapy
really is because they're too agreeable.
But what that means is they're not
assertive enough.
They have an integrated their capacity
for aggression.
And so other people can push them around
and,
and they're very conflict avoidant.
And,
and so the consequences of that across
time is that you don't stand up for
yourself well enough and you get taken
advantage of.
And that spirals badly downward.
And so partly what you do when you're
doing assertiveness training with people
is you find out what they're angry about
and there are usually angalee angry if
they're not assertive enough because
other people are taking advantage of
them.
Or You could say because they're not
putting their own necessities forward
with enough force.
It's hard to distinguish between those
two things.
But anyways,
you,
he try,
you get them to talk about what they're
angry about that often makes them cry
often many times.
And then you get them to kind of
envision what they would want to have
instead,
which they're often afraid to do because
people are afraid to think about what
they want because that makes it more
clear when they're not getting it and
that's painful,
right?
Or maybe they're afraid of hoping so
they won't specify a clear aim.
But anyways,
you get them to think about what they
might want.
Instead you get them to think about the
costs of not pursuing that.
And then you help them develop
strategies for integrating their
aggression and with their thinking so
that they can come up with a plan to
approach the world in a more confident
way.
So for example,
someone might come to me and say,
I'm being bullied badly at work.
And so then I'll say,
well what are your options?
You have to put up with it.
Well we'll,
we'll figure that out.
Cause maybe you do,
maybe you don't have options,
but here's how to find out.
Get your damn cv together so it's
pristine,
right?
It's,
it's ready to go get over your fear of a
new interview because it,
people are generally afraid of that.
Get over your fear of applying for a new
job.
Start thinking about what it would mean
to have a different job.
to have a better job even because maybe
your fear is just making you stuck here.
But I can tell you one thing,
if someone's picking on you at work and
you don't have options,
you lose.
So you get the person to start building
a strategy.
It's like,
okay,
if you're going to tell this person to
stop,
you have to know how to make them stop
and one and the one thing you need for
sure is an option.
And if you can't,
if you don't have an option,
then maybe we start thinking about the
fact that you need some more training or
something like that because you cannot
negotiate if you don't have any power.
So because while,
especially if you're dealing with
someone who's really out to get you or
really disagreeable,
if you don't have a leg to stand on and
they'll just push you over and maybe
they'll jump on youtube because that's
what they're like and they enjoy it
anyways,
so it's no joke.
So you'll put your options behind you
and then you start to think about
strategy.
So I tell people,
look,
if you're being harassed at work,
you documented every time it happens and
you write it down.
So you've got like 20 stories about it
and it's fully documented.
And then you go confront the person at
some point.
But with at least three pieces of
evidence and you have some sense of what
you tell them about what will happen if
they don't stop.
So you have to figure out,
well,
if they don't stop,
what are you gonna do about it?
Leave.
Not if you can't leave.
So you,
you,
you have to be able to,
what is it wield a big stick and speak
softly,
but you see that way.
It's,
that's how you take your aggression,
which is an absolutely necessary part of
your psyche and manifest it up into a
sophisticated means of dealing with the
world.
You don't just suppress it.
You say,
well,
I should be able to put up with it,
or I wish I wasn't so angry or
something.
It's like,
forget that.
That's all it will happen is your blood
pressure will stay high and you'll die
of a heart attack because anger for
example,
it's a very toxic emotion and it does
cause heart damage over time.
It's the only emotion that we really
know that's been linked to things like
cardiovascular risk and anger is,
is toxic because it's like you're
driving a car.
You've,
you're stepping on the gas and pushing
on the brake at the same time because
anger tells you to run away and to
attack at the same time cause you don't
know what's going to happen.
And so it,
it really amps up the physiological
demand on your body.
And so if you,
including your heart and your
musculature,
so if you stay like that for like 10
years,
you know you're going to age 20 years
and that's a bad plan.
So,
so you know,
you take your underground emotions and
you integrate them into a sophisticated
reality.
Now
Young said,
so first of all,
unite your,
you unite your mind.
You're thinking,
let's say with your emotions.
So that makes one thing instead of two
fighting things.
Okay,
that's a good one.
And then the next conjunction he talked
about was it isn't enough to unite your
mind and your emotions.
And he thought about that as a male
female pairing symbolically.
Now that's how it would manifest itself
sometimes in dreams.
So you take the masculine element and
the feminine element,
the thinking and the emotion unite
those.
And that makes you more like one thing.
Okay.
And now all of a sudden that's
represented as symbolically mail,
that one thing,
and it unites with something else that's
now represented symbolically feminine
female,
that's the body.
So you take the mind,
emotion,
integration and integrate that in your
body.
So what does that mean?
You act it out instead of just thinking.
So there's this philosophical idea
called a,
now I'm going to forget what it's
called.
It's a contradiction in action.
There's actually a technical term for
it,
but that's when you think and believe
something,
but you're,
but you don't act it out.
And so that means there's a dissociation
in you somehow between your abstract
representations and what you manifest in
action.
While that's another form of
discontinuity that isn't doing you any
good.
You know the driver's going one way and
the cars going the other and you won't
even be able to understand yourself if
you do that.
But even more,
you're not putting your principles into
practice so you're disassociated.
You're being is dissociated.
So once you get your mind in your
emotions working together,
then the next thing to do is to act that
out consistently.
So that was the second conjunction as
far as young was concerned.
And then the third one was,
this is the tough one and this is the
one that's related to phenomenology.
You erase the distinction between
yourself and the world.
Okay,
that's a tough one.
So imagine you're dealing with someone
who's hoarding.
Now,
people who are hoarding are often older
or neurologically damaged or they have
obsessive compulsive disorder.
But then you walk into their house and
there's like 10,000 things in their
house.
There's,
there's,
there's maybe a hundred boxes and you
open up a box and in the box there's
some pens and some old passports and
some checks and their collection of
silver dollars and some hypodermic
needles and some dustin,
you know,
a dead mouse and,
and,
and there's boxes and boxes and boxes.
It's like that in the house.
It's absolute chaos in their absolute
chaos,
not order chaos.
And then you think is that their houses
that they're being,
is that their mind?
And the answer is there's no difference.
There's no difference.
So you know,
I could say,
well,
if you want to organize your psyche,
you could start by organizing your room
if they,
if that would be easier because maybe
you're a more concrete person and you
need something concrete to do.
So you go clean up under your bed and
you make your bed and you organize the
papers on your desk and you think,
well just exactly what are you
organizing?
Are you organizing the objective world
or are you objecting your field?
Or are you organizing your field of
being like your field of total
experience?
And young believed that.
And I think there's a Buddhist doctrine
that sort of nested in there that at the
highest level of psychological
integration,
there's no difference between you and
what you experience.
Now you think,
well,
I can't control everything I
experienced,
but that's no objection because you
can't control yourself anyways.
So the mere fact that you can't extend
control over everything you experience
is no argument against the idea that you
should still treat that as an extension
of yourself.
So you could say,
well,
let's say you have a longstanding feud
with your brother while sat a
psychological problem.
Is that him?
Is it a problem in the objective world?
Or is,
is it a problem in your field of being?
And it's very useful to think that way
because you might ask,
what could you do to improve yourself?
Well,
let's step one step backwards.
The first question might be,
why should you even bother improving
yourself?
And I think the answer to that is
something like,
so you don't suffer any more stupidly
than you have to.
And maybe so others don't have to
either.
It's something like that,
you know,
like there's a real injunction at the
bottom of it.
It's not some casual self-help doctrine.
It's that if you don't organize yourself
properly,
you'll pay for it and in a big way.
And so will the people around you now
and you could say,
well,
I don't care about that,
but that's actually not true.
You actually do care about that because
if you're in pain,
you will care about it.
And so you do care about it,
even if it's just that negative way,
you know?
Um,
it's very rare that you can find someone
who's in excruciating pain who would
ever say,
well,
it would be no better if I was out of
this sort of pain is one of those things
that brings the idea that it would be
better if it didn't exist along with it.
It's in controvertible so you get your
act together so that there isn't any
more stupid pain around you than
necessary.
Well,
so then the question might be,
well,
how would you go about getting your act
together?
And the answer to that,
and this is a phenomenological idea too,
it's something like,
look around for something that bothers
you and see if you can fix it.
So now you think,
well,
let's say there,
let's say you go into a,
you can do this in a room.
It's quite fun to do it just when you're
sitting in a room,
like a room,
maybe your bedroom,
you can sit there and just sort of
meditate on it.
Think,
okay,
if I wanted to spend 10 minutes making
this room better,
what would I have to do?
And you have to ask yourself that,
right?
It's not a command.
It's like our genuine question and
things will pop out in the room that you
know you like there's a stack of papers
over there that's kind of bugging you
and you know that maybe little order
there would be a good thing and you know
you haven't,
there's some rubbish behind your
computer monitor that you haven't
attended to for like six months and the
room would be slightly better if it was
a little less dusty in the cables
weren't all tangled up the same way.
And like if you,
if you allow yourself just to consider
the expanse in which you exist at that
moment,
there'll be all sorts of things that'll
pop out in it that you could just fix.
And you know,
I might say,
well if you were coming to see me for
psychotherapy,
this easiest thing for us to do first
would just be to get you to organize
your room.
You think,
well is that psychotherapy?
And the answer is,
well,
it depends on how you conceive the
limits of your being.
And I would say start where you can
start.
You know,
if,
if something announces itself to you,
which is a strange way of thinking about
it,
as in need of repair that you could
repair,
then hey,
fix it.
You fix a hundred things like that,
your life will be a lot different.
Now,
I often tell people to fix the things
you repeat every day because people tend
to think of those as trivial,
right?
You get up,
you brush your teeth,
you have your breakfast,
you know you,
you have your routines that you go
through every day.
Well though those probably constitute
50% of your life.
And people think,
well,
they're mundane.
I don't need to pay attention to them.
It's like,
no,
that's exactly wrong.
The things you do every day,
those are the most important things you
do hands down.
All you have to do is do the arithmetic.
You figure it out right away.
So a hundred adjustments to your broader
domain of being and there's a lot less
rubbish.
And there's a lot of less rubbish around
it,
a lot fewer traps for you to step into.
And so that's in keeping with ewing's
idea about erasing the dis.
Once you've got your mind and your
emotions together,
and once you're acting that out,
then you can extend what you're willing
to consider yourself and start fixing up
the things that are part of your broader
extent.
Now sometimes you don't know how to do
that.
So you might say,
imagine you're walking down bloor street
and there's this guy who's like
alcoholic and schizophrenia and has been
on the streets for 10 years.
He sorta stumbled towards you and you
know,
incoherently mutters something.
That's a problem.
And it would be good if you could fix
it,
but you haven't got a clue about how to
fix that.
You just walk around that and go find
something that you could fix.
Because if you muck about in that,
not only is it unlikely that you'll help
that person,
it's very likely that you'll get hurt
yourself.
So you know,
just because while you're experiencing
things,
announced themselves as in need of
repair,
doesn't mean that it's,
you write that in there that should
repair them.
You have to have some humility.
You know,
you don't walk up to a helicopter that
isn't working and just start tinkering
away with it.
You have to stay within your domain of
competence.
But most of the time if people look at
their lives,
you know,
it's very interesting thing to do.
I liked the,
I liked the idea of the room because you
can do that at the drop of a hat.
You know,
we'd go back to where you live and sit
down and think,
okay,
I'm going to make this place better for
half an hour.
What should I do it they have to ask and
things will just pop up like mad.
And it's partly because your mind is a
very strange thing.
As soon as you give it a name,
a genuine aim,
it'll reconfigure the world in keeping
with that aim that that's actually how
you see to begin with.
And so if you set it a task,
especially if you have to be genuine
about it,
which is why you have to bring your
thoughts and emotions together and then
you have to get them into your body so
you're acting consistently,
you have to be genuine about the aim.
But once you aim,
the world will reconfigure itself around
that aim,
which is very strange and,
and it's,
it's,
it's technically true.
You know,
the best example of that,
you have all seen this video where you
watch the basketballs being tossed back
and forth between members of the white
team versus the black team.
And well,
you're doing that.
A gorilla walks up into the middle of
the video and you don't see it.
It's like,
you know,
if you thought about that experiment for
about five years,
that would be about the right amount of
time to spend thinking about it.
Because what it shows you is that you
see what you aim at and that man,
if you can get one thing through your
head and as a consequence of even being
in university,
that would be a good one.
You see what you a at.
And so because one
inference you might draw from that is be
careful what you aim at.
Write it.
What you aim at determines the way the
world manifests itself to you.
And so if the world is manifesting
itself in a very negative way,
one thing to ask is,
are you aiming at the right thing?
Now,
you know,
I'm not trying to reduce everybody's
problems to an improper aim.
People get cut off at the knees for all
sorts of reasons.
You know,
they get sick,
they have accidents,
there's a random element to being,
that's for sure.
But,
and so you don't want to take anything,
even that particular phrase too far.
You want to bind it with the fact that
random things do happen to people.
But it's still a great thing to ask.
Okay.
So Rogers was a phenomenologist and he
was interested in,
he didn't start his philosophy from the
perspective of subject versus object or
from the idea of psyche,
like sort of inside you,
your mind with its layers.
That's not how we looked at it.
And so let's go through,
well,
I'll introduce you to rogers.
I think I'll,
and then we'll talk about it more next
time.
I'm going to start with something that I
learned from him that I think it was of
crucial importance and so we'll set the
stage for the further discussion with
with this,
and I'm going to read it to you,
assuming a minimal mutual willingness to
be in contact and to receive
communications,
we may say that the greater the commuted
con communicated congruence of
experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual.
The more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same qualities,
mutually accurate understanding of the
communication's improved psychological
adjustment and functioning in both
parties and mutual satisfaction in the
relationship.
It's quite a mouthful.
What does it mean?
Assuming a minimal mutual willingness to
be in contact and to receive
communications.
Okay,
we're having a conversation.
I'm deciding I'm going to listen to you.
Right?
That's different than the people,
how people generally communicate.
Because usually when they communicate,
they're doing something like,
okay,
we're going to have a conversation and
I'm going to tell you why I'm right and
all win.
If you agree,
or maybe you're having a conversation
where I don't know what you're trying to
do,
maybe you're trying to impress the
person you're talking to so you're not
listening to them at all.
You're just thinking about what you're
gonna say next.
Okay,
so that's not this.
This is,
you might have something to tell me and
so I'm going to listen on the off chance
that you'll tell me something that would
really be useful for me to know.
And so you could take about it as an,
as an extension of the Piagetian.
Piaget talks about the fundamental,
the fundamentally important element of
knowledge being to describe how
knowledge is sought,
the process by which knowledge is
generated.
Well,
if you agree with me and I find that
out,
I know nothing more than I knew before.
I just know what I knew before and maybe
I'm happy about that because you know,
it didn't get challenged.
But I'm no smarter than I was before,
but maybe you're different than me.
And so while I'm listening to you'll
tell me something I would,
I don't like,
maybe it's something I find contemptible
or difficult,
whatever.
Maybe you'll find,
you'll tell me something I don't know
and then I won't be quite as stupid and
then maybe I won't run painfully quite
as many things.
And that's a really useful thing to
know,
especially if you live with someone and
you're trying to make longterm piece
with them is they are not the same as
you.
And they're way they look at the world
in the facts that they pull out of the
world aren't the same as your facts.
And even though you're going to be
overwhelmed with the proclivity to
demonstrate that you're right,
it is the case that two brains are
better than one.
And so maybe nine of the 10 things they
tell you are dispensable or maybe even
49 out of 50 but one thing,
all you need to get out of the damn
conversation is one thing you don't
know.
And one of the things that's very cool
about a good psychotherapeutic session
is that the whole conversation is like
that all you're doing is trying to
express the truth of the situation as
clearly as possible.
That's it.
And so now rogers' proposition,
and I'll tell you why he derived it,
was that if you have a conversation like
that with someone,
it will make both of you better.
It'll make both of you is
psychologically healthier.
So there's an implicit presupposition
that the exchange of truth is curative.
Well,
that's a very cool idea.
I mean,
it's a very deep idea.
I think it's the most profound idea.
It's the,
it's the idea upon western civil upon
which Western civilization,
although not only Western civilization,
is actually predicated the idea that
truth produces health.
But for Rogers,
that was the entire purpose of the
psycho therapeutic alliance.
You come to see me because you want to
be better.
You don't even know what that means
necessarily.
Neither do I.
We're going to figure that out together.
But you come and you say,
look,
things are not acceptable to me.
And maybe there's something I could do
about that.
So that's the minimal precondition to
engage in therapy.
Something's wrong.
You're willing to talk about it
truthfully and you want it to be better.
Without that,
the therapeutic relationship does not
get off the ground.
And so then you might ask,
well,
what relationships are therapeutic and
answer that would be if you have a real
relationship,
it's therapeutic.
If it isn't,
what you have is not a relationship.
God only knows what you have.
You're a slave,
they're a tyrant,
you know you're both butting heads with
one another.
It's a primate dominance hierarchy
dispute.
Oh,
I don't know.
You're like two cats in a barrel or two
people with their hands around each
other's throats.
But what you have is not a relationship.
So all right,
we may say that the greater the
communicated congruence of experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual,
that's,
that's a reference to the same idea that
I was describing with regards to yoke.
So let's say you come and talk to me and
you want things to go well,
well I'm going to have to more or less
be one thing.
Because if I'm all over the place,
you can't trust any continuity in what I
say.
There's no end.
There's no reason for you to believe
that I'm capable of actually telling you
I'm capable of expressing anything.
That's true.
So the truth is something that emerges
as a consequences of getting yourself
lined up and beating all the,
what would you call
all the impurities out of your,
out of your,
out of your soul for black of a better
word.
You have to be integrated for that to
happen.
And you do that at least in part by
wanting to tell the truth.
The more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same qualities.
So one of the things that I've been
quite influenced by Rogers,
one of the things I tried to do in my
therapeutic sessions is first of all to
listen to really listen and then well,
well I listen,
I watch and well I'm listening.
Things will happen in my head,
you know,
maybe I'll get a little image of
something or I'll get a thought or a
question will emerge and then I'll just
tell the person what that is.
But it's sort of directionless,
you know?
It's not like I have a goal except that
we're trying to make things better.
I'm on the side of the person,
I'm on the side of the part of the
person that wants things to be better,
not worse.
And so then those parts of us have a
dialogue and the consequence of that
dialogue is that certain things take
place and then I'll just tell the person
what happened.
And it isn't that I'm right.
That's not the point.
The point is is that they get to have an
hour where someone actually tells them
what they think.
Here's the impact you're having on me.
You know,
this is making me angry.
This is making me happy.
This is really interesting.
This reminds me of something that you
said an hour ago that I don't quite
understand.
And the whole,
the whole point is not for either person
to make the proposition or convince the
other that their position is correct,
but merely to have an exchange of
experience about how things are set up.
And it's extraordinarily useful for
people because it's often difficult for
anyone to find anyone to talk to that
will actually listen.
And so another thing that's really
strange about this listening is that if
you listen to people,
they will tell you the weirdest bloody
things so fast.
You just cannot believe it.
So if you're having a conversation with
someone and it's dull,
it's because you're stupid.
That's why you're not listening to them
properly because they're weird.
They're like wombats or albatrosses or
rhinoceroses or something like they're
strange creatures.
And so if you are actually communicating
with them and they were telling you how
weird they really are,
it would be,
it would be anything but boring.
So,
and you can ask questions.
That's a really good way of listening.
But you know,
one of Roger's points is,
well,
you have to be oriented properly in
order to listen.
And the orientation has to be,
look what I want out of this
conversation is that the place we both
end up is better than the place we left.
That's it.
That's what I'm after.
And if you're not after that,
you've got to think why the hell
wouldn't you be after that?
What could you possibly be after that
would be better than that?
You walk away smarter and more well
equipped for the world than you were
before you had the conversation.
And so does the other person.
Well maybe if you're bitter and
resentful and angry and anxious and you
know,
generally annoyed at the world,
then that isn't what you want.
You want the other person to walk away
worse than Youtube because you're full
of revenge,
but you know you'll get what you want if
you do that.
So we know from our research that such
empathic understanding is already
defined that I want to hear you.
I want to hear what you have to say so
we can clarify it and move forward.
I want to have your best interests in
mind and mine as well.
But you know both at the same time and
your families too.
If we could manage that,
we're after making things better.
We know from our research that such
empathic understanding,
understanding with a person,
not about him.
It's such an effective approach that it
can bring about major changes in
personality.
Some of you may be feeling that you
listen well to people and that you have
never seen such results.
The chances are very great that you have
not been listening in the manner that
I've described.
Fortunately,
I can suggest a little experiment that
you can do to test the quality of your
understanding.
The next time you get into an argument
with your wife or your friend or a small
group of friends stopped the discussion
for a moment and for an experiment
institute this rule.
Each person can speak up for himself
only after he has first restated the
ideas and feelings of the previous
speaker accurately would accurately
means is they have to agree with your
restatement.
Now that's an annoying thing to do
because if someone is talking to you and
you disagree with them,
the first thing you want to do is take
their argument,
make the stupidest possible thing out of
it that you can.
That's the straw man,
and then demolish it.
It's like so then you can walk away
feeling good about it and you know you
primate diamonds dominated them really
nicely,
so,
but that isn't what you do.
You say,
okay,
well I'm going to take what you told me
and maybe I'm even going to make your
argument stronger than the one you made.
That's useful if you're dealing with
someone that you have to live with
because maybe they can't bloody well
express themselves very well,
but they have something to say so you
make their argument strong.
All right?
Then you see what this would mean.
It would mean that before presenting
your own point of view,
it'd be necessary for you to really
achieve the other speakers frame of
reference to understand his thoughts and
feelings so well that you could
summarize them for him.
Sounds simple,
doesn't it?
But if you will try it,
you'll find that it's the most difficult
thing that you've ever done.
Okay,
good.
We'll leave it at that and then we'll
see you on Tuesday.