Okay,
so I'm speaking with MFA and you may
remember that Dr Jay had invited me
awhile back to speak at Ryerson
University on a Saturday and that's been
a rather popular youtube video and um,
he's been defending me and,
and making comments about free speech on
the Ontario Psychological Association
listserv.
That's correct.
If I got the details right,
but maybe you could tell everybody
what's been happening.
Okay,
sure.
So,
uh,
back in November,
one of our members that will put out her
name,
but she wrote a piece where she
basically,
I'll just say what I wrote,
um,
she basically said that,
that you shouldn't have a forum for
discussing what you were supposed to
discuss and that was the top of you.
We're going to have the University of
Toronto,
the debate,
the debate.
Exactly.
And so she wrote a,
uh,
a piece,
um,
and put online and she posted it to the
list serve and I essentially wrote in my
email to the list or whatever.
I've written a number of comments about
this.
Uh,
and mostly I've been saying every time
I'm,
one of your stories comes up or another
similar story comes up,
I'm posting it,
they're saying,
look,
this is what's going on,
this is not some mad ramblings.
This is a legitimate concern about
ideology run amok.
And either I get met by silence or I get
people,
you know,
ask me why I'm so angry or why I'm
taking it so personally.
Or I get people emailing me back
channel,
mostly older people,
most of the oldest psychologists who say
we support you completely over,
afraid to say anything because of the
consequences.
And what do you think they're.
What consequences do you think they're
afraid of
that?
I don't know.
I mean,
I,
some of them work with these colleagues,
um,
others may be trying to get
professorships or trying to get tenure
and they were afraid that uh,
these people who do a hold positions in
academia could hold them down.
I think that's the biggest,
it's a perverse effect of the tenure
system because it tends to silence
people before they have tenure.
And so then of course they practice
being silent and by the time they do
have tenure,
if you've practiced being silent for
eight or 10 years,
then,
or six years for that matter,
then it's going to be pretty hard to
break that habit.
So,
so what,
so what are they objecting to with
regards to your postings?
So whenever I post something,
it starts off pretty neutrally and I've
written a long a message to the Ontario
Psychological Association.
I sent it to the president.
I asked them to read it to them,
uh,
they are convening or they had convened
a meeting,
uh,
to deal with this issue.
And,
um,
it was very,
very long.
And I said,
I have not actually done anything wrong.
I post links to stories such as yours,
like the last Friday one at mcmaster.
And then somebody goes one of two ways.
Either somebody will impugn my character
or my motives.
Uh,
recently somebody had implied that your
message is full of hate.
They actually use that word and someone
who has hate in his heart,
you know,
so and by extension myself or they will
ask a question and I will address it,
but for the most part they're
mischaracterizing what I'm stating.
And so I will simply say,
look,
I did not say that.
Show me where I said that.
And more often than not they're not
picking on any specific issue.
It's just the,
the theme because on the Old Pa,
apparently if you're on one side of an
issue it's okay.
If you occupy a different position they
won't accept it.
And so what,
what do you think has is going to happen
and what have people,
like you said that they've convened in
our so called emergency meeting about
this issue.
And so do you have any idea why it's an
emergency and,
and,
and what,
what they're planning to do?
Well,
I think they consider an emergency
because I'm one of the board members.
She's the one who wrote that piece
saying that you shouldn't have this
debate.
And I,
she took umbrage at a post that I wrote
where she's from noisy.
And you know,
I don't say this like they're not being
facetious,
she doesn't always eat.
And another person from Boise
instituted this studies in education.
For those of you who don't know,
you might,
if you were feeling charitable,
you would recall it regardless as
ideologically possessed.
Right?
Right.
So,
um,
so she's from and she's the one who
wrote the piece and then somebody else
will always.
He wrote what anybody,
any reasonable person would say.
It was a,
um,
a fair comment,
which is basically trying to say,
look,
can we all just be a bit more polite in
our tone,
more respectful.
And she listened to five points that we
should all aspire to,
which I don't disagree with,
but the problem is she's also from noisy
and there's a subtext to the message,
which is basically this message is
directed at me.
So what I did was I wrote,
and by the way,
she posted this after the president had
already shut down the discussion.
As soon as he shuts it down,
I really attract,
I'm not going to say anything but to
other people put postings on and they
directly,
uh,
you know,
basically,
like I said,
they,
they mischaracterize me and they looked
me and tried to make me look bad.
And so I spoke out and in one of my
pieces I said to her,
if you really believe in what you're
saying,
I said,
please make sure you apply this to the
people who are on the other side,
the ones we're calling to shut down this
discussion.
I said,
you know,
the president of the OPA shut down the
discussion.
What exactly does that mean?
How does he,
I believe,
how does he do that?
Why did he do it?
Well,
he sends out an email and says,
please,
this is getting a bit out of hand.
Will you please not talk about this?
That's about the extent of it.
And reasonable people will refrain.
I shouldn't even say reasonable.
Let's say,
um,
people are trying not to cause conflict
will,
we'll stop posting,
which I have done.
And their concern is,
I think that the tone gets out of hand.
And again,
I don't think there's any tone.
The worst she can say about my tone is
it's blunt.
There's no name calling.
It's literally every single time I say,
show me where I said this,
you know,
or if you,
you're mischaracterizing that.
Or I say your argument is irrational,
irrelevant.
Basically,
uh,
you know,
don't appeal to emotion.
We're dealing with facts here.
Let's deal with them.
And,
and you know,
and the team.
And
do you have any examples of this sort of
things that you've posted that you could
share with us?
Certainly.
So in one of the postings,
so this woman who again,
posting something that seemed
reasonable,
um,
I basically said to her,
I said some,
I'll just read this,
a couple of paragraphs.
Some members might find my direct
rational,
logical and fact based fact based
messages not only with respect to the
issues themselves,
but also with respect to claims made by
those who disagree with me.
For instance,
when I respectfully state,
please show me where I said or did this
to be rude,
offensive or inappropriate,
which to me is a gross misuse of such
terms.
However,
some of those same people have directly
stated or implied that I am a
misogynist.
I transfer a big,
get,
hateful,
reprehensible,
unreasonable,
and unwilling or unable to engage in
respectful discourse.
The next step is where I got where
things got heated.
I said moreover,
and I mentioned the,
uh,
the colleague I alluded to a few minutes
ago.
I'm explicitly stated on this with a
survey in November that she did not
believe that Jordan Peterson should have
been given a forum to discuss what any
reasonable person would agree is far
from an unequivocal issue.
She posted a link.
I posted it to an online article she co
wrote,
and this is critical,
uh,
that stated her reasons for what most
objective people should find a
concerning call for censorship of not
only non hateful ideas,
but also scientific investigation and
discussion as well as civil debate about
poorly conceptualizing worded
legislation that could potentially cause
unforeseen harm.
I wrote that and her response was she
actually posted a response and I hadn't
heard from her for quite some time and
let me just read it.
She posted or an annotate.
I have just as much right to express my
opinion as anyone else.
I already put you on notice once,
but I will say it again.
Please leave me alone.
That's what I think led to the emergency
meeting and you know,
look at the context I have every right.
I have just as much right to express my
opinion as anyone else.
I agree with that.
But why would she be calling for other
people not to have that same?
Right?
They bought prosy is astounding.
And so Carolyn,
I really don't know.
They may ask me to,
uh,
you know,
to leave the LPA.
They may ask me to leave the LISTSERV.
I'm one of the OPA strongest advocates.
I just,
you know,
every time I'm in the media I will
mention the work that they do.
They do a lot of excellent work,
including the presence so that he's.
He's done excellent work for
homelessness and for promoting
psychology.
So the worst they can do is,
is try to pick me out.
I know that this member in question was
trying to enact something against me.
So,
you know,
some sensor like more formal censure it,
it never happened.
Aside from a public review.
Precisely.
I mean,
you read some of the things that you've
written.
I mean,
why is it that you're being targeted?
Well,
first for an emergency meeting,
which seems a bit like overkill,
but perhaps it isn't,
but what is it that they're,
what is it that they have on you?
So to speak that would result in
centering of that sort?
They literally have nothing because I've
not called anybody names.
Um,
you know,
even when I called the a member
immature,
I didn't name them at all.
So the worst they can say is the tone
might become a bit hostile.
But this is what worries me.
I,
again,
I might be forceful,
I might be blunt,
I might be repetitive and verbose,
but I stick to the facts.
Uh,
and right.
And the problem is those facts are on
the wrong side of their ideology and
that's what's propelling them.
They can tell you them and the other
thing is that,
so as I mentioned that he receives quote
unquote dozens of complaints from
members who this is what is incredible,
who are basically saying that they do
not want,
they can't tolerate the distress that
comes along with knowing that I'm
writing emails to the LISTSERV and that
they might give up their membership.
This is a kind of issue that's going on
and again,
if you look at my posts and I've written
to the OPA and every time someone
criticizes me,
I specifically write,
show me one thing that I've written
that's inappropriate or offensive.
No one's ever called and they can't and
you have a record of all these postings.
I presume I have them all.
Yes,
there.
Is there anything in them that you would
be.
I mean that you've written that you
would be unwilling to make public,
assuming that you could get rid of names
and so on that might identify people.
Is there anything that would make you
uncomfortable about revealing publicly?
The only thing I'd be concerned about is
making sure that we're not violating
some ethical code,
which I guess would be portraying a
psychologist or a psychologist in a
negative light.
Um,
I don't know if this qualifies as that.
I think this is having an honest
discussion about a personal.
You would only be,
I would suspect,
responsible for portraying psychology in
a negative light if your portrayal was
unfounded from a factual perspective.
I would presume,
I mean
reasonable leeway in a,
in a,
in a policy of that sort.
Although the problem is those things are
subject to interpretation.
Right?
And that's my concern is,
is that interpretation I will seek legal
counsel.
I don't know if our coverage applies to
such a situation.
Um,
but I will ask the lawyers that we have
insurance for and see if this would
count as that.
I really don't.
What's happened to you,
if anything,
as a consequence for hosting me at
Ryerson.
I mean,
not a lot of attention.
The only consequence is that people have
been thanking me for being someone who's
standing out and saying you're standing
up and saying we need to have this
discussion.
Nothing so far.
Oh,
well that's good.
Yeah.
That's two.
Now the thing is,
um,
my next contract is coming due at
Ryerson.
I'm cinema,
sessional lecturer.
I've been teaching it for 15 years.
Um,
I always get the positions I applied for
it because I've taught so far off on a
total of 160 courses at universities.
Excellent reviews.
And um,
if I find this term,
that's the first time ever that I don't
get the positions I applied for,
that's the consequence we will find out.
I don't think that they would do that.
I think we have a pretty strong union,
but I don't have tenure as we were
talking about.
I don't have a secure position and I've
got a very busy clinical practice,
but to stop teaching,
to be not to be able to communicate with
students who want to learn,
who wanted to learn about critical
thinking and being motivated to
challenge ideas that be,
you know,
a horrible consequence.
Yeah.
Well,
there's always youtube,
you know,
what facing you,
but it is certainly possible with you've
got something to say that people need to
hear and it actually constitutes
reasonable quality education that in in
a,
I would not say precisely in a pinch,
but it certainly is an alternative and
you have full control over that.
Well,
it'd be very interesting to see what
happens with your,
with your contract renewal and we can
certainly have another talk at that time
whether it goes badly or whether it goes
well either way.
So what do you think's going to happen
to you?
What do you think's going to happen to
you overall as a consequence of this?
What are you afraid of,
if anything?
I mean the worst that could happen is
that somehow the college decides that
this is,
you know,
this warrants some kind of heavy
sanctions.
That would be,
you know,
somehow I lost my registration over
this.
That's the college of psychologists got
involved in Ontario rather than just the
Ontario Psychological Association
because the college for everyone who's
listening to colleges,
the body that regulates our clinical
side,
clinical psychologists licensure in
Ontario,
and to have them make any action against
one of their,
one of the,
one of the licensed psychologists and
Ontario,
that can be a very,
very serious thing.
That was definitely something that
worried me while it still worries me to
some degree,
but certainly worried me a lot back in
October and November when,
when the remote was more negative,
when the university was responding
negatively,
for example,
to what I was doing and sending me those
warning letters.
I mean,
so far nothing,
nothing has come of that.
But um,
yeah,
I mean,
and that's the only real yes it is know.
And practically speaking,
let's say the Ontario Psychological
Association Listserv,
the LPA lists or um,
a lot of people send out referrals.
And so if I'm qualified to deal with one
of the cases that they send out to you
can be guaranteed that certain people
will not pass that referral by way of,
I met my practice is busy enough as it
is,
but you know,
that would be a potential consequence.
This is why other people might not want
to speak out.
And again,
if I'm applying it
is,
it is this sort of thing that,
that is why people don't want to speak
out.
And it,
it also,
I mean,
I get letters,
hordes of letters,
dozens of letters from people who say
exactly that if they're afraid to speak
their mind,
students and students and people from
all other walks of life who are afraid
to speak their mind because they're
targeted by my people who have
censorship on their mind and malice in
their hearts,
I would say.
And who are willing to use whatever
means necessary to intimidate people
whose opinions they don't agree with.
So exactly,
it's really not good.
And the thing is though,
this is what's worrying me is that the,
uh,
the OPA OPA.
And what I can tell from the comments
that people don't see what you're
saying.
I mean,
I think they think you're being
hyperbolic reactionary.
Um,
you know,
they say,
show me one case and now the thing is
they always apply it to the transgender
issue.
And I say,
please try to see it at a different
level.
It's not just to put transgenders you,
that's just the context under which it
happens.
But the actual issue,
look,
this was about preferred pronouns.
It would've died out in about a week and
it hasn't died out at all.
Quite the contrary.
Everyone with any sense knows perfectly
well that this is about far more than
and preferred pronouns.
That just happened to be the issue.
Does your,
so to speak?
And.
Yes.
But I have to say though that the most
recent,
uh,
when I posted the talks that you had on
Friday at mcmaster university where they
shamefully a shut you down and you
weren't able to speak.
When I posted that somebody wrote me and
again,
and they wrote to me privately and then
publicly on the lists are asking me
about why won't you just say they are
focusing on that even though we can
cruise is a deeper issue.
This is the rigidity with which they're
seeing this issue.
A reaction.
The reaction.
Why won't he just say they to viewing
what happened at mcmaster university is
a little bit on the peculiar side I
might say.
So,
you know,
it's,
what do they say?
Swallowing a camel.
Well,
straining at a nap.
I think that's how that saying goes.
So,
um,
all right,
well,
so is there anything else that you
wanted to talk about tonight or is that,
does that basically cover your concerns
and describe what's been happening to
you reasonably well?
I think it does.
I mean,
and I'll,
I'll look into it and see what I'm able
to maybe post publicly so that people
can see what kind of discussions are
being had.
It,
you know,
I won't put any names,
it will just simply be no,
this,
this is the manner in which we're,
we're,
um,
we're communicating.
And again,
I
managed to,
that would be that people can judge for
themselves,
you know,
because at the moment it's sort of he
said,
she said,
which is not great.
I mean it's not like mean certainly I'm
listening to what you say and believe
that you're portraying it accurately,
but it's much better for people to be
able to make that judgment themselves.
So that would be,
that would be a useful thing to do.
Assuming that you can do it without
compromising yourself or anyone else in
any unreasonable manner.
But I also don't think it's unreasonable
to make things like this public because
quality can make something public.
You really have to wonder what's going
on.
So if there's a restriction against
sharing what's been happening on what's
more or less a public,
it's more or less a public forum.
I know that it's part of the Ontario
psychological association,
but it's not exactly private
communication and if you're going to
get,
if you're going to get in trouble for
what you're posting and it's
unreasonable,
it would be useful for people to be able
to see that.
But you can decide that so.
Well,
I'm sorry Jordan,
if I can say one more thing just because
I do want to be fair to,
to sell then.
I mean,
as I alluded to earlier is concerned is
that it might be violating some OPA.
OPA is hosted by the APA,
the American psychological association
lists or for whatever reason,
and he's concerned that,
you know,
that it might be violating that.
So for him shutting things down,
I have no problem with that.
If he's worried about that reason.
It's the,
it's the,
um,
I guess the message coming from the
other members,
which is essentially they themselves are
saying they shut it down because we
don't want to hear it and they think I'm
being just to again too arrogant or,
or forceful.
But again,
that's not the real reason.
The real reason is that they don't like
what I have to say and um,
but,
uh,
but again,
I understand the,
uh,
you know,
the ostensible reason for which,
uh,
they're,
you know,
they're shutting down the discussion.
I just want to make sure I'm clear on
that and I don't want to misrepresent
that.
That's what they're saying.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean it's hard to hard to know what to
say about that.
I appreciate,
I appreciate what you're saying about
it.
I mean,
it still seems to me that the whole
point of a list service so that people
can communicate their ideas and I do
believe that we're entering an age where
forceful discussion is going to be
regarded as somehow will oppressive and
violent.
And the problem is it's very difficult
to discuss anything of importance
without a certain amount of
forcefulness,
which you know,
is also directness and bluntness and
speech.
That's to the point.
And we certainly don't want to interfere
with that and otherwise.
Well,
for obvious reasons,
for obvious reasons.
Alright.
Well thanks very much for talking about
this and I,
I guess I'll know.
We'll know very soon exactly how this
went and maybe I can talk to you again
when we find out.
I'll give you an update to find out
what,
uh,
what they decide.