I have the distinct pleasure today of
being able to sit down and talk to Dr
Steven Pinker,
Harvard University,
who's just written a new book,
many.
He's written many books,
but this is the newest one.
It's called enlightenment now and it's a
New York Times best seller for seven
weeks,
so that was a great accomplishment and
darker pinker has indicated to me that
it's doing,
it's,
it's doing better than his other books
have and and that.
And they've also done very well.
So that's really something.
So Steven Pinker is the Harvard College
professor of psychology at Harvard
University.
He's a two time Pulitzer prize finalist
and the winner of many awards for his
research teaching and books.
He's been named one of Time's 100 most
influential people and one of foreign
policies,
100 leading global fakers.
His books include the stuff of thought,
the better angels of our nature,
the blank slate and the sense of style.
And so I'm welcoming Dr Baker obviously,
and I'd like him to start telling us to
start by telling us about the book
itself and then we'll talk about broader
issues and about the other books he's
written and that sort of thing.
Well,
the book's subtitle is the case or
reasons science humanism and progress at
all.
I'll begin with,
with the progress because that was the
epiphany that more than anything
inspired the book.
I'd been in a previous book,
the better angels of our nature when I
was surprised to come across data sets
showing that many measures of violence.
It declined over the course of history.
I was stunned to see a graph that showed
the rates of homicide from England and
other western European countries from
the 13 hundreds to the 20th century,
showing a decline of anywhere from 35 to
50 in the chances of getting murdered.
Uh,
when I,
uh,
called attention to this factor and a
blog post,
I didn't got correspondence from
historians,
from international relations scholars,
from sociologists say,
you know,
you could have mentioned other declines,
another decline of violence.
And War scholar showed that the greater
depth of war had plummeted.
Another showed me the rates of domestic
violence have gone down,
still another that rates of child abuse
had gone down.
And I realized that this was an
important story here that was a,
that it had to be told that these
different declines of violence ought to
be presented to the world in between a
single pair of covers,
uh,
just because it didn't seem to be
something of a pattern.
And as a psychologist it opened up the
challenge of how to explain it.
First of all,
how to explain the,
uh,
the fact that there's been,
that there is so much violence in human
affairs,
but also the fact that it can be brought
down.
Oh,
I had a similar set of epiphanies that
led to the writing of enlightenment.
Now,
when after better angels was published,
um,
I started to come across data showing
that other aspects of human wellbeing
had improved.
The rate of extreme poverty had
plummeted by about 50 percent just in
three decades.
And now stands at less than 10 percent.
Life expectancy has been increasing all
over the world,
including the poorest parts of the
world.
Uh,
the number of kids going to school has
increased,
including girls,
more than 90 percent of people under the
age of 25 on,
on the planet are literate now.
We have more leisure time.
We're safer,
uh,
in measure after measure life has been
getting better.
And it's not the kind of development
that you could learn about reading the
papers.
Quite the contrary because journalism
covers what goes wrong,
not what goes right.
You could easily come away with the
impression that the world was getting
worse and worse as a kind of statistical
illusion of a feeding,
a cognitive bias and not realize until
you look at data sets,
how many ways in which life has
improved,
including measures like war and crime,
uh,
which would,
what my guests are going in the wrong
direction as opposed to the right
direction.
And I combined that.
The other motivation for the book was a
set of attacks on the application of
science to the traditional domains of
the humanities,
to,
to history,
to the arts,
to morality,
to language.
Uh,
a,
uh,
an effort that I think is quite a
celebrity is the fact that,
that,
that scientific insights that are being
brought to bear on a Cuban affairs and
how could they not give him the,
uh,
art and society or are in a sense
products of our,
our psychology products of human nature.
But in a lot of intellectual life,
there's bitter resentment to any
application of scientific ideas or the
scientific mindset to human affairs.
This was first noted by CP snow in this
famous lectures and cultures in the
early,
late 50,
[inaudible] early 19 sixties.
But the conflict was very much with us.
I wrote an essay called science is not
your enemy,
which were published in the new
Republican,
which went viral.
And that was the immediate,
a kickoff for the proposal that ended up
leaving and enlightenment.
Now,
uh,
I was involved in something of a
literary spat with,
uh,
with Leon wieseltier and editor at the
new republic.
But I quickly realized that,
uh,
two guys having an argument is not
enough to,
to,
to pump out a book.
And so I had the centerpiece of the
book,
just be the documentation of a fact that
most people are unaware of,
namely that in most measures,
life has gotten better over time.
Now,
as with the better angels of our nature,
I didn't want to just present a bunch of
grants,
although I did present many graphs,
but I wanted to explain them and it
seemed to me that if we,
if there was any overarching explanation
as to wildlife,
get got better.
It's that people,
uh,
in the past thought that by
understanding how the world works,
including ourselves,
uh,
we can try to solve problems,
remember what works a drop,
drop the failures.
And as we accumulate are our cultural
knowledge,
uh,
we can improve our wellbeing.
And I attribute that mindset to the
light and the idea that we can use
knowledge to improve human wellbeing.
Now that might sound almost too banal
and that tribe to be worth defending.
And so I thought that those ideals very
much needed a defense.
Yeah.
Okay.
So you're waiting a number of things
together.
So the first is your discovery that if
you look at the data that things are
getting better at a rate that's so
remarkable that it is really nothing
short of miraculous and you've produced
dozens of graphs showing that in
enlightenment.
Now I noticed the same thing about three
years ago when I was working for UN
panel on economic sustainability,
the for the,
for the secretary general,
the original narrative was extremely
pessimistic,
detailed how we were disappointing the
planet and how everything was getting
worse and how we are at,
uh,
at each other's throats.
And I started to read extremely widely
and I found that on measure after
measure with some notable exceptions
like oceanic oceanic overfishing,
we have been doing so staggeringly much
better in the last 150 years that you
can't believe it on almost every,
on almost every measure you can imagine,
which is exactly what you detail out and
enlightenment now.
And,
and then now that that's a secret,
let's say people don't know about it and
the,
and that's strange.
And then you also associated with a
critique of the,
of,
of the enlightenment and scientific
rationality.
And it seems to me that you're implying,
or perhaps you're stating explicitly
that you're stating explicitly that
there's a connection between the
pessimism and the lack of knowledge
about this and the critique of the
enlightenment and rationality.
Because there's a question here.
If things are getting so much better and
if the news is overwhelming on that
front,
I mean some of the things you outlined
are like the weather,
the decrease,
decreases and starvation,
I suppose the most remarkable and the
provision of bountiful food on less and
less farmland,
which is not something that people know.
It's like if all this is happening,
why don't we know about it?
And how is it linked to the.
How do you think if,
if it all is linked to the critique of,
of enlightenment rationality,
what are the reasons is an interaction
between the nature of journalism and the
nature of cognition?
Namely the news is about what happens,
not what hasn't happened.
And a lot of the.
A very beneficial developments consists
of things that don't happen.
Countries that are at peace,
that used to be kids who are not
starving.
I'm a kid,
a terrorist attacks that do not have it.
You never see a journalist saying,
I'm reporting live from a country that's
been at peace for 40 years.
But if a war breaks out,
you can be sure that we'll hear about it
all.
The more so now that,
that a majority of humanity consists of
a,
on the spot video.
Journalists,
thanks to smartphones,
uh,
also a bad things can happen quickly.
Things can blow up,
worse can start a massacre,
can happen,
but good things aren't built in a day.
And they often consist of incremental
improvements,
but few percentage points a year that
the compound that,
that accumulate,
but that can never make the news because
they never happened all of a sudden on a
Thursday in October.
But together with all the,
the,
um,
cognitive impediments to understanding
the state of the world,
the fact that news reports a memorable
events.
And we know,
uh,
from these study of the cognition of
risk and probability from Daniel
Kahneman and Amos Tversky,
that we tend to assess probability and
risk by a shortcut called the
availability heuristic.
Namely,
the easier it is to I dredge up an
example from memory,
the more likely we think something is.
And so people think that a tornado's
killed a lot of people,
but they don't realize that falling off
ladders kills far more people.
I just.
Because when someone falls off a ladder,
it doesn't make the news,
but when there is a tornado it guys.
Yeah.
Do you know the solar power kills more
people?
The nuclear power every year.
I did not know that,
but it doesn't surprise me because
nuclear power kills no one.
And I suppose as installers,
fall off routes is full approves for
example.
Yeah,
exactly.
And well,
so,
so that's interesting.
So you can imagine that.
So good news or bad news is sudden it's
dramatic.
We're,
we're tilted towards the processing of
negative information in any case.
That's right.
And we don't naturally computer ratio
between,
uh,
occurrences and not occurrences,
which is of course what goes into a
probability and a rational assessment of
risk and probability.
So there's that,
that it's,
it's more than that in that because
intellectual life in large parts of
academia in a commentary caters and
pundits,
there is an ideology of a,
of decline goes back to the 19th
century,
a part of the counter of light that
arose in a,
as a reaction to enlightenment,
hope score for progress of rationality
that said that the,
that the holes that society is Western
civilization is teetering on the brink
or it's circling,
circling the drain and it's going to
collapse any,
any time now.
And it's up to the intellectuals and
commentators and,
uh,
to,
point out how beckon into degenerate
society is.
And to people like that musical progress
comes also sit in a front.
The reaction is,
hey,
we've been,
we've been warning all of you about how
society is on the verge of collapse.
Don't come around and tell us that,
but everything's going fine.
What are,
what are we going to do now
with the romantic types like Russo?
And when I was reading,
I,
I wonder to the,
there's a,
there's a powerful Marxist narrative
that's run its course for about 130
years too,
that's predicated on the idea that there
is an oppressed class and the no
pressure class and that narrative seems
also to thrive on or to be affronted by
the idea that the current,
the current system might be producing
benefits across the board.
I think you do in fact,
in one part of the book ask about
whether or not these benefits are only
accruing,
for example,
to the rich.
And that doesn't seem to be the case as
far as,
as far as the data indicates,
is that a fair,
quite the contrary.
The most dramatic improvements have been
at the,
at the bottom of the machinery,
uh,
extreme poor where,
the proportion of the world's population
living in extreme poverty,
Scala and over the last couple of
centuries from probably about 90 percent
to less than 10 percent.
And the United Nations has set as one of
its millennia,
elegant goals to eliminate extreme
poverty everywhere by the year 20,
30.
That's probably too optimistic.
But the fact that it can be set as a,
uh,
as a,
as a plausible aspiration is itself a
Scottish.
Well,
I know the UN had said as one of its
millennial goals,
the having of absolute poverty between
2000 and 2015 and that was accomplished
by 2012.
Exactly.
Ahead of schedule.
Yes,
exactly.
Has a complicated relationship to
progress because Marxist doctrine
actually does a layout,
a pathway to progress.
Unfortunately,
that pathway consists of violet class
conflict.
Uh,
it isn't the light and the ideal of
progress through,
uh,
through problem solving from the pro se
a,
a belief that a nature throws problems
at us and that if we apply brain power,
we can gradually chip away at them of
progress.
Is,
is quite different.
And you're right that there is a strong
critiques of progress both from the left
and from the right.
But from,
from the left,
uh,
is a,
kind of contempt for institutions like,
uh,
like markets like liberal democracy that
deserve a lot of the credit for the
progress that we've made in that we,
to,
at least in the academic left a,
a,
a despising of the very idea of
progress.
And I found that the only political
faction is actually sympathetic to
progress or libertarians.
There have been a number of rational
optimist books in the last decade by
people like Matt Ridley and Ron Bailey
and Johan Norberg that,
uh,
that do have overlapping vision to the
one that I took on lightening.
Now namely documenting progress.
Um,
but both from the academic left and from
the political right,
there has been a,
a,
a contempt for the notion of progress or
were there different reasons in
academia?
It goes back to the Romantics to Russo,
as you mentioned,
but also to Schopenhauer Nietzsche.
Heidegger,
the existentialists,
the critical theorists of the Frankfurt
school have large swaths of the academic
humanities.
Uh,
actually detest the enlightenment,
ironically enough.
Not by no means all of them,
but,
uh,
but there's a significant faction.
Yeah.
Well,
the questionnaire I guess in part is
why,
I mean one of the things that really
struck me as I've gone through this
material over the last years is that
this is really good news.
Particularly it doesn't really matter
whether you're on the left to the right.
If you're on the left,
you think that the fact that the poorest
of the poor are being lifted out of
abject,
absolute abject misery at a rate.
That's just.
I don't think you could hope for a
faster improvement no matter how
optimistic you were.
And then on the right of course,
the fact that the benefits of liberal
democracy,
let's say and free markets are driving
this in large part,
you take would also be a cause for
celebration.
So there's the.
You talked about the availability
heuristic and some of the role that the
press might be playing,
the stock that negative events stand
out.
We can also see negative events all over
the world now,
so we can't think of all over the world.
Whenever you hear about a negative
event,
it's as if it's happening next door and
is not as a threat.
So are the breadth of our news is
exaggerated and the coverage is
exaggerated,
but there still seems to me to be this,
this mystery at the bottom of all this,
which is in the face of such radically
good news.
Why is there such an insistence that the
system is corrupt,
that we're going to hell in a handbasket
then that,
you know,
human beings are a cancer on the planet
and everything is heading towards the
apocalypse.
It's,
it's so,
it's so deep and it doesn't seem to be
moved by the fact much.
I kind of think sometimes that it's a
hangover from the cold war,
you know,
that was so deeply pessimistic for so
long.
It goes back before the Cold War.
It certainly as a,
as a psychological syndrome,
it goes back,
at least to the Old Testament prophets
who combined kind of social criticism
with a,
uh,
fortunately at apocalyptic disaster,
absolute that syndrome,
that combination of a moral schooling
with predictions of doom.
It's something that our species quite
naturally falls into.
Part of it is frankly a certain amount
of,
uh,
interprofessional competition that
society has various elites.
A,
there's the politicians,
the business people,
the military,
religious elites,
the academics,
the journalists,
they're always kind of competing for
status since intellectuals don't deserve
a whole lot of credit for getting
society to run,
for,
for putting food in the stores.
And that keeping the peace and,
and,
uh,
protecting the streets.
It's very easy to,
uh,
to look down on other societal elites
on,
on government,
on business and to say,
well,
you guys are all failing and we're the
ones who are morally a refined enough to
point it out.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't put down just a sheer human
competitiveness.
I'm not the first to say this.
One of my favorite explanations of the
veneration of,
uh,
of the past of golden ages comes from
comms hogs.
You said competition of praise,
inclined to a reverence of antiquity or
men contend with living not with a dead.
It also seems that the,
um,
there's a certain amount of resentment
that is driving that as well.
And that would go along with the status
competition because there's anger.
I suppose if you're a member of anemia
group to see that your paradigm,
let's say isn't leading the charge
forward,
um,
that's what I did.
And you talked about the astonishing
decline in global poverty and a part of
that story is it did not come about
through massive redistribution,
which for,
for many people on the left was the only
route to lifting up the poor,
namely to,
to redistribute resources.
Now that have been,
of course adjust adjustments either
shocks the fact that China and India and
Bangladesh and Indonesia have risen out
of poverty,
uh,
came in part of the expense of
manufacturing jobs in the United States.
That's not exactly what people meant by
redistribution.
And it literally is a redistribution of
resources,
although it is a shaking up of the
economies of many,
many nations.
But this massive increase in the wealth
of that Asian countries did not come
because it was,
the horses were,
were shipped from the wealthy west to
the impoverished east.
Right?
So that's also a threat to the doctrine
itself,
a direct threat.
The fact that wealth is being produced
and it's being distributed to people at
the low end means that implies that that
redistributive philosophy is likely an
error,
and you can understand that might be
regarded as a catastrophic threat,
particularly the people on the radical
left,
well certainly,
certainly for radical notions of
redistribution,
but at the same time,
the more limited kinds of redistribution
that have,
uh,
that are ubiquitous in wealthy
countries.
I have a graph showing that the amount,
the proportion of GDP allocated to
social spending a skyrocketed in the
20th century from about one percent to
about 22 percent in every developed
country.
No exceptions.
Uh,
and,
uh,
thanks to,
to spending on the cooler on children on
the sick,
uh,
on the rates of absolute poverty have
fallen in wealthy countries.
So not only,
uh,
have,
developed developing world become
wealthier and not directly expensive the
developed world,
but in the developed world,
thanks to some amount of social
spending,
I guess you could call it
redistribution.
Uh,
the,
even as inequality has risen,
poverty has not.
Right?
Right.
I wonder,
I was just reading a book by Walter
Shadelle called the great leveler is an
excellent book and one of the things he
did was an empirical analysis of left
versus right wing governments,
I think across the 20th century,
but it might've gone farther back then
now to see if there was any difference
in the Gini Coefficient across the
classes of government.
And what he found was that there was no
difference whatsoever.
He makes a fairly strong case that the
only redistributive techniques that work
our pestilence and war essentially,
and that's because they knock everyone
down to zero,
but you're making a different case like
an incremental case in some sense,
which is that governments perhaps
regardless of their ideological
proclivities in the 20th centuries as
they've become more wealthy,
they have incrementally devoted the
larger part of their,
uh,
of their resources to incremental
improvements in.
You might think about it as an
investment in the future rather than
redistribution or investment in social
capital education and health care.
Those sorts of things that,
well,
it's probably,
it's probably some combination.
It's a combination of investment in
public goods because of course the whole
society is better off if,
if everyone's educated,
uh,
also in assurance,
people support a,
a,
a safety net that's most popular
euphemism for social spending because
you never know whether it's going to be
you or your or your mother or your
brother who's going to be,
who's going to be a need in the lottery
of misfortune.
And then part of it's part of it is,
is,
uh,
his charity,
he was the modern conscience,
won't allow the little match girl to
freeze to death.
The jokes to,
to,
to Barry,
grandpa by the side of route 66.
And so I think social spending has been
pushed along by,
by,
uh,
all three.
Uh,
it hasn't necessarily in some countries
it probably has reduced the Gini
Coefficient in western European
countries which have a more aggressive
system of taxation.
The United States or Canada,
but more important than the ginny
distribution is that it's reduced the
number of people living in poverty which
are morally relevant measure at any
case.
Yeah.
So those two things are complicated
because obviously you want to raise
people out of abject poverty.
I mean,
that's,
that's a,
that's a zero argument proposition and
that seems to be happening very rapidly.
The question after that I suppose is to
what degree does the remaining degree of
inequality that's generated by
productive capital assistance also
constituted social threat?
Because there is evidence it was
reviewed best buy in the spirit level
that as inequality increases rates of
male homicide,
for example,
increase in all sorts of other negative
measures.
So there's some weird interaction
between raising absolute levels of
wealth and ensuring that inequality
doesn't,
I don't know,
exceed some hypothetical optimal that,
that,
that needs to be considered in social
policy.
Are there,
I,
I signed some skeptical Ri analysis of
the data in the spirit level.
And probably absolute prosperity matters
more than inequality in determining a
social health include such as happiness,
crime,
um,
other kinds of social pathologies like
drug addictions.
Uh,
it's not easy to try to tease them
apart.
No,
definitely.
You know,
countries like Sweden are a very
egalitarian,
but they're also very rich that are more
lopsided,
but they're also very poor and so it
takes a little bit of statistical wizard
rated to tie them apart and my reading
of the literature is that it's actually
prosperity that is more important than
that at any quality.
But also,
and this is a point that in the
psychological literature rate was
emphasized by Christina's Storman's and
Paul Bloom that what people sometimes
think of as a sort of aversion to
inequality to people having different
amounts.
It's actually an aversion to unfairness
to injustice.
Yeah.
That,
but people would really infuriates
people who said they think that the
people at the top half ill gotten gains
equal if they sense that the system is
basically fair,
that either greater effort,
talent,
or even luck,
uh,
result in an unequal distribution of an
impartial lottery,
for example,
that they're okay with that.
It's cheating.
That really.
Yeah.
And people are really good at
remembering cheating and recognizing it
as well.
Yeah.
So,
okay,
so there is something we could talk
about for a minute because you know,
there's a,
the,
the is political.
What do you call rumblings about the
fact that I think a lot of this is
generated by the radical left types,
particularly on the campuses that the
system is rigged and that it's an
oppressive patriarchy.
And that the reason that people were at
the top is because they played power
games.
You know,
it's this,
my sense is that the control is that
we're,
we're ethnic or racial or gender groups
and we're competing in the Marxist
manner and those who win have one
because of oppression.
But I know the literature on the
relationship between the individual
individual differences and longterm life
success in the Western world and the
literature is actually very clear.
So intelligence seems to account for
about 20 percent of the variance in
longterm life success.
And then trait conscientiousness
accounts for perhaps another,
maybe 10 to 15 percent.
And then there's smaller contributions
of emotional stability.
Um,
and also have trait openness,
which seems to be a good predictor of
entrepreneurial ability.
So it looks like in the West that you
can attribute about 40 to 50 percent of
the variance,
maybe that's a little high,
but it's not.
It's not radical over estimate to the
sorts of individual differences that are
associated with productivity because
increases an Iq Higher Iq at higher
conscientiousness definitely make people
more productive.
It seems to me that you can use that as
an index of the,
um,
of the,
of the genuinely meritocratic nature of
a culture and also as an index of its
willingness to engage in fair play
because you'd expect if a,
if your culture is aimed at productivity
and it turns out that those are the most
pr and it turns out that the most
productive people are in fact
differentially rewarded.
That seems to me to be a reasonable
index of the success of the society.
Now that data is still leaves 50 to 60
percent of the variance and explained.
And so you can in there,
you can include racism and prejudice and
the tyranny of the system and blind luck
and physical health and all the
arbitrary random events that make up
that determined whether someone is
successful or failures in life.
But it does seem to me to provide a
metric saying that not only is our
society crazily productive and
reasonably and reasonably good at
district distributing the spoils,
even though there's still some
inequality,
but a fair bit of inequality is actually
generated as a consequence of
differences in genuine productivity that
seem reasonable to you.
Uh,
yeah,
it,
it ought to be obvious and the now
except for the fact that in a lot of
intellectual life,
the assumption is that the correlation
between psychological traits and success
at zero.
So the fact that it's what,
you know,
let's say it's 40 percent,
let's say it's 33 percent,
that's a lot higher than,
than most people are willing to
acknowledge.
What you said is exactly right.
That leaves more than half of the
variance not to be correlated with
individual differences.
And of course various inequities could
go into that.
And they're not mutually exclusive.
It seems hard.
We know that there's a lot of gaming of
the system,
particularly.
Yeah,
by the wealthy.
Uh,
and that should obviously be eliminated.
It's not meritocratic,
not fair.
It's not productive.
We could also ask another question is
whether the rewards that go to
untalented aren't necessarily in sectors
that lead to what we might call a
productivity in the sense of,
of,
um,
increasing societal wealth and an
argument can be made that there is some
misallocation of intellectual resources
that we have.
Uh,
the,
the economy is too driven by,
by finance that the,
uh,
there are too many lawsuits.
Legal system is who each other.
Uh,
and so,
uh,
arrested by intellectuals,
this does still leave a,
a,
a place for criticizing a number of the,
uh,
the ways in which our economy is set up.
There's always scope for improvement.
Yes.
We were talking about why despite the
fact that a fair bit of the variance or
a third to half of the variance in life
success is taken up by,
let's say,
individual attributes.
There's still room for a systemic
critique that's valid.
Yeah.
One of the pathologies of intellectual
life that I,
I wrote about it in the blank slate of
the denial of human nature was that,
uh,
the in,
in polite company in intellectual
circles,
the amount of life success determined by
a inherent and largely heritable
psychological traits has to be zero.
I mean,
that's just the,
the,
uh,
only acceptable position.
And you and I know it's not zero.
Well also just send me interject for one
second.
I'm also,
there's a fairness element there.
But the other thing is,
it seems to me that that's extraordinary
extraordinarily selfserving of people
too,
because if you get together with a group
of Harvard professors,
for example,
it's pretty obvious that their innate
intelligence is one of the factors that
determine their success and to deny the
fact that heritable differences make a
difference means perhaps to act as an
Avatar of a social justice orientation,
but equally to deny the role of,
of the benefits of chance in your own
success and to therefore lack a certain
degree of humility that you might
otherwise be required to have.
So it's not at all.
And I'm not claiming that you were
implying this at all,
but it's not all in the service of
higher social ideals that people denied
the contribution of,
of heritable components.
For example,
the birth laundry.
So,
whoops,
we just stepped.
Okay.
Uh,
unfortunately the video just froze.
And after you said,
I'm not saying you claim this,
you suddenly froze on the screen,
so I'm not saying you're claiming this.
Sure.
Well,
it's just,
it seems self serving for people who are
particularly bright,
for example,
to not be grateful for the fact that
they won the genetic lottery in that,
in that manner,
and sufficiently humble to not know what
the role of that arbitrary chance in
determining their success.
I mean,
it's not like they don't deserve their
success because of that.
But claiming a certain degree of
biological determinism doesn't
necessarily make you a bad person even
though it can be read that way because
it makes you very sensitive to your own
good fortune if you,
if you think it through carefully.
Oh absolutely.
In fact,
successful people are the winners of at
least three lotteries.
One of them that you mentioned,
of course it's the Connecticut lottery,
the fact that some people were born with
greater intelligence and
conscientiousness and openness to
experience.
Another is that there's a,
a second lottery in a human development
that is not strictly genetic,
but it is in a sense of constitutional
or developmental.
The fact that I might consider this,
one of the most profound discoveries in
the history of psychology that
correlations between identical twins
reared together are generally on the
order of five point five and they share
not only their genome,
but uh,
the vast amount of their environments,
their parents,
their neighborhoods,
their older siblings or younger sibs.
The number of books in the house,
number of guns in the house,
number of tvs in the house,
they're not indistinguishable.
Identical twins are a correlate quite
highly,
but no one near perfectly.
Which means that there is a second
lottery that has to do either with just
the way the brain congeals during
development,
which can be specified down to the last
snips by the genes and perhaps by chance
life events,
which might leave unpredictable traces
that we can't add a document store or
systematically understand.
Then of course there's the third lottery
of what happens to you in your
profession.
Did you bet on the right sector?
Did you happen to have a good
relationship with the boss?
Numerous.
It's a matter of being in the right
place at the right time,
the right time.
So all that having been said,
um,
and,
and you're,
you're absolutely right.
We have to acknowledge the role of a,
of hereditary temperament.
Untalent be known zero role of chance,
and that still leaves a big chunk of the
variants that could be due to a systemic
features of the system that perhaps
ought to be changed.
There's just no doubt that the wealthy
game,
the system,
particularly in the United States in a
number of ways that don't work to the
benefit of society at large.
There are also aspects of the system
that are perhaps fair but irrational.
The fact that so much of our
intellectual talent now gets sucked into
finance.
Now,
of course we do need a financial sector
and it's weird that they're smart people
in it,
but having a lot of our brain power
devoted to figuring out how to act on
financial information,
Microsoft microsecond faster than ones
competitors is probably not the best use
of our societies.
Intellectual capital.
Likewise,
there's no doubt that we have far too
much brain power invested in a legal
system in a corporation suing each other
patent trolling a and another not so
productive uses.
The funny thing is too though,
that there's an erotica erotica of
pathology in in a system.
In some sense.
I mean,
one of the things that struck me quite
hard for example,
is that if you look at the creativity
curves across the lifespan,
they matched the criminality curves
almost perfectly,
and one of the things that make me think
when I was doing that research was so as
young men become more antisocial,
they also become more creative.
Even though those things might not be
correlated,
but they do map on top of one another.
I was taking in a society like the
United States,
which has a fair degree of criminality,
but also a fair degree of creativity.
We have no idea how loose the system has
to be so that malfeasance can thrive so
that it can also be similar caneously
loose enough so that creativity can
thrive,
right?
Because you might think if you were
optimistic that you can tighten up the
system and get rid of the criminal
behavior without adding a totalitarian
layer to this system that would also
simultaneously demolish,
you know,
individual variability and creativity.
We just,
our models just aren't sophisticated
enough to see such things apart,
you know?
Well,
there,
there I,
I'm not so sure there.
I mean,
I,
I do agree with you,
there's a certain amount of,
uh,
risk taking or young men on the bake
that might underlie both criminality and
a productive creativity.
But,
uh,
over the course of history,
I think one of the accomplishments of
civilization and indeed have a,
uh,
an enlightenment driven progress is that
we have managed to tease them apart.
Just two examples are the fact that the
rate of homicide punished by a factor of
about 35 from the Middle Ages to the
20th century,
and that in fact that includes the
scientific revolution,
the industrial revolution lightened
meant into all of the advances of the
20th century.
So justice people were not stabbing each
other.
So for instance,
if they were also coming up with the
theory of evolution and the atomic
theory of matter,
and then again,
19 nineties when the rate of violent
crime in the United States fell by half
and they were also declines in Canada,
Britain,
other western countries.
This certainly it was not a time of
economic stagnation or.
No,
no,
no.
Fair enough.
I guess then the question starts to
become is how in the world did those
things get teased apart so that we are
able to regulate anti social behavior
without simultaneously making things
excessively rigid,
unregulated,
totalitarian.
We managed it.
Maybe it's part of that same incremental
process that you detailed out at the
beginning of our talk.
You know,
another thing that struck me about your
book that was quite interesting,
I thought it was that you list the names
of a very large number of totally unsung
heroes and those are people in.
We have a very interesting table near
the beginning where you list,
I think about 10 names,
maybe 12 of people who've saved between
hundreds of billions and billions of
lives with their scientific,
but they're incremental scientific
productivity.
And yet those are people that are by no
means household names.
That's another place where things don't
make the news.
Yes,
absolutely.
And it's a,
it's funny how our moral,
a crediting our moral,
our awarding of moral Brownie points
doesn't quite correlate with how much
good it often doesn't at all correlate.
Uh,
and the case of the inventors of
synthetic fertilizer,
vaccines of chlorination,
of public water,
supplies of the green revolution in
agriculture are,
are pretty much unknown.
And they literally say billions of lives
a.
whereas various reformers and profits
and agitators are a pretty well known.
A number of,
uh,
certainly people who are sanctioned by
the Roman Catholic Church who have to
perform a miracle that might resolve it,
results in saving one life,
of course,
in fact did not because miracles don't
happen,
but the fact that that definition of
saint has nothing to do with saving
lives on skills of millions or billions
to shows like human moral sense is not
really well calibrated to morality as we
would a defended by,
I think it was stolen who said something
like a single death is a tragedy,
but a million deaths is a statistic.
He actually didn't say it,
but,
uh,
but it's,
it's,
it's a conventionally attributed to him.
So let's say for good reason.
I mean,
I suppose I could have said it to or I
guess maybe the same thing plays in
reverse a,
is that
the saving of a single life has a
narrative punch and the incremental
savings of 100 million lives,
especially through prevention.
That's another problem,
right?
Because prevention isn't dramatic
because the terrible thing merely
doesn't happen.
And that's not,
um,
I,
I rather cheekily wrote an article on
the human moral sense that began with a,
who do you,
who do you think is most morally
praiseworthy,
Mother Teresa or Bill Gates or Norman
Borlaug.
And this was before a gates is pivot
from a computer technology to
philanthropy was,
was well known.
It was about 10 years ago.
And I set it up as a bit of a trick
question because of course everyone
would say mother Teresa,
even in our field and in of moral
psychology,
whenever a speaker has to pull out at
the end example of a particularly moral
person,
Mother Teresa is the stereotype.
Even though if you ask people,
well,
what exactly did she accomplish?
Uh,
how many lives did she save?
How many sick people did she actually
cure?
A,
it's very hard to come up with our
actual accomplishment.
What does Bill Gates has already been
credited with saving perhaps 100 million
lives through his efforts to eliminate
effective infectious disease loving
world.
And Norman Borlaug won the Nobel Peace
Prize in 1974.
His role in fomenting the green
revolution probably saved a billion
lives,
selective breeding of hybrid crops that
required less fertilizer that could be
grown twice a year,
less water,
higher yields,
less susceptibility to disease,
uh,
which are countries like Mexico and
India from,
from basket cases to exporters of food
in,
in less than a decade.
Right.
Do you think that would be a story that
everyone in in elementary and junior
high school would learn because it's
such a remarkable,
absolutely remarkable story and no one,
I mean,
I don't know what percentage of people
would know his name,
his name,
but I don't imagine it's,
it's,
I suspect it's in the low percentages if
that.
I,
I'm,
I'm sure that's right.
I think it may have been a change.
I seem to recall a,
although I hate to begin any sentence
with when I was young,
uh,
but we,
we did read a heroic biographies of
medical pioneers,
like the discover of intuitive and that
Thomas Edison,
and I don't know if that kind of a
heroic biography of the innovator of the
inventor,
a scientist is as common in children's
education.
Yeah,
I suspect I strongly suspect not.
It certainly wouldn't be in Canada given
the tilt that our education system has
taken.
So.
Alright,
so a couple of a couple of broader
questions.
Again,
if you don't mind,
you have a whole corpus of work and
there are recurrent themes in some
sense.
One of them being things are getting
better in ways that we really don't know
and what are you,
what if you could have what you wanted
with regards to the impact of your
books,
what,
what would you want that impact to be
and also what do you think like one of
the things I've done on twitter recently
because I'm trying to figure out how to
use twitter is to tilt my tweets towards
people like human progress.org.
Someone you site in your introduction
and people who are purveying information
while including yourself by the way,
who are purveying information about how
much better things are getting and so
what impact would you like to have your
books have and how do you see that
playing out psychologically,
politically,
and what do you think people who are
listening now say could do practically
to get the good news out,
so to speak?
Certainly intellectual life should be
more data driven.
How bad you shouldn't be allowed to say
or talk about any reported trend based
on an event that happened yesterday or
this year because trend means change
over time.
And in so many areas we really do have
data and it's just irresponsible not to
cite those data,
particularly since they have become
increasingly available through websites
like our world and data and keeping
progress.
So I'd like to see a replacement of
ideological debate,
which so much of our current debate is,
it's whether the right or the left is
more St Louis Moral,
uh,
praiseworthy correct.
And more,
uh,
well,
let's look at the data.
It chances are that neither an off the
shelf position of the left door,
an off the shelf position of the right
is likely to have it all figured out.
No one is on this event or infallible.
These ideologies go back to the,
to the French revolution,
and they're unlikely to be the font of
solutions to complex problems.
What?
Let's try to see what works and what
doesn't and come up with the mixture of
what is most likely to solve our
problems.
Spoken like a true proponent of the
enlightenment.
Yeah,
I guess,
uh,
and stepping back even farther,
I would like to see a greater
integration of the,
um,
uh,
the insights and mindset of the science
into social and cultural affairs.
As we talked about earlier in the
conversation.
This very idea is often met with horror.
I don't just.
The humanities types I suppose in some
sense,
aren't very happy with the idea that
they'd have to learn statistics.
And I can,
I have a certain amount of sympathy for
that perspective.
But.
Well,
there isn't.
Yes,
there is a,
a horror therapy,
uh,
expanding realm of five member in data.
And a horror,
Epi,
a thought that,
uh,
ideas about human nature from,
from science,
from evolutionary psychology,
from behavioral genetics,
from social and personality and
cognitive psychology might be brought to
bear on our understanding of society,
of justice,
of,
of art,
literature,
fiction.
Quite contrary to be the mindset of the
enlightenment where all of the
enlightened few us off.
We're a pretty serious psychologists.
It'd be the field didn't exist at the
time,
so they weren't called that,
but they a mind the observations from,
from travelers and missionaries and,
uh,
and explorers,
Opi ways of other cultures.
They relied on their own observations
and common sense.
They tapped into what brain science
existed at the time.
So it's not a,
it's hardly a radical idea that our
understanding of,
uh,
of art and culture and society should be
informed by our,
of human nature.
But now the disciplines have become so
professionalized and they're housed in
different buildings on campus and
they're rivals for the money from the
dean.
Uh,
there's a great hostility to the old
enlightenment idea of consilience is
often a,
a,
a paranoid fear that this means that the
sciences we'll take over the humanities,
which of course is preposterous.
They wouldn't,
they would want to,
they couldn't there be good.
No,
and I think the sciences can really
inform the humanities.
I mean,
versa.
Yeah.
I'd been trained as a scientist.
My appreciation for the humanities is
actually substantially deepened.
So in here,
and indeed in many fields,
this is a complete my,
what am I own fields of linguistics.
It's just taken for granted that.
And no one really cares where the
humanities influences.
I ended the scientific ones.
Studies of philology of classical
grammar,
of a,
of texts now blend into a statistical
studies of Corpora of laboratory studies
have speech and language processing.
And uh,
the where the science ends up in the
ends off the humanities begins.
No one even talks to him.
The science can also really change.
Can really change your mind.
Like I've looked at individual
differences in relationship to political
belief.
And so I've learned three things from
doing that that I think are
revolutionary have been revolutionary
for me.
So the first is that I'm liberal.
Lefty types are characterized by higher
trade,
openness and lower conscientiousness,
and then conservatives,
the reverse and I,
I think,
well that's quite interesting because it
puts the liberal left types into
creative entrepreneurial domain because
that's characterized by high openness
and it puts the conservative types in
the managerial and administrative
domain.
And so that implies that the liberal
left types create new ideas and new
enterprises including entrepreneurial
enterprises because the data there is
fairly solid.
Whereas the conservative types manage
and administer those enterprises and so
each needs the other.
And so there's that nice polarity
dynamic.
And then there's also the idea that the
reason that openness and
conscientiousness unite to predict
political behaviors because of borders.
So open people liked the borders between
concepts to be fluid so that there's
information exchange and they're not
orderly.
The liberal types because they're not
conscientious.
And so they don't see any utility in
keeping things categorically distinct.
Whereas the conservatives are afraid of
the contamination of things because of
the movement of information and they
like to see the borders between things
to to ensure that that's the case.
So the reason that openness
conscientiousness stack together as
predictors of political behavior seems
to be because of the two fundamentally
different attitudes toward towards
borders all the way from the conceptual
to the political,
so the right wingers think while borders
are good because that stops and
contamination is a real problem and a
definitely problem often and the liberal
lefty type state,
no,
no.
We want as much information to flow as
possible and both of those perspectives
are valid and need to be discussed.
Then the other thing I learned from the
American empirical data was that
orderliness,
which is part of the part of
conscientiousness predicts conservatism,
is associated with disgust,
sensitivity and so that that feeds that
desire to maintain borders so that
there's no cross contamination that's
associated with what's been called the
behavioral immune system,
and so those are actually quite
revolutionary ideas from the perspective
of political theory or political belief
is temperamentally determined that the
reason that the two temperamental traits
determined political belief is because
of a difference in attitude,
fundamental difference in attitude
towards the borders between things that
you can make a case for open and closed
borders on evolutionary grounds and that
there's a.
there's an association between
conservatism and discussed,
which for me shed tremendous light,
for example,
and the motivations of Hitler who was an
extraordinarily orderly person and who
used disgust oriented language all the
time when he was formulating his
policies of extermination.
So those are revolutionary contributions
of individual,
different science to political theory.
It's all driven by hard data
statistically derived.
Well,
I,
I agree and I can sense the kind of
paranoid reaction that these claims
might elicit among some traditional
political theorists and thinkers that,
oh,
are you saying that the conservative
beliefs are nothing but an expression of
disgust sensitivity,
and of course it doesn't apply,
that he's a fascinating findings.
Don't say that the earned income tax
credit is a good or a bad idea,
or the Paris climate accords themselves.
The issue still have to be decided on
their merits the other hand,
if you do,
if you are aware of your own potential
biases than that,
that is a source of insight.
It's a source of understanding.
It could cause you to step back from
your own convictions and be more
receptive to arguments on both sides.
Of course,
that was definitely done.
That for me,
that it can't not be a helpful.
CanNot be an important source of insight
as to how political debates unfold.
Yeah.
Well,
if you know that the liberal left types
are necessary for the fostering of new
enterprises and the Conservatives are
necessary to run them,
then that certainly indicates why both
groups not only are necessary,
but are all of mutual benefit.
Somebody has to maintain systems and
someone has to expand them and those
things are gonna work in opposition to
one another because expanding a system
often fragmented,
so there's gonna be tension,
but no system can remain static forever
and,
and completely untrammeled
transformation throws everything into
chaos.
So there obviously has to be a dialogue
between those viewpoints like a,
it's like an opponent process issue
essentially.
And
yes.
And,
and,
uh,
all of us ought to be more aware,
have more insight into how our own
psych,
psychological proclivities might,
uh,
affect the positions that seem to each
of us to be obvious.
Well,
and that is what they do,
right?
Because the temperamental variable or
variables actually tell you what is self
evident.
That's how they operate.
My understanding from,
from the literature that you're citing,
is that the,
the,
uh,
variance and opinions that is correlated
with personality differences,
uh,
is also the hardest to get people to
give up to,
to persuade them.
Yeah.
Well,
I,
no doubt because I think the,
those temperamental differences are like
axiomatic values,
you know,
and they're grounded and I think they're
grounded in the hyper development of
separate circuitry.
So it's going to be very,
very mean.
And I also think that like,
if you're an x,
if you're an introvert,
you want to learn to be an extrovert,
you have to learn it.
Micro skill by micro skill,
right?
There's no revolution,
there's no revolutionary cognitive
transformation that's going to turn you
into an extrovert.
You can pick up the skills,
but it's bit by bit and it's
incremental.
And so I think it's the same with
political attitudes is you can develop
an appreciation for the viewpoint of
people who are on the other side of the
temperamental divide,
but it's a,
it's an increment by increment advance
and it's very,
very effortful but necessary.
It's necessary.
You know,
it's been really useful to me to see
where the cognitive,
sociological,
political utility of both political
temperaments lights and,
and,
and why it's so crucially important.
I mean,
with regards to disgust sensitivity,
you might think,
well that's pure reduct purely
reductionistic with regards to the
conservative viewpoint.
But no,
a lot of people in history have died as
a consequence of cross cultural
contamination,
right?
I mean there are estimates that up to 90
percent,
maybe even 95 percent of the native
Americans parish because of their
exposure to the Spaniards.
Right?
And so the idea that contamination is a
problem when,
when two things that were distinct unite
is,
is a truism and it's a powerful
evolutionary force and equally powerful
as the observation that.
Well,
yeah,
despite that,
despite that though,
the benefit of information flow,
free information flow and trade is so
overwhelming that you can't throw the
baby out with the bathwater.
Yes.
It's the case where the,
the,
uh,
evolutionary adaptive value of a,
of a motive or a,
an emotion is explicable.
And we can also recognize that thanks to
advances in science and technology,
the emotions themselves are no longer
particularly effective defenses against,
uh,
this case infection by my pathogens.
We have much better ways of protecting
ourselves,
but we are stuck with these ancient
adaptations which are,
are no longer quite so adaptive.
It can be harmful,
especially to treat other people on the
metaphor of contaminants are pathogens.
And you're certainly right that in,
in,
in Hitler's rhetoric,
despite the fact that he is often a
claimed to have used eugenic ideas to
motivate a genocide against the Jews,
much more of his language came from,
uh,
from pathology and histology.
Oh yeah.
It's contempt.
And there was a parasite
parasites.
Exactly.
Microbiology,
not genetics that Hitler is
ideas.
So I thought we might close by.
I have a question for you about your,
your derivation of these moral virtues
specifically from the enlightenment.
And I'm curious about that because.
Well,
first of all,
you could make a case that it wasn't so
much the enlightenment as it was the
specifically the rise of empirical
science.
And then you could of course have a
discussion about how those two things
are related,
but I'm also curious.
I've been reading Ian mcgilchrist book,
the master and his emissary and mcgill.
Chris makes a pretty strong case.
I would say that get the rationalistic
enlightenment values are in some sense a
consequence of the articulation of an
underlying set of principles that are
more metaphoric in nature,
more narrative in nature.
The case I also made in my book maps of
meaning and to some degree in 12 rules
for life that the enlightenment project
and it's rationalities nested inside a
deeper web of metaphor and ritual and
image that would be associated with
longer scale cognitive processes,
some of which are expressed in religious
thinking,
but some of which are grounded in not so
much rationality as in motivation and
emotion and the way your book is
structured.
And I think the way enlightenment
thinkers think is that there was a
miracle of sorts that occurred sometime
in the last three to 500 years and
people woke up and became rational.
And then the question is to what degree
was the ground for that awakening?
Prepared by events that weren't the
awakening itself,
but there were associated with other
processes and I'm just curious as to
what your thoughts are on that.
Uh,
there's nothing new under the sun and a
good intellectual historian can find the
antecedents of any intellectual movement
in various precursors.
Um,
you know,
it's hard to.
I don't think there's a lot in the
enlightenment that can specifically be
attributed to,
to,
um,
to a religion,
particularly Christianity just based on
the fact that it was already around for
a thousand years and nothing much
happened.
So it couldn't be religion or
Christianity itself.
Although there are,
as you say,
there are strands that were carried over
for in particular,
and this is an insight that I got from
my other half,
Rebecca Goldstein,
my wife,
uh,
who,
who are,
you've appeared on stage with winter.
The one thing that the Greeks didn't
have that,
uh,
the Christianity did was the idea of
compassion for the week and,
and universal human flourishing.
You don't really have that for all of
the brilliance of a,
of ancient Greece.
That wasn't a,
a big feat.
But the enlightenment,
of course,
did not spring out of,
out of nowhere,
if I were to identify the emphases,
what your why,
what,
what happened prior to the 18th century
that allowed her to fold them as opposed
to a couple of hundred years earlier,
a couple of hundred years later,
one of them was the scientific
revolution of conventionally located in
the,
in the 17th century,
which not only provided a kind of a
paradigm for understanding,
namely a testing propositions against
the empirical world,
seeking deeper naturalistic explanations
for phenomena.
And which,
of course overturned a millennia,
old dogmas reminding people that they're
their own common sense,
their own societies,
convictions were fallible.
So that was,
uh,
an essential precursor.
Another one was the discovery of the,
uh,
of the new world,
that there were entire civilizations,
entire world,
literally worlds in the sense that it
had been a unknown,
that the knowledge base that they had
been part of a Western civilization for,
for Millennia was radical,
incomplete.
And technologically,
I suspect that the greater,
uh,
exchange of ideas and people,
was a contributor of the prior to the,
just prior to the lightning in the
second half of the 18th century,
there's a massive growth in the
efficiency of a printing printing
presses itself,
but it was the democratization of books
and pamphlets,
the rise literacy,
uh,
and the movement of people.
It became easier for,
uh,
for,
for heretics and radicals to jump ship
and move to where things were cooler,
if things got too uncomfortable where
they were.
And it's amazing how many of the
enlightenment thinkers were persecuted
for their beliefs,
who they were threatened with,
imprisonment or death.
Many of them ended up in Holland or
Paris or London,
or jumped around to wherever they had
made the greatest freedom,
but also just the sheer,
a kind of precursor of the,
uh,
the web today.
The fact that pamphlet can be introduced
and within a few months and it will be
translated into a dozen European
languages and,
and smuggled in.
So the exchange of ideas,
uh,
I think it helped to accelerate the
route,
although since it only happened once in
human history,
we can never really know for sure why it
happened,
when it did.
But those are three good hypo.
Yes.
Well,
and we're in an interesting time now
where we can sit and make a video like
this and publish it almost
instantaneously and share it with half a
million people.
I mean that,
that ability to share ideas rapidly as
developing a pace and God only knows
what the consequence of that is.
We're,
we're in a situation now which has only
occurred to me about last year where the
spoken word for the first time in human
history has the same breach and
longevity as the written word.
And it's easier for people to listen.
No audio books are becoming very
popular.
Lots and lots of people listen to
podcasts.
You know,
I have working class people come to my
talks all the time and say,
look,
I'm sitting in my forklift for three
hours a day and I'm doing nothing but
listening to podcasts,
you know.
So that's,
that's a really remarkable thing.
So I think,
I think I'm going to let you go.
You've been very generous with your
time.
I appreciate the conversation very much.
I'm going to close by showing your book
again,
Steven Pinker's,
new book and lightened now,
which is tearing up the bestseller
charts and which is a guide to proper
end intelligent optimism in the 21st
century.
And maybe I'd ask you just in closing,
what do you think there are things that
individuals,
what do you think individuals should be
particularly optimistic about right now
and what do you think individuals could
do to spread the message that things are
getting better and that we can solve our
problems?
The fact that there are new efforts to
try transcend political divisions and
find out what works.
I tend to politicize and rationalize a
problems like poverty,
like climate change,
a light like war and peace like crime.
Those are very much worth supporting
organizations like at a political.
There are ngos that try to monitor the
state of the world.
There's effective altruism.
There's just the general application of
rationality to solve our problems that
is responsible for the progress that
we've enjoyed in the past and if there's
going to be progress ahead of us will be
responsible for what will enjoy in the
future.
All right,
well I'm,
I'm,
I'm would like to close to by mentioning
to everyone who's listening that you
know,
things are getting better.
They're getting better because people
are facing problems and actually trying
to solve them.
They're doing micro analysis of the
problems,
breaking them down into their
constituent elements,
being humbled enough to use incremental
solutions to solve them and to address
them at,
at,
at a high level of resolution instead of
a low level of or a low resolution level
of ideological debate.
And it's really working.
And I would,
um,
what would we say encourage people to
pick up Dr Baker's book because the
world is getting better and we should
know it and we should be happy about it
and we should continue to foster that
development in every way that we can.
And I think this is an excellent book as
an excellent contribution to that effort
as well as your other books like are,
are better,
better,
better angels of our nature.
So thank you very much for spending the
time with me today and for talking with
me and it was a pleasure to meet you.
Thanks so much.
Thanks for having to Jordan.
The pleasure was mine.