So in the first lecture,
I already told you guys a little bit
about this,
about this figure and I mentioned that
the idea of being swallowed up by a
beast of some sort and then cast back up
is a very ancient and archetipal idea
and an architectural idea you might
think of as an instinctive idea.
This is,
this is an idea of Carl Jung by the way,
although it had its precursor,
is another intellectual systems of
thought.
You might think of an archetype as an
idea that you can understand without
being predisposed to it.
Now,
now blank slate models of human
cognition assumed that all of our
knowledge comes from our sensory
experience.
But first of all,
there are very many problems with the
blank slate model.
First of all,
blank slate models are just wrong.
Like they're,
you know,
they're,
they were useful conceptual structures a
couple of hundred years ago and there
were situations where they could be
applied in part to
two systems of thought,
like,
um,
behaviorism.
But fundamentally we know perfectly well
that the human being is not a blank
slate.
And we also know that you couldn't be a
blank slate.
And the reason for that is that there is
so much information so to speak,
surrounding you and making up your
experience that without some a priori
structures to handle that experience for
you and present it to your consciousness
in a,
in a pre structured manner and there's
just not a chance that you could ever
make sense out of it.
So plus we also know,
you know that your biology and your
neurobiology is very much similar to
that of all life on earth really for
that matter,
but extraordinarily similar to that of
mammals.
And we know things for example that are
quite interesting like
the systems that make up the deepest
part of your brains and partly the part
say that keep track of things like
dominance.
Hierarchies are hundreds of millions of
years old and you share structure and
function of those neurosis neuro
psychological elements with animals as
distinct from us crustaceans.
So,
for example,
crustaceans use the serotonin system to
keep track of their dominance
hierarchies.
And you do the same thing.
And drugs that work on people for
dominance,
hierarchy related disorders like
depression also work on lobsters.
And so,
so if you,
if you have a lobster,
you know,
that's a friend of yours and it's
feeling depressed,
then you could recommend that it uses
Serotonin reuptake inhibitors and
that'll make it,
you know,
happy stretched out,
sort of confident lobster instead of,
uh,
you know,
bunched up and insecure lobster.
And the reason I'm telling you that it
is pretty comical.
Um,
but the reason I'm telling you that is
because it indicates something of
tremendous importance,
which is that you are one old thing and
there are elements of your structure
that are,
you know,
that are importantly hundreds of
millions of years old.
And they structured the way that the
world appears to you.
And so
an article tipple idea in some sense is
a,
is an idea that you can understand
because you're a human being.
And you know,
if you think about this even for a few
moments,
you can understand how this might be,
you know,
if someone comes up to you and says,
I'm angry today,
especially if you've been conversing
with them for some time,
it isn't generally necessary for you to
ask,
well what do you mean angry?
You might ask,
well why are you angry or what happened?
But because the person who's making the
statement has a nervous system,
like your nervous system,
you can both mutually assume that you've
understood and experienced the emotion
of anger and stow instead of trying to
describe what that's like.
You can just describe the particular
situations that elicited it.
And you know,
there's lots of evidence for basic
emotions.
I mean the list of basic emotions varies
from thinker to thinker,
although they congregate around a pretty
definable sat.
And part of the reason that they differ
at all is because,
well,
it isn't obvious how you distinguish an
emotion from a motivational system.
And it's not even obvious that that,
you know,
the class of emotion is a reasonable
class.
But there are certainly,
um,
subjective phenomena that emerge as a
consequence of the active activity,
a fundamental brain systems that
everyone shares.
So,
you know,
people understand what fear means.
People understand what pain means,
disappointment,
frustration.
People understand what surprise means.
They understand joy.
Um,
they understand,
discussed,
I think I hit most of the major ones
there.
And then there's,
you know,
there's other systems that don't look so
emotion like that are maybe more
motivation,
like,
like hunger and thirst and,
and you know,
uncomfortable hate and uncomfortable
coldness that people also understand.
And the reason you understand that is
because you are a certain way and you
are a certain way because for the same
reason you have two legs,
most of you and two arms and two eyes
and all of that,
you know,
you're,
you don't just spring out of the void as
a completely unstructured organism.
And you know,
it's difficult to say exactly what
elements of human experience and
behavior and cognition and thought and
all that are inbuilt precisely because
we're also quite modifiable from a
cultural perspective,
you know,
so it's,
it's structured plus the capacity for
tremendous modification,
but,
and it's hard to exactly say,
well how much is structured and how much
is modification.
And partly the reason it's hard to say
that is because it depends on how much
effort you put into the modification,
right?
The more effort,
the more modification.
But having said all that,
the fact that we're similar in a priori
structure is actually one of the
preconditions that allows us to
communicate with one another.
So there was a thinker,
a Harvard thinker named Eel Wilson.
Some of you may be familiar with that
name.
He,
he's a famous biologist and he basically
studies ants,
um,
which,
you know,
ants answer very complicated and they're
very successful.
There are more,
there are more ants by weight than there
are people on earth.
So even though they're not necessarily
concerned with overpopulation and
environmental degradation,
there are in fact more ants.
So,
but one of the things he will Wilson
pointed out was that,
you know,
even if we could talk to ants,
we wouldn't have anything to say to
them.
And the reason for that is because ants
concerned themselves with things that
human beings have no intrinsic interest
in.
So their fundamental value structure,
so to speak,
is so different from our value structure
that there wouldn't be anything to talk
about.
Because you talk about with your friends
and with your family,
you talk about shared human experiences,
you talk about variation in shared human
experiences,
and you just take for granted that the
shared element of that exists.
And so you can think of the shared
element of human experiences
architectural.
And then you might think,
well,
part of the shared human experiences
architect will,
because we share an underlying biology
and also to some degree of culture,
but then there's this weird,
um,
what no man's land in some sense between
the biological system per se,
and the system of subjective experience
and ideas.
And you might say that the biological
systems or ideational to some degree.
So you can imagine if you get angry,
you think angry thoughts.
And so what that means is the system
that mediates aggression is also capable
of thinking.
It thinks in abstractions.
And so there's a,
there's some relationship between the
biological function which prepares your
perception and your body for action and
your capacity for abstract thought.
The,
the system that produces anger in some
sense thinks within you.
It's really more accurate way of
thinking about it because as you all
know,
if you've become particular angry during
an argument or a discussion with
someone,
you may say things that you,
whatever you are,
comes to regret very soon after the
conversation.
And so it's as if in some sense the
system is speaking within you.
And if you start to think that way,
you can also develop much more
understanding right away of what the
psychoanalysts were about when they
started to talk about unconscious
processes.
So you could say [inaudible] this is a
realistic way of thinking about it.
Is that what the psychoanalysts,
um,
identified as unconscious process is in
some sense where the thought patterns in
word and image and sometimes in behavior
as well of fundamental biological
systems working within you.
And so even someone like Freud for
example would say approximately look,
you know,
you're a relatively loose collection of
somewhat integrated biological
subsistence and each of them posits a
goal that's worth attaining.
But the problem is is that many of those
goals exist in contradiction to one
another.
And your problem as an organism is to
unite those diverse biological goals.
And that would be the ID for example
from a [inaudible] perspective to unite
them into something that's relatively
coherent and non internally
contradictory.
And then also to express that union in
the social sphere where hundreds of
thousands of other creatures,
more or less like you are trying to do
the same thing.
That's a tricky balancing act.
And so,
but these,
these systems inside of you so to speak,
are informing you constantly.
And some of that they do with direct
physiological sensation because there
are generally sensations that are
associated say with motivational states
or with emotions.
So,
and we kind of think of those as
feelings,
whatever that means.
And then,
um,
there are ideas that are associated with
the two and some of those ideas are,
while they're often fantasies.
So I can give you an example of that.
So it turns out that the interest that
women have in sexual behavior is
dependent to some degree on their blood
levels of testosterone.
And that varies across the menstrual
cycle.
And so women tend to be most interested
in sexual activity when their fertility
is at a peak,
which is just after they offer late.
And,
but it doesn't look like testosterone
produces an increase in sexual behavior
in a causal sort of manner,
like a drive.
What seems to happen is that the
testosterone produces an increase in
sexual fantasy and the fantasy produces
the impetus for the action.
So that's a very interesting way of
thinking about it,
you know,
because what happens in some senses that
the biological system that's underlying
sexual desire sets up a world in
imagination that is more likely to
contain images of sexual gratification
and the organism so to speak,
follows in its wake.
And you know,
you can see this.
If you pay attention to the structure of
your own imagination,
you can see this sort of thing happening
all the time.
You know,
if,
if you're in an argument with someone
for example and they humiliate you or
put you down and that produces feelings
of resentment.
If you watch your imagination like it
might be quite conscious and it might be
quite fleeting,
you'll see that fantasies of revenge for
example in different scenarios of
revenge play out in the landscape of
your imagination.
You know,
and when you're hungry you're studying
the way in me,
you're concentrating on something and
you know your blood sugar level falls
enough.
So your hypothalamus notes that maybe
it's time for a few calories and so it
starts to pop up,
you know,
an alternative sit,
a sequence of ideas,
you know,
it's like well you know,
maybe it's time for a pizza and you
know,
you think about a pizza and it's got
some mushrooms on.
It may be if you happen to like
mushrooms and you know,
sooner or later the fantasy that's
associated with the hunger becomes
sufficiently demanding,
sufficiently likely to take up the space
inside your subjective experience that
you'll switch activities from what
you're studying.
Especially if you're not that interested
in it,
you'll,
you'll switch activities so that you
pursue the new goal that's been put
forth as a,
as a,
as a possibility by the action of one of
these underlying biological systems.
Now one of the things that Freud
proposed,
and you know,
it's an interesting idea,
is that if you interfere with the
activity of one of these systems,
especially the more troublesome systems
like sexual desire and aggression,
and those are troublesome because in
some sense they're the most social of
emotions,
right?
Because generally speaking,
at least sometimes you need a partner
for sexual activity.
Although that seems to be less frequent
than it used to be in the past.
And you know,
and anger is something that also is very
socially disruptive.
And so one of Freud's claims was it's,
it's particularly difficult for
individuals to integrate sexual desire
and aggression into their personality
and into the social world because those
emotions are either socially disruptive
or require a tremendous degree of
cooperation from someone else.
And you know,
that was this best sexuality that was
especially true before there was a
reliable birth control.
And also when there was a lot more
stigma associated with sex outside of
marriage and also with child birth
outside of marriage.
So,
you know,
I don't,
in my clinical practice for example,
now I don't see that many people who
have this sort of sexual repression
problems that Freud found so common
among his Victorian clients mean in our
culture it's more likely that people are
having a terrible battle with the demons
of,
of hunger.
And you know,
they have some sort of eating disorder
because they're starving themselves and
then bingeing and starving themselves
and then bingeing or eating some,
you know,
God awful combination of pure
carbohydrates and sugars on a sort of a
random basis.
And so they dysregulate there,
their hypothalamic systems because the
hypothalamus controls hunger and then
they get into a vicious battle with it
and you'd like,
you don't win against your hypothalamus
because mostly as far as it's concerned,
you're just an appendage to it.
So,
and it's much more powerful than you are
as you'll find out if you ever have a
scrap with it.
So you know people who have eating
disorders,
they gorge and binge complete against
their will and they don't seem to be
able to control it.
And that's because your hypothalamus
won't let you starve.
It's not,
it's not into that sort of thing.
So no matter how thin you want to be,
it would rather that you were alive and
it's more,
it,
it has the capacity to exert more
control over your behavior than you do.
Generally speaking,
the same thing often happens to people
who develop addictions and the
addictions and addictive substance in
some sense harnesses a fundamental
motivational system.
And if you,
if you train that motivational system
over a long enough period of time to,
to seek out,
to successfully seek out the addictive
substance and you train it and reward it
by using the addictive substance.
When you are able to come across it,
you'll create this little biological
monster in your brain.
You turn on at the drop of a hat and
that you have very little control over
when it's activated.
So,
and you'll see one of the things that
happens when people go into Rehab for
drug addiction is that pretty easy to
get them,
um,
through the withdrawal phase,
even if it's something like heroin,
you know,
and heroin withdrawal.
Although people are always,
you know,
writing movies about how awful it is.
It's public,
it's bad as a bad case of the flu.
And people,
you know,
very seldom died during heroin
withdrawal.
They die during alcohol withdrawal all
the time,
but you,
so you can get someone through
withdrawal.
But as soon as you put them back in
their natural environment where their
friends are and the cues that are
associated with the addiction are still
in place,
they start taking the drug right away.
And yet,
you know,
regardless of all their good intentions
and you know,
you can see that as well in your own
behavior.
Because I mean I doubt if a day passes
where you don't do something that you
swore you wouldn't do,
you know when you do it and then you
think,
hmm,
why did I do that?
It's like,
well what do you mean?
I precisely and that's the fundamental
psychoanalytic question cause I,
you know,
even the way the word looks,
it's one letter,
you know,
it's like a one I,
it's like well is there an eye there?
Well not really.
You know what there is generally
speaking is a loose aggregation of
systems that are more or less going in
the same direction.
That's diluted into thinking that
there's a unity.
And that's,
that's a,
that's a prime psychoanalytic theory.
And the part of the reason that people
suffer is because those systems,
first of all,
don't necessarily have your wellbeing in
mind.
You know,
your,
your pleasure,
your freedom from anxiety,
your freedom from pain,
like the system that mediates individual
rep production,
the sexual system.
Like it doesn't really care about you so
to speak.
It cares about whether or not you
reproduce.
And you know,
one of the things you might think about
if you think,
why is there so much conflict in human,
intimate relationships?
It's because the demands of sexual
reproduction and the demands of
individual happiness are not the same
thing.
And you know,
you have to,
you have to try to integrate both of
them,
but there's no reason that you would
necessarily find the partner who would
make your life most fulfilling.
Also the one that you're sexually
attracted to.
You know,
you'd hope that would be the case.
But like good luck with that.
You'll end up with some jerky can't
because you know,
you get so hot you can't stand it when
you were anywhere near them.
So,
and you know,
you might think,
well wouldn't it be nice if you could
bring that under voluntary control?
It's like,
well good luck with that.
So you know,
so these are the sorts of things that
you need to think about when you're
thinking about what the psychoanalytic
thinkers we're thinking about as the
unconscious.
In some sense,
the unconscious is the,
the ideational and motivational
activities of all these underlying
biological subsystems that make up your
makeup,
your being that make up the substrata of
your psyche.
You know,
like you tend to think of your yourself
as I,
so that would be the Friday and ego,
you know,
as the part of you that subjectively
experiences and maybe also the part of
you that has continuity of memory across
time and for one reason or another,
we tend to experience that as something
of a unity.
It's not obvious why exactly.
I think part of it is that we can
separate ourselves out as a unit from
the rest of the world,
including other people,
you know,
and we're aware of our boundaries
physically and also temporarily.
But I also think it's because for one
reason or another,
we only seem to be able to do one thing
at a time.
And so the limitation,
which is like a motor output limitation
seems also to to imply to us that
there's only one thing there.
But you know,
it's not that it's not that unreasonable
to think about ourselves as something
more like an anthill than as something
that's,
you know,
a completely unitary structure.
Because obviously our physical structure
is far from homogenous,
right?
You're made up of all sorts of different
sub parts and they're qualitatively
different.
So anyways,
what I want to talk to you about today
as far as as far as I can manage it,
is to,
to give you some insight,
or at least the insights I've been able
to develop about how it is that your
physiology speaks to your mind.
And I think the way to conceptualize
that I,
I'm trying to give you some sense of
what symbols are.
Now.
What Freud thought about symbols was
that,
well let's say that you're in a society
that was very sexually repressive and
you were still stuck with the problem of
a fairly powerful sex drive and your
culture had taught you that,
that needed to be suppressed and
repressed and controlled.
And Freud's idea was that,
well that thing like the monster in the
basement doesn't really like to be
pushed around and controlled and it's
going to manifest its desires and its
and its once and it's view of the world
in sub subversive form.
So,
and for Freud this subversive forums
would be different sorts of symbols.
So if you weren't,
um,
satisfying the system that was
underlying sexual interest,
then it would start to insert itself in
random ways into your behavior.
Perhaps when you're interacting with
someone of the opposite sex or maybe
into your dreams and your fantasies.
And it would do that in a disguised form
because while,
because the part of you that was the
integrated part,
the ego part in some sense wasn't really
willing to communicate with it.
So it had to sort of sneak its message
up and through.
Well,
the union take on that with site
slightly different human was perfectly
willing to assume that Freud knew what
he was talking about in some some
domains,
especially those that were associated
with psychopathology.
But for you in that realm of symbols
with something different and for young,
the realm of symbols was where knowledge
had its origin.
And so you can imagine that there are
things that you know absolutely nothing
about.
And of course you don't know what those
things are because you don't know
anything about them.
But there's lots of them around.
And then you might imagine,
and there's also lots of things that
exist that the people as a whole don't
know anything about,
not just you there beyond our
comprehension as a species.
For you,
the assemble was a mediator between the
absolute unknown and the relatively
known.
And so as the human imagination expanded
out and mastered more and more
territory,
there was like a periphery around the
island of knowledge and that periphery
was made up of symbolic representations
that were,
that were pre articulate knowledge.
So they were like things you might act
out,
here's,
here's the way to think about that.
So you know,
you might watch a child who's engaged in
pretend play.
Okay.
And often children will pretend to be a
mother or a father for obvious reasons,
you know?
And what they do is they observe their
mother or their father and then they act
them out.
But it's very interesting form of acting
out because we think of it as imitation,
oh look,
you know she's imitating her mother,
but imitation means you move your arm
like this and I moved my arm like this.
And that is not what children do when
they're playing.
What they do instead is a very complex
form of generalizations and they've
watched the mother and they extract out
something like the pattern of the mother
and they don't really understand what
that pattern is because they don't have
the articulation and the cognitive
capacity to generate a fully articulated
and verbalized model of the mother.
But they acted out in behavior.
And so it's a,
in a sense,
they're incorporating the spirit of the
mother.
That's one way of thinking about it.
Into their behavior.
And then they can act out things they
don't understand,
or at least they don't understand in
terms of being able to articulate them.
And you know,
lots of things,
you know,
you can't articulate,
you can't articulate how to walk.
You can't articulate how to ride a bike.
You can't articulate anything complex
like how to engage in a successful
relationship.
A lot of that knowledge is embodied,
assuming you have it at all.
So it's,
it's dramatic action.
And you can also think about the symbol
as a mediator between dramatic action
and full cognition.
So for example,
um,
imagine a child is playing at being a
mother and then you stopped them and you
say,
well,
what are you doing?
And the child might say,
well,
I'm,
you know,
we're playing house.
I'm pretending to be mom.
And then you might say,
well,
how do you go about doing that?
And then they're going to try to
articulate what they're doing,
you know?
And while they're doing that,
they're going to be using their
imagination and representing the things
that they're trying to understand.
And then you can see how the symbol,
which would be the visual representation
of the mother's action,
like a little movie that you might run
in your head.
You can see how it might lay itself on
top of the dramatic action as a
precursor to articulation.
And so that's,
that's a good way of thinking about it
is that the symbol is a precursor to
articulation and that you use symbols of
one form or another whenever you use
imaginative representation as a
precursor to understand.
And so that happens for example,
when you're fantasizing about something.
So now for the psychoanalysts,
particularly psychoanalysts like Yom,
the imagination was something that had a
spontaneous operation.
It would just go along on its own and do
things.
And of course you also experienced that
if you,
first of all,
when you dream,
obviously because you're not in control
of your dreams,
things in control of them and they
happen,
but it's not you or it's not the you
that you normally think of yourself as.
And then if you're daydreaming that
something analogous happens,
you know,
you find that maybe you're trying to
concentrate on something and something
that's of interest to you.
For one reason or another,
it starts to creep into the theater of
your imagination and lay out different
scenarios of one form or another.
And it's sort of like the natural
language of the psyche because it isn't
obvious that the natural language of the
psyche is in fact language,
right?
Because we don't really know how long
human beings have been using formal
language.
You know,
they estimates 150,000 years.
That's one estimate.
I doubt if it's more than 2 million
years,
2 million years seems to be about how
long we've been using fire.
So it's somewhere between 2 million and
150,000 years.
But compared to the entire history of
our cognitive development,
which you can stretch back well to the
beginning of life itself if you want,
or at least to the point where things
have nervous systems,
that's more like 500 million years.
And so the psyche was operating without
language for a much longer period of
time that was operating with language
and it was doing something to organize
its conceptions of the world that were
pre linguistic.
So what we're going to talk about today,
or what we're already talking about is
what the structure of those pre
linguistic cognitive forms might be.
And I'm,
I'm offering that to you partly as an
element of the integrating theory that I
told you I would try to deliver in the
first lecture.
And also as a means of giving you a,
a Schema or a language to start to
understand what symbolic representation
means from a psychoanalytic perspective
and all.
I hope that'll be very useful.
I mean,
it's,
it's been extraordinarily useful for me
because it offers a key to understanding
symbolic literature and symbolic modes
of cognition.
So for example,
religious systems are symbolic modes of
cognition,
part excellence.
That's what they are.
And they're not objects,
they're not primitive theories about the
nature of the objective world.
That's a foolish way of looking at
religious systems.
And it sets up an artificial dichotomy
between religious belief in scientific
belief.
And all that does is confuse people.
So religion,
religious belief is primarily about
morality and morality is about how to
act and religious symbolism is about how
to construe the world as a forum to act
Ian.
And that's what you,
you have to solve that problem because
the big pro biggest problem you have in
your life and the biggest problem you
always will have is how the hell should
yakked.
And you know that actually might be the
fundamental question of existence to,
to the degree that action is the primary
reality.
Now you know,
if you're a materialist,
you don't really think that way because
you think of the objective world
stripped of its subjective importance as
the ground of reality,
but it's not the ground of reality.
The ground of reality is whether or not
you survive and reproduce,
at least from a Darwinian perspective.
And that means that the most important
element of reality is how you act.
That determines whether or not you're
going to be selected,
so to speak,
for reproduction.
People are like evaluating each other.
On the basis of their fitness for
reproduction nonstop.
It's like almost all of social congress
has to do with that.
You know,
men organize themselves into very strict
dominance hierarchies by competing with
one another and women peel the men off
the tall.
And almost everything that you're doing
in your day to day interactions with
other human beings is an element of that
fundamental process.
So that's all action oriented.
So,
so it's very much important to get these
things right.
So I'm going to tell you how I piece
this together to some degree.
And so we're going to start with a
hypothesis.
We'll take a look at this.
There we go.
So one of the things you might ask is
what do our immediate mammalian
relatives,
how do they conceptualize the world?
And so we're going to assume that those
are higher order primates because you
know,
the evidence seems to suggest that we're
relatively genetically similar to
chimpanzees in particular and also to
Bonobos,
which are more or less a fordham of
chimpanzee.
Although their behavior differs.
And it looks like we diverged from the
precursor to chimpanzees,
Bonobos and human beings about 7 million
years ago.
So we didn't come from chimps,
chimps,
Bonobos and us came from something that
was the precursor to all three.
And we know,
you can calculate how similar you are
from a genetic perspective to another
organism by measuring,
if you split your DNA into its it into
its halves,
and then you mix those Dna halves with
the DNA,
how's of another animal,
they'll join up.
And the more related you are to that
animal,
the more energy it takes to pry them
apart once they've joined up because
they're a tighter match.
And so it turns out that we're,
you know,
extraordinarily tightly matched with
chimpanzees.
So,
um,
so when you know,
you're wondering why you're so erratic,
it's an uncontrollable and
unpredictable.
It's because you're basically a
chimpanzee that's been driven insane by
self awareness.
So,
you know,
what the hell do you expect from
something like that?
You know,
it's amazing that we can even all sit in
this room together.
So anyways,
you know,
you might ask,
well what it creatures like that no,
and one of the,
one of the things that we've been able
to determine our,
some of the precursors or associates of
of cortical development of rain size and
there's various things that seem to be
tightly associated with the development
of larger brains,
but one of them in primates in
particular is size of group.
So the bigger your group,
the more you have to keep track of the
more social information you'll have to
keep track of it.
And if that's driving brain development
at least in part because it's certainly
not the whole story if it's driving
behavior in part,
one of the things that that implies is
that one of the most important sources
of information that you have to contend
with if you're a social pride,
nate is the social structure.
And so what you can infer from that is
that your brain is primarily set up to
assess social information.
Now you can take that a little bit
farther and then you might think,
well that means that may imply that the
primary categories that you use
naturally.
So to speak,
to understand the world are in fact
social categories.
And then you could think,
well,
you know,
we've,
we've elaborated our cognitive systems
up into the abstract far farther than
our primate relatives have.
But because evolution is a conservative
process,
new structures have their roots in old
structures,
right?
It's a necessary part of evolution
because once an organism walks down the
certain psychophysiological road,
in some sense it's destined by that
road,
which is why you have the same basic
bodily platform as virtually,
well,
not only mammals,
vertebrates in general,
you know,
four legs,
two eyes.
It's a very,
very standard form.
So,
you know,
once it's developed,
that's it.
That's the platform upon which further
variation takes place.
Now you might ask,
well,
first of all,
think,
think of your own situation in
relationship to the primates situation.
How much of your time during the day are
you spending interacting with other
people in one form or another?
Now let's assume that that also means
books,
movies,
all the artificial representations of
people.
We're going to consider those
representations of people as well.
And so then you might think,
well,
not when you're asleep except you're
dreaming and you're almost inevitably
dreaming of people.
But when you're away,
well,
what is it said?
80% is 90% I mean it depends to some
degree on how extroverted you are.
Like if you're sufficiently extroverted,
you're going to try to drive it up to a
hundred percent you know?
And if you're really introverted,
maybe you,
you know,
you'd go hide in the closet now and then
because he can't stand being around
people.
But nonetheless,
most of your environment is a social
environment,
you know,
and like we like to think of the
environment has a forest or a landscape,
something like that.
But the environment is actually the
niche in which you live and the human
niche is highly social.
And then you add to that the fact that
we're pair bonding creatures and we have
very long lasting relationships and our
familial relationships are
extraordinarily long lasting as well.
Plus our period of dependency is
extraordinarily long and,
and,
and serious.
So,
you know,
we're for all day for the all the ideas,
mostly western ideas about,
you know,
radical individualism were unbelievably
social creatures and we can't really
survive outside of a social context.
And what that implies is that the
fundamental categories of our
perception,
our likely social and that we've taken
those fundamental categories and applied
them to other things.
So then imagine here's some of the
things that we know that that higher
order primates can track from,
they can track dominance.
So you know,
primates live in hierarchies,
there's a female hierarchy and a male
hierarchy in it,
you know,
and the nature of those hierarchies
depends on the pricing.
But there are hierarchies and the
hierarchies are extraordinarily
important because if you're at the
bottom of a hierarchy and you're a
social primate,
like you're a whipping boy,
you're going to get kicked around,
your children are going to get kicked
around.
If an f a disease comes whipping through
your,
your tribe or your truth,
then if you're at the bottom of the
hierarchy,
you're the one that's going to die
because you're already stressed and full
of parasites and poorly nourished.
And you don't have a good place to live
and so you're going to get wiped off the
map.
And even if you don't get killed by some
disease,
if we track your life expectancy across
time,
if you're at the bottom of the
hierarchy,
you're going to die way earlier and
you're going to be old,
much younger than the people or the
creatures that are at the top because
the ones at the top get the best of
everything and the ones at the bottom
don't.
And so it turns out that your,
your place of,
of,
of position in the dominants heart,
he's an unbelievably important
determinant of your probability of
reproductions,
especially if you're male.
Most females reproduce regardless of
where they are in the dominant search.
But that isn't the case with males.
What happens in males as he gets
something more like a prieto
distribution where there's a few males
at the top are unbelievably successful
and then half the males at the bottom
who are not successful at all.
And so that's one of the,
you know,
that's one of the chronic stressors that
civilized societies have to deal with
because
well,
for obvious reasons,
so,
so it turns out that primates are very,
very sensitive to dominance hierarchy
structure and they know who's at their
level and they know who's below their
level and they know who's above.
And they track that across time and they
track it across families and sometimes
they track it across generations because
it can last generations,
dozen human beings,
it doesn't chimpanzees.
So our brains are pre wired for
dominance,
hierarchy,
comprehension,
and okay,
so that's one domain,
the dominance hierarchy.
Now you can think about that in a
variety of different ways.
You can think about that as the social
organization.
You can think about that as the nature
of the tribe.
You can think about that as the state or
the nation or the people.
All of those things are dominance,
hierarchy variants.
In some sense.
You can think about that as the father
and or you could even think about that
as God the father with God being the
thing that's at the top of the
hierarchy.
In some sense,
and I think part of what religious
idiation actually does is take the idea
of the thing that's at the top of the
hierarchy,
whatever that is and make it into a day
Auntie.
Now the rate,
we know that people are much more likely
to imitate those who are close to the
top of the hierarchy because they want
to pull in the behaviors and the
attitudes and the ideas that made those
people successful than you might think
with regards to human beings.
That because we're extraordinarily
intelligent and very much able to
abstract that,
what we can do is we can look across
dominance hierarchies because there are
multiple sorts of dominance hierarchies
among human beings and we can say,
okay,
well this person's at the top here and
then this person's at the top here and
this person's at the top here and all
those talk people share things in common
that make them the top and then we can
abstract out what the top means and we
can say that's the top thing.
And I think that's partly what people
are doing in the multigenerational
process that they use to extract out
religiously significant figures of
adulation and admiration.
So they're like the best of all possible
people across all possible
circumstances.
Okay.
But we'll leave that aside for a moment.
It looks like the fundamental symbolic
structures that people use to represent
the structure of the dominance hierarchy
are paternal.
So the dominance hierarchy is like the
great father.
And I think part of the reason for that
is that among human beings and among
chimpanzees,
although it's not so true with Barnabas,
the male dominance hierarchy is the
dominant hierarchy.
And you know,
this is a claim even that feminists
make,
right?
Because the feminists say that well,
that our culture is basically a
patriarchal and you know,
they're not very happy about that.
But that's a whole different issue.
Okay,
so one idea.
Okay.
Now the other thing you can think about
here,
isn't it?
Your brain has got to be organized so
that it's capable of understanding the
things that are most constant about the
environment,
right?
And you might think,
well,
the things that are the most constant
are the most real.
That's a way of defining real.
It lasts a long time and it's evident
everywhere.
Okay.
So then you might think,
well,
what are the most real things that human
beings have to deal with?
You know,
and,
and one,
one answer to that as well.
There are certain kinds of objective
realities that are the most real.
So you might say,
well,
things like trees are extraordinarily
real.
But one of the things I'd like to point
out to you is that despite the fact that
trees are quite real,
they're not as real as dominance
hierarchies because dominance
hierarchies were around for a couple of
a hundred million years before there
were trees.
And so what,
there have been dominant turkeys around
for 400 million years long before there
were vertebrates have are tight.
And so the dominance hierarchy is an
extraordinarily constant feature of
life.
And part of the reason that we're wired
up to be able to detect variations in
dominance,
hierarchy status is because that,
that the fact of that structure is
constant across all times.
In all places.
And so it's built right into our nervous
systems and the fact that we share the
ability to assess our dominance
hierarchy position with crustaceans and
that this and which have a very simple
nervous system and the fact that the
same pharmacological substances work on
crustaceans that work on us for the same
reasons,
at least with regards to dominance,
archi indicates that the dominants
hierarchy counter that you have
functioning at the very base of your
brain,
so to speak,
is an unbelievably potent mechanism and
you're using it all the time.
One example is,
you know when you might ask yourself why
people are so obsessed with fashion and
why fashions have to change every year.
And part of the reason for that is that
by attending to fashion and keeping up
or being even on the event and guard,
you show that you're ahead of the curve
and the curve is always changing,
right?
It's like a technological curve.
You have to stay ahead of of the,
it isn't so much that you mastered the
technology,
it's that you stay ahead of the
technology and master the new and that
indicates that your conscious and alive
and aware and capable of competing.
And that's one of the things that makes
you more attractive,
at least in principle as a mate or at
least more competitive with the other
creatures with whom you're competing for
the attention of potential mates.
So that's just another indication of
exactly how possessed you are by the
operation of these deep seated
biological systems.
And we know,
for example,
that there's very,
very little difference between a severe
clinical depression and a very severe
dominance defeat.
It's the same biological process.
Fundamentally,
what happens often with people who are
clinically depressed is that there's
self assessed dominance is much lower
than their actual competence and it's
actually the gap between their
competence and their and their self
worth assessment that constitutes the
pathology.
So,
you know,
so you have someone,
when I assess people for depression,
I say well look,
you know,
do you have a job,
a good job?
You know,
do you have,
you have a family,
do you have an intimate partner?
Do you have interests in various things
in your life,
you know,
outside of your work.
Um,
you know,
do you have the sort of education that
you want?
How's your physical health?
Do you have a drug and alcohol problem?
And if the answer to all those is the
proper answer and they still feel really
terrible than you might think,
oh well that person suffering from
clinical depression because they're self
assessed dominant status is not in
keeping with their actual social status.
You know,
as opposed to people who come in and you
ask them the same questions and it's
like their families completely insane.
They're alienated from them.
You know,
they had a brain injury when they were
four because their father hit them
against the wall.
They've got no education at all.
They've got an alcohol problem.
You know,
they'd been unemployed for seven years
and they have a personality disorder.
It's like,
well,
they feel terrible,
but they're not depressed.
They just have terrible lives,
you know?
And it's not like you're not going to
suffer if you have a terrible life.
But if I give someone like that an
antidepressant or suggest that they take
one,
you know,
it might stop them from cutting the
risks,
but the probability that it's really
going to improve their situation is
relatively low because like what the
hell are you going to do with that?
It's just too overwhelming a problem.
Do you even address?
All right,
so it looks like the dominance hierarchy
as such seems to be represented by
masculine symbols.
And it's something to keep in mind when
you watch movies because symbols are
spoken sessions especially that are
associated with the father.
Like the king for example,
are,
are representations of the dominant
structure.
So,
so that's one fundamental symbol.
Um,
let's look at another here.
All right,
so this is a rather complicated shift in
argumentation.
So,
so perhaps you can,
except for a minute,
the association between the dominance
hierarchy and culture.
You see how those are the same thing?
Or at least that there are similar,
our cultures actually made up of a
variety of overlapping,
dominant.
Sorry.
He's right.
Because different professions and
different specialties have their own
dominance hierarchies in their sort of
integrated into a metta higher.
But so,
but regardless,
the culture is a dormant entire
hierarchy,
a complex dominance,
Herc.
And so then you might ask yourself,
well,
what exactly makes up the culture?
What is it that we're talking about when
we're talking about the culture and the
dominance hierarchy?
And so that,
that,
that leads into questions like what
exactly constitutes a law,
you know,
so we have laws and you might think,
well,
what does it mean that there's a law?
Well,
we can,
we can look at the obvious things.
There's a rule of some sort that's being
written down.
That's one.
There's a rule of it's been written down
that if you transgress against,
you'll be tracked down and punished.
That's another example of a law.
Another example is while it's a custom,
right,
most of the things that we have is laws,
our customs that people have adopted,
at least in principle,
to regulate our interactions so that the
probability of mutual cooperation is
high and the probability of mutual
aggression is low.
And so you might say,
well,
why do we all go forward on a green
light?
That's arbitrary.
Why is that a law?
And the answer is well,
because everybody decided that that
would be a law and then they decided
they would act it out.
So it's a costume and you can see why
it's an extraordinarily useful custom
because if we didn't have it,
then we'd be crashing into each other at
every intersection and none of our
vehicles would be good for anything.
So that's another example of a law.
Some of you think about a law as a set
of customers,
then you start to see the law as as the
codafide version of a behavioral
contract,
right?
There's ways that we have all agreed to
act,
or even if we have a degree act that
way,
we've agreed that there should be a
structure that describes how you should
act.
And that's what the culture is.
You know,
unless you're a nihilist or an anarchist
or a criminal or,
or a terrorist or something like that,
you basically accept the fact that this
structure has to exist and then you try
to position yourself within it.
Okay.
So then you can think,
well,
the culture and the dominance hierarchy
is,
is two things at the same time,
or maybe even three things.
One is it's the way you act.
So when you say that you're a citizen of
a given country,
what that essentially means is that you
imitate the body of laws that that
country has erected.
You're a behavioral manifestation of
those rules,
roughly speaking or reverse.
You could say the law is a codafide
representation of the way everybody in
the culture is behaving.
There's like a dyadic interaction,
right?
And so the law and the culture is
actually a pattern of behaviors and
expectations around those behaviors that
everyone shares.
And you could also say it's the
cumulative knowledge that the culture
shares.
So the culture as a whole has a body of
knowledge,
some of which is our objective and some
of which is moral and behavioral.
And you as a fragment of that also have
have that at least in fragmentary form,
right?
You're a partial representation of the
entire culture.
That would be something similar to
Freud's idea of the Super Ego,
right?
Because for Freud there was an end and
an ego and the superego and they had was
basically,
you know,
biology and its ability to control you.
And the ego was poor little you.
And the Super Ego was the terrible force
of culture,
crushing the little ego between the
terrible force of biology and itself.
And so the Super Ego in some senses,
culture,
and that's represented by masculinity
now or by,
by,
by the far to figured most generally
speaking.
Now you could also imagine the culture
as the collection of all knowledge.
Now that's fine.
Now then you got to think about what
knowledge is.
And that's a tough thing to get a handle
on.
So because there's different definitions
of knowledge.
We in many technical situations in our
culture,
we privilege factual knowledge and we
think of that as knowledge.
So for example,
if you're going to be an engineer or a
physicist,
someone who's really dealing with
things,
there are certain rules that apply to
the operation of things and you have to
know what those are.
And those don't necessarily have much to
do with how you behave.
You know,
if you're an engineer and you go to
work,
you work with things and you have to
know how the things work.
Now you also have to be part of a
culture because if you're not,
you're going to not get along with the
rest of the engineers and they're going
to toss you out.
So you have to have both forms of
knowledge.
But we're not interested in in the
moment precisely about the factual
knowledge.
We're more interested in the knowledge
that makes you acceptable other human
beings.
And that enables you,
while you're operating in your own life,
to negotiate the social structure in
such a way that you can be successful
and successful would mean well,
you get to live.
That would be one definition.
There's some probability that you might
find an intimate partner.
That's another element of success.
You're not suffering to the point where
your own existence is intolerable,
you know,
and you're going to survive for some
prolonged period of time with some
amount of security.
And so that's what you're,
you know,
that's what you're trying to do.
And I would say to the degree that
you're well inculturated,
which is that you're a good
representation of your culturals
cultures,
knowledge in so far as it's irrelevant
behaviorally,
then you're much more likely to be
successful.
Okay.
So we're going to,
we're going to equate that form of
knowledge with the possibility of
succeeding that makes you,
well,
you could call,
you could call it a no,
you could call it emotional
intelligence,
although I never would call it that
because there's actually no such thing.
But it's more,
it's knowledge about how to act,
you know?
And it's,
it's very,
very important that knowledge.
So just think about what you're all
doing in this class,
right?
Most of you don't know each other.
There's maybe 200 people in this class.
Three of you are pretty damn crazy,
really.
You know,
and,
and probably about 10 of you are like on
the edge.
So,
but there you all are sitting there
peacefully,
right?
You're following a rule code and you're
really following it.
First of all,
you're all sitting in your own chair,
right?
You're not sitting on the lap of someone
names,
right?
And that makes you laugh,
Because what would happen if someone did
that?
What would happen?
Well,
you know,
a little flurry would break out because
it's all of a sudden the primate is
doing something that a primates not
supposed to do.
And that opens up an area of,
of,
of the unexpected and the crazy,
right?
And God only knows what's going to
happen when a little spot opens up where
the unexpected and crazy emerges.
You know,
we don't like those spots.
And you can,
you can see this in your own behavior.
So,
for example,
if you're walking down bloor street and
you happen to come across someone who is
self evidently homeless and they're
wandering down the street and they're
gesturing and they're talking to
themselves,
there's a bunch of things you're going
to do.
The first thing is,
is you're going to glance and look away
and then you're going to make a
relatively wide birth around the person
and you're going to try not to make eye
contact generally speaking.
And the reason for that,
think about that.
The reason for that is the space that
that person in habits is undetermined by
cultural agreement,
right?
You don't know what the person will do.
And so all you do is walk around that
space because God only knows what
happened.
What might happen if you don't,
probably nothing because the person is
preoccupied by whatever demons happened
to be chasing them,
but you're not going to take that
chance.
And so you all come in here and I mean
look,
look you're,
you're pretty much all dressed the same,
you know,
roughly speaking,
acceptable variation,
but nothing outlandish.
So you get to be individual but not
peculiar.
I think
so far it looks okay.
Right?
And you know where you're supposed to
set.
And I bet you how many of you sat in the
same seat you sat in the first day.
Yeah.
So,
so a good proportion of view.
How many didn't?
Okay.
Well you will assume cause,
cause you,
you'll love it.
I'll keep,
you'll have established your little
territory,
you know,
and it will be,
it will be familiar to you and you'll
gravitate towards it.
And you'll be happy about that because
you'll start to become familiarized with
the people in your immediate vicinity.
And they didn't kill you the first time.
So they might not kill you the second
time.
Right?
And so,
and you're all participating in a,
in a kind of collective drama,
right?
So what's the nature of this room?
What does it look like?
What's it called?
It's a lecture theater.
Right?
Why?
Because there's a drama going on,
right?
And you're the audience.
And I'm hypothetically supposed to be
providing the drama and we all know that
because that's how the room is set up.
And when you come in here,
you will obey the room.
You do what it tells you.
There's chairs and you sit in them.
And when I'm talking,
generally speaking,
you don't,
maybe you want to,
hopefully if I'm speaking properly then
you don't care.
Because if you're happy,
listen and the rule is you're supposed
to look at me and listen and you're all
following that rule.
And you know all of that is because
you're very much inculturated and you're
sane enough to follow the damn rules.
And one of the things you might think
about this,
and this is where I thought the
psychoanalysts kind of went astray,
is that the psychoanalysts tended to
think that you were saying if your
interior psychological structures were
integrated and well put together,
so your psyche was sort of something
inside your head,
roughly speaking and sanity was
something that was an individual issue.
But I think you know another way of
looking at that at that,
and it's a more powerful way of looking
at it,
I think,
is that you're hardly self regulatory at
all.
All you have to do is behave well enough
so other people can stand being around
you and you can outsource the problem of
your own sanity.
Because as soon as you get a little
weird,
if you have people around you,
they'll just tell you.
And so you don't have to remember how
not to be weird.
You just have to pay enough attention to
other people around you.
So that when they indicate by not
listening to you are by not laughing at
your jokes are by raising an eyebrow or
by saying something smart about what you
just did that you stop and reconsider
and go on in your same manner.
So it's also why people who are
tremendously isolated often,
you know,
there's a loop there,
they're a little queer to begin with,
so to speak,
because you know there's something wrong
with their ability to behave and then
they get isolated and things just go
seriously astray as a,
as a consequence of that.
So anyways,
the point I'm trying to make is that a
lot of your knowledge is actually
knowledge about how to behave.
Right?
And that's the sort of knowledge that's
really critical for psychological
stability.
It's,
it's not related in any real sense to
the world,
to the knowledge you have about the
structure of the objective world.
And you kind of know that because
animals are perfectly capable of
surviving even complex animals like
chimpanzees,
what?
They don't know a damn thing about the
objective world,
right?
And their primary reality is social.
Okay?
So one domain of symbolic representation
is the dominance hierarchy.
And culturally I said that was
associated with the maternal and there's
reasons for that.
Now here's,
here's another thing that needs to be
conceptualized.
Okay?
When you're walking down bloor street
and you make a detour around the person
who happens to be talking to themselves,
where are they?
Okay?
Because wherever they are,
that's not the same place you are.
If it was the same place,
you wouldn't have any trouble walking
right by them wherever they are,
that's somewhere seriously different.
Now,
it turns out that we also have the
capacity to represent that.
And I would say an easy way to think
about that is that we have,
there are two domains that are
characteristic to experience and one
domain is the domain of the known and
the domain of the known is where when
you act in a certain way,
what you want to happen happens.
Got It.
And the reason that's the known is
because if you act in a certain way and
you get what you want,
that means that you know what you're,
it's actually the definition of knowing
what you're doing.
Yeah.
And that that's a different definition.
Then I know a fact about the object of
world,
you know,
so if you tell someone to joke or you
tell a group of people a joke and you
know,
they laugh and maybe they want another
joke,
it's like,
good for you.
You know what you're doing.
But if you tell them a joke and they
sorta,
you know,
look on easy and glance at each other,
well you know,
it's time to rethink your sense of
humor.
And what you just learned is that
there's some mismatch between the manner
in which you can figure social reality
and the social reality itself.
Now imagine what happens if you do tell
a joke or maybe a couple of jokes and
they flopped badly.
How do you feel when that happens?
If you have any sense?
How do you feel?
Embarrassed.
Yes.
So maybe you turned red for example.
What else?
What might happen if you feel
embarrassed?
What?
What would,
what would you do?
Okay.
Yeah.
Salesmen jokes.
Well hopefully,
right?
It's like,
you know,
that's right.
You'd reevaluate your knowledge and,
and you might think,
well what the Hell is wrong with me?
Or You might think what the Hell is
wrong with them?
Which I would say is not a good starting
point.
Yeah,
seriously though.
You know,
cause you got to watch that because if
it's 10 people and you,
maybe you're right,
maybe you are funny,
but if all 10 of them think you're not
well either you're not funny or you're
telling your jokes to the wrong people.
Right.
And sometimes it is the case that it's
everyone else.
That's got the problem,
but that's definitely not the first
hypothesis that you might want to
generate.
Okay.
So there's a place that as a place that
exists that manifests itself when things
that you don't want or expect happen.
And I would consider that unknown and
not known as a complicated place because
it's a place where unexpected things
happen and that's also symbolically
represented and that's generally
symbolically represented by feminine
figures.
Now the reasons for that is
extraordinarily complicated and it's
going to take a very long time to
explain it.
Partly it's because of the masculine has
a symbolic realm is already used up.
That's the dominance hierarchy.
And because we're basically social
cognitive organisms,
we're going to use
okay
representations that are basically
human.
Okay.
In order to start representing things
that aren't precisely human.
Because we have to start somewhere.
We have to start with our basic primate,
primate cognitive system.
And it's not like chimpanzees have
culture,
you know,
they have dominance hierarchies and
troops.
We have dominance hierarchies and troops
and culture and we have to represent
that some way.
And the way we represent it is by using
the same systems that we were
representing,
the simple structures with,
but generalizing with them to encompass
broader.
So no woman them.
So,
so
things that are permanent across time,
things you know or the fact that there
are things that you know,
things that you don't know or the fact
that there are things that you don't
know that's permanent.
And then there's one other thing across
time that's permanent.
You,
the fact that there's an I in the
equation,
right?
So you think,
well what are people's experiential
fields fundamentally composed of places
you're secure in and that you
understand.
So that's your territory.
And your territory is a very complex
thing.
It might even be an ideological
territory.
Your territory,
things that you don't understand,
that's not your territory,
that's unexplored territory and you
don't know what the hell is going on
there.
And that's the unknown.
And then the last common element is you.
And so basic symbolic structures tend to
represent those elements of reality
known and the unknown.
And the thing that mediates between
them.
And the thing that mediates between them
is you or more precisely the thing that
mediates between them as your individual
consciousness.
And that's like mediating between chaos
and order.
If you look up at the,
at the screen there,
look at the the Christian image,
John the left
that's called the open virgin and there
there are quite a few statues of this
sort that were created in medieval
Europe and the 13th 14th century.
And uh,
I wanna Sorta tell you what that
sculpture means using the analytic
Schema that I just laid out for you so
that you can get a sense of how this
symbolic representation works.
Now,
and this is a strange representation
from a Christian perspective because
while the representation is the Virgin
Mary,
right,
that's the superordinate figure,
the female and inside that is God the
father and inside that is Christ.
All right?
Now the reason it's a strange Christian
representation is that it's rare to see
Mary represented as a figure that
superordinate to God and well,
we'll just leave that aside for now.
I think part of the reason that that
happens at that happened for these
sculptors is because they were trying to
express the relationship between these
three fundamental elements in a way that
was slightly different than the
canonical Christian representation.
But here's how to read it.
Well,
the outside,
that's the unknown.
That's the mother of all things.
Now you might say,
well,
why is the unknown the mother of all
things?
Well,
where does new information come from?
New information comes from what you
don't know.
You already know what you know.
Everything new comes from what you don't
know.
And so what you don't know is
terrifying,
certainly because God only knows what's
going to happen when you encounter it,
but it's also unbelievably potentially
productive.
In fact,
you might think of it as potential now
known his potential itself.
And so you need to know how to deal
with,
because potential manifest itself in all
sorts of places that you wouldn't
necessarily,
uh,
technically you wouldn't expect.
It's almost by definition.
So you have the unknown on the very
outside.
And then inside that you have culture.
It's like,
and so that's like nature and culture as
well,
but it's like unknown territory and
known territory.
And then inside the culture holding,
holding you up so to speak,
is the individual.
And you might say,
well,
why in this representation is the
individual crucified?
And the answer to that is quite straight
forward.
Life is mostly suffering.
And there's more to it though than that.
The other element to it,
and this is part of this as part of the
complex representational system that
underlies the symbolic representation of
the individuals,
the individual is also something that
can die and be reborn.
And that's symbolic representation
already showed you in the figure of
Jonah,
right?
Because the idea was there that some
terrible things swallowed this creature
up,
pulled it down into the depths and then
let it reemerge.
And I would say that's happened to you
people many times already,
even though you probably don't know it.
So think back when your experience,
you know,
so,
so let's lay out a couple of things that
everybody knows about.
Someone close to you died,
someone close to you got a serious
illness,
you got a serious illness,
you are completely heartbroken because
it relationship failed catastrophic.
Lee,
you were betrayed by a friend.
Well,
I'm sure that for most of you at least,
well let's find out how many people in
this room have had at least one of those
things happen to them.
Okay.
Right,
right.
And are,
is there anybody in here who's got off
free from that so far?
Oh Wow.
That stuff's good.
That's amazing.
But you can see how,
you know,
unbelievably rare that is,
I'm sure you must have had some other
terrible thing happened to you with any
luck.
So,
so,
okay,
so you are,
you perfectly well understand what those
experiences are like.
So then the question is
where do you go with an experience like
that occurs?
And you might think,
well what do you mean?
Where do you go?
You're in the same place.
And I would say to you,
well no,
it depends pretty much on exactly what
you mean by a place.
You know,
places are times too,
and you can be one person at one moment
in the same place and a completely
different person in the next moment in
the same place.
And that means you're really not in the
same place at all.
And when something comes along and pulls
the rug out from underneath you,
when you fall,
when you fall into is the unknown.
And that's a completely different place.
And that's the underworld of classical
mythology.
And it's also the unconscious.
And part of the reason that it's the
unconscious so complicated when the rug
is pulled out from underneath you and
you're somewhere you don't want to be
and didn't expect and didn't like,
what starts to structure how you respond
is the fundamental biological systems
that make up the substrata of your
psyche.
So for example,
the first thing that might vital curry's
that you experience it as a terrible
shock.
And that's a physiological response.
And then maybe right afterwards you're
angry or you're afraid or you're
confused or you're depressed or you
know,
it's another emotional response.
And then you start to imagine
alternative scenarios are reasons why
this thing might have occurred.
There's a whole set of processes that
are automatically undertaken when you
encounter something that's outside the
realm of your expectation and your
desire.
And if you understand that,
you see,
if you understand that,
and this is why I've told you all these
complicated things today,
if you understand that that's a
different place and that you cycle
through that place and then back up to
normal reality and through that place
and then back up to normal reality
multiple times throughout your life,
you can see that one,
it's inevitable that the individual is
something that suffers to the
individual,
is something that can suffer and then
reconstitute itself as a consequence of
that suffering.
It doesn't necessarily happen,
you know now and then something can come
along and take you off at the knees and
you just never get back up.
But the general human experiences that
you learn as a consequence of your
failures,
and the reason for that is that the
place that you go when you fail has a
tremendous amount of information in it.
So,
for example,
it might be that if you were betrayed in
a relationship that you're just too damn
naive and there's a lot of things that
you should have paid attention to in the
world.
And maybe even within the person,
the person who you are attracted to with
regards to their character or your own
character that you should have known
more about.
And if you would have known more about
it,
well that would have been a particular
hole you wouldn't have stepped in.
You know?
And so the,
so the appropriate reaction to a
catastrophic failure,
and this isn't always possible,
is to react as how you're going to
react,
which is usually it was shock and
dismay.
And then to learn from the experience
and to gather whatever information there
is in the failures so that you can
extract out that information and rebuild
yourself out of it and restructure your
conception of the world.
So it's richer and more dynamic.
Now let,
let me just give you an example of that.
Remember the Hobbit,
right?
I don't know.
He spent a couple of hundred million
dollars on that movie and you know,
it was written in the 1960s but it was
based on very,
very old stories including some of the
north sagginess.
Remember the Hobbit at the beginning?
I think we established that that was
Bilbo,
right?
So he lives in this little area called
the shier that's really protected and
he's kind of a little guy and all the
people in the shire kind of naive,
it turns out in the Lord of the rings
that they're actually protected.
There's these people called striders
that walk around the border who happened
to be the sons of ancient kings who keep
all the bad guys away and the bloody
hobbits don't even know it.
And they're even kind of contemptuous of
striders.
But they're keeping these hobbits so
that they can be naive and self
satisfied and somewhat ignorant and you
know,
a bit on the arrogant side without even
knowing that they're being protected.
Okay,
well that's you.
That's why you were hooked into the
story right off the bat.
And then they extract out one guy from
this whole scenario who's,
you know,
got a little bit more going for them
than the typical hobbit.
And he wants to go outside of this
paradise,
so to speak,
to encounter the actual world.
And it's so interesting because what's
his,
what's his role?
What do they hire him as a thief?
Yeah.
You think,
Geez,
this is pretty weird disguise going on
this developmental quest,
you know,
and he's going to turn into a hero.
And what does he start by doing?
He starts by becoming a criminal.
Right?
But that's,
that seems to be part of the story.
It's actually part of their,
his heroic transformation.
You know,
one of the things you said about heroic
transformations was that the first thing
that happens when you put your self out
of side,
your zone of comfort,
if you do that voluntarily,
is that you encounter your shadow,
which is the part of you that is
fundamentally in some sense,
antisocial and criminal.
And then you extract from that element
of yourself,
those personality attributes you need to
survive when you're outside,
where everything is comfortable and
predictable.
And then what happens with bill bill
while he encounters a dragon,
right?
That's the dragon we talked about
already.
That's the thing that swallows you up
when you don't know where you are.
And he had,
and he gets a treasure as a consequence
of that.
Well,
you see,
what the story means is that if you go
outside your zone of comfort,
if you go outside of what you
understand,
and you do that voluntarily,
and you develop the skills that you've
rejected,
that are necessary for your proper
survival as an integrated human being,
you can encounter the thing that most
frightens you,
and you can extract something of value
as a consequence.
And that's the human story.
That's the fundamental story of mankind,
because we're always the thing that goes
outside of what we understand to
confront what we don't understand that
frightens us so that we can get whatever
that thing has.
And so that's part of the symbolic
representations that you need to
understand in order for us to continue
to develop our investigation of
phenomena like unconscious symbolism.
So that's that.
See you next [inaudible].