Hi everyone.
I'm talking to you today from Melbourne,
Australia,
where it's sunny and warm,
much unlike Toronto.
I left there five days ago
and it was blizzardy and cold,
so it's really nice to see the sun.
I've been here with my wife, Tammy,
and a good curb.
Dainty is the name of the,
of the crew that I'm traveling with,
a production company and they've been
really good. Um, we've been to Perth,
did two shows there to Adelaide,
have a show tonight at Melbourne with
about 5,000 people and Canberra, Sydney,
Brisbane, Auckland,
Christchurch, Wellington,
Auckland again, Sydney,
Melbourne, and Brisbane.
I just wanted to let you know that there
are tickets left to a number of the
shows on Thursday,
February 21st at the Michael Follower
Center in Wellington, New Zealand.
There are tickets available on Saturday,
February 23rd at the Logan Campbell
Center in Auckland, New Zealand.
There are tickets available Tuesday,
February 26th at the ICC,
Sydney theater at Darling
Harbor on Wednesday,
February 27th at the plenary Melbourne
Convention and Exhibition Center in
Melbourne, as you might've expected.
There are also tickets available.
And then finally,
Thursday,
February 28th at the Brisbane
Convention and Exhibition Center,
they can all be found@jordanbpeterson.com
forward slash events.
And so many of these shows are selling
out at a relatively rapid rate.
These latter ones were ones
we added because there was
additional popular demand.
So if you do want to see the
12 rules for life lectures,
this would be a good opportunity to do it.
Uh,
thanks to everyone in Australia and New
Zealand so far for making this a very
productive and positive trip.
I hope to see you there to shows
if being very gratifying and um,
useful and productive and
meaningful and positive,
all of those things. Uh, there are serious
conversations. Everyone seems to be,
um,
I would say engaged by them and focused
and it's altogether a positive thing.
So if you're interested,
the tickets are available and um,
I'll put a little bit more information
down at the bottom of the screen on the
description of the video.
So I hope to see you there.
Thanks very much for all the support. It's
much appreciated and quite remarkable.
Yeah,
experience. I would say, bye bye.