I'm not an atheist anymore because I
don't look at the world that way
anymore.
I'm not a materialist anymore.
I don't think the world is made out of
matter.
I think it's made out of what matters.
It's made out of meaning.
Look at it from,
uh,
from the perspective of modern brain
science,
what we orient towards unconsciously,
which means what captures our attention
is meaning and it captures our attention
before we know what it is the brain acts
as if the world is made out of
information or made out of meaning.
Heidegger,
for example,
German philosopher was convinced that
the world was made out of meaning
essentially,
and that people's primary interaction
with being was interaction with meaning
and that isn't what modern people think
because they're deeply materialistic.
If you go back 400 years or 500 years
and you look at what people meant when
they said matter,
which is what things are made out of,
what they thought mattered was,
isn't like what we think it is.
It wasn't like this material stuff sort
of like dirt that everything was made
out of.
It was.
It was much more complicated than not.
Problem with the standard view of matter
is that it doesn't really deal with the
fact that matter comes in a raise and in
patterns and the patterns and the
arrays,
which is sort of lost when you think
about Adam's.
That's where all the action is.
That's where the reality is.
God creates Adam and Eve explicitly in
his own image.
There's a variety of interpretations
about the first being that God created,
so there's a tradition in medieval
Christianity and Judaism as well that
the first man was hermaphroditic and
male and female together and then
separated into two separate entities
which then we're forever looking to be
rejoined and there's a very profound
psychological idea there which is that
the union of masculine and feminine
produces a kind of perfect wholeness and
you can think about that as being
expressed biologically given the males
need females and masculine needs
feminine.
But you can also think about it as
different aspects of the psyche or
between people or different aspects of
the psyche within people.
So whatever consciousness,
whatever consciousness is,
it comes in masculine and feminine
embodiments.
The masculine and the feminine
embodiment are equally representations
of God,
which I think is quite remarkable
because you know there's a whole line of
feminist criticism of the western
tradition that makes the presumption
that the whole structure is patriarchal
and I don't think that's true.
If it was patriarchal,
it would have been man that was created
in the image of God and it is explicitly
not that what feminine and masculine as
well as being markers for gender
behavior.
Also symbolic categories and the
feminine symbolic category is the the
genet tricks of things.
The Matrix because the female is
associated with the act of with with the
most fundamental aspects of the act of
reproduction,
so it's out of the feminine.
That new form spring for example,
new forms come out of what you don't
understand and that's the matrix of
being and new biological forms come come
out of a feminine substrate that's
female creatures and so the masculine
aspect is more seminal in in a symbolic
sense of that.
The seminal idea is the instigator,
so to speak,
and it's also.
It also stands in mythology for a kind
of logical clarity and cutting,
whereas the feminine stands for more
like something that's whole and
undifferentiated.
There's some suggestion in the story of
Adam and Eve that the woman is the
primary food sharer and I think that's
associated in some way with her ability
to make Adam self conscious,
which is exactly what she does.
She offers him something that makes him
self conscious and she becomes self
consciousness conscious.
Also.
As a consequence in women make men self
conscious.
You can't think of a truth that's truer
than that,
and the reason they do it is because
they're very selective and most men they
reject.
So God comes up and he's looking for
Adam because he's used to wandering
around with them and Adam's hiding
behind a bush which says something about
Adam's level of intelligence first.
Because you know God can see through
bushes,
but it also says something about his
level of self consciousness.
Because what it means is that when Adam
become self conscious,
he no longer believes that the fact that
he was made in the image of God is
sufficient to give him stature.
And so God says,
well,
who told you you were naked?
And this is where.
This is really Adam's fall,
I think he says it was the woman.
He blames her,
which is really pathological.
The woman you gave me,
it was her fault.
Yeah,
she made you self conscious.
Well,
Hooray.
You know,
you woke up.
There's something to be said for that.
Now.
Women torture man into being awake,
and I don't suppose that's always
received with gratitude.
John Milton,
he wrote paradise lost for two reasons.
One was to justify the ways of God to
man,
and the second rationale for his writing
was to codify mythologies stories that
were in some ways peripheral to
canonical Christianity into a single
coherent narrative.
Here's a question he tried to answer,
which was,
well,
if God was a all knowing,
why would he sat Adam and eve up to
fall?
And Milton has a very sophisticated
answer to that,
and it is that people truly have
freewill,
and even if God knew that they were
going to fall,
there was nothing he could do to stop
that except deny them freewill.
And Freewill is valuable that that
denial was not going to happen.
Dostoevsky points out that freedom
happens to be very important to people
and even arbitrary freedom,
like people want the freedom to go to
hell in a handbasket even they don't
want constraints.
They're willing to put up with a lot to
have their freedom.
And God's judgment is something like
freedom is better than safety.
The snake in the garden of Eden is a
really interesting character.
Human beings and their closest
biological relative chimpanzees are
innately afraid of and attracted to
reptiles.
They automatically trigger off responses
in a part of the brain called the
Amygdala that's associated with anxiety.
And I think the evolutionary reason for
this is that mammals and reptiles have
been at war in a sense over ecological
turf for something between $60,000,200,
million years reptilian features which
are cold blooded,
uh,
a piercing I'd tooth lurking,
nocturnal out there,
out in the unknown.
Outward chaos is the snake is
representative of the unknown in a
sense,
and it's an ambivalent feature and you
see that,
you see that even in its used in
mythology because for example,
the dragon in,
in,
in western culture is a negative
feature,
but in Chinese culture it's positive
feature.
And so the unknown is like that.
It's positive and negative.
The snake in the garden of Eden is
representative of all those things that
lurk when you think you know what you're
doing and when you think you know what
you're doing,
you've carved out this little Eden has
little paradise in which you're
operating,
but there's always something that's
lurking and that's all the things you're
not paying attention to.
Well,
that's the snake and we're not snake
pops up.
People are,
we're wired.
If a little snake pops out,
we might want to run away from it,
but we're curious about that.
We're going to go over there and
investigate right away.
Now,
when chimps come across a python in the
forest,
they have a specific cry.
It's called a snake wrath,
and the chimps who don't like snakes,
they don't run from it.
They back off and then they watch the
thing.
They cannot tear their eyes away from it
and some of them will stand there and
look at it for 10 minutes.
Other individuals will stand there for
hours watching the snake.
The unknown is fascinating.
We can't look away from it.
We have to encounter it even if it's
terrifying.
It's partly why,
you know teenagers like horror movies,
they're driven to look at the snake.
They're driven to interact with the
snake.
In Genesis,
of course,
interacting with the snake means the end
of paradise just like it does in life.
There are ideas that the serpent in the
garden of Eden was Satan and trying to
destroy God's handiwork.
People often look back in their lives
and they say,
well,
you know,
I got knocked out of my little paradise
by a,
you know,
this particular event,
but looking back on it really made me
grow up.
It really made me mature.
Whatever it is,
that's the serpent in the garden of Eden
certainly plays that role.
It's a catalyst.
Much of what's unknown is redemptive.
Much of what's unknown gives life saver
it.
It provides the kind of excitement that
justifies suffering.
The injunction behind religious thought
fundamentally is that you should live
your life in such a way that the
suffering it has to contain because
you're confined and vulnerable is
justified.
A Profane World exists because paradise
always falls apart now and that's a
catastrophe.
That's the human catastrophe and maybe
that's original scent and profane life
is characterized by suffering intense
suffering,
and that's a terrible thing.
I mean,
it's so terrible that the first two
people to really inhabit the profane
world,
who cain and Abel.
Cain is so disturbed by the nature of
the world that he turns into a
revengeful,
homicidal,
resentful,
fascist,
authoritarian,
and the father of war.
Well,
that's how bad,
that's how bad profane existence can be,
but if you keep going in the same
direction,
you can get so conscious that the
profane conditions of of being are no
longer tragic,
they're acceptable,
but you have to live well enough so that
the suffering is worth it.
If you took advantage of every
opportunity you had,
if you crawl through every window that
was open to you,
if you lived as perfectly as you could,
your life would be justifiable on its
own terms despite its suffering and
despite the tragedy in the world.
That's why character guard said that
people are redeemed one by one and not
in groups.
You know,
it's an individual project.
I would say human beings are built to
take tragedy,
but they're not built to take evil.
The most unsettling thing isn't that a
close relative dies of cancer.
Unsettling as that is the most
unsettling thing is to be treated
casually in a brutal manner for no other
reason.
Then the brutality itself,
that's what undermines your sense of
your belief in human existence and in
the value of human existence.
That's what demoralizes and kills many
social scientists in particular.
I would say.
I feel that the idea of evil is an
anachronistic.
The reason that evil is obliterated out
of consciousness is because we don't
have a theory to account for it.
Lana,
we don't have a framework within which
it fits on.
Religious ideation certainly provides
that kind of framework.
I also think that we dismiss evil
because it's such a terrifying phenomena
and whenever it crops up its head,
everybody runs around saying,
well,
who could have predicted this?
Who could have predicted this,
but you know,
all you have to do is look and you can
predict it,
and the people who perpetrated often say
exactly what they're doing and why.
So the columbine kids,
for example,
they said something very much like,
well,
we've taken a close look at existence
and it isn't worthy.
It's not worthy because people are
limited invulnerable and there's way too
much suffering and suffering.
Vulnerable things are kind of despicable
and it would be better if they were just
all wiped out.
Plus I'm the guy to do it,
and that's exactly.
Fundamentally,
that's exactly what they claimed.
You might say,
well,
why would someone come to that
conclusion?
It's like,
that's not a good answer.
Everyone comes to that conclusion from
from time to time when they're
disappointed or frustrated or when you
know their dreams of falling apart or
when someone near them suffers or they
doubt the utility not only of their own
existence but of existence itself,
if it's taken far enough,
taken far enough,
that attitude in genders,
atrocity,
it's evil,
and I think you can define it no problem
because people say,
well,
you can define evil.
It's wrong.
Evil is the production of suffering for
its own sake.
That's simple and if you think people
don't do that regularly,
well you know you're just.
You just haven't been looking.