So I have a plan I'd like to talk to you
about,
I presume that most of you watching this
video are subscribers and are interested
in the content of this channel.
Um,
I'd like to improve it.
There are some features of the videos,
especially the class lectures that I'm
not happy about and I presume you're not
all that happy.
Both them either.
Um,
most importantly,
I think they lack the proper images,
but there are also segments of the
videos that are only relevant to an in
class audience,
so information about tests and so on and
there's parts of them that arena audible
or where the digressions aren't exactly
appropriate and as well there are
lectures across years that pertained to
the same theme that should be unified in
some manner so that they're as
intelligible and tight as they could be.
I'd also like to make transcripts
available to people and it would be good
if the lectures were subtitled.
The transcriptions would help with that
and then maybe they can also be
translated.
Um,
I have some volunteers who are already
working on that.
So I set up a page for this channel on a
site called Patrion.
Patriot allows people who are interested
in the contents of say a youtube channel
like this one
to help in the further development of
the projects that are posted there.
So if you're interested in doing that
and you'd like to see the sorts of
things that I just described,
then you could click and subscribe and
maybe that would be good.
So
that's the plan.