So back in February,
I received the following letter from a
student at Linfield college and
according to its website
with campuses in Mcminnville,
Portland,
and a prestigious online program.
Linfield college is a premier choice in
the Pacific northwest for a high quality
traditional liberal arts education.
Want to learn more,
contact us for details about her degree
and certificate program offerings.
A student there who I won't name
sent me the followup letter.
Dear Dr Peterson.
I'm an undergraduate student and
Linfield college in Mcminnville,
Oregon.
The international students for Liberty
Conference recently granted me a small
sum to organize pro liberty events on
campus with an emphasis on the
importance of free speech.
I'm writing to ask you if you're
accepting speaking invitations at this
time and if you're scheduled sometime
between now and may,
would allow it to help narrow down my
options.
I would like to offer you $1,500 and an
invitation to speak here this spring
semester.
Your travel and accommodation costs will
also be covered.
I perceived Linfield as an institution
at an ideological crossroads.
I feel it is my responsibility to pick
the most effective voice possible for
helping linfield chart a course that
will ensure its future as a place of
reason and academic integrity.
After listening to many of your lectures
and interviews,
I believe your message is ideal for our
campus.
Honest and productive argumentation is
one of your specialties.
Linfield would greatly benefit from
being introduced to your ideas on the
subject.
We're a small college of roughly 2000
students situated in quiet wine country.
Your work continues to have a deep
impact on my personal and intellectual
growth.
I'd be honored to hear from you.
Thank you for your time and
consideration.
So after considering it for a while,
I agreed to come and speak at Linfield
College.
On March 18th,
I received a note from an invitation
student,
the inviting students who said,
good morning Dr Peterson.
I would be overjoyed to confirm a date.
So we went about doing that
on April seventh.
He replied to me again to update me.
He said the talk will be held in Ice
Auditorium in Melrose Halt April 24th,
beginning at 7:00 PM.
I'm referring to the events simply as a
talk with Jordan Peterson because his
speaking style allows for a lot of
fluidity in topic.
However,
the core theme to the event is the
importance of freedom of speech,
especially in higher education.
Some of the administration slash student
government have began to fret about the
potential for people to feel open,
quote,
offended,
and oppressed.
Close quote by Peterson's talk.
It's more pushback than I expected at
Linfield.
What?
I don't think it's a cause for concern.
I'm fighting hard to keep their worries
at bay and there's a very supportive
group of students and community members
who have my back free speech.
We'll win on April 17th.
The following article appeared in
student newspaper
Kenny Neal,
editor in chief.
It's called hate symbol on ball riles
campus.
The linfield young Americans for liberty
groups,
free speech ball outside of Walker Hall
on April Twelfth,
received attention from students and
faculty when a student drew pepe the
frog,
which has recently been appropriated by
white supremacist groups.
Linfield college posted the picture of
the ball when it's instagram account,
but it was later removed because of the
frogs association with alt right groups.
As soon as it was pointed out that the
photo included the image,
the instagram post was removed.
President Thomas Heli set the free
speech ball event.
The first event in this freely at series
at Linfield encouraged students to
express themselves by writing and
drawing on the ball to promote free
speech.
Pepe the frog is a popular Internet meme
that is often appeared in humorous ways.
The Anti Defamation League has listed
pepe the frog on its hate symbols
database.
I only heard about it secondhand and I
understand that it is a place for free
speech,
but in all reality,
it was certainly done in very poor
taste.
Junior John Christianson set according
to its website,
the a mission is to open quote,
identify,
educate,
train,
and mobilize youth activists committed
to winning on principle.
Our goal is to cast the leaders of
tomorrow and reclaim the policies,
candidates,
and direction of our government.
Post quote,
a member of Y,
a l drew the pepe,
the frog on the ball,
but asked to remain on identified open
quote,
I knew the person who drew happy.
He didn't draw it to be negative.
He drew it to be funny.
Close quote,
senior Parker Wells,
a member of y,
a l sad.
He continued.
We understand some groups appropriated
the image,
but any image can be appropriated.
Wells set his goals with the free speech
ball,
where to get people thinking about the
rights to free expression and to bring
more attention to the y a l group.
He said,
I understand that it's necessary to set
limits,
but I don't think this cartoon fraud is
a limit to set for free speech.
I find it unfortunate that people can
enjoy this event because of the frog
image
as a part of it's speak freely.
Series y a l is bringing Dr Jordan
Peterson to campus on Monday,
April 24th.
The group is also showing the
documentary the red pill on Tuesday,
May 2nd
professor of English resume Dot Fowler.
Stab,
stab,
open quote.
I find both the invitation of Jordan
Peterson and the screening of the
documentary,
the red by the young Americans for
Liberty Club,
extremely problematic problematic
because neither peterson northern film
will be promoting dialogues about
gendered inclusions,
but rather be promoting a dangerous and
offensive logic of gendered exclusions.
Dr [inaudible] continued promotion of
such exclusionary practices,
greatly threatened safe spaces for our
students,
staff and faculty who belong to
marginalized groups and violates our
ethos of upholding mutual respect on our
campus.
The president's diversity committee will
hold a discussion at 5:30 PM on Monday
in the pioneer reading room titled Free
Speech,
what it is and what it is,
not the discussion.
We'll examine free speech and members of
the Linfield community or encouraged to
attend.
So that's the end of that newspaper
article.
So I read that it was forwarded to me
soon after I tweeted the following
message.
Open quote,
I'm violating some more safe spaces.
Suit Linfield College.
April 24th.
Well,
on April 19th I received a letter from
the student who'd organized my car.
He said things have gotten nuclear this
email.
The one I'm going to read to you was
just sent to all of Lynnfield.
One of the stipulations they are
referring to is the contract which they
rejected because it was a day late.
Our Club is currently looking for space
in downtown in Mcminnville to hold
Peterson's stark and step.
The media is likely getting involved.
I'm sorry for this insanity.
We tried very hard to keep things simple
here.
So here is the letter sent out to the
entire community
linfield community.
I am writing on behalf of the Linfield
cabinet as officer in charge,
what President Kelly is out.
I want to let the Linfield community
know that the Aas,
Llc Associated Students of Linfield
College has determined it will not fun
Dr Jordan Peterson's appearance next
week because stipulations for the event
were not met by the requester,
young Americans for liberty.
Since the authorization parameters,
we're not satisfied.
The college will not host the event on
April 24.
Among the stipulations was that the
event was to be a private linfield
college only event by his own tweet
yesterday to 107,000 followers.
Dr Peterson indicates he would be open
quote,
violating more safe spaces soon.
Linfield College,
close quote,
likeminded supporters from outside or
community have responded affirmatively.
Our policy on anti harassment protection
and academic freedom states that open
quotes,
anti harassment policies are not
intended to limit the free exchange of
opinions or the vigorous debate over
ideas.
However,
intimidation,
harassment,
exploitation,
and the use or threat of force are
incompatible with the preservation of
this freedom.
The letter continues based on the
speaker's own words.
This event no longer presents the
possibility of academic inquiry within
the Linfield community.
Our policy is clear.
Open quote,
harassment and intimidation preclude the
very possibility for maintaining an
atmosphere of academic freedom.
We cannot welcome speakers,
witness stipulations for their
appearances are not mapped and who
attend,
who intend to violate the safety of our
community.
Respectfully,
Susan at Kipp and hand.
So I wrote a letter to Susan Agora
Chippenham.
Now you understand that by this time the
flights had been arranged,
the accommodation had been arranged,
everything was in place,
and of course they had known about this
for a long time.
Dear Susan,
I received a copy of your letter to the
Linfield community this morning as well
as an indication that my long scheduled
talk at Linfield has been canceled.
That is fine,
I suppose except that the plane tickets
have been booked and the hotel
reservations have been made as well as
three days taken out of my schedule at
my expense.
Alright,
thank you.
Are Treating me and the student group
who invited me in a manner that is
absolutely reprehensible as well as
cowardly and underhanded.
I have made arrangements to come to
lynnfield which is extremely distant
from me and that was the way in good
faith.
Now you cancel it with a plethora of
specious reasons including your anti
harassment policy.
Although I have harassed no one nor
intimidated,
exploited,
or threaten force had I not previously
received notice of the controversy
around my arrival,
which is in my opinion,
unwarranted.
I would not have tweeted my intent to
open quote violate safe spaces,
close quote,
which is a satirical comment in case it
needs to be said.
Obviously you were looking for any
excuse no matter how trivial to cancel
this event.
You also note that open quote,
this event no longer presents the
possibility of academic inquiry within
the Linfield community close quote,
I might point out that Lynnfield is a
college not a community,
and that ideas need to be discussed in a
college.
You also state that open quote,
anti harassment policies are intended to
limit the free exchange of opinions or
the vigorous debate over ideas,
close quote and then proceed to do
exactly that.
You also mentioned that you have
received support from open quote,
likeminded supporters,
close quote from outside of your
community,
which is hardly surprising or
informative,
given that they were likeminded.
You also suggest that because the
contract was delayed one day,
that constitutes sufficient grounds for
cancellation even though you knew well
that the event was booked and finalized
and it's such delays are by no means
unheard of in such situations.
You might also note that a guest invited
to your college might expect to be
treated with a modicum of consideration
and respect.
Here's what I plan to do.
I'm going to make a video tomorrow
morning at the latest reading this
letter on Youtube.
Explaining that by invitation has been
revoked what that means for me and the
nature of the reasons given.
I will also read this letter of response
from me.
It shouldn't be watched by about 150,000
viewers,
many of whom I imagine will be linfield
alumni,
supporters and students.
I'm perfectly willing to see what they
all have to say.
Then we can let the dust settle where it
may sincerely.
Dr Jordan Peterson,
professor of psychology,
University of Toronto.
I received absolutely nothing in
response.
God,
no,
he didn't even have the decency to send
me a notification explaining their
rationale.
Nothing.
So I was treated as far as I'm concerned
with,
with uh,
well,
let's call it unprofessionally and leave
it at that.
So what's the story now?
The organizing students tried to book an
alternative venue.
They didn't have enough money to rent a
suitable theater or lecture hall.
I told them that they could use my
honorarium to pay for the space which
they did.
The yamhill valley news registered
Dotcom posted this update April 20th off
campus venue found for controversial
Speaker Linfield college student
government organization this week with
drew permission for a newly organized
club,
young Americans for liberty to bring up
controversial speaker to campus for a
free public talk.
Monday,
the group has responded by lining up an
off campus location for the presentation
featuring Jordan Peterson,
Canadian professor whose campaign
against gender neutral pronouns is
considered offensive by some do the
transgender population.
Peterson has been rebooked for seven to
9:00 PM at the falls event center,
housed in the former chapel on the
evergreen aviation and space museum
campus.
So on with the show,
and you can figure out what I think of
the linfield administrators who pulled
this stunt on your own.
Thanks for watching.
Members of the community
community for liberty,
other organizations that support this
events in those who travel to get here
along with the people on the live
stream.
My name is Lucas Carter and I'm the
president of the linkage chapter of
young Americans for liberty.
My Vice President Keeper Smith Been.
You've been in the coordinator market
grills
in Secretary Alton Ramsey who was
handling tonight's a live stream.
Thank you.
So we're the team that organized this to
ensure that liberty wants a night
judging by this parallel.
I think we accomplished that,
but first,
just a couple of technical things to get
it.
Either way,
we're all doing a live stream because we
received support from all over the
nation and I mean all over.
So we're asking to stay off the white
bike please.
So all our friends and families can
enjoy this live stream without any
hiccups.
Uh,
secondly,
we do have a donation bucket in the back
to help cover a Jordan Peterson's travel
expenses.
Right now my goal is a $750 in any
excess funds will go towards his
research.
So moving on,
I can talk a little about the club when
keiffer nice story of this club.
Back in February,
we didn't know what to expect.
We didn't have a vision.
However,
given recent political events,
not just the
splits,
many people are afraid to speak out over
years of aspects to how was the club as
Dr Nate Libertarian values,
let's engage the public in the community
and like open free the bait for the sake
of intellectual advancements,
being able to debate,
being able to reach conclusions with St,
t in respect to one another's,
I'd like to think leadership that just
introduced all the hard work towards it
towards accomplishing this goal that we
truly believe in.
Finally,
I was the best next semester as chapter
President Keeper Smith era.
Take over next semester after I
graduates.
Now,
more importantly,
there was something I need to address to
the lingo community
on behalf of the club
on behalf of the club in the leadership.
I like to take this time to publicly
apologize for eating unintended harm
that has occurred over these past two
weeks.
It is not within the clubs with tensions
degenerate any arm or create environment
where people feel unsafe.
We just want to make that clear.
We want people be more movement.
That's our intention and I'm also going
to ask the public to not raising it.
Pitchforks at my school.
I love my school early.
Do I didn't move all the way out here
more to just to like trash anything.
I love my school.
And beyond that situation behind the
scenes is a lot more complex than what's
been released to the public.
Cloud itself has made mistakes too and I
just got to say thank you for
cooperation in these matters.
Now I'd like to introduce the main
coordinator of this events.
He has done far more work than any of
us.
You know,
he spoke with Pearson for an advance.
He spoke with the media who found this
venue last minute.
Such a beautiful venue by the way.
He handled most of the paperwork and
more.
I can't think of another note.
Please welcome event coordinator Parker
Wells.
Thank you.
Hello everybody.
I'm a senior at college and I'm
overjoyed to see a third response,
uh,
considering ms dot Dubay had some major
complications just last week.
Uh,
it's overwhelming.
The response has been so,
so positive here.
So thank you for that.
Um,
I have to express my gratitude to
students for liberty young Americans,
for liberty,
for students who are unsure about how to
get involved on your college campuses.
I highly recommend the network of
liberty minded organizations because
they've been very supportive throughout
this whole whole thank you to them.
Lastly,
I like to frame tonight's talk as an
opportunity for us to open our minds and
make an honest effort at understanding
each each other and on that note all the
way from the University of Toronto.
Please welcome Dr Jordan Peterson.
Thank you.
Thank you burt,
and also thank you for your persistence.
The first thing I'd like to say is that
Parker told me can 10 minutes before the
talk that he has very much enjoyed going
to linfield college,
which I just had had the opportunity to
stroll through absolutely spectacularly
beautiful lakes.
Looks like everyone's dream of a classic
Liberal Arts College,
and so he wanted me to let everyone know
that he's had a great time in Europe.
He didn't want to bring any disrepute on
colleges,
so I thought I'd end up.
It's important to know that it's easy
for things to be made black and white
because that's simple,
but certainly things are the least bit
simple.
It's useful to keep that in mind.
So I'm going to start this by reading
you something that I wrote specifically
for this talk.
I want to.
I always want to do something different
in each talk because one of the previous
talk and part of the reason that you
talk is to get things clear in your
mind.
It's a good way of thinking.
It's the best way of thinking.
So I suppose in some sense it's opens a
poll.
Maybe that's what it is.
It's.
It's what I hope to cover tonight.
So what I'm going to do is read you the
outline first.
I guess it's an outline and then I'm
going to go through it line by line and
see if I can clarify to us and also to
beat what I mean.
So I'm going to orient the talk tonight
around the ethics of free speech we've
talked about about or thought a lot
about,
let's say the right to free speech and
something you might want to also
consider the obligation to free speech
because I actually think it's deeper
than a right.
I think you're obligated to speak freely
because otherwise people don't have the
benefit of your whatever wisdom you
possess and at least you possess the
wisdom of your own experience.
At the very least you have that and
that's as valid as a form of truth,
as any other form of truth and it's
often a truth that can be usefully
communicated to other people.
And so it's to the communities benefit.
You say what your experience has taught
because there isn't anyone who has
experience like you and one of the
things that I've learned from being a
clinical psychologist,
but I would say more specifically from
being a very careful listener,
is that if you listen to people and they
can talk to you,
they tell you the most amazing things.
You know,
my,
my typical week I work,
even today I was speaking to four
different people.
They're supporters of mine online and I
beat some of the and I had four
conversations that were just absolutely
profound and it's so interesting because
if people are allowed,
encouraged to express themselves and
that's something that you could do by
listening to someone,
they open up and they were there as it's
as interesting as a Dostoevsky know
people's actual lights are
extraordinarily interesting and and
important that they can speak freely
about them because then they can tell
you all the things they know that you
don't know and then you get to know them
and that's such a good deal.
So.
So
I'm going to tell you some things that I
believe to be true and constitute the
back of his talk.
So the first thing is that life is
suffering.
And then I would say that this is an
attempt to.
This is my attempt to reconcile the
existence of multiple transcendent
virtues.
Transcended virtues are the lights that
guide you through your life essentially
that the principles by which it's
necessary to live if you're going to
have a life that's meaningful and
profound and beneficial,
and there are multiple transcendent
values.
It isn't clear how they relate to one
another,
and
this is my attempt to understand how
they relate to so I started with the
truth that I believe to be supreme,
which is that life is suffering and then
that love is the desire to see
unnecessary suffering,
ameliorated
and the truth is the handmaiden of law
and the dialogue is the pathway to
truth.
And then humility
is recognition of personal insufficiency
and the willingness to learn
and then to learn is to die voluntarily
and be born again in great ways and
small.
So speech must be untrammeled so that
dialogue can take place
so that we can all humbly learn.
So the truth,
concert law,
so that suffering can be ameliorated
so that we can all stumble forward,
so to speak,
to the Kingdom of God.
So I'll try to unpack that.
Well,
I think the idea that light is
suffering.
This comes as no surprise to anyone
in my estimation.
There's two reasons for that.
One seems to have to do with the
structure of being itself,
and by that I mean
there seems to be something about
limitation that's required for existence
and it's a difficult notion to make
clear,
but I can tell you a little story about
what I call him.
My son was young when he was three years
old.
Um,
I thought he was a remarkable creature.
I thought Saint Nicholas,
my daughter,
there's something remarkable.
Have little kids.
No,
they're,
uh,
they're a little beacons of enthusiasm
and wonder.
I suppose it,
although it takes great effort to care
for them,
they repaid you partly by their
enthusiasm and partly by the fact that
they looked at the world as if it's a
new thing and that allows you to do the
same thing when you're around them.
So they refresh the world for you.
And,
and that's,
that's a great thing.
Now,
of course,
if you're a parent,
one of the things that sprite Info your
children is that they're vulnerable.
That's part of the burden of
responsibility that's associated with
being a parent,
but then you might think about that
vulnerability as a well as a liability.
I suppose that's one way of thinking
about it,
but then I thought,
well that's an interesting way of
looking at it that it's only a liability
because maybe you would like your child
not to be vulnerable.
But then I thought that through and
not the practical map price close.
I thought,
well,
because I was worried,
you know,
he'd go up the street and the car would
go into the playground and some bully
would knock them over a dog bite up or
something like that,
you know,
and of course little kids are always
backing themselves and falling down the
stairs and that kind of thing.
And
I thought,
well,
what would you have to do to have a
little being that didn't have those
problems?
Well,
I thought you could.
it's like a superhuman intelligence.
That would be a start.
It could be 20 feet tall instead of
three feet tall and he can be encased in
titanium and know he could be made him
vulnerable or at near invulnerable.
But the problem with that is that you
have to replace what he was piece by
piece until there was nothing left.
And so that's one.
That was partly when I realized because
realizations like this of course unfold
over time,
that when you,
when you deeply care for someone,
you don't care for them.
Despite their vulnerability.
You care for them with the knowledge
that their vulnerability as an intrinsic
part of them.
You care for the remarkable fact of
their weakness and specificity just as
much as you care for them for whatever
abilities they bring to bear whatever
capacities they have.
And so to love someone is to Simmel
tediously accept their vulnerability as
a valid part of their feeding and that's
a necessary thing to do in life because
life is suffering and but without,
without,
without the vulnerability that brings
suffering,
then there doesn't seem to be any
possibility of individual existence.
And so to me,
it seems that in order for us to exist
as individuals,
in some real sense,
we have to be limited in precisely the
manner that we are limited in the Ba in
some sense requires that limitation and
that vulnerability.
There is an old idea,
I don't remember where I read it.
It was many years ago.
I think it was from Jewish commentary on
the Torah.
It was like a Zen Koan almost.
The question was what does it being with
the classical attributes of God
omniscient,
omnipotent and omnipresence?
What does it feel like now?
It's a very interesting question because
of course,
obviously the obvious answer is,
well,
nothing,
but that's the wrong answer.
The right answer is to be like that
blacks limitation and the commentator
was putting that argument forward as a
justification for the creation of man.
And I thought that was a spectacularly
brilliant insight that there was
something that something that lacks
nothing,
blacks max lack itself.
And I read something about something
written by Kierkegaard where he said the
same thing.
He said that he knew himself as someone
who was never going to be able to make
life easy for people in the way the
great,
the great inventors of the late 19th
century had been things increasingly
easy for people and so that his task was
going to be to determine how was he
could make life more difficult for
people and he knew he would be thanked
as one of the benefactors of the age for
doing precisely that regard.
Tempted to,
I suppose lay a heavy moral burden on
his readers and he knew that that was
perhaps not something that people would
appreciate immediately,
but perhaps on reflection they would
find that that was exactly what they
wanted and one of the things that speak
very remarkable to me as I've been
speaking to people recently is that
because I think that I'm doing something
similar.
I'm trying to lay a burden on people and
by all appearances I'm trying to lay a
burden on me.
At least that's who's responding to it.
I mean,
look at this audience.
It's like it must be 95 percent.
It's very,
very interesting to me,
but,
but there's something about about
responsibility.
It's associated with the transcendence
of suffering and it's absolutely
necessary for life to proceed properly,
so life is suffering because we're
vulnerable and it's also suffering I
would say because we're evil and I've
tried to define evil.
There's the tragic part of life is the
fact that our,
our vulnerability is built in and we we
have psychological problems or physical
problems and we all die and that's part
of the structure of existence.
It's the same structure that brain is
about tornadoes and hurricanes and
earthquakes and natural catastrophes of
all types.
It's,
it's the impartial brutality of reality
and that contributes greatly to human
suffering.
Probably would be,
as I said,
it also be a precondition for being
itself,
but then there's the other kind of
suffering that we bring the corner
herself and I would categorize that
under the heading of malevolence and
malevolence is the desire to break,
to increase suffering in some sense,
for the sake of suffering itself.
It's like an art form.
I think that's the best way to
conceptualize it.
Something is authentic.
It's the same aesthetic that drove the
Nazis to put that up.
Terrible Jill,
about gates of Auschwitz,
which was that work with make you free,
and of course the freedom that is being
offered it in the Nazi camps was death
and that was great,
terrible joke and it's.
It's a very malevolent spirit that would
dare to joke in that manner,
but that's the spirit that we all have
attended because there's part of each of
us that because of the suffering that
life entails is bitter about existence,
would wish in some sense to see it
eradicated and something I learned from
reading those great play faust.
He as a character in there
Mephistopheles who's sort of the
intellectual version of Satan,
I suppose,
and hurt the has mephistopheles attempt
to explain the reason for his existence
or at least the reason for his modem.
Ba in memphis softly says memphis golf
means basically says,
if you're.
That hasn't say this twice,
that because the existence is
characterized by such dreadful
suffering,
it would be better if it never existed
at all.
And that's what he's bringing.
Working to bring about.
And that struck me in a very
deep manner because I had recognized by
that time that life was difficult enough
so that it was challenging to walk
through it without becoming embittered
and resentful,
let's say,
and and then to become arrogant because
of that,
and then to become a judge of existence.
Because of that,
if you ever wonder,
of course you do what is going through
the minds of people who do such things
as shoot up elementary school's full of
schoolchildren knowing the things that I
just described is very useful in
developing some understanding because
the people who do that are resentful and
bitter and the brooded upon it for well
not hours,
weeks,
months and years,
and they conclude that existence itself
is evil and that it should be.
It should be taken revenge upon.
The way that you take revenge on
existence most precisely is to find the
most innocent people and punish them the
most.
Dreadful,
and that's the motive behind shooting
elementary school kids in a playground.
Let's say that's a very dark place to
go,
but that's a place that people are
perfectly capable of going up.
The terrible thing is that we have the
motivation to go there and you can make
a rational case for going there,
but that doesn't make it the proper
place to go and that brings me to the
second point,
which is that love is the desire to see
unnecessary suffering.
Ameliorated lob is a very difficult word
to use because in some sense it's been
most today.
I know such a commonplace.
If you're attempting to affect virtue,
then the first thing you do is speak
about love and it's very difficult to
speak about love without feeling.
I would say self contempt really because
it is a word that's misused so bad.
I'd like to offer a technical definition
of it and then put it into relationship,
into proper relationship with what I
already discussed.
If,
if hatred is the desire to CPA
eliminated because of its catastrophe,
that blog is the desire to see being
developed elevated maybe even because of
that suffering and to say that the
proper orientation in life is to work
diligently for the alleviation of
unnecessary suffering and to make that
the core element of your being,
your actual aim.
Because you need a name,
everyone needs an aid.
We're we're,
we're,
we're creatures who are evolved to aim
or hunters for that matter,
and we need a target to a map.
We're not ever oriented properly without
name and then he might say,
well,
why not choose a name that is everything
that you could possibly wanted to be an
and I would say that that is what you
want to do because first of all,
being miserable and vulnerable and
subject to catastrophe of decay.
It's easy to see st and to self contempt
and misery,
self-conscious misery,
and I think the only way out of that as
to
voluntarily shoulder a burden that the
shouldering out brand students some
respect for your own existence and so
then you think,
well,
the way forward confidently is to find
the biggest load that you can possibly
lift and then lifted and then walk
forward with it because they had.
You can see that there's something to
you that transcends your vulnerability.
It knows the world and works against the
very terrible problems of suffering to
the level that might drive you to
despair to begin with.
And so when I'm working with my clinical
clients,
and I think when I'm speaking to people
in general,
when I'm properly oriented,
this is the development of thought that
was originally laid down in part by Carl
Rogers,
so he was deeply influenced by by his
Christian background.
He was a very famous psychologist and he
said that when you treat people in
therapies with unconditional positive
regard,
and I would say that that's unknowable
formulation,
but it's erroneous because that isn't
exactly in my estimation what you should
do with people and I don't think it's
what I do with people.
What do I do with people is to try to
find the part of the striving towards
the light and that would like being
itself to be elevated and unknowable and
suffering ameliorating especially the
unnecessary suffering.
And then form an alliance with that and
communicate with that and encourage
that.
Which is what I think you do to people
that you love and you can't do that if
there's bitterness in your heart because
that's actually the part that you want
to destroy.
If you're bitter as the story of Cain
and Abel tells us
in a carer in a terribly brief period of
time the terrible power you replaced
contempt for being and resentment and
hatred with,
with law,
and that's the desire to see the good
flourish in you and others,
and I don't mean the good and that
smarmy and contemptible manner that it's
often presented.
I'd been good as the combination of
brilliant awareness and courage and
strength that it really is
you would wish to bring forward at
everyone to encourage and everyone if
you were oriented properly in the world
and to seek that kind of orientation is
to ground yourself in love instead of
Mephistophelean,
Patriot and
and
you have nothing better to do that now.
You might as well do the best that you
have to do because when you have to
lose,
you're going to lose everything anyways.
So in the process of preparing to use
everything,
you might as well risk everything you
have doing the best thing that you can
possibly conceive of and there's no loss
in that for you.
There's nothing but gain.
There's nothing but gain for everyone
around you if you do that,
and so why would you not do that?
Except for bitterness and resentment?
Perhaps luck,
a lack of confidence perhaps because you
haven't been encouraged properly and
that's too bad.
That's a lot different than being
empowered by the way to be encouraged.
It's a much better word.
So then I wrote the truth is the
handmaiden of love and what I meant by
that because I've always wondered
knowing that
truth in love or perhaps the cardinal
virtues,
what is the proper way of
conceptualizing the relationship?
And it seems to me that truth has to be
oriented towards something.
It needs a context.
There's no such thing as not in the way
that I'm thinking of truth.
There's no such thing as context free
truth up in the moral domain,
not in the domain of action,
and that's the talking about truth in
action.
Truth is the handmaiden of law bicycles
because having orienting yourself to the
highest good that you could conceive,
whoa,
like Japan or wishing on the star and
Oak Hill.
Then you speak truth with that
orientation in mind.
Having the faith,
I suppose that because B is good,
articulating its nature as clearly as
possible is the best way of continuing
to encourage that good to spring
forward.
Otherwise you're presuming if you use
deceit and falsehood,
that being is essentially corrupt
because otherwise you wouldn't have to
falsify it in order to operate in the
world.
So you could say,
well,
you could make the courageous assumption
that being is good despite I suppose
some evidence to the contrary and then
take the great risk of speaking truth in
relationship to that under the
assumption that whatever speaking truth
produces,
if it's oriented properly,
is good.
You have to make decisions like that in
your life.
I mean,
I can give you a
simple example.
I suppose awhile back I was speaking at
mcmaster university and there were a lot
of protesters there and that made me
nervous because you never know when
someone is going to do something
unforgivably stupid.
And so far I've been fortunate that in
the controversies that I've been
embroiled in that no one has done that.
They've pushed the edges of that but.
But they haven't done it and truly thank
God for that,
but having said that,
I wasn't upset by the presence of the
protesters because I couldn't tell if in
fact they were.
There was a good thing or a bad thing.
It could be a good thing.
You couldn't be a bad thing.
It was a consequence of what I had been
speaking up and that's what happened.
And so I thought there was no reason not
to let that play itself out because the
end of the story has not yet been
reached.
And the meaning of the events could not
yet be specified.
And you know,
sometimes in your family,
if you tell someone the truth,
and I don't mean I hope I've coined
this,
I don't mean black truths,
you know,
there's white lies.
It's in a way that I with to preserve a
higher moral virtue,
you,
you continue to get lower moral virtue.
You know,
perhaps you don't tell a child dying of
cancer that they're going to die.
I don't know because it depends very
much on the particulars of the
situation.
But you can understand that you have
mixed motives in a situation like that.
You can also speak black truths and
black truth is when you say something
that's normally true,
but you're using it as a weapon for
another purpose and that's the truth,
that's that's really more a more
profound an evil lie than any other one
that you can possibly manage because
you're using the truth in a way that
corrupts.
It corrupts the truth itself and that's
really reprehensible,
but barring the use of the block truth,
you know,
if within your family you say what you
mean,
say what you think.
That can often cause tremendous upheaval
because,
well,
because many relationships are cobbled
together by various alliances of willful
blindness and things left unspoken and
that's a very bad longterm strategy.
You know,
I've seen people who are embroiled in
the death throes of a relationship that
perhaps a crew 100,000 lies over its
course and became so unstable because of
that,
there is no hope for it.
Each of those lives was a forced stole
opportunity to address something
difficult with truth that was for gone
and all that does is make those unsolved
problems accumulate and multiply and
they eventually take over and attack and
generally when you're least expected.
And so if you speak the truth in your
family cautiously and carefully and
knowing that it could be wrong,
you will cause a that conflict,
but it's conceivable that that's the
least amount about people in conflict
that could exist to make things right.
And I believe that that is the case and
that one of the things that I tell
people who are too agreeable,
let's say I don't like to cause conflict
and I actually don't like to cause
conflict because I'm more agreeable than
I should be.
Is that the ethical requirement to tell
the truth trumps any desire to avoid
conflict.
And it's partly because
you only forestall the conflict and
magnified.
There's no escaping it and it's better
to engage in directly when it first with
the necessity first arises then to
forestall.
And so for people who are only too
willing to make peace at the expense of
themselves,
let's say I try to encourage them to
generate conflict by telling the truth,
and I would say inevitably that has
nothing but beneficial medium to
longterm consequences in their life,
even though it exposes them to more
conflict in the short term.
It also alleviates their resentment
because if someone has made me resentful
or if you become resentful because of
someone's actions,
then there's only two real reasons why.
One is that you should pull up your
socks and quit complaining.
Quit whining because you're being
required to shoulder responsibility or
you're being oppressed and tyrannized by
someone who doesn't know where their
proper limits are and in the former case
that you should get your act together
and in the latter case,
you should stand up and stop that person
from encroaching upon you
so you speak truth in your family.
Let's say perhaps even to yourself at
the risk of conflict and often severe
conflict.
But the ultimate goal is to bring peace.
It's paradoxical because
we often don't think of a piece of
something that's reached in conflict,
but that is precisely,
for example,
why we value free speech because the
wisdom of humanity and the wisest people
that we know that would include those
people who were intelligent enough to
follow this country on the principles
that is found on knew that whatever
conflict free speech might produce pale
in comparison to the conflict that was
generated by tyranny and repression of
exchange of opinion,
and so it's never a matter of picking a
safe path because there's no such thing
as a safe path.
It's only a matter of picking the path
that produces the least catastrophe
possible and it's an.
It's an inviolable principle,
I would say,
and also the fundamental principle of
Western civilization that speech freely
exchanged is the best pathway to peace
and redemption that we have identified
and so it should remain untrammeled
under all circumstances possible.
Subject to very infrequent restraints of
the sort that are already encapsulated
in law such that,
for example,
you cannot incite someone to criminal
activity
humility.
Dialogue is the pathway.
You can truth.
Well,
I understand that you have to understand
why we fake and the reason we think is
for the same reason that animals,
including us act and the reason that
animals act is so that they can survive
in the world.
They do things so that they can survive
in the world,
but the problem with doing things in the
world,
the problem with acting in the world is
that you can act in a manner that causes
the substation of your Ba.
You can act in a manner that gets you
killed.
You can act in a manner that makes you
sick.
You can make a mistake and you pay for
that,
and that's the danger of acting.
So human beings have replaced near
acting with thinking and what you do.
What you think is you produced variance
of yourself and you walk them through an
imaginary time and a place and you know
what happens to those imaginary
variants.
As they act out those particular
patterns of behavior and you know which
ones get into trouble at which ones
succeed and you let the ones that get
into trouble die and you let ones that
succeed grip.
Hold of your behavior and act them out
in the world.
It was a brilliant innovation you might
say on the part of our ancestors to grow
cognitive resources,
sophisticated enough to produce variance
of ourselves in a fictional space so
that our thoughts could die instead of
us,
and so that's why we fail so that our
thoughts can die instead of us,
and then the reason that we speak is to
learn from other people's thoughts,
but more than that,
it's that thinking individually is a
very limited process because you're
ignorant,
which means you don't know everything
and not only that bias in many,
many ways your bias by what you know and
what you don't know.
You're biased by what assumed you're
biased by how you deceive yourself.
You're biased by your temperament and
your locale at your and your position in
history.
All of these things make you a very
limited observer of the world,
and so I think as you like,
you can never think sufficiently.
And so what we do because of that is
taught.
And so if I talk and I'm speaking
truthfully,
which means I'm telling you how things
appear to be to me,
that does not mean that I possess the
truth,
that means that I am saying as in an
articulate manner as I possibly can,
how things appear to me,
that you can tell me how things appear
to you and I could listen to you and
maybe you can tell me some things about
how things appear that I don't already
know.
And that's such a good deal because the
purpose of thinking is to let our
thoughts die instead of us.
And if you can kill one of my thoughts
because it's stupid,
then I don't have to act it out and die.
And so that's like a really good deal.
And so the reason that we engage in
dialogue is so that we can take our
thoughts that protect us from our own
mortality and improve them and perhaps
improve the morale.
And there's just no loss in that.
And so what that means in some senses
that you can view everyone who disagrees
with you as a source of potential
wisdom.
Because if you talk to someone who
agrees with you,
all you're going to find out is what you
already know.
You already know that.
And if you talk to someone who doesn't
agree with you,
maybe one out of 10 things they say or
maybe one out of 100 things of God only
knows,
you know,
um,
maybe there is wise is you and they're
perverse way.
You can discuss something with them and
they'll tell you something you never
really thought of before and that'll
just make some potentially miserable
event in your life that much less likely
and how good for you can that possibly
be in like.
I do believe that I've learned that.
I've talked to you a great variety of
people and I don't care if people agree
with me.
In fact,
generally speaking,
I find it more interesting if they
don't.
And I don't try to convince people
because I don't believe that I have any
right to determine their destiny.
And I don't want to be turned in their
destiny because I don't know what's best
for them.
And so I do listen to all sorts of
strange and unlikely people and they
tell me things that I don't know all the
time and now it's just a spectacularly
good deal.
And I decided a long time ago that one
of the fundamental choices you make in
life is whether your
in love with what you know or in love
with what we don't know.
And I would say there's a lot more of
what you don't know that there is what
you know.
And so it would be better to be in love
with what you don't know because you
don't know so much that if you could
make friends with what you don't know,
then you're going to be continually
enlightened.
And to be enlightened is to be engaged
in the process of being enlightened.
Not to be enlightened in any final sense
because that's just not possible.
So it's to act in a manner that
continually in you.
And a huge part of that is humility.
And that's another word that's very
difficult to use.
I would say like love because it's,
it's another word that's been both to
death in some sense.
And it sounds like kind of cringing
cowardice,
limitation,
but that's not what it means.
What it means is that you know that
there isn't enough to you and you can
tell if there isn't enough to you
because your life isn't everything.
It could be.
That's the arrogance,
right?
If your wife has everything you could
imagine it to be,
well then perhaps you don't need
humility,
but since you're life is not everything
you could imagine it to be,
you're deeply wrong about a lot of
space,
and so since you're wrong,
then you should be looking around for
the opportunity to correct those errors.
Because why wouldn't you accept to
protect your territory and that
territory by definition,
give them the existence of your own
suffering is insufficient,
so why are you playing to it so
desperately?
It doesn't provide what you need or what
you want and a transformation of it and
the expansion and up and the refiguring
of it might be everything that you could
possibly want.
And so then you start to envision
yourself instead of as the holder of a
piece of territory,
as the person who is attempting to
expand their capacity to act within all
sorts of territories and exposure to
more people into more viewpoints,
especially with those people are telling
you the truth,
which they will do if you actually
listen to them,
then you can have your cake and eat it
too.
That's a great deal.
And it's another way of reducing
unnecessary suffering in the world by
certainly reducing suffering and then
perhaps learning to be how to be a
greater use to people around you,
which again seems to be nothing but for
the good.
So humility is recognition of personal
insufficiency and the willingness to
learn in order to overcome the
insufficiency and then to learn is to
die voluntarily and be born again in
great ways in small.
That's an archetypal idea at the basis
of Western civilization is the idea that
the logos,
which is the capacity for truthful
stage,
is somehow associated with the act of
death and rebirth.
And there is multiple ways of
interpreting that idea.
And because I'm a psychologist,
I tend to interpret it psychologically.
I don't claim that the psychological
interpretation exhausts the concept
because I don't believe it does,
but you see you are a certain way and
some of that way is an error.
And then when you learn them,
an error has taken place.
You have to let go of the conceptions
that produced that error and that can be
very,
very painful.
For example,
you may have entered into a relationship
that was pathological and you know it's
about analytical.
What you're hooked into it in,
your emotions are hooked into it and
you've configured your life around it.
And then in order to move forward,
you have to let go of that.
You have to admit to all the errors
you've made through the time was wasted
and you have to allow a large part of
himself to die.
Let's say you experienced in grief and
misery and sorrow and and and anxiety
and sleepless nights and all of that.
But it's better than dying completely.
And what?
What that indicates is that every time
you learned something large or small,
the part that was in the era prior to
obtaining that bit of information has to
deteriorating,
disappeared.
There's pain associated with that,
but then there's the possibility for
growth and transformation and one of the
most fundamental decisions that human
beings made in their lives is whether or
not they're going to identify with what
they are or with what they could be and
if they identify with what they could
be,
then they have to continually let what
they are die so what they could come
forward and so to learn is to dive.
Voluntarily,
have to be born again in great ways and
small.
So then I wrote,
yeah,
speech must be untrammeled so that
dialogue can take place.
I think of the discussions that I've had
with my wife and my kids,
but primarily with my wife who's a very
honest person.
In fact,
I've been married for 28 years.
I've known her for 45 years and I'm 55.
It's a very long time.
We'd been friends with very long time
and when she first came to be with me 30
years ago,
I was learning to some of the things
that I've talked to you about tonight
and I told her that if we were going to
be together
that she would have to tell the truth
because if you didn't tell the truth and
I wouldn't know who she was and I
wouldn't know where we were and I
wouldn't be able to solve any problems
and neither would she because we'd be
living a fictional relationship with one
another.
That struck me as a very bad idea,
and so she took that to heart.
I would say.
I would also say it's like the more
honest person than me
and I'm not claiming claiming to be
morally virtuous at any particular.
I'm aware why multitude of faults,
but the fact she has ripped so tightly
onto the truth means that if I ever have
a problem that I can talk to her and I
know what she thinks.
She doesn't tell me that she's right.
We've learned that you know,
because to tell someone the truth does
not mean to play that you're correct.
It only is to claim that you're trying
to communicate the way things look to
you as clearly as possible and that
you're open to the of correction,
right?
Because if someone can tell you how
you're wrong precisely exactly how
you're wrong,
that's such a gift.
If someone is willing to tell you the
truth,
then you have the possibility of
learning from them and then you have two
grades instead of one and that's a good
deal and that's actually the spiritual
purpose of marriage,
let's say,
is to produce a union between two
people.
It's predicated upon the truth so that
the information flow between the kid
maximize and so that they can both be
elevated above the,
the the restrictions of their own
solitary bias existence and that
facilitates.
That produces the proper environment for
children because then the child children
don't face the father or the mother.
They faced the union of the father and
the mother and that's an inviolable
forest and the children will attempt to
play one person off against the other.
Because they're tricky because they're
human and they're full of trouble.
They're very good at poking and prodding
and manipulating and invest in,
but they want to hit a wall.
They want to hit a wall that doesn't
move because that makes them secure and
if you have a relationship that's based
on truth,
then you can talk about how it is that
you should meet with your children,
for example,
and you can agree upon it,
and then when the children push the
limits as they inevitably will,
they don't find something spongy and
dictate and eat a find something that's
strong and sturdy and it's a wall and of
course they can't move through the wall
and that's frustrating,
but then they're protected by the wall
and that stops them from being anxious
beyond their capacity to bear.
And so that structure that's brought
about by truthful communication builds
the walls around children that allow
them to play freely and expand
themselves and exist properly in the
world.
And so speech must be untraveled so that
dialogue can take place.
It's the only.
If you talk to me,
I want to know what you think.
I don't say I don't agree with it.
If you disagree with me,
I'm going to fight with every bit of
power at my disposal to determine who is
correct.
Well simultaneously recognizing that
it's possible that it's you and not me
and I'm not going to risk undergoing the
small or large death that I have to
undergo.
If I find out that you're right without
being convinced that you're right,
so I'm learned to hit him with
everything I've got,
but part of that is also a quote that if
I'm wrong,
you will provide me with a better
argument than the one I already have and
that will make me better armed when I go
out into the world.
And so there's utility in neat,
defeated by a skillful opponent and my
wife is precisely that sort of opponent.
Also has the addition,
remarkable talent of being able to
string together a list,
a vicious insults,
one after the other,
like one I have ever encountered in my
life.
It's quite comical because sometimes
when we're embroiled in conflict,
she'll start to do that and say
something so outrageous,
so absolutely beyond the Pale that he'll
make me laugh and crack up,
and then of course that's great,
useful because if there is something
ridiculous about quieting and that
always brings to mind and when she does
that,
then I'm reminded why I liked her so
much back then and still do because it's
something to see someone with that kind
of at spirit,
that solar array for that,
so speech must be untrammeled so that
dialogue can take place so that we can
all humbly learn.
Well.
That's the other element of humility is
that humility is a precondition for
learning.
Right,
and you have to be open to the
possibility that you don't know what you
need to know.
That's the thing.
It's not that you don't know everything
because obviously you don't know
everything,
but it's more specific than that is that
you may not know what you need to know.
Sometime in your life was going to be a
piece of information.
That's pretty sure it'll be in a
negotiation or maybe in a medical
decision or or maybe relationship
decision or an art or in a,
in a complex,
in a,
in a complex tense situation with
urgency and danger and you'll need a
tool and then in there or things will go
badly for you and you won't have it
because there was an opportunity at some
point in your life where have you been
slightly more humbled you would have
learned,
you would have learned how to formulate
and and utilize that tool right then and
there and you didn't,
and that left you.
I know,
and the thing is that your most powerful
arms are your words by any,
by any measure and the opportunity that
you have to sharpen your capacity to use
your words through dialogue,
which is why space is cannot be safe for
any length of time.
It's because of the safer the space is
made now that more dangerous the space
is made in the future and that's
something that people are unwilling to
understand it because they don't want to
face the fundamental truth that life is
suffering.
There's no real escape from it,
and so they make artificial spaces where
people could delude themselves
temporarily into naive again that life
can be made safe,
would in fact the best you could do is
arm people to move forward in the past.
When you do that is to test them with
combat at every opportunity that you
have to do that with the most carefully
crafted arguments at your disposal and
to teach them to stand up and defend
their thoughts so that when they entered
the real world and they're challenged,
they know how to stand up forthrightly
instead of crying and running home.
Thank
so that we can all humbling so that
truth conserved love.
Well,
that's the goal is to
inform yourself and that's a good word
to inform yourself.
It's.
It's of course the short form of
information and I really liked that word
because it breaks into in formation and
something information is formed
properly.
Ambien,
the order.
It's information,
right?
It's everything is aligned and moving in
the same way like an army of information
and so if you expose yourself to
information,
you get informed and we put yourself
information and then your crystalline in
your structure and and and and difficult
to contend with and that's what you want
to be.
That's the thing to be.
And you do that by
learning humbling and that once you are
in Toronto than your capacity to speak
properly and to formulate your arguments
and to negotiate and to formulate
problems and to formulate solutions and
to seek consensus makes you powerful
enough.
Not so much that tragedy stays away from
you because it can't,
but so that when tragedy does come along
and perhaps even when malevolence comes
along that you'll be maximally prepared
for it and we'll be able to deal with
it.
Which is what you have to do as a human
being.
Because there is in fact no avoiding it.
And so what you do with someone that you
love as you make them strong,
you do not tell them that the world's
safe and that they're secure and that
there's nothing there to get the.
Because there is everything there to get
the
and so the best you can do is strengthen
them and that's what a college is
supposed to do and that's where the
university is supposed to do and I would
say that the colleges and the
universities are increasingly failing on
both of those fronts and it might be
said that that's isolated only to the
colleges and universities,
but we should remember that those are
the storehouses of our cultural
knowledge and the generators of the new
leaders and if the university's falter
and that's particularly true of the
humanities,
then that falter and undermines the
entire culture.
Perhaps the entire civilization,
and I do believe that we are in the
process of doing precisely that now and
I don't think that what I did six months
ago and the creating of these two little
videos complaining about a rather
obscure piece of legislation in the
rather tiny and insignificant country
would have the track that the attention
that it did attract.
If it was only about pronouns.
It's certainly not only about pronouns.
In fact,
it's not about pronouns at all.
So the truth can serve low.
Oh,
well you want to articulate
yourself and you want to be information
so that
you can formulate your existence.
You
generate your narrative.
You could take your position in the
world forthrightly and and with the
capacity to intimidate when necessary
and with the capacity to be a monster
when necessary,
have to be civilized and unnecessary and
there was nothing in that that making
yourself sharper or improve to make
yourself sharper is to carry a sharper
sort.
Of course in these days with the highest
virtue is harmlessness message like that
seems positive reverse,
but it's completely wrong.
This is why I think my talks attracts
men,
is that a woman who hates,
he wants to castrate you and make you
safe that way,
but a woman who loves you and wants to
make you incredibly powerful and wise
because then your housekeeper
destruction is regulated in that manner
and you're still good for something and
so that would be the optimal solution
rather than merely weakening and
destroying.
And I think we've had plenty of that.
You've had more than enough,
and I know as well,
but women who have their souls intact,
I would rather have monstrous man who
were civilized and cringing milk sops,
who were harmless but good for nothing.
Thank you.
Most women already have enough children
to take care of.
So the truth conserved love so that
suffering can be ameliorated.
Well,
obviously that's the goal.
No,
I,
I hear people all the time who are
possessed by a certain nihilism of
spirit and that's not surprising.
The understructure of the foundations of
our cultural to be severely assaulted.
I would say there were under tremendous
assault.
That's a process that has been unfolding
for very many years perhaps since the
development of empirical science,
which is,
which is one of the contributing factors
because it's undermined our faith in
our,
in our traditional religious viewpoints.
There was structure our,
our moral behaviors or decisions about
value.
There's many other reasons why the
foundations upon which Western
civilization rests are under assault.
Um,
and because of that,
it's easy to be uncertain and to say,
well,
what is the meaning of life?
There is nothing to life.
There's rolling,
rolling significant,
and there's nothing but suffering and
why should I do anything in the face of
all?
I would say,
well,
we can take that.
Part of that is a fundamental truth is
that the fact that life is suffering is
a meeting.
It's a meeting that no amount of
rational argumentation we'll,
uh,
will,
will rescue you from.
In fact,
the more nihilistic you come,
the more the fact that life is suffering
becomes self evident.
It's almost as if he was trying to teach
you something and it is trying to teach
you something.
It's trying to teach you that you cannot
argue with your way of suffering and so
then you might as well do something
about it.
And then I would say,
well,
that's where you can find the meaning.
It's very straightforward.
There's suffering in the world and much
of it is aborad and,
and,
and unacceptable to anyone who attends
to it.
Anyone looks at it and the right answer
to a child who's,
who's been beaten and abused is not
who's going to care in a million years.
But what can I do to stop that right
now?
And the nihilistic response that
everything is insignificant means that
the pain of children,
for example,
is insignificant.
And that seems to be to me close enough
to self evidently wrong so that it's an
argument.
15 just be dispensed with.
And so I might say to people who are
wondering where to look for the meaning
in their life is to take the self
evident phenomena of,
of phenomenon,
of suffering seriously,
and to orient themselves as rapidly as
possible towards its amelioration and to
work diligently towards that and for a
number of years.
And then to reevaluate the wife at the
end of that and see if they think any
differently about the world because they
certainly will.
And so the nihilistic argument to me
seems remarkably weak both on its space
and in depth because there are things to
be done and the things that need to be
done are obvious to anyone who will open
their eyes and look at them.
And so then I would say,
well,
open your eyes and look what needs to be
done immediately around you and do it
and keep doing that and keep doing it.
And then you'll find that the APP,
the questions,
the answers to the questions that you
have been paralyzed you for so many
years,
will manifest themselves to you clearly
enough so that you won't have to believe
that because they will be self evident
so that suffering can be ameliorated so
that we can all stumble forward.
Well,
why I stumbled well,
that's because we stumbled when we move
forward because we don't know everything
and so we moved forward in error
constantly,
which is why we need to speak with other
people,
can listen so that we don't stumble and
fall and be unable to arise and so we
stumbled forward because forward
movement is necessary to human beings
and forward movement implies that there
is something better to go to and there
is something better to go to the that is
at least a world where there is the
least amount of suffering that is
commensurate with the existence of the
world.
And I would say that we have ameliorated
a substantial amount of suffering in the
20th century.
We're doing a very good job of doing
such things as combating absolutely
already.
You may or may not know that every
single day about 150,000 people
worldwide are lifted out of absolute
poverty and about 300,000 people are
attached to the electrical grid that we
have.
We have the enriching the bottom segment
of the world's population for the last
15 years at a rate.
It's absolutely unprecedented in human
history and that makes me wonder just
how well we could do if everyone really
put their shoulders to the wheel and
pushed and so if we did that together,
then perhaps we won't degenerate into
absolute chaos,
which is certainly something that learns
now and is a real threat.
We're at a crisis point as far as I can
tell,
and we need to determine whether we want
everything to go to hell,
which it certainly could and I wouldn't
recommend that or whether or not we can
work together.
And that brings me to the last line,
which is that so that we can all
stumbled forward to the Kingdom of God.
And why do I put it that way?
And the reason I put it that way is
because.
Well,
first of all,
everybody does really know what that
means even though they may not believe
in it,
but that doesn't really matter.
I mean,
I think that to believe is to act and
not to spout a set of statements and it
is certainly possible to act as if what
you were attempting to do is bring about
the Kingdom of God and I would say that
doing so is something that will
radically justify your miserable
existence and that's really what you
need is radical justification for your
miserable existence.
And because human beings are so
powerful,
really powerful beyond the limits of our
imagination,
we have no idea what our ultimate
destiny might be.
That it's not unclear what our limits
are.
That if we decided to improve the place,
let's say,
and I would say starting with ourselves
because that is the safest and humblest
way to begin.
That.
There's no telling where we might end up
and since we're all fragile and
vulnerable creatures and we're going to
lose everything anyways.
We might as well risk everything to
obtain the highest possible good,
and then that will make the mystery that
constitutes our life bearable as a
consequence of our intrinsic nobility
and there's nothing in that accept the
good and so then why not do it,
and so that's what I would enjoy and
encourage,
encourage everyone to do because there's
nothing better to do than now and we
might as well all do that,
which there is nothing better than that.
Thank you
and so all repeat the outline
and then
no,
I was talking about the boundaries of
free speech and I believe that speech
should be untrammeled because it's too
dangerous with counseling does not mean
that.
I believe that speech free speech comes
without responsibility.
I believe quite the contrary.
The free speech carries with it the
highest responsibility because you went
right to speak and wish to shoulder the
responsibility of speaking.
Then you have to contend with the fact
that your words are the force that
shapes the world and that with every
word you utter things tilt slightly
heavenward or slightly pell word and
that that responsibility rests firmly on
your shoulders and it's inescapable and
that's a terrible thing to realize is a
very meaningful thing to realize and
people saying that they would like their
life to be meaningful,
but that's a questionable claim because
to recognize your life is meaningful,
is to understand that everything you do
matters and that what it means for
things to matter is that you're deciding
in some sense between heaven on earth,
hell on earth with every decision that
you make and the decisions that you make
echo far beyond you in ways that are
almost incomprehensible and the destiny
of the world is determined by the
collective decisions of all the
individuals that make up the world and
that we're all locked together.
Deciding in which metaphysical direction
our little planet will
we'll go.
So free speech carries with it heavy
responsibility,
but the responsibility is something you
want because it justifies suffering of
existence.
Said life is suffering.
Love is the desire to see necessary
suffering.
Meliorative truth is the handmaid of
love.
Dialogue is the pathway to truth,
humility,
that's recognition of personal
insufficiency and the willingness to
learn
to learn is to dive voluntarily and to
be born again in great ways in small
Paul,
so speech must be untrammeled so that
dialogue
can take place so that we can all humbly
learn so that truth can serve law so
that suffering can be ameliorated so
that we can all step forward towards the
Kingdom of God.
Thank you for inviting me to
Mcminnville.
Thanks.
Now we'd like to take the opportunity to
open things up for questions to answer
and what we might do here.
Obviously
a the person in the
simple answer your questions.
Thanks
for everything you said.
Excuse me.
I've ever had the opportunity to see so
many people in here
and he knew of test,
validated.
My whole exists.
To thank is we're working importantly in
India
and we're alone and we're.
We don't eat together.
It's like a death trap.
Medicare bringing people together is a
monster.
What is it that people are resonating to
that we can use that will bring people
together so that we can talk about
solutions?
No.
I watched this Netflix special with
Russell Peters and Russell Peters,
for those of you who don't know is a
Canadian comic.
He's of Indian descent.
He was raised in a suburb in Toronto
which makes them acutely or culinary
Canadian and he's very
similar to the Canadian culture and
Russell has made his living
insulting every racial and ethnic group
that he could possibly insulted and so
interesting because he filled up an
entire arena in London.
I think it was the most people that have
ever gathered together to see a comedian
before and it was a United Nations in
the.
In the arena.
The Arabs were there and the and the
Jews were there and the Russians were
there in the south.
Americans were there and every group was
waiting with their tongues out so that
Russell could insult their particular
ethnicity so that they could feel
finally that someone was saying
something that was truthful and not hide
it and to say it openly in some sense
and to make light of it and we would say
you bring people together by
telling them what you think without
manipulation,
without care for the outcome,
and people can hear the very rough terms
if they trust who's stating the heaters
is trusted by everyone because he's,
I suppose
non discriminant prejudice.
He hates everyone equally.
There's nothing behind his assaults
except
the desire for everyone to come together
in recognition of their idiocy and
vulnerability of people very much enjoy
that and so I would say you unite people
to the degree that they can be united by
saying what you think without trying to
manipulate the outcome,
and so that's a better way to live
anyways because you don't have to keep
track of anything that way.
Not so nice.
Say what you think carefully.
You observed the response and adjust
your behavior and and everyone likes
that.
So I don't know a better way of doing,
of doing it now,
so
I'm an author and a biologist and I was
researching
district keep disturbing.
It was written by
and the Irish.
It's a peculiar,
neither
exceed
because it voted so much energy
and the author took this and her
proposition was
so
full
of basically
and
the brain
as much of a
race.
Well,
that's a cool question.
I think that you retool the story of the
fall genesis,
you see,
I mean that because as far as I can tell
that story means is that at some,
at some point in time people became
conceptually sophisticated enough to
understand their own vulnerability,
to realize their own native units.
Do you discovered the path to discover
the necessity of work and to be blown
out of that preconscious paradise into
the tragic believe history.
I believe that's what that story means
and you can read that as a tragic
catastrophe with no solution.
And I would say though,
however,
that since that time and God only knows
when that was,
the human race has been collectively
attempting to address the problem and
the solution that's emerged is something
like,
although a little bit of excess
consciousness demolish us,
a lot more consciousness could save us,
and I think that that's the case.
There's no going back,
right?
Alcohol makes you unconscious,
for example,
when that's part of why people like it
then it's not surprising sedatives to
the APP,
the things that people do to themselves
to destroy your consciousness by
distraction,
do that,
alleviate the terrible catastrophe of
being morally that is easy to bear,
but it's the wrong solution.
The right solution is to be even more
awake and to pay even more attention and
there's a way out the problem that way.
And so the fall,
the idea of the fall indicates something
about people that's irredeemably
damaged.
Well perhaps not redeemable,
serious,
right?
There's this schism,
Mba,
let's say that's not easy to rectify.
What historic indicates,
and I think it's tightly tied with the
kind of evolutionary process that were
just commenting
on,
the Irish elk was actually
developed its excess antlers.
The theory goes as a consequence of
female sexual selection course,
female human beings are very choosy
maters.
Unlike chimpanzees,
let's say,
and there is reasonable evidence that
one of the factories that propelled our
political evolution forward was female
sexual choosing this and and that's what
perhaps that it's eve tempts Adam into
self consciousness in genesis,
and maybe that's why there's been new
eternal enmity between men and women
ever since,
because women certainly do make men self
conscious.
It might be the primary effect that
women have.
Men that's advantageous in a more
conscious men are better,
but it's disadvantages for the manner in
itself.
Consciousness is generally a very
unpleasant emotion,
so I would say however,
that self consciousness is the gateway
to transcendence and development,
and so the best thing for human beings
to do is to bear up underneath their
self-conscious tragic end to transcend
passed that by becoming even more
conscious.
And I think that's the hope that we
have.
I think that that's what the great
religions of the world constantly
dangled before us is that if you are
suffering in your half a weak state,
then it's time to wake up completely and
then perhaps that will go away.
Well,
we don't know,
but we don't have a better option.
No other option is annihilation and that
seems a bit premature,
shall we say.
Yeah.
Given that we're not all we could be,
it seems a bit premature.
Some of your youtube videos you have
talked about the ancient mythology of
Babylon in Egypt and you described it as
a way that they act out what they sensed
to be true,
but even because they couldn't
articulate,
is there a modern day equivalent of
acting out the truth and if so,
describe it for us?
Well,
I would say in large part Christianity's
exactly.
No,
it it.
It's fundamentally
description of pattern,
but in an optimized being be and the way
that it was generated,
and again this is a psychological
interpretation.
I don't claim that it's exhausting.
Not The least is that you could imagine
that as people move through time,
this is akin to the idea that the figure
of Christ is implicit in the Old
Testament,
which is also a psychological idea.
Imagine that as people progress through
time,
they observed that some
were handling exist,
it's better than others,
and those people attracted attention and
admiration and stories regenerated and
so you might say that out of 100 people,
the most capable of honorable and
respectable and useful and benevolent
person was identified and then celebrate
it at least with admiration and then
perhaps with stories and so then you
might imagine that there were 10 groups
of 100 people in each of them had their
story of the most admirable person and
then those stories came together as
those tribes amalgamated and then the
story of the 10 most admirable people
was amalgamated into.
I figured that was the most admirable of
those 10 and the entire groups group of
ten one hundred tribes.
People could come together under that
banner and it really looks like in some
sense that's how monotheism or
polytheism is.
That the tribal groups had their local
ideals,
let's say,
and then when they came together and it
was a local ideals were amalgamated into
what you might describe as a mat at
ideal and people were able to unite
under that Metta ideal.
So for example,
in in Mesopotamia there was a god known
as martyr and Martin had a very large
number of names,
some of which are quite fascinating and
the reason he had a very large number of
names was because he wasn't available.
Have a very large number of previous
thoughts.
So you know,
there's an idea,
a Christian idea,
for example,
that Christ we cave case,
let's say,
or a hero of heroes.
And from a psychological perspective I
just read that was straightforward
observation is that pass the stories of
the great people of the past,
amalgamated.
Out of that emerged in the human
imagination.
A conceptualization of the ideal.
It's a very strange conceptualization
because if it falls something like the
voluntary voluntary acceptance of
suffering and it's simultaneous
transcendence at that's a candidate in
some sense,
the old stories of the hero who fights
the dragon because of course in some
sense the ultimate dragon is about death
and also at the level that might produce
an unjust death and to be able to face
that without shrinking is perhaps the
essential hallmark of the most well
developed character out that ideal is a
product of the collective imagination of
humanity.
From a psychological perspective,
what it means to be on that,
if anything,
I no position to determine.
Okay,
great.
so the question is how do you speak
truth in a highly hierarchical
environment like a workplace where
perhaps you have disagreeable than even
tyrannical managers and a resistance to
the truth?
Well,
that's an excellent question.
The first thing I would say is you
prepare yourself and so if you want to
negotiate,
for example,
you can negotiate from a position of
weakness because you lose,
you'll lose in every way.
You can't stand the conflict.
You've got nothing to fall out.
So if you're in a workplace that's,
that's not admittable to
informative messages,
let's say the first thing you do is look
for another job or I don't,
I don't.
Mainly you take another job.
That is what I need.
I mean you need to provide yourself with
credible options because otherwise
you'll be weak when you,
when you stand forth and especially
somebody who's a bully will just pull
you right over because we've got no
power and so you have to prepare
yourself and you do that by reducing the
risk to yourself in an intelligent map.
And one of the things I counseled my
clients,
many of whom are executives or people
who are successful,
is that you should always be prepared to
make allowable awkward movement move
because otherwise you have negotiating
power.
And so of course that means that if you
have the options,
you're in a weak position,
but it is the case that if you have the
options that you're weak position.
So you keep your CV update,
you develop the skills necessary to make
you movable in the marketplace.
You reduce your fear of interviews as an
alternative.
Know that the processes that you have to
go to through to seek alternative
employment,
which is a very good thing to do
anyways,
and then if you could put yourself in a
position of relative strength,
then you can decide what it is that you
have to say first.
You don't fight unnecessary bouts and
you don't make unnecessary enemies and
perhaps you put forth attendant of
suggested with brain argumentation
behind it after perhaps also finding out
if there are other people who feel the
same way you do and I'm formulating
intentional solution and then generally
speaking,
under those conditions,
the probability that you will be
successful will be buried.
I would also say that if under those
conditions
you still can succeed,
that you should leave because you're
purchasing security of a person out
there,
pricing,
security,
soul,
and that's a bad choice.
It beat you down across time and you
don't want that.
So Yep.
Chicken,
chicken,
you again,
really young Americans for liberty.
So I'm thinking you guys and thank you.
Obviously I'm,
I'm also here for Portland.
I completely agree with your assessment
with some colleagues from the newsroom,
miserable newsgroup called torch cast
your mind if you've got split testing.
Um,
I do have a societal question for you.
What in your view is the macro agenda or
the goal,
the end goal,
the end game for the current sjw left
who fight free speech,
obfuscate the basic concepts of identity
and you pedal outright falsity in
regards to the with things,
for instance,
in the media and on college campuses and
is a solution,
not the solution,
but a solution to that moving of the
overton window,
so to speak,
through mischief,
trolling
speakers.
Well,
the motivational issue is,
is complex.
I think some of it is
the naive good harkness of youth.
Fair bit is that
some of it I think is the consequences
of the introduction of women aren't
passive to the political environment and
the manifestation of the personality
trait,
the personality trait,
agreeableness as a political force for
perhaps the first time in history.
It's a radical transformation and have
women occupy positions of power and we
don't know what that will be for better
or for worse.
To think that it will only be for better
is naive.
You want believe so and then there's
willful blindness.
There's ideological possession and
there's.
There's a kind of.
I'm grateful there's a deep gratitude as
well because in a sense of historical
lack of historical perspective,
it's quite compelling to me to my way of
thinking perhaps because I'm reasonably
well versed in the nature of historical
catastrophes.
The fact that we can all assemble
peacefully in this unbelievably
beautiful place in this crazily
beautiful town with with the tension
that does exist.
Just rather minimal white historical
standards and engage in this sort of
discussion peacefully and productively
is almost incomprehensible given the
evidence that's come forth to us.
Throw a kiss and I don't believe that we
do enough to teach our young people just
exactly how improbable that is and so I
don't think they know and so what they
see instead of the improbable
functionality of our culture is all the
errors that it still makes and it's
reasonable for them to see that,
but not without that broader context.
What to do about.
Well,
I think the fundamental thing to do
about it,
as I said,
is for,
and this is I believe the western way
fundamentally is for people to Excel to
magnify the degree to which they're
taking personal responsibility for their
life because I think that as individuals
they'll find the proper way to fight the
micro battles that will be necessary in
order to stamp the type of rising
radical
radicalism.
Let's leave it at that.
What I think will have with the amount
of what I would also encourage people to
do is to
stop enrolling in those classes.
I mean the humanities are bleeding.
People like map men are leaving in
droves.
There won't be a man in the humanities
at 10 years.
And then most of the social sciences as
well.
I mean I've watched the enrollment
curves for really for decades and have
seen this propagate itself across time,
but more delicately even is that the
overall proportion of enrollment amongst
students in the humanities has declined
every decade since the 19 sixties.
And so as the humanities moves farther
away from what it is that they truly
have to offer,
which is the transmission of the wisdom
of the past to youth so that they could
see their proper way forward and to
become articulate well are responsible
citizens.
As they abandoned that responsibility,
then all they have to offer is dynamism
and resentment.
That doesn't sell well except to a tiny
fraction of people who would like to
have as much of that as they can
possibly manage.
We see it.
We see it happening.
That essay,
overall cultural shift tour.
I'm selling also to people in the
liberty rally in Berkeley.
You look at essentially every post
college protest on the streets,
Portland to Chicago.
It seems that how,
how do we address the.
This type of narrative is not just
adding all this,
but it seems that the idea of what you
were given your framework of getting
into the Kingdom of God,
the kingdom is completely different for
the
cultural issues.
Yeah.
Well,
well,
you know,
in many times in my life I trucked face,
let's say the choice between a political
group and this say philosophical root or
a psychological root that I had chosen
to go and what I gave you tonight is
really the best answer that I have.
I'm not trying to make the case that
would that.
That's a comprehensive answer,
but I think that if you want to move
forward properly,
the best thing to do is to organize
yourself.
I need personally to organize yourself
as well as you possibly cap at the gift,
those things around you that aren't in
order in order your family,
how you conduct yourself because then
you're going to be in the best position
to make the proper decisions in the
specific situations that uptake to you
and I think that that's where people
have their power and I think that power
is not insignificant.
Not at all.
So that's the best I can do for that.
Yeah,
I mean I can.
That was a really interesting question
and I'm not a social justice warrior
myself,
but as I understand it,
I think a lot of people I've talked to
who we think about that,
I think they're really trying to
dismantle what they see to be unfair
systems have advantages and the
patriarchal structures they have it.
So,
um,
my question is because this,
this truth idea really,
really interests me.
Uh,
do you feel that because of the limits
of your own human experience and your
own identity,
that there are things that you will
never be able to change your mind?
I think there are that,
there are things that I'll never.
There are things are,
let's say would stake my life on,
which I think is a better way of putting
it.
I'm one of those is that it's better to
serve,
to denounce it at that it's better to,
to not lie,
let's say instead of telling the truth,
because someone asked earlier,
how can you go about telling the truth
and in some sense you can,
but you can't stop seeing things you've
known to be false.
Which is a good start.
And that's within anyone's scrapped and
I could say I'm not likely to change my
mind about the utility of doing that
either because I've decided that I'm
going to accept the consequences of
doing that gratefully regardless of what
the consequences are.
And so at some point in your life,
and perhaps not precisely when you're
young,
you have to decide what it is that
you're going to act out something Carl
you specify,
he said,
know you're going to act out of
mythological structure of one type or
another.
You're either going to be aware of it or
not.
If you become aware of it,
that perhaps you could choose it.
And that doesn't give you any guarantee
precise,
you know,
because even if you act out,
let's say that her path,
you know when you and you face the
dragon and combat,
there's no necessary.
It's not a necessity that you when the
dragon to the EU.
But the idea is that that's your best.
Fap All things considered.
It's your best bet to face it
forthrightly.
And I believe that.
I believe that because I'm a clinical
psychologist and one of the,
one of the things that clinical
psychologists know is that if you help
people confront the things that they
avoid voluntarily,
they get better and that that's a
fundamental truth and I think it's the
fundamental truth of human advancement
and learning and it's possible that we
are Irish elk and our fundamental
approach to the world is deeply flawed
and if we pursue it wholeheartedly will
end up estate.
It is possible that that's the case,
but if that's the case that there's
nothing I can do about it,
time,
part of the human race and I'm going to
act out its destiny the best that I can
manage and and I'm not willing to
reconsider things at that level.
I think that that's because I've thought
them through sufficiently for me and
because I've also determined the course
of my own life,
that and from watching the effects of
what I be talking about or other people
that what I'm doing is serving the good
at least as well as I could do it and
what I've learned is be very helpful to
me personally.
It's been very helpful to my family.
I know it's been helpful for my students
because they always tell me that and
people write me all the time and say
that they'd found a great utility in
what I was communicating and so that's
enough evidence for me right now that
I'm on a path that's sufficient,
that sufficiently justifies me.
So
I'd just like to say we have about 20
minutes until probably going to take
five
or 10 minutes more questions then about
10 minutes to fill about talks about
themselves and make their way out.
So typically
I just like to thank everybody who
helped organize this event.
Um,
I've been watching yourself on youtube
for a while now and I really felt that
you help me and I'm sure
really,
I really appreciate.
Hey,
it's a pleasure.
So I'm just wondering,
based on history and whatnot that you go
into a discussed like the archipelago
and whatnot,
what kind of role do you think
government should play in society?
I think that it depends on the
circumstances
and so I don't think that that's the
right question.
I think the right question is how should
the government constituted itself so
that it can respond flexibly to the
demands of the situation.
I believe that there's utility in a
conservative viewpoint and I believe
that there's utility in a liberal
viewpoint,
but that it determined it depends on the
specifics of the situation and that
there is also error and even
catastrophic error on both sides,
so the government needs to be
constituted.
I would say much like it is what else
were sovereignty is,
is instantiated it people for better or
worse so that the people can learn from
their errors and that we progress by
engaging in dialogue across people of
different temperamental types because
sometimes the borders are to open and
they need to be tight and sometimes the
borders are too closed and they need to
be elusive if they be.
If the borders between everything become
completely closed and everything,
God's right,
it's deprived of air,
water and everything died.
So there's endless mythological
representations of that would be part of
the reason that Egypt,
for example,
in the mosaic story,
is a kingdom of Sam.
That stone is because Sam Stone Water
and Moses who's,
who's,
who's someone who leads his people out
of tyranny is a master of water and the
message and that story is that sometimes
the kingdom turns to stone and it's a
tyranny and new revivification needs to
be integrated.
The doors have to open,
a new information has to flow in,
but then there are times when I.
The story,
for example,
there are times when,
uh,
there's too much influx of inflammation.
That's a flood.
That's one way of reading the flood
stories.
There's just too much pouring in.
Everyone drops.
And what we have to always ask ourselves
is,
are we tending the garden properly?
Right?
It's not drying out for lack of water.
It's not drowning because there's too
much,
there's too much moisture coming in,
and the only way we can determine that
is by paying attention to communicate.
And that's why free speech is such a
fundamental necessity.
So it's not,
it's not precisely what the government
can do because it has to do many things,
but because it's the society of people
and people have to do many things,
but how the government goes about making
decisions and then at least with the
government that has to do is protect
those,
what would you call the rare and
precious processes that enable it to
continue to be a responsive and alive
entity.
And I think that we have done a
remarkably good job of that.
The West and I think that the US is a
great example of that for all its flaws.
Everything is flaw,
but,
but the proper analysis is flawed
compared to white.
And the answer is to the hypothetical
utopia of your imagination.
The answer is to other similar systems
that have actually existed in time and
space.
And by that measure I would say the West
is doing spectacularly well and I don't
think that we should sync it because of.
Because we're ignorant to vote.
It's available.
Thank you.
Postmodern philosophers,
they mentioned this happened.
That's
destructive ideas caused people
questioning.
We cited
a who has mentioned as an inspiration,
so,
uh,
I wonder how might somebody like or
somebody like me
getting each other?
Well,
a
reasonable amount of food,
colon,
I would say that among the
postmodernists he's rather remarkable in
the fact that you can actually
understand what you say,
what he wrote particularly surprising,
like the idea that mental illness is in
part a social construct is if you're a
reasonably educated clinician that's
more than self evident in virtually
every complex activity that human
engagement is culturally determined to a
large degree,
a exterra doubt that I have a problem
with.
Uh,
and I also know that he put his finger
on a very complex problem,
which is like the central postmodernist
place.
Every situation allows for a potentially
infinite number of interpretations which
is true,
and therefore it's difficult to
determine which interpretation should be
held up as paramount.
Now that's true.
In fact,
the artificial intelligence researchers
ran into that.
They were trying to design systems that
could perceive the world because the
original idea was that perceiving the
world was easy because it's just made a
phase and learning how to manipulate
those states.
That act would be the complicated
problem,
but it actually turned out perception
was the complicated problem because
there's an indefinite number of ways to
perceive things.
Now,
the reason the postmodernist role were
wrong is because there aren't an
indefinite number of interpretations of
the world that don't kill you or make
others killed you.
There's a very constrained number of
interpretations that allow you to
continue to exist and equally
importantly,
allow you to continue to exist in the
presence of other people.
So although there are many
interpretations that you can ferret out
of the Shakespeare text,
your job is to ferret out what that
actually helps you live.
And that's hypothetically the goal of
the guides to great literature.
And so I think the postmodernists
radically overplayed their hand and
that's particularly true with data.
And I think that the people who followed
Aryzta are in many cases doing so
because it's a hell of a lot easier than
actually doing the difficult job of
extracting out useful tools from the
literature of the world,
which is what you do when you read,
you extract out useful tools with
regards to nature being each has said
something about everything.
And so every philosopher of the modern
age,
one way or another is deeply influenced
by nature and the problem with niches
that he was a thinker prolific beyond
comprehension.
Virtually I did recently.
I did a,
I think it was a 45 minute video on one
paragraph.
You choose beyond good and evil and you
know,
I barely started to scrape the surface
of it and of course he has multiple
books.
So Nisha is a very strange character.
And he said that he philosophize with a
hammer and he meant it.
And his critique of Christianity was
devastating I would say.
But I would also say,
and this is a rather shocking
comparison,
that nature play.
The role that you played with regard to
Christianity was the same rule that a
complaining that wooed,
which is the can devour athlete but
disease,
flesh and leave,
what's healthy behind,
and I think there is a reading if
Nietzsche that allows each of that
allows for precisely that when he said
that God was dead,
he also said that that would be a
catastrophe.
The likes of which we could not even
imagine that society itself would
oscillate back and forth murderously for
centuries as a consequence.
So it wasn't triumphant.
He strolled to find out what an
alternative to that point.
Yet he formulated the idea of the
overlap,
so essentially right.
The Superman was capable of creating his
own.
I think that each state there,
I think it was a mistake that was
rectified,
Carl Young,
because you'll know that I think was
really the first person.
Although Nicha has has intimations of
this because nature does say that art
drives philosophize,
right?
Which is very biologically oriented
observation.
Like what you noted was that,
well,
we don't create our own values because
the values are implicit within us,
but we can read the start and that's why
he was so interested in the analysis of
mythology and the unconscious and so I
think the postmodernists took the the
part of nature that's only destructive
to its final conclusion and that's
what's being played out now.
Derrida's critique of modern
civilization is failing a logocentric
right?
Male dominated,
centered around the idea of the logos.
He regarded that as nothing but a tool
of oppression and marginalization.
There's some truth in that because
whenever you produce a value system,
you also exclude things from the value
system as valuable obviously,
but the problem I think that the
postmodernist smoke address you the
alternative pretty all your systems and
dealing with the with the exclusive that
comes along with that is to drop it
nihilistic chaos and worse while you're
drawing to get nihilistic chaos,
you're going to call out sources of
totalitarian order and so it's no,
it's no sweat.
What I seek postmodernism doing do
students,
generally speaking,
it's demoralizing completely until they
come to university.
Looking to categorize the identity,
often cleaning to the last rebated
shreds of their culture.
That's just what's keeping them afloat.
All the postmodernist professors do is
take those remaining.
Frank's took her along to stay above the
water,
tell their illusory and take them away.
It's like,
well,
now you're free.
Like I've dropped you in the middle of
the ocean.
You could swim in any direction you
want.
You're free.
And I think that that's rooted in large
part.
Even in hatred of youth.
I really believed that because why would
you crippled people if you didn't pay?
And so there's hatred of humanity
lurking at the bar,
but the worst excesses of video logs in
general.
You know,
you hear this from environmentalist,
so I've heard this many times,
the planet,
it would be better off if there were no
people on it.
It's like,
well,
let's keep you away from the thermal
nuclear weapons.
Thanks.
So it's not easy to come up with a
canonical interpretation of nature.
There's no doubt about that.
Again,
would say,
I thought for a long time from a
psychological perspective,
I tried to understand whether the
speeches philosophy that drove him
insane,
but I think the evidence for that is
nonexistent.
I think he did suffer from a
degenerative brain disease severity and
I actually think different fundamental
laws,
which I haven't read everything he wrote
because there's books,
pumps,
but I read this great works in
chronological order,
I think is fundamental.
Philosophy is is affirmative negative,
but he's a critic and he wanted to find
something that he could stand on and
that's what critics,
real critics here.
You're not looking to destroy you.
I'm looking for something that you could
stand up and nature was certainly very
useful to me in.
I knew it was also extraordinary useful
to crawl your was a real student of
nature and I was really devoting himself
to solving the problem that each
proposed,
which is well,
what do we do with the aftermath of the
depth of God and humans?
Answer was we rescued from the deaths
and that's the right dance.
That's what the university should be
doing with young people.
It's like you're dead.
Father's in the library,
go out there and fought.
Fair to help.
Right.
And Unite.
Live and become the thing that keeps
chaos at bay.
Right.
Thank you.
Concludes our talk with Jordan Peterson.
Please join me in thanking.
You've been getting.
Thank you.