Last time we spoke,
it was not so long ago,
but
you've been in the headlights even more
since the,
since the release of the book and uh,
and also the,
a beautiful interview with Katherine
Newman.
Yeah.
Well that seemed to start a whole new
plateau,
let's say,
of interest.
Yeah.
And I thought that yes,
I've been in the headlines a lot and
rather an settling amount I would say.
Yeah.
And I don't want to dwell on the cat
thing,
human interview too much because,
uh,
you've,
you've been,
uh,
made to talk so much about it,
but I think you're probably tired about
it,
but just one thing that I think you
demonstrated very clearly,
uh,
about yourself and also about,
saying that patience is a virtue that
you actually,
in the end you want out,
uh,
because you stayed calm and you
explained what you actually meant.
And in the end she liked words and I
think that actually was an inspiring
example to a lot of people.
Yeah.
It seems to have been in,
although it isn't clear why was.
It isn't,
still isn't really clear to me why it
became so incredibly widespread.
I mean,
I think the interview itself on Youtube
as something approximating 8 million
views,
but if you add the commentaries to that,
lots of people have cut it up and
commented on it.
I think it's,
I suspect it exceeds 20 million and
there was something about the interview
that really attracted a tremendous
amount of attention.
So it's very interesting.
It's obviously part and parcel of the
political tension that's,
that's odd that it seems to underlie
virtually everything right now.
I think it's
from the platonic ideal states,
like this is the interview that
illustrates the cultural world where
everything that's wrong about not taking
your opponents seriously,
uh,
then you can always show that interview.
So it's a great,
a great way to just introduce people to
what's wrong with the political
discourse.
I think
I have.
I have a hypothesis to run by you.
Well,
so imagine what's happening.
Is this the.
We're in the midst of a technological
transformation and the online video
services are displacing network and
cable television.
And the online print services are
displacing the traditional print media,
so let's say that,
okay,
so there's increasing desperation on the
part of the traditional media and so
then let's say that as a consequence of
that,
that did that additional nervousness and
instability.
First of all,
many people are leaving,
second budgets are being cut and third
there's increasing desperation for to
hold on to market share.
And as a consequence of that,
more and more articles are polarized
because they attract more attention and
that that's driving the political
polarization in part.
Does that seem reasonable to you?
Yes,
I do think that seems reasonable.
And I do think
you also have a greater need for the
established media to debunk a sort of
the,
the people who are popular on Youtube or
podcasts
free free from
the big thing.
Yeah.
Also some of the TV channels.
So you think it's also direct
competition?
Yes,
but I'm not sure if it's
a sort of a conscious effort.
I think also it's incompetent
sometimes.
You never,
never underestimate everything together
like a
life extremism,
populism,
and they have a very hard time
discerning what sort of
the real Nazis from just people
having legitimate ideas and legitimate.
That's another issue,
right,
is that it's in the radical left
interest to lump everyone who opposes
their ideological attempts into a single
terrifying category because if,
if they had to contend with the fact
that you can be reasonable centrist or
even reasonable center leftist and
dispute the validity of identity
politics as a framework for conducting a
political discussion.
If you have to accept that reasonable
people can do that,
then you have to accept that reasonable
people can object to your ideology and
that implies that your ideology isn't
reasonable.
So there's every reason for people on
the radical left to not only assume that
their opponents are reprehensible,
but to make the case that they're
reprehensible without ever bothering to
scratch below the surface.
So I think that's happening too.
And then of course,
I never wanted to let the university's
off the hook.
And I think the fact that the
universities have allowed and encouraged
the growth of radical leftist ideology
in the humanities and the social
sciences is absolutely completely
inexcusable.
So I might even prove fatal to the
universities we'll see about that,
but it wouldn't surprise me.
Universities have been around a long
time though.
Last we spoke,
I was doing a piece on how radical
feminism had been mandatory for a course
at Lund University.
And we spoke about that.
The professor was a mandated to include
you in this course and I continued
writing about the universities and it
goes much deeper.
It goes even if you look at the grants,
if you look at,
we have 10,
10 billion kroners which are being
distributed from the state and uh,
they,
they are the,
the gender mainstreaming that's taking
place in the university universities
when it comes to courses and uh,
the,
the reading lists and the professors.
It's also when it comes to the grants.
So you have to include a gender
perspective or at least you have to
specify why you don't have a gender
perspective.
Right.
Which is probably fatal.
Yeah,
exactly.
So one of my,
a friend of mine that I got to know him
via his dog because I have a dog and so
our dogs became friends and then we
became friends.
So he made his phd about trouts and wild
and wild trout.
And uh,
and um,
how do you say
a domestic trunks?
No.
Yeah.
So the difference in behavior sounds
very boring,
but it's actually kind of interesting
when
he was about to not get,
not get a grant because he didn't think
religion perspective.
Yep.
And so,
well,
I know now
10 years ago and now it's spreading.
And so I'm,
I'm getting a lot of stories about that.
So it's crazy.
The universities or really it's shifted
into second gear here in Sweden with
this.
Yeah,
it's the same.
It's happening everywhere in the west,
I would say.
Um,
our,
our government just handed down a budget
and every,
as far as I can tell from the initial
response and every government program
has to include a gender perspective now
in the same manner.
And so our government is deciding to
solve a problem that doesn't exist.
Well,
what's happened is that we've accepted
equity,
we've accepted equality outcome as the
measure by which we're going to judge
the fairness of,
uh,
organizations,
um,
operations at the same time when the
social science research is stacking up
on the other side of the distribution to
state ever more clearly and with ever
more with ever less doubt that as you,
um,
as you flatten out the sociological
landscape so that men and women are
treated more equally,
that the difference in their
occupational choices widens,
become crystal clear.
And the,
the response to that from the radicals
is that pseudo science,
even though the people who are doing
these studies aren't conservative,
there aren't conservatives in the social
sciences.
And so people do these studies and
they're shocked by the results they
publish them because they're good
scientists.
Not because these findings buttress
their ideological position and plus
who's ideological position wasn't to
wish that as you flatten out the
sociological and political landscape,
you make men and women more different.
Who is hoping for that?
No one was hoping for that.
So as,
as the science stacks up the legislative
and political attempts to silence it and
to mount an ideological counterattack,
multiply
what do we need more,
more general science because the
differences are accelerating.
So now we need even more,
more of the same.
But I would like to jump into the,
um,
uh,
to the book and see what I'm.
Because I read your book or I didn't
really read it,
I actually listened to it,
which was I can really recommend to
people because you,
you did a fantastic job of reading the
book by yourself.
And so
I was looking at the reviews on audible
and there's a performance review and a
content review.
Performance Review is higher than the
content review and I don't know what to
think about that.
I don't know whether I should be happy
about that.
Are Not happy about that.
It's not much difference,
but I thought it was comical.
I think you should stop writing and you
should just be a narrator of books.
I think that's the takeaway.
Well,
I'm going to do an audio book version of
maps of meaning.
Yes.
That's great.
Yes,
that's coming that be like 25 hours long
or something like that.
Probably more so.
That's the first book I read,
uh,
as an,
as an audiobook was better angels of our
nature by Steven Pinker,
like 50 hours or something.
So it was a 25 hours.
It's not so bad.
Abi Bout too because it's a long book.
I'm probably,
I'm probably the amount of time we'll
see
in your book.
I think the first room stand up straight
with your shoulders back.
I think that's a really.
When you read the chapter,
it's a really good chapter.
But I,
uh,
as last time when I spoke to speak to
you,
I went into the Jordan Peterson found
groups in Sweden and uh,
I've,
I asked them what,
what do you think I should ask you?
And then they,
one of the guys was,
he said,
I really liked the book,
but when it says stand up straight with
your children's back,
I think you should explain more how to
do it.
And then a lot of the helpful other guys
in the threads started giving him
physical exercises,
how to strengthen the muscles between
the shoulders,
how your shoulders back.
It was like a long thread on how to,
how to build your chest up.
Like,
and then in the end,
like after 20 or 30 comments like
somebody suggested that maybe,
maybe you didn't mean it.
Literally.
He also meant it figuratively.
So,
but it was no,
no,
no meanness or anything.
But then it wasn't that,
it wasn't a physical advice.
It was mostly sort of a psychological
advice,
a good place where the metaphorical and
the literal meet.
Actually the important part of that
chapter,
I think a part is that I was really
trying to make a case and this is a case
that needs to be made over and over and
over until people understand it.
Uh,
there's a book I would recommend that
was recently written called the great
leveler,
like Walter Shy Dale.
And it's the study of inequality.
And it's a brutal book because one of
the things she does is he calculates
inequality coefficients,
like the Gini Coefficient,
which is a measure of inequality,
economic inequality,
and he looks over the empirical data to
see if there's any relationship between
the the left or the right wing nature of
a government and the inequality in the
society.
And so what you'd hope because
inequality is actually a genuine
problem.
You'd hope that left wing governments
were better at regulating inequality
than right wing governments.
You'd hope that there's no evidence for
that whatsoever.
So I'm making a case in chapter one that
hierarchies exist and because
hierarchies exist,
inequality exists,
or at least the two things are are
indistinguishable at many levels,
but that you can't blame the existence
of hierarchy or inequality on something
proximal like capitalism or Western
society.
Inequality is the rule all the way back
down to crustaceans.
And so when the Marxists complained
about inequality and how intractable it
is,
while they have a point,
but when they blame it on capitalism,
they're not taking the problem
seriously.
It's way worse than the Marxist.
Think
inequality is genuinely a problem.
Now,
but it's a problem in,
in a bunch of ways.
The first is,
is that
those at the top tend to get more and
those at the bottom tend to end up with
zero and zero's really not good.
Now you might say,
well,
in the capitalist society,
in modern industrial capitalist society,
people tend not to end up at zero so
much and that seems to be true.
It is definitely the case.
And,
and I think pinker has done a good job
of outlining this,
uh,
that people that human progress.org are
doing a good job of the two.
It's definitely the case that our modern
societies are making the poor,
much less absolutely poor.
So we've,
we've decreased poverty worldwide
between 2000 and 2012 by 50 percent a
massive accomplishment.
We should be partying in the streets
about it.
It's an amazing accomplishment,
but inequality is still a problem.
So,
so that chapter's about how deep the
problem is.
Now,
the suggestion is is that to compete in
a world where there's unequal outcome,
your best bet is to take the full
tragedy of being full frontal,
essentially,
right?
To open yourself up to the catastrophe
of existence and to move forward with
courage and and and with nobility and
with with truth on your tongue.
That's your best bet and I do believe
that.
Now I can give you an example of that.
We did research on a program called the
future authoring program,
and it's a part of the suite that's
offered at self authoring dog come and
we did the research.
The idea was to produce psychological
interventions that were very cost
effective that could be distributed to
many people,
but we wanted to test them because you
never know if you're an idiot.
Intervention is going to do something
good or something bad.
That's like rule number one for a
serious social scientists.
Assume your idiot intervention will
either be useless or harmful because
those are the most likely outcomes.
Right?
And any social scientist who's truly
credible understands that those who
don't are not educated properly.
So anyways,
we tested the future authoring program
and we mostly tested it in Holland and
we did some stratification by group,
so in Holland,
this was at the Rotterdam School of,
at at the Rotterdam School of management
at Erasmus University.
We had thousands of university students
do the future authoring program where
they laid out a plan for their life and
they tried to optimize their lives
along.
They want to consider their friendships,
intimate relationships,
career choices,
educational choices,
mental and physical health,
use of drugs and alcohol and use of time
productively outside of work to optimize
across all those levels and then to
avoid catastrophic pitfalls.
So you write about what your life could
be like if you could have what you
needed in three to five years and then
what,
right about what your life could be like
if everything fell apart on you and and
things went bad.
All right,
so they all did this exercise.
Now,
before the exercise,
the Dutch women were outperforming the
Dutchman,
let's say the Caucasians and the Non
Western ethnic minority women were doing
worse than the Dutchman and the non
western ethic minority men were doing
worse,
the worst of all,
four groups,
about an 85 percent performance
detriment compared to the Dutch women
two years after the intervention.
They were doing better than the Dutch
women,
right?
Man,
it blew us away.
We couldn't believe.
And that's research published with
mckayla shipper and and,
and,
and some other colleagues that from
Holland.
And what was so interesting about that
was that a psychological intervention
seemed to remove the barriers that were
produced by what was hypothetically
associate logical barrier.
It might be that if you're an immigrant
to a country that you don't have your
story straight because it's so
complicated.
Yeah.
So you need a better plan.
So.
And that's part of standing up.
It's like,
okay man,
make a plan for the future,
plan a good future and move forward
towards it.
And also one thing that I took away
from,
from the chapters and take yourself
seriously.
Otherwise no one else will.
If you don't stand up for yourself,
you will get pushed down and pushed over
and not be taking notice.
Yeah,
well,
I think the way you take yourself
seriously as you start to constrain
yourself as a player in the catastrophe
of the world.
Now the world,
and this is a motif route.
12 rules for life in many ways is a very
dark book.
Although it has a very optimistic
central message.
The darkness is life is tragic and
tainted by malevolence,
but the optimism is there's a hell of a
lot more to you than you think and I
think that's a message that's really
good for people because everyone knows
that life is a catastrophe that's
tainted by malevolence.
Everyone knows that even if people don't
want to admit it at the bottom of their
heart,
they know it and I think they also
suspect that there's more to them than
meets the eye.
So and so.
So the,
the,
the trick to taking yourself seriously
is to understand that your errors count.
They make things worse.
Like it really is the case that it
matters whether you get your act
together at least because if you're
fragmented and disillusioned and
resentful and angry and working to make
things worse,
you really can make them worse.
The school shooters are a good example
of that.
People who become so nihilistic and
desperate and then angry that no,
they,
they slaughter the innocent in,
in a,
in a fit events fullness.
Like that's sort of the bottom end of,
of the descent for human beings.
It's really terrible
because you,
you,
um,
you deal a lot with Christianity and
Christian thought with both,
with mostly with the old testament but
also with new testament in the Christian
motifs.
But you get the sense from your book,
from your,
your teaching when you talk about this,
that
we can really create for ourselves in
this world when we have no problem with
creating a variety of health for
ourselves and for others.
So that's within our,
our,
in our grasp.
That's exactly right.
Is that hell is definitely within our
grasp.
And uh,
and I think with our engineering we can
invent many kinds of health.
But I would also,
do you think there's a,
do we have the capacity to create
paradise on earth?
You think that within our grasp,
I think that that's what we struggle
upwards toward.
You know,
I was thinking recently about this image
came to mind of St Joseph's oratorial in
Montreal,
which is a huge religious building.
Um,
it's one of the biggest cathedral.
I don't think it's a cathedral because I
think it's an oratorial,
although I don't know technically the
difference.
Um,
but it's one of the biggest religious
edifice is in the world and it was built
in the latter half of the 20th century,
which is quite interesting because most
buildings have religious significance
work built that late.
But anyways,
it's up on Mount Royal,
so it's up on the hill.
And so it's the city on the hill,
right?
It's the universal city on the hill.
It's an image of perfection.
It's a lot.
It's like stonework lit,
like the interior of a forest devoted
towards the glory of being in God.
So it's an image of,
of,
of paradise we could say.
And then it's at the top of the hill and
you climb up to it as a consequence of a
very large staircase set into the hill
and pilgrims went there quite regularly
in the 20th century who were often
physically disabled and so they would
struggle up the hill on their crutches
or or or,
or with their,
with their,
with their damaged limbs and with their
illnesses.
And so they would struggle up the hill
towards the heavenly city essentially.
And that's what we're to do.
That's correct.
That it's a drama that people were
acting out.
Now,
St Joseph's also happens to be full of
crutches that people left there for.
Which is quite interesting to see.
But,
but that doesn't,
that doesn't matter in some sense.
So much as the symbolic meaning is all
these damaged people who were carrying a
terrible load,
like they weren't just subject to the
normative tragedy of being.
They were also physically disabled would
go there and struggle up these hundreds
of stairs as they were trying to send
instead of descending.
And it's like,
well,
we can certainly believe in hell if we
have any sense.
If you don't believe that human beings
can create hell,
then you're a child,
you're a naive child,
you know nothing,
you know nothing about history or
yourself and you say,
well,
can we,
can we bring paradise into being?
Well,
no,
but maybe we can at least walk up the
hill away from hell and who knows what
we could do if we took it seriously,
if we took our,
the idea that we needed to shoulder our
burden and with truth,
if we took that seriously,
as serious as the hell should make you
take it.
Who knows what we could accomplish?
You know,
as I said,
we've lifted,
you've reduced the poverty rate in the
world by 50 percent from the year 2000
to the year,
2012 and something like 300,000 people
are being attached to the power grid.
Now worldwide.
I don't remember if it's a week or a
day,
but it's either of those metrics is
still pretty good.
Fastest growing economies are in Africa.
Like,
you know,
we,
we've made amazing strides in the last
50 years and they seem to be
accelerating and so I don't know what
the upper limit for us is if we don't
dissolve ourselves into idiot identity
politics and,
and,
and start a civil war.
No.
So
I think one of the reasons why very,
I certainly do.
I think people in general do as well.
I'm a very easy time imagining horrible,
horrible things and daydreaming about
horrible things,
horrible things that could happen to you
or things that you could do and uh,
and,
but it's very hard to imagine a heaven.
For example,
look at Dante.
Oh,
inferno.
It's a,
I think he wrote about heaven as well.
I'm not
a really boring book.
Angels,
angels in white singing and stuff like
that.
Then it's,
it doesn't sound like heaven to me.
It's a but hell sounds like hell
right.
Interesting.
Because,
you know,
um,
I would say mainstream Christians,
especially on the Protestant and have
tried to force hell out of the human
imagination over the last hundred years,
maybe as a way of making Christianity
more marketable.
Although I don't think it's worked,
but I do think that belief in hell,
metaphorically,
let's say,
although I tell you if you're in one of
those situations,
it feels eternal,
so that's something to keep in mind too,
but I think it's unbelievably salutary
because even though we can't imagine
heaven so clearly,
we can certainly say,
well,
at least it's not Auschwitz.
Right.
Totally agree on that.
Whatever it is,
it's as far away from Auschwitz as you
can get
and that's.
That's a direction you know,
it's,
it's not as specific as you might like
it to be,
but that's also why I've been suggesting
to people that they think about this
locally.
It's like,
okay,
we're not so sure what the utopia might
be and we know that collectively,
presuming a utopia also seems to be a
dangerous thing,
but there are stupid things that you're
doing to make your life and the life of
people around you more wretched and
miserable than necessary,
and it's hypothetically the case that
you could stop doing some of them,
so there is a good place to start.
It's nice and humble.
It's like you're less than you could be
and you know it,
and there's things you could do about
that and you know it.
So,
so maybe maybe it would be okay to take
a step in the right direction,
think you say in the book,
and you open the return to the,
uh,
the,
the basic truth,
and you say that you arrive at this when
you contemplate the horribleness of the
20th century with Auschwitz and the
Gulag and the life there is,
life is suffering and you can't,
you can produce the way the pain of
existence.
And uh,
there is no totalitarian that can reduce
the way that
you can just forbid it in Venezuela.
Now it's illegal to last list the cause
of the death of a child as starvation in
the hospitals.
That's convenient.
Oh yes.
Isn't that something?
So there we go.
Now we've got the utopia.
It's now illegal to die of starvation in
the hospital in Venezuela,
or at least to have it listed.
And that's exactly it,
man.
There is a little slice of hell for you.
One of the.
It's easier to move away from,
it's not easy,
but it's,
it's easier to stop doing,
causing harm and causing suffering.
Then too,
uh,
Ryan at bliss,
that's sort of a basic way.
We are very bad at a pretty bad,
uh,
having eternal bliss in this life.
Well,
yeah,
it's not easy to conceptualize what it
would be.
I mean,
you do,
you do taste it at times,
you know,
you tasted with music.
And of course that's why there's imagery
of angels and,
and the heavenly hosts singing,
you know,
because people do get a taste of what
paradise might be like when they
listened to music,
which is why music is so powerful for
people because it speaks of a kind of
transcendent harmony of the,
of the layers of being.
And it engages a person in that.
And you get that as well when you're
engaged in what you're doing,
deeply engaged in what you're doing and
finding meaningful but mean stepping
rapidly away from hell might be a form
of bliss.
You know,
to know that a minimum,
you're not contributing to the terrible
suffering of the world and maybe you're
doing something to to lift the,
to lift the burden in a positive way.
I mean,
it's really complicated because you
don't want everything to be easy.
That's not a good idea for utopia.
Everything's blissful,
uneasy,
and all you're doing is laying back and
eating peeled grapes.
You know it's.
There's nothing to that that would last
more than a week.
You need and need an adventure and you
need a struggle,
but perhaps we could have the adventure
and the struggle without the pointless
suffering and malevolence.
We could at least aim at that and then
who knows what we might transmute that
into at least we might be able to
transmute it into lives that are
meaningful despite their suffering.
That would be a good start and I do
believe that that's a.
I believe that that's an attainable
reality.
I believe that that we are strong enough
as in our essence to rise above the
tragedy of existence and to live
normally and with purpose and honorably.
I believe we can do that,
and so that's why I think 12 rules for
life is a fundamentally optimistic book
because I also think that that's a
believable message.
No one's going to say,
well,
we believe that.
Well,
we're going to eradicate suffering and
malevolence.
It's like,
no,
I don't think so,
but we can constrain it within the
confines of our own being.
And that's good enough.
That's a good start.
Rule number eight,
you say,
tell the truth.
You should tell the truth and you're
right,
that it is our responsibility is to see
what it is before our eyes courageously
and to learn from it,
even if it seems horrible,
even if the horror of seeing them,
which is our consciousness and half for
instance.
Uh,
and then I just thought about that for
awhile.
And,
uh,
during the,
when Isis invaded Iraq in 2007,
14,
I think it was 2015,
2014.
And,
uh,
I was one of the few who wrote about
following that right then because nobody
thought it would take over such a large
part of Iraq.
And then I was watching loads of videos
of mass killings and the capitations and
murders,
and I was seeing,
I had contact with eyewitnesses via a
journalists whose names Newark Newer
Keno,
and it was horrible,
really,
really horrible,
horrible,
the most horrible thing I've ever seen.
And because I had contact with neuro
Akina,
whose father had had family members down
there,
Assyrian Christians who are being
murdered and driven from their homes.
And this was even before the same jar
where they took this sex slaves and they
murdered the whole people use the CDC
app.
So it was really horrible.
And so for them,
I mean,
of course that's the big deal.
Uh,
but I,
I felt I had the responsibility to see
this for myself,
get not just listening to journalists
who hadn't seen it because I was writing
about it a lot myself and I could feel
it changing me because this is the
absolute as close to absolute darkness
as I've ever come come.
Because it was,
it was,
it was not historical.
These for people,
uh,
some younger than me,
some older.
But it was happening as I was watching
it.
Uh,
and then I thought about the quote by
nature,
if you gaze into their business,
their business also gazes into you.
And I really felt that
I was thinking about this when I read
your book for the.
I would ask you that.
How can you be certain that you can
defeat the,
the darkness that when you face that,
I mean it's a.
I don't think that you can be certain
that you can say,
well,
if you go to face the dragon to get the
gold,
it wouldn't be a dragon if it could meet
you.
The issue isn't that the issue isn't
that you're certain of success.
The issue is that you don't have a
better pathway.
And so if you're going to confront the
dragon of chaos,
say and dare to attain the goal,
then you have to put yourself on the
line for it.
But paradoxically it seems the more
you're willing to put yourself on the
line for it,
the higher the probability of your
success.
Which is also the part of opening
yourself up to the catastrophe.
Knowing.
That's why Christianity has increasingly
occupied the theater of in my
imagination,
because there's this idea that you know,
even speaking psychologically that
whatever Christ represents,
whatever that image is,
it is in part the call to accept the
catastrophe of existence,
to accept it voluntarily because the
fundamental story is that Christ went to
his torturous betrayal with his eyes
open,
right and well,
that's a hell of a thing.
It's no wonder that image has never left
people's imagination because that's the
reason you can't ask any more of someone
than that
and you might say,
well,
is it okay that everything will be asked
of us?
And the answer is it doesn't matter
because everything is going to be asked
of you like you're going to die.
You're going to have to accept that in
one,
in one form or another.
The question is how well the answer is
what?
You have to open your arms.
You have to accept it.
You know when there's an idea in the new
testament that if you can,
if you can love fate deeply enough,
you can transfer,
you can transcend your limitations of
your mortality.
It's something like that and you know,
that's,
that strikes me as a plausible
possibility.
Now you said when you were watching all
those things that,
that changed you.
You mean what did,
what did it change?
You realize
what's your facing something real
if evil has,
has meaning,
if there is evil that is evil,
and what if that was sort of then you
have a terrorist attack in Sweden and in
your,
you started sort of thing.
What would I,
what would I do if I were in that
situation?
And you speak to people who have,
who have relatives there and you realize
that,
uh,
you're very lucky but you living in
Sweden and not there because I,
I,
I think
would not be very hard to take up arms
against these people.
That's the thing is that you realize
things about yourself if you,
if it gets to that device.
Well,
you know,
the terrible thing too is,
and this is a Motif,
again that also runs through 12 rules
for life,
is that,
well,
let's say when the,
when the.
I'll give you a personal example.
So when I heard about what happened in
Cologne on the new,
on New Year's eve and I see I had a
situation where my son was mugged a
number of years ago and he was mugged by
a gang of,
of kids that were brought into our
neighborhood as a favor to them so that
they can play basketball in a local boys
and girls club.
And there was about six or seven of
them,
18 years old and they mugged my 13 year
old son and took his,
his,
um,
I think they took his cell phone and he
came home and he was shaken up mostly
with anger because he couldn't believe
that six,
18 year old young men could be so
cowardly that they would gang up on a 13
year old kid.
Like.
So for him it was a betrayal of humanity
apart from being afraid.
But mostly it was anger on his part and
I was absolutely outraged.
So I contacted the police and I
contacted the nearby club that had
sponsored two kids and I said,
look,
this is what happened.
And they did nothing about it.
The club knew who it was and wouldn't
release the names because of
confidentiality and all sorts of other
nonsense and I had this fantasy that
went on for weeks about standing outside
the boys and girls club and waiting for
those kids with a lead pipe because I
was not happy,
but you know,
I was and I couldn't pursue it with any
degree of legal.
I couldn't pursue it to the degree that
I wanted to in the legal framework
because at the same time my daughter was
very ill and that was taking precedence.
But you know,
I had these terrible fantasies come up
over and over the very,
very dark fantasies and I talked it over
with my son because I told him what was
happening in my imagination because I
want it to let them know that this
really bothered me.
That he was attacked and that I wasn't
going to put up with it.
But I also understood that that's not.
See.
I would have been.
I think I would have been a very weak
man to not have had those feelings.
And then you think,
well,
lots of times it's the better man that
takes up arms,
but it isn't necessarily the best man
who takes up arms because maybe there's
a place past that you might say,
well,
it's naive it and cowardice that stops
you from defending yourself,
you know,
and then you transcend naivety and
cowardice and then you become dangerous.
But maybe you can transcend dangerous.
Maybe there's a place past that.
And well,
let's hope there is.
I'm not sure if it's in the book,
but the,
you said it before,
you have to develop some teeth
because you can,
you shouldn't mistake a weakness for
virtue.
Right?
And,
but in Christianity,
and one,
one thing that I struggled with,
Christianity is the meek shall inherit.
Yeah.
But you know,
I read,
I learned it.
The other world of Christianity that I
find very.
I'm not sure if it's a temperamental.
No,
it's a mis translation.
I looked that up.
That's a line that always bothered me.
And I,
when I did these biblical lectures last
year,
which I'm going to continue by the way,
as soon as I can possibly manage it.
Um,
I looked up that line,
there's a couple of lines that really,
really,
I couldn't forget them.
I'm the poor,
will always be with us.
That was one,
um,
to those who have everything more shall
be given from those who have everything
from those who have nothing.
Everything will be taken away.
That's a rough one.
And then the meek shall inherit the
earth.
But meek is the wrong word.
Has slipped over time.
It doesn't what it meant.
If you go back into the original,
if you go back the original texts,
let's say here's a better translation,
um,
those who have swords and know how to
use them,
but keep the machines will inherit the
world
right
on the cheek in
Christianity.
Yeah.
Well that goes along with that.
Resist not evil,
but look,
look,
I can tell you some things I've learned
about that too.
So I'll give you two examples.
So,
you know,
there's been a lot of points for me in
the last 18 months where things could
have gone badly wrong.
So for example,
I went to mcmaster university about a
year ago or thereabouts and there was a
big demonstration and it was quite
obnoxious.
I mean there was about 200 people there
that were just see me,
came to see me in about 50 protesters
likely and they drowned me out
completely.
And,
and,
and there was a handful of them who were
really,
I would say really not good people,
like most of them were just foolish kids
and foolish self righteous kids who were
diluted by the radiant professors and by
their own resentment.
But there were four or five people there
who would have been perfectly happy in
that crowd that you described that
descended into Iraq.
And I can tell who they were by looking
at them.
They,
you know,
they were people that,
that just,
they just,
I
perhaps I'm wrong.
But I,
I,
I believe that I could see what they
were.
And there were two of them behind me,
woman and a man.
The woman wasn't quite so bad,
but the man was pretty bad and they were
blaring air horns at me,
an air horn apnea and close enough to
damage my hearing,
which I was not the least bit impressed
about.
And I told them,
I said,
look,
you can blow your Damn Air Horn,
but if you get it too close to me.
Well I went and I went and had a word
with the police at that point,
but you know,
so,
so it was quite,
it was quite provoking and,
and,
and pushy,
but I just,
I knew that most of it was foolishness
and
I mostly watched and I tried to give my
talk and it was completely drowned out
and then we had to leave and I gave the
rest of my talk outside.
But you know,
all of that was filmed and then it was
put up on youtube and all of the
consequences of that holding my temper,
all of the consequences of that was
positive.
And that's one thing I've really learned
and it is associated with this idea of
resist not evil and also of turning the
other cheek.
It's,
it's not like you can't respond,
it's that you don't.
And then without Kathy Newman interview,
you know,
it's the same thing.
It's a good really good example of that
is that
no one,
maybe I managed it because I have had
quite a bit of experience now dealing
with hostile people and hostile press
let's say,
but I,
I was able fortunately to stay detached
and,
and with,
with maybe with even with a bit of a
sense of humor during the interview and
not take it personally and not get
offended by it.
Even though what was happening was
deeply wrong.
There was an element of being able to be
detached about it and that worked,
you know,
like I didn't really fight with her.
I didn't allow her to
set the linguistic agenda,
let's say,
but I didn't defend myself anymore than
was absolutely necessary.
You know,
it's minimal necessary for something
like that and that was overwhelmingly,
it was overwhelmingly well received.
When
you,
you're in a public situation,
it's sort of a,
it's a different.
It's different when you meet someone in
streets,
if you're one on one stuff to you or if
you're at a dinner in a personal setting
or something,
but when you're in a public setting it's
basically a,
your receiving so you can,
you can be detached because it's not
really the whole you,
is there an Avatar of yourself,
a speaker or a role you inhabit so you
can have it,
you can have patients,
not you,
you,
but,
but I mean as a person you don't have to
take it.
So personally I think people make that
mistake.
Yeah.
Well that's,
that's the thing too is like,
it's not easy to know when you should
take something personally and when you
shouldn't.
Like I didn't give you a good example of
that too from politics like years ago.
Who was running for.
I think it was Mondale.
I think so,
I might have this wrong,
but he was um,
he was governor of Massachusetts now.
Who was that?
Who?
Who ran for governor of Massachusetts.
Oh.
Anyways,
I wasn't Monday,
I don't believe,
but it doesn't matter.
He,
he was governor of Massachusetts and he
had released a,
a prisoner or or his or his prison
system and released to prisoner who
immediately raped someone and he was
being raked over the coals on a TV show
about,
about the fact that this has happened.
I think the rapist name was Willie
Horton,
if I remember correctly.
Dukakis was.
It was Dukakis when Dukakis was running
for president and a journalist asked
him,
well,
how would you feel if,
um,
Willie Horton had raped your wife or
your daughter and your CAC is gave a
very,
I would say placid answer,
and it,
it was one of the things that insured,
he was not going to be elected president
president.
And what he should have said was my
imagination would immediately go to the
darkest possible place,
but because I'm a civilized person and
understand that that pathway leads to
nothing but may have,
I'd be willing to let the legal system
take that moral obligation from my
shoulders because otherwise everything
gets worse.
That's the right response.
The first response is mess with my
family at your peril.
And the second response is,
yeah,
but I don't get to start a feud.
I don't get to destabilize the entire
society in my pursuit of what you might
regard as justifiable revenge.
Right?
And so that's part of that idea of
having a sword,
but keeping it,
she's right and it is the opposite of,
of,
and I talk about that in rule 11,
don't bother their children were going
to skateboarding,
which is in part a a,
I suppose a bit of a diatribe against
the idea that the way that you make men
good is by making them weak.
It's a really uninformed and and naive,
uninformed and malicious idea.
All of those things.
At the same time,
you make men good by making them
unbelievably strong and dangerous and
then asking them politely to hold
themselves in a band at all times
dangerous.
It's just
being strong.
Something.
If you are strong,
then you have the capacity to be
dangerous,
right?
Something separate from being strong.
So
people have misinterpreted sometimes
when they heard you that they think
you're calling for sort of the British,
a hyper masculine men.
But that's not what I heard you say,
I heard you say,
is that if you have somebody who's
confident and strong in your convictions
and you speak the truth and you're not
afraid to,
uh,
to protest when something is wrong and
stand up for yourself and stand up for
people a week and then a protection,
then you're strong and then you can be
dangerous.
Uh,
but yes.
So,
uh,
have you starting a testosterone or
something?
I'm not sure.
Right?
Well,
of course,
that's exactly for people who are afraid
of who,
for people who are afraid of or hate
competence,
like to confuse it with tyranny.
And you know,
the mean Joe Rogan is kind of an
interesting example in that regard
because,
and so is this guy named Jocko willink
who's got an increasingly popular
podcast and willing because he's a very
tough guy,
you know,
he's very physically intimidating and I
would say psychologically intimidated
comic book character looks and what he
has done in real life.
Exactly,
exactly.
Well,
there's also that.
That's exactly right.
He's articulate and all of those things
and you know,
and he told me quite clearly that he
could have easily been like a hyper
delinquent when he was a kid,
but decided that he was,
because he's,
you know,
he's,
he's an aggressive guy and he decided he
was going to be a good person instead
and you can't be a good person without
the capacity for malevolence
interestingly enough.
And you know,
maybe that's one of the reasons if you
think about it metaphysically,
let's say.
I mean,
one question is always be,
well,
why?
Why is there evil in the world?
And I mean this is only a partial
answer,
but it's possible that you cannot fully
develop your capacity for good without
also developing your capacity for evil
because you have to be able to do things
even if you will do them.
I mean,
even if it's a matter of learning how to
withstand temptation and until you're in
a position where that temptation is
real,
you're not withstanding anything.
So you know,
if you're not sleeping with 100 women a
year because they're not lining up to
sleep with you,
that doesn't make you moral.
It just makes you undesirable.
Yeah.
I also think this is perhaps one of the
reasons that the bad guys or so
or so
people want to be the bad guy and the
band guys.
Interesting in movies and
TV series and also this is part of the
is actually a part of Christianity which
I think is very interesting,
is that the protocol sheet returning to
the herb and the protocol and and you,
you find that in
the most awful criminal who's starting
to have doubts then that's an,
that's a great one of the best
characters in movies.
I mean the,
the awful villain who's having second
thoughts and then in the end turns out
to have a heart of gold.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
But if you,
if you are the lamb that's much more,
that's a boring movie.
Like,
like the lamb who's,
who's never done anything wrong.
You can't because you can't.
Yeah.
Well there's an.
There's an interesting scene in
revelation in revelation,
which is a very strange book.
It's like a hallucinogenic.
It's like a hallucinogenic trip.
In fact,
I think it probably is a hallucinogenic
trip.
That's my suspicions.
So Christ comes back with a sword in his
mouth and he judges humanity and so he's
very merciful in the gospels,
but in revelation,
he's the ultimate judge.
And the reason for that is that any
ideal is a judge,
right?
If you hold something up as an ideal,
then you are reflected poorly in the
mirror of that ideal.
So it's instantly a judge and there are
far more damage than saved in,
in,
in the revelation story.
But Christ tells people when he judges
them,
um,
I'm,
I'm paraphrasing,
but,
but the meaning is,
is,
is appropriate.
Um,
if you're hot,
that's okay.
That's commendable.
If you're cold,
that's okay.
But if you're lukewarm then I'll vomit
you out of my mouth.
That's the line.
And that's so interesting because it,
it's,
again,
it's an echo of what you just described,
is there,
there is no virtue in,
in non commitment,
right?
There is no virtue in week harmlessness
in fact it.
And you see that too.
I mean when,
when,
when Hannah wrote,
wrote her,
her book on Eichmann in Jerusalem,
it's Eichmann in Jerusalem,
I believe the banality of evil.
She talked about Eichmann and Eichmann
was one of these characters who was a
lamb,
right?
He,
he,
he was,
he wasn't,
you're spectacular cartoon book villain.
He was the harmless kind of soft guy
next door who sort of went along to get
along and he happened to be in a
hierarchy where the goal was to
eradicate the Jews.
But who is he to question the hierarchy?
No one.
So she titled Her Book The banality of
evil.
And I always thought she had the titled
Backwards.
It should have been the evil of
banality.
I haven't thought of that.
Yeah,
that's a deep thought.
I've read a couple of Christian
critique.
So your,
your,
uh,
your thoughts and your,
your book and one of the,
uh,
one of the critiques was that you,
you think that because people have
within their grasp to do good and evil
by themselves,
uh,
your committing to a Christian heresy
called pelagianism.
Yeah.
See,
I don't really believe that.
I don't really believe that,
but it's very difficult
because eastern orthodoxy then you can
only do good because of our sinful
nature.
You can only do good by the grace of
God.
So we are,
if we have,
if we are not sinful in our nature,
if we deny that,
then we are basically,
uh,
having,
committing vanity because we think we
are so struck by that,
that that's a claim that I've seen being
thrown
a critique that I was a thought that I
would like to hear you respond to them
because
yeah,
it's an unbelievably deep problem.
So the first thing I would say,
you can only speak metaphorically about
such things in some sense.
So I would say the Christian claim is
that Christ's sacrifice redeemed us.
And so I would say that's true,
but we still have to do the work.
You might say,
well,
how can both of those things be the case
simultaneously?
And the answer is,
well,
it depends on your view of time.
So and I can't explain it any deeper
than that,
so I'm not going to because it would
take forever.
But I would also say I do believe that
you should step forward to do good.
Humbly.
I do believe that if you're going to
step forward to do good,
that you should do it well guided by
the,
by the divine images.
I do believe that you're likely to err
in your judgment of what's good,
which is why I entitled the chapter,
don't tell the truth or at least don't
lie.
It isn't obvious to me that you can
discern the truth,
but it is obvious to me that sometimes
you know when you're lying and you could
stop doing that.
And so I think that those critiques are
now,
but then I would also invert the
criticism and I would say that part of
the danger of modern western
Christianity in particular.
I don't think this is quite the same
with the Orthodox Christian types is
that by assuming that everything good is
done by the grace of God,
you reduce the burden of the imitation
of Christ.
The question is,
what does it mean to believe in Christ?
Let's say,
and one answer to that would be to say,
I regard this statement that Christ's
crucifixion redeemed me.
I regard that statement as true.
Say I'm a Christian.
Okay,
well that's one definition.
Here's another definition.
Pick up your cross and walk up the
Goddamn hill and that's the proper
definition as far as I'm concerned.
And so and this is a nichey and critic
criticism of,
of institutionalized Christianity,
which is that it lifts,
it made moral board burden to light
because the burden is supposed to be
confront evil constraint in your own
heart except the tragedy of being pick
up the load of mortality and walk up
hill.
It's like,
God,
that's rough man.
So and then young wrote about that,
you know,
because he was interested in the
Nietzschean critique and he said,
look,
you got to understand that you can be
cynical about the Catholics and their
idea that you've been redeemed by an
external source.
Say it's not that it's not precisely
that clear will parody a bit for the
sake of argument and maybe you can also
be.
I'm cynical about the idea that you can
go in and confess and receive absolution
and walk out sin free,
but you have to understand is the church
is somewhat merciful and its endeavors
because it's trying to also free people
from the intolerable consciousness of
their own insufficiency.
You know,
cause I couldn't say to you,
well,
you need to bear the weight of all your
transgressions.
It's like Jesus really with no mercy.
That's how we're going to play this.
Who could tolerate that?
And the Catholics at least say,
well look,
you're fallible.
You're going to make all sorts of
mistakes.
It's going to happen over and over.
At least can go in and have the burden
lifted from time to time.
You're supposed to play it straight.
You're supposed to go in and actually
confess and repent and try to do better
in the future,
but at least you don't have to drag your
catastrophic cell past self along with
you every step of the way.
So anyways,
I'm not trying to elevate human beings
to the status of demi gods,
you know,
but I guess I am suggesting that we can
at least participate in that to the
degree that we're willing to hoist our
own burdens.
And I do think we should do that with
humility and without thinking that we
can see the way forward.
So clearly.
I do think we can walk away from
Auschwitz though.
Yeah,
I think so too.
I know.
No,
this was,
uh,
this has been a recurring question for
you.
I'm not sure if I asked you the last
time really
it's about truth and how you return to
the Christianity.
Some parts of Christianity.
This has been true.
You said like the truth of the
individual,
I think you said,
and how.
My question is how can,
how can be true and,
and um,
four for cs Lewis when he,
when he started like accepted that
Christianity was true for him,
it was like a mixture.
He was a talked into it by talking and I
don't remember that guy's name with one
other friend and he said the combination
of a myth or a dying God,
he always loved the dying like diagnosis
and um,
but,
but in Christ it company combining the
dying God wrote with an actual
historical figure.
He actually set that this is a,
it's not just a myth.
It's true.
It's true because it's also historical.
And then he said that,
and then you distinguished.
If you,
if you watch from the outside and
analyze it,
well of course you can see that it's,
it's just so you can see similarities as
a scientist,
but from the inside because if the
truth.
And so that was his,
his view of it.
Here's,
here's the strange possibility.
One of the things that's happened to me
as I've delved farther and farther into
religious stories is that I've found
continually that their depth is
inexhaustible.
And at some point it becomes less
impossible that they're true,
then it is impossible that they're not
true.
Something like that now,
okay,
now I'm not.
So there are,
there are,
there are truths in genesis that are
unfathomably deep now and I've outlined
them to the best of my ability in the
biblical series that I did.
Now I don't know how to reconcile those
truths with,
with,
with the scientific view of the world
that the view,
the fact that the universe is 14 billion
years old and that we've crawled our way
up from the sludge and the mod.
I don't know how those things coexist
precisely.
I know that there are truths that guide
behavior and there are truths that
describe the material world,
but I certainly don't think that the
truth that we have that described the
material world,
our final truths,
because I don't think our material is
few point is accurate.
It's accurate for some purposes
obviously.
Um,
and I am a practicing scientist and,
and,
and uninformed one,
I would say,
um,
I don't believe that people act as if
they confronted material reality.
I believe that people act as if they
confront and infinite realm of
possibility,
one pole of which is having and the
other pole of which is held and I
believe that we treat each other as if
that's the world that we live in because
we upgrade each other for not upholding
our moral duty and we understand what
that means and we upgrade ourselves for
being less than we could,
and so we confront a world of potential
and we don't have a good model for that
and the mythological descriptions
describe the human being as the eternal
confronter have a world of potential and
there's something about that.
It's accurate.
Now,
with regards to this Christian stories
specifically,
I do think the idea that that eternal
myth was made historically concrete is
one of the things about Christianity
that's unalterably powerful.
I don't know what the limits are,
but let's say that what you're called
upon to do until in life is to open
yourself up to the tragedy of being
completely to.
To accept it,
to welcome it,
even even to love it.
If you can do that,
and that's no easy thing you watched
Iraq being invaded,
there's no easy way of loving.
Now,
there's no easy way of saying yes to
that,
but your job in some sense as a,
as a incarnated finite creature,
is to say yes to the possibilities of
being in every possible way.
The question is,
well,
what's the upper limit to that?
Like what are the transformations that
are possible as a consequence of doing
that?
And the answer to that is we don't know.
The Christian story is in part an
investigation of that is if you're
willing to accept your.
If you're willing to accept the
brutality of the mob,
the betrayal of your friends,
the torture of your existence and your
unjust death.
If you're willing to accept that and
welcome it,
what happens to you?
And the answer is
try it and find out
just the
scenario though.
Well,
you did that in part,
you know,
when you,
when you were,
when you decided to immerse yourself in
what was happening in Iraq,
you know,
you could have looked away.
Yeah.
Four.
I often find that the,
my,
uh,
my role as a journalist or I'm not a
real journalist,
I'm more like an editor.
I'm an editorial right,
that,
but it's sort of a missed between me and
some reality,
so I could,
I can,
I can do it as a
take on my,
my jackets and then I watched the
reality through that Lens.
So it sort of shields me from some,
some of it.
But
yeah.
Well that's the advantage of having a
well developed persona from the union
perspective.
You know,
you put on an image like,
like Clark Kent,
Superman puts on Clark Kent.
That's why superheroes always having a
normative alter ego,
right?
They have to be able to live in the
normal world.
Right?
So you need to have an element of
yourself that can,
that can exist.
Well,
they can act as a mask between you and
the world.
I suppose that's what a persona is.
So,
but I mean to the degree that you're
able to open your eyes,
you know,
neat.
You also said you could determine the
depth of a man's character by observing
how much truth he's willing to tolerate.
Right?
Right.
Which is,
you know,
you think,
well,
how can that be associated with the idea
of the truth will set you free.
It's like,
well,
it might set you free,
but it will take you places you're not
sure you want to go first.
Yeah.
In the movie matrix when neo wakes up
and he's flushed down the drain pipe,
woken up to this awful,
awful world.
And that's reality.
That's the truth of the underworld
and it's an old truth.
Uh,
hopefully the truth is not all the time.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
there's an old.
Well,
the funny thing is that there's an old
Christian idea too,
that when Christ was crucified,
he went and harrowed hell before he rose
to heaven.
It's like there is this idea that you
don't go up without going down.
And I really do believe that's true.
And I think that maybe see,
one of the images in genesis that's
really hard to understand is that when
God throws Adam and Eve out of paradise,
he puts an angel at the gates of
Paradise with with flaming swords to
borrow the way you might think,
well,
why would God bar the way to paradise
with with flaming swords?
And maybe the flaming swords cut all the
dead wood off before you step through
the gate.
And if you're all dead wood,
then there's nothing left of you.
Once the flaming swords are done with
you and to observe what you observe with
the Iraq invasion,
that's a set of flaming swords.
You know,
because what you're watching is what
human beings are like and you happen to
be one.
And to the degree that you're like that,
that's you doing that.
That's a hell of a thing too.
That's a hell of a thing to realize.
You think,
well,
what's the right response to watching
that?
And I would say to stop being an evil
person and now it's no simple thing.
One of the things with these people that
met goes there and during the Icelandic
state,
they're evil,
they're just,
a lot of them are evil.
Of course they are psychopaths and are,
and if you are a psychopath and you
really want to do violence,
that's a great place to be and you can
probably do great there.
But there are also people joining the
error.
Really.
They want to do good.
They just really a really twisted sense
of what's good.
And that's one of the most depressing
things about,
uh,
Islamic state is that some of the people
that go there,
uh,
they do horrible things and then they
regret themselves.
But I mean,
how could you let them back into society
after what they've done?
Yeah.
So,
so it's
the power of ideas is you can,
you can convert people that under others
circumstances would have done,
done good.
The tools so evil and stuff.
Well,
this is partly why I tried in some sense
are allowed,
in some sense,
12 rules and my lectures as well to be
so harsh because imagine that there are
many young men who are looking for an
adventure.
They need an adventure,
right?
and maybe their normative life is
sufficiently soft and undemanding so
that they could recede into a kind of
domestic unconsciousness as an
alternative,
but there's nothing in that except a
prolonged prolonged non-existence,
self contempt and bitterness,
right?
It's not good.
You need to be called to an adventure,
and so I would say,
well look,
this is what etiologies offer young
people is the call to an adventure,
but it's a false adventure.
I would say instead,
look,
you want an adventure is open up your
eyes,
open up your eyes to what the world is
really like,
and then take your place in it as a
productive,
awake,
attentive,
and truthful being and see how far you
can walk up hill.
That's an adventure.
It's the alternative to the call to war,
right?
Because the call to wars and adventure,
William James said a 130 140 years ago,
we need a moral equivalent to war
and,
and it touches on exactly what you're
saying is these,
these kids who are lost,
let's say,
and maybe somewhat bitter and resentful
as a consequence.
They see in Isis a call to adventure.
Well,
you know,
I understand that.
I saw this kid once in Montreal and an
outside shopping mall.
He was about six foot five and he was
dressed up like a punk rocker,
you know,
and he was standing on the corner with
two pink shopping bags in his hand and I
thought,
what a ridiculous figure he cut because
he was all dressed up like a viking.
Right?
He was ready to go out there and have
his damn adventure.
And what he was doing instead was
standing in an outdoor shopping mall
with two pink shopping bags.
It's like,
come up to a kid like that and you say,
hey,
you want to go get into some trouble,
some interesting trouble.
He's gonna like throw those shopping
bags away and come with you instantly.
It's like,
okay,
well you need some interesting trouble.
Well,
what could that be?
here's something.
Get your act together,
discipline yourself,
look at the world,
see if you can find a problem to solve,
grow up.
You know,
when.
What's so interesting.
One of the things that's been so
interesting to me to observe as a
consequence of what I've been talking
about is just how many people are
starving for that message.
You know,
I have after my talks now say I was in
La and about 700 people lined up
afterwards to have a book signed and
they,
all,
the vast majority of them have a story
to tell and so the little exchanges I
have with people are very intense,
you know,
because they want to have a minute to
tell me what's happening and,
or 30 seconds even and they say,
look,
here was 10 things going terribly wrong
with my life and I've been trying to aim
up and say what I have to say it.
Everything's much better.
Thank you very much and I thank God,
good work,
and then the next person comes up and
says the same thing and I've got like
25,000 letters that have said that since
August.
And so,
you know,
there is a way of calling people to an
adventure that perhaps isn't
destructive.
They have enough right in front of them
to have a great adventure if they're,
if they're willing,
let's say,
to try not to lie and to tell the truth
and to aim up hill.
Maybe that adventures right in front of
us.
Maybe that's part of,
maybe that's part of the process of
engendering paradise,
to find the adventure in,
in,
to find the proper divide.
Excuse me,
to,
to find the divine adventure in every
individual life.
That's the,
that's that union of the divine and the
historical and Christianity too,
right?
It's to make the archetype real.
Number six,
set your house in perfect order before
you criticize the world.
I think that also you begin,
you begin with yourself and you start to
be,
be the change,
so to speak.
And that's,
uh,
a way of,
um,
being
bitter against the world,
at least not to begin with.
At least that's right.
It's a start.
You can say to yourself,
look,
everything looks pretty terrible to me.
What the hell?
How can it be this way?
But then you can take the next step and
say,
yeah,
maybe I not everything I could be.
So how about if I try to be everything I
could be?
And then think about it again later and
it's the right.
That's because the alternative to that
is just a catastrophe,
right?
That's the key to dignity,
Can Be dignified.
Even if you're,
you're not the best,
strongest,
most beautiful love.
If you,
if you set yourself in order and you
take yourself seriously,
then you can have dignity and other
people will notice it and you will
notice it.
That's a great place to start from and
to strive for,
and that's one of the most.
One of the best things about your book
really,
that you,
you bring dignity into,
I think,
bring to people's lives with this book.
Go with your lecturers.
One of the takeaways I have from
speaking with people,
because after the last interview I did
and then people read the piece I wrote
and then people,
a lot of people thank me for introducing
you to
and then that's been one of the
recurring themes.
I feel so much a strongly themselves,
so some of them at least.
I think that's a great.
That's a great observation.
I mean,
you know our society's week because we
think about happiness.
Why don't we think about dignity?
Why don't we think about mobility?
Why don't we think about truth and
responsibility or beauty.
All of those things there.
They're much.
They're the values that sustain you
through suffering.
Happiness cannot do that.
Not that happiness is is to be to be
what?
There's no,
there's no utility in contempt for
happiness.
Thank God if it comes,
but dignity mean we can't even.
When is the last time you heard someone
talk about that?
Even part of the public discourse and
it's so crucial.
It's not something you strive for it too
much.
You won't get it.
Do you mean dignity or happiness?
Happiness.
Definitely.
Well,
you might say if you strive for dignity
and truth,
sometimes you'll be rewarded with
happiness.
Right.
That's a grace of God that that
happiness,
that's not something you can conjure up
on your own.
Good luck trying.
So I think I've taken up almost two
hours of your time and we write the
piece,
makes the interview with the book and
also just I was writing this piece and
it was 18,000 characters and I was just
so stressed out and I was telling my
wife,
it's like fighting.
It hydrates,
new heads coming up all the time and she
was just laughing at me like,
oh,
you read too much.
He's invaded your language either.
Well that's a terrible thing with
regards to architectural stories is that
once you hear them,
there's no getting rid of them.
My wife has also read your book,
so we're talking.
We've talked a lot about you.
Well say hello to her for me and maybe
we can bump into each other when I come
to Sweden.
Yeah,
you should really come in the fall.
I would love to meet.
I'll stay in touch with,
with regards to the.
When I'm done with the text and
everything,
great.
Nice talking with you.
Nice talking to you,
kate.
Bye.