Yeah,
that's a hell of a welcome for someone
who's going to talk about the Bible.
So I thought I would get farther than
through genesis by the,
by this point,
but I'm,
I'm not unhappy about the pace either.
I've learned a tremendous amount and so
hopefully what we'll do today is finish
genesis completely.
And then I think I'll try to start up
with exodus in me depending on what
happens next year.
I have a busy travel schedule,
but I would really like to do it.
I really liked the exodus story and I
understand it very well.
A lot of the stories in genesis,
especially after the first few stories
say up to the Tower of Babel,
I had to do a tremendous amount of
learning about,
which is really good,
but I do know the exodus story,
so I'm really looking forward to that.
So.
So let's dive right into it and see how
far we can get today.
So we'll review first.
So Joseph's father is Jacob and Jacob is
the patriarch of Israel essentially that
the father of the 12 tribes.
And,
um,
we,
you might remember that,
uh,
he had a very morally ambivalent pathway
through life and it's one of the things
that I think so interesting about the
stories in the,
in the Old Testament is that these so
called patriarchal figures are very
realistic and it's something that I was
over being struck by that counts in the
new testament that way.
There's lots of things that Christ does
that you'd think would have been edited
out over time and sanitized,
but they're not.
The Old Testament is definitely not a
book that's been sanitized.
And that's,
it's quite interesting that that's the
case.
So you sort of see people with all their
flaws and I've been trying to also
derive some general conclusions about
the moral of the story of the genesis
stories and because these stories are
fundamentally moral and moral as far as
I'm concerned,
has to do with action,
right?
Because moral decisions are the
decisions that you make when you're
structuring action.
When you decide to do one thing or
another,
generally want to do things that are the
best things that you can think of to do.
And hence good,
but sometimes you also want to do things
that are the worst things you can do,
you know,
because you're,
or resentful or bitter.
And so the moral decisions that you make
that govern your actions are really the
most important decisions that you make
in your life.
And it's not that easy to figure out how
to make moral decisions.
We don't have an unerring technology for
that the same way as we do for say,
making decisions about empirical
reality,
which in some ways seem a lot simpler,
um,
partly because we can work collectively
at it partly because we have a rigorous
methodology for deciding what's true and
what's not.
So one of the things that's really
struck me,
like it's an overarching theme,
I would say that emerges out of genesis,
especially after the really ancient
stories say,
especially after the stories of Cain and
Abel and Noah and the Tower of Babel.
When you get to the accounts of the
historically for historically real
people,
one injunction seems to be get the hell
out there and do something.
You know what?
One of the major themes for all of the
Patriarchs that we've talked about,
Abraham,
say Jacob and Joseph is move out into
the world regardless of the
circumstances at hand.
Now that's in,
in,
in the Old Testament stories that's
basically portrayed as hearkening to the
voice of God.
Something like that.
Maybe you could think about that as
destiny or psychological calling.
Um,
and the funny thing too is,
is that it's not that these people have
an easy time of it when they heed that
call.
So what's,
what's fascinating is that they often
run into extreme difficulties right
away.
And I think that's very interesting.
First of all,
because life is obviously full of
extreme difficulties.
And second,
it's another example of the failure to
sugarcoat things,
which is one of the things I think makes
a mockery of antireligious theories that
are even quite sophisticated say,
like Freud,
because Freud thought of religion as a,
as a wish fulfillment essentially.
And,
and also marks who thought about
religion is the opiate of the masses.
It's if those were true.
It seems to me that there'd be a lot
more wish and a lot less reality,
a lot less stark,
harsh reality.
No,
I mean the first thing that Abraham
encounters is a famine and then he has
to hide his wife and then he.
He basically journeys into a tyranny,
so that's about as bad as it gets in
some ways,
and those themes recur continually and
no one ever lives where they're supposed
to live.
They leave and live in Canaan and not
the promised land,
and so it's a pretty rough.
It's pretty rough series of stories,
but the fundamental idea is something
like
there's no time for sitting around.
There's time to go out into the world
and engage,
and then there's.
There's hints about the proper and
improper ways of engaging right?
So clearly the improper way to engage
is,
I think,
most clearly delineated in the Cain and
Abel Story and with Kane exemplifying
the inappropriate way to engage with the
world and that's to engage with the
world in a bitter,
jealous and resentful manner.
Now,
one of the things that I really liked
about Cain and Abel story and that theme
recurs continually with the,
with the duality of the brothers,
right?
There's,
there's constant conflict between a
perspective that's essentially like
canes and uh,
and the,
and the opposite perspective,
which all,
which I'll get to in a minute,
but Cain sees that the world is a very
tragic place and that the rewards are
distributed unfairly and that there are
people who do better and people who do
worse,
and as a consequence of that,
he becomes bitter and resentful and
curses God and then he becomes
homicidal.
Fratricidal which is even worse than he
destroys his own ideal than his
descendants basically become genocidal,
something like that.
So that seems to be the wrong way to go
about things,
you know,
unless your goal is to make things
worse.
Like it's not like it has a limited
number of things,
has nothing to object to.
He's got plenty to object to.
His situation actually is bad.
He's overshadowed terribly by his
brother who everyone loves,
who does extraordinarily well and who's
good at everything.
And the story is a bit ambivalent about
the reasons for keynes failure,
although a fair bit of it's laid out his
own feet,
but he's definitely failing and so you
can understand why he would have this
terrible attitude.
But the problem is all it does is make
it worse.
So it doesn't seem to be one of the
things I've also learned as a
psychologist,
sort of pondering these sorts of things.
It's often a lot easier to identify what
you shouldn't do then what you should
do.
Like it's.
I think evil is easier to identify than
good.
I think good is trickier,
but evil stands out to some degree and
then at least you can say if you're
trying to get as far away from that as
possible,
we could even say just for practical
reasons so your life doesn't become hell
and your family life doesn't become
hell.
At least you could get as far away from
that as possible.
Even if you weren't able to conjure up
what would constitute the good as an
Ame,
you could at least avoid those sorts of
pitfalls.
And I do also think that it's pitfalls
like that that really threatened our
society right now.
You know,
that I see a tremendous rise in
resentment fueling almost all of the
political polarization that's taking
place seems unfortunate given that by
and large,
everyone on the planet is richer than
they've ever been.
Now,
that doesn't mean there's no disparity.
There's,
but there's always disparity.
Anyways,
Jacob,
of course,
Jacob and Rebecca,
the deceiver,
Esau and Jacob ends up with,
with,
uh,
with Isaac's blessing.
And so that's,
that's a moral catastrophe.
And then he has to run because his
brother wants to kill him.
And so that's the fratricidal motif.
Again.
I liked that too.
I think that's really realistic.
You know,
one of the things that Freud noted
constantly,
and this is where Freud really is a
genius,
is that the most intense hatreds and
also sometimes the most intense love is
within families.
You know,
when in the Freudian world of
psychopathology,
it's all,
it's all inside the family.
And in fact,
the pathology in the Freudian world is
actually the fact that it's all inside
the family because people who get
tangled up in the Freudian familial
nightmare,
which is roughly to in structure,
can only conceptualize the world in
terms of their familial relationships
that they've been so damaged by the
enmeshment and the trauma and the deceit
and the betrayal and the blurred lines
and all of that,
that they just can't expand past the
family and go out in the world.
So the idea that brothers can be at each
other's throats,
I think is out.
It's a very powerful idea and it's not
something that people like to think
about.
So,
so Jacob has to leave and it's not
surprising because mean what he did was
pretty reprehensible.
He betrayed his brother,
but nonetheless,
he's the person who dreams of the ladder
that Unites Heaven and earth.
And that's a very perverse thing.
You know what?
One of the things I think it does is
give.
In some sense,
it gives hope to everyone because it
isn't,
you know,
if only the good guys when we're really
in trouble,
right?
Because it's not that easy to be a good
guy,
it's,
it's really not that easy and most
people are pretty keenly aware of all
the ways that they fall short,
even have their own ideals,
and so if there was no hope except for
the good guys,
almost all of us would be lost.
And so that's one of the things I really
liked and was more surprised about with
the old testament stories is that these
people are very complex lives and they
make very major moral errors by anyone's
standard and yet and yet the overall
message is still hopeful and the message
that runs contrary to the message of
evil say that message of good is
something like,
well,
there's a lot of emphasis on faith.
Right?
And that's a tough one because cynics,
people who are cynical about religious
structures like to think of faith as the
willingness to demolish your intellect
in the service of superstition and well,
there's something to be said for that
perspective,
but not a lot
because the reality is much more
sophisticated.
Part of the faith that's,
that is being insisted upon in the old
testament is something like,
and I'm speaking psychologically here
again,
that it's useful to pause it.
A hi.
Hi.
Good to aim at.
So,
and I,
I really think that's practically useful
to the research we've done with the
future authoring program,
for example,
indicates pretty clearly that if you get
people to conceptualize an ideal and a
balanced ideal,
you know,
so what do you want for your family?
What do you want for your career?
What do you want for your education?
What do you want for your character
development?
How are you going to use your time
outside of work?
Um,
how are you going to structure your use
of drugs and alcohol and places where
you might get impulsive?
How can you avoid falling into a
horrible path?
If you really think that through and you
come up with an integrated ideal and
you,
you put it above us,
something to reach for,
then you're more committed to the world
in a positive way and you're less
tormented by anxiety and uncertainty.
And so.
And that makes sense,
right?
Because here you are alive and
everything,
and so unless you were Cape,
if you're not capable of manifesting
some positive relationship with the fact
of your being,
then how could that be anything other
than hellish because it would just be
anxiety provoking and terrible because
you're vulnerable and there'd be nothing
useful or worthwhile to do.
Well,
that's just not.
I just can't see that as a winning
strategy for anyone.
You can make a rational case for
adopting that strategy in that you know,
you can say,
well,
there's no evidence for for a
transcendent morality or for an ultimate
meaning.
There's no hard empirical evidence,
but it seems to me that there's
existential evidence as well that has to
be taken into account.
And of course psychologists have talked
about this a lot.
I'm Carl Rogers,
for example,
in human for that matter.
Freud,
for that matter,
most of the great psychologists have
pointed out that,
you know,
you can derive reasonable information
that's solid from your own experience,
especially if you also talked to other
people and you can kind of see in your
own life when you're on a productive
path.
It sort of ennobles and enlightens you
or a destructive path and I think it's
kind of useful to think that maybe the
dichotomy between those two paths might
be real,
you know,
and,
and because that also allows you to give
credence to your intuitions about that
sort of thing.
But I don't anyways,
I don't think it's unreasonable to pause
it,
that since you're alive adopting the
highest possible regard for the fact
that you're alive and that you're
surrounded by other creatures that are
alive.
I just can't see how that can possibly
be construed as a losing strategy.
And so that's the first.
So that's something like faith,
right?
It's faith,
it's not,
it's not only faith in your being but
it's faith in being such.
And the faith would be something like if
you could orient your being properly,
then maybe that would orient you with
being as such.
And you never know.
Like,
I mean it might be true.
There's no reason to assume that it
wouldn't be true.
I mean,
even if you just take a strict
biological perspective on this and think
about us as the product of three and a
half billion years of evolution,
I mean we have struggled over all those
billions of years to be alive and to
match ourselves with reality.
And so because one of the things I've
often wondered is,
you know,
life is definitely difficult.
There's no doubt about that and it's
unfair and there's inequality and all of
those things and people are subject to
all sorts of terrible things.
But I also wonder if you weren't
actively striving to make things worse,
just how much better could they be?
You know,
because people are very.
They're like houses that are divided
amongst themselves.
They're pointing in different directions
at the same time.
They're working at cross purposes to
themselves because of bitterness and
resentment and an unprocessed memories
and childhood hatreds and unexamined
assumptions,
all sorts of things.
And you just gotTa wonder if you could
push that aside and orient yourself
properly.
And then the other thing that of course
is stressed very heavily in the old
testament and of course that goes
through the entire biblical corpus is
that it's not only enough to establish a
positive relationship with being,
which I think is the essential,
it's a good description of faith.
You have to make that decision,
right?
Because being is very ambivalent and you
can make the case that maybe it's
something that should have never
happened,
but that doesn't seem to be productive
to me.
And faith seems to be,
I'm going to act as if being is
ultimately justifiable and that if I
partake in it properly,
I will improve it rather than making it
worse.
So I think that's the statement of
faith.
And then what seems to go along with
that is something like truth in
conception,
inaction.
You know,
even people like Jacob who are pretty
damn morally ambivalent to begin with,
get hammered a lot by what they go
through.
And what seems to happen is that they're
hammered into some sort of ethical
shape,
right?
So by the mid point of their life's
journey,
there are people who are solidly planted
who you can trust and who don't be trey
being or themselves or their fellow man.
And so it's an interesting.
I mean it seems reasonable to me to
first assume that you have to establish
a relationship with something that's
transcendent.
It might even be just the future version
of you and then second that you have to
align yourself with reality in a
truthful manner and that that's your
best bet and
the biblical stories are actually quite
realistic about that too because they
don't really say that if you do that,
you're going to be instantly transported
to the promised land.
Like even Moses,
as we'll find out in the accident
stories.
He never makes it to the promised land.
And so it's not like you're offered
instantaneous,
final redemption.
If you move out forthrightly into the
world,
establish a faithful relationship with
being an attempt to conduct yourself
with integrity,
but it's your best bat and it might be
good enough,
and even if it's not good enough,
it's really preferable to the
alternative,
which seems to be something closely akin
to hell,
both personal and social.
So Joseph's father is Jacob later
Israel.
He who wrestles with God and we've
talked about that a little bit.
It's sort of implicit in what I've been
saying is that I think we all do that to
some degree.
We wrestle with reality itself.
That's for sure not only the reality we
understand,
but the reality we don't understand,
which is sort of a transcendent reality
and then maybe whatever reality is
outside of that,
you know,
because the classic Judeo Christian
conception of God is that there's time
and space and of course there's lots of
things about what exists in time and
space that were completely ignorant to
oven that's transcendent in that sense.
But then there's an idea that there is a
realm outside of that which is a.
well,
it's an interesting idea.
It's very sophisticated idea,
I think rather than a simple idea and
it's.
It's difficult to know what to make of
it,
but it doesn't really matter because I
think regardless of what your attitude
is towards those sorts of things,
intellectually,
you still end up in the same position as
Jacob for all intents and purposes,
practically speaking,
because I don't think that there's
anyone who at some point in their life
or perhaps even everyday doesn't at some
level wrestle with God and you could
just call it well the nature of reality,
I suppose if you want to be,
say reductionistic about it,
but I don't think it makes any
difference.
It's still something you're stuck with
and it's not only the nature of reality
itself that you have to struggle with,
but it's also the nature of your moral
relationship to it,
your behavior in relationship to it.
So that's how you should perceive it and
how you should conduct yourself.
And then whether or not the,
the advantages of doing it properly are
worth the difficulty and the
disadvantages.
So that seems to me just a straight
existential statement.
Then you know,
Jacob gets damaged by his wrestling,
which is also very realistic.
So anyways,
he also ends up as father of Joseph,
who's the favorite son,
son who's born in his old age,
to his favorite wife,
and that's who we're going to talk about
two today.
So you remember.
So Jacob is the for father of the 12
tribes of Israel and there's his,
his wives and the son and the offspring
that resulted.
Those are all the sons.
There's a daughter named Diana as well,
and Rachel is the woman he really loved
and the first son he had with Rachel was
Joseph,
and that was when he was older.
And so that's in some sense why Joseph
is his favorite.
So
this is the beginning of the story of
Joseph.
Now Israel.
Jacob loved Joseph more than all his
children because he was the son of his
old age and he made him a coat of many
colors and there's a lot packed into
those two sentences.
You know,
the first is that now Israel loved
Joseph more than all his other children.
That's probably not so good.
One of the things we've seen in the
stories that have preceded this is that
whenever there's marked preference on
the part of parents for one child over
the other,
with,
with Jacob,
and Esau was Rachel was,
uh,
Jacob was Rachel's favorite and Isa was,
um,
Isaac's favorite that didn't work out so
well that put a real twist in the entire
structure of the family.
And so there's a warning there right off
the bat you might say,
well,
you can't help having a preference for
one child or another,
but I don't know if that's true.
And it's certainly something that you
should be very cautious about because it
doesn't seem to work out very well
because he was the son of his old age
fair enough.
And he made him a coat of many colors.
That's a very interesting image,
that coat of many colors they have that
idea.
And so I'm going to delve into that idea
because it sets the stage,
like it says what sort of person Joseph
is.
He's favored,
he's younger,
he's favored.
But he also has this particular garment
that characterizes him,
you know,
and one of the things I've really
learned from analyzing women's dreams in
particular is that women very
frequently,
in my experience,
very frequently dream of clothing as
role.
And so if you're interpreting women's
dreams,
then if they put on the shoes of their
grandmother for example,
then you understand very rapidly that
that dream is trying to make an
association between their own behavior
and something that's characteristic of
either the state of being a grandmother
or the particular grandmother.
And it makes sense,
right?
Because clothing protects.
But it also signifies a role.
And uh,
it's interesting in the old testament
stories,
often if someone is going to act
deceitfully they changed their,
they changed their outfit.
And that's Kinda what you do when you
act deceitfully,
right?
You dress up like someone else,
you present yourself like someone else.
So anyways,
back to the coat of many colors.
Well,
for something to be many colored,
it sort of spans the entire gamut of
possibility.
And so there's a hint there that if you
want to be a full fledged person that
you have to manifest a very large number
of traits.
And so I want to go into that idea a
bit.
The first thing I want to talk about is
some of the things that we've learned
about what happens to you when you go to
a new environment.
You know,
there's this idea in very deep idea and
clinical psychology,
a fundamental idea,
which is that if someone's anxious about
something,
what you do is you.
And it's getting in their way.
You take what they're anxious about,
new define it because that already
delimits it,
right?
Because one of the problems with being
anxious about something as you won't
speak of it,
it's like voldemort.
And then if you don't speak of it you,
it's way bigger than it should be.
As soon as you start talking about it,
you cut it down to size.
And so,
and it,
it's for a bunch of reasons.
It's because you're not as.
You're not as afraid of as many things
as you think.
And you're braver than,
you know.
And more and more capable,
so as soon as you're brave enough to
start talking about what you're afraid
of,
then you see that there's more to you
than you thought and that there's less
to the problem than you thought,
and then you can decompose it further
into smaller problems and then you can
figure out how to approach those smaller
problems and so and then it doesn't seem
to meet to be that you get less
frightened.
It seems to be that you get more
courageous,
which is way better than being less
frightened because there's lots of
things to be frightened about.
So if you're courageous that,
that really does the trick.
Now the question is what happens if you
like,
let's say that you're a very socially
inept and you don't know how to
introduce yourself or to make any,
were established the initial parts of a
relationship with anyone.
And so then you start putting yourself
in situations where you're required to
do that.
And so then the question is how is it
technically that you transform?
You say,
well,
you learn.
Well,
we want to be more specific about that.
What does it mean that you learn?
Well if you're dealing with someone
who's particularly socially inept and
you're doing psychotherapy with them,
you might teach them how to shake
someone's hand properly and say their
name and remember the other person's
name,
and so you just practice that with them
so that they have the motoric routine
down so that form of knowledge is built
right into your body.
It's like,
look at the person,
put out your hand,
shake it.
Don't not like a dead Halibut,
but you know with a reasonable grip.
Say Your name.
Don't mumble it.
Look,
look at them so that they can hear you,
and then when they say their name,
try to remember it and that's meant so
you can practice that with people and so
then they develop something that's
Metorik,
right?
It's embedded right in their body and so
and then you can say to them,
well,
the other thing you can do is when you
start a conversation is don't sit there
thinking about what you're going to say
next because then you won't be paying
attention to the person and you'll make
a fool out of yourself.
Because you'll manifest nonsequitors,
right,
because you'll get out of.
It's like if you're dancing and all
you're paying attention to is where your
feet are,
then you're going to step on the other
person all the time,
so you want to pay attention to the
other person and then whatever
automatized social knowledge you have
will come to the forefront.
So it's a good thing to know if you're
socially anxious,
right?
If you're socially anxious,
one of the things you should do is pay
way more attention to the person you're
talking to rather than less.
And you should pay as little attention
as possible to yourself.
So if you feel yourself falling in
because you're anxious,
then what you do is you push your
attention out and pay attention to the
person because to the degree that you've
been socialized,
then all your automatic responses will
kick it.
So.
But anyway,
so you go out into the social world and
you learn to shake someone's hand and
you learn how to listen to them and ask
them questions because that's the next
thing.
Because people love.
You can't just ask them random questions
obviously,
but if they start talking to you and you
don't understand something about what
they're saying or maybe something they
said is interesting in you ask them a
question,
they're pretty damn happy about that
because it means you're actually paying
attention to them and people actually
love to be paid attention to because it
hardly ever happens.
So they really,
really like it.
And so,
okay,
so,
so what's happening?
Well first of all,
you're mastering the automated motor
movements,
right?
Where to point your eyes,
where to put your hands,
how to move your lips,
like really embodied knowledge.
It's a special kind of memory and you're
practicing that and so that's building
new skills for you.
And then by listening to the person and
watching yourself interact,
you're also generating new new abstract
information that enables you to
conceptualize the world in a different
way.
So if you go out to can you go talk to
10 different people or 50 different
people?
Then you get to listen to what those 50
people said.
You get to watch how they're,
how they express themselves,
and you gather a corpus of knowledge
that changes the way you perceive.
That broadens you as a social agent.
Okay,
so that's two forms of knowledge,
but then there's a third one which is
really interesting,
which is that you know you have a lot of
biological potential and it's hard to
know what potentially is,
but part of it is that you're capable of
generating proteins that you haven't
been generating.
So you should get right on that by the
way.
So,
but what the way that works in part is
that if you put yourself in a radically
new situation,
then your brain that there are genetic
switches that turn on because of the
demands of the new situation that code
for new proteins.
So it's as if you have latent software.
That would be one way of thinking about
that will only be turned on if you go
into this situation where that's
necessary.
And so then you might think,
well,
if that's the case,
how much have you could be turned on if
you went a whole bunch of different
places.
And that's a really,
really,
that's a profound question because one
of the deep answers to how you should
get your life together is you should go
a very large number of places and turn
yourself on.
And I want to walk through that a little
because there's a very rich symbolic
world that expresses that.
So now the idea about having a coat of
many colors would be that the person who
is the appropriate leader,
because remember,
or the proper person,
which would be the same thing.
One of the things that these old stories
are trying to express and to figure out
is how is it that you should act which
is the same as what constitutes the
ideal.
Those are the same question.
And the hand here with Joseph is while
you should wear a coat of many colors,
which means that you should be able to
go have a drink in the pub with the guys
who were,
you know,
dry walling,
your,
your house.
And you should be able to have a
sophisticated conversation with someone
who's more educated in an abstract way.
And that maybe you should be equally
comfortable in both situations,
right?
Because you might think,
well there's more,
one of the indications that there's more
to you is that you can be put more
places and function properly and that
would be a good thing to aim at because
here's the other issue is that you know
perfectly well that the fundamental
tragedies of life and your exposure to
malevolence in the course of that life.
So those being the worst things,
there's not a lot you can do to,
to alter that fundamentally because
their conditions of existence,
you're going to be subject to your
vulnerability and your going to be
subject to malevolence.
That's that.
And you can't hide from it because it
actually makes it worse.
So you're stuck with it.
So then the question is,
well,
what are your options?
And one option is to curse the structure
of being for being malevolent and tragic
and fair enough.
And the other is to make yourself so
damn differentiated and dynamic and able
that you're more than a match for that.
Now that's not an easy thing,
but it doesn't matter.
Because like what?
What's the alternative?
There's no good alternative and that's
also worth knowing.
So you see these ideas expressed in the
strangest places and so we've talked a
little bit,
I think in this,
in this series about Pinocchio,
but if we haven't,
it doesn't matter.
You see,
there's Jimminy cricket at the opening
of the Pinocchio Movie,
pointing to a star,
which is roughly the Nativity Star for
all intents and purposes,
and it's a.
it's a symbolic indicator of a of
something diamond like and pure right
glimmering in the darkness that's
transcendent,
that above the horizon upon which to fix
your eyes,
and so that's the thing is you need that
technically and the reason you need that
is because we know enough about
psychology now to know that almost all
of the positive emotion that you're
going to experience in your life and
positive emotion is analgesic by the
way,
right?
It actually quells paint,
so it's not just positive and also gets
rid of negative,
which is a big plus.
Almost all of the positive emotion that
you're going to feel.
You're going to feel in relationship to
a goal because you feel positive emotion
as you approach a goal,
and so if you want to feel positive
emotion,
then you need a goal and then you might
think,
well,
if you want to maximize that positive
emotion,
which is enthusiasm,
and also what pulls you out into the
world as well as feeling good,
then you need the best possible goal.
Well that because that's going to engage
the largest segments of your being,
like if your goals too narrow,
then a bunch of you isn't going to be on
board for it.
You know?
If the goal is well developed and
multifaceted,
then all of you can partake in that.
Even your negative elements,
even your anger and your fear can get
onboard with that.
Let's say so you need a goal,
man,
that's worthy.
You got us.
Thank you.
Good.
You need a goal that justifies the
tragedy and malevolence of life.
That seems to be the bottom line.
Now maybe you think,
well,
there's no goal that can do that.
It's like,
well,
there are still better and worse
schools,
so and I,
I'm not convinced that there are no
goals that can do that.
I think that's an open question.
You'd never know that until you pursued
the proper goal long enough to find out
who you would be as a consequence of
pursuing it.
So that's also your destiny or your
existential voyage,
right?
It's also not something that anyone else
can do for you.
Someone can say,
get your act together for Christ's sake
and get it.
Get good at it.
That's,
that'll make the world unfold best for
you.
But there's no way you can know that
without doing it.
So,
and unless you think you've done a
particularly stellar job of that,
then you have no reason to doubt its
potential validity.
So plus,
like crickets are telling you this.
And so you know,
there are a very reliable source.
Okay,
so you see the star,
The star recurs as a Motif in Pinocchio.
And one of the more interesting elements
of it here is that when Japan wants to
transform his puppet Marionette,
whose being played by forces that
operate behind the scenes,
which is really good definition of the
persona from a union perspective,
right?
And also something indicative of
something like an ideological or
conceptual possession.
Japan who's a good guy is positive
father figure read lifts his even though
he is a patriarchal figure,
right?
And a very competent one.
He's still even lifts his eyes up to
something that transcends his mode of
being positive as it is and wishes that
his creation would undertake the kind of
transformation that would make it
autonomous and fully functional as a
moral agent.
No strings.
Right?
So that's very interesting.
I think soldier hits and said the
salvation of mankind lies only in making
everything that concern of all.
That's a pretty decent star,
like goal I would say.
And so what happens in the story is that
because,
and I think this is a symbolic
representative of what I just described
you,
that happens at a genetic level,
if you put yourself in new situations.
So Japan is roughly culture in the
Pinocchio Story,
right?
He's,
he's a craftsman.
he's,
uh,
and he makes Pinocchio.
So He's,
he's who's his son.
He's the socializing agent and he aims
for something above mere socialization,
which is,
I think,
part of the mysterious element of human
beings.
You know,
when our scientific models,
we basically have socialization and
biology,
but there's always a third element and
mythological stories,
which is whatever you might construe as
the spontaneous action of consciousness
that's associated with freewill.
And you know,
that's just basically being
conceptualized in religious terms as
something akin to the soul.
Now we don't have a category for that
scientifically because what we try to do
scientifically is to reduce everything
either to socialization or to biology.
But it isn't clear to me that that's.
It's perfectly reasonable from the
perspective of practicality at a
scientific level.
You don't want to multiply explanatory
principles beyond necessity,
but there's many things that that
doesn't come to terms with,
such as the fact that we all treat each
other as autonomous beings with free
will and that that seems to work.
And that if we stopped doing that,
then things go to hell very,
very rapidly.
So,
and the mere fact that we have been able
to conceptualize what that conscious
freewill might be,
metaphysically or physically,
it doesn't mean it doesn't exist,
it just means that we don't understand
it.
I mean what it was only in the last 15
years that we discovered that 95 percent
of the universe was made out of some
kind of matter that we can't even whose
properties we can't even imagine except
that it seems to have mass.
So anyways,
what happens is when Japan Eto reach
lifts his eyes up to the star,
he,
so it's society aligning itself with the
proper goal with regards to individual
development,
right?
So,
so there instead of society being at
odds with the individual,
they line up and then what happens is
nature comes on board and that's the
blue fairy in the,
in the Pinocchio Story.
And that's seems to me to be a symbolic
representation of what happens
biologically when when you set the goal
properly,
get your culture behind you and move
into the world,
is that there's a biological
transformation that occurs as a
consequence of that,
which means that a bunch of you that
hasn't been turned on turns on.
And I guess one question would be is
what would you be like if you turned on
everything inside of you that could be
turned on?
Well,
that's a good goal.
That's a good thing to find out.
So now I'm going to introduce a couple
of other ideas.
There's this idea in union psychology
called the circumambulation and young
had this idea that you had a potential
future self which would be in potential
everything that you could be and that it
manifests itself moment to moment in
your present life by making you
interested in things and the things that
you're interested in are the things that
would guide you along the path that
would lead you to maximal development.
Now it sounds like a metaphysical idea
or a or a mystical idea even,
but,
but it's not.
It's not,
it's a really profoundly biological
idea.
The idea is something like,
well,
your setup so that you're automatically
interested in those things that was
fully expand you as a well adapted
creature.
Well like there's nothing radical about
that idea.
How well what else could possibly be the
case unless there's something
fundamentally flawed about you that is
what the situation would be.
It's kind of interesting to think about
how that would be manifest moment to
moment,
but the idea is something like,
well,
your interest is captured by those
things that lead you down.
The path of development will have better
be the case.
Okay,
so that's fine,
and so there's some utility in pursuing
those things that you're interested in.
That's the call to adventure,
let's say so and the call to adventure
takes you all sorts of places.
Now the problem with the call to
adventure is like,
what the hell do you know?
You might be interested in things that
are kind of warped and bent,
and often it's the case that when new
parts of people manifest themselves and
grip their interest,
say they do it very badly and shoddily
and so you stumble around like an idiot.
When you try to do something new.
That's where the fool is the precursor
to the savior from the,
from the symbolic perspectives,
because you have to be a fool before you
can be a master and if you're not
willing to be a fool and you can't be a
master,
so,
so you're going to.
It's an error error ridden process and
that's also laid out the old testament
stories because the first thing that
happens to all these patriarchal figures
when God kicks them out of their
father's house when they're like 84,
is that they.
They run into all sorts of trouble.
And some of it's social too.
Some of it's natural.
Some of it's a consequence of their own
moral inadequacy.
So they're fools and.
But,
but the thing that's so interesting is
that despite the fact that they're
fools,
they're still supposed to go on the
adventure and that they're capable of
learning enough as a consequence of
moving forward on the adventure so that
they straightened themselves out across
time.
And so it's something like this and this
circumambulation that young talked about
was this continual,
we'll return to this,
this continual circling in some sense of
who you could be.
You might notice,
for example,
that there are themes in your life.
You know,
when you go back across your
experiences,
you see,
you kind of have your typical experience
that sort of repeats itself and there
might be variation on it,
like a musical theme,
but it's like you're circling yourself
and getting closer to yourself as you
move across time.
That's the circumambulation.
Now you remember that for a sec because
we'll go back to it.
Okay?
So imagine that something glimmers
before you.
It's an an interest that's dawning and
you decide,
well,
first of all,
you're paralyzed.
You think,
well,
how do I know if I should pursue that?
It's probably a stupid idea,
and the proper response to that is,
you're right,
it probably is a stupid idea because
almost all the,
all ideas are stupid and so the
probability that as you move forward on
your adventure,
that you're going to get it right the
first time is zero.
It's just not going to happen.
And so then you might think,
well,
maybe I'll just wait around until I get
the right idea and which people do,
right?
So they're like 40 year old,
13 year olds,
which is not a good idea.
And so they wait around until it's
waiting for Godot until they finally got
it right.
But the problem is you're too stupid to
know when you've got it right.
So waiting around isn't going to help
because even if it's the perfect
opportunity manifested itself to you in
your incomplete form,
the probability that you would recognize
it as the perfect opportunity is zero.
You might even think it's the worst
possible idea that you've ever heard of
anywhere,
highly likely,
highly likely.
So,
so you ha,
there's a niche nature called that,
uh,
will,
will to stupidity,
which I really liked.
So because he thought of stupidity as
being,
you know,
it's,
you have to take it into account
fundamentally and work with it and so
and so you can take these tentative
steps on your pathway to destiny and you
can assume that you're going to do it
badly and that's really useful because
you don't have to beat yourself up.
It's pretty easy to do it badly.
But the thing is it's way better to do
it badly than not to do it at all.
And that's the continual message that
echoes through these historical stories
in genesis.
It's like these are flawed people.
They should have got the hell out of
their house way before they did and they
go out and they stumble around in
tyranny and feminine self betrayal and,
and violence.
And,
but it's a hell of a lot better than
just rotting away at home.
And that's the,
that's great.
So that's good.
And so why is that?
Well,
okay,
so you,
you start your path and you think that
you're heading towards your star and so
you go in that direction and then
because you're here,
the world looks a particular way,
but then when you move here,
the world looks different and you're
different as a consequence of having
made that voyage and so what that means
is that now that thing that glimmers in
front of you is going to have shifted
its location because you weren't very
good at specifying it to begin with and
now that you're a little sharper and
more focused than you were,
it's going to reveal itself with more
accuracy to you.
And so then you have to take a,
you know,
it's almost like 180 degree reversal,
but it because you know,
you've.
I mean you've gone this far and that's a
long ways to get that far.
But that's a lot farther than you would
be if you just stayed where you were
waiting.
And so it doesn't matter that you
overshoot continually because as you
overshoot,
even if you don't learn what you should
have done,
you're going to continually learn what
you shouldn't keep doing.
And if you learn enough about what you
shouldn't keep doing,
then that's tantamount at some point to
learning at the same time what you
should be doing.
So it's okay.
So it's like this.
Now what's cool about it though,
I think is that as you progress,
the degree of overshooting starts to
decline,
right?
And that we know that there was nothing
hypothetical about that.
As you learn a new skill,
like even to play it,
play a song on the piano,
for example,
you overshoot madly making all sorts of
mistakes to begin with.
And then the mistakes
they disappear.
There's a great ted talk,
I think it was about sky,
a setup,
a really advanced computational
recording system in his home and
recorded every single utterance his
young child made while learning to
speak.
And then he put together the child's
attempts to say certain phonemes and put
them in the list.
And you can hear the child deviating
madly to begin with,
and then after hundreds and hundreds of
repetitions,
just zeroing in on the exact phoneme so
you know you might not know this,
but when kids babble,
because they start babbling when they're
quite young,
they babble every human phoneme
including all sorts of phonemes that
adults can't say,
and then they they die into their
language so that after they learn,
say English,
then there's all sorts of phonemes they
can no longer here or pronounced,
but to begin with,
it's all there,
which is really quite interesting,
but so they zip as they learn a
particular language,
they zero in on the proper way to
pronounce that in their errors minimize.
And every time you learn something,
now it's how it is.
And that's really useful to know too,
because it means that it's okay to
wander around stupidly before you fix
your destination.
Now you see that echoed in exodus,
right?
Because what happens is that the
Egyptians or the Hebrews escape a
tyranny,
which is kind of whatever you do
personally and psychologically.
When you escape from your previous set
of stupidly held and ignorant and
stubborn axioms,
it's like away from that tyranny.
It's like,
great.
I freed myself from that.
Well then what?
Well you think,
well now I'm on the way.
It's no,
you're not.
Now you're in the desert where you
wonder around stupidly,
you know and worship the wrong things
until you finally organize yourself
morally again and had in the proper
direction.
So that's worth knowing too because you
think,
well,
I got rid of a lot of things,
baggage,
excess baggage that I didn't need in my
life,
and now everything's okay.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
You've got rid of a whole set of
scaffolds that were keeping you in place
even though they were pathological.
Now you have nothing and nothing
actually turns out to be better than
something pathological,
but you're still stuck with the problem
of nothing.
And that's.
Well,
that's exactly why exodus is structured
the way that it is.
It's that you escaped from maturity.
It's hooray.
We're no longer slaves.
Yeah,
well now you're nihilistic and lost.
It's not necessarily an improvement,
but it is,
but it is the pre.
See.
It's also useful to know that because
you can also be diluted into the idea
that imagine that you're trying to
become enlightened,
which might mean to turn all those parts
of you on that could be turned on.
You think,
well,
that's just a linear pathway uphill.
You know,
it's just from one success to another.
It's no,
it's not.
It's like here you are and you're not
doing too badly in the first step is a
complete bloody catastrophe.
It's worse and then maybe you can pull
yourself together and you hit a new
plateau and then that crumbles and
shakes and bang.
It's worse again and so because part of
the reason that people don't become
enlightened is because it's punctuated
by intermittent deserts essentially by
intermittent catastrophes and if you
don't know that well then you're
basically screwed because you go ahead
on your movement forward and you
collapse and you think,
well,
that didn't work.
I collapsed.
It's like,
no,
that's par for the course.
It's not indication that you failed.
It's just indication that it's really
hard and that when you learn something,
you also unlearn something and the thing
you unlearned is probably useful and
unlearning it actually is painful.
You know,
let's say if you have to get out of a
bad relationship,
it's like not every,
not any real.
There isn't any relationship that's a
hundred percent bad,
and so when you jump out of it,
well maybe you're in better shape,
but you're still lonesome and
disoriented and you don't know what your
past was and you don't know what your
president is and you don't want to know
what your future is.
It's that's not.
That's why people stay with the devil
they know instead of,
you know,
looking for the devil they don't know
so,
so anyways,
the fact that you're full of faults
doesn't mean you have to stop and thank
God for that.
That's a really useful thing and the
fact that you're full of faults doesn't
mean that you can't learn and so you can
pause it and an ideal and you're going
to be wrong about it,
but it doesn't matter because what
you're right about his positing,
the ideal moving towards it,
if the actual ideal isn't conceptualized
perfectly well first surprise,
surprise,
because like what are you going to do?
That's perfect.
So it doesn't matter that it's
imperfect,
it just matters that you do it and that
you move forward.
So that's really,
that's really positive news as far as
I'm concerned because you could actually
do that,
right?
You can do it badly.
Anyone can do that.
So that's,
that's useful.
Okay.
So like if you were an efficient person,
you would have just done that but you're
not.
But who cares?
You know,
you still end up in the,
in the same place and maybe the trip is
even more interesting.
Who knows?
Probably two interesting young.
I began to understand that the goal of
psychic development by which he means
psychological development or spiritual
development is the self.
There is no linear evolution.
There's only a circumambulation of the
self are getting closer.
It's like it's like you're spiraling
into something,
something like that and the thing that
you're spiraling into recedes as you
move towards it and gets more and more
sophisticated and well developed as you
move towards it because you're not going
to run out of goals,
right?
No matter how much you have your act
together,
there's probably undoubtedly 30
dimensions along which you could get
your act together a lot more so,
and some of those aren't even
conceivable to you when you're in your
initial on carved state,
let's say uniform development exists at
most at the beginning.
Later,
everything points towards the center.
This insight gave me stability and
gradually my inner peace returned.
So this is fun.
On the left there.
That's the sharp cathedral.
That's the one that has the maze in it
that I told you about.
They actually light that up with lasers
now and so that's it lit up with lasers
and so.
So they're turning it into a cathedral
of light,
which I think is really fascinating and
it's.
It's a continuation of the same idea,
right?
Because the stained glass windows were
obviously,
I wouldn't call them primitive attempts
to do that.
I mean stained glass windows are pretty
impressive,
you know,
but it's an elaboration of the same
thing.
So now you can go to that Cathedral.
They light up the whole town like that,
which is really something.
And so they're.
And there's how the cathedral is built.
It's across.
Um,
and do you remember the cross is an ex
that marks the center of the world and
the cross is the place where each
individual is.
And I think that's the fundamental
message of Christianity is the cross
marks the place where every single
individual is.
And it's a tragic place that consists of
suffering and exposure to malevolence
and that the only way to come to terms
with it is to accept it.
And that seems to me,
I don't see anything metaphysical about
that statement whatsoever.
It's like,
well,
x marks the spot.
Fair enough.
You're in a spot,
you're right in the center of your
world.
It's right in the center of the world as
far as you're concerned.
And the same with the rest of us.
It's characterized by suffering and
exposure to malevolence.
There's no doubt about that.
What are you going to do about that
bitter,
resentful,
hateful.
All that does is make it worse.
So you have to accept it.
Now,
that's not an easy thing because that's
actually,
I would say,
a heroic task to voluntarily accept the
conditions of your own existence.
And that happens at the cross.
So that's fine.
And that's associated with light.
Well,
that's good that that's associated with
light.
You wouldn't want that to be associated
with darkness.
That would be a bad thing.
So,
and so there's the,
there's the,
uh,
the labyrinth that was built in 1200
add.
And so the idea is you walk in here,
it's the same idea as that star sequence
of slides that I just showed you.
So here's the idea,
is that north,
south,
west and east.
So that's the whole world laid out in
two dimensions.
And so the question is,
how do you get to the center?
Now we already know what the center is.
The center is the center of the Cross
and that's the place of maximal
suffering.
You could save maximal malevolence as
well,
but it's also the place where that's
transcended,
so how do you get there while the answer
is,
well,
you don't just stand on the outside
looking in,
that's not gonna help,
so and you can't just run right to the
center even if you're in California and
so you have to walk in here and then you
see you go like this and you go to every
single place,
every single place on that,
on that little cosmos,
and then once you've gone to every
single place and expanded yourself as a
consequence of going north and west and
east and south,
then there's enough of you so that
you're at so that you can tolerate being
first of all that you can figure out
where the center is,
but also that you can tolerate being at
the center.
And so that's what that represents.
And that's pretty.
And look,
I mean let's make no mistake about it.
Hey,
people were pretty damn serious about
those ideas.
Like that's,
that's quite the piece of work for
people in the twelfth century in all of
those.
Some of those damn cathedrals took 300
years to build.
We don't build anything that takes 300
years,
you know,
and people were putting a lot of effort
into whatever these things meant,
you know,
and if you think they meant bearded man
in the sky,
then you know,
it's hard to.
It's hard to account for the kind of
motivation that would produce these
buildings with that kind of paucity of
conceptualization,
you know,
the towns.
And it was certainly the case in charter
that they groaned under the tax burden
that was required to produce these.
Now you might think,
well that's partly tyrannical and no
doubt that's the case,
but,
but that's not the whole story.
The whole story is that the people who
produce those buildings,
they thought about every bit of it.
Nothing's accidental and they're trying
to portray something just like that
window is trying to portray something
that's the same thing as this.
It's the center from which all things
manifest themselves.
You see that's Christ there and being
portrayed as,
as that center or the center within him,
something like that.
Very much like the shockers and in,
in um,
in a yogic practice,
same basic idea.
It's the opening up of the internal
structure and its proper realization.
So there are people walking the
labyrinth,
so that's the coat of many colors,
right?
That's this differentiated motive being
that enables you to be competent at home
in the widest possible number of places
and that that's a real differentiation
of your personality to breaking through
the boundaries of your personality,
including the ones that you impose on
yourself to become someone who is useful
wherever they're put.
And that's really relevant to this story
of Joseph too because one of the things
that happens to Joseph is that,
well,
a lot of bad things happen to him
because he's the favorite of his father.
His brothers hated him,
and so the first they're going to throw
him in a pit.
I think they do throw them in a pit.
Then they sell them to be a slave.
Then he ends up in,
well,
we'll go through the story.
He ends up some places where you
probably wouldn't want to go prison
being one of them,
but it doesn't matter because even when
they put them in prison,
he's actually not in prison.
He just figures out how to make the
prison work way better.
Then he's in control of the prison and
it's a really.
It's an interesting.
I had this friend,
you know,
and he was very smart but very cynical
and he wasn't employed very well and he
got a little older than he should have
given his level of intelligence and
employability and so he had to take jobs
that weren't very intellectually
challenging.
You know,
on.
One of the things I tried to convince
him of was that even if he worked,
he wanted to work behind the parts
department in an automotive store
because he liked cars,
but it was beneath them,
you know,
because it was sort of a.
As far as he was concerned,
it was a,
he was too smart for a job like that,
which actually turned out not to be
true.
He wasn't smart enough for a job like
that or it wasn't wise enough.
But you know,
I,
one of the things I tried to tell them
was that you're looking at the situation
wrong because even in a simple job,
so called simple job,
like let's say dishwashing in a
restaurant,
which I did an awful lot of.
It's not that simple.
You're dealing with a lot of other
people,
very fast staff changeover.
You're feeding people,
you're helping them have a celebration,
you're helping them take a break,
like you can do it really well and then
the kitchen can operate properly and
then people can come out to the
restaurant.
It's not a bloody catastrophe and like
you're even when you're doing something
that's a menial job,
so to speak,
like dishwashing,
there are ways of doing it really badly,
resentfully and horribly and doing it
really well.
And as soon as you do it really well,
it's not a menial job anymore.
It,
it immediately transformed.
Now,
I mean
you can be around people who won't let
that happen and you should go get
another job if that's the case,
but if you do it properly,
then it's not meaningful at all.
And that's also a good way out of
resentment,
you think,
well,
I've just got this,
you know,
two bit job.
It's like,
yeah,
what if you did it as well as you
possibly could,
you know what would happen?
Well,
the first thing that would happen is
you'd get a lot smarter,
that's for sure.
And that's hardly a negative thing.
Okay.
So that's the coat of many colors.
So it's an estimation of what Joseph is
like and what we're seeing with all of
these patriarchal figures is the
continual realization of the ideal
person.
Right?
You could think about it as success of
approximations of the ideal person.
And the story is exploring all sorts of
different possibilities,
including ones that are very violent and
catastrophic and malevolent.
It's trying to cover the entire
territory and to focus in on what the
proper way through the maze,
the maze of life,
the labyrinth.
And the hint here is that while you
should be multidimensional,
these are the generations of Jacob.
Joseph being 17 years old,
was feeding the flock with his brothers
and the lad was with his sons of Bilhah
and with the sons of Zilpah,
his father's wives,
and Joseph brought unto his father.
They're evil report.
Well,
we already know that Joseph has Jacob's
favorite,
and so that doesn't make him very
popular among his brothers.
He's younger and now we also find out
that he's been set up more or less,
as you might say,
a snitch because that's what this phrase
means is that he goes out and watches
his older brothers and if they do
something they shouldn't do that.
He comes trotting back to Jacob and
reports,
well,
that's not going to make you popular.
So.
And you would say,
well,
is that Joseph's problem?
Or Jacob's problem?
And I would say,
and this is something I learned from
reading too,
is that that's a conspiratorial problem,
right?
Is it's the parents that fault,
but so is the child who agrees to do
that.
They've got a little cabal going and you
might say,
well,
it's only the parents' fault,
but the sun will be taking advantage of
every advantage that offers him because
he could say no to.
I won't do that.
So anyways,
so Joseph is the favorite.
He's a bit of a teacher's pet.
That's what it looks like now.
Israel loved Joseph more than all his
colors because he was the son of his old
age and he made him a coat of many
colors.
And when his brethren saw that their
father loved him more than all his
brothers,
they hated him and could not speak
peaceably unto him.
So let's say you have a child or number
of children and one of them is your
favorite.
How should you treat that child?
Well,
it isn't obvious that you do them any
favors by overtly making them be your
favorite,
right?
I mean,
first of all,
maybe you don't them as much as you
should.
And second of all,
you definitely set up a Cain and Abel
like scenario in the household and that.
Or maybe it's new situation too,
because you happen to love your child
more than you love your spouse,
which is,
that's not a recipe for familial
harmony.
So it's,
it seems to be a bad idea.
Okay,
so now we have two reasons that Joseph
is not liked by his brothers is.
One is,
well he's a bit of a rat fink and the
other is that he's the,
he's the favorite and he's playing that
to the hill by the looks of things.
And when his brothers saw that their
father loved him more than all his
brethren and all his brothers and they
hated him and could not speak peaceably
unto him.
And Joseph dreamed a dream and he told
it to his brethren and they hated him.
The more he said unto them,
here I pray you this dream which I have
dreamed for.
Behold we were binding.
We chiefs in the field and Lo my sheaf
arose.
And behold,
your sheaves stood round about and bowed
to my sheaf and his.
And remember he's the young one,
right?
And,
and also the daughter of the favorite
wife,
which is another thing that's,
or the son of the favorite wife,
which is another thing,
not really working in his favor.
And his brethren said to him,
Shalt Thou indeed reign over us or shall
thou indeed have dominion over us?
And they hated him,
yet the more for his dreams and for his
words,
while there there's a shock,
you know,
that makes perfect sense.
So when it gets worse,
so you see here,
well there's the wheat sheaves bowing
there and uh,
and then you see this,
what's going on here?
Well,
that's not the end of his,
let's call it grandiosity.
And there's an idea to and in the Old
Testament,
especially in the stories of Joseph,
that if God sends you a dream twice,
he really means it.
And so I don't know if that's true,
although I do know that people have
repeating dreams.
It might be true that that a dream you
have twice is really trying to punch
something home.
You know,
it's certainly the case that recurrent
nightmares are meaningful and that
recurrent nightmares are associated
quite tightly with decreased states of
mental health and that if you can treat
the nightmare,
which is often quite easy by the way,
then the some of the mental health
problems will decrease,
so repeated dreams seem to be important.
Anyways.
He dreamed yet another dream and told it
to his brethren and said,
behold,
I've had another dream,
and be and behold the sun and the moon
and the 11 stars bowed to me and he told
it to his father and to his brothers and
his father rebuked him and said unto
unto him,
what is this dream that though history
of I in my and your mother and your
brothers indeed come to bow down
ourselves to the to the earth,
and his brothers envied him,
but his father observed to say,
well,
what the hell do you make of something
like that,
right?
If someone tells you that it's like,
are they responsible for their dreams?
We don't really seem.
We don't really hold ourselves
responsible for our,
for the dreams we have at night,
and what do you make of a dream is like
one of the things that [inaudible]
pointed out,
this is where he differed from Freud's
substantially is Freud tended to think
that the dream head,
its meaning because it's contents
weren't acceptable to the conscious mind
and young said,
no,
you don't understand.
That's not what happens.
What happens is the dream is doing the
best it can to express something that
the person doesn't yet really know and
young thought about the dream as a
manifestation of nature.
It wasn't associated with the ego at
all.
It was just like you have a dream and
there were things happening in it.
The same way that when you walk into a
dinner party,
there are things happening there.
You know it's not.
The dream isn't something that's subject
to your capacity for manipulation.
It's something that happens to you,
not something that you do.
And so,
so if someone has a dream like that,
well you've got three options.
You can just discount dreams altogether,
which is what people in the modern world
tend to do,
which is a very bad idea because there
are thoughts and you shouldn't discount
them.
You know what I mean?
And they're hardly random as some
neuroscientists claim.
That's absolutely cockeyed theory.
That random like television,
snow on a TV set,
if it was random.
So,
so one is while you just discount
dreams.
The other is that you consider the
person a liar and a braggart and a
narcissist.
And the third is,
well,
what's the third?
It's like he dreamt that the sun and the
moon and the stars bowed down to him.
You might think about that two or three
times so,
but it's not necessarily something
that's going to make you happy.
And his brother and went to feed their
father's flock and check him.
So they took off and Israel said unto
Joseph,
you're not thy brethren,
feed the flock and check him calm and I
will send thee unto him.
And he said him and he said to him,
here,
here tomorrow.
And when they saw him afar off,
even before he came near onto them,
they conspired against him to slay him.
Rough people act then,
right?
This is,
this sort of thing is happening quite
frequently.
Um,
and they said to one another,
behold,
the dreamer cometh.
Come now,
therefore let us slay him,
cast him into some pit,
and we will say some evil beast has
devoured him and we shall see what
becomes of his dreams.
So there's an echo of the Cain and Abel
story there.
Obviously,
you know what I mean?
It's not quite as clear because it
indicate enables store able is clearly
just doing well.
And here you can't quite get a handle on
Joseph's character.
You can't tell if he is actually the
elect or if he's just a spoiled Brat
with delusions of grandeur.
But it doesn't matter because his
brothers,
they're so irritated at his.
The fact that he's favored and perhaps
even the fact that he might be someone
destined for something,
that they find it perfectly reasonable
to destroy that.
And it's so hard.
It's so interesting how often that motif
of pulling down an ideal manifest itself
in these old stories,
right?
It's the pattern is established in the
Cain and Abel Story.
It just repeats and repeats and repeats
and I.
I think that's dead true.
I think it just repeats all the time so
that people are annoyed about how tragic
their lives are.
They're annoyed that they're subject to
malevolence and they're annoyed that
they're not doing as well as other
people are doing and that makes them up,
puts them exactly into this state of
mind.
Now,
maybe with modern people,
if you're going to kill someone because
you're resentful as a modern person,
you don't generally slay them and throw
them into a pit.
You know what you do is you just killed
them slowly over a few decades and it
isn't obvious to me that that's any
better.
So I've seen plenty of married couples
who were in that situation.
It's like,
it's like there is this Mitch Hedberg he
used to complain about Turtleneck,
said it was like being strangled by a
really weak midget,
probably really politically incorrect
jokes,
but it's a funny joke.
So,
uh,
and then you see,
you see relationships that are like
that.
It's like each person has their hands
around the neck of the other person,
but they don't have enough courage to
actually to squeeze it,
just put enough pressure on to cut the
circulation off a tiny bit.
So the person just gets like a die over
a 30 year period,
something like that.
So yeah,
and you all laugh because,
you know,
it's true.
That's why.
And we will say some evil beast has
devoured him,
which would be true actually.
It would be the evil beast that's inside
the brothers and we shall see what will
become of his dreams.
Huh.
That's uh,
that's interesting too because.
So they want to spite themselves because
maybe Joseph is something special and
then they want to spite their farther,
which is probably not the wisest idea
because they owe him some gratitude.
I mean,
maybe he's acting like a pain in the
neck.
There's some evidence for that,
but this is a little bit harsh,
but they also want to spite God just
like Cain did because that's what it
means.
We shall see what will become of his
dreams,
right?
Because then as soon as you're,
in some sense trying to fight against
the intuition of someone,
the natural intuition,
if someone,
you've set yourself up against the
structure of being itself and so pretty
bad,
and Reuben heard it and he delivered
them out of their hands and said,
no,
let us not kill them.
And Ruben said unto them,
shed no blood but cast him into this pit
that's in the wilderness.
It's like Reuben's the good guy in this
story.
And uh,
and there's no water in the pit by the
way,
lay no hand upon him that he might read
him out of their hands
to deliver him to his father again.
So Robin was actually trying to save him
steady,
might read him out of their hands to
deliver them to his father again.
And it came to pass when Joseph came
unto his brethren that they stripped him
of his coat,
his coat of many colors that was on him,
and they took him and cast him into a
pit and the pit was empty and there was
no water in it.
And then they sat down to eat bread and
lifted up their eyes and looked and
behold,
a company of ishmaelites come came from
Gilead with their camels bearing spices
and bomb and murmur going to carry it
down to Egypt.
And Judah said unto his brother,
how does it profit us if we kill our
brother and conceal his blood?
So He's,
he's the practical guy here.
What?
Why would we kill them when we can sell
them?
It's like,
come let us sell him to the ishmaelites
and let not our hand be upon him for he
is our brother and our flesh and his
brother and we're content.
Then they're passed by the midianites
merchantmen and they drew and lifted up
Joseph out of the pit and sold Joseph to
the Ishmaelites for 20 pieces of silver
to amount that echoes through into the
future.
And they brought Joseph into Egypt.
I've never really sure how these slavery
stories work.
It's like,
so it's two 2,500,
3000 years ago,
and I decided I'm going to sell you to
the Israelites and that just works out.
They I get the money,
you get to be a slave and they take you
away.
I don't really understand how that
works.
I can't figure out how people were just
selling each other all the time.
But maybe if you're a family you can do
it.
So there are.
They sold him and Rubin returned to the
pit.
And behold Joseph was not there and
Rubin rant is close.
So Rubin's very upset about this.
And he returned unto his brothers and
said,
the child is not in our.
Where shall I go?
And they conspired.
They took Joseph's coat and killed a kid
of the goats and dip the code in the
blood.
That's interesting too,
because blood is actually another color,
right?
So he's got this coat of many colors and
blood is definitely a color.
And so this is the addition in some
sense of the color of blood to Joseph's
coat.
And I would say it's probably a
necessary color because I don't think
that you're serious enough till your
code has been dipped in blood.
Now it can happen in many ways.
And they sent the coat of many colors
and they brought it to their father and
said,
so they lied to him.
It's very,
very nasty business.
This they.
They sell his son to slavery.
They claim that he's dead.
They lie to them,
they put them into an extreme state of
grief.
There's a lot of hatred underneath that
write a tremendous amount of hatred for
Joseph and also for Jacob.
This we have found no.
Now whether it be thy son's coat or not,
and he knew it,
he said,
it's my son's coat and evil beast,
has him.
Joseph is without doubt,
rent in pieces and Jacob Torres clothes
and put sackcloth on his loins and
mourned for many days.
And all his sons and daughters rose up
to comfort them,
either refused to be comforted.
And he said,
I'll go down into my grave.
Morning,
my son does.
His father wept for.
So that's Jacob collapsing at the news
and the midianites sold Joseph into
Egypt,
onto Potiphar,
an officer of Pharaohs and captain of
the guard,
and Joseph was brought down to Egypt and
Potiphar,
an officer of Pharaoh,
captain of the guard,
and the Egyptian bought him of the hands
of the Ishmaelites,
which had brought him down thither.
So now he's a slave.
So now you'd think,
well that would be,
this is a man who has a lot of reason to
be irritated out the structure of
reality,
right?
He's gone from being the favorite to
being betrayed by all of his brothers.
That's pretty rough.
And then he's been transformed into a
slave and now he's being.
He's being sold to work as a slave.
So you'd think that that would corrupt
his character because you know,
one of the things,
I think this is the case anyways,
I think people are always looking for an
excuse to have their character
corrupted.
Because if your character is corrupted,
then you get to lie and you get to cheat
and you get to steal and you get to be
trained.
You get to act resentfully and he get to
do nothing and that's all easy.
It's easier to lie than to tell the
truth.
It's easier to do nothing than to do
something.
So there's always part of you thinking,
well,
I need a justification for being useless
and horrible because that.
That'd be a lot less work.
And so then if something terrible comes
along,
you think a high.
That's just exactly the excuse that I
was waiting for.
And then out all that comes,
you know,
soldier should Ipsen when he was in the
concentration camps in Russia watching
how people behaved,
you know,
he said that there were people that were
put in the camps who immediately became
trustees are guards and they were even
more vicious than the people who had
been hired as guards.
And his idea was that they had collected
all that.
He called it fallenness,
if I remember correctly around them in
normal life,
but they didn't have the opportunity to
express it.
But as soon as you gave them the
opportunity,
it was like there.
It was right away.
And so,
so one of the messages that seems to
echo through these old testament stories
is that just because something terrible
happens to you doesn't mean that you get
to be,
that you get to wander off the path and
make things worse.
And maybe it doesn't matter how terrible
it is that what happens to you,
that's a tough call,
you know,
because you see people now and then in
life who they've really got it rough
man,
like 50 bad things are happening to them
at the same time.
And you think,
oh,
it's no wonder if you are bitter and
resentful and hostile and be like,
yeah,
no wonder.
But then you meet people and socialize
again,
talked about this in the Gulag
archipelago.
He said he met lots of people in not
lot.
He met enough people to impress him in
the concentration camp system who didn't
allow their misfortunes to corrupt them.
And that's something man,
because maybe the only real misfortune
is to become corrupted.
That's a really useful thing to think,
you know,
maybe the rest of it,
maybe the rest of it is trivial in
comparison.
I know that's a rough thing because you
can be in very harsh circumstances,
but I do think there's something to that
and the Lord was with Joseph and he was
a prosperous man and he was in the house
of his master.
The Egyptian and his master saw that the
Lord was with him and the Lord made all
that he did to prosper in his hand.
So that's an echo of the idea that we
encountered earlier about walking with
God.
Right.
So Adam walked with God before he ate
the fruit with eve and then he wouldn't
walk with God and they had noah walked
with God and Abraham walked with God.
And so the idea is,
well,
that's that alignment with the highest
ideal.
I think it's something like that.
And you know,
we could think about that as a
metaphysical claim as well,
but I don't think it is.
I mean,
I've got thousands of letters now in the
last year from people who have told me
that they were in a pit.
That's exactly right,
and that they decided that they were
going to try to put their lives together
and that it worked,
and so that's really something,
you know,
and they write surprised.
It's like,
well,
I decided that I was going to work hard
at what I was doing and I wasn't going
to lie any more than absolutely
necessary.
I thought I'd give it a try for a few
months,
you know,
and all sorts of good things started to
happen.
To me,
it's like maybe that's how the world
works now.
Obviously it doesn't work like that all
the time.
Right.
Because you can get sliced off at the
knees.
I mean there's an arbitrary element to
existence that's that you can't wish
away,
but that doesn't mean that there are.
It doesn't mean that there aren't bad
strategies and good strategies and so I
do think that one of the most
fundamental existential questions is
like,
if things aren't going well for you in
your life is,
are you absolutely certain that you're
doing absolutely everything you can to
put things in order?
Because if you're not,
then you shouldn't complain because you
don't know to what degree you're
actually contributing or even causing
the circumstance.
Now,
that's a very annoying thing to think
and I'm not trying to blame the victim.
You know,
I know that people end up with lung
cancer because they were exposed to
asbestos,
you know,
I'm not trying to.
Although I also know too that if you
have lung cancer because you've been
exposed to asbestos,
that can be a tragedy or it can be hell.
And to some degree that depends on how
you conduct yourself.
So I mean,
I know that's pretty gloomy
possibilities,
right?
But so anyways,
so Joseph as a slave,
but it turns out that he's a,
he hasn't sacrifice the integrity of his
character.
And so it turns out that being it out,
that he's not asleep,
it's just that everyone around him
thinks he's a slave,
but he's not.
So that's pretty interesting.
He was a goodly person and well favored.
Well,
so he's a good guy and he's an
impressive specimen as well.
This is pretty interesting given the
current political climate,
I would say,
and it came to pass after these things
that his master's wife cast her eyes
upon Joseph and she said,
lie with me.
That means that actually has two
meanings,
right?
But he refused and said unto his
master's wife,
behold,
my master does not know what's with me
in the house and he's committed all that
he has to my hand.
There is no one greater in this house
than I.
Neither has he kept back anything from
me but you because you are his wife.
How then can I do this great wickedness,
wickedness,
and sin against God.
And it came to pass that she speak to
Joseph Day by day that he harkened not
unto her to lie by her or be with her
being sexually harassed.
Joseph,
and it came to pass.
Well,
it's,
it's right.
I mean,
look,
look at the painting and it came to pass
about this time that Joseph went into
the house to do his business and there
was none of the men of the house they're
within.
And she caught him by his garment saying
lie with me,
and he left his garment in her hand and
fled and got him out.
So that's kind of embarrassing for poor
Joseph,
I would say,
and a bit on the suspicious side.
And it came to pass when she saw that he
had left his garment in her hand and was
fled forth,
that she called unto the men of her
house and spake unto them,
see,
see he hath brought into Hebrew
democracy.
He came in unto me,
lie with me,
and I cried with a loud voice.
So what is it Hell hath no fury like a
woman scorned.
That's the proper commentary on that.
And it came to pass when he heard that,
I lifted up my voice and cried that he
left his garment with me and fled and
got himself out.
And it came to pass when his master
heard the words of his wife.
So that's the Faro,
which he spake unto him,
saying,
after this manner did thy servant to me,
his wrath was kindled.
And Joseph's master took him and put him
in prison.
A place where the king's prisoners were
was,
were bound and he was there in the
prison.
Well,
that sort of socks.
It's like first his brothers betray him
and throw him in a pit and then he gets
made a slave,
which is probably better than being in
the pit and then he becomes sort of like
king slave.
So that's working out pretty well and
now someone lies about him.
He gets betrayed again and now it's into
the prison with them and so it's this.
It's this again,
right?
It's the same thing.
It's sisyphus up with the Rock and then
down and its order,
chaos,
order chaos,
and then you have to think,
well,
are you the order?
Are you the chaos or you the thing
that's moving between them because
that's the right thing to be because
otherwise you're just ordering.
That's a really bad idea or you're just
chaos and that's a really bad idea.
You can be the thing that's dynamically
mediating between them and that's what
he's doing,
but the Lord was with Joseph and showed
him mercy and gave him favor in the
sight of the keeper of the prison.
That's no easy thing to do.
I would think,
you know,
it's like you're thrown in prison and
now the jailer likes you.
How exactly are you going to manage that
much good thing to think about because
you might think,
well,
if you are really in dire straits,
how is it that you should conduct
yourself so that you have the highest
probability of having things work out
and it's not saying,
well,
Joseph took over the thumb screw,
you know,
and started using that on the other
prisoners that that's not the indication
here at all.
It's that he's doing something.
He's acting like a person who isn't a
prisoner even though he's in the prison,
just like he was acting like someone who
wasn't a slave when he was a slave,
and so it makes you wonder who you can
be despite the fact that other people
think that you're whatever you appear to
be.
And the keeper of the prison committed
to Joseph's hand.
All the prisoners that were in the
prison and whatsoever they did there he
was the doer of it.
The keeper of the prison look not to
anything that was under his hand because
the Lord was with him and that which he
did.
The Lord made it to prosper.
So it's a repeat.
It's a repeat of exactly what happened
when he was the slave of the pharaoh,
except it's one rung deeper into hell,
so to speak.
Right?
So it's slave pharaoh,
adherence,
prisoner,
jail,
master.
But it doesn't matter.
The same thing happens.
So now Joseph has imprisoned and the
Pharaoh has a fit one day of peak and
throws the chief of his Butler's into
prison.
And the chief of his bakers and they
have a dream.
Each of them.
And,
uh,
Joseph interprets the dreams,
seems to be something that he can do.
And he tells the Butler that history
means that the fair was going to forgive
him and put him back in his position.
And he tells the baker that the Pharaoh
isn't going to forgive him and that he's
going to take off his head and hang them
in a tree,
which is rather rough dream.
But that is what,
that's what happens.
So anyways,
that the baker or the Butler goes free
and Joseph says,
look,
you know,
maybe you could just keep in mind the
fact that I did do a bit of a favor here
and told you something that was
accurate,
but the chief didn't really remember
once.
He.
Once he was freed interpreting dreams in
prison,
and so now the pharaoh has a dream and
he actually asked to dreams.
So it's another one of those doubled
motifs.
So the idea is these are really
important dreams because they came in a
pair and behold there came out of the
river seven well favored kind and fat
flesh.
So cattle and they fed in the meadow.
Meadow and behold,
seven other cattle came up after the
motor of the river ill favored and lean,
fleshed,
starving and stood by the other cows on
the brink of the river.
And the ill favored and lean fleshed
kind did eat up the seven well favored
and fat.
So feral it woke fair enough.
It's pretty nasty dream.
And then he has another dream to two
headed home and he slept and dreamt the
second time.
And behold,
seven years of corn came up upon one
stock rank and good and behold,
seven thin years and blasted with the
east wind sprung up after them and the
seventh thin yours devoured the seven
rank and full years and pharaoh woke and
beheld it was a dream and then it says a
little later and for that the dream was
doubled unto Pharaoh twice.
It is because the thing is established
by God and God will shortly bring it to
pass.
It's interesting because one of the
better theories about dreams is that
they're part of the way that the right
and left hemisphere communicate,
or maybe the nonverbal part of the brain
communicates with the verbal brand,
verbal part of the brain,
and so the nonverbal part of the brain
which is less differentiated and things
more globally,
is looking for patterns and anomalies in
the world.
Things that don't fit well with the
current way of conceptualizing the
world.
Things that make you anxious and
uncertain,
and those are things you haven't
mastered,
right?
So they don't fit well into your
conception of realization of the world
by definition.
Because if you had mastered them,
they wouldn't make you anxious,
nervous,
and so the the nonverbal parts of your
brain or like an alarm system,
they're looking around for places where
you're probably wrong and then they put
those in images and try to conceptualize
them so that you can update your model
of reality to take them into account,
but that also produces a fair bit of
negative emotion,
especially at night and so,
so we know that we know if you deprive
people of dreams that they go insane
very rapidly.
Animals as well,
necessary part of mental equilibrium.
The way you do that with rats in case
you want to know is that you've got rats
that you want to drive and saying this
is how you do it.
So you put the rat on a like a pedestal.
It's pretty small.
And then when he fall,
that's surrounded by water and then when
he falls asleep,
his nose hits the water.
Then he wakes up and so you can deprive
the route of sleep and that doesn't.
The rats don't respond to that very well
after some period of time.
So that's one of the ways that that's
been discovered,
but anyways,
the dream does seem to be an update
mechanism and so if,
if,
if you have a very powerful dream,
like a nightmare,
especially if it's repeating,
it's like something is trying to hammer
on the door that needs to be let in and
often you don't know how to let it in
and that's,
that's a problem.
So then Pharaoh sent and called Joseph
because he had talked to his,
his butler,
and they brought them hastily out of the
dungeon and Joseph shaved himself and
changed his clothes and came in unto
Pharaoh.
I guess he didn't want to shock pharaoh
with how people dressed in a prison.
And Pharaoh said Unto Joseph,
I've dreamed a dream and there's none
that can interpret it.
I've heard safety that you can
understand a dream to interpret it.
And Joseph said,
it's not me.
God will give Pharaoh announcer of
peace.
It's so Jacob isn't taking credit for
his ability to interpret dreams,
which also indicates quite
interestingly,
there's,
there's nothing to,
despite the fact that he's successful
and competent,
he's not narcissistic.
If he happens to have this gift,
he regards it as a gift and not as
something that you.
He renounced his favorites,
just something that he happens to be
able to do,
and so that's,
that's a hallmark of someone who's got a
pretty well put together personality as
far as I'm concerned because you know
people have gifts that they didn't
really earn.
Those will be your talents,
your intelligence,
your good looks if you happen to have
good looks,
etc.
And they're not.
There's no sense being All puffed up
about that because it's.
It's great.
It's luck of the draw though,
and the proper attitude is to note that
it's luck of the draw and to be grateful
for it.
It's quite a fine painting that one hold
there.
Come seven years of great,
plenty throughout the island of Egypt
and then there shall arise after seven
years of famine and all the plenti shall
be forgotten and the famine shall
consume the land and the plenty shall
not be known in the land by reason of
that famine following for it shall be
very grievous.
So now we see to that jacob.
Well,
he can interpret dreams,
but he's also the sort of person who can
look into the future and think this is
sort of what adam was called on to do
when he got kicked out of the garden of
paradise is you're going to be able to
conceptualize that even if things are
going well now that that doesn't mean
that they're going to go well into the
future.
And so he's The ant and the grasshopper,
right in the grasshopper and the ants
story.
It's like everything's good,
but you should wake the hell up and you
should test to see how things can go
wrong and you can see if your systems
can survive them.
Things going wrong and which is
something that I think we could all
harken tube because I think we do a very
bad job in the modern world of testing
to see if our systems can go wrong.
Okay.
So the pharaoh was pretty impressed by
this dream interpretation and pretty
worried about it and I guess he's a
reasonable person,
despite the fact that he put joseph in
jail,
uh,
gifts.
He didn't have much choice.
Now therefore,
let pharaoh look for a man discreet and
wise and set him over the land of Egypt.
Let pharaoh do this and let him appoint
officers over the land.
This is what joseph was saying,
and take up the fifth part of the land
of Egypt in the seven plenteous years
and let them gather all the food of
those good years that come and lay up
corn under the hand of pharaoh and let
them keep food in the cities
and just like that joseph has restored
to his position.
So pharaoh said unto joseph,
I am pharaoh,
and without these shall no man lifted up
his hand or foot in all of the land of
Egypt,
and so he comes out of the prison and he
really,
in some sense,
as far as I'm concerned,
he actually occupies a position that's
higher than the position of the pharaoh.
It depends on how you look at it because
the pharaoh is relegated himself to
ceremonial status,
right?
Joseph has all the responsibility,
makes all the decisions.
So defacto,
he's the pharaoh.
He doesn't get the glory precisely,
although he's not doing too bad for
himself.
Now there's a lesson in that too.
I wrote these rules for corp a long time
ago and one of them,
I have written them into this,
some of them into this book you guys got
a pamphlet about today.
One of the rules that I didn't write
about was,
um,
note that responsive it note that
opportunity lurks where responsibility
has been abdicated,
which is really interesting.
I think.
I mean,
I've seen people in their jobs,
they say things like,
well,
my guy worked with doesn't do any work.
It's like,
well,
you could do it.
I mean,
I know there's limits to that,
but one of their things you can do at
work is make yourself indispensable.
I mean,
you might get the cane types against you
if you do that,
but there's something to be said for
being indispensable because when people
start to be dispensed with you probably
won't be one of them.
Or even If you are,
then the fact that you're indispensable
just means you can go somewhere else and
be indispensable there.
Now it's just as useful.
So it's very,
very difficult to permanently put down
someone who's really good at doing
things because they can just go off and
do them somewhere else.
And one of the ways that you get like
that is to take responsibility when
someone else is failing to do so and you
think,
well,
I shouldn't have to do that.
That's one way of thinking about it.
Another way of thinking about it is,
oh good,
I get to do that.
And the seven years of plenty isness
that was in the land of Egypt were ended
in the seven years of dearth began to
come according as joseph has said.
And the dearth was in all the lands.
Well,
that's an archetypal story,
right?
The archetypal story.
It's the business cycle story.
It's a little harsher when you're
starving,
obviously,
but that's not the point.
The point is,
is that sometimes things are getting
good and sometimes things are getting
bad and that's you can be sure that
that's the case that's going to happen
to you.
And so the wise person takes stock of
the fact that things are going to get
bad.
Is this is the same thing that happens
with noah?
It's like assume the flood because it's
going to happen and you think,
well,
it's a hell of a world that has floods.
It's not if you have a boat,
right?
It helps a lot.
If if there's a flood and you have a
boat,
it's like you can float on the flood and
then it's not such a problem,
and so if you refuse to look out the
fact that things are going to be going
downhill badly and that you're going to
be in a pit at some point,
you and your family perhaps then when it
happens,
it will be as bad as it possibly can be,
but if you're awake and alert to that
possibility,
then you can mitigate it.
And the dearth was in all the lands.
But in the land of Egypt there was bread
and when the land of Egypt was famished,
the people cried to pharaoh for bread
and pharaoh said unto the egyptians,
go to joseph.
What?
He says to you too,
do you do that?
And the fireman was all over the face of
the earth.
And joe boo,
joseph opened up the store houses and
sold to the egyptians,
and the feminine waxed sore in the land
of Egypt and all the countries came into
Egypt to buy to joseph to buy corn
because the famine was soaring all the
lands.
Now,
when jacob saw that there was corn in
Egypt,
jacob said unto his sons,
why are you standing around looking at
each other?
He said,
I've heard that there's corn in Egypt.
Get down there and I from a buyer for us
so that we may live and not die.
It's pretty straightforward advice that.
And joseph's 10 brothers went down to
buy corn in Egypt,
but benjamin,
joseph's brother.
So that's the youngest one,
right?
The only one left.
That's the one that was younger than
joseph.
The only youngest one,
and also rachel's other son.
But Jeff Benjamin,
joseph's brother jacob didn't send
because he was worried that something
bad would happen to him,
which kind of indicates to me that maybe
jacob was a bit suspicious about what
had happened to joseph the last time he
sent all the brothers on a adventure.
Joseph was the governor over all the
land and and he,
It was that sold to all the people of
the land in joseph's brothers came and
bowed down themselves before him with
their faces to the earth.
While there's the dream.
Now the thing is too,
is that one question you have in your
life is who should you bow down to?
And you might say no one,
but that's not exactly the right answer
because that means that you don't have
an ideal because you bow down to your
ideal.
That's what makes it an ideal.
And if you don't have an ideal,
then what the hell are you going to do?
So you have to bow down to something.
And so what happens here as well,
the brothers are bowing down to the
person who is so bloody resilient and
competent that they can take themselves
out of a prison and become the ruler of
the land that happened to vaclav havel,
right in czechoslovakia.
It also happened to,
um,
mandela,
South Africa,
like these things actually happened.
It's really something.
So you'd,
god only knows what you might learn in
prison.
So,
so they bow down to joseph and properly
so you know he's,
he is even without his coat,
he's still the person with a coat of
many colors and joseph saw his brothers
and he knew them,
but he made themselves strange onto
them.
It's a number of years have passed and
he spoke roughly onto the mini,
said down to them,
where do you Come from?
And they said,
from the land of canaan to buy food.
And joseph knew whose brothers were but
they didn't know who he was
and they came back to jacob their father
and told him all that and said,
the man who is lord of the country spoke
roughly to us and took us for spies.
And we said to him,
we're,
we're true,
man.
Honest man were not spies.
We be 12 brothers,
sons of our fathers.
One is not.
And the youngest is this day with our
father in the land of canaan.
And the man said,
here's how I'll know that you're honest,
man.
Leave one of the brothers here with me
and take some food for the famine of
your households and be gone.
And then bring your youngest brother to
me.
Then I'll know that you're not spies,
but that you're honest,
man,
and I'll deliver the other brother and
you shall trade in the lounge so you
don't have to starve to death.
And it came to pass as they emptied
their sacks that behold every man's
bundle of money in his sock.
And when both say in their fathers,
saw the bundles of money,
they were afraid.
So they had bought food from joseph and
he gave them the food and then he put
all their money back in their socks,
which I can imagine would worry them to
some degree.
and jacob said,
me,
you have already bereaved of my
childrEn.
Joseph is not as is.
Not now.
You'll take benjamin,
benjamin away.
All these things are against me.
And ruben spake unto his father,
saying,
slay my two sons.
If I bring him not to the,
deliver them into my hand and I will
bring them to the again
and he.
And he said,
nope.
My son shall not go down with you for
his brother is dead.
And he's left alone.
If mischief befall him by the way in
which you shall go,
then you shall bring down my greer or
gray hairs with sorrow to the grave.
Now there's a hand.
See what happens in the last part of the
jacob storage.
The joseph story is,
and this is associated with the idea of
putting your house in order your
individual house in order,
and then putting your family's house in
order.
Let's say it's reversed a little bit,
this story because joseph puts himself
together and then he puts the state of
of Egypt in order,
which is really quite interesting
because Egypt is the canonical tyranny
right in the old testament.
And so the idea is very,
very clear here that the person who
wears the coat of many colors can put
the tyranny right,
and then the next extension as well,
he has to put his family right now.
You know,
generally the progression would be put
yourself right.
Then put your family right,
then put the state right,
something like that.
It doesn't really.
If you can do it in a different order,
that's probably okay too.
But so,
so that's what happens at the end of the
story is that,
you know,
joseph is doing pretty damn well and so
is the state that he serves,
but that isn't good enough for him.
He wants his family to be functional and
put together properly even though they
did terrible things to him.
And that's very interesting because once
someone does terrible things to you,
then the logical thing or a logical
thing to think as well go to hell in a
hand basket.
You know,
like you,
you deserve exactly what you get,
but
it's not a very productive attitude,
especially if you're around people that
you have to be around,
you know.
So like if it's your family and you go
have a family dinner and one of you
punches the other and then the other
punches you back,
and then that's like the family dinner
for the next 30 years.
It doesn't seem to be very productive.
Even if you're the person who happened
to get into the last blow because you're
going to have to put up with them at
minimum.
It might be nice to just let what you
can go go and work to make towards
making things better.
You have to get rid of the idea of
revenge and resentment and all those
things that you carry along,
but,
but it's probably better to think about
how your family could be if it was
really functioning well and then just
aim unerringly of that.
I know that's not easy.
I mean people are very screwy and
there's no end to the depths of
pathology within families,
but of course this story states that
very clearly.
I mean they tried to kill them.
They sold him into slavery.
It's,
it's a pathological family,
let's put it that way.
And,
but joseph's attitude is,
well,
we got to set this right,
not least because of his father,
but it isn't only because of his father.
As you see,
as the story unfolds and the famine was
sore in the land and it came to pass
when they had eaten up the court in
which they had brought out of Egypt,
their father said unto them,
go again and bias a little food.
And judah spake unto him,
saying,
the man did solidly protest on you,
not you will not see my face except your
brother be with you.
They can't go back to Egypt without
benjamin.
And they said,
the man asked is straightly of our eight
other kindred saying,
is your father yet alive?
Have you another brother?
And we told them according to the tenor
of those words,
could we know that he would say,
bring your brother down?
and judas said unto Israel,
his father,
send the lab with me and will arise and
go,
that we may live and not die.
Both we and vowel and also our little
ones,
I will be surety for him.
My hand shell,
they'll require him if I bring them onto
the inset them before the lesson.
Let me bear the blame forever.
Well,
so judah who played a pretty dismal role
in the original selling joseph into
seems to obviously have learned
something by this point since he's
willing to put himself on the line,
you know,
to take responsibility for the situation
and to put himself on the line and to
stand in for benjamin.
So he's making himself into a
sacrificial object of sorts,
and so the game that joseph's playing,
because he sort of teasing his brothers,
but he's also testing them.
The game that he's playing is twofold.
One is have you bloody well learned
anything or are you just as corrupt and
useless as you were before?
That's game number one.
Then game number two is maybe if I poke
and prod you and put you into a
relatively difficult and mysterious
situation,
I can get you to clue the hell in and
adopt some responsibility and we can
move this whole mess forward.
And so that seems to be happening.
So judah is taking responsibility.
And ruben did that as well and the men
took presence and they took double money
in their hand and Benjamin Rose up and
went down to Egypt and stood before
joseph.
When joseph saw benjamin with them,
he said to the ruler of his house,
bring these men home and slay and make
ready food for these men shall dine with
me at noon.
And the men mandate is joseph bade in
the man brought them in into joseph's
house.
And when joseph came home,
they brought them the presence which was
in their hand and bowed themselves again
to him,
to the earth,
and he asked them of their welfare and
said,
is your father well,
the old man of whom you speak is whom he
spake as a yet alive.
And they answered thy servant,
our father is in good health.
He's yet alive.
And they bow down their heads and made
obeisance.
And he lifted up his eyes and saw his
brother benjamin,
his mother's son,
and said,
is this your younger brother,
of whom you speak unto me?
And he said,
god,
be gracious unto thee.
My son and joseph made haste for his
bowels,
did urine upon his brother,
and he sought were to weep.
And he entered into his chamber and wept
there.
And he washed his face and went out and
reframed himself and said,
set on the bread.
And they sat before them.
Now he plays another trick on his
brother.
So he has them all sit at the table,
but he lines them up according to age.
And so he started to.
What is he trying to do?
Sort of freaked them out fundamentally
and so at an imanage is that because
they have no idea how in the world they
could possibly he could possibly pull
something like that or if they think
it's magic and the men marveled at one
another and he took and sent messages
unto them from before him,
but benjamin's mess was five times as
much as any of theirs.
So what's he doing?
Well,
he's testing his brothers again.
The fact that when he was the child
joseph,
that he got more meant that his brothers
got terribly Jealous and then murderous.
Right?
And so now he's doing the same thing
with benjamin.
He's thinking,
okay,
well I'll give this kid more than his
share and a watch how these reprobates
and see if they've learned anything and
so and he commanded the steward of his
house saying,
fill the men sock with food as much as
they can carry and put every man's money
in the sock as well.
And put my cup,
the silver cup in the sax mouth of the
youngest and his corn money.
And the steWard did according to the
word that joseph had spoken.
As soon as the morning was light,
the men were sent away along with their
transportation.
The big cup is found in benjamin sack.
Well,
so benjamin's kinda young.
And
joseph sends out people to find out
where the company's going and they find
it in benjamin's,
in benjamin sock.
And they're very upset about this.
They said that a harsh punishment would
be fall.
Whoever had the cop in his sack,
they rent their clothes and late at
every man his ass and returned to this
city and judah and his brothers came to
joseph's house for he was out there and
they fell before I'm on the ground,
very unhappy and apologetic.
And joseph said unto them,
what need is this that you have done?
I don't you know that a man like I can
certainly divine.
I know what's going on.
And she would've said,
what shall we say?
What shall we speak?
Or how could we possibly clear
ourselves?
God found out the iniquity of thy
servants.
Behold we are your servants,
both we and also he with whom the cup is
found and he said,
god forbid that I should do so,
but the man in whose cup and whose hand
the companies found he shall be my
servant.
And as for you,
get you up in peace to your father.
It's the discovery of the cup.
Judah says,
now,
therefore,
when I come to this servant,
my father,
my father and the loud be not with us
and seeing that his life is bound up in
the clouds.
Life.
It shall come to pass.
When he sees that the loud is not with
us,
that he will die and the servant shall
bring down the gray hairs of thy
servant.
Our father with sorrow to the grave,
for thy servant became security for the
latin to my father saying,
if I bring him not unto thee,
then I shall bear the blame too.
My father forever.
Now therefore I pray thee.
Let me stay instead of the lab and let
the lord go with his brothers for how
shall I go up to my brother and allowed
to be not with me.
Let's pair adventure.
I shall see the evil that will come on
my father.
Okay,
so what's happened?
Well,
they learned their lesson.
So now judah again is willing to stand
in the place of benjamin and become a
slave himself.
And so now joseph has determined that
his brothers have developed their
character to the point where
reconciliation might be possible.
You know,
it says you should forgive and forget,
but the conditions for that are quite,
are quite specific.
You know,
if you're,
if you have a dispute with someone,
they've wronged you in some sense and
they apologize.
The question is,
well,
what's the apology?
Well,
it's a layout of a rationale.
It's something like,
as far as I can tell,
here's the reasons I did this horrible
thing and here's what I've learned from
it and here's what I'm going to do to
try not to do it again.
And would you give me another crack at
it?
That's the proper repentance,
right?
And then you forgive because you're an
idiot too,
and you'll probably do something stupid
and maybe you'd like the same kind of
break at some point.
And and besides,
if we all held each other completely to
Account at all possible times for
everything,
then it just be hopeless because there'd
be no room for error.
So if forgiveness,
which joseph is showing is why is
forgiveness,
he's not going to put himself out on the
line for people who haven't learned so
that the same stupid thing can happen
again so that they can continue to
spread misery wherever they go.
He's going to find out if they've clued
in a little bit and then if so,
then they can move on with putting a
family together.
And so that breaks them up.
He says,
joseph could not refrain.
Refrain himself before all of them that
stood by him and he cried.
And then he said,
get every man away from me.
So all the people except for joseph's
brother left and there stood no man with
him while joseph made himself known unto
his brothers.
Joseph said,
I'm joseph is my father is still alive.
And his brothers could not answer for
they were troubled at his presence.
It's like,
yeah,
understatement of the decade there.
And joseph said unto his brothers,
come near to me.
I pray you.
And they came near and he said,
I am joseph,
your brother,
whom you sold into Egypt,
but don't be grieved or angry with
yourself that you sold me hither for god
did send me before you to preserve life.
So now it was not you that sent me here
but god,
and he's made me a father to pharaoh and
lord of all his house in a ruler
throughout all the land of Egypt.
Hurry and go to my father and say unto
him,
thus say they son joseph,
god has made me lord of all Egypt.
Come down onto me and terry naught and
thou shall dwell in the land of goshen
and now shall be near unto me,
thou and thy children and their
children's children and their flocks and
herds and all that thou hast.
And either I will nourish you for yet
there are five years of famine,
less dow and I household and all that.
Thou has come to poverty,
so that's the other thing that another
bit of a hint that the bread hint here,
who's the what's the most reliable
source of bread?
Well,
it isn't bread itself.
It's whatever it is that gives rise to
bread and what joseph is in this story.
He's the force that gives ride rise to
nourishment.
That's an joseph is often considered a
type of christ,
which means like a precursor in some
sense that's.
That's one way of thinking about it and
you can see that echoed right there.
It's like,
well,
what do you store up for?
Famine.
You store up character.
That's the best way through.
Now that doesn't mean you don't also
store up bread and they went out of
egyPt and came into the land of canaan
unto jacob and told him joseph is still
alive and he's governor and jacob's
heart fainted for he didn't believe them
and they told him all the words of
joseph,
which he said to them,
and when he saw the wagons,
which joseph had sent to carry him,
the spirit of jacob,
their father revived and Israel said,
it has enough.
Joseph,
my son is he had live.
I will go and see him before I die,
and Israel took his journey with all
that he had and came to beersheba and
offered sacrifices unto the god of his
father,
isaac and god spake unto Israel in the
visions of the night and said,
jacob,
and he said,
here am I.
He said,
I am god,
the god of my father.
Don't fear to go to each down into Egypt
for I will make you a great nation
there.
And so that's how the israelites ended
up in Egypt.
I will go down with the into Egypt and I
will also surely bring the up again and
jacob shall put his hand upon his dies
and Jacob Rose up from beersheba and the
sons of Israel carry jacob their father
and the little ones and their wives in
the wagons which pharaoh had sent to
carry.
So the families now all united in the
proper state of being that joseph has
raged and they took their cattle and
their goods.
It's so interesting too because of
course joseph isn't even.
He's a foreigner as well as being a
former slave and prisoner,
foreigner,
slave and prisoner,
and yet he ends up ruling Egypt sheer
sheerly because of the force of his
character and competence and that's
really something to think about and they
took their cattle because that story
there is that there isn't anything
stronger than that.
Doesn't matter what the circumstances
are that there isn't a forest that's
more powerful not,
and I don't think that that's naive.
In fact,
I think it's the exact opposite of
naive.
No matter where you are,
you can generally make things better if
that's what you want to do and unless
you're in some place that's really hell
itself,
not usually is something that elevates
you and elevates the people around you
and you can do that wherever you are
because there isn't a place that's so
small that you can't do that.
That's the message of the prison and
they took their cattle and their goods,
which they had gotten in the land of
canaan and came into Egypt.
Jacob and all his seed with him and he
sent judah before a month to joseph to
direct his face onto gosh,
and then they came into the land of
goshen and joseph made ready his chariot
and went to meet Israel,
his father and presented himself to them
and fell on his neck and wept on his
neck.
A good while and Israel said,
I can now die because I've seen your
face because you're still alive,
and pharaoh spake unto joseph saying
that father and thy brethren,
they're coming to the land of Egypt is
before the in the best of the land.
Your father and brothers can dwell in
the land of gosh and let them do well,
and if the now know any men of activity
among them,
then make them rulers over my cattle.
It gives them a job.
And joseph brought in jacob his father
and set up before pharaoh and jacob
blessed pharaoh.
That's a very interesting little turn of
events because you'd expect the opposite
under those circumstances.
So it appears that jacob was a man of
relatively great self-possession because
that's not a.
You wouldn't blast queen elizabeth.
In all likelihood,
as you had a lot of gall and pharaoh
said unto jacob,
how old are you?
And jacob said,
I'm 130 years.
Few and evil have been the days of the
years of my life and I've not attained
into the days of the years of my life,
of my father's,
in the days of their pilgrimage.
And jacob blessed pharaoh and went out
from before pharaoh and the Israel dwelt
in the land of Egypt,
in the country of gosh,
and and grew and multiplied exceedingly.
And jacob lived in the land of Egypt.
Seventeen years.
So the whole age of jacob was 147 years.
And the time drew nigh that Israel must
die.
And he called his son.
Joseph said unto him,
if I have now found grace in thy sight,
put I pray thee thy hand under my thigh
and deal kindly and truly with me,
bury me.
Not I pray thee in Egypt,
but I will lie with my father's.
now shall carry me out of Egypt and
burnaby.
And they're burying place.
And joseph said,
I will do,
as you've said.
And it came to pass after these things
that one told joseph,
behold I father is sick,
and he took with him his two sons,
madison ephram and one told jacob and
said,
behold thy son,
and one told jacob and said,
joseph cometh unto thee,
and Israel strengthened himself and sat
upon the bed.
And he Israel said unto joseph,
I'd not thought to see your face and
low.
god has also showed me your children.
And joseph brought them out from between
his knees and out himself with his face
to the earth.
And joseph took them both a in his right
hand towards israel's lefthand and
madison is lefthand toward Israel,
his right hand and brought them near
unto him.
And Israel stretched out his right hand
and laid it upon eh firms had who was
the younger and his left upon madness's
had guiding his hands purposefully for
madison was the first born.
And when joseph saw that his father laid
his right hand on the head of ephraim,
it displeased him.
And he held up his father's hand to
remove it from him.
Firms had under my head and joseph said
unto his father,
not,
not so my father for this is the first
board put the right hand upon his head,
head at his father,
refused and said,
I know it my son.
I know it.
he shall also be my people and he shall
also be great,
but truly his younger brother shall be
greater than he and his seed shall
become a multitude of nations.
Another repeat of the same thing that
happens continually.
It's.
It's when,
when god wants to intervene in human
affairs,
what he does is invert tradition at
something like that,
and so that's a sign that there's
something new and special going on and
that gives precedence to the younger
child rather than the older child
precedent to what is new rather than
what's traditional.
Of course,
sometimes that's necessary because
tradition is insufficient and sometimes
something new has to come into being in
order to update it.
And jacob called together his sons and
said,
gathered together so that I can tell you
that which shall befall you in the last
days,
gather yourself together and here you
sons of jacob and hearkened unto Israel
your father,
ruben.
I'm not going to go through all 12 of
these rubin,
thou art,
my firstborn,
my might,
and the beginning of my strength,
the excellency of dignity and the
excellency of power.
Now the story's quite interesting here
because jacob blesses joseph's sons
before he blesses his own sons,
and so what he's doing is placing the
rights of the firstborn into the sons of
his favorite son.
And then he goes to his sons.
And so that has implications for the way
the biblical stories laid themselves out
from thence forward the excellent of
dignity in the excellency of power,
unstable as water.
Thou shalt not excel because that went
has stopped to thy father's bed.
Then defiled it.
He went up to my couch.
You may remember that ruben slept with
his fathers,
cucumber,
ca,
concubine.
Simeon and levi are brethren.
Instruments of cruelty are in their
habitations.
So that painting there,
what happened with simeon and levi was
that somebody lay with her sister diana,
and then offered to marry her and then
had and then became circumcised because
that was part of the deal and then how
to older men circumcised.
And then simeon and levi went in when
they were recovering and killed them
all.
And then jacob and all his people had to
leave because all that irritated their
relatives.
So see me.
Simeon and levi are brethren,
instruments of cruelty or in their
habitations oh my soul.
Come out now into their secret.
Until their assembly might honor,
be not thou united.
For in their anger they slew a man and
in their self self will they dig down a
wall,
cursed be their anger,
for it was fierce and their route for it
was cruel.
I will divide them in jacob and
scattered them in Israel.
Judah,
thou art,
he who?
My brethren shall praise thy hand shall
be in the neck of dynamics that father's
children shall bow down before the judah
is alliance help from the prey.
My son art gone up.
He stooped down.
He couched as a lion and as an old lion
who shall rosa bump the sceptre shall
not depart from judah,
nor a law giver from between his feet
until shiloh come and unto him shall the
gathering of the people be joseph is a
fruitful bough,
even a fruitful bough by a well whose
branches run over the wall.
The archers have sorely grieved him and
shot at him and hated him,
but his bowl abode in strength and the
arms of his hands were made strong by
the hands of the mighty god of jacob.
For then since the shepherd,
the stone of Israel,
even by the god of my father who shall
help the and by the almighty who shall
bless thee with the blessings of heavens
above blessings of the deep that a
thunder blessings of the beasts.
Breasts in the womb,
the blessings of your father have
prevailed above the blessings of my
progenitors unto the utmost bound of the
everlasting health.
They shall be on the head of joseph and
on the crown of the head of him that was
separate from his brother and all.
These are the 12 tribes of Israel.
And this is it that they're farther
spake unto them and blessed them.
Everyone according to his blessing,
he blessed them so that what we see here
is an echo in some sense of what happens
in the mesopotamian creation story.
When the mesopotamian creation story is
the dragon of chaos tie matt and her
consort appsu freshwater and saltwater
respectively in they're mingled
together.
and,
and that combination of chaos and order,
it gives rise to the first assembly of
the ancient gods.
And then the ancient gods kill appsu
casually and foolishly and enraged,
tie a mat with their foolishness and
ignorance.
And she comes back with a vengeance in
the meantime.
And then she produces this huge army of
monsters and puts king knew the worst of
the monsters out its head and that
decides she's going to take out her
creation.
And so that's a little warning from 3000
years ago about foolishly undermining
your tradition.
so anyways,
the gods in their friends and go out and
try to fight against high mountain.
They come back with their tails between
their legs continually.
But then a new god appears on the scene.
And that's marduk and he's got eyes all
the way around his head and he can speak
words of magic and they know that
there's something new about this newest
god.
It's his capacity for vision in this
capacity for articulate speech.
And so they say,
well,
why don't you go out and try to deal
with the chaos?
And mark says,
yeah,
okay,
no problem,
but here's the deal.
You elect me,
top god,
and now I determine the destiny of the
world.
And so they're desperate because like
thai,
matt is coming to get them.
That's chaos with the worst of all
possible bonsers.
They're probably thinking he's not going
to win anyways.
And so they agree and how he goes and he
confronts timeout.
He was the goddess of chaos and he cuts
her into pieces and he makes the world
out of her pieces.
And one of his names is he who makes
ingenious things out of the combat with
tire math,
which is so interesting.
That's such a remarkable.
That's a remarkable bit of nomenclature.
So who's should be at the pinnacle,
the forest that sees and speaks and goes
out to confront chaos voluntarily.
You know how many years it took people
to figure that out.
That's like the pinnacle discovery of
humanity.
That's what that is.
And it's echoed here.
You know,
you see simeon and levi are too angry.
The other brothers,
they all have flaws and faults of
various sorts and so they're not
elevated to the highest place,
but joseph,
because he has his coat of many colors
and because he lands on his feet,
no matter where he goes and because he's
not resentful and bitter and malevolent
and genocidal and,
and he's not shaking his fist at the sky
or yelling at god because of trump,
let's say.
Then he's the,
he's the right,
he's the right representative of the 12
tribes.
And so that's brilliant.
It's a brilliant story.
All these are the 12 tribes of Israel
and this is it that their father spake
unto them and blessed them.
Everyone according To his blessing,
he blessed them when jacob had made an
end of commanding his son.
So it's the last thing he does to state.
He knows that these are the 12 tribes
that will progress into the future of
this people and now he's trying it.
The last thing he does is to try to
hierarchically organize their relative
virtues as an indication of what has
been learned and when jacob has made an
end of commanding his sons,
he gathered up his feet into the bed and
yielded up the ghost and was gathered
unto his people.
And joseph fell upon his father's face
and wept upon him and kissed him.
And joseph commanded his servants to the
physicians to embalm his father and the
physicians embalmed Israel.
When the days of his morning we're past
joseph's spake unto the house of pharaoh
sayIng,
if now I have found grace in your eyes
speak,
I pray you in the ears of pharaoh
saying,
my father made me swear of saying low.
I die in my grave,
which I have digged for me in the land
of canaan.
There shalt thou burry me now,
therefore,
let me go up.
I pray thee and bury my father and I
will come again.
And pharaoh said,
go up and bury thy father according as
he made these swear for his son's,
carried them into the land of canaan and
bury them in the cave of the field of
mac pella,
which abraham bought with the field for
a possession of,
of burying place of effort on the
hittite before mammary and joseph
returned into Egypt.
He and his brother and all that went up
to him and that all and all that went up
with him to bury his father after he is
brewed,
after he had buried his father.
And when joseph's brethren saw that
their father was dead,
they said,
joseph will now hate us and will
certainly pay back to us all the evil
which we did unto him.
And they sent a messenger saying,
my father did command before he died,
saying four shall say unto joseph,
forgive I pray thee now the trespass of
thy brethren and their sin pretty
sniffily.
Really for tHey did unto thee evil.
and now we pray thee.
Forgive the trespass of the servants of
the god of thy father.
And joseph wept when they spake unto
him,
and his brethren also went and fell down
before his face and they said,
behold,
we be thy servants.
And joseph said unto them,
fear not for am I in the place of god,
but as for you,
you thought evil against me,
but god meant it unto good to bring,
to pass,
as it is this day,
to save much people alive.
Now,
therefore fear not I will nourish you
and your little ones.
And he comforted them and spake kIndly
unto them.
So the the idea there is that there is
no evil,
so evil that good cannot triumph over
it.
And joseph dwelt in Egypt.
He and his father's house and joseph
lived 110 years.
And joseph saw frms children of the
third generation.
The children also have makir the son of
menace that were brought up upon
joseph's knees.
And joseph said unto his brethren,
I die and god will surely visit you and
bring you out of this land unto the land
where he swore to abraham,
to isaac and jacob and joseph took an
oath of the children of Israel saying,
god will surely visit you and she'll end
you shall carry my bones from hence.
So joseph died being 110 years old and
they embalmed him and he was put into a
coffin in Egypt.
And that's genesis.
So
thank you.
So thank you all for persevering.
Thank you.
This has been very worthwhile.
As far as I'm concerned,
I learned an awful lot and so I'm very
much looking forward to continuing it
and thank you all very much for your
support and your rapt attention and your
seriousness in this endeavor and your
care and all of that.
It's really been a privilege to be able
to do this.
It's a completely surreal thing to
manage.
And uh,
so far,
you know,
I think about 5 million people have
watched it.
So that's seems to be a very good thing.
So
thank you.
I'm going to ask the question,
if you've asked a question in the last
three sessions,
please don't ask a question today
because I never get through everyone and
so I'd like to have some questions from
people that I haven't answered questions
from before,
if that's okay.
I professor peterson,
just a two second.
Thank you very much for my community and
the jewish community.
So many people who have been inspired by
you to be better people and I wouldn't
be able to speak to without saying that.
So thank you very much.
A couple of things.
The first thing I wanted to do is make a
quick comment that you might find
interesting that in the jewish
astrological calendar,
um,
we read the yearly cycle of the five
books of moses and it just so happens
that we are reading this,
a part of the,
of the twitter story that very
interesting.
that's cool.
And synchronistic,
which brings me into a question that I
wanted to ask you about,
which is one question with two parts
about your knowledge of,
of,
of hebrew,
um,
because if you look at the torah scrolls
that you find in a synagogue,
there are no vowels,
there are no sentences.
There.
It is a,
it is chaos,
chaos and order is trying to be bought
into it.
I'm wondering how knowledge of you
knowledgeable are you of the hebrew
which has many layers of,
of,
of dimensional,
staggeringly ignorant of it.
So,
you know,
I,
I read a lot of commentaries,
right?
I'm trying to zero in on the,
like with each of the phrases that we
went through today,
I probably looked at 10 different
commentaries and so,
and then I have this underlying
psychoanalytic knowledge that it's sort
of like if you have a bunch of different
templates to look at things through and
then something shines through all those
templates at the same time,
that's very unlikely.
And sO then you can know a coincidence
is one thing,
but five coincidence is that's no longer
a coincidence.
That's something else.
And so I think I'm hoping that despite
the fact that there's many,
many things that I don't know that
there's enough things that I do know to
kind of weave my way through this with
some degree of utility,
if not certainty.
Yeah.
BecauSe I just was just the second part,
which I guess maybe you don't know that
the,
the jewish oral stories that date back
almost as long as these stories which
fill in a lot of mindblowingly crazy
random and so many details about these
stories.
And I was just wondering if you had
encountered any of them before.
I've encountered some of them,
but again,
it's a,
it's well as you know,
it's a very,
very rich tradition.
And so I haven't encountered enough of
it.
Were you thinking of anything in
sPecific specifically in relationship to
this story?
Not in particular.
I actually forgot it.
I was,
I was intending to bring you a,
a book of majestic store.
That's a hell of a thing to say now.
Well,
it just,
I dunno,
I,
I felt like I had to say that.
Um,
but yeah,
maybe for the exodus version I'll bring
you back.
All right.
That would be good.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hi,
Dr.
Peterson,
I would just like to ask you to please
talk about what you called a psychic
death,
also known as an ego death.
Okay.
Sorry.
Say that again.
Would you please talk about what young
refer to as a psychic death also called
an ego death.
That's what happens when someone who
loves you betrays you.
Right?
So imagine that.
Like the world is complicated beyond
comprehension,
right?
When you only see a very little bit of
it and the way you structured your
understanding is you make assumptions
about things and they're simplifying
assumptions.
So if you trust someone,
you reduce their complexity massively,
right?
Because like,
let's say we were married,
then there's a whole bunch of ways that
you're going to act that are going to be
simpler.
Okay.
So then I can tolerate being around you
in some sense because you're not
everything at once.
Now those simplifying structures are
hierarchically assembled and some of
them are far more important than others.
Trust is one of them,
especially trust in loved ones,
family members,
which is why I'd be trailed by a family
member,
is really catastrophic because it
destabilizes your past,
right?
All the memories you have,
it destabilizes your present.
It destabilizes your future is shakes
your faith in human beings including
yourself and everything collapses and
that's an ego death and so now
underneath the ego as far as young was
concerned,
was another structure that he called the
self and the self is this thing that
remains constant across ego deaths,
but it's.
It's deeper and less personal.
It's architectural and it's the thing
that the eagle collapses into when it
collapses and then rebuIlds the ego,
something like that across time,
but that's when an ego death is now.
There's variants of that because you can
have a voluntary or involuntary ego
death and a voluntary ego.
Death is when you learn a bunch and
you're willing to let go,
so that would be your own emulation.
It's like your lighting,
your,
your a phoenix,
and your lighting yourself on fire.
That's a much better idea even though it
can still be really harsh.
The involuntary ego deaths,
they're really hard on people.
People will do almost anything to stop
that from happening,
which is partly,
they fight to maintain their group
fostered axiomatic simplifications.
It's not surprising because it's very.
You lose your like that ego death is a
journey into the underworld or it's a
collapse into chaos.
And that's not so bad if you do it
purposefully.
But in the pinocchio story,
for example,
that's exemplified by pinocchio going
down to the depths to rescue his father
from the whale.
Now he does that voluntarily,
but it damn near killed him right in.
First of all,
he hardly gets out of the whale.
Second,
he actually drowns in dies,
but he comes back to life.
So even if you do it voluntarily,
it's still well think it's just better
than doing it in voluntarily,
which is the other alternative.
So that's what it is.
You bet.
Hello,
Dr.
Peterson.
Uh,
so I've been listening to bach to all of
these biblical lectures for the second
time now.
and um,
I wanted to show you an observation I
came upon because I was trying to find a
question that you haven't been asked
before,
which is harder than doing my ryerson
exams,
that's for sure.
So,
so I've noticed,
I think you're getting funnier.
Oh yes.
Oh no.
I think michael koren said that this
week I think.
But the word he used was bizarre.
I think actually I'm feeling better,
so that's,
I actually have a sense of humor.
It's,
it's hard to believe that.
So it sort of comes back when I'm not
feeling like I'm going to die at any
moment.
So yeah,
I basically noticed one,
you're making more attempts at jokes,
so that's great.
Oh,
thank you.
thank you to those Jokes are landing
more often.
But then there's this third element
which I think was what steve martin quit
because of,
which is that I think the audience is
anticipating jokes more and they're
actually,
you know,
I've noticed people laughing more at
things that aren't intending to be
jokes.
So I was just wondering what you make of
that and um,
their intended.
I'm hoping they're intended,
just because I keep a straight face
doesn't mean they're not intended to be
jokes,
so yeah,
no,
it's good.
look,
one of the things is like it's,
and I've tried to keep this,
I learned a while ago,
probably about five years ago,
that even when you're dealing with
really serious matters that if you're
not handling it with a light touch,
you're not an expert at it.
You're not a master at it,
and you'd think while there are some
things that are so deep and dark that
you can't handle it with a light touch,
and that's actually not true.
You can.
That doesn't mean you make light of
them.
It doesn't mean anything like that.
It's tHat you don't.
It's minimal necessary force,
something like that.
You don't hit it any harder than you
have to,
and it's a.
It's an art when you're discussing
serious matters and so
well,
one of the upshots of that is that
because we're discussing serious matters
and serious matters are being discussed
in the ultra large right now,
it would be really good if everybody
could keep their sense of humor.
You know,
when I see positive signs of that,
like there's a lot of satirical activity
on the net,
you know,
and that could easily catalyze into
horror mob,
but it isn't,
it is,
you know that that's happening to some
degree,
but a lot of it's satire and comedy and
as long as we can keep a sense of humor
about this,
then I think,
well we're not as close to disaster as
we might be.
ANd so one,
one of the things that I have found
rather ominous is that there are
comedians,
first of all,
being persecuted for under free speech
restriction legislation,
which I think is absolutely appalling.
But also that there were comedians now
who won't perform on university
campuses.
John cleese won't seinfeld.
That's like,
well,
you know how offensive he is.
It's no wonder that.
I mean he's like the straightest nicest
comedian you could Possibly imagine.
he won't perform on college campuses.
I think louis ck won't perform an or or
anywhere else,
but it's a bad sign.
But no humor.
Humor is good.
And it's interesting because I've been
kind of watching how I'm represented on
the web weirdly enough,
and there's all these memes that have
emerged,
I don't know,
thousands of the bloody things and most
of them are comical and that's good.
Like people are,
are,
are there,
whatever it is that they're doing,
I don't know what the hell it is,
but it's being done with a relatively
light touch and that's really,
really good.
that's how it should be.
You got to have a sense of humor.
I mean,
it's one of the things that makes life
bearable,
so,
or maybe even better than bearable.
So you bet.
Dr.
So I want to say what a great lecture
series and uh,
this is the last one this year.
So a merry christmas to you and your
family.
Thank you.
I just want to say this,
this,
don't gEt too enthusiastic about that.
I wrote you an essay of a question and
then I use the,
uh,
the lecture or the essay writing guide
on site to 30 to narrow it down to just
a few pages,
a few lines.
And then during this,
uh,
this particular lecture,
like the zigzag slide manifest again and
I thought,
ah,
basically just had all my questions
answered.
So,
um,
basicaLly I just,
I,
I want to ask,
um,
the idea of a,
your,
you've made a lecture that was,
um,
on youtube many years ago and uh,
you keeP referring to cain and abel and
the,
uh,
the death of abel by cain and the curse
in it.
and I think that that was the,
um,
that was the single brother,
two brothers conflict.
Um,
but,
but here we have in the sense of jacob
the 12.
There was one who was one who's good,
one who was enable archetype and there
are 1211 that came after him.
so that,
I don't know,
maybe there was something about the
division or a.
No,
that's a good observation.
I hadn't thought about that.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean there's a bit of variability
because ruben and ruben isn't quite as
bad as the rest,
but yeah,
I would say it's probably easier for the
cane side,
the multiply.
Luckily it's not as powerful because it
doesn't do anything like it.
Yes,
yes.
And you know,
you'll,
there's young was often included,
accused of manichaean isn't not
pronouncing that properly,
but there was a,
there was a variant of christian dogma
that held that good and evil.
We're separate metaphysical realities
and that they were battling for the,
for governance of the cosmos,
something like that.
But they both had an independent
existence and the classical christian
idea which won out over that was the no,
that good was real,
but evil was the absence of good now
that produced all sorts of the absence
of good produces all sorts of
consequences and it is interesting to
read young because he does get kinda
manichaean in his discussions and I
think it was partly because he was so
concerned about what happened in nazi
Germany and then with a cold war
afterwards,
you know,
because evil seem to be a palpable
force.
BuT I don't think that it's as powerful
as good.
But I do think it's easier for it to
multiply because it's what's easier
path.
It's easy to be resentful and hostile
and bitter and do nothing.
That's easy.
It's horrible and it's hard on people,
but it doesn't require a tremendous
amount of faith or effort.
So maybe that is why it's multiplied in
the final story in genesis.
Yeah,
and I,
I've been reading ahead and for my own,
based on the interest of the present
presented stories and I keyed in on a
few other books and chapters in the
bible,
first corinthians 13,
which is the love chapter,
and that cycles through the idea of I
can have all things in life,
uh,
knowledge,
power,
but it's all passing and uh,
the law now and forever.
Faith,
hope and love.
And then of course love trumps overall.
Yeah.
Well the love the issue.
See I've,
I've been,
I've,
I thought a lot about the relationship
between love and truth because I've
thought and talked a lot more about
truth and I think partly that's because
love is a word that you can hardly even
say because it's been so.
It's like it's being dragged behind a
car through mud puddles.
It's something like that.
But let's,
let me Just finish it.
Liberating this idea,
but I think that the,
the,
the love idea is associated with w for
me at least with what I discussed at the
beginning of this lecture with regards
to faith.
Think you have to make a decision about
what your attitude towards being is
going to be and the proper attitude in
my estimation is that you're working for
its betterment,
you know,
and so maybe maybe you have the same
attitude towards being as you do towards
someone that you love,
like a son or a daughter or wife,
that you want things to be better and
that.
So that's your aim.
So the aim is basically the aim is
motivated by love.
You want things to be better because I
think that's a good definition of law.
Like if you really care for someone you
can tell because you want things to be
better for them.
And then I think truth is nested inside
that because I think that truth is the
best servant of love,
something like that.
So I've been struggling with an idea
recently that I was thinking maybe you'd
be able to help me out with.
Basically in a recent interview you
talked about how myth is meant to
reconcile inherent contradictions in
reality.
Right?
But,
but I'm sort of stuck between two
mythological or psychoanalytic ideas
that I think are both really important,
but they seem to have a inherent
contradiction within them that I've been
trying to figure out.
So on one hand you have this idea that
there's times in your life where you
have to identify things in yourself that
are insufficient or there's a problem
somehow that you have to kind of have a
controlled burn.
Or like a phoenix like transformation
where you discard part of yourself that
doesn't fit or it's not working.
But then on the other hand,
you have talked about this,
this union idea where as you become
really.
When you get older,
you mature by reincorporating.
Things about yourself that you lost whEn
you were younger or that you're trying
to integrate your shadow or you're
trying to find parts of your personality
that.
That maybe you've been rejecting and try
and figure out how to bring them into,
into the folder and whole.
so he's got this quote that I really
liked,
which is I'd rather be holding good.
Right,
right.
So,
so on one hand you may identify
something as a problem and you want to
get rid of it or burn it off.
But then on the other hand it seems like
the path to being stronger is to figure
out how to put everything together.
So there's the,
there's the,
one of the things you wrote about in his
works on alchemy was an explanation of
the prime l chemical dictum,
which was solve a coagula which meant
dissolve and integrate.
Right?
So,
so imagine this,
imagine that.
Imagine you had a fairly hostile father
who was not very well controlled and his
aggression,
decent person.
Other than that,
but let's say that.
And so your reaction is I'm never going
to be aggressive.
And so you've built a,
like a moral structure that's part of
your personality and there's possibility
floating around.
Outside of that,
did you,
you've denied an ethical,
you've denied any ethical.
What would you say?
You've stripped the idea of aggression
of any ethical utility whatsoever?
Okay,
so what happens?
This burns off and then that comes back
up.
Now you still have to integrate it.
So it's associated in some sense with
niches,
ideas,
morality as cowardice.
Because one of nature's most trenchant
critiques of traditional morality,
let's say,
is that most of what passes for morality
isn't reality.
It's just cowardice.
It's not that I'm a good person and I
don't hurt you.
It's that I'm afraid to hurt you and
because I don't want to admit that I'm
afraid to hurt you.
Then I say I'm moral because then I can
mask my essential fear and cowardice in
a guise of morality.
And that happens far more often than you
would think because harmless and moral
are by no means the same thing.
So some of what you're burning off you
can sit.
And this is where freud was such a
genius,
I think is because he concentrated on
aggression in sexuality,
which are perhaps the two most difficult
parts of a personality to integrate.
So that,
um,
the,
the hyper simplified morality stops you
from tapping into deeper recesses of
your psyche and it's partly because
there are primal forces.
It's not surprising that you don't want
to have anything to do with them,
that you stay away from situations where
they might make themselves manifest.
But the problem is by denying the worst
in yourself in that manner of
suPpressing it,
you preclude the possibility of the best
because no one can be a good person
without integrating their capacity for
aggression.
Because without that capacity,
you have for aggression.
You cannot say no because no means if
you really say it,
no means there isn't anything that you
can do to me that will make me change my
mind or,
or conversely it means I will play for
higher stakes than you will.
And unless you've got your aggression
integrated,
there isn't a chance you can say that.
And if you did,
no one would take you seriously because
they'd know it was just a show.
So one of the most useful things that
young did,
I think was to work on this idea of the
integration of the shadow because he was
really interested in the idea of evil,
right?
Especially working with trying to parcel
out what happened in nazi Germany and
during the second world war.
What do you do with the part of you
that's aggressive and potentially
malevolent?
You just crush it.
That's the super ego response in some
sense.
do you just put it behind you so to
speak?
Is that a possibility or do you admit to
its existence and bring it into the game
and that's c for.
For freud,
in some sense,
morality was super ego clamping down on
the bed and there were fundamentally
opposed.
Both young and piaget had a different
idea and I think they were right.
It's like,
no,
you invite the bad guys out to play,
and so you're an aggressive hockey
player,
but it's disciplined aggression that
makes you,
gives you access to a whole source of
energy you wouldn't otherwise have.
And then with regards to sexuality,
it's like,
well untrammeled promiscuity doesn't
constitute a virtue,
but neither does unavoidable virginity.
Right.
In fact,
I think that's worse because it also
masks itself with virtue,
so like,
well you should be able to.
You should be able to do things that you
wouldn't do.
That's,
that's like the definition of a
genuinely moral person.
They could do it,
they don't.
That's not cowardice.
And so that's,
you burn off the things that get in the
way of that integration.
When you say dissolve and integrating,
it'd be a good way to sort of bring the
two ideas together that the burning off
and the difficult processes necessary
because the elements of yourself are
structured together in a rigid way that
is not working properly.
Yeah.
That's what happens to Japan in the
belly of the whale.
He's so caught in his presuppositions
that he can't escape.
Right.
And so pinocchio represents the new
forest.
So it's very interesting.
So when you watch pinocchio,
tried to rescue him.
The first thing joe petta does this
confuse pinocchio with a fish because he
wants something to eat.
But pinocchio is better than something
to eat because he could rescue him so he
doesn't need to eat.
And then pinocchio wants to make a fire
engine pedo objects because he's going
to burn up all the furniture.
So like we don't need the damn furniture
if we're getting out of the whale,
you know,
and so,
so Japan and he's old,
so that,
that,
that's the,
that's the rigid structure.
That's the old gear that has to die off
before the new year can be born.
It's a forest fire that allows for new
growth and that's how those things are
put together and to see.
And it's useful to know too because if
you burn something off,
you might think,
well,
there's nothing left.
It's like,
that's not true.
If it's dead wood,
then you have room for new growth and
you want to be doing that on a fairly
regular basis.
That's the,
that's the snake that sheds its skin and
transforms itself,
right?
That's,
that's the death and resurrection from a
psychological perspective,
it's exactly the same idea.
Now we don't know the upper limit to
that,
right?
Because we don't know what a person
would be like if they let everything
that they could let go,
let go and only let in what was
seemingly,
let's say.
But you can See that it's funny,
we don't know that to some degree you
can see People very far.
You can see people start to do that
without.
That's not an rare experience and people
improve very rapidly.
It can improve their very rapidly.
A lot of it's low hanging fruit,
like if he just stopped doing really
stupid things that you know are stupid,
your life improves a lot so and it,
it frees you up.
It also means there's a,
there's an element there that's also
associated with pride because people
tend to take pride in who they are and
that's a bad idea because that stops you
from becoming who you could be because
if you're proud of who you are,
you won't let that go when it's
necessary.
You won't step away from it,
you know,
and then you end up being your own
parody.
Something like that.
That's also a very bad idea.
You want to be continually stepping away
from your previous self and so big and I
guess part of that too is that you have
to decide,
you know,
are you,
are you order or chaos or you the
process that mediates between them and
if you're the process that mediates
between them,
you,
you are the thing that transforms and
that's the right attitude for a human
being because that's what we are.
We're the thing that voluntarily
confronts chaos and transforms.
That's what we are.
And so for better or worse,
you know,
that's our deepest biological essence
you might say,
and so you can let things go if you know
that there's more growth to come.
So yeah,
thank you.
One more.
Thank you for your time and thank you
for spending your time with all of us.
Hey,
my pleasure.
It's been a pleasure.
So if I could,
since we are at the end of genesis,
I liked the opportunity to challenge or
at least have you take another look at
your position you've held with regards
to reflection on the murder of evil.
Uh,
I bring this up because it's actually a
part of genesis that has bothered me for
awhile and it's not like because it's
not as straightforward as it's
presented,
usually in straight.
I've been wrestling with it.
So in this series as well as in a couple
of your maps of meaning lectures,
you summarized it,
something to the effect of cane coming
to the conclusion that what he did leads
to a punishment which is more than he
believes he can face,
which I believe to be born out of a
natural reading,
a specific translation choices
incorrectly made entry innocently made
by editors Just for readability sake.
So in genesis four,
13 cane does not say my punishment is
greater than I can bear.
He actually says they'll meat,
so my sIn is greater than I can bear,
which is this,
which is to say it's not his past
actions.
We'll just say it's not as past
sections.
It's his future as consequences which a
past actions not as feature
consequences,
which he regrets for him to say,
oh,
won't iniquity or sin.
That is far too much for him to bear as
a reflection on the reality of this
corruPtion and not a plea of mercy to
the dd despair him.
Okay,
well that's,
that seems to be a deeper interpretation
I would say.
And I think it's more that's the same
line of reasoning that dusty see pursued
in crime and punishment,
right?
Because in crime and punishment,
skolnick of gets away with murder and
then he cannot stand it.
He cannot stand that he did it because
he's no longer the same person,
but even more he cannot stand that he
got away with it.
so that's more in keeping with the,
with that interpretation.
So,
uh,
this also is reflected in the following
verses for 14 where he states the
consequences of his actions,
mainly that god's presence will be
hidden from him and that he will be
killed.
The first opens with the word hain,
which means indeed more or less.
And to note the sense of acceptance and
not a complaint,
it is the difference between saying,
oh no,
well god,
now hide his face from me and will I be
hunted versus of course god will hide
his face for me and I will be hunted and
killed,
which I've been wrestling lists and have
taken away to possibly mean that there
are sins that we can do that we'll just
push us too far.
Well,
okay,
there,
there are.
Well,
okay,
so one of the.
Well,
one of the things that you see in
posttraumatic posttraumatic stress
disorder situations,
for example,
is that people view themselves doing
something so terrible.
They don't know how to put it right.
So that.
So you could say under those
circumstances,
the face of god is hidden from them
because they cannot,
they cannot atone for it.
They count reconciled themselves to it.
It's there all the time and they can't
see anything good beyond it.
It's hell essentially.
And so in sometimes when you're working
with people with posttraumatic stress
disorder,
you know,
you,
you kind of initiatE them into a
philosophy of good and evil so that they
can see when joseph talks to his
brothers and they've got all this guilt,
right?
and,
and he doesn't want them to have more
guilt than necessary to fix themselves
because it just burdens them.
otherwise he says,
look,
don't forget,
yeah,
it was you.
But it's also god's doing.
And I had a client once who,
who had obsessive compulsive disorder.
And um,
he was a very smart guy.
He also happened to work in a active lab
that hug a lot of radioactive materials,
which wasn't the best place for someone
with ocd.
And he was worried that he would make
some mistake.
This is very common with ocd that would
result in someone's suffering,
which you will,
you,
you'll do that.
And it wasn't until I could get him to
conceptualize himself and his life in
part as a force of nature that he was
able to reconcile himself to the
possibility that an error on his part
would produce catastrophic consequences.
But people often find themselves in
situations where they just cannot
reconcile themselves to what they've
done and that it makes sense to me that,
that the interpretation that you're
describing that that makes,
that makes plenty of sense from a
psychological perspective that will push
us to like just beyond our limit that
are too far,
but there are also no consequences to
our actions that are devoid of a truth
we can accept and learn from.
And this is what I've kind of delved out
of this a bit with cain and abel.
So this is the case.
Why then does it take us so long?
And it was so much self to now before we
accept personal responsibility,
my face with tragedy,
especially when it's self inflicted.
Well I don't think you want to
underestimate the contribution of just
sheer dIfficulty.
Like you know,
let's say you,
you,
you're grieving because someone close to
you died.
It's like,
well it isn't just that you've lost
them.
Although that's a big part of it.
It's that you have to rebuild yourself
and it's really hard to do that.
So it is sort of proportional to the
significance of your errors,
so if you commit an error and then you
recognize that it's an error,
if it's a sort of surface area it's like
well you can just touch up the paint,
but sometimes the whole under structure
is just rotten and then you don't know
what to do.
And then.
So that's one problem.
Just sheer bloody difficulty.
And I see this with people very often.
It's like they're at a point in their
divorce,
let's say,
and they don't know what to do.
They cannot solve the problem.
It's too complicated.
They just don't have the resources and
maybe they've squandered some of their
resources as well,
but sometimes they just don't have the
resources.
And then if you add to that error and
sin and malevolence and blindness and
all those other things.
people.
There's a guy named thomas says,
who wrote this really interesting
article in the 19 sixties and book
actually called the myth of mental
illness.
And it was classic reading for clinical
psychologist when I was training.
And the reason for that was,
that sounds pointed out,
and this is true,
is that lots of times if you're a
psychotherapist,
people don't come to you because they
have mental illnesses.
They had come to you because they have
insoluble problems in their life.
You know,
like maybe they've had a two year affair
at work,
their wife is alcoholic and they have a
very and their father has alzheimer's
disease.
It's like they just don't know what to
do.
It's too much now,
you know,
they shouldn't have had the affair.
So there's a moral issue and maybe they
should have intervened in the alcoholism
in the family.
Maybe they use their wives,
alcoholism as an excuse to have the
affair.
You know,
like these things get very tangled.
It's just,
it's so bloody complicated that people
can't untangle it.
So.
And I would say that's in keeping with
the interpretation that you laid forth
with regards to cain is it sounds like
it's one of the reasons why it's so
useful to read multiple translations,
right?
Because nuances matter.
it sounds to me from that descriPtion
that he actually woke up at least
briefly and noticed what he did and
said,
there's no coming back from this and and
it is.
You can easIly get places that you do
not know how to come back from.
Now.
You know,
they say,
well,
all things are possible with god and
there's always the possibility of
redemption.
No matter how serious the sin,
but I'll tell you is sometimes people
have no idea how to get back from where
they went well,
and you can understand often why people
wouldn't do that,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
that's a funny thing because one of the
things Carl Rogers said too about
Psychotherapy is that you can't do
psychotherapy with someone who hasn't
recognized that they have a problem.
so it's a massive thing to recognize
that you have a problem and it does open
the door perhaps to recovery,
but it also means that you've recognized
that you have a problem and that can be
very,
very.
it's the desert,
right?
You're out of the tyranny,
but you're in the desert and the sun's
beating down on you and there's no
necessary reason to presume that you're
going to survive.
So thank you.
Have guidance.
Thank you all.
Thank you.