I got a video yesterday from a group in
California that are trying to refocus
the Democrats and I want to tell you a
little bit about it today and take it
apart and analyze it.
If we're all in luck,
given the importance of a stable,
intelligent,
functional two party political system in
the u s and in consequence everywhere
else in the world,
the video will make a reasonable case
for something approximating and returned
to normative political debate in image
and word.
I'll show you the whole thing first and
then we'll take it apart.
We stand for the working men and women
always have,
always will,
and we define ourselves by what we've
done to help them get their shot at the
American dream,
social security,
the Gi bill,
the Civil Rights Act,
medicare saving an auto industry,
23 million people with health insurance
for the first time in their lives and
all along it was American workers,
farmers and factory workers,
immigrants and engineers of every color
speaking every language we're building,
the highest standard of living the world
had ever seen.
Who's innovations were changing history,
whose courage made America of beacon of
hope and freedom for those living in
tyranny around the world?
Working People made America work.
Then something happened.
Some people in Washington took the side
of the powerful against American
workers.
That game got fixed for an entire
generation and come flatline.
Big donors made sure lawmakers cared
more about Wall Street than your street.
Back in the 80s a CEO made 30 times what
is workers made now they make 300 times
since the great recession,
almost all of the income gains have gone
to the top 0.01% not 1% 0.01% instead of
raising your salary,
they buy back stock to increase their
own bonuses.
They merged companies and reduce
competition so they can make even more
money.
All while your cable bill gets bigger,
your cell phone bill gets higher,
you're internet gets slower,
the seat on your flight gets smaller,
their taxes get lower and your health
bills get raised.
Who's looking out for you?
The people in power are so busy giving
tax breaks to the wealthiest that they
blow up the deficit and leave nothing
for roads and bridges,
nothing for veterans or Medicare,
nothing for job training.
Something has to change
and we're going to change it.
A new generation of leaders who know
what needs to be done and who have the
will to stand up to those who would hold
us back.
We want our America back.
The land of decency and fairness of
generous hearts and big dreams and the
freedom for anyone who wants to work
hard to make those dreams come true.
I don't care what your politics are.
I don't care what God you pray to or
what color your skin is.
I don't care if you ride a tractor and
run a business and I hope your business
is a big success as long as everybody
plays by the same rules,
the same rules,
because this is America,
this is America,
and this
is our generation's great calling to
rise to the challenge like those who had
the courage before us to build a future
for all Americans.
Not just a few to fight for the higher
pay working people have more than earned
to fight to make healthcare available to
everyone who needs it.
Just stop those who would try to cut the
social security and Medicare benefits
that are rightfully yours to protect the
environment instead of selling it to the
highest bidder to fight for a government
free of corruption where your
representatives work only for you
to build a future that is just and free
full of hope and opportunity.
Our Future,
our children thank us for leaving
because democracy is built not bought by
the strong and the free.
So that's the statement,
the story,
the appeal to voters and the
establishment of direction.
We want to take a look at the images,
assessed the text,
determine what's in the video and
equally importantly determine what is
not.
So I'll give you some background first.
This is about the group that's created
it.
After the election in 2016 we created a
political organization to work on the
important issue of expanding the reach
of Democrats and focusing on shared core
values.
Future majority.
That's the name of the organization.
Under the leadership of Mark Rydell
continues to work on a vast scale to
rebrand and define the party,
particularly in red and purple states
and districts.
In an effort to shore up our base,
speak to swing voters and turn out those
voters who we lost in the last election
built,
not bought created by Marshall
Herskovitz,
Gregg Hurwitz and Kelly.
Corey is the cornerstone of a new
initiative that answers the question.
What do Democrats stand for?
The four minute film celebrates the
singular importance of working people in
the creation of modern America.
Well,
calling out the big donor influences
that have eroded our democratic
institutions over the past few decades.
It is a patriotic,
optimistic solutions oriented
affirmation of core American values,
decency,
fair play,
the belief in a boundless future that
seem too often forgotten in our partisan
era.
It's a call to action to build a future
that has just in free full of hope and
opportunity.
First is the name of the video itself
built,
not bought.
This is obviously a direct appeal to the
idea of labor as opposed to capital and
is in keeping with the traditional
Democrat emphasis on the contribution of
the working class.
I think it skews a little left and an
unfortunate manners strategically
because the amazing infrastructure
around us was built and bought since
people need to be paid for their labor
because capital contributes just like
labor,
but perhaps that's a forgivable
rhetorical flourish.
Let's turn from that to the opening
shot.
We stand for the working men and women.
We opened moving forward to a sun
dappled mountain vista that indicates
the possibility of awkward movement
progress and we switched to an image of
a typical American nuclear family.
I liked the choice of that image a lot
to open.
The opening scene of a film is
particularly important and the fact that
these filmmakers chose to highlight the
typical American nuclear family strikes
me as a reasonable,
intelligent,
cautious,
and somewhat traditional initial choice
and we define ourselves by what we've
done to help them get their shot at the
American dream.
Social Security,
the Gi bill,
the Civil Rights Act,
medicare saving an auto industry,
23 million people with health insurance
for the first time in their lives.
This is followed by a 22nd section
detailing the Democrats contribution to
the higher standards of living currently
enjoyed by working class people in the
United States.
This seems to me to be handled with
reasonable credibility.
Long.
It was American workers,
farmers and factory workers,
immigrants and engineers of every color
speaking every language we're building,
the highest standard of living the world
had ever seen who's innovations were
changing.
History,
whose courage made America a beacon of
hope and freedom for those living in
tyranny around the world,
working people make America work.
I like this section quite a bit and
found it surprising.
It was surprising because of the
unabashed appreciation shown by the film
makers for the effort put in by working
class people to produce a higher
standard of living.
There's some genuine appreciation for
the fact that this occurred,
and I see this as standing at quite
marked contrast to the all too typical
dialogue on the radical left,
concentrating on the pernicious effects
of modern culture by image and word.
The filmmakers in this section testified
the utility of the efforts of people in
the working class to producing the
productive and relatively wealthy
society that exists in the United States
and elsewhere today.
So I thought that was really good.
I also think it's important not to miss
the positivity.
Radical inclusion of a young boy playing
in army helmet with an airplane.
That's a bit of respect shown both to
the way boys typically play in the
military all simultaneously.
So that's quite something.
Then something happened.
Some people in Washington took the side
of the powerful against American
workers.
The game got fixed for an entire
generation.
Income flatlined.
Big donors made sure lawmakers cared
more about Wall Street than you are
street.
Back in the 80s a CEO made 30 times what
is workers made now?
They make 300 times since the great
recession,
almost all of the income gains have gone
to the top 0.01% not 1% 0.01% instead of
raising your salary,
they buy back stock to increase their
own bonuses.
They merged companies and reduce
competition so they can make even more
money.
All while your cable bill gets bigger,
your cell phone bill gets higher,
you're internet gets slower,
the seat on your flight gets smaller,
their taxes get lower,
and your health bills get raised.
Who's looking out for you?
Yeah.
I think that the section we just watched
is the weakest part of the film and I
think it's inclusion was an error of
other reasons to decry access
inequality.
I thought the emphasis on the unnamed,
they and the images of wealth is under
and luxury were unsophisticated,
cliched,
and unnecessarily divisive.
It is absolutely necessary for the
Democrats and for all those who wish for
return to politics as usual,
to distinguish between the majority of
wealthy individuals in the US who are in
their money honestly and through benefit
to society,
freely chosen by consumers and the
minority who gathered their position
through unsavory or counterproductive
means there is almost nothing more
important than distinguishing between
the successful who earn their success
and those who managed it through
exploitation and conflating the two is
an assault on the ideas of competence,
aspiration,
and accomplishment.
As such,
I truly believe that all this section
was a regressive mistake,
a call to resentment as a reason for
civic engagement and an insult to the
hardworking people of the u s whose
accomplishments were celebrated just
prior to the deliverance of this darker
message.
The people in power are so busy giving
tax breaks to the wealthiest that they
blow up the deficit and leave nothing
for roads and bridges,
nothing for veterans or Medicare,
nothing for job training.
Something has to change.
Now I found this section problematic to
the people in power.
Well for a lot of the last while those
people were also Democrats and the tone
in this section in the film we just
watched,
it implies that it was someone other
than the people who are addressing you,
her responsible for the current mess.
I think this part of the film would have
been a lot stronger,
had the Democrats taking some
responsibility for the corruption that
there decrying instead of attributing
its existence to unnamed others lurking
somehow in the background.
This was a great opportunity in the
course of the film for the Democrats to
note their own contributions to the
current state of affairs and to promise
to do better
and we're going to change it.
A new generation of leaders who know
what needs to be done and who have the
will to stand up to those who would hold
us back.
They're at a disability to be made.
It's appearance again.
It's not good to look for the cause of
trouble outside.
It's an ethical error.
It's another place where the film makers
missed an opportunity to take
responsibility on the part of the
Democrats for what's happening around us
today.
That's an ethical mistake.
We want our America back,
the land of decency and fairness of
generous hearts and big dreams and the
freedom for anyone who wants to work
hard to make those dreams come true.
I don't care what your politics are.
I don't care what God you pray to or
what color your skin is.
I don't care if you ride a tractor and
run a business.
Your Business is a big success as long
as everybody plays by the same rules,
the same rules,
same rules because this is America.
This is America,
this is America.
I like this section a lot and again
found its inclusion.
Quite surprising.
There's even a bit of nostalgia for the
past,
something never seen on the progressive
landscape.
There's emphasis on generosity,
certainly,
but also real consideration given to
aspirations,
big dreams,
something that has been woefully lacking
in the discourse generated by the left.
This is reiterated in the statement and
the freedom for anyone who wants to work
hard to make those dreams come true,
which is again remarkable for its
unabashed insistence that there's a
relationship between hard work and
success and that success in itself is
desirable,
admirable,
and worth pursuing.
Then there's a positive disavowal in my
opinion of identity politics with each
speaker alone and identified visually as
an individual and insistence on fair
play,
an analog of equality,
of opportunity,
not outcome and this direct statement
from a policeman no less,
and I hope that your business is
successful,
very radical in a time where success is
all too often reflexively equated with
privilege and oppression.
I think the ethos in this section stands
in powerful contradiction to that
presented earlier,
we're wealth and success was negatively
portrayed,
which attitude is going to prevail?
It's obvious to me that the ladder
message is most desirable and also most
likely to generate a favorable majority
response.
People vote their dreams,
not the realities,
and it is perfectly reasonable for the
Democrats to reconstitute themselves as
the party that can make the dreams of
individuals come true even if those
individuals occupy a lower rung on the
economic ladder.
And to do so by insisting upon a fair
playing field the same rules and to know
finally that this characterizes America,
this borders on stating that a shared
value structure is a necessary
precondition for social harmony and for
the possibility of progress and upward
mobility.
Much more of this on the part of the
Democrats is necessary and would be
widely applauded and welcomed.
And this is our generation's great
calling to rise to the challenge like
those who had the courage before us to
build a future for all Americans,
not just the few to fight for the higher
pay working people have more than earned
to fight to make healthcare available to
everyone who needs it to stop those who
would try to cut the social security and
Medicare benefits that are rightfully
yours to protect the environment instead
of selling it to the highest bidder,
to fight for a government free of
corruption where your representatives
work only for you
to build a future that is just and free
full of hope and opportunity.
Our Future,
our children thank us for leaving
because democracy is built not bought by
the strong and the free.
Yeah.
The film ends positively with a call to
the future to build something promising.
It's marred once again in my opinion by
the reference to those who had cut
benefits and sell the environment to the
highest bidder.
More politics of resentment,
but uses positive imagery of
infrastructure,
productive work and aspirational
engagement presents a promise to fight
corruption and closes with something
positive about both strength and
freedom.
It could have been better for the
reasons I outlined,
but it could have been a lot worse.
There's much less of the radical left is
tilt towards identity politics that has
characterized so much of the recent
democratic conversation.
There's a strong sense of shared
American society values.
There's tremendous emphasis on a fair
playing field and the importance of
promise of hard work,
not something typical of those who
insist,
for example,
on equity or equality of outcome,
and do claim that our whole societies of
patriarchal tyranny,
in my estimation,
this film is a welcome move towards
classical liberal values and away from
the divisive politics of political
correctness and naive but dangerous
utopianism.