Hi Guys,
girls and interested others.
I thought I'd give you an update on the
week's events.
I've still been involved in discussions
with the dean of the Faculty of Arts and
Sciences,
David Cameron on the upcoming debate.
And so I thought I'd fill you in on all
of the events,
but first of all,
I want to make a slight detour.
So one of the things that's happened to
me since I put my lectures on youtube is
that I frequently come across people
claiming that high sound a fair bit like
kermit the frog.
Kermit the frog here.
Hi.
Oh,
kermit the frog here.
Hi.
All kermit the frog here.
And uh,
I wasn't really sure what to make of
that.
It might not have been my first choice
for animal Avatar,
although I suppose it could be a lot
worse.
I need.
Kermit is a pretty good guy and he's a
decent spokes frog and a and a good
organizer and,
and all of that.
So.
But anyways,
I was thinking about that this morning
and I realized something and I think
it's an example of what the psychologist
Carl Jung called synchronicity.
Synchronicity.
The simultaneous occurrence of events
that appear significantly or
meaningfully related,
but have no discernible causal
connection.
And since I've been engaging in this
free speech campaign,
I have experienced a number of
synchronous event.
So one of them was that when the
Canadian Union of Public Employee Queer
Caucus was sent,
the University of letter denouncing me
essentially at exactly the same moment
that letter was released.
I had another Canadian Union of Public
Employees President in my office who
was,
who is a representative of one of the
major groups on campus who was talking
to me about his concerns about the new
university sexual harassment policy,
which has been formulated in response to
the demands of Kathleen winds,
Ontario government that threatens to
make normal,
let's call the misunderstanding social
misunderstandings perhaps of a sexual
nature,
all equivalent to rape,
um,
and,
and to sexual violence.
And this qp organization president was
telling me about his concerns that
that's going to put tremendous stress on
the interactions between the people that
he had.
He has to represent.
So that was an interesting
juxtaposition.
He couldn't find anybody in the
University of Admin administration to
properly address his concerns.
But then the frog issue.
Well,
here's something cool,
so you'll notice these sculptures behind
me,
they're made by an artist,
a native artist named Charles Joseph,
and Charles Joseph is a friend and now a
brother of mine,
um,
as I've been inducted into their tribal
group,
which happened by say,
by the way,
the same week that I was being accused
of being racist by many people on the
University of Toronto campus.
So that was another major active as far
as I was concerned.
But one thing that's kind of cool is
that I had this mask made by Charles
Awhile back.
And this is a frog.
So there they are.
Now.
I've got my,
my Kwakwaka'wakw,
the Kwakwaka'wakw people are tribal
people who live in,
in,
uh,
on the west coast of Vancouver Island.
And they have a remarkable artistic
tradition,
which I've been very interested in.
And I've had a lot of work done by
Charles who,
as I said,
as a residential school survivor and he
made this beautiful frog hap for me.
And so,
and here's something cool too.
So I asked Charles about the
significance of the frog and
Kwakwaka'wakw mythology,
and he said the frog is a harbinger of
dangerous,
a dangerous times because if anything
pollutes the waters,
then the frogs disappear.
And of course that did happen almost all
around the world a few years ago because
the frogs,
frogs have very sensitive skin and so
they pick up anything that,
that,
that has gone wrong and it interferes
with their ability to reproduce and to
live.
And so I would say that as spokes frog,
I'm announcing that there's something
polluted,
devote the water in which we're all
swimming in,
that we better clean it up and,
or there's going to be trouble.
So,
um,
there's a bit of synchronicity for you.
So what I've been doing this week,
because working out the details of the
debate with,
uh,
with the dean of the Faculty of Arts and
Science,
David Cameron.
And uh,
I met him Monday,
November first in the meeting.
He threw a curve ball at me,
I would say.
Um,
he said that if the debate was going to
go forward,
the university couldn't allow it to go
forward.
If I was going to repeat my assertion
that I would not use gender neutral
pronouns to refer to people if they
asked me to do so.
And you may know that the university has
already sent me two warning letters
telling me that,
um,
my refusal to use these pronouns is in
violation of university policy.
We'll get to that in a while.
And also contravenes the Ontario Human
Rights Code.
And,
and also that as my employer,
the university is as responsible for my
speech acts as I am.
And of course I did know that because
that's exactly why I made the videos to
begin with.
And that's exactly what I said in the
videos.
And so the university is distancing
itself from me because they know that if
I get called for my hate speech because
of my refusal to use these pronouns,
than the university is just as guilty as
I am.
So what they're doing is setting up a
series of legal documents that are
designed to show that they acted in good
faith,
trying to discipline a wayward employee
who is contravening these policies.
And David implied quite strongly.
I would say that with each of those
assertions,
the probability that I will be able to
teach at the University of Toronto come
2017 when I started my undergraduate
teaching is diminishing.
And so I knew that,
but it was still a sharp to hear it.
And then of course that put me in a
conundrum because I wasn't sure if it
was reasonable for me to proceed with
the debate if a risk because it's a
debate about free speech.
Say if a arbitrary restriction was
placed on what I was able to say.
And so initially I thought,
well that I could proceed with the
debate because I really want to talk
about bill [inaudible] and issues that
our larger scale than my mirror refusal
to use these pronouns.
But then I went home and I really
thought about it and I talked with my
family because we thought it was
perverse in some sense that in this
debate the debate would begin with a
significant restriction on what I was
allowed to say.
So I wrote a letter,
which I'm,
which I'm going to read to you.
I wrote this on on Tuesday,
November second,
and I sent it to American Gertler,
who's the president of the University of
Toronto show band,
Nelson,
Dean,
Faculty of Arts and science,
the vice provost who was a signatory of
the second letter I received from the
university,
the one asking me not to repeat my
assertions anymore,
asking me to silence myself to Cheryl
[inaudible],
who's the vice president and provost to
Kelly Hannah Moffat,
vice president,
human resources and equity.
A Hannah Moffitt is still working with
the black liberation collective by the
way,
despite the fact that on their website
they basically,
they refuse to disavow violence in their
pursuit of social change.
And also,
um,
were started and continued to be
strongly influenced by two people have,
let's say,
dubious reputation.
You can read about them online if you
want,
and also Suzanne Ferber,
who's the chair of the Department of
Psychology,
who gave me the first of the two warning
letters.
So what the university is doing is
setting themselves up so that if I'm
taken to court and they're taking the
court along with me,
then they can claim that they've done
everything they possibly can to reign in
this,
you know,
this abusive professor who refuses to
let other people determine the words
that he says.
And uh,
so this is the letter I wrote,
Dear Dean Cameron yesterday.
You indicated that if the debate where
to proceed and if I repeated my
insistence that I would not use gender
neutral pronouns during that debate,
the university would find itself in an
untenable legal position.
This is because number one use of those
pronouns is mandated by university
policy and the Ontario Human Rights Act
and its surrounding policies as laid
out,
for example,
on the Ontario Human Rights Commission
website and two,
under those laws and policies,
employers are responsible for the
statements of their employees as if they
were making the statements themselves.
Thus,
if the university hosts this debate,
providing me with a platform for my
views and I restated my intention to
refuse use of the mandated pronouns and
legal action and sued the university
would not have properly upheld its legal
obligation to ensure that its employees
follow the requisite laws.
You also indicated that if I continue to
insist publicly that I will not use the
mandated pronouns.
The university may also be required to
suspend my courses beginning in January.
You suggested therefore that I agree
during the debate not to repeat my
refusal to use gender neutral pronouns,
so as not to further compromise the
university and to allow the debate to go
forward.
I sat at our meeting that I would
consider this and I have.
I cannot abide by this request.
Part of the discussion that needs to be
had during it outside of the debate is
precisely what the university should do.
Because of my refusal.
Here are the options.
Number one,
the university can consist,
continue to insist upon my silence based
on its understanding that my actions are
currently legal.
Sorry.
Based on its understanding that my
actions are currently illegal
on its concern,
a bit refusing to use gender neutral
pronouns is illegal and more precisely
be that my statement that I would refuse
to use them if asked is also illegal.
It can then take continue to take
whatever actions that deems necessary to
distance itself from me and my opinions.
Option two,
the university can reaffirm its
commitment to its statement on freedom
of speech written in May 19,
92,
which explicitly states that quote,
the essential purpose of the university
is to engage in the pursuit of truth,
the advancement of learning,
and the dissemination of knowledge.
To achieve this purpose,
all members of the university must have
as a prerequisite freedom of speech and
expression,
which means the right to examine
question,
investigate,
speculate,
and comment on any issue without
reference to prescribe doctrine as well
as the right to criticize the university
and society at large.
The existence of an institution were
unorthodox ideas.
Alternative modes of thinking and living
and radical prescriptions for social
ills can be debated,
contributes immensely to social and
political change,
and the advancement of human rights both
inside and outside the university.
Often this debate may generate
controversy and disputes among members
of the university and the wider
community.
In such cases,
the universities primary obligation is
to protect the free speech of all
involved.
The university must allow the fullest
range of debate.
It should not limit that debate by
preordained and conclusions or punishing
or inhibiting the reasonable exercise of
free speech.
And I said the university must decide it
can express option one,
which in my opinion means sacrificing
it's commitment to free speech as
expressly laid out in the aforementioned
statement or it can accept option to
defending my right to quote,
criticize the university and society at
large and quote by all legal means
necessary.
This would mean throwing it support
behind me and fighting the restrictive
legislation on embodied in the Ontario
Human Rights Act and associated policies
and soon to be instantiated in federal
bill.
See 16 all the way to the Supreme Court
of Canada if necessary.
I understand that the statement also
says that quote,
the purpose of the university also
depends on an environment of tolerance
and mutual respect.
Every member should be able to work,
live,
teach,
and learn in university,
free from discrimination and harassment
and quote,
my actions have been deemed by some to
constitute discrimination.
So the two major principles outlined in
the statement or now in conflict and the
university and our society at large has
to decide which one takes priority.
As Professor Jonathan Haidt,
professor of ethical leadership at Nyu
Stern School of business recently
indicated in the US universities must
choose one t loss that's guiding
principle,
social justice
or truth.
I have similarly juxtapose social
justice and freedom of expression and
chose the latter.
Make your decision.
I've made mine.
May God himself help us live with the
consequences.
Now,
Jonathan Haidt.
I'm going to read you a little bit about
what he wrote.
He wrote this last week and all.
All set.
Yup.
All set up the link and the video in the
comments on this video so you can look
at it.
Jonathan Haidt,
who's very good political psychologist
by the way,
says no university can have truth and
social justice as dual t locis final
goals.
John Stuart Mill is the patron saint of
what all call Truth University,
which sees truth as a process in which
flawed individuals challenge each
other's biased and incomplete reasoning
in the process all become smarter
truth you dies when it becomes
intellectual uniform or politically
orthodox.
Karl Marx is the patron saint of social
justice,
you which is oriented around changing
the world in part by overthrowing power
structures and privilege.
It sees political diversity as an
obstacle to action.
Each university must pick one.
Alright,
so now David Cameron,
the Dean,
wrote me back.
That's the same day,
which is what I requested and he said,
I have reviewed your letter dated
November second,
2016.
I do not agree with the way that you
have framed our conversation,
which was a good faith attempt to find a
way to identify a terms of reference
that would allow for you as an academic
to engage in a discussion about your
views regarding the provisions of the
Ontario Human Rights Code that it
protected against discrimination based
on gender identity and gender expression
since 2012.
That's the similar legislation in
Ontario as well as similar amendments
that are being considered federally.
In Bill [inaudible].
David repeats his commitment to the to
the forum or the university is quite
prepared to host a forum where arguments
are presented concerning the gender
identity and gender expression
protections of the Ontario Human Rights
Code,
or those being considered under bill
[inaudible].
Arguments are presented concerning
freedom of expression and how it should
properly relate to nondiscrimination
protections that exist in Canadian law.
Arguments are presented as to any
alternatives that might be preferable
and slash or discussing,
listen to and respond to arguments of
colleagues who may have different views
on these subjects.
The university cannot host a forum that
will offer a platform for an expressed
intention to engage in conduct with your
students and colleagues that you
appeared to have Nolan acknowledged
would have been in,
would be in violation of the Ontario
Human Rights Code.
If you wish to engage in a further
discussion about this way of proceeding
with the scholarly forum,
we would be glad to receive your written
comments.
Yours sincerely.
David Cameron,
Dean,
Faculty Arts and Science.
So
I slept on that and,
and,
and I'll tell you what I decided to do.
So I talked about it,
talked it over again with my family and
some friends who have been following
this and who are wise people.
And,
and then I also thought about this in
mythological terms,
so I'll give you the context of that.
So
one of the oldest stories we have got to
the story in genesis indicates that the
environments that people find themselves
in at an architectural level.
So this is all human environments could
be likened to a garden,
a walled garden,
a is a means walled garden.
An Eden means well watered place by the
way.
And so genesis presents the proper
environment for human beings as a a
garden with walls.
I'm a well watered garden with walls and
so that's a combination of of of culture
and nature that the walls are culture
and the garden itself is nature and so
human beings lived in a,
in a,
in an environment that's always partly
nature and partly culture and those two
things need to be kept in proper
balance.
But the thing about the garden is that
there's always a snake in the garden and
it's.
It's like the idea that there's a snake
in the garden.
There is the idea that nothing can exist
without,
without a flaw.
Nothing can actually exist that doesn't
have a serious flaw and the same ideas
expressed in certain Asian ideas.
For example,
the Buddhist beautiful Buddhist Gardens
in Japan very carefully manicured,
always have a flaw as often do a certain
forms of Japanese pottery and it
expresses the same idea that that
reality to exist must be allowed to have
its flaws.
And the Yin and Yang symbol is like that
too.
Because in the,
in the chaos serpent,
there's a white dot that indicates that
in every chaotic circumstance order can
emerge and in the and in the white
serpent,
there's a block dot which indicates that
in every orderly place that a chaotic
element can emerge,
but you can't get away from the tension
of opposites.
And so I thought,
well,
it's necessary for this debate to
proceed because it's important and,
and I want the,
the topics here to be aired properly and
thoroughly and it would be better for
the university to host it.
I,
I very seriously considered renting a
theater and just making my views known
there.
But I thought that's not as good as
having the other side have it's
opportunity to have their concerns
noted.
And I agreed that I would provide my
arguments,
at least an outline of my arguments to
my opposition,
let's say,
or to the people on the other side of
the discussion beforehand.
So that they had a chance to marshal
their arguments.
And so I decided that despite this
restriction,
which is still the precise nature of
which is still to be determined,
that it would be better,
all things considered to go ahead with
the debate.
And so it,
it looks like it's likely to occur
sometime in the next two weeks.
And um,
and that's that.
But I would like to close by noting that
the university appears to have made its
choice.
And when I met David on Friday,
we had a somewhat more heated exchange,
still friendly,
I would say,
where I suggested that the university is
making a big mistake here and that they
have to make a decision as Jonathan
Haidt said about which side they're on.
And that if the university,
the university has substantial legal
resources and if they were as concerned
about free speech as I think they should
be.
And as their own policy,
which I'm supposed to abide by by the
way.
Because because I'm supposed to abide by
university policies that the university
policy on free speech,
which I think is its highest order
policy,
suggests that I have the right.
Or perhaps maybe even the obligation to
criticize the university and society at
large without,
without reference to any preordained
conclusions.
And so I,
I strongly suggested to David that,
um,
the university is on the wrong side of
this,
that they picked the side of the social
warriors over this side of freedom of
expression,
or perhaps even as Jonathan Haidt has
pointed out,
perhaps even over truth and that that's
a huge mistake,
that they're violating the most
fundamental principle upon which the
university is predicated.
And I sincerely believe that to be the
case,
but I've decided to go forward with the
debate because I believe that a flawed
debate is better than none.
And perhaps all you can hope for in the
world of actuality is a flawed process
that can grow and struggle.
However,
wretchedly and awkwardly towards
something that might be regarded as the
truth.
So make no mistake about it.
This is what's happened.
The university has drawn the lines and
they have decided that if they have to
support political correctness slash
social justice,
um,
neo Marxism or freedom of speech,
then they're going to pick the former.
And not the latter,
and so that's the state of the art at
Canada's perhaps Canada's greatest
educational institution.
And I would say that's also the,
uh,
a diagnostic indicator of the,
shall we call it the state of the
polluted water works that make up our
current culture and as spokes frog for
the nation.
Let's say I'm,
I'm stating quite bluntly,
that we better clean up our act or
there's going to be hell to pay.
It's not easy being green
having to spend each day the color of
the leaves
when I think it might be nicer being red
or yellow or gold or copper,
much more colorful light.
Then.