Okay,
so we're going to wrap up Freud today.
So Freud
occupies a strange position in the
history of psychology because Freud
wasn't a psychologist,
he was a medical doctor,
and many of the people whose theories
were discussing that work clinicians
were mds,
not psychologists.
Well then of course when Freud was
around,
at least when he was trading,
psychology hadn't yet become an
independent science.
Now the same was true of Yom,
and part of the consequence of that was
that when the new science of psychology
developed into what you're studying
today is psychoanalysts and the medical
community basically stayed outside of
that.
And there's never really been a
meeting of the minds between
experimental psychologists and
psychoanalysts.
Although by the 1980s the cognitive
psychologists were promoting their
discovery of the cognitive unconscious,
which always felt to me a little bit
ungrateful given that Freud had actually
laid the groundwork for the theory of
the unconscious or an elaborated that in
quite great detail,
you know,
almost a hundred years before there's,
there's some resistance in this.
And that's what a psychoanalyst would
say.
There is some resistance among the
experimental psychology community to
Credit Freud with any of his real
discoveries.
And I think that's very unfortunate,
partly because he did make the
discoveries.
And B,
the psychoanalysts still understand more
about the nature of the unconscious than
modern experimental psychologists
because modern experimental
psychologists insist on viewing the
brain as that cognitive processors
something like a computer.
And that isn't what it is.
It's a living system composed of other
living subsystems.
And that means that as we've discussed
already,
that the human psyche and its
subordinate components are better
conceived of as personalities and
subpersonalities then in any other
manner then in systems or an or an
information or that information
processing machines.
And it's,
it's,
I think perhaps the most fundamental
accomplishment of psycho analysis
following Nicha actually to view the
human mind,
the human psyche as a place of
relatively integrated subpersonalities,
um,
mean
when even when modern people talk about
themselves,
they talk about the eye,
which would be roughly the ego in Friday
and terms,
they tend to think of themselves as a
unitary.
So nomina but
the problem with that notion is that
people continually do things that they
find themselves doing things that in
principle they don't want to do or
things that they're ashamed of or lying
when they don't want a liar,
generally misbehaving.
And so also of course everybody's
observations that you can try to tell
yourself what to do,
but that doesn't work very well.
So you know you've experienced this
undoubtedly in your own life many,
many times when you're sitting down and
you're trying to study for something,
particularly if you're not very
interested in it,
they had all sorts of alternative
possibilities will make themselves
manifest in your,
in the theater of your,
of your imagination.
And in a sense what's happening in those
situations is that
parts of you that that are organized,
organized around other goals or from the
authority perspective,
say driven by other desires are trying
to hijack control of your motor output
and that frequently happens so that you
find yourself,
for example,
procrastinating or rationalizing or
displacing,
those are all Freudian concepts at
displacement would be instead of doing
the work you're supposed to do,
you go off and do some other work.
No,
it's not a bad way of procrastinating,
but it's not great because you're not
focusing on what you should be focusing
on.
And so in some sense you're at war with
yourself and the major player in the
war,
at least in principle,
is the ego.
And that would be equivalent to Freud's
conscious money that at least in the
initial phases of his theory,
it's somewhat complicated to talk about
Freud because of course it's theory
developed across time and in the
beginning he basically broke the mind up
into the conscious mind and the
unconscious mind.
And you can think of the conscious mind,
well that's you.
Essentially that's the you that you can
refer to during day to day experience.
And then the unconscious mind is a
storehouse of two broad classes of
phenomena and one would be drives that
are grounded in instinct that are either
at odds with your current goal or
memories often traumatic that you
haven't been able to integrate into your
conscious framework.
And so those pesky things take on their
own life.
You know,
if you,
if you take an animal,
then you take out increasingly large
segments of its cortex,
say the animal still organizes itself
into that animal,
like it starts to lose function,
especially if you go deep into the brain
and you can kill an animal if you go
deep into the brain.
But if you stay on the cortical surface,
you can take an awful lot of brain
tissue out without interfering with a
lot of the animal's ability to sustain
itself.
And what that shows is that the brain is
organized in such a way.
So that isolated components of it,
we'll take on a function of the entire
personality,
not demonstration in some sense that the
sub elements of the,
of the psyche or or perhaps subsystems,
subsystems of the brain can organize
themselves into functional living units.
And it stands to reason.
I mean if you lose an arm,
you don't stop functioning.
You just reorganize your personality
minus the arm.
And if you,
you,
if,
if you have only managed to integrate a
certain subset of the potential psychic
manifestations of your mind,
then that subset is going to formulate
the main personality.
But all the other things that you're
ignoring or can't integrate,
they're going to have a life of their
own.
They don't just disappear.
And so Freud offers the unsettling idea
that you're by no means master in your
own house.
And one of the ways you can determine
that is by watching yourself do things
that you don't want to do.
And those are things,
for example,
that you'd have a hard time facing up to
because of course most of the things
that you don't want to do are things
that you might be ashamed of or anxious
about.
And then of course there's the defeat
that you suffer when you,
when your ego is hypothetically and
control of the circumstance and you find
your behavior or your thoughts directed
in some direction under the control of
something that you think that you've
mastered.
You can really see this in conditions
like anorexia.
So especially if it's accompanied by
Bulemia,
which it often is.
So anorexia is a,
an eating disorder that causes people,
I think essentially become extremely
disgusted with their own physiology,
with their own physical being and warps
their perceptions terribly.
So,
um,
I had,
uh,
an anorexic client at one point and um,
she was a rather small woman,
maybe five,
two or something like that,
quite thin.
Obviously she had anorexia and I asked
her what she was in my office if her
thigh was bigger or smaller than mine.
And she said,
well,
it was about the same size.
So I took a piece of paper and I'm sat
on at 10 I drew the outline of my thigh
on it.
And then I had her sit on the same piece
of paper and she drew the outline of her
thigh.
And of course there was probably that
much space on both sides between the two
outlines,
which probably looked at that for 15
minutes.
You know,
she,
she could not believe that that could
possibly be the case.
And I think what happens in our
anorexics is that they stopped being
able to look at their whole bodies.
So when you,
when you look at yourself in the mirror,
you kind of have to look in a gestalt
manner.
You have to get a picture of the whole.
Alternatively,
you can focus on small parts,
but the more you focus on parts,
the more difficult it is to see the
parts in relationship to the hole.
And anorexics get unbelievably focused
on small elements and they confuse
themselves.
So for example,
if they're looking at their arms and
there's some flesh on it,
they,
they are unable to make a distinction
between the flesh and fat.
And they want no fat,
they want to go right down to the bone
and they can't because they're concerned
about that tiny little part or maybe
this tiny little park or wherever they
happen to be focused there.
They get completely unable to perceive
their own bodies and it's quite striking
how far that can go.
And then the believe mick end of it is,
well the,
the person will starve themselves for a
long period of time.
And of course we'll think about this and
modern physiological terms feeding
behavior is regulated by the
hypothalamus.
And that's a,
that's an ancient brain area that the
controls fundamental motivational
systems and it's right above the spinal
cord and it's a very,
very,
very powerful center of Control in the
brain.
It's functional enough.
I think I told you this before,
that if you take a cat and you take off
its entire cortex and even most of its
emotional systems,
if you leave it just with the
hypothalamus and the spinal cord,
which basically means it has almost no
brain,
it can organize its behavior almost
perfectly as long as you keep it in a
simple environment.
So anyways,
the anorexic attempts to starve.
But so that's a conscious goal you might
say or or that might be an ego related
goal.
Or You could even think about it as a
goal that's motivated by other
unconscious forces because maybe she
doesn't know exactly why she wants to
start.
But in any case,
what generally happens is she'll run
into an emotionally upsetting situation
now,
emotional upset,
act,
say it,
it makes you anxious or it puts you in
emotional pain that activates higher
brain centers then the hypothalamus,
but they're still pretty low.
There's still pretty primordial.
And one of the things that kind of
emotional upset does,
let's call it stress,
is shut off your longterm planning.
And the reason for that is,
is that if you're stressed in the,
in the,
in,
in the immediate,
now your body and brain presume that you
should devote divert resources from the
hypothetical future to solving the
problem that's right in front of you.
And that's often a more behaviorally
oriented,
uh,
solution like freezing or withdrawing or
something like that.
So it shuts off your prefrontal cortex
on.
As soon as that happens,
then the hypothalamus,
which is as I said,
a very powerful system just reaches up
in some sense and dominates the person.
I mean it's been there for God only
knows how long,
you know,
tens of millions of years and it's job
is to stop you from starving to death.
And you know,
you could imagine that over the course
of evolutionary history,
anybody who had a relatively weak
feeding instinct died.
And so they were at our ancestors.
And so what happens to the Baleen is
something will upset them and then
they'll get an uncontrollable desire for
often something that's high calorie and
sweet and full of fat,
logically enough because they're
starving and then they'll eat like a
whole quart of ice cream in two loaves
of bread.
And you know,
they described the state that they're in
while they're doing that as dissociated,
you know,
it doesn't feel like them.
Well,
you can imagine why in some sense,
I mean partly is the whole realm of
eating behavior and it eating is as some
personality.
It's not just a behavior and it's not a
drive.
Like when you think about when you're
hungry,
it's not like your brain is moving.
You literally step by determined step.
It's that you start fantasizing about
food and you start thinking about what
you may be wanting.
Then you start to make plans about where
you're going to go or how you're going
to cook it and what social,
you know,
what social surroundings going to be in
a whole bunch of things.
And that's,
that's the hungry you well in an,
in an anorexic or Bulimic,
the hungry part of the person is so
dissociated from the part,
the ego part,
but they're basically in a war.
But one of the problems with being in a
war with your hypothalamus is that it
almost always wins and it's a good thing
because otherwise you die.
You know,
and lots of anorexic stu manage to
starve themselves to death.
And so that's a good example of just
exactly how dissociable the mind can be.
And the mind is,
is also the brain is dissociable in the
strangest possible ways.
So here's an example.
I don't remember the name of this
syndrome,
it might pop into my mind.
But so you can have a particular kind of
stroke.
And here's the effect of the stroke.
You develop the fixed delusion that a
person who's very close to you capgras
syndrome,
a person who's very close to you has
been,
has died or being kidnapped or somehow
disappeared and has been replaced by
their exact double.
And so and so it's obviously something,
it manifests itself as something akin to
psychosis.
And what happens is that the stroke
damages the relationship between the
generally the visual systems that
identify faces and the emotional systems
that tag that identified face with
familiar emotions.
So basically what happens is,
let's say it happens to you and it's
your mother,
you look at your mother,
but it isn't your mother.
You know,
your mother comes with a whole complex
of memories and you know,
she's sat in there in a very broad
context of memory and emotion.
And then you look at this person and it
looks like your mother,
but none of that is happening.
And so then you develop this idea as
well,
if it's not my mother,
it looks exactly like my mother.
Well then what could possibly be going
on in the answer as well?
Obviously she's being taken away and
replaced by her exact duplicate.
People get into real trouble with this
sort of delusion as you might imagine,
because they get obsessed with trying to
solve the problem.
Like what did you do with my mother?
And you can understand why,
but here's the,
here's a weirder thing even,
which is that it's,
it's modality specific so that if they
listened to their mother on the phone,
that's their mother.
So,
so you see exactly how dissociable the
brain is.
The mind is even down to small,
um,
sub function.
So there are people with strokes who can
sing,
but who can't talk.
And there are people who lose nouns and
there are people who lose only versed.
And there are people who can identify
things,
but they can't name them.
So the idea that the brain is a
dissociable entity is obviously correct.
And here's another example of it.
While you dissociate all the time.
Now,
if you look at the way the brain is
structured,
so there's a strip right about here
called the motor strip.
And if you are doing brain surgery and
you touch someone with an electrode on
that strip,
they'll move the corresponding part of
the body.
And the hands are very,
very overrepresented.
And so is the face and the lips and the
tongue for obvious reasons.
We fiddle around with the world a lot.
We move our arms and our hands a lot.
The feed are overrepresented too.
And then we communicate about that with
our face and our count.
So there's huge representation there.
Um,
so,
and if you touch that,
you'll get a mo emotion,
or at least the person who will will,
um,
describe a strong impulse to move well
out of that grew the prefrontal cortex.
And the best way to think of what people
think about that as the substrate of
abstract thought.
It's not really a good way of thinking
about it because you're not really out
to think you're out to act.
And the reason you think is so that you
can try out some actions in a little
world.
And found a seat before you implement
them in your behavior.
Right?
So to think things,
things through means to conjure up an
abstracted world and then to conjure up
a representation of yourself acting in
that world to calculate the consequences
and then to decide whether you're going
to implement it.
Well that's another form of dissociative
ability because you can think without
acting,
now you know it certainly that part of
you that's able to corner up the
alternative worlds that human beings
seem to particularly identify with.
You know that part that's thinking at
least modern people really think of the
part that's thinking as them or the part
that's capable of conjuring up abstract
ideas.
And if it wasn't dissociable you just
act out everything you thought,
well that wouldn't work very well.
So the brain is actually designed in
many ways,
so to speak,
to be dissociable now.
So if you understand that and then you
understand the two,
the two l of the two sets of phenomena
that are likely to be dissociated,
then you kind of got the essence of
Freudian theory and the things that are
likely to be dissociated are one
memories that were traumatic.
And I'll,
I'll talk about that in a minute.
And two impulses,
they're not,
they're not even drives,
which was the Freud,
you'd way of thinking about it.
They're subpersonalities troublesome sub
personalities.
And you can imagine that those would be
linked to complex,
positive and negative emotions.
One might be resentment,
guilt,
shame,
anger,
anxiety,
jealousy,
rage,
lust.
All of those emotions are,
are difficult to integrate into a
personality property.
Partly because in their pure
manifestation,
they're not there.
They disrupt the social order,
you know,
so like,
think about how well regulated all of
you are sitting here,
you know,
and you think,
well,
you're 6 million years since you
dissociated or since you've diverged
from chimpanzees.
If we took a bunch of chimpanzees that
knew each other as well as you know,
each other,
this place would be an absolute brutal
massacre.
So you know,
for,
for whatever reason,
you can control your primordial
instincts.
That's one way of looking at it.
That's how Freud would look at it.
You've learned to control them.
And Freud's theory,
and this is where it differs from the
theories that we talked about earlier,
say with regards to piaget,
Freud's theory is really more about
control.
He thought of all of these potential
subsystems and memories conflicting with
each other like a war,
like a Hob.
See in war.
So hobbes was the philosopher who said
that life is nasty,
brutal and short.
And that in the state of nature,
everyone is at war with everyone else.
And so you need a,
uh,
a Leviathan,
a talk down control system,
a Leviathan who will punish any deviance
from the social contract.
Well,
that's the Freudian Super Ego.
Now,
Freud thought of the unconscious and the
conscious mind to begin with,
but later he dissociated that up into in
ego and superego.
And then he thought that each of those
had their unconscious elements.
So you know,
so you,
if you're under the grip of an ID
related subpersonality,
let's say you can be conscious of that,
but there's the possibility for all
sorts of other interrelated
subpersonalities to emerge.
So those would be in your unconscious
and it's also possible and highly likely
in fact that the way that you're
perceiving the world and the way you're
acting in it and even what you state as
your goals are influenced in ways that
you don't understand by the action of
these unconscious systems.
So for example,
you know,
maybe some of you are headed for medical
school and if I asked you why,
he'll give me six humanitarian reasons.
But the actual reason is,
is because you know,
your grandmother would be disappointed
if you weren't and she might not even be
alive anymore.
You know,
she may have,
your mother may have imitated your
grandmother so that that ideal is firmly
embodied in her.
And that set up the unspoken
expectations about your behavior ever
since you were a tiny child.
So that's an interesting sub element of,
of psychodynamic theory too.
And it's really something to watch for
in your personal relationships.
It's very,
very frequently if you watch carefully
that you can see someone,
especially someone you love,
cause you have to know them well being
taken over in some sense by the spirit
of one of their ancestors.
And I,
I don't mean this in a metaphysical way,
I mean that the,
the,
the thought,
the personality of the grandmother or
the personality of the mother has a,
has a structure that's well known to
the,
to the individual in question.
And that individual spent a lot of time
imitating them in all sorts of ways.
And those imitated structures can be
passed down generation to generation.
I mean,
in fact,
that's partly what constitutes your
culture,
right?
It's the imitated personality of all of
your ancestors that constitutes your
culture and those things can possess
you.
It,
he ologies possess you and exact not
exactly the same way,
but in a very similar way.
So,
okay,
so you've got the end and you've got the
ego and the superego.
And as in the Harpsi and worldview,
there's real tension between them.
So that the end is always trying to get
its base gratifications it's based
desires ratified now in the in Friday
and times that was mostly problematic in
relationship to sex and the reasons for
that are quite clear.
There was no valid birth control,
there was very little employment option
for women.
So there's sexual behavior had to be
very,
very tightly regulated or they'd fall
outside of the social structure into
prostitution or something like that.
And then there was that,
the threat of various venereal diseases,
most particularly syphilis,
which is as awful a disease as you can
imagine it,
it can imitate or mimic all sorts of
other diseases and it's transmissible
from mother to child.
So it's a nasty one.
So sick.
It was very difficult for the victorians
to integrate sexuality because,
well,
exactly.
How did you do that there?
The the one pathway to potential
integration.
Something the Super Ego say would
approve of was a miracle pathway.
But you know,
people back then that,
you know,
in the 1960s people were getting married
around 19 or 20 but that's actually a
historical anomaly.
I mean typically speaking in the
Victorian age,
a man usually couldn't afford to get
married til he was in his mid to late
twenties he just didn't have the
resources and women who were married
usually younger than that,
but so there was a long period of time
for men particularly,
but also for women where the sexual
drive from a Friday and perspective was
in full,
was fully flourishing,
fully manifesting itself.
But there was no socially approved mode
of expression.
And so under conditions there's a war
between the ID and the superego in a
sense.
And the Portland Ego was crushed in the
middle.
Now you could certainly see that when we
were watching the movie,
the crumb brothers movie,
because they are basically in the same
situation,
right?
There was no socially approved way that
they could manifest any sexual or any
aggressive behavior.
And what happened as a consequence was
that the both of those fundamental
subpersonalities,
let's call them,
become incredibly pathologized as
particularly characterized by resentment
and the desire for revenge.
Because remember these systems think,
you know,
if someone's excrutiatingly sexually
frustrated,
let's say,
and let's think about it in the broader
scheme of things because sexuality isn't
really,
it's not a narrow unit,
dimensional drive it,
you know,
it's associated with playfulness and
it's associated with the desire for
social contact and the desire for
communication and the desire for
touching.
Like it's a complicated multi branching
phenomena.
Well,
in,
in the case of the people who we were
watching in the movie,
none of that was either integrated into
their personalities,
let's say,
or permitted by society.
And so it,
it,
it was bent and warped and,
and frustrated and then generated all
sorts of ideas about resentment and
revenge around it.
So you can develop an incredibly,
an incredibly pathological
subpersonality in the one cartoon,
if you remember when it was the one that
was most disturbing where Mr Natural
brought Robert that headless woman.
So he wanted pure gratification without
responsibility.
So it's a really it driven phenomenon.
And so he had intercourse with her and
immediately after that was unbelievably
guilty.
You know when you can see.
So you think about what that must mean.
It's like someone is under the grip of
one subpersonalities.
It's shaping all of their thoughts and
their memories and their emotions and
all of a sudden that becomes gratified.
So it's satiated,
it disappears in Bang up comes the other
one and it's,
you know,
wealth.
In this particular example it was guilt
and shame and anxiety,
terror even and self loathing,
all of those things.
And if you read about the experiences of
people who commit particularly atrocious
crimes,
it's very,
very common for them to experience
exactly that there are driven by sexual
slash aggressive impulses because those
are generally the ones that culminate in
a particularly atrocious,
you know,
individual crimes and they'll commit
them and then the instantly flip back
into their normative personality.
Except they're absolutely terrified by
what they did.
And you know,
it's more than one person is inhabiting
the same psyche and it's very,
now they're tied together by memory,
generally speaking.
Although Freud would say you can also
dissociate memory.
And so Freud talk,
talked about memories being repressed
and that's caused an awful lot of
trouble because,
well,
for a whole variety of reasons because
because memory is not cat memory is not
the object of recording.
It's not the objective unbiased
recording of actually occurring events.
First of all,
because you cannot actually objective
where you record certain kinds of
events.
Like we've talked about this before,
you can't really objective where you
record a discussion between a man and a
woman who'd been married for 20 years
about anything important because for
them,
each word and each phrase and each
sentence and each facial expression has
to be interpreted within the context of
the entire relationship in order for the
meaning of the utterances to be
extracted.
And there's just no way you can record
that in a video.
You,
you'd have to have video the entire
relationship and so you're not going to
do that.
And so memory is a very,
very peculiar thing.
And the idea that you could have an
objective record is not a very
sophisticated idea.
Anyways,
Freud's idea,
in some sense he had a rail,
uh,
somewhat,
I hate to say it was an insufficiently
sophisticated notion of what memory was.
Now I hate to say that because Freud was
a very sophisticated person,
but he did in some sense believe in the
existence of an objective interpersonal
world.
And so he thought if something terrible
happened to you when you were a child,
that you had a record of the memory,
it was there as the mammary,
as the event,
and then you needed something that would
like a sensor that would repress that.
And then you needed a place for it to be
repressed into,
which would be the unconscious.
But if you,
but if you take apart a traumatic
memory,
generally speaking with someone and he,
then he also,
sorry.
He also thought that that repressed
memory might be represented in a,
in a symptom,
a symbolic symptom.
So I think,
I think that the repression theory,
okay.
Suffers from the inadequacy of its
representation of memory.
Because here,
here's a different way of thinking about
it.
It's more in keeping with the layer more
than the hierarchical layer model that
we've been entertaining as we progress.
So imagine that you were molested by
your uncle because it's usually a family
member when you're for sexually
molested.
Okay.
The first thing you have to ask yourself
is just exactly what kind of memory do
you have.
Imagine you're completely sexually
naive,
which basically means you know nothing
about the sexual act and and it's,
and it's implications or the mechanics.
But this happens to you.
So the first question is how do you
represent that?
And the answer is because to rip,
to remember something,
you have to represent it.
That's the thing.
Cause you don't just have a memory of
that event.
It's always interpretation because
there's so many things going on.
Well,
so maybe you,
maybe your representation is pain and
confusion,
something like that.
And then there'd be another layer over
that which would be the necessity for
secrecy because of course the person who
does the molesting is going to tell you
what one of two things.
It's three,
maybe it's good for you.
You asked for it.
Um,
don't tell anyone or,
or they'll think you're a bad person.
This will be our little secret.
Something like that.
So then there's that whole overlay of
secrecy and inadmissibility.
And what are you supposed to do about
that?
When you're for how you're supposed to
understand that something has just
transpired,
that you're not allowed to share it with
anyone.
You don't have a model of the world
that's sophisticated enough to account
for all that.
And so then
perhaps from then on,
what you do is avoid thinking about it.
Now,
that's not the same as repression.
Avoiding thinking about something is not
the same as repression because it
doesn't require an active repressor in
order to do it.
And then maybe,
you know,
years later you start to recall what
happened.
But what you recall is an unclear mess
and the read and maybe most of it
because you might say,
well,
how are things represented as memories
when you can't develop a sophisticated
representation?
And what seems to happen,
and this is in a sense the reason
reversive Freud and theory is that
right?
The the
and is represented in the body.
And so you can think about the
representation of advance as a
multilayered neurological phenomenon.
And so if you were in town or something
that's unexpected or frightening,
the first thing that happens is that
very,
very ancient reflex of systems act
first.
And those things are fast.
And so that's the sort of thing that for
example might protect you against a
snake bite.
If a snake jumped out at you are going
to jump backwards.
And believe me,
you do that before you even see the
snake because it probably takes you a
quarter of a second to produce complex
visual representation of the snake.
And if you wait around for a quarter of
a second,
then you're dead.
And so what's happened is that your
nervous system has conserved basic
reflexes that are only a few snaps as
long.
So maybe those work between your retina
and your spinal cord,
your retina,
and maybe a very primordial emotional
system.
Like the Amygdala is wired up to detect
things like snakes and it just sends a
message down to your spinal cord or,
or slightly more sophisticated motor
control systems that says jump backwards
now and then maybe you think about it
isn't even till after that that your
heart rate goes up and your blood
pressure goes up and you start to
breathe heavily and then there's a wave
of fear and revulsion,
which is perhaps there to teach you not
to do such a stupid thing again.
You know,
we don't exactly know why you would
experience negative emotion,
you know,
or what function the negative emotion
has except that we do know that a
pattern of neurological behavior that's
followed by a punishment or a threat is
likely less likely to be re implemented
in the future.
Okay,
so the reaction to the anomalous thing
is barley and then maybe it's emotion
and then maybe it's image like
imagination.
You know,
what just happened and then maybe it's
articulated speech,
but lots of things don't get past image
to articulate in speech.
And some things I think don't even get
past body.
Sorry about that.
So I don't think that these traumatic
memories are so much repressed as Freud
had it as never brought forward for
development.
So,
um,
let me,
I'll tell you a story about how this
might work.
Okay.
So one time I had this client,
she was about 27 I only saw her once.
This is when I was just training to be a
psychotherapist.
And she came into me and she said that
she had been plagued by these thoughts
of being sexually abused when she was a
child.
And I said,
well,
who was doing this to you?
And she said,
well,
it was my brother.
And I said,
she said he was a lot older than me.
And so I formulated this mental model of
her being,
you know,
somewhere between 10 and 13 and her
brother being somewhere between say 15
and 20 because the way she described it
was,
you know,
that she was overpowered by our larger,
a physically larger male.
So we talked for awhile and then she
finally told me,
I said,
well,
how old were you when this happened?
And she said,
well,
I was four.
Okay,
and now,
and then I said,
well,
okay,
how old was your brother?
And she said,
well,
he was six.
And so I said,
well look,
you know,
here's one way of looking at it.
Like you're looking at it from the
perspective of the four year old.
It's a regression in some sense.
That's still how old you are as far as
experiencing the memory.
Here's an alternative hypothesis.
Your brother wasn't a Predator,
you were both terribly supervise
children.
Well,
you know,
that made the lights go on and you're in
her mind because she never thought about
it that way.
Like she'd never taken that
representation,
which would be her emotional experience
as a four year old related to a six year
old.
A six year old is a lot bigger and more
powerful than the four year olds.
Right.
It's,
it's,
it's you know,
50% owner.
So it's a big deal when you're four.
But if the,
if the issue for the memory is its
relevance to current conceptualization
and behavior,
it was much better for her to update the
memory in a sense.
And think,
well yeah,
like a six year olds this and like the
four year olds this high.
I'm like,
what the hell were my parents doing
anyways?
And that's an entirely different story
than,
than the one.
And she had come up with come in with,
you know,
and that seemed to be a great relief to
her.
And that's partly because,
you know,
if you're bothered by a traumatic
memory,
it keeps resurfacing on which it will.
And it's actually one of the ways of
identifying a traumatic memory is that
the thing won't leave you alone.
It keeps coming up and dreams.
And when your mind is wandering,
it'll keep coming up when your mind is
wandering and maybe it'll come up when
you're going to sleep at night and like
it invades your mind.
There's a reason for that.
And the reason is is that the underlying
emotional systems that are associated
with anxiety,
so those are mostly hippocampus and the
Amygdala duel duo in some sense that are
mediating those there an alarm system
and the alarm is something that's
potentially dangerous has happened.
You need to figure out what it means so
that you can miss stop that from
happening in the future.
Okay,
so you need a plan,
you need and get applied and you do have
to do a causal analysis of the
relationship between your behavior and
the traumatic outcome.
That would be the first thing and then
you have to come up with a way that that
won't happen again.
And of course for my client,
that happened pretty much right away
because now she was a 27 year old woman
and the probability that she was going
to be subject in any serious way to a
situation the same as the one she was
remembering was zero.
But,
and I've seen this in other clients too,
is when,
when they're,
when,
okay.
I had another client who,
who,
uh,
when she was,
I think I told you about her briefly,
when she was young,
four years old,
she jumped in a shopping cart and went
down a hill,
like a paved hill in the shopping cart
is filled out at the bottom and hurt
herself and they took her to the
hospital and you know,
so then she's all primed for being
threatened.
And then,
so that kind of means you're open to
rewire.
We need some sense.
And so then when she's in the hospital,
they don't let her parents come and see
her for a couple of weeks.
You know,
so the trauma,
the pain and the anxiety and the threat
than the ambulance ride and all those
things,
which sort of puts you in a state like
this,
which might be at like a,
uh,
state that's particularly conducive to
learning if something traumatic is
happening,
you should be learning about that,
what the world's like around that right
now.
And,
uh,
she developed it a permanent trauma
related paranoia about institutions,
which turned by the time I met her,
had turned into a whole philosophy of
institutional oppression.
But it's core was that terror.
And you know,
rightly so,
it's core was that combination of
physiological trauma and psychological
trauma and you know,
mishandling of the situation by people
in authority.
So,
so you can see under those circumstances
how a traumatic memory can become the
core,
a whole large subpersonality.
Now it has to be taken apart very
carefully,
especially if that sub personality isn't
the kind that can be easily integrated
into the world.
So,
for example,
if you're paranoid about all
institutions,
you're in real trouble because in a
modern world you're faced with,
there's necessity of dealing with
institutions all the time.
And if you're more distrustful and
paranoid about them,
then you couldn't be,
if you were sophisticated,
all of that's going to happen is they're
going to continually mistreat you.
Right?
Cause I mean if a dog comes up to you
and it's,
it's looking suspiciously and barking
and growling,
you're not going to pet it.
You know,
the way you interact with the system,
it depends the,
the reaction of a system to you is
dependent to a large degree on how you
approached the system.
So anyways,
the dissociate ability ideas,
a really good one
mean
if you want to get to know yourself
better.
And this is sort of a combination of
Freud and in union ideas.
One of the things to do is to,
so imagine that you have some sort of
goal in mind.
The first question is you that you might
ask yourself is why do you have that
goal?
What are the influences on you that have
set that goal up?
Cause it easily could be conscious or
partially conscious or poorly explained
or implicit,
any of those things.
So you want to know that,
why are you doing what you're doing?
Okay.
And the second thing is if you find
yourself avoiding things on the way to
that goal,
the next question is why are you
avoiding them?
And you know,
that'll mean delving into parts of
yourself that are quite hidden and quite
uncomfortable.
So for example,
if you discovered that the reason you're
pursuing a particular goal is because
it's what your parents want you to do,
one question that immediate you're rises
is,
yeah,
but is that what you want to do?
And you know that that's a very
complicated question because you'd have
to dissociate the part of you that's the
you that doesn't want to do it from the
part of you that's the you that does
want to do it.
And then you have to figure out why in
the world you'd be avoiding.
So you know,
it might be that you're an unbelievably
angry that you've been tilted towards
this particular goal for reasons that
have nothing to do with your choice.
And so that every time you have the
opportunity to study or,
or accomplish something that would move
you farther to that goal,
you're either not motivated.
So you can't pay attention,
you can't study,
you can't learn,
and you procrastinate all the time,
or you actually do seriously
counterproductive thing.
So people,
for example,
people can be
okay.
I just had someone write me here a while
ago,
um,
because he was watching the youtube
lectures and he said that he had dreams
for six weeks,
that he drove his car off a cliff and
crashed it.
And then at the end of the series,
he drove his car off the cliff and
crashed it.
And he asked me what that meant and I
said,
well,
the dream is telling you that you're
being far too careless with your life.
Like that's what driving cliff off a car
off a cliff repeatedly needs.
It's like,
you know,
that's a good descent,
unconscious descent into the underworld.
Well,
and he was being warned,
the,
the psychological reality was such that
the warning was extremely serious and so
was the danger.
And so then you might say,
well,
why would he drive himself off a cliff?
Well,
you know,
that's a suicidal gesture.
And then you might ask,
well,
why would money be suicidal?
And that could be,
well,
they're out for revenge against their
parents or they're out for revenge
against the whole world or they're out
for revenge against themselves or they
just want to make their painful
consciousness go away.
Or they're living a messy and pointless
and painful life and,
and they want to punish themselves for
it.
And you know,
it's very,
very complicated and tangled down there
at the bottom of things and people don't
really like to look into it.
And I suppose to some degree that's the
shadow element because what you find
there is seldom what you want.
I mean,
one of the prime victims of unions,
psychotherapy and most psychotherapies
are predicated on the idea that you
should find out what you're avoiding and
then you should figure out how to
voluntarily face it.
Now you might add to that,
you should find out what you're doing
and why and see if that's actually what
you want to be doing.
And if those reasons are reasons you
like that might you know in some sense
some up therapy in a couple of phrases,
but
in order to manage that then you have to
look at all the things you've been
avoiding.
Well,
what do you avoid?
it isn't rainbows and cookies,
right?
The things that you avoid are the things
that no one wants to look at and so
humans,
primary dictum for his psychotherapeutic
practice was a Latin phrase which is in
sterk wiliness invented tour,
which I'm probably pronouncing wrong,
which means either in fill it will be
found or where are you want most is to
be found where you least want to look.
You know those nausea.
That's what that,
that's how horrible philosophy,
but you can see that it's almost self.
It's almost self fulfilling because of
course the things you're going to avoid.
Are there things that you don't want to
face?
Obviously now the shadow element of the
psyche in some sense when you were
watching the movie,
for example,
you saw these drives mostly sexual and
aggressive that were manifesting
themselves in all sorts of ways.
And so that would be navy,
the repressed or unincorporated elements
of the end.
But then there was a side of,
there was another more complex side of
that where the,
the,
the people were reacting to that,
you know,
cause they felt downtrodden and
oppressed and,
and antisocial and critical of social
structure and all of that because they
were unable to manifest themselves
properly in the world.
And that produced fantasies of extreme
destruction,
exceptional destruction,
and for them,
and they were mostly sexually related,
but for other people that can manifest
itself in incredibly violent fantasies
about the destruction of society as
such.
So
if you can't invite all the parts of you
out to play,
the parts that get left behind are not
very happy about it.
And they don't just sit around having a
tea party,
you know,
they turn into,
they turned in,
especially as you mature,
they turn into these work monsters and
they're,
their mode of action in the world is
anything but positive.
And the Freudian world,
like the,
the,
the world of the psychoanalytic
unconscious is quite a terrifying place
because it makes you second guess
everything.
It's like,
it's not a paranoia.
Okay,
okay.
You never,
it's very,
very difficult once you're trained
psychoanalytically to ever assume that
someone's benevolent motivations are
only what they claim they are.
You're always looking for the other
missing piece.
And I think it's extremely useful
because you know,
you run into people in particular to
idiot logs who will claim that they're
acting on the world's behalf.
It's like,
yeah,
who made you is saying and why should I
believe that all the good is on your
side?
Like what is it that you're not talking
about?
What it is that,
what is it that you're not revealing?
I got something from Greenpeace once,
for example,
that was asking for donations.
And the brochure was just photographs of
all the people who were on the board.
I thought,
okay,
why do I want to see photographs of all
the people who are on the board of
Greenpeace?
Or the other question is why do they
want to show them?
Well you don't have to fake very hard to
figure that out.
You know,
it's a status maneuver.
What you'd expect in a mail out like
that is,
you know,
here's six things that we've done in the
last year that improve the planet.
And you know,
here's what we spent in relationship to
administrative costs and here's why it
was a good idea,
not here's our leaders.
Now there's something wrong there.
And I mean that's,
I picked Greenpeace cause it just
happened to pop in money.
But it's the case for all sorts of,
of organizations.
So,
all right,
so
freud by 1900 had identified a lot of
different functions of the unconscious.
And so here's four of them.
One was the unconscious,
how to conservative function,
which meant that it stored memories
often unaccessible to voluntary recall.
Now,
we don't really know how memories are
stored in the brain,
but here's,
here's I guess so when you have an
experience,
imagine that that produces a pattern of
neural activity.
It's just neuro,
but a pattern of that activity in your
brain and in your body,
at least part of how you remember is to
reactivate that pattern,
but it's not that simple obviously,
because otherwise you docked out all
your memories precisely and we don't
know exactly how that initial
pattern of experience gets edited down
to the thing you remember,
but we do know that it it,
it gets edited down in some ways as a
consequence of its relevance to your
current goal structure.
How that happens,
it seems computationally impossible.
We really don't understand how it
happens at all.
We don't understand how you can compute
what's relevant and what isn't.
It seems that the world is too complex
for that to even be possible.
So Conservative dissoluted the
unconscious contains habits once
voluntary,
now automatized and dissociated elements
of the personality which may lead a
parasitic existence.
That's,
so I talked to a little bit about
traumatic memories and how they might
form the node of the development of the
subpersonality,
but there's something else that's worth
understanding too.
So let's say you,
you start practicing a new minor mode of
being a new attitude or a new
personality attribute or new habit,
let's say.
It can be a fairly small thing.
When you first start practicing it,
you're not very good at it.
For those of you who are musicians,
you know when you first start to play a
piece,
you're very inefficient at it.
And then the more you practice it,
the more efficient you get.
It's,
it's quite weird.
I'm not a very good pianist,
but I learned to play one really
difficult song.
But the terrible thing is,
is a learn to play it.
And then at some point I'll realize that
I don't know the notes anymore.
And as soon as I realized I don't know
the notes,
I can't use those habit patterns
anymore.
And then I have to figure out the notes
again.
It's very,
very annoying,
but anyways,
when you first start practicing
something,
it's effortful.
It requires a lot of brain activation.
That's what the scanning studies show,
but as you practice it more and more,
the amount of the brain that you use
starts to shrink.
It generally moves left cause the right
hemisphere is more involved in novelty
processing.
It generally moves left and then it
moves back and the area gets smaller and
smaller and smaller until you've
generated up a little machine or it's a
little hard wired.
Some personality that takes care of that
particular operation.
Now that's where thinking about too,
because what that means in some senses
that your brain is full of the things
that you've practiced,
and that's not exactly psychological,
right?
It's psychophysiological.
It's part of your psyche,
but it's also hardwired into your brain.
If you want to overcome one of those
habits,
you have to build a new machine that
shuts it off.
You can't just get rid of it and then
what happens if you get stressed?
Often that new machine will get,
don't know exactly how it happens.
The stress will reduce the functioning
of the new machine and old habit to pop
back up.
Some of you all have noticed this.
How many of you have moved away from
home?
Okay,
so how many of you noticed when you go
to your family of origin that all sorts
of personality traits that you thought
you abandoned immediately come flooding
back?
So are you,
you know that,
you know that sensation,
right?
You go back there and it's like bang,
there's a groove and you're right in it
and you know,
maybe you're as mature as a 30 year old
when you're at your own house,
but as soon as you come home it's like
poof,
you're 14 again.
And it's partly because that's the
expectancy situation set up by your
parents.
But it's also partly because you just
don't understand how much of your
behavior is automatic and cued by
ongoing events.
It's habitual.
And so those,
you might think of those as somewhat
dissociated elements of the personality
as well.
Creative,
the unconscious serves as the matrix of
new ideas.
So that's a more union idea and the way
that seems to work.
You might think,
how in the world can you come up with a
new idea because it doesn't make sense,
right?
I mean,
what are you conjuring something out of?
Nothing.
Well,
and you can say,
well they're combinations of old ideas,
but you know,
that's not that helpful because you
can't just take a bunch of old ideas and
like shuffled them and come up with some
new spectacular ideas.
It's a lot more complicated than that.
So here's one way to think about
brought forward,
investigated in some sense,
the surface of the creative unconscious.
And he was more concerned about the
relay he called Freud's unconscious,
the personal unconscious.
So that might be the unconscious that
you have that's related specifically to
your experiences,
conscious and unconscious.
Like it can be d you'll have a dream
once.
For example,
hope I've got this right,
that Freud and him were excavating the
basement of a structure and that and
that you'll broke through and found
another huge structure underneath that.
And that's just about exactly right.
And so there's the personal unconscious.
And then underneath that,
in theory,
there's what you'd called the collective
unconscious and that would be,
God only knows what that is.
But in part what it would be is whatever
it is that makes you human from an
evolutionary perspective and we don't
know,
like you have a specific mode of being
that's a human mode of big,
I think it was Eo Wilson,
who's a great entomologist and also the
originator of sociobiology,
which is like a branch of evolutionary
psychology.
Um,
he studied dance forever and social
behavior of ants and he's one sad if,
if we could talk to enhance,
we wouldn't have anything to say to
them.
And what he meant by that is that like,
answer,
interested in a bunch of things that you
just don't care about at all.
Like they're not jealous.
They don't get jealous.
They don't fall in love.
They don't have sexual feelings or
behaviors.
They're not a cognitive creature.
It's like,
what the hell are you going to talk to
an aunt about how it's,
how is it going carry him?
That grain of sand,
it's like an ant.
Doesn't mean that doesn't even care
about that.
And so it's interesting.
It's really a profound observation
because what it indicates is that you
couldn't even communicate with someone
unless you were 99% the same as they
are.
Because to communicate with someone
means you have to share a whole massive,
immense set of presuppositions.
So for example,
if I say,
um,
I got jealous at a party last week,
it's like,
you're not going to say,
what do you mean jealous?
That isn't going to be your question.
You're going to say,
well,
what were their particular circumstances
that he elicited that response?
I don't have to explain anger.
I don't have to explain playfulness,
hunger,
oh,
you know,
all the basic human motivations that you
see displayed,
say the typical adventure movie or
romantic comedy.
It's like those don't need explanation
because we're the same.
And it's that sameness that constitutes
the essence of the collective
unconscious.
Now his hypothesis was that you're not
only biologically structured,
you know in terms of your morphology of
your physiology,
but that that extends right up into your
brain structure.
And even above that,
into the contents.
Either the contents of your psyche or at
least into the way that your psyche
becomes organized across time.
And you know,
it seems,
it seems like a hypothesis that's so
bloody obvious that you can't believe
that people would have disputed it for
so long.
But experimental psychologists were very
strongly influenced by behaviorists and
the behaviorist assumed partly for
ideological reasons and partly for the
sake of scientific simplicity that human
beings were blank slates and that all we
were was what we learned.
Well,
there's a book out now called human
universals.
I'm unfortunately,
I can't remember the name of the author
right now,
but it's a book.
It's a work of sociology slash slash,
anthropology and this person has
collected human commonality.
So what's the,
what's the same about people everywhere?
Well,
we pretty much all wear clothes
sometimes for protective purposes,
but if not generally for at least for
ceremonial purposes,
there's pair bonding in societies.
People Fall in love.
The basic emotions are the same.
We use fire.
That's a big deal.
You know,
cause no other animal can manage that.
There's,
there's literally dozens and dozens of
universal commonalities across people.
And that's part of the substructure of
the collective unconscious.
So anyways,
back the creative idea.
Well partly your creative act is going
to be a consequence of your attempts to
integrate the peculiarities of your own
experience with the peculiarities of
your culture and the spirit and did more
general
phenomena states of being that you share
it with other people.
So because you come into the world and
have your own viewpoint,
you're,
you have access to information that no
other person has access to.
And so to some degree that can be the
basis of your creativity,
just that information.
But then in order to communicate it,
which is also part of being creative,
right?
Cause he,
you can't just be,
if you're creative but no one can
understand you,
your,
it's more like your schizophrenia then
like your creative,
right?
You have loose associations and so
forth,
but you cannot put together a coherent
story.
So then you have to take that unique
information and integrate it with your
cultural knowledge,
your cultural narratives and grounded in
universal human biology.
And then you can present that as a
creative act.
Now
that's one possible place for the origin
of new ideas.
But here's another,
so
remember we talked about Piaget and
piaget basically said that to begin to
understand something you acted out.
So you represent the world with your
body by sitting on a chair,
you represent the chair with your body
by walking through a doorway,
you represent the doorway with your
body.
By grabbing a glass,
you do the same thing.
So you're matching,
you're imitating the world all the time.
So you're mapping it onto your
physiological structure.
So okay,
so that you get a sense that would be,
that's kind of what understanding means,
you know,
cause that's a complex term to sort of,
to understand what does it mean to
understand something.
It means to get a grip on it.
And you know,
we use those,
those terms for a reason.
It's to be,
you know,
you're standing firmly in relationship
to it.
You can handle it,
all of those things.
So that's one.
So that's the beginning.
But then also you're capable of
imitating so you can imitate yourself,
which is what you do when you repeat
experiences that had a positive outcome.
But you can also imitate other people.
But then you think,
okay,
well who are those people imitating?
Well,
the answer to that is it's like we're
led screens and we're constantly
rippling imitations of imitations,
of imitations,
of invitations across our physiological
landscape.
I mean you guys are the sum total of a
very long evolutionary process,
but you're also the sum total of an
incredibly long process of mimicry.
And so what you mimic is your culture.
So you can think of your culture.
It's something with the personality,
it's complex personality,
and it's the personality of your
ancestors that perfectly reasonable way
of looking at and you imitate that.
You know?
That's why we call our our laws of body
of laws.
And you could say that the legal system,
especially with English common law,
is the articulate,
articulated representation of the
imitative customs and rituals of the
entire society.
It's been brought right up into full
articulation,
but it was there to begin with.
So part of where you draw your,
your,
your material for creativity is that you
observe the behaviors and interactions
of all people who've been imitating all
people since the beginning of time.
And that's unbelievably informative.
It's way more informative than you could
ever represent.
You know,
how much information someone can
indicate with just lifting your eyebrow
a quarter of an inch,
right?
That can indicate irony.
Anik can indicate the relationship of a
joke to another set of jokes that that
person knows that you and it,
it's very complicated.
You can't articulate all that,
but in some sense,
you know it,
right?
You're a player in that game.
Well,
now and then,
so then imagine,
okay,
you've got all that embodied to the
degree that you're a sophisticated
player,
then your imagination is representing
you and it's representing the world.
So that's an abstraction,
right?
Because your imagination is not the
world.
It's a representation of the world.
And then what you can do.
So that means in the imagination,
there's all sorts of information that's
about the imitative behavior.
And then Ben,
you can talk about the image.
That's sort of what you do when you
interpret a dream.
So what's your dream doing?
Your imagination is watching you wander
around in the world,
you know when you have your category
systems and your theories and so forth.
And so then the dream puts forth what
that like an image,
an image representation of what that
might signify.
And it's in this weird language which
has an image,
an image laden language.
It can be,
it can range from completely incoherent,
just juxtaposed images to unbelievably
complex and sophisticated,
full develop narratives.
And that's part of the process by which
the information that's embedded in you
and the culture at a behavioral level
moves up to the imagination and then
pops up into articulated space.
So you have a dream,
the dream is about you.
And then you talk about the dream and
what you're doing.
You're trying to translate the images
into articulated representations.
And that's also a good way of thinking
about how memory moves from the bottom
up.
And what's interesting,
you know,
when sometimes you have a realization or
a moment of insight,
you know,
and that there's a feeling that goes
along with that.
It's like a charge.
And I think it's a charge that you get
from,
from simplifying something,
but also from experiencing the new
possibilities that emerge as a
consequence of that realization.
What seems to happen is that you have
the behavioral realm,
let's say the things you act out and all
the things you imitate.
It's very,
very complex.
And then on top of that,
you have the image of that,
right?
And you're trying to get the image
right,
but it's really hard because this
changes and this floats around.
So you're trying to get those lined up.
And then on top of that you're trying to
get your articulated representations
lined up so that you can say what you
know about who you are.
And when all those come together,
you think,
man,
I've got my act together.
But now and then you'll have an insight.
You know,
you'll think,
well like this woman who,
who I told you about who had be
molested,
the insight was while I was a little
kid,
but so was my brother Bang.
It's like wow,
all sorts of things that didn't make
sense anymore.
Just fall into place.
You get this articulated representation
that can sum up a whole bunch of,
what would you call them,
divergent and apparently unrelated image
representations.
And then all of a sudden your path
forward is clearer because you know more
about who you are and you know more
about how you,
where you're going.
So that is in large part what's
happening in psychoanalysis.
It's certainly what happens with dream
analysis,
which is something that Freud also
pioneered.
No Freud believed that dreams were
wished fulfillments and you know,
and he believed that the function of
dreams about wish fulfillment,
where to protect sleep.
So for example,
navy,
you're really thirsty and you go to
sleep and you dream about drinking
water.
Some of you who have consumed too much
beer the night before,
it might be familiar with those sorts of
dreams.
And so you're dreaming that you're
searching out fountains and you're
drinking and Freud's interpretation that
would be,
well,
you should stay asleep.
And so the dream is providing your
underlying,
interrelated motivational systems say
the one that governs thirst with the
fulfillment of its desire.
But I think that's,
I really think that's wrong,
although it's weird because dreams of
course could be doing all sorts of
things,
but what seems to happen instead,
I realized this most particularly once I
heard about a study about the effects of
testosterone cycling testosterone on
female sexual activity.
So the plan is this,
is that in women,
testosterone levels vary across the
monthly cycle and so does sexual desire.
And
what seems to happen is that as
testosterone,
testosterone increases,
the frequency of sexual acts doesn't
necessarily increase,
but the frequency of sexual fantasy
increases.
And so the f the hormone is driving the
fantasies and then the fantasies drive
the behavior.
It's something like that.
And so the dream isn't fulfilling a
wish.
What it's doing is that's how the
motivational system manifests itself in
a plan for action.
It's like,
well,
you could be,
you should be going to look for sources
of water if you're thirsty.
And so because of the,
you know,
your hypothalamus has to communicate
with you somehow.
It doesn't just grip your behavior and
move you around like a robot,
you know,
it has to indicate what the state,
what your state is.
It does that all sorts of ways.
And then start tilting you towards a
solution using your memories and your
skills and everything that would be
related to successful outcomes of that
form,
that form in the past.
And the other thing I should say about
creativity,
and this is I think something very
useful for understanding people's
reactions to psychoanalysis.
I have a lot of creative people in my
clientele for a variety of reasons.
And some who aren't creative and
creativity is a trade and most people
aren't creative.
It's not common.
So,
and some people who are creative are so
creative,
it's just absolutely beyond
comprehension.
So,
um,
Picasso for example,
created 65,000 works of art three a day
for 65 years now that guy was created.
So anyways,
lots of people aren't creative and
they're not interested in psychoanalytic
ideas.
They're not interested in architectural
They're not really gripped by narrative.
So if you happen to be one marker for
creativity,
by the way,
for openness is I'm really liking
fiction.
So,
and women actually like fiction more
than men and because women are actually
slightly higher and part of openness,
the men are.
So what else?
If you,
you like poetry,
you know,
and it gives you an aesthetic,
an aesthetic experience.
If you really get deeply involved in
music,
if you're able to produce things that
are created.
So if you have the kind of mine that
works in association.
So for example,
if I told you guys up,
all right,
write down as many words as you can in
the next three minutes that begin with
the letter l.
Those of you who are more creative would
come up with more words.
So there's a verbal fluency component,
I could say.
Okay.
Um,
how many uses can you think of for a
break?
And then I would score that.
The first would be how many uses you
came up with.
That'd be the sheer number I'd throw
away.
The stupid ones that make no sense.
And often you have to get a panel of
people to,
to make that judgment strike you.
You know,
you could say,
well it's a thing.
You could use it as a thing.
It's like no x,
you don't get,
you don't get a score for that.
So then you get another score for how
uncommon your response was because
that's an originality dimension.
And actually if you calculate those two
dimensions,
fluency and originality from a divergent
thinking tasks,
which is the one I just told you about,
you can predict how creative people
aren't quite well anyways.
The really creative people seem to have
a deep wellspring of unconscious ideas
that are always flowing forth.
And some of those people dream like mad
and they have extremely sophisticated
and complex dreams and those dreams seem
to guide their behavior.
So,
and that's quite,
that's quite entertaining when you see
that in psychotherapy,
if you have an interest in such things
and you might say,
well,
how do you know if your dream
interpretation is true?
And that's for that is,
well,
how do you know how you interpreted?
The last book you read is true and
that's you.
That is you don't know how you don't.
And even if you did and you don't know
how you know it,
right?
Because lots of people can read a book
and they come away with slightly
different interpretations of it.
And that's because did imagine that the
book is a multilevel pattern and then
the reader is a multilevel pattern.
And then if you put those two together,
you get a multilevel pattern that's made
out of the reader end of the book.
And that's going to be unique for every
single reader except that we have
commonalities of structure and so that
we can communicate about it.
So you read a book and it strikes you,
certain things strike you and certain
things seem right.
If you do a dream interpretation,
it's a collaboration between you and the
client about the,
about the interpretation.
So usually what I do is I have people,
first of all,
they'll tell me their dream from
beginning to end.
Now,
Freud would say already you're
introducing all sorts of bias because
they're not telling you the dream.
They're telling you the dream as they
interpret and remember it.
It's like,
yeah,
that's a problem.
So,
but you do what you can,
you know,
and I tell people,
just write it down as fast as you can
and try not to think about it too much
because we don't want post dream
editing.
So then I'll listen to it and then then
they'll tell it to me again slowly,
and then I'll listen to a sentence and
I'll let my associational network work
on it and see if,
see what that reminds me of.
And then I'll ask the person what it
reminds them of.
And then we'll talk about these.
Those are the direct associations.
So those are the things Freud would call
free associations.
And you could say,
well around every utterance,
like a sentence,
there's a collection of potential
meanings,
right?
And those meetings might be direct
meanings,
like really tightly associated with it
to sort of loose meanings.
And so you can hit it back and forth
with the client and therapist until you
faint.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
That seems to be,
that seems to be where that's going.
And you're also thinking about it and
relationship to the person's current
life experiences and the rest of the
dream and maybe all the dreams they told
you about before.
So it's insanely complicated,
but it's what people do when they listen
to a conversation,
you know,
how do you,
how do you know your interpretation of a
conversation is true?
Well,
you know,
there's a variety of ways that you can
approximate that,
but yet you don't know.
And there's lots of different ways of
interpreting a conversation.
That's why the postmodernists,
you know,
ended up in their little hole with
regards to literature.
They realize that,
well,
there's no limit to the number of ways
you can interpret a book.
And,
but then they took the next step,
which,
which was that therefore it has no
meaning.
It's like,
no,
wrong,
wrong.
That's very unsophisticated thinking.
It just means that the way the book
portrays meaning is exceedingly complex
and you can't describe it using normal
linear rationality doesn't mean the
meaning isn't there.
That's so pathetic cetera.
That it's dangerous too because it means
that nothing has any meaning.
And you know that's the most dangerous
theory that,
so anyways,
you talked to the person about the dream
and the dream image and about what that
triggers off in their memory.
And you also watch what they say because
sometimes,
so for example,
someone,
this just happened recently,
someone might be describing a dream
where they,
you know,
where they're wandering around somewhere
and they'll say,
and I'm taking the wrong road.
You Think,
oh,
okay,
well now we know what your dream meant
cause you just said it.
I'm taking the wrong road.
And that's a Freudian slip.
And it's so interesting because if you
listen to people tell their dreams,
you have to kind of listen.
It's like they have two minds talking at
the same time and one is describing the
dream,
but the other one is describing their
life and they don't even notice the
connection.
And you pointed out and they go,
oh yeah,
right,
right.
I didn't know I said that.
And that's a Freudian slip.
And I think what's happening in part is
the right hemisphere,
which is an image accumulation and
aggregation system.
It's kind of a low resolution pattern.
Collection System uses mostly images and
it tries to put them together in
meaningful ways,
but the meaning is vague and
comprehensive and then the left
hemisphere roughly speaking,
which is the linguistic hemisphere,
is trying to state what that says in
words and it's very difficult to make
that,
to make that transformation,
but that's why I dream analysis works
and part is because you're facilitating
the movement of the information in the
images into the articulated part of the
personality.
You're moving information up the
abstraction hierarchy to the point where
it can be well utilized and that's now
I'll end this with,
I'll end this discussion of Freud with a
description of some research that was
done recently by relatively recently,
let's say the last 20 years by this
psychologist at the University of Texas
at Austin who's name is James Pennebaker
and pennebaker's,
a particularly smart psychologist.
He had this idea,
Freud had another idea that was related
to therapy and he thought that what
happened if you came into therapy and
you talked about a traumatic event with
that you are cured by Catharsis,
which meant that that trauma had to have
a bunch of emotion associated with it.
And that was repressed.
But it was down there and kind of
struggling to get up and causing you all
sorts of stress and misery,
trying to hold it down.
And then if you could just tell someone
about it and like express your feelings,
then that would help you.
Expressing your feelings does not help
you by the way.
But,
but because that turns out to be wrong,
although it's wrong in an interesting
and useful way,
cause it's sort of,
it's almost right.
So with pennebaker did was he took
undergraduates and he had them come into
the lab and for three on three sick,
sick quenches days and he had them write
for 15 minutes each day about the worst
thing that they had ever done or the
worst thing that had ever happened to
them.
Often people are traumatized by
something they did.
Not something that happened to them.
In fact more often cause someone watches
themselves do something absolutely
horrific.
And then they think,
oh my God,
I did that.
Who am I?
They don't know.
Then that's,
you know,
things started coming unglued.
So anyways,
pennebaker had them do that and then for
the next two weeks they felt pretty
wretched about it.
And so that's interesting cause if they
would have only measured the result of
the intervention in a two week timespan
everyone wanted to said,
never,
never write down your traumatic
experiences cause it'll make you worse.
But over the next six months,
what happened in particular was that
their physical health improved.
They went to the doctor last,
they reported less illness and so forth.
It's because their overall level of
stress decreased for complex reasons
that we can talk about later.
But then pennebaker being and excellent
scientist,
he thought,
okay,
well Catharsis works here.
You're expressing your,
you know,
trauma and poof you're fixed.
But he went back and he thought,
well wait a second,
maybe how you express it matters.
So we went back and he counted all the
words that were associated with emotion
and all the words that were associated
with understanding and cognition.
And what he found was two things.
One was the more words that you used,
particularly as your narrative developed
that indicated comprehension and
understanding the better you did over
time.
And so what happens is not,
it's not the expressing of your emotion,
it's the expressing of your emotion and
then the weaving of the memory into a
new coherent representation from which
you derive a moral.
So what's the moral of a trauma?
Don't let it happen again.
That's the moral and the the threat
systems are going to be throwing that
thing up at you constantly until you
figure it out.
How did I get into this?
How do I avoid it in the future?
And it doesn't mean it's your fault,
but your anxiety systems,
they don't care about that.
They care about how you're not going to
fall into the same hole.
And the only way to do that is to
analyze the causal pathways that lead to
the whole to begin with and see if you
can either reconfigure your behavior in
your attitudes so that that doesn't
happen again.
Or maybe you just don't go those places
anymore,
you know,
either way and you're the trauma threat
systems.
As soon as you come up with a
comprehensive representation that you
believe in,
they'll leave you alone.
And this can happen very,
very rapidly.
Like with nightmares,
I,
I've cured people's nightmares in one
session,
no problem.
I asked them to bring the nightwear
mirror too,
opt in to their imagination.
Maybe someone's chasing them.
It's like,
okay,
think about them chasing.
You got to visualize it.
Really visualize it.
The more real you make it,
the better.
Okay?
They're being chased.
How are you feeling?
I'm all anxious in the frame.
Okay,
turn around and look at the thing that's
chasing you.
So they do that.
Then maybe they tell saying what it is
or whatever,
but maybe they don't even do that.
And I say,
okay,
now,
before you go to bed at night,
just when you're almost falling to
sleep,
you're in a hypnagogic state where
images are starting to come.
You run that,
they run that Poof,
that nightmare is gone.
And the reason for it is that they've
now reconfigured themselves as the
thing,
not the thing that's being chased.
That's prey animal.
They've configured themselves as the
thing that can turn around and face the
thing that's chasing them.
And that's the same Motif as the dragon
hunting the union archetypes,
right?
Face what you're afraid of it not will
cure you.
And that's really one of the fundamental
motifs of Freud and psychoanalysis.
So you know,
when you have an exam on Thursday,
I'll post questions about sort of
representative questions on the exam
when I get home after this lecture,
probably deceiving the liquor there.
The essays are,
that test is here.
It's multiple choice.
You'll have no problem finishing it.
It's not that loan.
And if you've done the readings and come
to the lectures,
you'll probably do fine.
So it's not a tricky test.