So
here's how to conceptualize yourself in
union terms.
Okay.
The part of you that you consider you
roughly speaking young,
considered the ego and you might think
about that as the most individual part
of your cycle.
Physiological being,
I mean
the difference between individual and
collective in that sense is that you
share very many attributes with other
people.
Obviously your physical form is very
much like that of other people.
And then you share attributes with other
living creatures way back down the
phylogenetic chain.
And so in that regard,
there's nothing specifically individual
about you.
Okay.
But the part of you that you identify
with most completely and that you regard
as unique,
that's the union ego.
Now young sort of conceptualized your
psyche as a,
as a,
I would say as a place I suppose that
many spirits could inhabit and you might
think about a spirit.
Okay.
From,
from the union perspective as
okay,
a personality that can inhabit the
psyche.
And so like all of the psychoanalysts
young regarded the psyche as a
relatively loose collection of partially
integrated personalities.
And each of those personalities had
their own perspective,
their own thoughts.
Like their own way of looking at the
world.
That would be the perspective,
their own thoughts,
their own emotions,
their own habits,
their own actions.
And those are roughly aggregated into
some sort of unity.
And that was the,
that was the ego.
Now
ego has a public face and the public
face,
you don't call it the persona.
Persona means mask and the persona is
both that part of you that you showed
other people instead of the part that
you hide.
And then also to some degree it might be
the form that your ego takes even to
you.
So for example,
if you're a naive person,
you might think that your public face is
all there is a view
that the rough difference between the
ego and the persona might be
conceptualize this way that
you know there are things that you think
that you won't say in public,
maybe not even in private.
Okay.
Some of those things you're pretty aware
of and those would be thoughts that are
relevant to the ego but not the persona.
And then some of them you don't even
really want to be aware of and young
would consider those more associated
with the shadow now.
Okay.
The Shadow,
the existence of the shadow.
First of all,
you might want to remember that the best
way to conceptualize umes archetypical
constructions is in some sense as
metaphors.
So you could say that while you thought
that it was useful to separate up the
psyche into persona,
an ego and then shadow,
it isn't that there aren't other ways
that it could be broken up,
but breaking it up this way is useful
for certain purposes.
And Yoni regarded this terminology as
particularly useful from a
psychoanalytic perspective and also from
a historical perspective.
So
perhaps the divisions could have be
made,
could be made otherwise,
and there are many ways of looking at
archetypes,
but this is sufficiently useful to
progress with.
Now,
people's personas are generally somewhat
harmless and somewhat socialized.
If you don't know how to act in public,
you don't have a well crafted persona.
You know,
some of you are going to be the kinds of
relatively deep thinking intellectuals
who think that small talk is nonsense
and uh,
there is some utility in that thinking
because in some sense,
from a philosophical sense,
obviously it's nonsense.
But if you don't know how to make small
talk,
basically what that means is that you
have a poorly developed persona.
And what that'll mean is that you're not
going to do very well,
at least at the beginning of social in
social engagements because you need to
be able to convince people that you're
basically civilized and social before
it's even reasonable for them to go
beyond pleasantries with you.
And the ability to exchange pleasantries
in a relatively banal way in a variety
of different circumstances is part of
having a persona.
And you don't want to denigrate the
utility of that because you need it.
You know,
as you progress in your careers,
for example,
you're going to be thrust into
situations where you don't really know
anyone.
And the purpose of the gathering is to
familiarize a large number of people
with one another.
And there's a skill that's associated
with that that's somewhat Glib,
social ability.
The unions would say,
well,
you shouldn't,
if you don't have a persona,
you're just a disaster.
But by the same token,
you shouldn't be only persona because
one of the possibilities is that the ego
can identify with persona and then the
person thinks that they are what they
show the social world.
And the problem with that,
at least from the union perspective,
is that,
um,
a people are a lot more than the
persona.
There are a lot more than the ego and be
a lot of the things that make them more
than mere persona or mere that more than
mere ego are not necessarily things that
are acceptable in casual public
gatherings.
So for example,
because of your psychophysiological
makeup,
you all have the capacity for
aggression.
Now,
a lot of you,
especially the ones that are more
agreeable,
you could say that even it's either that
that capacity for aggression has been
underdeveloped because you've identified
with a certain mode of social being or
you could say perhaps if to the degree
that agreeableness is temperamental,
that the aggressive tendency isn't as
powerful in you as it is and other
people that might lead you to make
judgements like,
and I'm sure some of you,
perhaps some,
some of you who had an angry parent or
particularly an angry father have
decided at some point in your life that
to be aggressive is wrong,
to be angry is wrong,
for example,
or to be aggressive is wrong.
It's morally wrong.
One of the things that happens in
psychotherapy very frequently though is
that people come into psychotherapy for
a variety of reasons.
Some of them are merely practical.
They're having problems in adaptation
because their lives have got very,
very complicated and they really don't
know what to do about it.
Sometimes they go into psychotherapy
because they have very high levels of
negative emotion and that can be
associated with the first problem.
But very often they come into therapy
because they're getting pushed around
constantly and they really don't have
anything that's a sufficiently well
developed personal identity and
generally those that happens by the way
most more often with women than it does
with men.
And that's because women are by
temperament,
more agreeable than men.
And perhaps also by socialization.
Um,
temperament certainly plays a big role
often then they,
the goal of therapy is assertiveness
training and assertiveness training you
could think of as the behavioral
psychologists equivalent to
incorporating the shadow.
So,
you know,
you may think,
well it's,
it's a necessary part of existence to be
nice to other people.
And there's some truth in that.
Not really.
It's a very shallow way of looking at
the world because nice is not a very
sophisticated work.
But even if that's the word that you do
use,
you should also be nice to yourself.
And sometimes what that means is that
you have to put forward your own wishes
and desires in a manner that causes a
certain amount of conflict.
And in order to withstand that conflict,
you have to have,
you have to be able to draw on the
sources of aggression that in some
sensor are,
are,
are a deep part of your,
your inbuilt set of possibilities.
Now the reason that's necessary in part
from a biological perspective is that
people are often afraid of engaging in
conflict because they're afraid because?
Because,
because conflict can be real trouble and
anger inhibits fear.
So if you don't have a well developed
capacity for while we could say rage,
then you can't overcome your fear and
then you can't stand up for yourself and
then you're going to get run over.
Now the problem with that is is that if
you get run over enough,
it'll make you resentful and then that
will make you aggressive except it'll
make you aggressive and sneaky
underground and somewhat unconscious
ways that are much less likely to be
productive.
Then you know,
a frank exchange of viewpoints and some
conscious negotiation.
So one of the things I do in therapy for
people who need assertiveness training
is I get them to pay attention to their
resentment.
And resentment is often a good avenue
into the shadow because first of all,
resentment is a pretty destructive
emotion.
It's extremely useful emotion,
but it can be very destructive cause it
gives rise to,
well first of all sense of victimization
and second then the underground growth
of all sorts of ideas of revenge and
vengeance and and also a kind of
stubborn non cooperativeness because
who,
who wants to cooperate when they feel
taken advantage of.
And so part of young's idea with regards
to the shadow is that obviously the
social world wants you to be peaceful
and predictable and maybe even easy to
get along with.
But that doesn't necessarily mean that
peaceful,
predictable and easy to get along with a
are the only virtues because they're
certainly not.
And one thing we know about virtues is
that if they're taken to two,
great at an extreme,
they become vices.
And B,
there are certainly not the only
virtues.
You know,
there are what you might call darker
virtues,
so to speak.
There they're more dangerous virtues in
some sense because they harness forces
that can be very destructive if they're
not utilized consciously.
And aggression is certainly an example
of that.
So here's some fundamental rules about
the shadow that you might think about as
you move forward through your life.
So a lot of times you're going to have
to negotiate on your own behalf.
And so what that means from the
perspective of agreeableness and
aggression is that you should be able to
stand up for yourself at least as well
as you would stand up for someone that
you care for.
So the problem with the idea of being
nice to other people is that it doesn't
take you into account.
And that's supposed to be an equation,
even though it's,
as I said,
nice is a pretty weak philosophical
term.
But the fundamental rule is that you
should certainly include yourself in the
circle of people who deserve respect and
care.
And that means that you have to be
willing to advocate for yourself.
And if you're willing to advocate to
yourself for yourself and you want to do
it,
you have to be able to say no.
You have to,
because otherwise you have to say yes
and then you can't negotiate.
And in order to say no,
you have to have armed yourself with
strategies and plans that enable you to
say,
no,
you can't be dependent.
You can't be afraid of potentially
searching out new opportunities,
et cetera.
You have to be willing to stand your
ground.
And it's very difficult to do that
without drawing on some of the deeper
sources of psychological energy that are
part of our psychophysiological
heritage.
So young would say,
well,
there's the persona and the ego and you
can identify with your persona and then
you're,
you're a kind of a shallow puppet of
culture.
So Pinocchio as the Marionette is a
Persona Pinocchio himself as an eagle,
but as a Marionette,
he's the persona.
So anybody who's ideologically
possessed,
by the way is a persona,
although they're also possessed by the
shadow,
even though they don't know it.
And you can tell when someone's
ideologically possessed because you can
predict whatever they're going to say
once you know,
a few axioms of their particular
radiology.
So given ideology probably has four or
five explanatory,
um,
axioms,
like everything is caused by economic
disparity.
That might be one.
Um,
or success is due to hard work,
that might be another,
and those are broad enough statements,
even though they're in opposition to one
another,
both of those statements are broad
enough so you can virtually explain
everything with them.
The problem with it is,
is that you can predict what the
explanation is going to be before you
even have to talk to the person.
And whenever you're talking to someone
and you can predict exactly what they're
going to say because they're using some
idiot,
logically mediated structure,
then you know perfectly well that
they've identified with the persona.
You also know that they're likely to be
possessed by a pretty vicious shadow
because we know that the shadow of
ideological possession is repression and
death.
So one of the things that's always
interesting about the psychoanalysts is
that whenever they see something good,
they're always looking for the dark side
of it and vice versa.
By the way,
whenever they see anything dark,
they're looking for the good side of it.
And so they're very unlikely to take
anything at face value.
And so if someone comes up to you and
says,
I stand for some good thing,
the thing that you ask,
you're a psychoanalytically minded is,
well,
what does that mean that you hate?
Because there's a reasonable probability
that even though you think that you're
standing for something,
that a lot of what's motivating you is
the desire to be against something.
And that's particularly the case when
you're dealing with,
with negative emotions because they're
more powerful than positive emotions.
So it's one of the things,
George Orwell,
who was one of the 20th century's great
anti Edea logs,
published a book in the 1940s Thirties
forties called up road to Wigan pier
where he went to stay with some coal
miners in the north of England.
And those coal miners,
man,
they had a hard life.
Like some of them had to crawl three
quarters of a mile to work in tunnels in
the morning in tunnels where they
couldn't stand up just to get to work.
So and then they do,
they're like 10 hour shift in the coal
mine digging out call and then they'd
have to crawl back three quarters of a
mile underground,
you know,
so they had very,
very hard lives.
And so you know,
Orwell was pretty unimpressed by the
conditions in which they were forced to
work.
So he wrote an essay for the English
left book club and they were,
that was a socialist publishing house,
but he upended another essay to it where
he criticized the socialists who are
most likely to read that sort of book as
much more oriented towards hating the
rich.
Then then loving the poor as devastating
criticism.
And the left book club didn't even want
to publish his book,
but they ended up publishing has become
a very famous essay,
but it lays out a general principle.
It's like if you have identified with a
given persona,
which is like a,
a social machine in a sense,
and you think you're all good because of
what you think,
then you might ask,
well where'd all the parts of you that
aren't good go?
Because unless you think that you're a
saint and that everyone who thinks
differently than you is Satan himself,
then you're missing a chunk of yourself.
You're not taking a chunk of yourself
into account.
And that's the part that is nowhere near
as well behaved or as benevolent as you
might think or that you actually have
any reason to believe,
you know?
And so one of the things that has struck
me as a consequence of analyzing 20th
century history and,
and often through a union lens,
is that there's not much evidence that
the sorts of atrocities that
characterize the Soviet Union,
um,
and,
and Nazi Germany were the result of a
few extremely corrupt people at the top
of the hierarchy,
forcing everyone down into slavery and
then making them do terrible things.
I think that's a very weak explanation.
In fact,
I think it's,
I think it's wrong.
I think the historical record is quite
clear that it's wrong.
I mean,
in East Germany for example,
one third of the people government
informers.
So that means if you had a family of
six,
two of your family members were
reporting on you to the government.
So when you look at human capacity for
destructiveness,
if you don't regard yourself as one of
the agents of that destructiveness,
or at least one of the potential agents
of that destructiveness,
then from the union perspective,
at least there's a high probability that
you're part of the problem rather than
part of the solution.
Now,
that doesn't necessarily mean that you
should be blamed for it because blame
has to come from another person and it
isn't obviously clear that like I get to
blame you for being potentially violent.
That's I think is a complete mistake.
But if you,
if you familiarize yourself with the
realm of human capability and then you
regard yourself as human,
what that means is that you have to
regard yourself as a creature that's
capable of what human beings are capable
of.
And human beings are capable of a lot of
things and some of them are absolutely
wonderful.
I mean,
there's nothing more remarkable than a
human being on the planet.
I mean,
people can do amazing things.
But the downside of that is that we can
do absolutely horrible things.
And it's not obvious that it's only the
pathological people who do that.
In fact,
it's,
it's that,
it's not reasonable to assume that.
So the shadow for young was a very big
deal,
you know,
and he believed in some sense,
and this is where the idea is get
archetipal.
He believed that the ideas of,
of,
uh,
the evil twin of the king or the evil
twin of God for that matter,
so that would be Satan and Christian
theology.
That was,
uh,
that was as real a representation of the
human and transpersonal human capacity
for evil as there was.
And he believed that if you look deep
enough into your own follow motivations,
and if you look far enough down that
you'd be looking,
so to speak,
into hell itself,
and you'd find the main controller of
hell deep inside your psyche.
So it was no journey for the timid.
And you'll also believe that,
and this is what separates him from a
new age thinker because he's often
accused of being a new age thinker.
New Age thinkers tell you things like
follow your bliss and you'll,
you know,
you'll run into utopia,
your own counter utopia.
But that isn't what the unions
especially young said about his process
of individuation at all.
He said that if you follow what's
meaningful and you do it,
honestly,
it will take you somewhere.
You really do not want to go.
And until you go there,
you'll never be able to climb up higher
on the other side.
And so that provides a real impediment
for enlightenment because for
enlightenment,
there's a price to be paid.
And if you look at architectural
representations of the cost of
enlightenment,
you often find that the person who
becomes enlightened has,
is damaged in some profound way before
it happens.
So for example,
in the ancient Egyptian stories of
Horace and Oh,
Cyrus,
horace loses an eye when he has to
encounter set who's the ancient Egyptian
equivalent of sate.
So it's no joke.
It's seriously no joke.
You know,
and it's,
you know,
one of one of young's propositions
essentially was that the human race will
continue to be plagued by phenomena like
the outbreak of the genocidal Nazi and
Soviet ideologies.
Until people realize that the Nazis and
the Soviets are them,
that it isn't someone else's problem.
It isn't other people who weren't you,
it's you.
If you were there,
it would've been you.
And you might say,
well,
no,
I would have been a hero.
It's like,
no,
probably not.
Because they were rare.
And I mean,
unless you have real reason to think
that you could have done it,
then it's safer to think that you
couldn't have and wouldn't have.
And so then there's a responsibility
that goes along with that.
And the responsibility is to broaden
your capacity of who you are so that you
have the possibility of controlling the
parts of your psyche that are very dark.
Now,
let me give you some examples of this.
So you know,
there's a philosopher named Bruce,
so,
and most of you are resilience without
knowing it.
And Russo basically made the following
propositions.
He said that human beings were basically
good,
but they were corrupted by culture.
So human essential human nature was
good.
And the corrupting influence was was
society.
Now that's true,
but it's only half true.
And there's a philosopher named hobbs
who said exactly the opposite thing.
He said,
no human beings are base and violent and
uncontrollable.
And unless we have society structuring
their interactions,
he was more like Freud structuring their
interactions.
They would be constantly at one
another's throat.
And then if you think,
well,
who's right,
Russo or hobbs,
first of all,
they're both right.
Even though they say the opposite thing.
And second while you look around the
world and you tell me whether there are
more hobbsy and states are resilient
states announcer,
that's pretty clear.
Most countries are disastrous.
Authoritarian dictatorships in which
people where people live and suffer,
and the places where civilization has
has become stable enough so that people
can live peaceful,
relatively peaceful and productive lives
are very rare.
They're more common than they were in
the past and they seem to be getting
more common all time.
Thank God.
But it's a lot easier to be disorganized
and brutal that it is to be organized,
productive and free.
So now you believe that the,
the shadow is something that kind of
comes apart when you,
when you face it.
So it's a blurry black mass and in a
sense before you start to differentiate
it and so you can,
you can tell what the shadow is as far
as any one of you is concerned because
you,
you can start to notice how you aren't
like you act,
especially when you act around,
act around people that you're trying to
impress or people whose opinions you
think are important to you.
You have to pay attention to it though.
And you,
you'll be able to see that there's a
distinction between what you say because
you're saying something in order to make
something turnout the way you want it to
turn out and what you actually think and
the shadows at work in two ways.
There.
One way is that it's convincing you that
using your speech and actions to
manipulate the world in a conscious
manner is a good idea and it's not.
And the second is that you'll see that
there are counter thoughts to what you
think.
So if you,
for example,
if you find yourself in the position of
being too nice to someone,
maybe it's a boss for example,
who's bit of a tire it,
you know,
and you don't feel that you're in a
position to say anything,
um,
in your only defense against his or her
bullying tactics.
The consequence of that is that you'll
think all sorts of dark and dangerous
thoughts about that person in your own
fantasies when you're not interacting
with them.
And if you catch a hold of those
fantasies and you let them play
themselves out consciously,
you'll see that they take you to very
dark places now,
okay.
Or at least to places that you regard is
very dark.
So
w
young's notion essentially is that when
you start to uncover those elements of
yourself that
don't fit comfortably within your ideas
about yourself is that you discover
things about yourself that are also
potentially very useful.
It says if you threw the baby out with
the bath water when you were setting up
your personality.
So,
for example,
earlier I talked about people who may
have decided very early in their life
that they're just not going to get
angry.
It's like,
well,
it's not necessarily something that you
want to throw away.
It might instead be something that you
want to bring within the realm of your
personality so that it,
it can express itself consciously and in
an articulated manner.
Because without anger,
for example,
you don't have any power,
which basically means that no one needs
to be afraid of you.
And you might think,
well,
people shouldn't be afraid of you.
And then a union might ask,
well,
what in the world would ever lead you to
believe that
mean?
The distinction between being respected
and being feared is not clear.
But I would say that you don't respect
anyone
whom you couldn't imagine fearing if
they decided to make that their
priority.
So
without the capacity for aggression,
you're not going to get any respect.
That doesn't mean that people have to
fear you,
but it does mean that you have to
incorporate your capacity for aggression
enough so that they would fear you if
you wanted them to.
And if you think about it,
that makes a lot more sense for memorial
perspective,
then the argument that you should be
nice to everyone because if you're nice
to everyone because you don't have any
choice because you're weak and
ineffectual and harmless,
then that's not a virtue.
That's just,
you just can't do anything else.
You're,
you're,
you're harmless by default and harmless
and virtuous are by no means the same
thing.
If by contrast you're capable of causing
all sorts of terrible trouble and you
know it and you know how and then you
decide not to do it because you can
articulate,
carefully,
articulate a different route,
well then you have the possibility of
virtue because without the capacity to
sin,
so to speak,
there's no virtue in not doing it.
So if you're a,
if you're a young man who feels that
sleeping around is wrong but never has
the opportunity to do it,
then you can hardly attribute that to
your virtue.
So a good union would say,
well,
you're just making a virtue out of
advice.
It's just rationalization.
It has nothing to do with,
with virtue.
Okay.
Now if you are attractive to people and
you decide that that attraction should
only manifest itself within certain
tight boundaries.
And that's a voluntary choice,
that's a whole different issue.
Now,
when you claims,
for example,
that you throw the baby out with the
bath water when you're trying to develop
and become a socially personality,
that happens in a different way as far
as he's concerned for each of the
genders.
And so one of the prices young would say
that we pay,
and that this is a very modern idea in
some ways for growing up
as a distinctly gendered society,
is that it's very easy for men to
suppress and fail to develop,
to develop those elements of their
character that might be considered
classically feminine.
And it's difficult for women to develop
and express those aspects of their
personality that might be classically
considered masculine.
And but so young believed that Nastad
inside the shadow in some sense where
the contra sexual capacities.
So for example,
for a man,
given what we knew about the
temperamental difference between men and
women,
it may be that men could be more,
could develop the capacity.
For true compassion and care.
If they,
huh?
They could find that ability within what
they've thrown out in the shadow and
women for example,
could find the capacity to be aggressive
and assertive because that's part of
what they threw out during their stage
of their course of development because
of,
because of it's a priori categorization
as inappropriate behavior.
Now that doesn't mean that you thought
that there was,
that people should be raised without any
gender identity.
That issue never came up for him.
He just thought that once you had
established a personality that was
sufficiently
develop to be acceptable socially and
functional on the individual level,
then you could have the opportunity to
expand that personality and to take into
yourself elements of,
of perception and thought and behavior
that
you wouldn't have had the sophistication
to be able to handle at an earlier stage
of development.
So young would say perhaps that if
you're a male,
you have to become masculine before you
could become feminine.
And if you are a female,
the reverse is true.
But that if your development only star
stops with a narrow and categorical
gender identity,
then there are elements that of,
of,
of being that you could draw on that
aren't at your disposal and that will
make you weak.
So the shadow breaks up into the Anima
ananymous and the Anima is the female
inside the mail,
so to speak,
in the animus is the male inside the
female and you and believe that he could
see those partial spirits manifesting
themselves in people's behavior.
And so he talked about a couple of
typical behaviors that he thought were
associated either with anema possession.
So that would be in the case of a man or
animus possession in the case of a
woman.
And so he would regard,
if you ever talk to someone who's female
who seems to respond to all of your
propositions with nothing but
argumentation for the sake of
argumentation,
human would regard that as a
manifestation of possession by the
animus.
And if you ever talked to a man who
is
irrationally possessed by
okay,
second rate and few tile emotions,
then he would regard that as possession
by the anima.
Okay.
So and you can see that if you watch for
it and if you believe in such things,
um,
yeah.
The best thing to do when confronted
with someone who's Animus possessed is
just shut up because you're not going to
make any headway.
Because the point of the argument of an
Animus,
inspired argument is to get you to argue
not to win.
Because by getting you to argue the
animus wins.
So and then behind those two things,
behind the shadow and the anima and the
Animus,
there's a final archetype,
which is the archetype of the self.
And that's young,
believed that the self was what you were
as a totality.
And that's a hard thing to understand
but,
but you could think about it this way.
You could think about the self as the,
as the total of what you are now plus
the total of all those things that you
could still be.
So it would be you as a reality.
Plus you as potential.
And that's a strange idea,
right?
Because we don't really know how to
understand the idea of potential as
modern and empirical people because
potential virtually by definition is not
yet manifest and also not a straight
forward thing to either measure or
conceptualize.
By the same token,
everybody acts as if they're,
they have potential unrealized potential
and so you know,
generated up a category to account for
that which he felt was expressed in all
sorts of symbolic weight.
So for example,
the wise old man,
like like the wizards in the movies that
all of you have seen in the last five
years,
it's always the same wizard.
Sometimes it's even the same actor.
It's like that's an archetype of the
wise old man and for young Christ was an
archetype of the self as well.
And I told you why that was to some
degree and it's partly because the
phoenix is also an archetype of the self
because the Phoenix is something that
can die and be reborn.
And so the Phoenix stands for the part
of your that can let one thing go.
One part of you,
which is an ally live part,
can let that go and burn up so to speak
so that something new can be born
because you very seldom gain something
before you let something else go.
That's partly because what you already
assume can be the worst impediment that
you have to work to learning something
new.
And it's complicated because sometimes
what you know worked in the past,
you know,
so you can think about that.
Maybe you're a perfectly well adapted 11
year old and you're still acting that
way when you're 15 it's like,
well,
it's hard to let that go because it
worked and you put a lot of effort into
it,
but unless you let it go,
the new personality isn't going to be
able to manifest itself.
So you have to stop being a child before
you can be an adult and there's a
sacrifice that goes along with that.
It's also a sacrifice that parents have
to make,
right?
Because in order for a parent to
encourage you to adopt the
responsibilities of an individual,
they have to allow you as a child to
die.
And Freud's observation on that
phenomena was that many parents and he
believed this was particularly
characteristic of mothers because of
their tight bond with their children and
the dependency that that implies that it
was particularly difficult for a mother
to let her child die so that an adult
could manifest itself in that child's
place.
And that's fundamentally in many ways
the oedipal complex.
Okay,
so now I'm going to show you some of
these things again,
because the thing about young is that
it's not easy to understand what he has
to say and it's not a simple thing to
explain it.
And his books are complicated,
although I don't think there are any
more complicated than they have to be.
Like I don't think young is obscure.
I think he's just difficult.
And then beyond difficult,
he's actually frightening.
So there's lots of reasons that people
don't like you,
and the fact that he's difficult and
frightening are probably the two
foremost objections.
I think the other thing that happened to
you that maybe slowed his acceptance as
an intellectual was that many of his
students were women,
like his primary students and the people
who developed his ideas.
Many of the people who identity I,
um,
continued to develop his ideas after he
died were women.
And that was perhaps not the most
effective way of making headway in the
academic world at,
at the time that he was alive.
So let's look at some things.
I'm going to show you some things from
the lion king because the lion king
shows you archetypes everywhere.
So
let's do this first.
Okay.
So the first thing that I would like to
point out here is that this takes place
at daybreak.
And daybreak is when the sun re-emerges.
And from an architectural perspective,
the sun re-emerges from a terrible Babel
that had had with the thing that devours
the sun at night and it comes up again
triumphant in the morning.
And so it's the dawn of consciousness
and not that idea that the sun
undergoes.
This battle is associated with the idea
that you descend into unconsciousness
when you sleep.
And magically you,
we reemerge from it in the morning and
you do that in accordance with the sun.
So for you,
darkness is a time of unconsciousness
and there's a tight relationship between
unconsciousness and darkness.
And so young would say,
people projected that idea.
It was an idea that was in there in
their imagination,
that unconsciousness and darkness,
we're tightly aligned.
And so they use their imagination to
explain the world and conceptualize the
sun in those,
uh,
in those terms of imagination.
So that if you analyze the terms of
imagination,
you can get some understanding into the
structure of the imagination.
And so that's one of them.
Consciousness and light are the same
thing,
illumination,
enlightenment,
all of those things.
And that's because we're primarily
visual creatures and were conscious
during the day.
And so this is a new beginning,
the new day,
which is something that everyone also
experiences because sleep washes away
the carers of the previous day.
Um,
and it does revitalize you.
We know perfectly well that if you
deprive people of sleep for any length
of time,
it's not good for them.
It,
it,
it derails them entirely.
Deranged ranges them entirely.
So there is a reason that this movie
opens with the dawn of the day.
Okay.
So there's another re casting of the
same idea,
right?
Except the also indicated that there was
an association between the dawn of self
consciousness and the emergence of the
light because the lyrics were,
when we step the day,
we stepped onto the planet and stepped
out blinking into the light.
There's a,
there's a transition from
unconsciousness to consciousness
metaphor underlying that.
And so one of the statements that film
is making,
or one of the ways that the film is
trying to set you up to understand this
as a story about the emergence of
consciousness into the light.
Now you might say,
well,
did the film makers know all this?
The answer to that is a,
it depends on what you mean by no,
which is really of critical factor in
this sort of discussion and b,
well,
yes,
and the re the way they manifested the
fact that they knew it is because they
knew when things fit together.
So you know,
when you're writing a story or something
like that or reading a story,
you know when the story is going well
you think,
yeah,
that makes sense.
In fact,
you don't even notice it,
right?
You just assume that everything's fine
because it makes sense.
It doesn't jar you out of the narrative.
And so people are perfectly capable,
especially if they concentrated on it
for long periods of time of assembling a
narrative with images that make sense.
Now they may not know why it makes
sense.
In fact,
if they're actually artists,
they don't know why it makes sense
because they're,
they're ix,
they're expanding their capacity to
comprehend and explain things well.
They're producing what they're
producing.
They have to be moving beyond what they
know cause otherwise they're just
producing propaganda.
You know,
when there were elements of many Disney
films that sync now and then into
propaganda,
it's sort of conscious moralizing.
But when the films are really working,
they're not doing that at all.
And when,
when,
when they are consciously moralizing,
they're boring very quickly.
Plus they date extremely rapidly.
Si.
Okay.
So that's a brilliant piece of film
editing there because the the filmmaker
sweep your eye along and then make
something appear as a revelation and
they do it at exactly the same time that
the music swells to a climax.
And that's indicating to you that
something of tremendous importance is
about to be revealed.
And so you see two things here.
The first thing you see is what's called
pride rock,
which is a,
is a roughly peer middle shape at least
to triangular shape that emerges in the
middle of the landscape that actually
serves symbolically as the center of the
kingdom are.
You can think about that as an Egyptian
pyramid or you could think about it as a
dominance hierarchy.
It doesn't really matter.
It's both of those things.
It's also the thing on which the thing
that the animals are subjugated to
stands right?
Cause that's where the king is and the
king happens to be a lion and the lion
is a solar beast.
It's always been a solar beast.
It's associated with the sun and it's
the king of beasts because it's an apex
Predator.
It's at the top of the hierarchy and for
whatever reason,
although obviously the lions in the
animated movie are there are not
actually lions.
It's important to remember that while
you're analyzing the film because it's
very easy to just think of them as lines
even though clearly they're not.
Now you also see this little character
up in the right hand corner,
left hand corner,
and that zoo,
right and Zazu is the eye of the king
and so the king is on top of the
pyramid,
but the king's eyes free from the king
and the kid go where all over the place
even where the pyramid can't see and
that's the eye on the top of the
pyramid.
You've seen that symbol everywhere.
No doubt.
It's the symbol that's on the back of
the American dollar bill and there's a
reason for it.
It's because the eye of the king is not
part of the hierarchy.
The eye of the king is something that's
always free of the hierarchy and can,
can fly over all hierarchies and that's,
that's equivalent to the thing that
could make its way up any hierarchy in
some sense.
It's also the same as horace though.
The God of vision in the ancient
Egyptian stories.
No.
Okay.
So there are,
we've got the king and we will see that
he's on top of the Rock,
which is where the king belongs.
He's also in full sunlight even though
that's not characteristic of any of the
other animals.
He's got his little bird there that
tells them things because the king is
someone who pays attention because the
king who doesn't pay attention is a
tyrant and then the wind is blowing
through the king's hair because the wind
is spirit.
And so the king is also something that's
associated with the everlasting spirit.
PNEUMA PNEUMA is the breath of air and
it's also the,
the,
the essence of life from an
architectural perspective.
So to be inspired is like risk.
Respiring to be inspired is to take in
spirit and the kind of spirit that the
king takes in is associated with the
image of the wind.
Now you got to look at his face.
You remember before I was saying,
cause the animators do a very good job
of this.
They gave him a very mature face and a
mature phase is something out of which
something is coming instead of something
into which something is coming.
And you'll see that the move Fossa is
always looking like this.
He's very intent and focused and,
and um,
intimidating.
Whereas his son right up until he
becomes
mmm
initiated is like this always as soon as
he becomes initiated.
And I'll show you that in the film,
his face hardens and it isn't until his
face hardens that he can go back and
fight scar who's basically a figure of
the shadow.
Now originally this character we're Fiki
was going to be one of those typical
sort of Disney kick buffoons that didn't
work out so well in the narrative.
And he ended up as a symbol of the self
and Stan and Rick Fiki is obviously a
showman and he's the part of the psyche
that guides its transformation.
So here's another way of looking at the
self is very interesting idea.
So you know,
as you go through life,
there was going to be triumphs and then
catastrophes and when there's a
catastrophe the psyche falls apart.
And then maybe it gathers its resources
back together and pulls itself together.
It's going like this.
Well young would say the self is what's
guiding that process.
So the ego feels it like this.
So that's triumphant catastrophe and
triumph and catastrophe or tragedy and
comedy.
But the self is the thing that's
underneath all of it,
allowing those transformations to take
place.
And that's where Fiki and that's why
he's associated as well with the sun.
So when he's a good king,
because he's in touch with the self.
So that makes him not something that's
either serving his persona or his ego.
But you could say that what are you
serving is a manner of ruling that
allows for the appropriate amount of
stability and transformation to take
place in the kingdom so that it remains
stable,
but also adapting to change.
And the king has guided,
did not buy the little bird who tells
him what's going on in those places he
can't see.
Now that's clearly a Madonna and child.
The image.
Yeah.
And the reason for that is quite simple.
I mean,
you might think,
well,
why would the idea of the Madonna and
child,
which by the way is a far older idea,
then the Christian representation of it,
there's lots of fingers of Madonna's and
Cha,
Madonna,
Madonna's and children.
Yeah.
In the ancient Egyptian art,
for example,
now the Isis with horace.
Well,
the reason that that's an archetype is
any society who doesn't regard the dyad
of mother and infant as something
sacred,
which would mean of highest value is
doomed obviously.
Because without that being held as a
value,
the society will cease to propagate.
And that will be the end of it.
So if the society isn't structured so
that,
that's that that dyad is up among the
highest of values,
then the society is become ungovernable.
He corrupt.
Okay.
So you see refuke you,
they're just anointed the little king
with something that was orange.
And that was something like the sun.
So the idea that the film is expressing
is that there's some sunlike substance
that's being associated with the,
with this new born son of the king,
and that that's,
uh,
a dramatic manifestation of his destiny.
And an indication that he asked also be
in cultured because what Rafiq he is
doing as a cultural act before he's
going to be complete.
Now the sand is also an indication that
he's mortal.
Now watch what happens here because this
film makers,
I think they just nail this part.
So they're going to do the sweeping
thing again and the music rises to the
ultimate climax of the song.
And what's happening here is that the
self is presenting this the sun.
And so it's a,
it's a presentation of the savior
fundamentally.
And that's the thing that has just been
born.
That's the hero.
And when the hero is presented and the
sun breaks open wide and shines on
immune would call that a synchronous
event.
And what happens is there's an emotion
associated with that which you will
feel.
And it's at that time that all the
animals bow down and they do that
spontaneously.
And the idea is that there's a hierarchy
here and the little boy in the sun is
the highest element of the hierarchy.
And when that it manifests itself and
you can see beyond the facade facade to
something that's divine behind it,
the consequence of that will be a
spontaneous bursting forth of law.
And I really think the filmmakers nailed
out here.
Okay.
Yeah,
so they hit that pretty hard there.
So there's also a nuclear family thing
going on in the background that you
might have noticed because of course the
little king has a mother and a father.
That's partly because that works better,
but also partly because the,
the archetypical hero is the son of
culture had nature.
So okay,
so here's a,
here's a shadow figure.
Yeah.
Here he's represented here,
not so much a symbol as shadow,
although he's part of Simba Shadow.
He's represented as Mufasa is shouting.
And so it's quite a complex idea because
what it says is when,
when a king like organization grows up,
which means any organization,
anything that's a hierarchy and that's
powerful,
there's a shadow element to it that
tends towards totalitarianism and
tyranny.
And that's represented often by the
king's evil brother.
It was a very common motif in,
in mythologically based stories.
And the king is generally blind to his
brother,
so often willfully blind.
Although that doesn't really seem to be
the case in the lion king,
it's,
it is clearly the case that move well
fossa underestimates the danger posed by
his usually older and smarter brother.
It's and,
and the miss very often make the case
that the evil king is the older one and
also the one that's more intelligent.
And the reason for that is that as far
as I can tell,
is that intelligence is something that
can go very wrong if it goes wrong.
And one of its big temptations is that
it produces models of the world and then
falls in love with the models.
And when it falls in love with the
models,
that makes it totalitarian because it
believes that its constructions are good
enough so that there doesn't need to be
anything else.
So it eliminates the necessity of the
transcendent.
And that's definitely a characteristic
of any totalitarian system.
It says,
this is everything we need,
and then you know,
if you happen to suffer or if you happen
to openly rebel against the system,
then you're regarded as an enemy of
truth and then it's fine to do with you
whatever might be done because
everything worth doing is already been
done.
Yeah.
Now he's got an interesting facial
expression and it's really worth
watching facial expressions in animated
cartoons because they're not faces,
right?
What they are is the consequence of the
observations of extremely talented
artists about how's people's faces
configure themselves over very long
periods of time.
Because these people are high level
artists,
they know what they're doing,
and so they're able to distill down
certain facial expressions to describe a
character.
Now this guy's obviously,
he's whiny,
he's got this supercilious and arrogant
voice.
So He's,
he's,
he's arrogant beyond belief and he all
is also hard done by and resentful and
that's a really good,
and maybe he has a reason he's got a
scar or something happened to them that
wasn't good,
but he's taken on this attitude as
resentful victim who really deserves to
rule.
If only everyone could see how wonderful
he was.
And then he has all sorts of reasons why
the fact that he isn't powerful has
nothing to do with his own shortcomings,
passes on his way.
He
doesn't matter if
they're looking at me that way.
Okay,
well as we can tell the eyes of the king
and scarred not friends.
And that's because scar doesn't really
want to see what's going on.
Now here's an interesting little
archetype.
What,
okay,
so that's quite interesting.
There's a variety of statements there
that are very,
very cool.
So one of them is
the kingdom is a bounded place and so
that's playing off the idea of explored
territory versus unexplored territory or
the known versus the unknown.
And the proposition there is that
whatever the dominance hierarchy happens
to be,
it has a limited domain of
a limited domain of competence and the
domain of competence is defined by
everything that the light touches.
Now this is actually something that you
can notice in your own life.
It's,
it's quite interesting.
You'll see that if you move into a new
place or a new neighborhood,
or if you do anything new at all,
that nothing that you haven't attended,
two is actually yours.
It will,
it will stay foreign in a sense and
unfamiliar to you until you interact
with it with a substantial amount of
attention.
And that's partly because while you're
attending to it,
which is an act of conscious swill,
you're,
you're modifying your perceptions and
your thoughts and your actions and your
emotions to take it into account as a
phenomenon.
And that means that you're competent
there.
And it takes conscious effort to be
competent because you have to practice
being competent at a new domain.
And until you've practiced being
competent in a new domain,
it's not yours.
And so this clip is showing what's
basically an eternal truth,
which is that your territory is whatever
you've mastered and it's demarcated by
everything you haven't mastered.
And in this particular representation
that's associated with,
with death,
it's also associated in some bizarre
sense with paradise.
Because of course,
Simba encounters the elephants grave out
in no man's land,
so to speak.
But when he runs away across the desert,
he also finds paradise.
And so there's a paradoxical idea there
that the unknown contains death and
everything you need to make your life
worthwhile.
Here comes the anima.
That's
okay.
So you see that cocky?
He's a cocky little rat here.
Okay.
So he's very confident,
but that's egotism and also persona.
Well,
it's no wonder he's confident.
He's the son of the king,
you know?
And the fact is that he has a position
of dominance that he doesn't deserve
merely because he was born into it.
And that's him.
Shallow and arrogant and possessed by a
persona.
No,
this little figure who is basically an
anima figure always knocks him down.
A peg continually knocks him down a peg.
How many of you seen groundhog day?
Yeah.
You remember in Groundhog Day,
Bill Murray's character is a real,
he's a jackass at the beginning.
He's very arrogant and he's very
unskilled.
And then he gets stuck in the same day,
which is pretty funny because that is
what happens to you if you're arrogant
and unskilled,
you end up in the same damn day.
That's not fun.
And then in that day he becomes
attracted to this woman who's an anima
figure and for for years as far as the
films concern,
every time he approaches her in his
arrogant and clumsy way,
she slaps him.
So there's one scene in the movie where
I think it lasts for about 30 seconds
and it's nothing but clips of her
slapping him probably 30 times at that
point.
You've seen him go through the same day
and the continually painful way that he
does and she slaps him in those longer
clips and after a while the film maker
gets tired of that,
just shows you nothing but the slaps,
you know,
eventually he's brought so far down as a
consequence of being stuck in the same
day and continually being slapped that
he falls completely apart.
Right?
Then he tries to kill himself.
And one of the very comical things about
that movie is that that doesn't work
either.
He just wakes up at the same day again.
And you know,
what that means in some sense is that if
you're too damn stubborn to change,
you will keep running into the same
thing over and over continually.
And that's why you're in the same day
because you won't let go of it.
And that might drive you even to
question the value of your own being.
But that's also not a very useful
adaptive strategy,
you know?
And it isn't till he starts to take his
rejection seriously that he starts to
actually build some real character,
right?
And then he starts paying attention to
the day and finds out that there's all
sorts of things that he can do during
that day to make it rich and meaningful.
And as soon as he does that enough and
becomes an expert at it,
poof,
he gets out of the the day,
the same horrible day.
And they saw that horrible day is also a
representation of tier of the tyranny of
the state because the state is something
that's static.
So anyways,
now la,
she's
was,
yeah,
and well,
they're not paying attention.
They end up in the shadows,
outside the kingdom.
So
here's,
here's that image of scar transforming
himself essentially first into Hitler,
but because there's a lot of Nazi
imagery in this,
in this clip,
but also into a sate tannic figure at
the end,
you'll see he's associated with the
crescent moon.
So we turns into the horn demon of the
night essentially.
Okay,
got
you.
See,
that's all images of hell obviously.
Alright,
come on board talks back.
Slide
my words.
See,
one of the things that happened to
people like stolen for example,
is Stellan had nothing but contempt for
people and he thought all they ever did
was lie.
Well,
what happened to Stellan is that he's,
he became surrounded by people
with to whom he could demonstrate
contempt and who never did anything to
them except lie.
Cause the reason for that was they were
so terrified of them that they would
never tell him the truth about anything.
And so he got into this spiral,
which is kind of the spiral of the,
of a paranoid psychopath where I
distrust you so badly and set things up
so that you'll be punished so hard if
you ever deviate from the appropriate
line that you'll do nothing but lie to
me.
And so then I'm fully justified my
contempt and sort of,
it's like Peter pan in some sense,
king of the lost boys.
It's like,
well who do you want to be king of while
the route that scar took,
which is the negative archetype.
The shadow root means that he's king,
but you know he's King of Hell and all
he's God are these brainless minions.
And so you know he's King of people he
wouldn't want to associate with.
It's not exactly a,
it's not exactly,
I'm about
to
start quizzing me.
So you,
you,
you may remember or you may not remember
that or who may not know that Hitler of
course set up the war,
the biggest meeting arena that the world
had ever seen for the Nuremberg Nazi
party rallies.
And there's,
there's something to see.
They were filmed quite brilliantly in a
film called will to power.
I think that's what it's called,
Leni Riefenstahl and what Hitler has
arrayed in front of him,
our blocks of thousands of soldiers
everywhere as far as you can see an
absolutely perfect
uniformity,
and that's the idea,
because if you're already right,
nothing has to be different.
Everything can be the same as the
perfect thing.
The problem with that is you're not
right and things have to change.
And Hitler,
he was a master of the use of fire as
well,
and also put as displays on at night.
And so he took all the Luftwaffe is
error craft spotting spotlights,
which were huge,
massive lights,
maybe they must have been 20 feet
across,
and he had them all lined up behind him
on the stage and they would shine miles
up into the sky.
And so he would address these thousands
and thousands of people in this
nighttime ritual with a curtain of light
behind him that was several miles high.
It's an unbelievably powerful pageant.
And the people who made this film or
drawing on on that
to produce these images.
Modern people will say things like,
well,
the idea of hell is just a superstition,
but then you watch this and it makes
sense and then you think,
well hell is where Satan himself rules
and nothing happens but the body's
burning death and that's exactly what
happened during the Holocaust.
And so thinking that these sorts of
archetipal ideas are superstitious is
it's extraordinarily foolish and naive
because they represent possibilities of
being that continually manifest
themselves and everyone knows about
them.
So you know the,
the,
the implicit idea here is that if you
take the path that scar torque,
which is one of resentment and deceit as
well as arrogance,
which are three major motive,
major,
major shadow motivators,
then you'll end up at best ruling over
hell.
And it's no joke,
like it's not a superstition.
The stories are trying to tell you
something,
that,
that his mode of being is the pathway to
perdition and,
and that the things that happen there
are so terrible and so deep that the
only way you can really express them is
using the kind of imagery that we've
come to associate with religious and
religious imagery in a sense is imagery
that cannot be made more powerful.
That's what makes it archetipal.
It's like a limit.
You can't go past it in terms of the
representation.
And so when you represent the ultimate
destiny of evil as eternal hell,
where all the bodies burned forever and
there's nothing there except demonic
chatter,
that's about as far as you can go in
terms of your capacity to represent
something.
But it's representing something.
So when you can say,
well,
it's an eternal place,
while that's because this possibility's
always there,
it never goes away.
It's always there.
And that's also what makes it
archetipal.
And do you know that because otherwise
you wouldn't be able to understand the
story and everyone knows it.
Otherwise this story wouldn't be,
I still believe it's one of the top 10
grossing films of all time.
So obviously it makes sense.
Okay,
well I'd like to show you a lot more,
but,
but I can't,
so we'll see you Thursday.
I'm going to post some sample questions
on the website
very soon tonight,
possibly tomorrow morning,
possibly somewhere around there.
So check it out.
Neil gets some sense of what the exam's
going to be like.