Hey,
so we divided up the brain one way
and now we're going to divide it up
another way,
and so this is the brain from the top
down and you know you have two
hemispheres and you might think,
well,
why do you need two hemispheres?
Do you know?
By the way,
some of you probably know this,
that a Zana who's a relatively famous
neuropsychologist,
studied split brain patients.
Now you know that your cortical
hemispheres,
your brain is united down in the
subcortical areas.
You know,
it's sort of stuck together.
Although you have twin 11 twins of many
of the subcortical structures like you
have to Hipaa camp,
eye to Amygdala,
for example,
one on each side,
but at the top the hemispheres are quite
separate and,
but they're connected by the Corpus
callosum which makes them communicate.
It's kind of interesting because you
kind of wonder,
well why aren't they just all glued
together?
You know,
and what it seems to indicate is that
there's some utility of functional
independence combined with some utility
of communication,
you know,
so it might be like,
do you really want to be networked at
the same time?
To everyone in the world,
it's like,
no,
you don't.
You want some narrow channel pathways so
that only the important information
comes through,
so it's sort of maybe like the right
hemisphere is one kind of computational
device in the left hemisphere is another
kind of computational device.
Of course they're not computational
devices,
but you get the point and only the
important information and process
information from the right hemisphere
goes across and only the process,
the information from the left hemisphere
goes across something like that,
whatever.
If you have someone who's epileptic or
or that that has a brain illness of some
sort of specific type,
it's usually epilepsy but not always and
you do surgery on them and you cut the
Corpus callosum.
What you find weirdly enough is that
each hemisphere develops its own
personality and so it's Kinda Nice as
other evidence.
I would say for the idea that what the
brain does is produce personalities,
right?
You can keep pairing the brain down and
what it's going to do is produce lower
and lower resolution personalities all
the way down to the bottom.
They're just known as detailed.
They're like,
if you lost,
say 80 percent of your cortex randomly,
you'd sort of be like a thumbnail of
yourself,
so you'd still be you,
but just not at the same detail.
So I'll tell you,
here's an interesting idea from the
Catholics.
It kind of goes along with the Avatar
idea.
So the Catholics had been wrestling for
a long time with the question about how
God could have fit himself in the human
body because you could imagine that
would obsess Christians.
It's like God is great,
Big God and you know,
little bitty body put God in there,
just bursts the boundaries.
Well,
they have this idea called Kenosis,
which means emptying.
And so the idea is that God had to empty
himself,
followed before and get inhabited human
body and it's very much like a thumbnail
ideas.
So you know,
and young would have of course thought
exactly that the self was a thumbnail of
God.
I mean,
if you wouldn't put it that way,
but definitely that's where his thinking
was leading.
So.
So that's a pretty damn cool idea.
So anyways,
so this is from.
I developed this before I ran what I'm
going to tell you,
but it doesn't matter because I'm going
to talk about it from another theorist,
his point of view,
the guy I'm going to tell you about,
his name is Al Cohen and Goldberg and
he's a neuropsychologist and he was one
of learning as students who ended up in
New York and Goldberg was obviously
influenced by Luria and all the Sokolov
and vinegar,
silver and gray and all those people
that I've already talked to you about
and he was interested in why you have
two hemispheres.
Well,
there's a bunch of things that you can
say broadly speaking about the
hemispheres,
and I've written them some of them down
there,
so the right hemisphere.
This is an idealized representation of a
relatively highly lateralized right
handed male,
and the reason I'm saying that is men
seem to be more lateralized than women
and the right handed lateralization is
the standard kind,
but you know the brain can be louder,
lysed all sorts of ways.
What you might say is that
there's a bunch of ways of looking at
it.
One way you can look at it is that your
cortex gets colonized by underlying
structures so and that each underlying
structure is likely to call annise a
particular area.
So for example,
when you,
when you are born and you wake up and
you see your eyes are going to call an
eyes,
your visual Cortex,
most likely because it's sort of adapted
for that,
but if you don't have a visual Cortex,
then your eyes will colonize something
else.
So,
so that's.
So the brain has proclivities towards a
certain kind of structure,
but especially early in development.
It's unbelievably plastic.
And so brains can be organized in
lateralized in a bunch of different
ways.
But so to simplify what you do is you
kind of take,
okay,
well let's take the most straightforward
and typical brain and talk about it as
if it's the canonical brain.
But I think what you can say is
regardless of where these systems are
localized,
they exist.
So it's an over simplification,
whatever.
It doesn't matter what you've got with
regards to your core to cs is a quick
and dirty cortex and that's the right
hemisphere.
And then you've got a longterm detailed
cortex and that's the left hemisphere,
left hemisphere,
specialized for language language,
cuts,
things up into little tiny bitty pieces,
you know.
And that's really useful if you're doing
little tiny bitty things and you
shouldn't be precision,
right?
Pinpoint accuracy.
But that takes a lot of time and a lot
of computation.
Whereas the right hemisphere says,
yeah,
let's get to the bloody point,
you know?
And so it captures the thing in an
image.
So like the monster I showed you from
the hippy cartoon,
that's a right hemisphere thing.
It's an image that represents a class of
entities and which of course the images
do.
Now,
here's this woman named
I
carefree number autistic woman.
She's a developed cattle handling
facilities all across.
What's her name?
Temple.
Grandin.
Yes.
Very cool person I saw at temple grandin
speak at the University of Arizona at
the consciousness conference.
And it was like the funniest speech I'd
ever seen in my life.
Not because it wasn't perfect,
it was bloody perfect.
Like she's a tough woman.
She looks like a cowboy and she spent a
lot of time with animals.
She kind of comes out on the stage and
her cowboy outfit and she's unbelievably
straightforward and without nuance.
She's autistic,
she's severely autistic and she,
you know,
her mother helped her a lot and she
developed this thing that you would go
inside to compress her and hold her was
a little machine and that would comfort
her.
Anyways,
she turned herself into quite the quite
the person and she thinks she thinks
like an animal,
which is why she can design cattle
handling facility often slaughter houses
so that the cattle don't get all freaked
out as they're on their way to their
eventual demise.
And so one of the things she does is she
walks through where the counselor going
in anything that bothers her,
she assumes will bother a cow.
So for example,
if the cows are walking through this say
spiral or they're on their way to the
slaughterhouse and there's a coke can
lying on the ground,
all the cows will stop and look at the
coke can to normalist.
Now.
She talked a lot about how she thought
and what she said was she could not
devise abstract representations.
So she said,
okay,
imagine,
imagine how a child draws a house.
Okay,
so what,
what is he now?
Charles' house,
right?
There's a triangle and a square on the
left,
and then there's another rectangle and
another kind of Parallelogram,
and then there's a door and two windows,
right?
Then there's a chimney with smoke coming
out,
which is quite cool.
It's like,
why is that?
Where's the smoke?
You know,
you don't see that modern houses,
but kids still do that.
It's like,
then maybe there's a tree and usually
there's a sun and then house.
It's like you think,
oh,
isn't that cute?
A simple drug.
It's like that drawing.
It's not simple.
You've never seen a house that looks
like that in your life.
It looks nothing like a house.
It's not a house,
it's not a picture.
It's a hero cliff.
It's a pre linguistic representation and
it's like the essential elements of
house.
And so you might say what the child has
done is extracted out all those things
that are common across all houses and
then represented that it's not a
drawing.
Now if you take autistic people
sometimes and you get them to draw,
they'll start in one corner of the house
and what they'll draw is that helps,
like with every damn brick in place.
So there are autistic people,
for example,
who they can look at a building and they
can count every single window at one
glance.
And then there's another guy who in
England who's really famous,
this guy is just completely out of.
He's unbelievable.
They take them up in a helicopter and
show them a city that he's never seen.
Then he goes home and has a piece of
paper,
like as big as a wall and he starts in
one corner and he draws the entire city,
you know,
and he doesn't sketch it out,
right?
It's,
it's from the bottom up.
And you know,
that's autistic savant drawing.
And often what happens is he's very
realistic looking.
You know what happens if the autistic
drawing survivors languages,
they start being able to draw and that's
because the abstraction interferes with
the realism,
you know?
So it's really hard to draw a hand.
And the reason for that is if you draw a
hand,
you draw a hieroglyph the hand,
this is what heroin looks like.
You tried to draw your hand.
It's really strange.
And one of the strange things about
trying to draw your hand is that in
order to draw it,
you have to stop seeing it as if it's a
hand and then it pops out.
You think,
my God,
that's the weirdest looking thing.
It's like a tree root.
It's like you know it's a claw because
it's,
you know,
if you look at your hand like that,
it looks nothing like a hand.
That's how it hair looks.
What the hell is that?
It's like some sort of spider,
you know,
so.
But you have to see it that way before
you can draw it.
And so well.
So partly what happens is that your
capacity for abstraction interferes with
your ability to see detail and not
probably good.
It's one of the ways that you simplify
the world anyways.
The right hemisphere looks like it's
specialized for anomaly.
Now the way I look at it is this,
okay?
So you've got your hippocampus down
there and it's keeping track of the
comparison between what you want and
what you think is happening.
Bang,
something emerges.
It's anomalous.
You don't know what the hell is going
on,
and so you freeze.
That's the representation.
Then you start to feel anxious.
Then the right hemisphere comes up with
some pictures.
What might this be?
You can experience this at home for your
own enjoyment.
Let's say you're home at two in the
morning and it's dark and you're alone.
Okay?
Maybe you've watched a horror.
Movies are all nicely pride,
you know,
and then you hear a noise in another
room and not knowing shouldn't be there
and so you're going to go investigate,
right?
And so let's say the door is just a
little bit open and it's dark in the
room and you have to put your hand in to
turn on the light.
It's like you just watched what your
imagination populates that room with.
When you do that,
it's like,
you know,
guy with acs,
snake alligator,
like whatever.
But your right hemisphere is going.
There may be one of this class of
dangerous things in there and what it's
doing is basically coming up with a
hypothesis.
What sort of monster might be in there
and you're all sort of freaked out about
that even though you know that you know,
who knows what happened,
you know nothing.
Something creepy,
but you're all like on edge because your
brain doesn't work at night like it does
in the day and everyone knows that.
Wake up in the middle of the night.
It's like all manner of horrors go
through your imagination and that
usually happens when you're asleep.
You're asleep for that most of the time,
but sometimes you wake up and it's like
you worry about everything.
So anyways,
so that's the right hemisphere.
It's coming up with pictures of what
might be there and they're generally
monstrous pictures and reason for that
is while it's obvious what the reasons
for that is,
you know,
now you'll probably turn the light on
and look anyways,
even though you might sort of peer
around the corner and then when there's
nothing,
you'll be embarrassed about how foolish
you are.
But.
But you can see the instinctual behavior
right there and it's,
it's wise,
you know,
there's a low probability that something
terrible is there,
but zero times low probability times
infinity equals large danger.
So if there's a two percent chance that
there's a killer in there,
it pays to be a little on the 10 side
because being killed really sucks.
And so your,
your,
your prime to feel negative emotion more
intensely,
right?
Because you're so vulnerable.
So anyways,
that's kind of what the right hemisphere
is up to.
It does quick and dirty representation,
but it also does categorization.
So it's not,
it doesn't give you exactly realistic
representations of what's there.
What it does instead is gives you
categorical representations.
And so you might say,
how should you represent an unknown
danger?
You should use an amalgam of all known
dangers to represent it.
And that is what it is in a sense.
You know,
like that's why I talked to you earlier
about the category of all dangerous
things.
So the aborigines in Australia have
this,
this category,
which is women fire and dangerous things
like what you think,
well,
why are all those things in that
category?
It's like,
oh,
it's not that hard to figure out if you
think about it,
but it's also a category that you very
frequently see say,
and Disney cartoons.
So the wicked queen for example,
in sleeping beauty,
I mean she's constantly bursting into
flames and turning into a dragon and no
one seems to object to that.
It makes perfect sense that the wicked
queen would turn into a fire breathing
dragon.
It's like it doesn't make any sense at
all,
but although it does,
but it's not a rational transformation.
But because it's in keeping with an
archetypal structure,
everybody goes,
yeah,
of course that's what she's going to do.
And it happens all the time.
And Disney movies like Ursula,
you remember her from,
from the Little Mermaid.
She's trying to keep her daughter from
becoming conscious.
Yeah.
Nice mother doing that.
And she trapped.
Sold Zeus,
you know,
she squeezes it soul to death.
Traps them in the underworld because
he's also.
Well,
we won't get into that,
but anyways,
what happens to Ursula is when you find,
get her irritated.
Now if she grows into this huge ship
destroying store monster,
that's part octopus,
right?
Or giant octopus,
you think,
wow,
that makes sense.
Okay.
It doesn't make a lot of sense,
but it's a kind of hypothesis now that's
a representation of mother nature,
red in tooth and claw,
and there's also a reason that that's
female.
It's not female,
it's feminine.
It's actually a different thing.
So.
But we'll get to that.
So the right hemisphere,
well,
it's specialized for a.
normally it does quick and dirty
analysis under the influence of the
limbic system.
It's not linguistics,
so I would say it's still dominated by
the systems and my suspicion is that
animals are still dominated by the
subcortical systems.
Their brains worked from the bottom up.
We have a top down model and that's at
least a part of the left hemisphere
linguistic system and it's a new thing
that people have and it's based on our
capacity to abstract.
So that would partly be visual like here
or glyphic.
And then also to transform things into
linguistic form.
And it seems to me that that's the part
that we really identify as ourself,
right?
Because it's weird if you're,
let's say you're home alone and you get
freaked out and all these images come to
mind.
No,
if you think of those images is part of
you,
you think more.
There are things,
things that appeared to you and that's
what you think about your dreams.
There are things that appeared to you.
They're not you.
It's like,
why would you think that?
I mean they're there in your
experientials space.
Why is it that separation between you
and your dream?
I had a dream,
not I thought up a dream,
or look what I created.
It's like there you are.
The Observer.
And up comes a dream.
It's very,
very weird and you know,
it shows you that there are forces
operating in your psyche that are
impersonal,
genuinely impersonal.
And of course that's part of what you
can call it,
the collective unconscious.
So,
and it's the thing that generates these
weird images and protects you.
So in its nature,
that's for sure.
And it can be absolutely terrifying.
I mean,
people can have dreams that are so
terrible that.
Well,
like the one my my little niece nephew
had that's pretty damn nasty little
greasy door things with big beaks.
I mean that's an ugly.
That's a very ugly representation.
And then if that wasn't bad enough,
there had to be a fire breathing dragon
behind them,
creating them in to this thing like it's
no bloody wonder.
He was waking up screaming.
It's like,
oh no.
I figured out what life is like.
So like at four,
that's pretty.
That's pretty traumatic.
So okay,
now the left hemisphere,
this is,
this is out,
and the goldbergs.
Hypo potts says she got one hemisphere
or system that operates when you know
what you're doing and when what you want
is happening,
and that's the happy talky part that
thinks it knows what the hell is going
on.
And then you have another part that only
turns on when you don't know what's
going on.
And it's full of anxiety and negative
emotion.
The Right Hemisphere,
by the way,
is specialized for negative emotion.
If you,
if you sustain right prefrontal damage,
you become inappropriately happy and you
think you're full of positive illusions.
You Think,
oh,
that's an excellent thing.
It's like it's not.
You make really impulsive,
risky decisions and your life goes
directly to help because he needed the
negative emotion.
Obviously you know the reason you suffer
with negative emotion is because if you
didn't suffer with negative emotion use,
you'd suffer from being destroyed.
Those are your options.
There are people by the way who were
born without pain and so you think,
hey,
that's a good deal.
It's like they never last past 20 and
part of the reason for that is you don't
this,
but while you're sitting there,
you're going like this all the time,
and the reason for that is,
is that if you sit for any length of
time on one part of your body,
then it doesn't get much blood and it
doesn't get oxygenated,
and so you do that.
A bitch is a little bit little pain,
so you shift,
you shift and you shift and so you're
just doing this all the time because
otherwise you wear out your damn body or
you get bedsores or that sort of thing.
Well these people that don't have any
pain,
they just wear themselves out.
So.
So you need the negative emotion,
you know,
it keeps you going and,
and it can get out of hand and have its
own pathologies,
but,
but it's definitely necessary.
So the right hemisphere does negative
emotion inhibition of behavior.
That's the freezing and its attendant on
anxiety does image processing,
holistic thinking.
So it's the quick and dirty hemisphere
pattern recognition,
pattern generation and gross motor
action not.
It's interesting too,
right?
Because the gross motor action is again,
the quick and dirty stuff.
You know,
if you need to slap something away,
it doesn't really matter that it's a,
you know,
a gross motor gesture.
You don't have to go like this and be
precise.
It can just be fast and sloppy and it'll
still work.
Now the left hemisphere is specialized
for when you know what the hell's going
on and you can concentrate on the
details so and then you can think about
it in terms of the hierarchy that we
discussed,
right?
So what it implies is that at the level
of specific fine detailed motor output,
the left hemisphere is operating and so
that's kind of associated with positive
affect.
I know exactly what I'm doing and I'm
making minor adjustments and
everything's going well,
and then if you go up the hierarchy
towards more and more abstract
representations,
then increasingly that's moving over
into right hemisphere space.
And so that's also partly why when you
disrupt those higher order structures
that well literally all hell breaks
loose.
So left hemisphere operation,
unexplored territory,
positive emotion,
activation of behavior.
So that's also exploration,
a word processing,
linear thinking,
detail recognition,
detailed generation and fine motor
action.
So you need one system that works when
you don't know what's going on and you
need another system that works when you
do,
because sometimes your where you don't
know what you're doing and sometimes
your where you do know what you're
doing.
Now Ramachandra,
who's a fairly famous neurologist who
operates out of La,
he associated that totalitarian eagle
with hyper domination of the left
hemisphere.
And the reason he did that,
it's very cool.
So he's got these patients that have a.
what's it called?
He said Agnosia.
It isn't.
We'll call it neglect.
Neglect.
Okay,
so this is what happens.
Okay?
You have a stroke and the stroke affects
the back part of the right hemisphere.
All right?
So what happens?
Your left side is paralyzed.
You can't do anything with it.
Okay?
So however you also don't notice that
it's not working.
And so one of the things you might do if
you do become aware,
you're laying in bed,
you've had a stroke,
and for some reason you noticed that
there's an arm lying in there with you
and then what you do is you pick it up
with your other hand and you try to
throw it out of the bed and when you
find out that it's attached to you
because it's not your arm,
you're not very happy,
or maybe you throw yourself right out of
bed.
And then if someone gets you to draw a
clock,
you draw half a clock and if you eat a
plate full of food,
you eat half the plate unless someone
turns it and then you eat half of that
and so half the world is gone.
It's hard to imagine what that would be
liking.
But I think what it's sort of like is,
you know how there's a whole world
behind you and you don't,
you don't detect it as not there.
Like it's not black or anything.
Like when your eyes are closed,
it's just not there.
And I think what happens with people
with neglect is that the not there
becomes three quarters instead of just
half.
It's something like that anyways.
So fine.
So you don't know what's going on.
And there you are like this and someone
says to you,
I noticed that you can't move your left
arm today.
And what do you say?
You say,
well that's because I'm tired.
Or you say I'm,
I don't feel like moving it and,
and so forth.
So you'll have this reason that you're
not going to move it.
And you know,
you might say the same thing about the
left foot or whatever.
It's like,
yeah,
well I don't feel like moving it.
Then you'll have some story about why
you're not going to move it.
Okay.
So that's fine.
So for Indians thought about that as
traumatic denial,
you know that it was so overwhelming to
you that you lost the left part of your
body,
that you couldn't face it and you just
denied it happened.
It's not a bad theory.
It's not quite right.
But it's not a bad theory.
So,
so fine.
So I'll tell you a couple of associated
stories.
Let's say you're on dialysis.
That sucks.
You have to have this big thing in your
arm that's like a shunt and then you
have to go get hooked up to a dialysis
machine like all the time because your
kidneys are failing.
And so who wants that?
Nobody.
So everybody thinks time for a kidney
transplant.
So then they're on a long waiting list,
make it one kidney that's not very many
kidneys.
And so then they say,
okay,
you got your kidney.
And everyone's thrilled about that.
Here's your antirejection medication,
make sure you take it and so then a year
later you lose your kidney.
Why?
Because you don't take your damn
antirejection medication.
That's the most common reason you might
think,
well,
why in the world would you not take your
antirejection medication?
While the Freud's would say denial?
Here's a different hypothesis.
You're a whole map of you is person with
kidney and then you lose your kidneys
and it's like you're a whole weird thing
that you have no idea about and it's
virtually impossible for you to update
your model and you think,
well,
does that make any sense?
Like,
have you ever lost a tooth?
Right?
What is your tongue do for like six
months?
You're sitting there in your tongue is
like fiddling away in there like a mad
dog investigating every nook and like
it's an obsessive exploratory device and
it doesn't even when you don't want it
to and then six months later you get
your mouth remapped.
So that's just a tooth man.
Lose a kidney and see what happens or
lose the whole left side of your body.
It's like,
what are you going to do about that?
Well,
okay,
so then Ramachandra and he's testing
these people for balance and so what he
does is he checks out this phenomena
called Nystagmus.
And so if you pour cold water in
someone's ear,
their eyes move back and forth because
it screws up the,
um,
you know,
you have a balanced system in your,
in your ear.
And if you pour cold water and air it
screws it up and then your eyes move
back and forth.
And you know,
it's not very pleasant.
So what he found was that if he poured
water in the cold water in the left ear,
then all of a sudden the people would
wake up and go,
oh my God,
I don't have the left side of my body.
And then they would have a catastrophic
emotional experience,
may be all upset about it and crying
away,
which is of course what they should do.
And then 20 minutes later it would wear
off and then you'd say,
well,
you know,
is there anything wrong with your left
side?
And they'd say,
well yeah,
I just don't feel like moving it.
So,
so what seems to have happened is
something like,
so there's a body representation center,
let's say in the back of the right
hemisphere and you blow that soccer out
with a stroke and that means you can't
represent that part of your body
anymore,
but maybe there's tatters of it left.
Like it's like a network that's damaged
and under some conditions you could more
or less get it to operate.
So you pour some cold water in the year,
you shocked the whole system.
And then there's enough neurological
activity.
So the network kicks in even though it's
damaged for like 10 minutes.
And then you get this tremendous burst
of negative emotion,
which is what the right hemisphere
should be doing.
When you lose half your body and you
experienced that and will left
hemisphere is like flapping away trying
to account for this,
which it can't because it's such a
massive archer catastrophe.
But then you know,
the,
the shock wears off and bang,
the system shuts back down and Poof,
you're back in denial.
So that's a good example of the
relationship between the left hemisphere
and right hemisphere.
The left hemisphere has a fixed idea
about the world.
So in some sense you might think about
it as the instantiation of your latest
Avatar.
Even certainly see that with people who
are ideological,
he possessed,
right?
They've got this verbal system that
accounts for the whole world and there's
just no damn way that things go in
anywhere.
So you know,
and it's got this totalitarian aspect
because it wants to explain every last
thing.
It doesn't like to normally at all.
It hasn't come to terms with the
normally at all and there's no sense of
transformation within the system,
which is partly white totalitarian
systems die.
It's like the Red Queen says to Alice in
wonderland when she was in the
underworld and my kingdom,
you have to run as fast as you can just
to say in the same place.
That's why totalitarian systems don't
work is because the damn environment
shifting around on,
you know,
and if they are fixed in place,
the gap between their theory and reality
gets larger and larger and larger and
larger.
Until finally,
you know they fall into a pit and that's
the end of it.
So now it's what happens to people too.
If they don't stay updated,
you know,
if they let things get away on them,
eventually the ignored reality comes
flooding back and we'll see that
represented in mythology because it's
represented very nicely and mythology.
That's where I often dragons in
fairytales,
for example,
in the St George Story and in the
Hobbit,
for that matter,
the dragon is an eternal thing.
It lives underneath the earth and most
of the time it leaves you the hell
alone,
but now and then it comes back and it
tries to destroy the city and then you
have to zip out there and fight the
thing so you get to go back and it's
whole and maybe you get the treasure
that it's caring and then it's back in
the hole for a while,
but that thing's coming back.
It's always coming back and so you build
the walls and all that,
that's fine,
but a dragon can destroy any walls and
so walls aren't enough.
You have to be prepared to go out there
and fight the damn thing,
and that's how you keep it at bay and
you know,
that basically means that you have to
maintain everything you build.
It's something like that,
right?
Because otherwise it falls apart with
increasing entropy.
So,
all right,
so
Goldberg thought about this as an
anomaly system and offy system and a
route and ization system.
But I tended to think about it more from
an anthropological or,
uh,
um,
what would you call it?
A ecological perspective,
thinking about an animal.
US In our natural environment,
it's not so much novelty versus root
analyzation.
It's explored versus unexplored
territory.
And that's what the world's made out of.
It's made out of,
explored versus unexplored territory.
And so there's a domain that you inhabit
which is the center of the universe from
a mythological perspective with you,
right in the middle of it and around you
is this circle of which is your place
that you move around with you.
And in that circle you know what the
hell's going on.
And that's partly because you've mapped
it,
but it's also partly because you don't
go outside of it,
you know,
so you have your friends and you have
your routine and that's nested inside
your culture and you try to keep that
thing from flipping upside down and you
do that all sorts of ways partly by
doing the same thing all the time,
but also partly by refusing to go
anywhere that might seriously challenge
your beliefs.
And you know,
fair enough,
you can understand that although it
makes you weak to do that because you're
not as prepared as you might be.
So you could say,
you know,
human beings are tribal,
social animals that have a territory and
the territory.
Then you think,
well what's the territory while let's
say tree dwelling chimp,
ancestors,
territories,
the jungle.
It's like,
no,
it's,
it's not the territory.
The territory is a little bit of the
jungle plus the things that come in from
outside plus the primate dominance
hierarchy that exists in that area.
Right,
right.
So that's the,
that's the territory.
That's the environment,
you know,
because for mythological reasons,
we tend to make a separation between the
environment and culture,
but it's yes,
makes sense at one level of analysis,
but at another level of analysis,
all it does is screw you up because your
territory fundamentally isn't the world,
not the natural objective world.
You want to stay as far away from that
thing as you possibly can.
Your territory is that circle of people
with whom you spend 90 percent of your
time and so if you're a gym for example,
or some other kind of monkey,
highly social,
what do you do all day?
You sleep,
you eat,
your chew leaves.
If you're a chip and you grew mother
gyms like it's constantly social
interaction and you're jockeying for
position in the dominance hierarchy like
mean girls and not in that movie.
You know,
and you're mapping out the social
territory,
knowing who's who and what's what,
and then trying to get up somewhere near
the top.
And that's your environment.
That's your environment.
And so your,
your,
your world is that social natural
circle,
which is a four dimensional territory
because it's,
you know,
what's going length,
width and height,
plus it stretches across time.
So it's this transforming natural
entity.
And then inside that there's a pyramid
and the pyramid is made out of all the
primates that you interact with.
And that's the world.
A circle with a pyramid on it.
Now I'll give you a vision.
This vision I had once when I was trying
to figure this stuff out.
Okay?
So what is the world?
So imagine that there's a field in front
of you that stretches as far as you can
see.
Okay.
And then you're flying above it.
And what you see everywhere are these
pyramids,
let's say for the sake of argument that
they're like skyscrapers made out of
glass.
There's peers,
tears in them and you fly down and one's
here and one's here.
And some of them overlap and some of
them are really big and some of them are
small and like they're just everywhere.
And you're flying around above them and
you fly close enough to look inside.
And what you see inside them are people
all packed together trying to scramble
up to the top.
And that's the world.
That's the reality.
And the funny thing is,
is that you can be in one of those
pyramids,
crap,
clambering away to the top or you can be
flying above it.
Those are your options and if you have
to choose,
you should be flying above it.
And so the relationship between the self
and the Ego Avatar is the same as the
relationship between the thing that is
flying above and the thing that's within
one of those pyramids trying to scramble
to the top,
you know,
you say,
well I'm going to get to the top,
top of what?
There's 100 talks,
there's 200 talks and then you might
say,
is there anything above the top?
Well,
there is.
There's this part of you that isn't
entrapped within that particular system.
And that can move from place to place.
If you look at Egypt mythology,
so you know,
you see on the back of the American
dollar bill,
that's a symbol of value,
right?
Okay.
So what's The pyramid?
There's a pyramid on it,
right?
What's the top of the pyramid?
It's the triangle separate from the
pyramid.
There's an ID inside it.
That's because the top of the pyramid is
an IRA and it's separate from the
pyramid.
And what that means fundamentally is
that
the thing that transcends the structure
is attention,
voluntary attention.
Now,
the Egyptians worshiped voluntary
attention in the form of Horace
[inaudible].
He was,
uh,
he was gone,
right?
Horace.
And I'll tell you about horace and
detail,
but one of Horus is avatars was the
fault and the reason for that is falcons
can really,
really,
really see and they fly around.
And so they're like the king's eyes,
like,
like the little bird zoo in,
uh,
in the lion king,
right?
He was the king's eyes to thing that
flies around the boat and he was a
particular enemy of scar scar.
Eat some at the beginning and then spits
them out.
And the reason that the king's eyes is
an enemy of scars because the king's
eyes can see what he is,
right?
And he's the eternal forest that works
to disrupt the kingdom and bring
everything into ruin.
Classic myth.
Classic Grantham.
Partly accounting for why that was the
largest selling highest grossing cartoon
in Disney history.
Right.
They got from mythology pretty right.
So okay,
so attention.
Oh,
okay,
well we'll do this.
So you might say what's a human being
like?
Remember I told you that when Penfield
was mapping the brain,
he was poking people and you can either
poke them along the sensory strip,
which is if the motor strip is here,
the sensory strip is just behind it and
the motor strip is where the motor
systems of your body are represented in
so far as you can control them.
And the sensory strip is where the
sensory systems are represented in so
far as you can feel them.
So what this is is a that the bar is
laid out weirdly on the motor cortex.
One of the things that's pretty funny is
that the Genitalia area in the sensory
Cortex,
it's right beside the feet.
And so I think you know,
there's,
that's why people have foot fetishes and
love massages,
foot massages is because they're
spreading activation from the foot area
to the general area and God only knows
why that is.
Maybe because you had to have really
sensitive feet to tromp around without
stepping on horrible things,
whatever.
So you can,
you can put this weird stretched out
body representation together in a,
in a representational form like this.
And they called that the whole monkey
plus,
which is the like the little man that
exists inside your brain.
So what you see that's the motor
Homunculus,
not the sensory Homonculus,
but what?
So what do you see?
What?
What's a person as far as brain is
concerned?
Well,
hand,
that's for sure.
Thumb,
It's like your thumb is represented as
your whole body and it's because your,
your,
your chest,
your torsos hardly represented at all is
why is that?
It's like,
well,
how many things do you manipulate with
your chest?
Like none.
Right?
So you don't,
you don't have motor control over it.
So it's not represented so.
But the hands man,
those things,
they're represented like mad and so is
the face and the lips and the tongue and
there's a bunch of reasons for that.
One is that when you're an infant,
you explored like mad with your mouth,
but you do that through your whole life
because when you eat,
you know what it's like.
If you're eating something and there's a
bit of sand in it like you,
you find it and you take it out.
It's like you can detect this teeny
little thing that's not supposed to be
in your mouth and while that's a good
thing because lots of things aren't
supposed to be in your mouth.
So that's part of the reason.
Then the other part of the reason is,
well,
think about what you do with your
tongue.
I mean there's a lot of things you do
with your tongue.
Some of them are eating,
some of them are talking,
some of them are all sorts of intimate
behaviors.
That thing is wired up and it's wired up
right at birth and then it's the same
with your lips and your and the rest of
your mouth.
You use that to communicate so your
hands will wander around taking the
world apart and putting it back
together,
which is exactly what your brain does
and then you blab about what you're
doing to everyone and that's basically a
human being and I like to think of this
thing is it's sort of the.
It's a comical representation of the
hero that goes out to confront the
world,
right?
Because the hero has two elements.
One is explore
and that sort of what?
That's where the West is powerful.
I would say like we have a really well
developed mythology of the exploratory
hero,
but where we're not so well developed as
the second part because in the second
part of the classic Hero's story,
you're supposed to come back and
communicate about what you found and so
there's a individual exploration element
and then there's a communicate and
update.
The culture element and both of those
are equally important and it's something
that we don't do well.
We don't have much respect for tradition
in the west and it's a really,
really big problem because the ethical
responsibility of a human being is to
take the dead culture,
so that's the dead father or the dead
God,
and to revivify it with attention and
communication and you've failed to do
that.
Then everything disappears and we,
we are failing to do that.
We're leaving it all behind instead.
It's not a good idea.
You know,
if the old gods die,
as Nietzsche said,
they had new gods in very rapidly and if
you think the old guard was bad,
you wait till the new gods get ahold of
you.
So while we saw what happened in the
20th century,
right,
with all the ideologies that sprang up
in the absence of classical religious
belief,
it's like,
okay,
you're not so thrilled with Catholicism.
If you think about that as,
you know,
the fundamental tradition of the West,
with the witch burnings and the
inquisition and all that,
it's like,
yeah,
well get a load of the Nazis and then
see what you think.
So or the communists for that matter,
it's like
from bad to worse in an unimaginable
way,
you know,
so and that's partly because those
archaic systems,
those are religious systems,
they weren't ideologies.
There are a whole different class of
thing and we don't understand them very
well and it's not good because you
cannot live without understanding them.
You don't know who you are.
And then you fall prey to weird mental
diseases like nihilism.
That's,
that's one.
And the other one is ideological
possession.
So you become a totalitarian or a
analyst and that's a bad outcome and you
might think,
well,
what's the alternative?
Well,
you know what happens in Pinocchio,
right?
You've watched Pinocchio.
Okay.
I often show up in oak you to this
class,
but I don't know if I'm going to do that
this year.
But anyways,
but now he's a puppet marionette.
Someone else's pulling his strings has.
It wouldn't hit.
He's not very bright.
He hasn't banged around the world at
all.
He's got a good father.
The old Japan who really would,
rather than he was a real boy,
right?
A real person.
So he's the kind of father that wants to
produce an individual and not a slave.
So,
and that's why,
you know,
in his workshop it's all friendly and
there's a nice fire and he's making toys
and there's lots of music.
It's like go Japan.
Oh,
he's a good guy.
So it makes this little puppet and he
sends them out in the world,
says,
go be a real boy.
Well,
Pinocchio runs into a whole class of
different obstacles.
One is evil,
right?
That's the,
uh,
that's the coachman.
And uh,
the Italian stereotype guy who makes him
a dancing puppets celebrity,
which I think is pretty funny.
I mean,
that's really prescient because you
might think,
well,
what's the goal of your typical
boneheaded,
you know,
mid adolescent in North America.
It's like unearned celebrity.
Well,
that's exactly what Pinocchio goes for
first.
And that doesn't work out so well
because he ends up a slave.
And then the next thing that happens is
he capitalizes on the fact that he's
vulnerable and pretends he's sick and
goes off for a vacation under the
direction of the coachman who's
basically Satan in disguise.
And it goes out to treasure island,
pleasure island,
and meets all the delinquent.
So we're just like Nazis.
And it turns out that in fact,
the whole ploys to enslave everyone,
to deprive them of their voice,
that's the donkey's brain and to make
them into slaves pretty damn horrifying.
And that was,
that movie came out about the same time
that the Nazis were really,
you know,
grasping power in,
in central Europe.
It's like they got it exactly right.
Here's what's really going on behind the
scenes.
So.
And then what happens?
Well,
Pinocchio turns halfway into a brain
donkey because,
you know,
he's gone off the path and in order to
get back on it,
he tries to go home,
but it's too late.
He's grown up.
You can't go home.
He's not a kid anymore.
Goes home and dad,
isn't there surprised,
surprised?
Because once you grow up and you go
home,
dad isn't there.
It's just another human being.
So then what happens?
Well then he has to go into the ocean.
Now that's particularly weird,
right?
It's like,
there he is,
half donkey.
He's a puppet.
The dove comes down and drops him a
message from God.
It's like the Holy Spirit descending,
except it's actually from the blue fairy
weirdly enough,
and the message says you have to go to
the deepest part of the ocean and rescue
your father.
It's like,
yeah,
that is what you have to do.
If you don't want to be a bloody puppet
donkey,
you have to go down into the depths and
find your dead father and you have to
revivify him.
And that's what happened.
So Pinocchio goes way down there to the
deepest depths and finds monster who's a
monster.
So terrible that the fish swim away just
at the sound of his voice,
just like,
what's his name?
Uh,
he who shall not be named Voldemort,
right?
You can't even say his damn name.
Same with monster.
Put occhio goes down there.
It goes into the whale.
What happens in Japan?
Oh,
says there's no getting out with this.
There's no getting out of this.
We just have to sit here and Cook Fish
and Pinocchio.
Thanks.
Cook.
And then he starts breaking up all the
chairs and everything.
And as far as freaking out,
it's like,
what do you do?
Breaking all these chairs?
What are we going to sit on?
And then Pinocchio Lights them on fire.
He's a master of fire.
It's a shamonic ritual,
but he is a master of fire.
That's where human being is.
He,
he gets everything burning.
Of course,
pedal was all freaked out about that
because what are they going to sit on
and Pinocchio thinks,
who cares about sitting?
We're going to solve the problem once
and for all.
And so then the whale turns into a fire
breathing dragon,
which is pretty damn weird thing for a
whale to do.
Half Kills Pinocchio.
He lived,
washes up on shore dead,
but he saves his father.
And then at the very end of the movie,
he's lying on his bed,
all drowned.
They're all like having a show.
He's a dead pop it now.
It's like,
do you want to be alive?
Popular?
A dead puppet?
Well,
maybe the dead puppet is better than the
live property.
It depends on where you're going.
So then he's on the bed.
The blue fairy comes down and says,
well,
you've been honest and courageous bag.
Now you're real.
You know,
and then they have a little party and
that's,
that's just exactly right.
Got that.
Exactly right.
So that's how.
That's part of the hero mythology is the
rescuing of the father,
the father,
because otherwise you're a corpse like
you're a historical creature.
You're cultural creature.
You're a.
You cannot live without your culture.
You think you can,
but you can't.
It disappears in and you don't even
look.
I'll give you an example.
In the Mesopotamian creation myth,
which I'm going to tell you about next
week,
one of the things that happens is that
the first round of gods,
so they're like primordial forces.
They're pretty damn careless and they
killed their father and they make this
place to live on his corpse.
Okay?
That's where we live.
We live on the corpse of our ancestors
because we live in this society.
It's dead.
It's the product of dead people.
So it's got this dead element,
but we're living on it.
Okay?
They're very careless.
They kill it.
They render it completely dead.
Well,
what happens is Taya Matt,
who's the mother of chaos,
she comes flooding back and she thinks,
oh,
you killed the thing that protects you.
You just wait to see what happens and
that's exactly.
Yet you killed the thing that structures
you.
You will know it.
It's like niches,
prediction from the death of God.
It's like you killed this.
You think are.
It doesn't make any difference.
It's like,
Huh,
wrong.
It's like the striders protecting the
hobbits.
You get rid of that thing that protects
you in chaos,
comes flooding in and you like.
You have no idea what's possible.
We do though,
because we lived through the 20th
century,
we know exactly what's possible.
You know,
hundreds of millions of unnecessary
deaths.
That's what's possible.
We're lucky we didn't blow the whole
damn thing up so and we still could.
So people pursuing their dead
etiologies.
You don't rescue the dead father.
You're the puppet of death.
That's what you are already on.
That cheery note.