So here's a brief note to tomorrow's
student demonstrators.
For those of you who don't know,
there's a demonstration plan for
tomorrow.
They call it a rally and teaching,
um,
at Sydney Smith Hall,
that's 100 St George Street,
Toronto,
479 people are interested.
Two hundred and 32 people are going in.
1,100 people have been,
have had this missive shared with them.
And so this is the call to action
released by people who are planning the,
um,
the rally.
And I'm addressing that for a number of
reasons.
Um,
but I'm only going to,
I'm going to stick to one very briefly.
The people who are putting out this call
to action say,
have said the following,
Jordan Peterson,
University of Toronto professor and
practicing psychologist has released the
first of a plan three part video series
of attacking political correctness and
academia.
And this video he declares this proud
unwillingness to call transgender people
by any pronouns he does not believe
apply to them.
His disbelief in the very existence of
non binary people and his belief that
any attempts to challenge him or anyone
else on these points,
amount to Marxist fash fascism.
Okay.
So the first thing I would say is that I
do not regard any of those three
statements about what I said as accurate
representations of what I said,
but I don't have time at the moment to
do a detailed refutation of them point
by point.
So I'm going to have to make this very
straightforward and simple.
I don't disbelieve in the existence of
non binary people.
Okay.
Do you want me to say that again?
Obviously people who don't fit into
standard binary categories of sexual
identity,
uh,
however you decide to construe that
broadly or narrowly.
Obviously those people exist.
I never said they didn't exist.
What I said instead was that biological
sex,
gender identity and gender expression do
not vary independently and they don't
vary independently.
And we'll just leave it at that for now
because I don't have enough time to go
into the rest of it all the way will in
the future.
So if you're going out tomorrow to this
demonstration because you want to
indicate your discomfort with my
disbelief in the very existence of non
binary people,
you might as well just stay home.