You,
it's supposed to be nice.
So my name is Tammy Jordan and I known
each other
for nearly 50 years.
Nearly 50 years.
Oh,
that's better.
We come from northern Alberta.
He lived up the street from me.
I always knew he would be a fascinating
person.
So in my late twenties he moved east.
I was in Montreal and I thought it's
probably time to marry them because if I
don't marry him I won't know what
happens
and now we're seeing what's happening.
Yeah,
I mean he's been talking about these
things.
He's been talking about what's going on
in our society and how it's moving left
and how things are destabilizing for the
last 20 years.
And so when in September he said he came
down one morning and he was quite
disturbed and he said,
you know,
I've got a couple of emails that I can't
deal with.
I can't deal with quietly and I'm going
to have to say something.
What do you think can.
I said,
well,
you've been speaking to me and my son
who was there to for for a very long
time,
and maybe it is time for you to tell
everyone
what's going on.
And so he didn't know.
He didn't know what would happen,
you know,
we didn't have any idea,
he just went up and made a video except
what he's said and what he's always
thought and what he sees coming down the
pipes.
And it resonated with tremendous
response and mostly almost 95 percent or
more positive response.
So although it was destabilizing and I
found beginning though,
it's,
it's a good thing.
And we've worked a lot with myself.
I wasn't as learned that,
but I sure liked a lot and I know you
guys have to and you're going to learn a
whole bunch of more today.
So welcome.
Thank you.
So who's your filming this?
Can I walk around?
Can you hear me without the microphone
then I will be able to walk around.
So I want to tell you a story.
It's not,
not be as good if you're
not on the mic is going to be broadcast.
So.
Okay,
so
I started studying the things that I
have been talking about in.
Well really as long back as I can
remember.
I think that's true.
I wrote an essay when I was about 13 on
the,
on Auschwitz.
It wasn't very good essay but I was only
13 so it's not that surprising but,
and I don't know exactly why it was a
particular concern to me except that of
course it's the sort of thing that
should be of concern to everyone.
How about if I speak a little louder?
Alright,
alright,
now I'll,
I'll do it.
I'll do it this way.
I think if you have any trouble at the
back,
let me know what I'll,
I'll make sure that I'm,
I'm projecting.
So I said when I was about 13,
I wrote an essay on,
on our sweats and I,
I was trying to understand it.
Um,
I think maybe I tried to understand it
in a way that was somewhat different
than most people who examined historical
events because I was trying to
understand how human beings could do
that knowing full well that I was one of
them.
Then that's the critical thing because
generally when people examine especially
something horrifying that's done by
humanity,
they make the assumption that it's other
people doing it and that's a big mistake
in my estimation because if a lot of
human beings have done something
terrible,
you can be sure that
being a human being that you're capable
of it
and you know one of the things that
we've been asked repeatedly to do as a
consequence of what happened in World
War Two is to not forget it,
but it's always been my contention that
you can't remember something you don't
understand
and you don't understand what happened
in Nazi Germany or in the Soviet Union
for that matter.
Until you understand that had you been
there,
the probability that you would have
played a role and that wouldn't have
been a positive one,
is extraordinarily high.
When people do think about themselves as
actors in situations like that,
they have a proclivity to cast
themselves in their heroic role.
Assuming that had they been say in Nazi
Germany in the 19 thirties that they
would taken on the burden of
fighting against the Nazis and defending
the things that should have been
defended,
but that's a very foolish
presupposition.
Especially because it's more or less
self evident from the historical
perspective that that isn't what people
did and in order for us to come to terms
with that it means that we have to
understand how it happened,
but more importantly what role we still
play as individuals in
acting in such a way that such things
are not only likely but desired.
When I was older and in university,
I was plagued by nightmares mostly
about.
They were apocalyptic nightmares,
mostly about the Third World War and I
had very large long series of dreams
about,
about nuclear bombs.
I remember one of them,
I was living in Edmonton at the time and
on the
on the south side,
and I can remember watching out through
my window in the dream and seeing
mushroom cloud form over the main core
of the city.
And then the dream shifted locales and
there were a bunch of people in the
wreckage and they started to fight and I
thought that's just exactly right.
And that was exactly what my nightmares
were like,
is that no matter how tremendous the
catastrophe,
we don't seem able to derive the proper
conclusions from it and start to act in
a way that makes such things less rather
than more likely.
When I was in graduate school at Mcgill,
which would have been after that,
I was studying political science before
that,
sorry,
back when I was in Edmonton.
And before that I had even thought about
going into,
into law.
But as I studied political science,
I got increasingly disenchanted with the
explanations that were being offered to
me about motivations for,
for human conflict,
um,
that especially in the upper years of my
undergraduate education,
that the lower years were pretty good
because mostly what I studied was
political philosophy and literature.
And I found that very helpful.
But in the upper gears,
the contention of the professors was
that people primarily
engaged in conflict for economic
reasons.
That never struck me as a very deep,
deep explanation because it didn't get
up the core of the issue,
which was,
well,
okay,
people fight about things of material
value,
but why do they value those things?
I mean,
it's kind of self evident if you think
about food and shelter and so forth,
but generally speaking,
especially in the 20th century,
it wasn't necessarily about the basics
of food and shelter that people were
engaging in conflict about.
It was.
It was something much more subtle than
that.
Maybe it had more to do with national
identity,
with identity,
that kind of thing.
And so there was a psychological element
missing in the analysis of the human
propensity for conflict.
That to me bloomed larger and larger and
so I decided at least in part for that
reason to pursue a graduate degree in
psychology and in clinical psychology
and I went to mcgill and that's when I
started to read very much more broadly I
suppose,
and I spent a lot of time reading.
I read a lot of Freud and a lot of all
the classic clinical psychologists who
were extraordinarily useful.
Carl Rogers and Sigmund Freud,
Alfred Adler and a whole host of them,
all the classic thinkers I could get my
hands on and also most particularly the
philosopher Friedrich Nietzsche,
most of whose major works I read at that
point and Theodore Dostoevsky who was
writing very similar things to it very.
In fact,
Nisha was quite influenced by
Dostoevsky.
Dostoevsky was a like a master in the
literary genre,
has five great books
focused on the most difficult questions
that face humanity both socially and
individually.
I found those books overwhelmingly
powerful and also extraordinarily useful
beyond good or a credit punishment,
for example,
is a brilliant,
brilliant piece of work outlining the
motivation of someone who regards
himself as above all law and who decides
that to not kill when necessary is an
act of cowardice and so Dostoevsky walks
through his rationalization and and the
murder and the aftermath of it in a way
that's extraordinarily
enlightening and painful simultaneously
and at the same time niche and Germany
was writing philosophical tracts on
exactly the same themes there.
Their lives ran in in unbelievably close
parallel.
In fact,
when Nisha finally went insane,
he had some illness that has been very
difficult to diagnose.
He had.
He'd seen someone beating a horse in a
street and embraced it out of compassion
and there's a scene exactly like that in
one of Dostoyevsky's stories,
so it's the parallels are really uncanny
and I also read a lot of neuroscience
because I did my thesis on the
biological predisposition to alcoholism
and that required a lot of investigation
into more hardcore science investigation
into the structure and function of the
brain and I tried to weave all of that
together in a book that I published in
1999.
It took me about 15 years to write.
I was writing three hours a day every
day and thinking about it all the time,
like I was absolutely 100 percent
obsessed by
by the sorts of issues that I'm
discussing with you today.
It took me deep.
I read the Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn,
much of what he wrote at the same time.
And then of course I,
I,
I studied Carl young in great depth.
When,
when I finally started to crack,
what he was talking about was
extraordinarily difficult material.
I read volume nine of his collected
works,
which is called archetypes of the
collective unconscious.
At first time I read it,
I didn't understand a word he was saying
and I think that's very common
experience for people reading young
who's certainly persona non grata in the
modern ECAP academy.
And I think the reason for that is that
while I think when you first encountered
union attended,
bounce off of,
and then the next thing that happens is
you get very frightened and then you
just leave it the hell alone.
And it's no wonder as far as I'm
concerned,
because I don't think I've ever read
anyone including me.
Chip that was more terrifying than
young.
Um,
neat.
Young was a student of nature.
I don't,
I don't mean technically speaking,
although Nisha was everywhere.
Niches thinking was everywhere.
When human was maturing.
People know Carl young primarily as a,
as a disciple,
let's say a Freud,
which is true in part because Freud of
course did the initial,
you might call,
might describe it as initial excavating
work.
Outlining the fact that there was more
going on in the human psyche then that
met the conscious I and his greatest
work likely was the interpretation of
dreams where he started to perform an
archeology of the of the symbolic
unconscious.
I'm showing that much of our mental life
went on in some sense underneath our
conscious awareness,
which is of course regarded as a truism
now by psychologists,
but was quite revolutionary at the time.
It wasn't Freud's.
It wasn't entirely an original idea with
Freud.
Few things are entirely original ideas,
but he went farther than anyone else
synthesizing it and also publicizing and
promoting it and also basing a
psychotherapeutic theory on it.
Really remarkable set of accomplishments
and young was very much influenced by
Freud but also by niche and the reason
he was influenced by nature most
particularly was that niches
announcement of the death of God.
In the late 19 hundreds was was a very
striking philosophical event and and
I'll,
I'll return to this,
but Nicha believed that because God was
dead,
so to speak,
and the value structure upon which
Western civilization was constructed,
had God at its foundation that that will
all crumble and that people would have
to become their own daddy,
is in a sense they would have to
discover or create furniture to create
their own values and before nature could
outline how that might happen.
He suffered the unfortunate descent into
madness and then died,
and so we left this major,
major problem behind which is if it's
the case that the
ideational foundation of Western
civilization
was predicated on an illusion,
on an illusion.
What?
What,
what?
What would we do next?
And he just said,
well,
that what we will certainly do next is
descend into an unholy combination of
nihilism and totalitarianism.
Because those will be the things that
will back in most clearly in the chaotic
aftermath of the disillusion of the
value structure upon which our society
has been predicated and nature in his
book will to power prophesied very
directly that millions of people would
die in the 20th century specifically
because of Communist revolutions and
that was 40 years roughly speaking 30 to
40 years before the communist revolution
in the Soviet Union.
So that's an act of prophetic vision
that's absolutely incomprehensible to.
I mean in the West.
We didn't know that the Soviet Union was
going to fall until the day it fell and
niche and knew what was going to happen
in the 20th century in like night in
like 1880.
It's absolutely remarkable.
Young was very interested in the
Nietzschean problem.
More interested in it than anything else
because he knew that the question of
where we would derive our values from
and how we would ground them in some
sort of underlying solid underwrite
lying reality would become was the
paramount psychological question of the
of the age.
And he spent his entire life his entire
life attempting to address that.
You Young's idea was that we weren't
going to be able to create our own
values because human beings cannot
create their own values and you know
that if,
if,
if you observe your own action,
if you observe your own being,
you can make resolutions.
You can try to act in a particular way,
maybe a way that you regard as better,
but you'll find out very rapidly that
you can't enslave yourself and tell
yourself what to do so easily.
Even when you're motivated to do good
things.
You know when you make your New Year's
resolutions and say that you're going to
eat properly and go to the gym.
That generally lasts about a week and so
you can't boss yourself around.
As it turns out,
no more than you can really boss other
people around.
And it's because you do have a nature.
You have a nature and you can't just
arbitrarily,
um,
mold and shape that nature because you,
like other people will rebel against
your own will.
And so and so young.
His contention was that we would have to
go inside ourselves,
that that's how he looked at it,
into the symbolic background of our
psychological structure and rediscover
what we had lost,
and so
I found that's the ancient mythological
motif of voyaging to the depths and
rescuing your father from the belly of
the beast,
and you see that idea
reflected often in popular culture.
A very well developed example of that is
in the Movie Pinocchio,
which I'm sure how many of you have seen
that movie.
Yeah,
right.
Well,
that speaks for itself,
right?
I mean,
there's a why.
Why?
Why are you watching a puppet,
an animated puppet rescue his father
from the belly of a whale?
It makes absolutely no sense,
but you don't care when you're watching
it.
You think this is quite interesting and
the reason it's interesting is because
it speaks to you at a level that you
understand,
but that you do not understand how you
and of course any good work of art does
exactly that to you.
It speaks to you about things that you
almost know but don't yet know,
and that's what makes it profound.
And you knew that it would be necessary
for modern people to journey to the
chaotic depths and rescue they're dead
father from the underworld,
which is a very interesting symbolic
realization in the aftermath of
Nietzsche statement that God had died.
And so that's what you did.
That's what he spent his entire life
doing.
And he detailed that out in a very long
series of very difficult and,
and very unsettling books,
um,
which people tend not to read and,
and,
and no wonder,
no wonder.
And so I read everything I could get my
hands on that young had published at
that point and a lot of work by various
historians of religion and like Murcia
Eliana,
who's,
who's out of favor because the
postmodernists don't like him.
And uh,
and I put this altogether in this book
that I published in 1999 called maps of
meaning.
And it's also a very difficult book.
And that was some somewhat purposeful
and somewhat inevitable.
It was,
it was purposeful because I knew that if
I was going to discuss such things and I
didn't make it ridiculously rigorous,
at least to the degree that I was
capable of doing that,
that it would be easily dismissed and
that seems counterproductive,
but,
but it was also because I was trying to
figure out rather than trying to write a
book,
I was trying to figure something out and
I was doing that by writing because
writing is a very good way of figuring
things out and I was trying to make it
as clear as I could,
but that wasn't all that clear.
It's about 500 pages long.
I think this book and it's and I,
I think I rewrote every sentence in it
at least 50 times,
probably too many times because by the
end it got.
I think I over edited it.
I think it was,
it,
it's in some sense too tight to it.
It's like it's like an overworked piece
of art that that might be one way of
thinking about it,
but.
And then it,
it's taken me decades of speaking about
it to continue to.
What would you call it?
Purify and refine it so that I can
discuss it without having to go through
dozens of hours of explanation and to
condense it down into something that's
more easily comprehensible.
So that's what I'm going to try to do
this afternoon.
I want to tell you why I think we're in
the position that we're in,
what that position is,
and also potentially what can be done
about it and those seams because also I
believed and still do believe that if
you actually understand the problem,
you can solve it,
but but you have.
That's actually an indication of your
understanding.
Right?
If you,
if you,
if you haven't solved it,
you actually don't understand that
there's things about it that you still
don't grasp.
And so when I was writing maps of
meaning,
I wasn't so much trying to only figure
out why it was that people were capable
of the terribly barbaric things that
they so happily did at Auschwitz,
but also to figure out what could be
done,
if anything,
to stop that from happening.
Because it was also by no means self
evident that anything in fact could be
done about it because that might just be
an expression of that central human
nature that I was talking about earlier
and the fundamentally irreparable.
There's.
There's been no shortage of writers
who've proposed that human beings are
fundamentally flawed in a way that
cannot be rectified and that are and we
have a catastrophic destiny waiting for
us.
As a consequence.
I mean in some sense that's built right
into the fabric of Christianity itself
because of course at least certain
variants of it,
and I'm speaking about Christianity
because in many ways it's at the
foundation of Western Society because
certain elements of Christianity at
least regard people as irretrievably or
irreparably tainted with original sin
which emerged right at the birth of our
species.
And there's something extraordinarily
powerful about that idea because of
course everybody in this room knows that
they're seriously flawed and also knows
that they do things that make those
flaws more rather than less likely.
And everyone has that sense about
themselves.
Unless they're narcissistic beyond
belief.
In which case they also suspected.
But only at an unconscious level,
so we do carry this sense of ourselves
as deeply flawed and imperfect and,
and,
and maybe fatally so and that seems to
be built right into us.
And so maybe there is no solution,
but that seemed like a dismal hypothesis
to begin with.
So I wanted to do as in I wanted to
investigate as deeply as I possibly
could to see if I could conjure up
something that vaguely rick represented
the solution
for a long time.
You know,
there were months when I was writing
where really felt quite mad
and what the one of the most intense
periods of time where that occurred was
when I think I was kind of on the cusp
of figuring out what I needed to figure
out.
I'd figured out two things.
One was that I kind of understood
finally,
white people had belief systems and it
wasn't
the belief system was there because we
have to deal with an infinitely complex
world and we have to simplify it down to
proportions that we can manage because
we don't have infinite cognitive or
emotional or physiological resources
were very bounded creatures living in an
unbounded environment.
Roughly speaking,
it's too much for us and so we have to
impose structures of simplification on
the world or or we we,
we get so stressed we die that that's
roughly the bottom line.
For example,
if you develop posttraumatic stress
disorder which occurs when you encounter
something in your life that you cannot
compute,
so to speak,
your body goes into emergency
preparation mode,
which which makes it hyper,
hyper responsive to threat and ready to
do anything which is emergency
preparation and that's so
physiologically demanding that it
demolishes your health is not merely
psychological.
It damages your brain.
I mean it,
it.
You just can't stay in high gear running
flat out continually u dot and so people
need to simplify the world.
They need to live within structures of
simplification because that's how they.
That's how they protect themselves from
the terrible onslaught of complexity,
but by the same token,
we organize ourselves into these,
these structures of simplification.
That's what our cultures are.
We negotiate them,
we inhabit them jointly,
and because of that,
when we run into people who do that
differently,
the probability that we'll engage in
conflict is extraordinarily high because
I can't give up my beliefs just because
you have different beliefs and if we
don't have the same beliefs,
then we can't peacefully occupied the
same territory,
so there's seems to be nothing for that
except conflict.
If we can't negotiate,
then we have to fight.
So then I thought,
well that's,
that's,
that's that.
Then on the one hand,
the cat and our belief systems because
they structure our realities and protect
us,
but
and we can't fight because now we're so
technologically powerful that if we do,
we're going to destroy everything.
It's like,
well,
that's that.
There's option one and its opposite.
That completely exhausts the options.
And so that was a horrible realization.
Absolutely dreadful realization because
you know,
it's certainly possible if you think
about this from a biological or an
evolutionary viewpoint,
is that we're kind of a peculiar species
and we've developed these terrible
technologies of war and there's
absolutely no reason to assume that we
won't just use them to wipe ourselves
out and you know,
maybe 30 percent of us as individuals
and in our own psyches would be happy
about that because life is pretty
dreadful and it's full of suffering and
there's lots of that are harsh about
existence and so maybe we should just
let the whole thing go and believe me,
people are plenty motivated to do that.
If you haven't observed that motivation
in yourself at some point in your life,
either you're not paying attention or
don't want to pay attention or something
sufficiently dreadful has not yet
happened to you,
but it will.
It will,
you know,
because everyone encounters catastrophic
crisis in their life and it drops the
bottom out of them and makes them
desperate and angry.
And,
and that's also part of the human
condition.
Luckily after about three months of
thinking about that,
I had a series of dreams that helped me
sort out a third alternative,
and that was of course,
at least in part
emerged as a consequence of all the
things that I was reading,
so
I want recert return to the Nietzschean
conundrum,
so
Nisha was an extraordinarily astute
critic of the Judeo Christian tradition.
He's.
He wrote a book called the antichrist in
fact,
and he also said that he philosophizes
with a hammer and what he meant by that
was that he was taking the hardest,
heaviest object he could and smashing up
everything he possibly could with as
much intellectual rigor as he could
manage,
and that was plenty because he was truly
a genius,
but he was.
He wasn't a nihilistic person.
Quite the contrary,
had a very good reputation among those
who knew him,
for example,
is a very kind man,
but he was in part looking for something
that he couldn't destroy.
All right,
because that's partly how you find out
what's real you.
You hit things so to speak.
You push against the.
Your children do that to you.
For example,
they push against you to see where you
won't yield and then they think,
ah,
there's reality there.
There's a wall there.
I can't go beyond that,
and that's what Nisha was searching for
and he was doing it all out.
Fundamentally,
how his contention was that what had
happened in the West was that there that
the Judeo Christian tradition and even
the precursors of that tradition upon
which from which that tradition he
merged had insisted for millennia that
the pursuit of truth was the highest
moral value and that one of the
consequences of that was that
the west developed science,
which was part of that pursuit of the
truth and then and then the tools of
science once successfully grasped and
universalized were then turned against
the dogmatic structure of the church.
When everyone woke up as scientists,
so to speak and thought,
well,
we're living by a set of superstitions
and and they're not true
and we have to with them.
And so that was copernicus,
Darwin,
and that was Freud,
and that was these repeated blows that
that are symbolic culture took at the
hands of something that had fostered and
created and
Nisha said something as well.
At the same time when you remarked on
this,
on this consequences,
he said,
one of the most terrible things about
discovering
that assist them you believed in no
longer functions is no longer sufficient
or can be undermined,
is that it raises the specter that all
such systems have the same flaws.
You know sometimes you can jump from
atheism to Christianity and from
Christianity to socialism,
say in success of leaps,
and then you're someone who's faithless
from within the perspective of a given
system,
but you're faithful to the idea that
there are in fact systems that will
work,
but if your system fails enough,
then you can end up in a situation where
you don't even have any faith in the
idea that systems as such can work and
that makes you nihilistic.
And Nisha saw that as,
as,
as the origin of the specter of
nihilism,
hopelessness.
Fundamentally.
Now it's more complicated than that
because there are underground reasons,
so to speak,
for being nihilistic,
that have nothing to do with the mirror
collapse of irrational belief system,
and we'll talk about those too,
and he also talked about the,
the,
the inevitable rise of totalitarianism
as a medication for the loss of all
meaning.
In some sense you might say,
well,
if you're in a chaotic state because you
no longer know what to believe,
it's very,
and someone offers you a set of
certainties to guide your life.
By then it's very attractive for you to
reach out and grip onto those with all
of your soul,
so to speak,
because that stops you from merely being
adrift.
And then there's underground reasons for
that too.
That all also returned to.
So the first question is,
was it necessary
for the sense of truth that needs you to
described as developed by the Judeo
Christian tradition that then manifested
itself in the scientific methodology to
turn against the symbolic foundation of
that structure and demolish it?
Was that inevitable and wasn't correct?
And that's the first question.
And so the answer to that was
the conflict between science and
religion is a consequence of the
immature state of both of those domains
of thinking.
It's not built into the structure per
se,
it's just that we aren't good enough at
being religious or good enough about at
being scientific in order to see how
they might be reconciled.
Now that's a,
that's a hell of a claim
mean it's a frightening claim because,
and this speaks to some degree to the
underground reasons for being
nihilistic.
So the terrible thing about being
nihilistic is that nothing you do has
any meaning.
And,
and that's not so good because actually
it's actually untrue because there are
forms of meaning in life that nihilism
will protect you from or,
or even increase your exposure to.
And those are the tragic meanings of
life.
I don't care how nihilistic you are,
what you don't believe in.
You're going to believe in your own
pain.
anxiety.
You're going to believe in the fact of
pain and anxiety for everyone else.
You're going to believe in tragedy.
You can't think yourself out of the
catastrophe of the world by being
nihilistic,
so the negative meanings remain.
You can dispense with the positive
meetings,
which seems to be a bad bargain,
but the upside of doing that is quite
straightforward.
If I said to you,
here's your alternatives,
nothing you do matters or has any
meaning.
Alternative one,
everything you do matters and has
meaning,
which one would you pick?
And you might think,
well,
of course I would go for the second
alternative because the first one is so
horrifying,
but the truth of the matter is the
second one is even more horrifying
because it means that the things that
you do for better or worse actually do
matter and in some sense you're
responsible for them not only for the
effect that they have on you in the
immediate circumstances of your life,
but for the effect that they have
radiating out from you to others.
The other people that your network too
and also as they read,
as they,
as they make waves through time.
It couldn't be that everything you do
does matter.
That every choice that you make matters,
and I do believe that that's the case,
that you're constantly making choices
between good and evil and that that
determines the destiny of being and it
isn't obvious to me at all,
that that's something that you would
wish upon yourself and so one of the
advantages to be nihilistic is it
enables you to be totally irresponsible
even though the price you pay for that
is the sacrifice of all positive
meaning.
Well,
so much for the intellectual purity of
nihilism.
Right?
And so those sorts of things have to be
considered very deeply because when
someone says,
well,
I'm hopeless,
sometimes it's because they're suffering
and people can suffer terribly because
of that,
but sometimes it's because they don't
want to be responsible for anything.
And no wonder
back to your point,
young started to examine
religious idiation.
I would say symbolically,
but it's more complicated than that
because you might think that the attempt
to analyze religious thinking
symbolically would reduce it to nothing
about psychology,
but that isn't what happens precisely
because it's as you reduce the religious
ideas to psychology,
you elevate the psyche and so they meet
in the middle and this is something you
understood very,
very well.
It was for that reason that he believed
that Christ was a symbol of the self,
the self being your full totality.
That might be one way of thinking about
it.
Everything that you could conceivably be
if you were everything that you could
be,
and that's that potential,
that risks inside you that everyone
knows about.
You know,
we also even speak about it because we
take people to task when we say you're
not living up to your potential and
everyone knows what that means,
but no one knows what it means because
what the hell is that potential?
It's not something that's real.
By definition,
it's something that's virtual.
It's something that is yet to be and may
never be,
but we still treat it as if it's real
and we also treat the entire world as if
it's made out of potential and I believe
that that is the correct way of viewing
the world.
It's not the dead matter of the 18th
century,
rationalist or empiricists.
It's the living domain of potential that
we interact with on a regular basis from
which at least to some degree,
we extract our own potential.
Here's a rough outline of the story that
that young told that I've been working
on.
So I'm going to tell it as I understand
it,
according to the,
this,
the selection of stories that were
encapsulated in,
in the biblical tradition.
The world is roughly 6,000 years old.
And of course at one level of analysis
that's palpably absurd.
I would say.
Um,
and also narrow because I think to
conceptualize the world has 15 billion
years old with a developmental history
that extends across that massive amount
of time.
And to note that it extends
incomprehensibly vastly outward is a
much more magnificent view of the cosmos
than the rather constrained cosmos that
we inherited from thinkers in the Middle
East,
say 10,000 years ago.
But there's something about it that's
true and the truth in it seems to be its
relationship to the origin of
civilization because it is the case that
civilization everywhere in the world of
the sort that we would regard as complex
and technologically is about 6,000 years
old and why that is is not so self
evident.
Although I suspect it has something to
do with how long it took us to
reformulate ourselves after the last ice
age,
which of course was only roughly 15,000
years ago.
It's not really that far away in time.
So that's the first thing.
But the second thing is what the story,
the creation stories in genesis,
for example,
actually mean because they actually mean
something.
And what they mean is absolutely
remarkable in my estimation.
And so I'm going to tell you a little
bit about that story
because it's necessary to understand
what the story means to determine if
what Nisha said about the inevitable
destruction of our symbolic religious
structures by science was inevitable and
necessary.
And I think the answer to that is no,
we just didn't understand what the hell
we were doing any more than we really
understand why we put up Christmas trees
at Christmas.
So we do that in part because the
Christmas tree is a symbol of life
because the tree is a symbol of life
because we inhabited trees for untold
millions of years and we put lights on
the trees to symbolize the coming back
into the darkness of Midwinter of the
Sun and the light.
And so we play this symbolic game that
celebrates both life and the emergence
of light and consciousness.
And we associate that with the birth of
the savior.
But we don't know that we're doing that,
but we do it anyways.
And,
and we do that sort of thing all the
time because we're smarter than we know.
And that has to be the case because we
don't know ourselves.
We would need a psychology or sociology
and anthropology or any of those things.
If we were transparent to ourselves.
We're machines,
so to speak,
that are far more intelligent and wise.
Then the machines themselves can
understand and we've reveal ourselves to
ourselves.
You know,
our action and our symbolic gestures
constantly.
And then have to reflect on that to try
to understand what it is that we're up
to.
So here's the idea that looks at the
beginning of Genesis.
So
there's,
there's three elements that are involved
in the creation of,
of habitable,
the creation of habitable order from
chaos at the beginning of time.
One of them is whatever is represented
by God,
the father,
and one of them is whatever is
represented by the chaos that exists at
the same time.
And the other is whatever is represented
by the idea of God's word.
That's the logos from a Christian
perspective,
which is a very,
very strange idea.
So there's this idea that was developed
over the course of thousands of years
that a redeeming savior was also the
thing that God used to extract habitable
order out of chaos at the beginning of
time.
It's a very strange idea and and to to
assimilate an idea of that
preposterousness and magnitude to mirror
pre irrational superstition is foolish
first of all,
because we don't even understand what it
means,
but it means something outwardly
profound and it means something
that we cannot forget.
We forget that at our peril.
The story at the beginning of Genesis
means that structure,
that's the father,
that's the patriarchy,
if you will,
structure extracts habitable,
order from chaos through speech.
That's what we do is says in genesis as
well,
that human beings are made in the image
of God and that's why because we've
observed these are ancient ideas,
they were,
they were created with so much blood and
effort that it's incalculable.
You cannot contemplate it.
Now idea is that there's something about
the human being,
whatever it is that makes us conscious,
that interacts with the chaotic
potential that constitutes reality and
extracts out from that the order within
which we live and that there's something
divine about that and that's the value
of the human being,
right?
That's the ineradicable value of the
human being and the idea that each
individual,
even criminals,
even murderers,
the worst and most reprehensible people
have to be treated with the respect due
a divinity because we partake in the
capacity to extract habitable order from
chaos with our consciousness,
with our speech and with our capacity to
communicate and we recognize insofar as
we each recognize the other as valuable.
It's predicated on that observation.
We each have something to offer each
other and something vital and you know
that if you engage in a real
conversation with someone,
a meaningful conversation that suspends
your sense of fragile mortality for a
moment.
You understand that in that
communication between paypal,
something of inestimable value emerges
that you have to pursue and you live
for,
that.
You live for that relationship with
yourself.
You live for that.
That discovery of that relationship,
when you're engaged in an artistic
pursuit,
it's the core of meaning in life and
it's not an illusion,
in fact,
it's a manifestation of the highest
functions of your nervous system because
what your nervous system does is
signaled to you that you're in a place
and time that you cannot see when you're
engaged in something meaningful you need
comes upon you and it's the cure for the
catastrophes of tragic mortality.
That wonderful engagement in what's
meaningful that you do,
you can undo experience and that you can
get better at experiencing if you
practice,
and that's because your nervous system
which has evolved over billions of
years,
has learned to tell you when you're
standing on the border between chaos and
order and keeping them in balance and
that's what manifests itself as
meaningful and that's the same phenomena
that's referred to in the creation
stories in genesis and it's the same
idea that's reflected in this strange
Christian insistence that the thing that
saves mankind is the same thing that
draws order from chaos at the beginning
of time.
It's unbelievably brilliant and we've
been trying to figure it out for who
knows how long forever and have never
been able to fully articulate it because
it's so complicated.
It's such a complicated idea,
but there's nothing in the lease that's
illusory about it.
The habitable order that is created at
the beginning of time.
That's paradise,
right?
Paradise.
That's a walled garden.
It's a well watered place.
That's what he did means Paradise Means
Paradise is a walled garden and that's
where Adam and Eve are first put.
And why is that?
Well,
it's because we do comment,
male and female form.
That's part of it.
So that's part of our,
our eternal landscape that that's how
you can think about it,
is it's the landscape that transcends
all landscapes.
It's the landscape that is what all
landscapes have in common.
That's what it is.
That's what makes it an archetype.
It's a walled garden.
Why?
Well,
the walls are structure and culture and
the garden is nature and all that says
is that people live in an amalgam of
nature and culture and of course that's
precisely the case and that's another
variant of the order.
Chaos,
juxtaposition,
order being culture and chaos being
nature and so we live eternally in the
balance between nature and culture and
if it's properly balanced,
it's as close to paradise as it can get,
but paradise is flawed and why is it
flawed?
Because there's always something lurking
in it that can turn it upside down and
that's the snake and the reason it's a
snake is because the circuits that we
use to process the things that turn our
lives upside down is the same circuit
that are tree dwelling.
Ancestors used to identify predators $60
million years ago,
and so the symbolic structure has
remained exactly the same.
That which lies outside what you
understand is predatory and dangerous.
Well,
that's why you demonize others.
The foreign others because they do stand
in that relationship to you and you use
extraordinarily deep circuitry to do
that,
but human beings being slightly smarter
than your average chimpanzee also have
noted that the terrible Predator that
lurks outside the domains of what you
understand is also the thing that bears
gold.
Right?
And that's the Classic Dragon Myth.
The hero goes out beyond the confines of
order and culture into the chaotic
unknown,
to confront the ultimate Predator who
simultaneously offers the best that can
be possibly gathered,
and that's what human beings are like.
Predator,
animals and prey animals simultaneously
we've learned to represent the unknown
is that thing that threatens us.
Hideously with a multitude of paralyzing
snakes in the head of Medusa,
but continually also offers us precisely
what we need to continue our movement
and everyone knows that which is why we
go to movies that tell us that over and
over and over and over and over trying
to learn what it means and that's what
it means and that's what it means to
partake in the logos and the logos.
The reason that I made the videos that I
made in September in relationship to
free speech is because I know that
respect for the logos and respect for
free speech are the same thing and that
without that respect,
our societies cannot maintain their
structure,
differentiate and progress.
They cannot do it.
We use our free speech to face the
chaotic potential of the world and its
horrors to structure it,
to understand it,
to communicate about it,
and to reach consensus.
It's the mechanism by which we adapt.
There can be no restrictions put upon
that unless you want to sacrifice
adaptations,
and I wouldn't recommend that things get
stale,
old decay,
dad and dangerous with extraordinary
rapidity if living people don't maintain
their responsibility to update the state
and there's no difference between that
and diving down into the chaotic depths
and rescuing your father from the belly
of the whale.
It's exactly the same idea.
It's an ancient,
ancient idea and the reason that we
haven't forgotten it was because
everyone who forgot it died.
So unless that's where we want to go,
we better stop forgetting about it.
Nature said that after God had died,
there would be two things that would
happen.
One would be the emergence of nihilism
as a temptation,
and we already discussed nihilism.
It's like it's a logical consequence of
the collapse of value systems,
but it's also a place for the
irresponsible to hide fine nihilism
totalitarianism.
Well,
we need you to believe that once you had
experienced the collapse of one value
system,
you are unlikely to put your faith in
any value systems.
So then why totalitarianism particularly
say it.
It's nationalistic and communitarian
forums,
which are the two forms that we saw,
act as immense devils in the 20th
century,
right?
With nationalism being pushed most
forcefully forward by the sorts of
political creeds that were exemplified
by the Nazis and with communitarianism
being put forth by the sorts of creams
that were exemplified by the Soviet
Union.
Both absolutely catastrophic
evolutionary dead ends.
Well,
nationalism is easier to understand,
I think because
you need an identity and it has to be
collective because human beings live
collectively.
I mean,
it's the fact that we share an identity
that we can all sit here in this room
peacefully because the identity is
partly who you think you are,
but it's also partly what you expect
from the world and from others and
because you have an identity that's
similar to you,
you can sit together peacefully because
you expect and desire something and so
to you and it's the same thing and
that's what it means to have a shared
culture and so you can't.
You have to defend that culture and it
has to be of sufficient,
let's say tightness or magnitude so that
it makes sense for you to belong to it.
It's not so diverse and chaotic that it
means nothing and I think that part of
the reason why we're seeing a return to
nationalism in places like Europe is
because
the European identity is so amorphous
that people can't establish a
relationship with it and that's not a
good thing because identity is actually
something you have to have a
relationship with.
And so you know,
it's the identity,
your identity.
It's the identity of you within your
family.
It's the identity of your family within
the small community of friends that
surround you and then the broader
community of the town and a somewhat
broader community of the province and
the state and so forth,
but as it expands,
it gets vague and it disperses and at
some point the identity that's universal
is so all encompassing that it means
nothing at all and leaves people
chaotic,
and so that's what's happening,
at least in part in Europe.
It's happening to some degree in the
United States as well because we've been
pushed so quickly forward into adopting
a global identity that people are
shaking because that's too amorphous for
them.
And so we pulled back and say,
no,
we need to be around people who we
understand.
Which is of course absolutely true.
Now the downside of the nationalist
endeavor is that you also need to be
around people that you aren't alike and
don't understand,
partly because they exist and if you
don't take them into account,
then you're going to have a war with
them.
Which is a very bad idea.
But also because they have something to
offer.
And so we're trying to sort out the
proper balance between differentiated
identity,
say at the nation state level and the
global identity that seems to be
manifesting itself partly because of our
widespread electronic communication.
So,
okay,
nationalism beckons.
If you're in a chaotic state,
you know,
I heard the Gallup people that pollsters
at one point,
I had never seen this made public,
but I remember it very well said that,
uh,
this was back when Quebec was still a
large proportion of the Quebecois
population was still agitating for
separatism.
I'd always looked at that and I thought,
well,
it made perfect sense because you,
if cal Catholicism collapses,
it leaves a void.
What are you going to fill the void
with?
Well,
it's either nihilism,
which we've already discussed or well,
or what.
Well,
nationalism obviously,
and the Gallup people said that if you
are a lapsed Catholic,
you are 10 times more likely to be a
separate.
It's perfect.
It's exactly what you'd expect because
you have to have an identity.
So you turn from church to state.
Well that's fine if you believe that the
state is the ultimate identity.
And that's really this story that is
being sold to people who are sold a
nationalist story.
The state is the ultimate identity.
It's like,
well actually that's technically wrong.
That's why.
That's why it's wrong.
It's not wrong because it's
ideologically wrong or morally wrong.
Precisely it's,
it's wrong because it's technically
wrong.
Because the problem with the state is
the state is what's uniform across
people
and the thing is is that we need what's
actually diverse across people in order
to rejuvenate the state and to keep it
awake.
And so if you reduce individuals to
what's homogenous about them across all
people,
you eradicate the very variability that
allows people to adapt to new things.
And because we're constantly being
presented with new things,
we need to keep that individual
variability
paramount because it's upon that
variability that the very state depends
on.
That's actually what the West
discovered.
That's why we have always subordinated
the state to the divinity of the
individual.
And that's expressed,
as I already said in our,
in our,
in the primacy of free speech in our
civilization.
It's the cornerstone,
the primacy of free speech,
and it's because the individual has
something to offer the state,
and so state identity is something that
can only it constructure and it can
reassure,
but it also constrains to too great a
degree,
and so societies that become only state
immediately become old and blind,
malevolent and collapse,
and that's an ancient story.
The Egyptians had this figured out 3000
years ago in their fundamental
mythologies.
They had a daddy named Cyrus who was
threatened by his evil brothers set who
later became the Christian Satan.
The words are related.
Etymologically and set was like scar in
the lion king.
He was waiting in the wings to for the
old king to turn a blind eye so that he
could chop them into pieces and rule in
a malevolent way across the entire
state.
The Egyptians had another day at a
horace who was the son of Cyrus and the
queen of the underworld.
Isis,
who is the eye,
the Egyptian I who was the fall can
because falcons can see,
and horace was different than,
oh cyrus,
because he could see what set was up to.
He grew up outside the kingdom like King
Arthur and came back and try and find,
overcame,
set,
losing an eye in the process
you overcame as evil uncle and banished
him to the corners of the world and then
he took his eyes,
went into the underworld where his
father,
oh,
cyrus was living a life of a of a dead
ghosts.
That's one way of thinking about it and
he gave him his eye and that revivify to
cyrus,
Cyrus and horus went back up to the
surface from the chaotic underworld and
their union was the symbol of what the
Pharaoh had to manifest in order to rule
Egypt properly.
The Egyptians figured that out 3000
years ago in their.
In their great story,
but it's very difficult to make
something like that and articulated
reality,
but that's the relationship that has to
obtain between the individual and the
state.
The state is a corpse.
The state is dead,
but it's a gift that the dead have given
to you and you have to provide it with
vision and with speech because otherwise
it can only blunder around like a
Zombie.
You go to university,
you become educated so that you can
serve as the eye and the mouth of the
rejuvenated state.
That's the purpose of developing.
Say had an education in the humanities
when there was still such a thing left,
but that's the purpose of that education
is to turn you into the thing that
ensures that the entire ship doesn't
founder in sync and that's your
responsibility and if you're looking for
a meaning in your life,
that's the meaning.
Keep the state afloat.
Why?
Well,
because it's better for us all to be in
a ship than drowning in the icy water,
and that's the alternative.
No one if you're.
If you find that the tragedy of life is
too much for you to bear without
becoming resentful and bitter and
murderous and even genocidal,
it means that you haven't picked up
enough responsibility because if you
picked up enough responsibility for the
rejuvenation of the state and the
eradication of unnecessary suffering,
you find enough meaning in that so the
idea of meaninglessness would vanish in
an instant.
You'd have more meaning than you knew
what to do with and that's a terrifying
thing as well,
but to fight off one terrifying thing,
the specter of mortality and insanity
and finitude and death,
you need another monster of equivalent
size and that's one that you can find
and it's one that you can bear up and
it's one that you can live and that's
what we need to do because if we don't
do that,
then all hell breaks loose really,
really eternally.
That's what those stories mean.
Viewed in this light.
You can understand postmodernism because
postmodernism managers has a response.
It's a response to the NIETZSCHEAN
dilemma,
right?
The cornerstone of civilization has been
demolished by rational critique and no
wonder it needed to be criticized,
but it needed to be more deeply
understood and criticism and deep
understanding are the same thing unless
the criticism is only destruction
because if you criticize something,
what you're doing is separating the
wheat from the chaff.
You're not burning all of it.
You're saying,
well,
not this,
but definitely this.
Definitely this,
and that's what education should provide
you with the opportunity to do as well.
What should we conserve and what should
we dispense,
what we can serve,
what centrally true,
and now we need to understand it.
We have to conserve the idea that the
individual has an infinite
responsibility to the direction of being
and we know that you know perfectly
well,
that you live in a relationship with
your own conscience and when you violate
the moral order,
that's part and parcel of your soul.
You're ashamed and hide and bitter,
and then you get angry.
You can't show your face to other
people.
You can't even look at yourself in the
mirror and you know perfectly well.
That's true.
Even though you may not know what to do
about it or how to get out of it,
it's there's a moral order built into
human beings.
If there wasn't,
there was no way we could even
communicate with one another because
there'd be no rules of communication.
There'd be nothing that we mutually
wanted or expected from each other.
You know,
one of the things I figured out is that
we're all appalled when we run into
another person who is not yet the
redeemer.
Every person you ever meet your you're
dissatisfied with because they're not
who they could be,
and you're broadcasting that message at
everyone all the time.
You're not who you could be.
I'm not who I could be and we're all
facing each other with our emotional
displays,
pleading with each other to become that
which we could become
and everyone knows it,
but we won't do it,
and it's no wonder
the postmodernists,
they're the.
They're the logical conclusion of the
Nietzschean dilemma.
God is dead value.
The value structure collapsed.
The specter of rises of all value
structures collapsing.
That's the postmodernists dogma.
All value structures have collapsed.
They're only there for the purposes of
exclusion.
They have no intrinsic value.
It's a very,
very powerful argument.
That's why it dominates the
universities.
That and the fact that it allows people
to dispense with their moral
responsibility,
which is something that's never
discussed by the postmodernist,
but you have to give the devil his due.
What's the problem with postmodernism?
Well,
if all value structures have collapsed,
then there's nothing to do because in
order to do something,
one thing has to be better than another
because otherwise why do it and so
people who are ensconced in the
postmodern tradition are undermined by
their own philosophy.
They can deconstruct their own
deconstruction,
in which case they might as well just
sit there and do nothing which would
actually be preferable to what they're
doing now.
So how do they extract themselves from
that dilemma?
They do ideologically,
but they don't care because the
postmodernists first of all,
don't believe in logic.
That's a reflection of the logos they've
dispensed with dialogue.
They don't believe that because that's a
reflection of the logos which they've
dispensed with logic and dialogue are
irrelevant.
Well,
that does bring up the problem of what
to do.
Well,
there's postmodernist finesse that by
reverting to the Marxist doctrines from
which postmodernism emerged,
and so they say,
well,
yeah,
you can't get any direction from
postmodernism,
but we don't.
We're not going to worry about that
because we don't worry about such
things.
What we'll do is just use slight of hand
to push forward the communitarian
doctrines out of which our original
hypothesis emerged and everyone says,
well,
we'll turn a blind eye to the paradox
because we actually need something to do
and plus to the degree that we're
communitarian,
we can take out our nihilistic
resentment and arrogance and in
gratitude on every single person we
deemed to have something more than we
have.
And so if you're wondering why certain
values can exist in the absence of any
value,
you have to look no farther than to
understand that people who are desperate
and chaotic will still be angry and
destructive and they can manifest that
perfectly with the moral mask that says,
well,
I'm not really after what you have
because you have a little more than me.
I'm speaking on behalf of these people
who have even less.
It's like it's absolute nonsense.
It's so funny watching Yale students
complain about the privileged.
They're in the top,
one 10th of 100th of a percent of people
who've lived in in the entire history of
the planet,
much less just the people that are on
the planet.
Now they're dominating patriarchs in
training,
right there,
baby representatives of the Patriarchy
and all they do is complain about that
tiny,
infinitesimal fraction of people who
have slightly more than they have now.
It's appalling and their idiot
professors pat them on the back and send
them out the world to do that.
Instead of teaching them how to live,
they damaged their mental health.
They they,
they heard our society,
they're bringing things down and that's
what they're aiming at.
The postmodernist managed to be
nihilistic and totalitarian at the same
time,
which is something that not even need
should dreamed about despite the fact
that he had the greatest imagination for
pathology that perhaps ever existed.
In addition,
they combine the nihilism and
totalitarianism with the worst aspects
of dogmatic religion because what
they've essentially established is a
cult into which children who attend
university are now indoctrinated at
great cost,
I might add and with very little
practical outcome,
what's the alternative given that they
have a point as far as I can tell,
the alternative is a proper return to
the past,
and that is precisely to journey into
the chaos,
to look at the worst possible thing and
to pull the dead father up from the
chaotic depths.
That's how you stop being a puppet.
Someone whose strings are being pulled
by forces they do not understand behind
the scenes,
you find out what's great about your
culture is thing that's provided us with
everything that we see in this room,
this amazing warmth that we're
experiencing when it's 30 bloody below
outside the fact that the electricity or
the heart and the computational
resources are working in that we can all
sit here peacefully and then no one is
hungry.
Fact,
we're too fat.
That's our big problem.
Oh No,
we have so much stuff.
We're getting fat.
Yeah,
well that's a good problem to have.
We should have some gratitude for what's
being produced that's brought us to this
point and we need to wake up and
understand what we're doing.
Well,
that's what.
That's what people like.
That's what the psychoanalysts were
trying to do in the 20th century.
That's what all the great clinicians
we're trying to do and I would say above
all else that was what Carl young was
trying to do.
He believed firmly that the idea of the
divine spark within the individual was
a,
was a metaphysical reality by which he
meant a reality that actually
transcended and existed super to the
physical reality of more real reality.
That's whatever consciousness is
something we understand from a
scientific perspective,
not at all that's been represented in
our mythologies as far back as we can
push them as an independent agent in the
world,
giving rise to form.
That's how we treat each other.
That's how we recognize ourselves.
That's how we judge each other.
You make your bed and then you lie in it
and everyone knows it,
and that's not to say that you're not
subject to random and chaotic
circumstances and the tragedy of life.
Just because you can do some things
doesn't mean you can do everything,
but you can do some things and if you
don't do them,
then things fall apart and the problem
with things falling apart is that you
will be happy about it to the degree
that you're not trying to repair them
because to the degree that you do not
manifest what's within you,
then your life falls apart around you
and everything that could make you
bitter multiplies until you're in a
situation where you want the
destruction.
You want to bring it on,
and it's not surprising
because life can be so terrible that the
question of whether or not it should
exist at all can be a real question.
But the answer to that is his life so
terrible that it shouldn't exist.
Well,
the answer is it depends on how you live
it and if your life is so terrible that
you can't bear it,
then it raises the question of whether
or not you're living it properly,
and that's not to say that people don't
suffer under burdens that are too great
for them to bear.
They certainly do.
It doesn't matter because if you let
that embitter you,
if you let that destroy your allegiance
to the proper path,
all it does is make that worse and
everything else.
It's no out.
So what did I learn from studying
from studying the terrible situation
that obtained in the mid 19 eighties
when the Soviets and the West had tens
of thousands of hydrogen bombs pointed
at each other,
ready to go at a moment's notice.
Why did that happen?
What did I learn?
It was simple.
The reason that that situation existed
was because I was not good enough.
I was not good enough.
The reason that the terrible situations
in the world exists now is because
you're not good enough.
You're not good enough,
We could solve any problem.
We can solve any problem.
If we used all the resources that were
available to us,
if we live properly,
we have no idea what we could turn,
what were in into,
so I would say
you support free speech because it's the
mechanism that maintains the sanity of
the individual and society and you live
in relationship with the spoken truth to
the best of your ability because the
alternative is hell,
and if hell is what you want,
then you can remain arrogant and
resentful and deceitful,
but if you want to work to better the
world to bring it up to what it might
be,
then you speak forthrightly.
You clarify yourself and you act
properly in the world and then you see
what happens,
and this is the final thing I'll say,
I spent a long time studying the sermon
on the mount.
It's a key document.
It's Christ's commentary on the Ten
Commandments.
In a sense,
the question being,
if you codify the rules by which a
society might function,
is there something within the structure
of the rules that rises above them that
acts as the fundamental principle from
which they're all derived?
It's the ultimate question of human
ethics.
What is the highest principle and the
answer that's put forth in the sermon on
the mount is quite straightforward.
Aim at the highest possible good that
you can conceive of whatever that is
that you can conceive of that serves as
your God.
For all intents and purposes,
having aligned yourself with that good,
speak the truth and see what happens.
That's the act of faith.
The act of faith is whatever the truth
reveals is the best of all possible
worlds.
Regardless of how it appears to you.
Now it's a guess,
right?
It's a.
it's something you stake a bat on.
Well,
what do you think the best of all
possible worlds will be brought into?
Being by deceit,
it seems unlikely.
You know that doesn't work in your own
life.
You Tangle yourself up in your own lies,
right?
One lie breeds Tandon.
10 breeds a hundred and maybe you put
the consequences on down the road and
you don't fall into the pit for five or
six years.
Maybe you've even forgotten why you fell
in when you finally do fall in,
but everyone knows that.
Everyone knows that you don't get away
with anything and so the issue is,
well,
what would happen if you just said what
you thought stupid as it is,
inaccurate as it is,
and listen to people criticize you in
response to shape you and make you more
articulate.
What would your life be like and
answered?
That is,
and I know this to be true,
I've worked with many,
many people on precisely this problem.
Your life gets better and better and
better and richer and deeper,
but that comes with a heavier and
heavier burden of responsibility.
Well,
that's okay.
You use the observation of your own
capability to bear responsibility to
buttress yourself against the terrorists
of being finite.
You say,
we can miserable as I am.
I can still stand up to the terrible
tragedy of life and prevail and that's
good enough.
Thank thanks.