Okay,
well we're going to continue our
discussion of the big five traits today
and I'm going to talk to you about
openness and intelligence,
roughly speaking.
So the first thing I want to do is put
them into context.
You need to understand where
intelligence fits in the in the trade
hierarchy structure and so we've,
we've looked at this before,
but you can break the big five into the
big to plasticity and stability.
We'll start with stability here and
stable people are conscientious,
high and stress tolerance or emotional
stability or low in neuroticism,
depending on how you look at it and high
in agreeableness.
Then conscientiousness breaks down into
industriousness and orderliness.
Neuroticism breaks down into volatility
and withdrawal and agreeableness breaks
down into politeness and compassion.
And then for the second major trait,
you have the big two trait.
You have plasticity and plasticity is
made up of extraversion and openness and
those look like the reason they clumped
together.
The reason the first three clump
together we think is because they're
roughly associated with serotonergic
function.
Um,
and the reason the latter two clump
together is because they're roughly
associated with dopaminergic function.
And the dopamine system mediates
exploratory behavior in the face of the
unknown,
but it also mediates positive emotion.
And,
and it's because in order to move
forward into the unknown,
it isn't that you have to experience
positive emotion.
It's that the emotion you experience
when you're motivated to move forward
into the unknown and explore is a
positive emotion and positive emotion is
very much also associated with
interaction in the social environment.
And maybe that's because a tremendous
amount of what you're doing in the
social environment is essentially
exploratory behavior,
right?
Because for example,
when you're communicating with people
that's primarily exploratory behavior,
um,
so it's not surprising that the
circuitry overlaps and in that manner,
um,
openness is the one we're going to
concentrate on most particularly today.
And it is openness to experience
technically and it seems to break down
into intellect and openness proper,
which is,
it's in its intellect,
which is interested in ideas,
maybe facility with ideas and to
openness,
which is more like creativity.
That's,
that's now.
You can't divide them into interest in
ideas and creativity.
So precisely because they,
they overlapped to a,
to a great degree.
But there is,
there is reason for differentiating
between them.
So for example,
women are about a third of a standard
deviation higher than men in openness
slash creativity and men are about a
third of a standard deviation higher
than women in interest in ideas and
intellect.
And that's actually quite a substantial
difference within a trait.
That's when the two traits are so highly
correlated.
So there's reason to do the,
to do the fractionation.
So anyways,
so we're going to concentrate on
openness today and the reason that I'm
presenting the trait description first
rather than moving immediately into say
Iq and creativity is because it's
reasonable to.
It's useful to know that you can take
intelligence and put it in the big five
taxonomy and you can actually measure
intelligence a lot more accurately with
an Iq test and perhaps also with a
creativity test than you can with the
self report.
Personality tests that relies on
adjectives,
you know,
because I could ask you guys how smart
are you on a scale of one to seven?
And that would be roughly correlated
with your Iq.
But if I really wanted to know how smart
you were,
roughly speaking,
it would be much better to give you an
Iq test and if I was wanting to know how
creative you are rather than asking you
how creative you are and getting you to
report,
even though there would be some accuracy
in that,
it would be better actually to give you
some of the different tests of
creativity that we'll talk about today.
Now,
the weird thing about the big five are
one of the weird things about it is that
we don't have great tests for the traits
independently of self report for almost
all of the traits.
So for example,
one of the things that I've been trying
to do in my lab for the last five years
is to find some sort of laboratory task
that conscientious people do better on
or unconscientious people do worse on.
And you'd think that would be simple
because conscientiousness,
for example,
is a very good predictor of longterm
life success.
Success.
It's also a very good predictor of
university grades.
It's not as good as Iq,
but it's still a good predictor.
But we have had one insanely difficult
time trying to find a non self report
test that associate that,
that,
that actually predicts
conscientiousness.
So much appreciated.
Yes.
No,
it's neuroticism.
Neuroticism is associated with being
more self aware and it's actually,
it loads on negative emotions,
so being self conscious as associated
with being high in negative emotion.
I mean you can assess neuroticism using
tests that that asks you about anxiety
and emotional pain or depression,
but that's also not much different than
than than self report.
Anyways,
we're gonna concentrate on openness
today and we're going to concentrate
both on creativity and intelligence and
there's actually almost nothing in
psychology that's more contentious
generally speaking.
Then the investigations into the,
the technical or the what,
the set of skills and abilities that
falls under trade,
openness.
And the reason for that,
and this is especially the case with
intelligence,
is that intelligence is actually quite
measurable.
We've been able to measure it since
roughly the beginning of the,
of the,
of the 20th century.
Been a originated the first,
I would say reliable and valid Iq tests
and they've been used quite extensively
for a long period of time and ICU.
I'll tell you what Iq is as we go
through this,
but there isn't anything that social
scientists have been able to measure
more successfully than Iq and there's
nothing that social or very little one.
There's one exception.
The relationship between income
inequality and male homicide is a power
more powerful relationship than the
relationship between Iq,
say in general life success or Icu and
general school success.
It's.
It's even a little stronger than the
relationship between Iq and the rate at
which you learn something new,
but other than that,
it's pretty slim pickings and so we're
gonna walk through very carefully how Iq
his Iq tests are created and formulated
and exactly what it is that they measure
and why and will equate that to some
degree to creativity and also
differentiated from creativity as well.
Making the assumption that the aspects
of openness,
intellect,
and openness proper are the proper
aspects and that they're usefully
differentiated.
So the first thing that you might want
to consider is that the world is a very
complicated place.
Now we've talked about this before and
the way that you handled this way too
much complexity for you to handle in its
in its entirety.
So for example,
in a room like this,
there's an endless number of phenomena
that you could focus your attention on
right from the sort of macro phenomenon
which would be the overall say,
color or appearance of the room to the
micro phenomena,
which would be the details at the
highest level of detail that you're able
to perceive that litter the landscape
anywhere.
And so one of the problems that you have
to solve when you're operating in the
world is how you perceive the world.
And we do that in part by making,
I would say that we perceive low
resolution representations of the world
and we also confuse those with the
world.
So when I'm looking at you,
I'm really looking at a low represent
what I perceived consciously as a low
representation,
low resolution representations of you.
Right?
I only see the front of you to begin
with.
I only see your surface and in some
sense,
you know,
I even perceive you in some sense as a
more or less uniform color.
It's hard to tell exactly what color his
skin is.
It's sort of a light pink,
roughly speaking,
but my,
my perception is fairly is fairly.
I don't know a better way of putting it
than low resolution and I seem to
perceive you at the level of resolution
that's sufficient,
the the lowest resolution.
That's sufficient to facilitate our
interactions because I don't want to
clutter up my perceptions of you when
we're just talking with excess details,
so there's lots of things about you I
don't need to see.
I certainly can't see any of your micro
below the below the phenomenal level
like I can't tell without tremendous
further investigation what you're made
of biologically.
For example,
and I certainly can't perceive the
networks of society that you're engaged
in your family or the other sorts of
networks that you're embedded in.
I see you here now,
the front of you at low resolution and
you can tell that to some degree,
and we've talked about this before
because if you see say animated movies
that use very low resolution
representations of people like South
Park's a really good example because the
imitate or the animation in South Park's
very iconic and and and simple.
It actually makes almost no difference
to following the story and so that shows
you how iconic your perception really
is,
can be replaced by very simple icons and
you instantly adapt to that,
you know,
and so we can go and see the lego movie
Batman Lego movie for example,
and the fact that it's Batman,
which is an abstraction to begin with
and then it's made out of Legos is
almost irrelevant to following the plot.
So some people have compared our
perceptions to the user interface on a
computer.
You know when you're interacting with
your computer,
you don't really interact,
so to speak with the computer.
There are iconic representations on the
screen of the computer that you interact
with and those represent,
obviously they share some functional
relationship with what's going on in the
computer,
but mostly they're there so that you
using your perceptual structures can
interact with the computer in a manner
that's easy for extremely intelligent
apes,
roughly speaking now,
so one of the problems that you have to
solve in the world because it's so full
of detail and so complex is how do you
actually see the world?
How do you actually perceive it,
and it isn't really self evident that
that's a problem because you think when
you look at the world that it just
presents itself to you,
but it's a tremendously complicated
problem and that's partly why developing
artificial intelligence systems that can
actually see the world and act in it in
any real way has proved to be a much
more difficult problem than people had
originally suppose.
Because you know,
we were told maybe from the early
sixties onwards that such things as
speech to text or object recognition,
recognition or robots that could operate
in the world.
We're only two or three years away and
well,
I mean we're in.
We're in a situation now where there are
some fairly complicated robots built,
but they're still really in their
nascent form and it's because perceiving
the world and then figuring out how to
act and it turns out to be a much more
complicated problem than we originally
thought because the borders between
things are not self evident and what
level of resolution you should be
perceiving things at for say maximal
functional utility is also not self
evident.
It's also tied up very strangely and in
ways we don't understand with the nature
of your embodiment,
you know.
So for example,
we tend to see things that are handy
because we can pick them up and
manipulate them and we can make use of
them.
And so to some degree our brains are
evolved to make the world manifest
itself to us in a set of discrete,
usable tools.
That's,
that's a reasonable way of thinking
about it.
And there are discrete and usable
because we have a certain kind of
biological platform,
you know,
because we have hands and mouths and
because we walk in a bipedal manner,
then it's logical for us to break up the
world in a manner that makes operating
in this body maximally useful.
But that doesn't mean that there's a
straightforward one to one relationship
between our perceptions of things and
the things themselves.
Quite the contrary.
And that's partly,
of course we know that because with any
perceptible object,
like I could conceptualize you as one
thing for all sorts of purposes.
But if I'm trying to solve a complex
problem in relationship to you,
it's going to be very difficult to
determine how to conceptualize you.
So if I'm,
if you come to me because you're
suffering from a psychological problem
of some sort,
then I have to figure out,
you know,
is it organic?
Is it,
is there's actually something
physiological wrong with you and I need
to know what level of analysis I would
probably conceptualize you out.
Is it psychological?
Is it.
And if it's psychological,
is it functional?
Like do you lack the skills or do you
lack the ability to apply the skills or
is there something really going wrong
with your family,
or maybe it's even a reflection of an
overarching sociological problem.
We know,
for example,
that when the unemployment rate goes up
one percent,
psychiatric hospitalizations go up five
percent,
and so then you might ask,
well,
you know,
if you're.
If there's a huge rise in depression and
anxiety across the population and at the
same time there's a huge increase in
unemployment.
You have to ask yourself what level of
perception would best be suited to solve
that problem because it isn't self
evident that it's psychological at the
level of the individual.
Anyways.
My point is is that perception is a very
difficult problem and so now here's.
Here's something interesting.
You can think about this for a minute.
I went and saw an autistic woman speak
at one point.
Her name was temple grandin.
She's really worth looking up.
Temple Grandin is a very interesting
person.
She's very seriously autistic when she
was a child,
but her mother and her worked her out of
it so that she could be,
she's very functional.
She works as a professor,
I don't remember where it's in the
midwest somewhere now.
She's famous,
not only be for being a highly
functional autistic person who talks a
fair bit about what it's like to be
autistic,
but also for designing slaughterhouses
across the United States.
And the reason she can do that as far as
she's concerned is because she thinks
she thinks like an animal thinks.
And so she doesn't.
And she's identified maybe at least part
of what the core problem is with autism.
So she talk,
I heard her at was in Arizona and it
was,
uh,
was a really,
entrancing talk she sewed,
she showed some really interesting
pictures of animals.
So what she's done is she's redesigned
slaughter houses so that when the
animals enter the slaughterhouse,
they go into like a spiral.
Basically.
They can't see what's around the corner
and the walls are high,
so they're not distracted by anything
outside.
So one of the things she showed,
for example,
was a bunch of cows going through a
standard sequence of of gates
essentially and off to the side there
was a windmill spinning and the cows
would stop because the windmill,
they didn't understand what the windmill
was and they'd stop or showed other
pictures where cows were going down a
pathway to and there was a coke can
sitting in the middle of the pathway and
the cows would all stop because they
didn't know what to do with it or she
had another picture of cows out in the
middle of the field all surrounding a
briefcase and they are all looking at
the briefcase and the cows didn't like
anything that shouldn't be there and had
a hard time mapping it.
Now she said,
here,
here's a little exercise she did.
She said,
think of a church.
Okay,
so maybe you think you imagine a child's
drawing of a church.
It's like your standard house,
like a pen tag Pentagon,
right.
Which is basically how children draw the
front of a house with a steeple on top
and maybe a cross on top of it or
something like that,
which actually isn't at church.
It's an icon of a church.
And you think about how children draw
houses too.
Pentagon,
rectangle.
What is a trapezoid chimney?
Almost always with smoke,
which is quite interesting.
It's.
I don't know where kids get that
exactly,
but they almost always draw a chimney
with smoke even though chimneys with
smoke aren't that common anymore.
But anyways,
you know,
you can see what a child's picture of a
house looks like in your imagination.
One of the things that you might want to
think about is that is not a picture of
a house at all,
right?
It's an iconic representation that's
Kinda like a hero cliff because no house
looks like that.
And then you think about how a child
will draw a person circle,
stick,
stick.
And you show it to somebody to go,
that's a person.
It's like,
really?
It looks nothing like a person,
right?
I mean you.
You immediately recognize it as a
person,
but it looks nothing like a person.
Well,
what grand and said was that when she
thinks of a church,
she has to think of a church.
She's seen.
She can't take the set of all churches
in abstract out an iconic representation
and use that to represent the set of all
churches.
She has.
She gets fixated on a specific exemplar
and she thinks that one of the problems
with autistic people and they have a
very difficult time developing language
by the way,
is that they can't abstract out a
generalized representation across a set
of entities.
They can't abstract and then they end
well and of course if you can abstract
and it's also very difficult to
manipulate the abstractions and you see
very strange behavior with autistic
children for example.
So they don't like people and that's
because people don't stay in their
perceptual boxes like a human being is a
very difficult thing to perceive because
we're always shifting around and moving
and doing different things.
Like we don't stay in our categorical
box.
Autistic people have real trouble with
other people,
but they also have trouble,
so for example,
if you're autistic,
child gets accustomed to your kitchen,
let's say,
and you move a chair,
then it especially if they're severely
autistic,
they'll have an absolute fit about it
because you think kitchen with chair
moved,
they think completely different place
because they can't abstract the
constancy is across the different
situations and represent them
abstractly.
So I made this little diagram.
I made this little diagram here to kind
of give you a sense of what you might be
doing when you're abstracting
perceptually and so you could say think
about something that's that complicated.
It's sort of my model of how complex the
world is,
but the world is a lot more complex than
that,
but the world is made out of everything
is made out of littler things and those
littler things are made out of littler
things and so forth and those things are
nested inside.
Bigger things and so forth.
And where you perceive on that level of
abstraction is somewhat arbitrary.
It has to be bounded by your,
by your goals.
That's the other thing is that your
perceptual structures are determined by
the goals that you have at hand.
I mean some of that,
that's not completely true because your
perceptual systems also have
limitations,
right?
There's things you can't see or hear
even if you need to.
So there are limitations built in,
but within that set of limitations,
you're still trying to tune your
perceptions to your motivated goals and
that's also very useful to think about
when you're trying to understand
artificial intelligence because for
human beings,
without goals,
there's no perception because there's no
filtering mechanism that you can use to
determine the level of resolution at
which you perceive.
Anyway.
So there's the,
there's a thing made of smaller things
which are made out of smaller things and
it's so.
It's kind of my iconic representation of
the complexity of the world and then you
could think,
well,
what is this?
How can you see this object?
And I think if you just look at it,
you can detect.
So like a necker cube,
you know those cubes that are line
drawings that you can see the front of
it.
Then it'll flip to the back.
Have you seen those?
So this is kind of necker cube like or
at least it is for me in that when I
look at it,
my perceptions play around with it.
Sometimes I focus on the kind of cross
like shape in the metal and sometimes I
can see these other lines and then
sometimes I'll focus on that square and
sometimes I can see the little dots
there are maybe one daughter and my
perceptions are going like this,
trying to fit a pattern to it and you
can kind of detect that when you're
watching it.
And so I would say,
well you have the options of perceiving
this in its full complexity or you can
simplify it essentially.
There's lots of ways you can simplify
it,
but some of them are laid out there.
So you take the complex complex thing,
you make a low resolution representation
of it,
so that's rough.
That's the rough area that all those
dots occupy,
that's the rough area broken down to its
most fundamental quadrants.
That might be how you would look at it
if,
if this was a map of an orchard and you
were trying to walk from south to north,
that would be a useful representation.
This,
this and this.
That's the.
That's the highest level of resolution
that you can perceive this object at.
That's lower resolution than the object
itself.
So the first issue is how should you
look at things?
Well,
that's a problem that intelligence has
to solve.
So that's one of the problems that
intelligence goes after.
And then I think what happens is we have
the thing in itself and then we simplify
it with a perception and that's an
iconic representation.
And then we nail the iconic
representation with a word and that's
how we compress the world's complexity
into something that we can manage.
We take the complex thing,
make it into an icon and represent the
icon with a word.
And then when I throw you the word,
so to speak,
you decompose it into the icon and then
decompose it even further into the
thing.
If you can't,
if you know the icon and you know the
thing.
And so then we can use shorthand,
right,
because you have representational
structures of Soda,
why?
And I'm just tossing you markers about
your representational structures and you
can unfold them and that's what you do
when you're reading a novel because the
novel comes alive in your imagination,
in your own idiosyncratic way,
and it wouldn't if you didn't understand
the references of the novel,
right?
The novelist has to assume that your
basic perceptual structures and your
intuitions and your instincts are
basically the same as his or hers
because otherwise they have to assume
that because otherwise they would be
lost in an infinite regress of
explanation.
So it's problematic.
Often.
For example,
if you start reading Victoria novels,
you may find that it takes awhile to get
into them because the presuppositions,
the expectations are slightly different
and so is the language.
You have to update the representations,
but anyway,
so that's roughly as far as I'm
concerned,
that's roughly a representation of what
intelligence is doing in the world.
It's a big part of it.
It's how in the world do you look at
things so that you can use them for the
purposes that you need to use them for,
and then the next problem that
intelligence has to solve,
which is related,
is once you've got the perceptual
landscape sorted out,
how do you abstractly represent the
action patterns that you're going to
implement in the world?
So it's how do you perceive where you
are now,
how do you perceive where you're going
and how do you construct op and then
implement strategies that enable you to
move from where you are to where you're
going.
So it's a continual process of mapping
and movement.
And so it's.
It's,
it's navigation.
That's what we're doing in the world all
the time is navigating through it
because we're mobile creatures.
We're navigating through it attempting
to make the world manifest itself in
accordance with our wishes.
And that's the fundamental problem that
intelligence has to solve and animals
have their perceptions to rely on.
But we have our perceptions and our
ability to abstract from those
perceptions multiple and then to
abstract finally until into language.
So we live in a very abstracted world
and it also means that we can learn the
lesson in one place and generalize it
across many other places,
which is also something that animals
have a hard time doing because they
don't know how to do that perceptual,
initial,
perceptual generalization.
So,
okay,
so then the question might be,
well,
if intelligence has to solve the problem
of how to perceive in and perceive and
navigate within the world towards ends,
towards in order to fulfill,
in order to,
uh,
to make the world manifest what it needs
to manifest so that you can maintain
yourself and stay alive.
What ends is it orienting itself
towards.
And I think that's a good way of
thinking about the traits,
the traits,
the traits motivate the perceptual
frame.
And so you might think that,
well,
extroverted people are after social
success and you can understand why that
would be because social success brings
with it all sorts of rewards.
Social failure brings costs and you
could also understand why that would
frighten you away from it.
And social success also requires the
expenditure of effort and introverted
people seem to be much more conservative
in a sense,
in terms of expanding social,
expending energy socially and I suppose
they're protecting themselves to some
degree against the possibility of social
failure.
We don't really know.
We know more about how extroverts in
some sense,
how and why extroverts orient themselves
the way they do in the world.
We're not so sure about introverts.
What it is that what the,
what the proper landscape is for
introverts.
I can show you a word cloud.
I'll do that at some point that
introverts that were generated from
introverts on facebook and they seem to
be into fantasy and gaming a lot and and
I don't know why that is exactly because
the fantasy element should be more
locally localized in openness.
But the introverted types,
I mean I suppose they're the people that
are on the Big Bang theory roughly
speaking,
you know,
they seem to be the introverted types
and but we don't understand that much
about them and exactly how it is that
they're orienting themselves in the
world.
People are high in neuroticism,
are oriented towards security and
safety,
agreeable people versus disagreeable
people are oriented,
say towards cooperation versus
competition.
Conscientious people are oriented
towards order,
duty,
obligation and implementation and open.
People are oriented towards abstraction
in both idiation,
landy and representation,
and so those are also to some degree,
you might also think about those as
value systems,
right,
because what you value is definitely not
only what you pursue,
that's too narrow a view.
Value is also what you perceive and
pursue and so thinking about these
things as this entire frame of I think
is a much better way of doing it.
We talked about this earlier,
this sort of structure earlier as a
micro personality and I mentioned that
determination of micro personalities by
fundamental underlying biological
systems like defensive aggression and
sexual sexual
desire and hunger and thirst and so
forth.
Those are all systems that can grab your
perceptions,
make you look at the world in a certain
way,
make you pursue something else in a
certain way,
and prime action responses that are in
keeping with all of that.
The traits seem to be something like
higher order agglomerations of those
more fundamental biological motivations.
Although we don't quite understand the
relationship between the underlying
biology and the traits,
we're starting to sort it out so we
know,
for example,
if you look at the function of the
hypothalamus,
the hypothalamus regulates the basic
biological motivations that I just
outlined,
but it's also the place where the
exploratory systems find their ultimate
physiological grounding and openness and
extroversion seemed to be variant
manifestations of the exploratory
impulse and that's grounded in the
Hypothalamus,
so we're starting to be able to put the
traits to sort of nail the traits down
to their underlying biology.
With regards to neuroticism.
Well,
if you're high in neuroticism,
you're more sensitive to anxiety and
that's regulated at least in part by the
hippocampus and generated in part by the
Amygdala.
There's another part of the brain called
the periodic with aqua ductal gray that
seems to be associated with the
experience of pain and pain is quite a
complex phenomena.
Depression is pain like grief is pain,
like social isolation is pain.
Like disappointment is pain,
like there's anxiety components to that
too,
and so neuroticism seems to be something
like threshold for activation in those
negative emotions systems.
So if you're higher in neuroticism,
one unit of uncertainty might produce,
let's say three units of
psychophysiological response.
Whereas if you're lower in neuroticism,
one unit of uncertainty might produce
one unit of psychophysiological
response.
It's hard,
obviously that's a simplified Schemata,
but there's variability because if
something unexpected or threatening
happens to you,
it isn't obvious how upset you should
get one answer,
what might be a brush it off,
it's nothing.
Now.
Their answer might be it's a bloody
catastrophe and often when something
uncertain or threatening occurs,
you don't have enough information at
your disposal to make a full
determination of the potential import of
this circumstance,
especially if it's uncertain.
And so then you have to guess at how
upset you should be and where you are on
the normal distribution with regards to
trait neuroticism.
Say that sort of determines what your
guests on average is going to be.
So you know,
the other with conscientiousness say,
might say,
well how hard should you work?
Well,
that's a really difficult question.
If you're going to die tomorrow and then
you probably shouldn't work very hard
today at all.
So one thing you might say is that the
degree to which you should work hard is
dependent on your assumptions about the
stability of the future.
We actually know this to be true because
if you put people in wildly uncertain
circumstances,
they discount the future,
which is exactly what you should do,
right?
It's only makes sense to store up goods
for future consumption.
If the future is likely to be very
similar to the past and the present.
You need a stable society for that and
conscientiousness only works in a stable
society because all you do otherwise,
if you're piling up goods,
which is kind of what conscientious
people do,
is leaving them there for the criminals
to take or waiting for the next chaotic
upheaval to wipe out everything that
you've stored.
And so even conscientiousness is a kind
of guests,
hardworking people say,
well,
you know,
sacrifice the present for the future.
That's great.
As long as the future is going to be
there and you can predict it.
But if it's not going to be there and
it's unpredictable,
then the right response is take what you
can take right now.
Well,
the getting's good.
Now obviously there are troubles with
that too.
It,
I'm speaking,
you know,
I'm offering rough rules of thumb,
but I'm trying to provide you with some
indication of how and why these
difference in value structures exist
because there are applicable in
different environments.
You know,
sometimes in a dangerous social
environment,
it's not obvious that being an
extroverted person is a good idea
because extroverted people,
they stand out,
especially if they're extroverted and
creative,
right?
Because not only are they noisy and
dominant and assertive,
they're also colorful and flamboyant and
provocative.
Well,
that's great if you're in a society that
rewards that sort of thing.
But if you have,
you know,
if you're ruled by an authoritarian king
who wants absolutely no threat
whatsoever to his stability ever than
dressing in gray and shutting the hell
up is a really good survival tactic.
So the utility of the trait depends on
the structure of the environment that
surrounds it.
And that's why there's variability in
traits.
And so you have to be careful when
you're thinking about it from a strict
scientific perspective to make the
assumption that positioning at any place
on the normal distribution is
preferable,
preferable to positioning anywhere else.
Now,
one exception to that maybe might be icu
because one of the things that you can
see an icu with Iq is that people with
higher Iq seemed to do better,
but that's also only true in complex
societies.
And then there's another problem that
seems to emerge with Iq and I don't know
exactly what to make of this,
but we know that as women's Iq
increases,
the probability that they're going to be
to remain without a mate also increases
because women tend to mate across or up
dominance hierarchies.
And so
if you're a woman with an Iq of 130,
then you've already eliminated about 95
percent of the men.
And that's only using one criteria.
That's just straight intelligence.
And so there also might be limitations
to the,
to the utility of intelligence with
regards to reproduction that we don't
really understand very well yet.
So
anyway,
so you get the point.
So there's these underlying,
I kind of put down to value structures.
They're capitalize on social groups.
That would be an extroverted value
structure,
say maintain order.
That would be a a conscientious
strategy.
Conscientious people are going to want
to maintain order because they don't
want things to shift across time because
if they shift too much across time,
then the things that have been stored up
for the future start to become
increasingly irrelevant.
There's lots of other reasons to
maintain order as well,
but that's one of them.
So all right,
so that your cognitive ability allows
you to do modeling.
Now this is where human beings have have
leapt ahead of their competition.
So an animal animals can think,
but it isn't exactly obvious how they
think.
They think strategically.
I think they think the same way that
children think in some sense when
they're playing with Legos,
when they're not thinking about the
Legos.
You know when they're,
when they're just moving them around.
We know of like if you watch a smart
Predator group like lions go after a
target or watched chimpanzees hunt down
a monkey,
you can see intelligence at work because
hunting behavior is very,
very complicated.
Obviously,
you know,
especially if you're chasing something
intelligent,
but there isn't that level of abstract
representation.
So whereas,
so let's look at this.
So here's,
here's a,
here's a picture of the,
of the human brain with someone facing
this way,
right?
So here's the,
here's the primary motor Cortex,
okay,
so you're using that to voluntarily move
your body.
Okay?
Now,
then I might say to you,
close your eyes and imagine doing
something.
So just close your eyes and imagine
picking up the cup that's in front of
you and just visualize it.
Okay?
So then you might say,
well,
what part of your brain are you using
then?
And the answer is used part of this
part,
this part because it,
that's where you have your body
represented,
but use this part here,
the premotor cortex to envision
potential auctions.
Now what's happened is that this part of
the brain evolved out of this part and
that makes sense because the first part
is just how you would move,
but the second part is how you would
think about how you would move and then
the next part,
which is this part huge in human beings,
is how you would think about how you
would think about how you would move so
because that enables you to start to do
extraordinary extraordinarily abstract
planning.
So I could say,
well,
envision how you would pick up the cup
and obviously that's something that
you've separated out as a,
as a potential simulation from the
actual action,
but we can talk about extraordinarily
high level abstractions that have
effects across multiple specific domains
way into the future and the more
abstract that your manipulations become,
the more they seem to be moved away,
say from the primary motor cortex out
into the prefrontal cortex.
Hierarchies of abstraction.
And the reason for that as this was Karl
Popper,
this is really,
really were thinking about why.
Think.
Let's say you're an animal and you act
and it doesn't go very well.
Then you die while you've learned that
the acting that way didn't work,
but now your dad,
so that's not that helpful.
Then you might think,
well,
maybe you should represent how you're
going to act so you know here's a box
with the snake in it and your Coffee Cup
is inside the box with the snake in it
and I say to you,
imagine picking up the Coffee Cup and
you imagine it and you think,
oh,
I'll pick up that coffee cup and then
the snake will bite me and old die,
and so then you do.
You decide that implementing the
strategy of picking up the Coffee Cup is
probably not a very good idea and so
that stupid idea has to die and not you.
And so popper's idea was that the reason
that we developed the capacity to
abstract was so that our stupid ideas
could die instead of us.
And that's really it.
It's almost impossible to overstate how
brilliant and observation that is
because what me,
what it means is that as a standard
animal,
you would have to produce variance of
yourself,
reproductively to go out into the world
and try their hand at survival and
that's pretty costly because you have to
produce all the biological replications
of you,
so you could only probably manage that
maybe 13 times if you really,
really worked at it and then then the
cost of their failure is extraordinarily
high because they die while you can just
sit there and produced like 20 different
versions of you stay extending out over
the next week or the next month and you
can run them through a simulation and
kill off all the ones that you don't
regard as suitable and then only
implement the successful ones.
Now you know,
you could debate about how accurate you
might be at doing that because it would
depend on your knowledge,
but we do know that intelligent people
tend to do better across the course of
their life.
And so it does seem that there is some
utility with regards to survival or at
least with regards to positioning in the
dominance hierarchy,
which is somewhat of a proxy for
survival and for reproductive success.
There's some association between that
and the ability to abstract.
So we could say that part of the reason
that people got smarter was because
smarter people were more likely to stay
alive.
Now,
I think it's more complicated than that
too,
because I believe that human males and
females are in an evolutionary cognitive
arms race,
roughly speaking.
And so as men get trickier,
women get trickier to understand them.
And then as women get trickier to
understand,
men get trickier to understand them.
And so we'd been chasing each other
around this cortical expansion loop
pretty much since we parted ways with
our common,
with the ancestor that we had in common
with chimpanzees.
And so that's roughly about 7 million
years ago.
We've undergone a tremendous cortical
expansion since then and there's lots of
reasons that have been propelling that.
So.
So what do you have to do with when
you're thinking while you have to figure
out where you are and how to see that
you have to figure out where you're
going and what that should be,
and then you have to era.
You have to
generate and represent appropriate
auction strategies and simulate those in
time and space.
And then one of the things that's worth
noting is that what you do when you read
a story or when you tell a story,
and so part of the reason that you like
to read stories is because that's
exactly what story stories are telling
you.
How someone is going about doing that.
And so then you can see how if you think
about preference for fiction,
which is actually part of openness,
preference for fiction,
that utility in fiction is that allows
you to experience a plethora of
simulated worlds and to embody the
consequences in abstraction without
having to go through the trouble of
doing that for yourself.
And we do know there's good empirical
literature now showing some of it done
by x students from my lab showing that
reading fiction does improve your
interpersonal intelligence,
for example,
your ability to understand the position
of other people logically enough because
that's what you're doing when you're
reading.
So okay,
so I'm trying to give you some
background so that you can understand
what it means to abstract and also why
it's useful because we need that in
order to move forward with the idea of
intelligence.
So here we go.
Okay.
So that's how you act voluntarily and
then that's how you represent how you
act voluntarily.
And then that's how you think about how
you represent acting voluntarily.
And the reason I'm telling you this is
because it's useful to think about
intelligence as abstract action because
we tend to think about intelligence as
abstract representation,
right?
Intelligence is the manipulation of
facts or the understanding of facts,
but if you look at it neurologically,
I would say that's a miss apprehension
because of the part of the brain that
does the highest level of abstract
thinking is actually something that's
emerged from the motor cortex.
Now you can.
That doesn't mean you don't use your
intelligence to represent you do,
but the purpose of intelligence is to
represent potential action patterns and
we're embodied creatures and we need to
move in the world,
and so that's the proper as far as I'm
concerned.
That's the proper way to conceptualize
intelligence.
So,
and here's a.
here's a study I'll read you.
This study imagery and the premotor
cortex.
Well,
studies on healthy subjects have shown a
partial overlap between the motor
execution and motor imagery.
Neural circuits.
Few have investigated brain activity
during motor imagery in stroke patients
with Hemiparesis,
so a partial overlap between the motor
execution and motor imagery neural
circuits.
Well,
here's an interesting side consequences
of that.
So let's say I'm thirsty and I look at
that glass of water and part of what
happens when I look at the glass of
water is that my eyes activate this
directly.
So you know I've already talked to you
to some degree about how your eyes work,
right?
There's patterns,
they're out there in the world,
the patterns are mapped onto the retina,
so it's a pattern display
matrix,
and then that pattern is propagated
along the optic nerve and then that
pattern manifests itself in the visual
cortex and then that pattern manifests
itself in the motor cortex and it
manifests itself in bodily movement or
preparation for bodily movement.
Technically you don't need conscious
imagery for that to happen.
Now that's something really useful to
know is that your eyes can activate your
body without you being aware of the
image because you think there's the
world.
I see it.
Then I determine how to act.
It's like yes,
but also no.
There's the world and seeing it prepares
me to act.
Forget about the damn imagery.
So when I look at that Cup,
part of the part of the act of looking
at it is preparing that gesture and
that's especially the case if I also
happened to be thirsty because if I'm
thirsty the cups signifies something
that I can use to quench my thirst,
which makes it a very different thing
than what it is when it's empty or when
I'm not thirsty so I'm not even gonna
use the same part of my brain to
perceive it because it's not the same
thing in relationship to me.
So I look at it and then just just even
just understanding the size of it,
there's not much difference between
understanding the size of it and doing
this.
So let's see how I got that.
So that's pretty good.
So that's my underneath when you will
ask,
well what does it mean to understand
something?
Well that's what it means in so far as
this is a cup because it could be tinder
for lighting a fire for example,
or something to stomp on to make a noise
in so far as it's a cup than
understanding it means pattern.
Mapping it onto exactly this
and if I do that successfully,
then I get a little reward,
a little hint,
a little kick of dopamine and that
dopamine makes me feel a little bit
better,
but it also bathes the neural tissue
that I use to make that perceptual,
that to to to structure that perception
and also to undertake that act and it
makes just a little bit more likely that
I'll see it that way and act that way
and its presence again,
and that's how you learn,
right?
You lay out a perceptual scheme,
it's got a goal.
If the perceptual scheme and its
associated action patterns make the goal
of manifest itself,
then you get a little burst of positive
click.
Then that makes it those little neural
circuits that instantiated that thrive a
little bit and get a little bit more
predominant and that's also why you got
to watch yourself.
If you're taking psychomotor stimulants
like cocaine or alcohol,
even for that matter,
because they produce hyper learning and
so you know,
I'll glance at that and maybe it'll
trigger off a bit of thirst,
but if that was,
if I was a cocaine addict and that was
cocaine paraphernalia and I glanced at,
it was like,
wow,
that thing that I've built in my head
out of repeated know massive hits of
dopamine is going to grab my perceptual
structures and my auctions and bring me.
That'll be that craving,
which is an impulse to move forward
towards it.
You'll feel that instantiated in your
body.
That's the craving.
It's very,
very difficult to get rid of that even
if you're.
If you're a cocaine abuser and you've
gone to a treatment center for several
weeks and got over the worst of the,
at least initial parts of the elearning
not to abuse the second you go back into
your natural environment and take a look
at the cues.
Bang.
Nothing will be right back there.
Directing your action,
and what happens is when one of those
perceptual systems comes up,
you can see this when you're hungry.
It suppresses all the other potential
perceptual systems.
You can see this when you're angry too,
right?
You get angry and you're angry with your
partner and all you can think of is all
the stupid things they've done for the
last 10 years.
You don't even remember that you like
them.
It's like you could remind them.
I know you're mad,
but remember you liked me now.
Well,
not right now.
You know,
so.
So it just shows you how those micro
personalities can dominate and suppress.
That's,
that's what happens because if they
didn't suppress the other micro
personalities,
they wouldn't be able to run themselves
to conclusion.
And then you'd never get what you want.
Okay?
So anyways,
studies have shown a partial overlap
between the motor execution and motor
imagery neural circuits.
So what happens is you see something and
it primes you for the appropriate
action.
Few have investigated brain activity
during motor imagery in stroke patients
with hemiparesis.
Hemiparesis is motor impairment from,
from,
uh,
from the stroke.
This work is aimed at examining
similarities between motor imagery and
execution in a group of stroke patients.
11 patients were asked to perform a
visual motor tracking task by either
physically or mentally tracking a sine
wave forest target using their thumb and
index finger.
So they're doing this
during FMRI scanning results.
Whole brain analysis confirmed shared
neural substrates between motor imagery
and motor execution in bilateral
premotor cortex.
So that's the part that I was talking
about.
I won't tell you about the rest of the
brain in pride.
A lobule.
This is partly associated with body
recognition.
So.
So basically I showed
you that study because it it.
It's one of the studies that lend
credence to what I was just describing
is that imagery is the precursor to
action and that it's associated.
Get the imagery going here and the
action there.
Think about,
think about thanking think act.
That's roughly how it works.
Okay.
Now,
now down to cognitive ability.
Well,
how can you conceptualize intelligence?
this is a major problem because your
initial conceptualization determines in
part the strategies that you're going to
use to investigate intelligence.
And when you say,
when you,
when you pair a sentence down to what is
intelligence,
the sentence is problematic because part
of it is a question about
if and how such a thing might manifest
itself in the world.
So there's a fact out there that are set
of facts that corresponds to
intelligence.
But the other problem is,
well,
what do you mean when you say
intelligence?
And you kind of have to nail that down.
If you're going to have a conversation
about intelligence that doesn't go
entirely astray.
And so you've got to.
You've got a definitional problem as
well as an empirical problem.
And so
there have been,
and this was especially true in the 19
nineties,
people have been studying intelligence
Iq intelligence since the 19 twenties.
And it is a very well established branch
of psychology.
One of the things I have to tell you
about Iq research is that if you don't
buy Iq research,
you might as well throw away all the
rest of psychology.
And the reason for that is that the
psychologists,
first of all,
who developed intelligence testing,
were among the early psychologists who
instantiated the statistical techniques
that all psychologists use to verify and
test all of their hypotheses.
So you ended up throwing the baby out
with the bathwater and the ICU people
have defined intelligence in a more
stringent,
stringent and accurate way than we've
been able to define almost any other
psychological construct.
And so if you toss out the one that's
most well defined,
then you're kind of stuck with the
problem of what are you going to do with
all the ones that you have leftover that
are nowhere near as well defined or as
well measured or as or as a or,
or who's predictive validity as much
less than it has been demonstrated with
much less vigor and clarity anyways.
Despite all that,
people have posited a number of
different intelligences and reasonably
so because there's a.
If you think of intelligence as that
which might move you forward
successfully in the world,
obviously there's a fair number of
phenomena that are associated with
individuals that might fit into that
category.
So we have
people have made these distinctions.
Bob Sternberg,
for example,
is distinguished between practical
versus analytical intelligence and he
kind of thinks of practical as like
street smarts and has attempted to
dissociate that from the kind of
analytical intelligence that that
characterize this more straight Iq
research.
I don't think he's done it successfully
as well at all and since the 19
nineties,
interest in his practical intelligence
has declined precipitously because when
it is matched head to head with standard
Iq intelligence,
the Iq intelligence seats up all the
variability.
What's really happened as far as I can
tell so far is that when we're trying to
predict people's course through life,
Iq does a very good job and then one of
the traits does a very good job as well,
which is conscientiousness,
but it doesn't do as good a job as Iq.
Now,
that partly might be because we can't
measure conscientiousness very well.
We're stuck with self reports or maybe I
could gather peer reports about you or I
could gather your parents reports about
your teachers reports and each of those
seems to pick up a little bit more of
the pattern because you know yourself,
but other people know you differently
than you know yourself and there are
still some accuracy in that.
You can get multiple rater reports of
something like conscientiousness and
that'll up.
It's predictive validity,
but in the final analysis,
the best you seem to be able to deal
with conscientiousness is about a point
four correlation with longterm
performance.
Whereas with Iq in complex jobs,
you can probably get point five and
maybe point six.
Point five is 25 percent of the
variance.
You've got to square it.
Point six is 30 percent,
36 percent of the variance,
and point four is 16 percent of the
variance.
So even at the low end,
let's say high end for conscientiousness
is point four or 16 percent.
Low End for Iq is point five or 25
percent low and estimates of Iq make it
one and a half times more powerful than
the high end estimates of
conscientiousness and I think that's
about right.
You'd think,
why do we even have to debate this
because it's so bloody obvious to me
that intelligence is a major predictor
of life success.
I mean you people.
I've measured the Iq of University of
Toronto people,
you know,
people in this room who have an Iq of
less than 120 are rare.
Well,
why?
Well smart people go to university now.
Is that actually a contentious
statement?
What shouldn't be a contentious
It's self evident.
Universities were actually set up so
that smart people could expand their
abilities.
That's why they were there.
And you're selected on the basis of
assessments that are essentially there
to assess something like intelligence.
Yes,
but that,
that will,
that will.
That is part of the controversy.
Is it reasonable?
And this is a measurement issue and
that's why we're.
That's why I've been instructing you to
some degree in psychometrics because we
actually know how to do this.
We know how to answer that question,
so let's a look at how
at how intelligence has been assessed
and why,
and then you can make up your own mind
anyways.
Here's some of the examples of other
forms of intelligence and so then the
question is,
well,
what does it mean to have a different
form of intelligence?
Would would form a and form b be
completely uncorrelated like
extroversion and neuroticism,
or would they be slightly correlated or
would they be highly correlated and then
you might ask,
well,
how highly correlated did they have to
be before they're the same thing or how
uncorrelated did they have to be before
they're different things and actually
the answer to that comes down to
something like practical utility.
It's like,
imagine I'm trying to figure out how
well you'll do in university and I
measure one thing and it's correlated at
point seven with another thing I measure
about you.
Then I might say,
well,
are those two things the same or
different?
They're pretty highly correlated.
Your high and what it means you're going
to be higher than the other.
Well,
so what is there any utility in
measuring both things and the way you
figured that out actually is you do it
statistically,
so we take the target,
which might be your performance across
university.
Then we say,
well,
can we predict your performance across
university better by using one variable
or two variables?
So we would enter them both into a
regression equation.
All a regression equation does.
It's quite simple,
so you're trying to predict the target
and the regression age regression
equation tells you how well you can
predict that target.
If you know another fact now,
then it gets a little complicated
because that's a correlation.
How well you can predict be with a well.
A regression will say how much you can
predict.
See if you know a and B or a and B and c
and d and e because you can use multiple
predictors and you can weight them.
So it might be two times a plus one
times b equals c,
and that's all a regression equation
does is just multiplication and
addition.
Very,
very straightforward.
And so two variables are sufficiently
different functionally if you can use
both of them simultaneously to predict
something of interest.
So again,
it's a tool like approach.
This is how the psychometricians do.
It is something real well,
it's real.
If you can measure,
measure it,
it,
it helps you predict that that's how
it's defined.
So then you might say,
well,
are are there these multiple
intelligences?
Well,
the first question would be,
well,
what do you mean by are there?
And the answer to that would be,
well,
let's specify the question since we're
going to be scientific about it.
Let's predict how well people do in
university.
We'll start with the assumption that
intelligence,
if intelligence isn't associated with
university success,
then you're probably not talking about
intelligence.
Now you could argue that,
right?
Because you could say,
well,
intelligence has nothing to do with
university success,
but that's a definitional matter.
We'd have to agree to begin with.
Is it reasonable to start with the
presupposition that intelligence and
university success share something in
common?
Well,
I think you have to be daft to,
to deny that initial proposition.
Although you could,
because you could say it was privileged
or socioeconomic status or or or,
or any number of sociological phenomena
and some of those are obviously relevant
social class for example,
because you know,
if you're in a higher social class and
all things being equal,
intelligence included,
if you're in a higher social class,
you're more likely to go to university
then you are if you're in a lower social
class.
So there's other,
there's other factors that are going to
influence whether or not you do well in
university,
but we're going to assume that one of
them might be intelligence.
Well then you would ask,
well,
if you measured social intelligence,
so that's what do they call that?
Social Intelligence.
Now,
emotional intelligence,
which does not exist by the way.
Emotional intelligence,
moral intelligence,
linguistic musical,
logical,
mathematical,
spacial body,
kinesthetic,
interpersonal and intrapersonal.
All different forms of intelligence.
Okay,
so to answer the question of whether
they exist,
what you do first is pick a target
prediction of university performance.
Then you make a measure for each of
them.
Then you test to see if the measure
measured the same thing across multiple
instances within the same person.
That's a reliability tests because what
the hell good is your ruler.
If it stretches when you use it has to
measure the same thing multiple times
and then you would say,
okay,
we'll take all these different
intelligence is measured the way we've
decided to measure them.
The first thing we'll do is see how
highly correlated they are because if
they're complete,
two of them are completely correlated.
Then you have one.
You don't have to because that's
virtually the definition of one.
Instead of two.
You can factor analyze them and see if
you can pull out what's common across
all of them.
That's another thing because then you
might say,
well,
intelligence is what's common across all
the measures of these intelligences.
It's a proposition.
It's not a fact.
You have to decide if you're going to
agree with it,
but that if you were going to do that,
you'd use a factor analysis and you'd
say,
well,
if someone was more likely to be
musical,
if they were also high in linguistic
ability and more likely to be logical
and mathematically inclined,
if they had a high spatial ability,
et Cetera,
then you'd be hypothesizing that there
was one factor behind all of those
manifestations that somehow similar and
maybe there wouldn't be,
and then you take all your measures and
you put them in something like a
multiple regression analysis and you'd
predict your target university
performance and then maybe you'd say,
well,
wait a minute.
Let's not just use university
performance.
Let's use junior high performance,
high school performance,
university performance and job success,
and then let's say that the only things
that predict success across all of those
categories and that are the same,
we're going to define as intelligence.
Well,
that's basically how you end up with Iq.
You could say that Iq is what's common
across all possible sets of of
intelligence tests.
Now people are
going to debate that because you still
have to define what constitutes a test,
but the way the psychometricians have
managed it and have taken care of this
at least to some degree,
is to say,
well,
we're going to.
We're not going to define everything
that we measure as intelligence,
so extroverted people are more socially
fluent.
Are we going to call that intelligence?
No.
We're going to call that personality.
We're going to call that extroversion
and we're going to call stress
tolerance.
You could say,
well,
if you can tolerate more stress,
you're more intelligent.
It's like,
well,
no,
that isn't how we've defined it.
We're going to define that as being
lower in neuroticism.
If you're cooperative,
you're more intelligent.
That's emotional intelligence.
Well,
what you're less intelligent if you're
competitive.
Well,
no.
So we parsed that off to agreeableness,
so then the question might be,
is there anything left of these so
called intelligences?
Once you control for personality and Iq
and the answer is no.
Nothing,
nothing left of them and the people who
keep pushing these ideas keep trying to
push them because they don't like the
idea of real individual differences.
And to me that's just a matter of
sticking your damn head in the sand
because it's obvious here you're going
to have a child,
you want the child to have an Iq of 65
or 145 decide,
okay,
so you're all going to vote.
Okay.
You think any one of you is going to
vote to have a child with an Iq of 65,
that child's going to have a hard time
developing even linguistic ability.
They're never going to learn to read,
right?
They're never going to leave home in all
likelihood.
So which child are you going to pick?
Well,
so do you believe in intelligence or
not?
Well obviously if you have any sense
for every time something statistically
came up in the morning.
Yup.
So all these things just have their
statistical validity and just names.
So then if we're going to assign me to
the doctor,
are we assigning the names based on what
we consider to be reasonable?
Okay,
that's a good question.
So look here.
Here's one thing.
So let's say this is actually what
happened when people develop the big
five.
So I'm going to give a very large number
of people every question,
every a huge set of questions that cover
every element of their personality.
I can think of.
It's agnostic,
right?
What I'm really trying to do is come up
with the biggest possible set of
descriptors that someone could actually
fill out that's eliminated.
I can't give you 10,000 questions as so
maybe I take a set of 10,000 questions
and randomly select a few sets of 100,
right?
Because then I would have represented
the entire set.
Then I give them to a thousand people
agnostically.
Then I do the factor analysis,
Bang five factors come out,
and then the factor analysis tells me
which questions load on each factor in
what the factor analysis is saying.
Here's 20 questions and there's
something about them that's the same.
So then I read the questions and I
think,
wow,
those questions are referring to
something the same.
What is that?
Well then maybe I talked to three
colleagues and we think,
well that's something like band.
We have a name and then we could go see.
Now that we have a measure of
sociability,
we could go associated with other
measures of sociability.
Like we might say,
well,
are people who score high on this
measure,
associate it more likely to go to
parties and the answer would be yes,
because what happens if you take 10,000
questions about personality and randomly
select sets of 100 and give each of them
to a thousand people and do a factor
analysis.
The first factor is extroversion and
it's the.
It's the factor in human personality
that seems to pick up the biggest amount
of variance and so so then we say from a
statistical perspective,
extroversion is real,
but we define real.
Real means that if you use linguistic
representation randomly applied across
large sets of people and you factor
analyze it,
these come out as clumped together
because you have to define what
constitutes real.
If you're going to play that,
this is real game,
which is basically what you're doing in
science,
and so that's what happened with the big
five and then people started to look,
well,
okay,
is there a biological substrate for
this?
Bang,
it turns out there is incentive reward.
That's the positive reward system.
So and then while neuroticism,
that's often but not always the second
factor.
Well,
is there a biological basis for it?
Yes.
Threat sensitivity and pain sensitivity,
they seem to lock together.
Agreeableness,
that's the care system that Jaak
Panksepp has identified.
So that's basically.
That's basically matter analogy.
It's something like that.
You had another question
but
intelligence.
Well,
it's because we found out how to measure
intelligence so and so,
and I'll get into that right now.
So then the question is,
well,
how do you measure intelligence?
Okay,
well it's similar.
It's similar to this linguistic
approach,
but here's how it differs.
Generate 10,000 questions that require
knowledge and you get get 50 people to
do it and have them and have them be of
diverse opinions about what constitutes
knowledge so much the better then you
cover that.
You want to oversample the territory,
so you want to have some quick questions
in there that only one person out of 50
would think that measures intelligence
because you can over sample statistics
will take care of that.
So you want to ask more questions than
you think are reasonable and that's part
of the way that you get rid of bias in
the sampling.
It's like you think goal,
find out 10 questions that someone could
answer.
If you think they're intelligent,
I don't care what they are.
And then 50 of you do that.
Bring me the questions.
Well,
let's say we get a nice set of 10,000
questions and we can take random sets of
100 and give them to a thousand people
and then we can score their answers to
the questions and then we can rank
order,
we could say correlate their performance
across different sets of questions.
So I give you one set of 100 questions.
You scored 90.
I'll give you another set of questions.
You score 90 out of 100,
you score out of 100.
Well then we would think if a bunch of
people did that,
those aren't measuring the same thing
because if you're high on one and you
should be high on all of them.
Well with Iq it's like if you do that,
the reliability is like point nine.
It's unbelievable.
You take one set of 100 questions,
you rank order people,
you take another set of 100 questions.
You rank order people,
you correlate the rank orders.
It's like this is point nine.
The people who did well in one do on all
of them.
The people who did bad on one do bad on
all of them.
That's ICU or more technically,
this is what Iq is.
Take a thousand people and give them 20
tests of 100 items and then factor,
analyze the 20 tests and extract out the
central factor.
That's g,
that's fluid intelligence.
So then what do you do with that?
Well then you can try to use it.
Then you can see,
well is there a biological basis for
this?
Is there something about if you're
higher in the ability to operate across
these sets of questions,
are there things about you that are
physiologically different?
And the answer to that is yes.
Your reaction time is faster,
just simple reaction time,
so light turns on you push a button,
light turns on you push a button.
Okay.
There's a lag between the light going on
and you pushing the button.
The shorter the lag,
the smarter you are.
Well,
what is it that's really interesting
because you know if you're perceiving
something complex,
it takes a lot of neural connections to
generate the perception,
but simple reaction time is like two
neurons whack.
There's no complexity in that at all and
yet how fast you are at that is still
correlated only at about point two,
five,
but that's not trivial.
If you're doing research in psychology,
generally speaking,
and you come out with a point two five
correlation between whatever you're
measuring and whatever you're interested
in,
you're having a pretty good day.
Point two,
five is not bad at all and so it's not
accounting for all of it,
but it's accounting for a fair bit of
it,
how big your head is.
That's also correlated how how big your
brain is physically and then even more
accurately,
how big your brain is in relationship to
your body.
Now again,
these are small correlations,
but they're not.
They're not nonsignificant.
What else?
Nerve peripheral nerve conduction
velocity.
That's this study.
Two studies with sample sizes of 90 and
90 roughly speaking,
are reported that investigated
relationships among measures of
intelligence,
speed of information processing,
and peripheral nerve conduction
velocity.
In both studies,
neural conduction velocity was
significantly correlated with Iq scores.
Point four,
two point four,
eight.
Man,
that's a whopping correlation.
How do I know that?
Because a guy named Hemphill,
where is he right there.
You might say,
well,
how big is the correlation Coefficient
before you call it big?
And the answer to that is generally lets
guests.
So if you talk to psychologists and they
talked to you about how big the effect
sizes are,
they use guesses that were generated by
statisticians in the fifties and so they
radically underestimate the actual of
correlation coefficients because they
never studied it empirically.
Well,
this guy handheld because here,
how big is the correlation Coefficient
to be big?
How do you answer that?
Take a thousand psychology studies rank,
order the effect sizes and break them
into percentiles,
right?
That's an empirical way of doing it.
How big is the effect that the typical
study generates?
Then you can use that as a way of
assessing how impressive the effect is
that you generated.
Okay,
so this is it.
Here,
Hemphill,
2003.
Interpreting the magnitude of
correlation coefficient.
Now you could say that's a dopey way to
do it because why defined size in
accordance with the size that people
have discovered and handheld would say,
well that's because I'm doing it this
way with this paper.
If you want to do it a different way,
go right ahead,
but there's utility in this.
You come up with an RF point two,
how likely is it that your next paper is
going to have an effect size of that
magnitude?
How happy should you be?
Well,
the answer is a lot happier than you
think.
So to get it our of point five,
that's 25 percent of the variance.
So you still have 75 percent of whatever
explaining your phenomena left to be
explained.
Our point five,
92 90,
a 97th percentile,
so 19 out of 20 psychology studies that
are published and that's a hell of a lot
more fewer psychology studies that
exist,
right?
Because this tiny fraction of them get
published,
95 percent of them show up a correlation
coefficient of less than point five for
her third point three,
five,
two point five,
zero.
It's that's greater than 75 percent of
them.
Point one,
five,
two.
Point three five is pretty typical and
the typical correlation between a
personality trait and the target of
interest is usually something in the
neighborhood of point two,
two point two five.
With Iq,
you get up two point five.
The relationship between income
inequality and male homicide is like
point seven five.
It just covers all of it,
which is to say that everywhere that
everyone's poor,
there's no male homicide and everywhere
that everyone's rich,
there's no male homicide,
but places where there's poor people and
rich people,
the male homicide rate goes way the hell
up right,
especially if it's a steep distribution
because the men at the bottom think
somebody has a lot more than me and
that's not very fair.
I'm going to do something about that and
that usually means killing other men and
so it's a.
it's unbelievably powerful relationship.
That's a useful thing to keep squirreled
away in your imagination.
Poverty does not cause crime.
Relative poverty causes crime.
That is a completely different thing,
so and its dominance hierarchy issue.
Fundamentally it's men.
Men are generally the criminals and as
the dominance hierarchy gets harder to
climb,
the young man,
especially the aggressive ones,
get more likely to turn to violence.
You really need to know that.
So credibly important fact.
I'm going to interview the guy who
figured that out.
Martin Daly.
I'm going to interview him for one of my
podcasts in the next month or so,
so you might be interested in tuning in
on that if you're interested in this
sort of thing.
Okay,
so back to these correlations.
Look,
peripheral nerve conduction velocity is
correlated with Iq at like point,
let's say point four five.
It's a whopping effect man,
and that's.
That's a pretty straightforward thing.
Speed of electrical propagation along
your neural tissue determines how
intelligent you are.
While is that really so surprising you'd
expect,
if that's associated with neurological
integrity,
at least to some degree,
it's exactly the sort of thing you would
expect,
but it shows you how biologically based
it is too.
Faster.
Neural conductance philosophy was
associated with higher Iq scores and
faster speed of processing.
Why?
Who knows?
Here's a hypothesis.
What if you're trying to remember a
phone number?
Just the seven digit one.
What do you do when you're remembering
the phone number?
You say it over and over again,
right?
Or you or you.
If you don't say it,
you think it over and over again,
and if someone distracts you,
then you lose it.
That's working memory,
roughly speaking and your working memory
capacity,
so imagine you could do four digits and
remember them.
You could do six,
you could do eight,
you could do 12,
likely not 12 is really pushing it.
That's a great estimator of Iq working
memory.
In fact,
there's almost no neuropsychologists
like to think that working memory is
something in and of itself,
but that's because they don't know a
damn thing about psychometrics.
Generally speaking,
there's almost no difference between
fluid intelligence and working memory
and the reason for that is that all
measures of intellectual function
collapse into Ge and so we can take a
look at what that means.
This is from this character here,
Carol joynt.
Carol,
if you want to know everything there is
to know about Iq.
This is a book that everyone who's a
psychologist should.
It should.
You shouldn't be able to be a
psychologist unless you've read this
book.
In my estimation.
There's a couple of key texts and this
is one of them.
This guy,
Carol,
wrote this thick book.
You don't have to read the whole thing
because a lot of it's just in some sense
demonstrations and proof of what he
saying,
but what he did for Iq is the same thing
that psychometricians did for the big
five.
You've got the big two at the top.
They're not very highly correlated.
I think it's about point two,
something like that.
So they're pretty independent.
Then they fragment into the big five and
then you can differentiate them further
into the big tent and there really are
five different traits because they're
only correlated with each other at about
point two to point three.
So really quite distinct.
Um,
the question is,
if you fractionate Iq,
how correlated are the things that you
fractionated into.
And the answer to that is point eight or
point nine.
There's one factor in Iq,
roughly speaking you,
if you,
if you take
imagine that you took an Iq test and you
took,
it was 100 items long and you took the
50 items that were the most correlated
with each other.
And then the 50 items that were the
least correlated with those 50 items.
So you broke it into two as much as you
could,
you maximally differentiated,
you might ask,
well how correlated with the scores
beyond those two different subsets,
and the answer would be like point nine
because there isn't two things that
you're measuring.
Even if you break it up that way,
post hoc and say,
well it's unfair,
but we're going to say because these are
the 50 most highly correlated and these
are the leftovers,
like we're really capitalizing on chance
there.
You're still going to get an almost
identical readout from both sections of
the Iq test and it's just not the same
with personality.
So and so this is,
this is carol's model basically stratum
three.
That's the highest level of abstraction.
That's fluid intelligence and then you
can break it down into these sub
categories of cognitive ability and you
might say,
well,
how different are those subcategories?
And the answer is not very.
If you're high in one,
you're very likely to be high in all of
them.
Now there's a bit of a Coda to that,
which is that the lower your Iq,
the higher the correlation between these
sub aspects of intelligence,
the lower your Iq,
the higher the correlation between the
sub aspects of intelligence.
As you get up into the higher strata of
Iq,
your eye,
your intelligence differentiates more
across the potential range of
differentiation,
which is to say there's one way of not
being very bright,
but there's multiple ways of being
bright.
So,
but even even so,
if you're high on one,
you're still quite likely to be high on
the rest of them.
So then the question is what's the
correlation between Ge and each of these
sub elements of Ge and then what's the
correlation between the sub elements of
GE themselves?
So if this was plasticity and we were
looking at openness and extroversion,
the correlation here would be about
point.
I think it's about point five,
something like that,
and the correlation between openness and
extroversion would be about point three.
Quite a bit of difference.
But with this,
there's GE,
there's the sub elements,
there's the correlation coefficients
point nine,
almost point nine,
five point.
What is that?
Six or eight?
Eight point eight point six,
point eight,
point nine.
Pretty much.
Point nine.
Well,
you can fractionate it the best you
possibly can.
It doesn't matter.
It's one thing.
It's one thing and it looks like it's
the ability to abstractly represent and
then to manipulate the abstractions.
I said with working memory,
you know you can get it.
That's simply how many digits can you
keep in your head simultaneously without
dropping one.
That's it.
God.
It's unbelievable.
It's pretty straightforward.
And then it's this viciously powerful
predictor of longterm life success.
Probably prediction of around point
five.
Now psychologists,
psychologists hate this.
They won't admit that it exists and I
think it's because there's something
about intelligence that against our
intrinsic egalitarianism,
right?
There's two things that do it.
First,
let's say you're successful.
You like to think I'm successful,
you know,
and you like to attribute it to your
own,
do it.
And Fair enough.
I'm not saying that there isn't an
element of it that's your own doing
whatever that means,
but if your nerve conductive velocity
happens to be high,
there's a lot more probability that
you're going to be successful and it's
kind of hard to blame that on you or to
attribute it to you for that matter.
So it indicates a kind of statistical
arbitrary ness about the distribution of
success and failure in our society.
Okay,
so that's one thing people don't like
that idea.
The second thing is,
is that it turns out to be very
difficult to raise Iq.
Now it's tricky because it looks like
you can raise Iq across whole
populations because these fluid
intelligence looks like it's been rising
quite substantially over the last
hundred years.
Maybe as people are better nourished and
better educated,
but also more prone to continually
manipulate abstractions in their life.
Because I mean kids start with computers
when they're like two,
you know,
so.
But if you take a group of people and
you try to.
If you take a group of low Iq people and
you try to raise their Iq,
it's very,
very difficult to manage it without a
tremendous amount of investment.
That doesn't necessarily mean the
investment isn't worthwhile,
but it does mean that it's very
difficult.
Well,
the best thing to do as far as we can
tell,
the best thing to do is get nourishment.
Right?
That seems to be the most effective.
Yeah.
So I'm part of the reason.
Part of the reason,
the theory is part of the reason that
population iqs have been increasing over
the last hundred years is because
there's just no one left who's seriously
enough malnourished so that it's going
to profoundly impact their intellectual
capabilities.
So breastfeeding seems to raise Iq,
so it's two,
two points,
three points with every year of
breastfeeding.
It's something like that.
So it's,
it's,
and that's actually quite a lot.
Two or three points actually makes a
difference as it turns out.
So.
Okay.
So he's Iq real depends what you mean by
real Iq is average performance across
average sets of questions that require
abstraction to conceive of.
And and answer is it real well,
it's real statistically,
and you can use it to predict important
outcomes that other things can't predict
and from a scientific perspective,
and it's also correlated with various
physiological and biological phenomena.
While that's,
that's how you define real
scientifically.
So yes,
it's real.
Are there other factors that determine
people's success and worth?
Iq Isn't a measure of people's worth in
any intrinsic sense.
It's a,
it's an estimate of their ability to
succeed in abs,
in hierarchies that are dependent on the
ability to manipulate complex sets of
information.
There's lots of other things about
people that differentiate them in terms
of quality and quantity and all of those
things.
And the most evidence of those are the
big five traits.
Now,
if you're a psychologist,
and this is another thing every
psychologist should be taught,
if you want to discover something about
human beings that hasn't already been
discovered,
the first thing you should do is make
sure it isn't Iq and it isn't any of the
big five traits and psychologists almost
never do that because what happens is
that if they control for ICU,
so in regression you'd say,
okay,
here's the thing I'm interested in
predicting.
The first thing we're going to do is add
ICU and not.
I've measured that you took in five
minutes either like a real Iq test
because you want to use a good measure
to test your hypothesis against and not
a 10 item measure of the big five.
Either like 100 item measure.
So you get a reliable measure.
You throw in Icu,
you throw in the big five,
and then you throw in your dopey
construct and then you see if it can
predict anything.
And the answer is no.
And so psychologists don't do it because
whenever they do it properly,
it destroys their construct and that
makes them irritated because their claim
to their position.
Of Authority in the educational
dominance hierarchy is predicated on the
validity of their construct.
Now,
if you're a real scientist,
what you try to do is destroy your
construct.
You think,
okay,
it looks like this is real.
Then you think it's probably not,
and I don't want to spend the next 10
years chasing a ghost and a Mira,
so I'm going to try to destroy the damn
thing.
So you say,
well,
we'll match it up against a good measure
of Iq and a comprehensive big five and
it still survives.
We'll do a couple of replications to
make sure that we can't kill it any
other way and maybe we'll do the
statistics three or four different ways
to make sure that the thing just doesn't
disappear when you use a different
statistical procedure and people don't
do that,
and that's why the replication rate even
among well established psychological
finding,
so to speak,
once that have been highly cited is
extraordinarily low and no,
if you talk to psychologists,
they'll wave their hands and they'll
say,
well,
I don't really believe in Iq.
It's like,
okay,
you know,
we're not talking about what do you call
those?
What did the ghostbusters hunt down?
We're not talking about paranormal
phenomena.
They're not things you get to believe in
or not,
right?
There are rules for defining what
constitutes something that's real from a
scientific perspective and a
psychometric perspective,
so you don't get to say,
well,
apply one definition of reality because
I don't like Icu,
and then I'll use the same definition to
justify my own constructs.
Like,
sorry,
that isn't how it works.
Not You can do that.
If you're a postmodernist,
you can do that,
but if you're a person who actually
thinks scientifically,
you don't get to play that game,
so now you know,
part of the reason that we need to know
about these sorts of things.
See how are we doing for time here?
Oh yeah,
we're doing good.
I think we need to know these things
partly because they have policy
implications.
First of all,
you need to know them for your own life
because you got to know that there are
differences in intelligence.
It's really important.
If you go into a job and you're not
smart enough for that job,
you're going to have one bloody
miserable time and you're going to make
life wretched for the people around you
because you won't be able to handle the
position and as you climb hierarchies of
competence,
the demand on fluid intelligence
increases,
and so unless you want to fail,
you don't put yourself in over your head
while what's over your head.
Well,
that's a tricky thing to figure out.
I mean you have to figure that out with
intelligence.
You have to figure it out with
conscientiousness.
You have to figure it out.
With creativity,
you have to figure out with stress
tolerance with agreeableness because you
want to go into a cooperative
environment and not a competitive one.
If you're agreeable and with
neuroticism,
you probably want to keep the stress
level of your job relatively low because
those are all places that you can break
down and most people have at least one
significant weakness in their
intelligence,
personality makeup,
and you got to be careful not to place
yourself in a position where that's
going to be a fatal flaw.
But what you really want to do as far as
I can tell,
if you want to maximize your chances for
both success and let's say wellbeing is
you want to find a strata of occupation
in which you would have an intelligence
that would put you in the upper core
tile.
That's perfect.
Then you're a big fish in a small pond
and you don't want to be this.
You don't want to be the stupidest guy
in the room.
It's a bloody rough place to be.
So.
And you probably don't want to be the
smartest guy in the room either because
what that probably means is you should
be in a different room,
right?
You should look at a place where if
you're right at the top,
it's you've mastered it.
It's time to go somewhere where you're a
little lower so that you've got
something to climb up for.
So I can.
If you're not hyper conscientious,
for example,
you're probably not going to want a job
that you have to work 70 hours a week at
because you're just not wired up that
way.
You'd rather have some leisure and like
more power to you if that's how you're
wired up.
There's nothing wrong with having some
leisure,
but if you're someone who can't stand,
sitting around doing nothing ever,
then maybe you can go into a job that's
going to require you to work 75 hours a
week and almost all jobs that are at the
top of complex dominance hierarchies
require very high intelligence and
insane levels of conscientiousness as
well.
Generally speaking,
as pretty damn high levels of stress
tolerance,
you know,
because that can knock you out too
because there's going to be sharp
fluctuations in your career generally
speaking,
at the higher levels of,
uh,
of a,
of a structure.
And you have to make very complicated
decisions often with very short time
horizons.
So you have to decide if that's what you
want.
Okay?
So here's some ICU items.
So this is,
this is from a task roughly.
It isn't from the direct test,
but it's an analog of the Raven's
progressive matrices.
Now,
here's how the Ravens was derived.
So imagine that you have,
you got your hundred questions and you
can take out the some of those and call
that Iq.
Okay,
so now you'll have a score.
Then you can do a correlation between
all of the items and that and you can
find out which single item is the best
predictor of the total score because you
might see that question 39 has no
correlation with with the,
with the meat,
with the average.
You say,
well that isn't a very good question.
You would actually throw that out of the
next test,
but you'd say,
well item number 15 is correlated at
point seven five with a total score.
So that's a good single item.
So then imagine that you went across
sets of Iq tests and you took out the
best single item predictors of full
scale Iq.
What you'd end up with is something like
this.
So the Raven's progressive matrices is a
very good test of fluid intelligence and
it's relatively non-linguistic,
which is also an advantage,
right?
Because imagine you wanted to assess the
intelligence of a very diverse range of
people and they all came from different
linguistic backgrounds.
Well as long as they can understand the
instructions which are almost self
evident,
then they're going to be able to do
this.
Okay,
so this is,
you see,
you have to guess case you didn't
already figured this out,
which you would have had you been using
your intelligence and applying it.
You're trying to replace the question
mark with one of these.
And so here's how you do it.
Roughly speaking,
it's also,
it's probably a working memory task
because you have to hold a variety of
variables in imagination at the same
time.
Okay.
So the first thing you think,
see us,
every role has a star,
a triangle,
and a square.
And each role has a dot,
two dots and three dots.
And so every role has to have a
triangle,
square and star and one,
two or three dots.
Okay.
So this one,
first of all,
what's it missing in terms of shape
triangle.
Excellent.
See,
that's why you're at the UFT and then.
Okay.
And then what's it missing for dots?
Two dots.
Excellent.
So we do a little scan here and we say,
oh look,
well it could be that one or it could
be.
That's it.
It's that one.
And so is that right?
Yes.
Aren't we smart?
No,
that was easy.
So No,
you're not very smart if you figured
that one out because pretty much
everybody can figure that one out.
I think this next one is more difficult.
Okay.
So in the first row you see that there's
two objects.
Each are different color and they move
together,
right?
They joined that one.
There are separate there.
They joined,
they're together,
they're separate.
They're.
And they joined there.
So this one should be halfway in between
those two.
And the other thing that happens is,
let's see up this item actually might be
incorrectly represented because the blue
should be on the other side.
Whatever.
What's that
three?
Yes.
Did they flip?
Okay,
well anyways,
you see that it's three.
See not very bright because I've
lectured for an hour.
Okay.
So.
So that was a more difficult item.
And then this one is more difficult if I
remember correctly.
So let's see.
So they're all three different colors so
it has to be color than what's the other
thing and the relationship between the
colors change.
So what's the answer?
Pot.
You're all,
you're all scared to answer,
aren't you?
Because you might be wrong and the more
anxious people are even less likely to
answer number three.
Okay.
So if you want to test someone's Iq,
then you put together a nice batch of
these at different levels of difficulty
and then you sum them and then you rank
order and then you correct for age and
then you have Iq and that's that.
And then you can say,
well then you can sort people into the
complexity of their occupations.
And isn't that dismal and wretched,
but it's true.
So here you go.
This is from the wonderlic people.
There are commercial company that makes
general cognitive ability tests and it's
often used by corporations even though
it's actually illegal,
it's actually illegal to use Iq test,
but the wonderlic doesn't
promote themselves as testing Iq.
I think they think it's general
cognitive ability,
which is the same thing,
but whatever the sats,
the Gres,
the Olsat,
all of those are Iq tests,
so now they're more crystallized than
fluid and we'll get to that in a minute,
but crystallized knowledge is what you
accrue across type,
so you could say that fluid intelligence
is what programs your brain,
it fills it with facts.
Let's say it fills it with knowledge and
then,
but you can get an estimate of your
intelligence by sampling your domain of
factual knowledge,
and the reason for that is that while
obviously the better the program or the
better the content,
and so what that also means is that you
can.
You could,
if your prefrontal cortex was damaged
later in life,
your fluid Iq could plummet,
but you're crystallized.
Iq remain more or less intact.
So even though they're not different,
one produces the other,
and then once the producer has produced,
then the producer can disappear and you
still got the encoded knowledge.
So at least that's how it looks to me.
So okay,
so how smart do you have to be to be
different things in life?
Well,
if you were to have an Iq of 116 to 130,
which is 85th percentile and above,
so it's one person in eight up to one
person in 1:30,
I believe is 85,
90 95.
Is it 95?
Ninety five,
one person,
eight to one person in 20.
Then you can be a attorney,
a research analyst and editor and
advertising manager,
a chemist,
an engineer and executive manager,
et Cetera.
That's,
that's the,
that's not the high end for ICU by the
way.
It can go up.
Well,
it can go up indefinitely,
although there's fewer and fewer people
as it goes up.
So if you want to be the best at what
you're doing,
bar none,
then having an Iq of above 145 is a
necessity and maybe you're pushing one
60 in some situations and maybe that's
make me make a new one person in 10,000
or even one person in 100,000 and then
also to really be good at it.
You probably have to be reasonably
stress tolerant and also somewhat
conscientious,
so people think,
well why is it that smart people are at
the top of dominance hierarchies and the
answer to that in part is because they
get their first,
right.
I mean everything's a race roughly
speaking,
and the faster you are,
the more likely you are to be at the
forefront of the pack.
And intelligence in large part is speed.
That's not all of it is.
So if you're moving towards something
difficult rapidly,
the faster people are going to get there
first.
So Iq of 1:15,
1:10 to 1:15,
so that's 80,
fifth to 70,
30,
85th percentile.
Copywriter,
accountant,
manager,
sales manager,
sales analysts,
general manager,
person,
purchasing agent,
registered nurse,
sales account executive.
If you look at universities,
the smartest people are.
They're above this.
Who are the smartest people at
University?
What do you think?
Mathematicians,
physicists,
and mathematicians.
Right?
Right.
I can tell you who's on the other end,
but I won't.
Yeah,
I'd like to though.
Anyway.
Anyways.
Okay.
Going down the wonder three to one a way
to slightly above average rate,
60th to 70th percentile,
store manager,
bookkeeper,
credit clerk,
lab tester,
general sales,
telephone sales,
accounting clerk,
computer operator,
customer service Rep,
technician,
clerk,
typist.
So you see at this level people are.
People have some technical skill and
some ability to deal with complex
things.
Okay,
that's dead.
Average hundred is average dispatcher in
a general office,
police patrol officer,
receptionist,
cashier,
general clerical inside sales clerk
meter reader,
printer teller,
data entry,
electrical helper,
95th to 98 machinists,
food department manager,
quality control,
check,
security guard,
unskilled labor maintenance,
arc,
welder,
die setter mechanic.
Good,
good Iq range for relatively qualified
tradespeople.
80 seven to 93 messenger,
factory production worker Assembler,
food service worker,
nurses aid,
warehouseman,
custodian,
janitor,
material handler,
packer.
Now what you're seeing,
what you're starting to see is that as
you move down the hierarchy,
the jobs get simpler.
They're more likely to be assigned by
other people or the repetitive because
what Iq predicts to some degree is how
rapidly you can learn something,
but once you've learned it,
it doesn't predict how necessarily how
well you do at it,
and so the more repetitive jobs,
10 people with lower iqs are more suited
to more repetitive jobs under 87.
Is there something?
Well,
no,
right,
that's a big problem and it's something
our society has not addressed at all.
Jobs for people with our of less than 85
are very,
very rare.
So what the hell are those people
supposed to do?
It's like one,
it's 15 percent of the population.
What are they supposed to do?
Well,
we better figure it out because one of
the things that's happening too is that
as the,
as the High Iq tech geeks get a hold of
the world,
the demand for cognitive power is
increasing,
not decreasing,
right?
You want to be a teller.
Well,
you know those checkout machines,
they're not so simple.
You want to work at Mcdonald's.
You think that's a simple job.
You don't see robots working at
Mcdonald's and the reason for that is
that what Mcdonald's workers do is too
complex for for robots to do so
well.
So this is a discussion that no one
wants to have,
but that's okay.
It's still a problem and it has to be
dealt with.
So the US government,
I think I told you this at one point
already,
it's illegal to induct anyone into the
US army if they have an Iq of less than
83,
right?
It's about 10 percent of the population
because the US army and they'd been
doing Iq testing since Iq testing began
because they want everybody they can
possibly get into the army because in
peace time they use it as a way of
moving people up the socioeconomic
ladder and in war time.
Well obviously you need as many soldiers
as you can get your hands on and so
you're not going to be any pickier than
you have to be.
So when the U,
s army says it's illegal to induct
anybody into the armed forces.
If they have an Iq of less than 83,
then you know that they've done it for
absolute necessity.
Right?
And when people have made a finding that
contradicts what they want to hear and
they're doing it out of absolute
necessity,
you can be reasonably true that it's one
of those facts that just won't bloody
well go away.
And so you might think,
well,
if there's nothing for someone with an
Iq of less than 83 to do in the army,
what makes you think that there's
something that they can do in the
general population?
And then the issue is because the
Conservatives will say,
well,
they should just work harder.
It's like,
sorry,
that ain't gonna fly,
and the liberals will say,
well,
there's no difference between people
anyhow and you can just train people to
do everything that's wrong so they're
both wrong and they're seriously wrong.
And the fact that neither side of the
political perspective,
we'll take a good cold hard look at this
problem means that we're going to
increasingly have a structural problem
in our societies because we're
complexifying everything so rapidly that
you can't find employment unless
increasingly,
unless you're intelligent,
you guys are really going to face this.
You know,
lawyers are disappearing like mad.
And the reason for that is you can look
it up online.
Increasingly.
You can do things yourself if you're
smart.
And so like the working class people
have been wiped out pretty nicely over
the last 30 years by by automation and
various other things.
It's the low end of the white collar
class that's coming up next.
So I'm not saying that lawyers are in
the low end,
but low end lawyers are in the low end
of the white collar class.
So there's still going to be plenty of
positions for people who are creative
and fast on their feet and super smart.
In fact,
people are going to have all the money
that's already happening to a great
degree,
you know,
because if you're smart and you can use
a computer,
you're so smart.
It's just absolutely unbelievable.
Right.
And if you can't use a computer and lots
of people,
and I don't mean you can open word,
that isn't what I mean.
I mean maybe,
I mean you can program and if you can't
program while you're right at the next
and so if you haven't got that with you,
you're,
you're going to be left behind.
Oh,
a lot of them will take demerol.
That's what's happening in the United
States.
Yeah,
it's an opiate.
Yeah.
So there's a massive drug problem
emerging and.
Yeah.
No,
I'm telling you,
that is what's happening there.
Yes.
Drugs.
Yeah.
Drugs of abuse.
Well,
that what,
what is happening to a large degree is
people drop out of the employment race.
They get very depressed.
They develop chronic pain problems,
especially if they're men,
because chronic pain and depression are
very much the same thing.
And then they subsist on opiates which
are subsidized by Medicaid in the US.
I'm not kidding about this.
This is exactly what's happening.
What,
what else is going to happen to people
for whom there is nothing to do.
They have a terrible time,
especially if they're conscientious.
That's a good question.
You know the Ai guys are pushing hard on
this.
Hey,
what's the biggest employment category
driver?
Think about it.
What's Tesla doing?
What are all the ai guys working on as
fast as they possibly can?
Driverless cars,
no problem.
Except that's the biggest employment
category for men.
So what are those guys going to do?
Yeah,
they're going to sit home and be
miserable with their wives and take
opiates because they have chronic pain
problems,
right?
Nasty,
and you might think,
well,
could they think of something else to
do?
Well,
if you have an Iq of 83 or less,
you're not going to be doing a lot of
thinking about something else to do.
You know?
That isn't how it works because you're
more of a.
you're an act person,
not a thinking person,
roughly speaking,
you know,
and so if you have a task at hand,
especially if you're conscientious,
you can diligently go about it,
but you know,
I've tried to train people with Iqs of
80 and less to do what I would consider
tasks that,
that one of you could learn to do in 10
minutes and never make a mistake again.
And it's like tens of hours with bare
minimum mastery of the tasks.
So it's ugly situation,
no doubt about it.
Okay.
Openness.
So creativity.
Oh
well I can talk more about this on,
on,
on Thursday.
Maybe we'll just stop and I'll go into
creativity on Thursday.
So we've got about five minutes.
So if anyone has a question,
I'd be more than happy to entertain a
question.
So it did it.
What I tell you what you need.
We're in a technical area to some
degree,
right?
So you need to understand how these
tests come about because you can't
understand the concepts without
understanding it.
So I'm hoping that the way I told you
that the Iq tests were derived made
sense.
I mean,
it's a fairly straightforward thing,
but that's what you want to concentrate
on.
You had a question?
Yep.
You can't change.
You can't train simple reaction time.
It's really hard.
You talk about very rapidly and it here.
But let's take your question a little
further.
So let's say,
um,
Iq predicts how fast you'll master of
video game.
So then,
and it does.
So then let's say we're going to train
the hell out of you on a video game.
So you get super good at it and then
you'll get like tetris.
You know,
everyone.
Does everyone know what Tetris is?
Okay,
well,
this is really an I an Iq test for all
intents and purposes.
It's spacial rotation test.
So you can get really good at Tetris,
right?
And you think,
hey,
my Iq is increasing.
It's like,
well,
here's the problem.
Let's say I produce a variant of Tetris
that requires that the idea is basically
the same,
but it requires different operations.
Being good at Tetris won't help you be
good at that test.
You don't get crossover.
And people have been trying this for a
long time.
It's like,
well,
maybe you could practice a bunch of Iq
tests and you'd get better.
It's like,
no,
you get better on the Iq test,
you practice,
but you don't get better on Iq tests and
you see even fluid,
you can't move it.
And there are people who come up with
claims all the time.
Like the lumosity people.
It's like,
well,
here's a bunch of complex.
So then they thought,
look,
practice one test.
That doesn't work to make you smarter.
So then practice a whole bunch of tests
and then maybe what you learned across
all the tests will make you smarter.
No,
it doesn't work and it really sucks
because one of the things you'd hope is
that once you had extracted out a
central factor for intelligence that you
could get people to practice the micro
skills that were associated with it and
it would boost icu.
It's like it doesn't work and you know,
about every five years someone comes out
with a claim that says,
hey,
we've developed a new test and if you
just do this test,
you'll get smarter.
And then someone tested out and they
usually use the Raven's progressive
matrices as the marker and they show no,
it's the same thing.
Domain specific knowledge doesn't
generalize to other areas.
So it's a hell of a thing if you,
if you can figure out how to raise
people's fluid Iq,
you will be a billionaire,
but you won't be able to do it because
it looks like it's impossible,
but you never know,
you know,
maybe someone will crack it at some
point,
but we certainly haven't yet.
So
no transfer?
No.
There's no generally no.
No generalizability of a specific skill
to ICU.
So,
you know,
if you practice one thing and it,
there's something that you're doing
that's close that there's going to be
some generalizability.
It's Kinda hard to define what close
means though.
Pro Pro.
Well,
it depends on.
It would depend on how big the factor
you changed was.
But the general rule of thumb is no
transfer.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
The higher the Higher Iq.
The Higher Iq person will lose and learn
the new thing faster.
Pretty much no matter what it is.
Yes,
yes.
But even so then you might think,
well,
what if you practice learning a bunch of
new things fast,
would that make you faster at learning
new things?
And the answer is a,
people are doing that all the time.
So you're probably maxed out on that to
some degree and be no,
it won't.
So.
And it,
believe me,
people have tried this for a long time,
so and for good reason and we haven't
got anywhere.
Yes,
Yep.
Yeah.
The language one is tougher because like
if you say say you learn two languages,
can you pick up the third faster and.
Well the answer is how it depends on how
linguistically close the new languages
to the two that you've already learned.
And then if you learn 30,
you can probably learn a new one in like
two days because once you've learned 30,
you've covered the domain of languages.
So the language issue is a little bit
more complex because languages have a
fair bit of commonality in their
underlying structure.
So,
but you don't learn one language faster
after you've learned three because
you've got smarter,
you learn one language faster after
you've learned three,
because you know more about languages.
So.
Okay,
we should stop.
We'll see you Thursday.