About a month ago,
I had my funding for my ongoing research
projects refused by the federal
government,
a social sciences and Humanities
Research Council,
and as an event from rebel media decided
to host on Indiegogo crowdfunding
campaign to replace it,
which was very good of him.
Um,
so thank you to Ezra and also to itn
deal board who helped out a lot and to
Hannah Vander Coi for managing it.
It was extraordinarily helpful.
Um,
we raised about $80,000 the first day
and then since then we've raised about
$180,000,
2,500 backers.
The original grant proposal was for
$300,000 across five years.
So that's basically three years of
funding.
So I'm extraordinarily impressed by
that.
And also very thankful for all of you
who donated.
Um,
thank you very much.
I've put together this video with two of
my graduate students whose academic
careers will be supported as a
consequence of this funding so that you
know a little bit more about them and
also about what it is that you helped
out with the third,
Christine Brophy is working on political
correctness.
And the relationship between personality
and political belief as well as on the,
on the biological basis of the big five
personality traits.
She couldn't contribute to the video
for,
for various reasons this time round,
although she did a lengthy interview
with ray rebel media that you can catch
on a,
on social justice issues and,
and their basis in personality.
And so,
uh,
after this very brief introduction,
I'm going to let the students speak for
each for five minutes.
They've prepared a video telling you
what they're up to.
So anyways,
thanks very much.
We have one day left of the funding
campaign runs for 24 hours.
So this is the final update in all
likelihood by March.
Hi everyone.
My name's John Tenant.
I'm a first year master's student in Dr
Peterson's lab.
My research interests include technology
for cognitive enhancement,
personality development,
and music cognition.
My background is a little bit different.
I did my bachelor's degree in music
theory and my undergraduate research
focused on mathematical models of
musical harmony and timber.
This year I'll be designing and testing
a biofeedback system for increasing
people's ability to flow,
self regulate and get in tune with one
another.
I'm using a variety of sensors to
measure things like heart rate,
breathing,
arousal,
and brainwaves.
How are we turning these signals into
quads?
I'm musical stimuli to give people
feedback about their body and mind in
real time.
They should be able to help people
better understand themselves and
regulate their stress and emotions if
used in pairs,
they might even be able to help people
sync up with one another,
perhaps fostering empathy and helping
them get into a kind of interpersonal
flow state.
I have a huge personal interest in
combining music,
psychology and technology.
In my undergraduate work with Dr
Peterson,
I tackled theoretical issues surrounding
visual representations of music.
While working on that project,
I developed a method for making
important musical parameters such as
harmony,
pitch,
rhythm and tamber accessible to our
visual system.
I created two software.
Music visualizer is based on these
principles.
I found these techniques also translate
well to other applications such as the
visualization of biological data.
If you'd like to see the music
visualizes,
I developed or read about the principles
behind them,
you can check out my
website@JohnMatthewtenant.com.
There you can also find my undergraduate
paper on math and musical harmony.
In my personality research this year,
I looked at female mate preference in an
online study.
Women read the profile of a fictional
man and size picture.
Women then rated the man's
attractiveness and personality.
They also answered questions about their
own personality and completed an Iq
test.
From this data,
we were able to build a model of what
kinds of personalities are attractive to
who.
On average,
women tended to prefer men who are
conscientious,
extroverted,
agreeable,
emotionally stable,
and open to experience higher Iq
participants.
However,
where the men is much less attractive on
average,
and they were less moved by those
traditionally attractive characteristics
like extroversion,
conscientiousness,
emotional stability for more intelligent
women.
The only things that made a significant
difference where creativity and
plaintiffs,
which are sub aspects of openness and
agreeableness,
we think creativity might be especially
attractive because it indicates
competence in unfamiliar situations.
The attraction to agreeableness might be
due to a desire for a partner who will
share resources and care for children
in my upcoming personality research and
developing a new method for
investigating the structure of
personality.
In traditional personality studies,
participants rate themselves on every
item.
This limits the number of items that can
be analyzed simultaneously.
Instead,
we're going to use collaborative ratings
of fictional characters and public
figures.
Multiple people will provide ratings of
the targets personality,
and we can build up a complete
description from the multiple raters.
This will allow us to investigate the
personality data contained inside larger
sets of descriptors.
This will help us rapidly expand the
vocabulary of words we can use to
measure personality,
which should increase the precision of
our models.
The first study to use this method will
attempt to integrate positive and
negative person descriptors with our
existing personality models.
This is important because when the
original scales were devised,
researchers purposely omitted words like
evil,
untrustworthy wise and admirable,
but adding these words to our models of
personality will be able to further
explore the virtues and vices associated
with personality dimensions.
We might also be able to pick up on new
effects and correlations.
This can be especially useful in the
labs,
ongoing research into the personality
underpinnings of political belief,
so I'd like to thank everyone for
supporting our research.
It makes a really big difference,
especially to us the graduate students.
If you're interest in any of my work,
I'd love to hear from you.
You can also check out my site at John
Matthew Tenon Dot com.
I have demos and papers posted there.
Thanks for watching.
My name is victor swift and I'm a phd
student in Jordan Peterson's lab.
I joined the lab in 2013 as a master's
student,
primarily researching how mental health
is shaped by the ways in which people
relate to their own descriptions of the
world.
Today,
my overall research investigates the
nature of the big five personality
traits.
The big five represent distinct patterns
of feeling,
thinking,
and acting that are shared by all of us.
Humans and higher primates seem to
possess five distinct dispositions,
hence the name openness,
a tendency to seek novel ideas and
experiences.
Neuroticism tendency to seek certainty
and experience negative emotions,
extroversion,
a tendency to seek attention and
experience positive emotions,
agreeableness,
a tendency to seek social harmony
through politeness and compassion,
and finally,
conscientiousness is a tendency to
adhere to standards and goals by working
hard and staying organized.
This final trade has been the focus of
my research for reasons that I will
explain shortly.
Every person has these five traits to
some degree and these traits remained
relatively stable throughout adulthood.
As such,
the big five traits are important to
both industry and academia because they
can be used to reliably capture who a
person is.
Now,
we are confident that the big five model
represents a real and meaningful
psychological construct because it has
been arrived at through several
independent methodologies.
However,
we do not yet know why human
dispositions cluster into these five
traits,
nor do we know how to ascertain big five
traits without directly asking people to
introspect about themselves.
This is where my research comes in.
For the past three years,
I've been investigating how the big five
traits can be detected without self
report.
This effort has taken many forms which I
will continue to pursue throughout the
course of my phd.
For instance,
I've been investigating whether the big
five traits map onto differences in
fundamental cognitive processes such as
attention thus far.
I have found support for the idea that
conscientious people are remarkably
better at deliberately attending to
specific features under distractions.
Well,
people who score high on openness are
notably flexible at attending to
changing attentional demands.
This research suggests that the big five
traits may have a basis in fundamental
cognitive processes,
and this may lead to the development of
personality screening measures that have
a basis in part on cognitive
performance.
I've also been investigating whether the
big five traits reveal themselves in
motivational reactions to positive and
negative feedback on a variety of tasks.
So far,
this line of research has revealed that
conscientious and neurotic people can be
provoked to work harder by using
negative feedback.
However,
this effect only emerges when the task
is somewhat enjoyable and the effect is
first.
If the task is frustrating.
This line of research suggests that the
big five may have a basis in more
fundamental motivational tendencies,
and this may lead to the development of
a motivational intervention that's
tailored to specific personality
profiles.
What am I most promising?
Research projects concerns the detection
of personality through language use.
This research is founded on the
presupposition that character can be
revealed through the words that
individuals tend to use this ideas
intuitive when we think about simple
dispositions such as pessimism and
optimism.
For example,
we would expect an optimist to use a
disproportionate amount of positive
words.
However,
it was unclear as to whether this would
extend to complex dispositions such as
conscientiousness,
which again represents a tendency to
work hard and stay organized.
This disposition does not clearly map
onto word choice,
so to test our hypothesis,
we generated a list of more than a
thousand adjectives that are
theoretically relevant to conscientious
people.
These words included things such as
methodical,
persistent,
and resourceful.
We then acquired a variety of writing
samples from different groups of people.
These writing samples included
recollections of positive memories,
negative memories,
ordinary experiences,
as well as stream of thought essays.
And even facebook statuses across all of
these samples,
we found highly conscientious people to
use a disproportionate amount of
conscientious related adjectives.
Not only that,
but we also found that the use of these
adjectives predicts the same outcomes as
conscientiousness itself,
including increased income and increased
passion for work that we have
demonstrated that it is possible to
identify complex personality traits from
many different language samples easily
and reliably.
We started with conscientiousness loan
because of its clear real world
applications.
Many of our most valued social,
organizational and individual outcomes
are determined by conscientiousness.
People who possess this trait enrich our
communities by exercising social
responsibility and relational fidelity.
As top performers at work in school,
conscientious people drive up the
productivity of our organizations and
the grades in our classrooms.
By demonstrating that conscientiousness
can be detected through natural language
use.
We have opened the door to a new
approach for detecting a highly
desirable personality traits.
The trait that many people lie about
precisely due to its societal value.
Am I coming years in the Peterson lab?
I plan to develop a personality
measurement battery based on these
natural language findings.
The development of this battery will
require more research into the language
production tendencies associated with
conscientiousness,
as well as an extension of this
methodology to other big five
personality traits taken together with
my research and attention and
motivation.
This work will help solidify what the
big five represents and will afford the
development of new tools for measuring
and accommodating personality.