So I want to continue talking about this
basic story or subpersonality or game or
map.
So what I've discussed with you so far
is that there are
different ways that you can construe the
objects and territories that you inhabit
and that modern people generally think
that the world they inhabit is the one
that's defined by science.
But
I would say
I would say actually it depends on which
scientist you mean because I don't
believe that the worldview that emerges
as a logical consequence of Darwinism is
the same worldview that emerges as a
logical consequence of Newtonian
presuppositions.
And
the reason I'm bringing Newton into it
is because we still think a newtonian
terms.
I mean it's been more than 100 years or
100 years,
I guess since Newton's models expanded
by quantum physics,
but no one thinks that way because you
can't think that way.
And besides that,
the reason you don't think that way is
because at the level of resolution that
you exist,
things behave in a newtonian manner.
So it's in accordance with our natural,
with some of our natural perceptions.
Now
I started thinking this way for a
variety of reasons,
but I was influenced later by a guy
named Gibson,
Jj Gibson who wrote a book called an
ecological approach to visual perception
and he made the case quite strongly that
what you directly perceive is the
implication of of situations and
objects.
So for example,
I suppose you've all seen the famous
visual cliff experiment with babies
where if you put a piece of glass across
the open space and space is evidently
deep,
the baby won't cross the glass and so
there's some evidence there for
relatively innate,
not only depth processing.
It's not just depth process,
right?
Because in order to not crawl off that,
you also have to perceive that,
well,
Gibson would say that it's a falling off
place and he would say that's actually
what you perceive is a falling off
place,
and then maybe you could abstract out
the idea of cliff,
but that isn't what you perceive and
know
the sense you have that when a bear is
chasing you,
that that's dangerous.
That doesn't seem to be merely
psychological in a sense like it's not
merely in a sense,
it's not.
It's not less real than perceiving the
bearer as an object,
an object that eats you.
It's not the same object
as an object that remains neutral to you
or positive and it seems quite clear.
And this is where the Darwinian issue I
think arises that
you have to evaluate with your
perception because otherwise you're too
slow.
So anyways,
I developed this diagram as a
consequence of thinking about these
things for a long time and the diagram
is predicated on the idea that when you
begin to act in the world,
you're inside of motivational frame,
let's say,
and that motivational frame can have,
can be,
oh,
instantiated or,
or,
or put into practice by or put into
place by any number of underlying
motivational system.
Some of them,
the more basic motivational systems that
we share with animals going far back
down the evolutionary chain and some of
the more complex mixtures of emotional
or a motivational drives that had been
organized across
lengthy periods of time and in social
circumstances.
So
for example,
if you're at a bar and you're looking
for someone,
it's not really reasonable to say,
we'll we'll take a simple case.
It's not really reasonable to say that
your behavior is motivated by sex
because that's what happens only if
you're actually in a sexual act.
Before that the motivations are multiple
and they have to be because otherwise
you wouldn't have this sophistication.
Do you begin a conversation with anyone?
And so to think of that as as driven in
some sense,
bisexuality means either to consider a
much more expanded notion of sexuality
or to not consider it driven in that
manner.
Now I think it's reasonable to make the
presumption that you're motivated to
move ahead and we know that for a
variety of reasons.
Partly that's because if you look at the
brain,
at the level of the Hypothalamus,
which is a very,
very are,
are archaic and Primordial sub system in
the brain.
Then it's roughly divided into two parts
and one part is responsible for a lot of
the things that we consider basic
motivations.
And the other part is responsible for
exploration.
And that's so the.
The dopaminergic tracts that WHO's
operation underlies movement forward and
incentive reward and what you generally
experience as the sorts of positive
emotions associated with hope and
excitement and curiosity.
That system is instantiated in the
hypothalamus and a lot of the
hypothalamus,
this is donut is devoted to it,
so it was a very primordial system who's
operation appears to
be a default.
It's a default operation if none of the
other motivational systems need current
attention.
Well the other default,
I suppose it's sleep or rest and you can
certainly see that in animals because
you know if you have a cat,
you'll notice that they sleep.
Of course they're nocturnal,
but they sleep up a large part of the
day and so the dogs,
so you know if you.
If you're not looking for a partner,
if you don't want to play,
if you're not hungry,
not thirsty,
and so on,
not under the grip of any direct
biological necessity,
let's say.
Then your default position is to rest or
sleep or to explore.
And the thing about the exploratory
circuit is it's really old.
It's as old as pain.
It's as old as lust.
It's as old as anger,
it's as old as hunger.
It's as old as thirst,
like it's a really,
really old system.
It's a very,
very primordial system and human beings
are quite hyper exploratory,
at least collectively as you can tell,
because we keep inventing new things and
exchanging new modes of being and so so
you can say it in some sense that you
have a drive to engage with the world
and to expand your domain of knowledge
and the reason that you have that is
because the human race has has gambled
on that as a sufficient means of
ensuring our reputation into the future.
And it's a strange one,
a because most animals are very,
very conservative.
In fact,
most human societies are very,
very conservative,
so it's certainly possible for even
relatively modern human society.
So let's say those that have arisen in
the last 50,000 years to remain
relatively unchanged for for periods
during that time of up to 10,000 years.
That seems to be what happened,
for example,
with regards to the original inhabitants
of Australia and so it stays this.
That's the norm,
not transformation and no,
even societies that we feel we're very
dynamic like let's say ancient Egypt
still there are,
there are indications in the
archaeological record of relatively
unchanged customs and practices for
periods of periods that you would count
in the thousands.
So most animals and many societies that
just doing the same thing over and over.
It's gonna.
It's gonna do the trick,
you know,
and human beings.
Well that isn't what we're like
and
God only knows how that originally came
about.
You know,
what was the conjunction of many,
many processes enforces and,
and it would be very,
very difficult to tell a complete causal
story.
But anyways,
here we are now.
It's reasonable
to think of us as motivated to move
forward and motivated to explore.
And so
that's the fundamental motivation for
engaging with the world.
Apart from anything that's let's say
strictly lower level biological.
And while we're doing that,
it's also customary for us to look at
the world in terms of its utility.
And I would say with human beings,
it's,
it's a very tool based utility because
you know,
our brain is part of our body,
our brain is adapted to our body and our
body is adapted to our brain.
Obviously they call evolved and so the
kind of brain we have is the sort of
brain that a creature that stands
upright and can manipulate the world
has,
and we'll see some evidence of that
later.
But because we're so handy,
we can speak with our hands and we can
manipulate things with our hands and we
can transform things with our hands and
we can tear things apart and we can
haunt and there's like,
there's a.
and we can plant and there's,
there's an endless number of
possibilities for hand utilization.
The world appears to us a rate out as
tools,
roughly speaking.
And a tool would be something.
It,
it's hard to get the word exactly right
because I like tool because tool implies
something that you can use.
Um,
whereas Gibson would have talked about,
um,
what did he call it?
I can't remember.
It'll come to me in a minute.
It the word reflects the fact that the
world is presenting itself to you as
something that you can use.
Let me just look that up for a second.
That's very annoying.
No,
that's not right.
It's not facilitators.
Oh,
well,
whatever.
So naturally when you lay out the world,
if it lays itself out into things that
are going to be useful for you,
things that you're going to get in your
way and then things that have neither
property and under most circumstances,
the things that have neither proper
property are the overwhelming majority
and that's partly how you managed to
process the world and all of its
complexity with
your relatively narrow processing
capacity.
Most things have no significance and
they have no significance within this
very,
very focal frame which is,
you know,
if you remember the hierarchy diagram,
it's like in that hierarchy diagram,
most of the time you're operating at the
level of motor interaction with the
world.
You're actually engaged with the world
either through articulation,
but forget about that for now or you're
actually in engaged moving in the world
and moving it around and interacting
with it.
So it's,
it's as if you're viewing the world
through a series of concentric lenses
and the all of those concentric lenses
exclude,
and then the very,
the highest resolution lens,
the one that enables you to focus
closest is the one that helps you
highlight those few things in the vast
perceptual world of nothingness that
seemed to be critical for that
particular operation.
So now you can see that mean the most
dramatic example of that.
I was really personally thrilled about
Dan Simons grill experiments because I'd
been thinking about this for a long time
before that experiment came out and it
was the clearest demonstration I'd ever
seen.
I mean,
there's a lot of demonstrations like
that now,
but it was the clearest demonstration
I'd ever seen that indeed most of most
of what your perceptual systems do is
exclude.
So now what that means,
this is the tricky thing,
is that what that means is that wrapped
up in what you exclude is the entire is
all of being virtually.
And that's a very tricky problem because
when,
when you're excluding all of being,
in some sense,
you're setting its value to zero.
You say,
well,
except for those few things that I'm
concentrating on now,
everything else is zero and zero and
unchanging.
And the problem with that is that lots
of times that's not right now.
It's,
it's right enough.
Luckily enough,
and I,
I suppose this is a consequence of
evolution to
were fast enough or slow enough
depending on how you look at it so that
we can assume constancy across some
spans of time under some conditions.
Now,
from a philosophical perspective that's
inadequate.
Some of you might have heard of the
phrase the scandal of induction.
Well,
it's a,
it's a pointer to a very profound
philosophical problem.
And the philosophical problem is how do
you know that the same thing is that
happened before it's going to happen
next.
And the answer to that is generally you
don't know.
So,
and it's a very tricky issue to come to
terms with,
you know,
um,
I think you can,
you can think of things as you know,
if you think about a hierarchy of
resolution,
again,
I think you can think of things as
varying rather predictably in their
unpredictability.
So for example,
there's some indication that protons
decay,
but they decay over such a long
timeframe that the probability that
that's going to affect us is virtually
zero.
And then,
you know,
there's other things that we interact
with quite regularly,
like the sun that are stable across
timeframes that make it virtually
ignorable.
But
well,
I'll tell you a story about that and
this is a good story to indicate how
everything is nested in what you ignore.
So part of this story is fictional,
but part of it isn't.
So one time when I was in graduate
school in Quebec,
in Montreal,
I always typing on my hard drive
computer and it stopped and you know,
computers do that.
And so what happens when your computer
stops?
Well,
the first thing that happens is it
depends on what you're working on.
That's the critical issue,
right?
I mean,
and so what happens is you have a
reaction that's proportionate to the
deemed importance of what it was that
you're working on and that there's going
to be an association between that and
deadlines.
And there's going to be an association
between that and amount written that you
think he might have lost.
And then there's so,
so there's,
there's because what you're doing is
nested in a hierarchy,
you know,
I'm writing a sentence to write a
paragraph to write an essay to handy
essay in to fulfill a requirement of
class to graduate,
etc. All the way up the nested
hierarchy.
You're going to be upset in
proportionAte in proportion to the upset
that or to the,
to the cost of this failure in terms of
that entire structure.
And so you do a rough estimate a because
you don't really know and generally you
don't assume the worst,
although you might immediately cause you
know,
that's the sort of situation where
someone will go,
they'll,
they'll get angry or I will anyways,
I'll pound my fist on the on and then
I'll curse microsoft usually or,
or whoever happened to make the
computer.
And then all remember that I can usually
fix computers if there's something wrong
with them.
and that probably all it needs to do is
be rebooted and so forth.
And so what happens to begin with is a
burst of emotion and the reason for that
is that you,
the significance of the unexpected event
cannot be easily constrained.
And that's because there's so manY
things that might've gone wrong now,
you know,
because the worst case scenario is,
well maybe,
maybe your computer's dead.
And then that's a problem for all sorts
of reasons we don't have to go into.
And it's not just a technical problem,
right?
It's also a political and social and
economic problem,
weirdly enough because then when you go
buy a computer you have to figure out
well who's the manufacturer and where's
the manufacturing done and what's a high
quality computer?
And it's like,
good luck figuring that out because they
change every month so you just can't
keep track of it.
So.
So it opens up a whole rat's nest of or
hornet's nest of problems where a pit of
snakes,
which is a better way of thinking about
it.
Okay.
So fine.
So my computer's dead.
So I tried to reboot.
It doesn't reboot.
And so I think,
well,
I don't know,
maybe it's burned out or maybe there's
something wrong with the plug.
So I plug a lamp in into the same outlet
and I tried to turn on the lamp and the
lamp doesn't go on.
And so then I think,
aha,
I blew a fuse.
This place had fuses so fine.
So I go to the fusebox and it's daytime,
so it's not a problem.
And I look at the fuses and there's
nothing wrong with the fuses.
and so I think,
well,
I'll go down to the corner store and get
a cigarette because I smoked at that
time.
Then,
um,
I'll think about it on the way.
And so I go outside and all the street
lights are off.
And so the whole city has come to a
halt,
I think,
oh,
there's a power outage.
It's like,
yeah,
there was a power outage.
And here's what happened.
A solar flare emerged from the sun
surface and it was a whopping big one.
And a solar flare like that sends out a,
a wind essentially have charged charged
particles.
It comes zooming towards the earth and
there were protected from them for a
variety of reasons,
including the fact that the earth has an
the earth's magnetic and for complicated
reasons that helps protect us from from
cosmic rays,
which is really a good thing as far as
I'm concerned,
but now and then those things are so
powerful that they'll.
Well,
here's an example,
if you have a hydrogen bomb,
a big one,
and you,
you detonated in the middle of north
America,
in the atmosphere,
say high up,
you wipe out all the electronics in the
entire continent permanently because
what happens is that when the bomb goes
off,
there's an electromagnetic pulse and
that produces electrical electrical
current that runs through the wire and
that'll be it in very brief obviously,
but of sufficient intensity to fry the
electronics.
So well,
thAt's what the sun is.
The sun is of massive hydrogen bomb and
so now and then it goes off with the
force of,
you know,
millions of hydrogen bombs and then we
get the pulse and radiating towards us
and then it sets up current in the power
grid,
which is what happened here and takes
out the whole power grid.
That's what happened that at that point
the quebec power grid was down for quite
a while and it was because this.
So that's why my computer crashed just
because the sun wasn't as stable as I
thought it was,
you know,
and that,
that gives you an example of just how
interconnected things are and how much
what's in,
how much you're taking for granted when
you make anything invisible.
No,
and I,
I would say that part of what happens in
a civilized society will say a civilized
and productive society is that there are
rules of conduct in place and there are
effective processes in place so that
most of the time you can rely on things
being like they were yesterday.
So for example,
our power supplies unbelievably reliable
given that you know,
it's so,
it's so intrinsically unstable.
People have to beetle around nonstop
just to keep the power on,
but they do.
And so we can sit here and ignore it and
you know,
when we can concentrate on something
more arcane and much more focused,
but it's also because we're,
it's a relatively peaceful society and
we have relatively free speech and so on
and so forth.
And you can predict with a high degree
of certainty that if you come to class
then what's going to happen in the
class?
The worst that's gonna happen in the
class likely is that you're either going
to get bored or hot.
So that's not so bad,
you know?
So.
all right,
so you're going from point a to point b
and you see your tools.
I still haven't remembered that damn
word.
Oh,
what the hell is that word?
That's so annoying.
Nope,
whatever you go along,
you see these tools,
these are things that are going to help
get you to your goal.
And whenever you see those,
then you get a burst of positive
emotion.
And basically that means two things,
that positive emotion,
think about it as a little dopa mean
care.
And this is where this story
differentiates a little bit from classic
behaviors.
So the behaviors would say you get a
little dopamine kick and that increases
the probability that the action that you
just took will be taken again in the
future.
And so,
so it's partly because the dopa mean
kick has a positive emotional,
uh,
it provides a positive emotional
experience,
but it's also because the dopamine
facilitates neural growth.
And so if you're battling along and
something good happens to you,
then your brain makes the things you
were doing,
the circuits that underlie the things
you were doing just before the good
thing happened a little bit stronger.
But,
but the other thing that happens when
you're battling along and doing your
positive thing is that you give a little
dope is that the fact that it's working
also validates your frame of reference.
Because,
you know,
you might say,
well,
if what you're doing is working and
you're getting what you want,
how is it that your right.
And the answer to that is,
while in some ways you're right enough
up the entire hierarchy,
and so what that means is that every
time you proceed along the path that
you've chosen and that's working,
that that entire structure gets
stabilized a bit more and that's how it
should be.
Now,
I've tried to work out exactly how this
happens and,
and I think I can give you the best
example by telling you about cocaine
addict.
So
addicts used to have this phrase monkey
my back and that phrase referred to the
compulsion,
the compulsive subpersonality that
develops.
It's interested nothing but more of the
substance.
Now you know what you think about that
as being hurt and you might think about
it as a motivational drive or a
biological drive.
But the thing is,
it's not like that.
It's,
we're just not that deterministic.
I'm an addicted person,
has grown and addictive subpersonality
and I mean grown.
It's not psychological,
it's psychophysiological.
And so,
so imagine this.
Imagine this is how it works.
Okay?
So,
and I'll.
Okay,
I'll first tell you what happens to
cocaine addicts.
If you take them out into a treatment
center,
heroin addicts is the same thing roughly
speaking,
so you take this person who's dependent
out to a treatment center and with
heroin and say you have to let them go
through withdrawal and that takes about
48 hours,
something like that,
and you've seen movie representations of
it,
but it's been compared by reasonable
observers to having a very bad flu,
so alcohol withdrawal by the way,
that kills you.
Often you have a seizure and you die,
and so if you're an alcoholic and you go
to the hospital and you need to
detoxify,
they'll give you valium or something
like that so that you don't seize
yourself to death while you're
withdrawn.
You know when you have a hangover.
Part of that is part of what's happened
is you've actually lowered your seizure
threshold,
so something to think about if you're.
you know,
if you're prone to seizures,
it's a bad idea to have a hangover.
In fact,
they bred mice to study hangovers.
They bred mice that could drink alcohol
and then they'd get a very bad hangover
and if you showed them a cat,
they'd have a seizure,
so because the fear was enough to
trIgger seizures here,
so you've got to get seizures,
go somehow if you're going to study
them,
and that's so in,
that can be bred so.
So anyways,
you take your,
your heroin addict,
let's say,
and they get over their,
their,
their withdrawal,
and so that means that technically
they're no longer physiologically
dependent on the drug.
Now that doesn't mean that their work is
over by by no means,
but frequently In a treatment center,
as long as the person is nowhere near
where they usually are.
Once they've gone through withdrawal,
they can stay away from the drug quite
effectively,
but the problem is as soon as you put
them back in the situation that they
came from,
they end there around the things that
have been associated with heroin.
Let's say they get a craving and the
cravings haven't gone away.
That's a different system than the
system that went through withdrawal and
so they always relapsed.
So now
you think about how this craving works
and I've seen this probably most
seriously I guess with cocaine addicts,
but also with alcoholics,
so imagine that.
Imagine what you have to do in order to
become an addict.
You know,
the first thing is you have to start
using the drug.
okay,
but that,
but,
and,
and fair enough,
so people experiment with all sorts of
drugs and so,
you know,
that's part of human nature.
So you know,
It's risky and dangerous,
but it's not yet catastrophic.
Okay?
But then let's say you start using it
enough so that you,
you can't not use it.
You have to use it everyday or something
like that.
And then the next thing that happens is
that gets a little bit expensive and so
then your life is starting to go
downhill because you're spending all
your tiMe trying to gather resources to
get some more of the drug.
Now what you might ask yourself is what
do you have like exactly what's the
chain of behaviors that's being
reinforced by the drug?
Well,
somewhere along the way,
you know,
maybe when you're just starting to
misuse it,
there's part of you that saying,
you know,
really this is probably not a good idea,
and then there's another part of you
that has a different thought which might
be,
oh,
to hell with it.
It's only once.
It's only tonight,
and so then you take the drug and then
there's a chain leading from the thought
to the drug behavior,
but the drug reinforces all the way back
along that chain.
So what happens is that little system
that's thinks,
oh,
to hell with it,
it's only one night gets a little
stronger.
Now.
It doesn't get as strong as this systems
that are being reinforced that are
activated directly before the drug
drug hit.
But the thing is is that maybe you take
heroin in 50 different situations and so
you're conditioning yourself to cues and
all those different situations use
slightly different behaviors and so on.
So there's different things being
shaped.
But one of the things that's always
being reinforced,
even though not that much is this
thought pattern.
And the thought pattern is something
like,
well,
to hell with it doesn't matter anyways
because he has to think that in order
to,
especially at the beginning of a nice
downhill trip,
you have to think that.
And so what happens is you build this
monster in your head.
It's full of lies and rationalizations
and their whatever lies and
rationalizations allowed you to continue
the behavior to begin with,
but you're making them more and more
potent.
And so you build a subpersonality inside
of you that is,
it's a one eyed monster.
Fundamentally all it wants is the drug
and its armed with any number of
perfectly depends on how smart you are.
You know like you can.
You can come up with a very
powerful nihilistic,
rational argument.
Why about life is futile and your
future's dad and there's nothing better
to do anyways and you'd be a fool to be
engaged in such a destructive society
and et cetera,
et cetera.
Like you cAn.
You can conjure up a very,
an argument that's virtually impermeable
to rational
to rational argument,
rational counter argument.
Because you know there's some things
that you just can't prove.
You can't prove that life is
intrinsically worthwhile,
you know,
because,
well for obviously for obvious reasons,
so now the reason I told you that is
because I think it's a good example of
how things are nested inside of each
other,
you know,
and also the relationship between this,
this very large nesting of concentric
lenses,
let's say,
and the way that those things are shaped
and reinforced across time.
Whenever you're acting locally and
something goes the way you wanted to
let's say,
and not the way you expect because
that's what soaked in vinegar deliver
and Jeffrey Gray and the people who were
looking at the orIenting response first
presumed they presumed that you wanted
things to go the way you expect,
but that's not exactly right and it's an
important distinction.
You want things to go the way you want
them to go and if it's just expectation,
then it's a cold cognitive model of the
world,
right?
It's like robotic,
okay,
happened now,
be should happen now.
See should happen.
It's like,
that isn't how you think at all.
You're always inside of motivational
frame and it isn't only that you expect
the next thing to happen,
but if the next thing happens,
it matters whether it's what you want or
not.
If it's what you want,
then that little system is reinforced
you.
It's pleasurable for you,
and then the whole hierarchy grows a
little bit stronger and if it is not
what you want,
well then you have a problem and that's
where things get weird and interesting.
So okay,
so you're going along from point a to
point b and you can see tools and you
can see obstacles and obstacles or
anything that get in your path.
And what that means in some sense is
that what a tool is and what an obstacle
is switches very rapidly as you change
focus and as your intended changes.
So it's a dynamic system.
All right?
And so the way emotion motion works in
this regard is that if things are going
the way you want them to,
then you feel positive emotion and that
keeps you moving forward towards your
goal.
And if you run into an obstacle,
then you feel negative emotions.
Okay?
So the next issue might be,
well,
just exactly what should you experience
when you experience negative emotion?
Well then you might say,
well that's a tricky question because if
you encounter an obstacle that means
that something about your model is
wrong,
because if it was right,
then you wouldn't have been counted that
obstacle.
And so this is,
this is a very interesting way of
thinking.
It's a pragmatic way of thinking because
what it illustrates is that whenever you
do something,
you're acting out a theory of truth,
and the theory of truth is
the actions that I'm undertaking at the
moment are sufficient to reach the goal
that I'm aiming at.
And so you set up a theory of truth with
each act.
You know,
so
so you're,
you're,
you're always struck with the reality of
truth and error or correct and incorrect
because
you cared,
posit that the goal is worth having,
and if there's a path to it that might
be clear or,
or obstructed without also saying it
matters whether you know what you're
doing.
Okay?
so you hit an obstacle
and that produces negative emotion.
Now,
the problem you have here is that in
principle,
the reason you hit that obstacle could
be that there's an error in your nested
model at any level of the model.
So that's why I told you the little
story about the sun.
It's like normAlly you just turn your
computer on and off because something
has happened that's local,
but now and then your problem is the sun
isn't as reliable as you might like it
to be and so you're faced with is
insanely complex problem,
not when things go right,
because when things go right,
you can just continue ignoring
everything that you were ignoring,
but when they go wrong,
the search space that opens up before
you is just about infinite.
Now that that has real world
consequences,
I mean one of the things that happens
when people develop panic disorder,
what seems to happen is that I can tell
you the typical story about how you
would develop panic disorder with
agoraphobia because the two things are
somewhat separate.
So generally this happens to.
It generally happens to women.
It generally happens in their forties.
Women are more susceptible to anxiety
and depression and men just so you two
were more susceptible to substance abuse
and antisocial behavior
figures that something would go wrong
right now.
Okay,
so now what do I ask myself?
Well,
if this is going to disrupt the class,
does it mean that there's something
wrong with my computer?
Should I call these help people?
And they'll say,
well no,
we'll ignore it on the assumption that
it will continue working and until that
had martha says fails,
then we can ignore it.
Okay,
so,
so something goes wrong in the search
space opens up in front of you now.
Okay.
So back to the agoraphobic.
so what happens to her usually is
generally these are people who've had
dependent relationships and so perhaps
they,
they had a relatively over predictive
family or let's just say protective
family and then they had a,
an intimate relationship early in their
life and maybe that lasted for quite a
long time or maybe they're still married
to the same guy,
but the,
the,
and,
and inside that relationship,
she's relatively dependent,
which means probably she doesn't go
anywhere without her husband.
And she doesn't,
she doesn't do a lot of things
autonomously,
let's say.
Okay,
so then
she gets my menopause and you know,
she's getting some strange physiological
symptoms from that of various sorts.
And then maybe at the same time she
maybe she talks to her husband about a
divorce or maybe he talks to her about a
divorce or maybe her sister gets
divorced or maybe a close friend dies
or,
or maybe her.
Maybe she starts to experience heart
palpitations because of the menopause.
And then she thinks,
oh my god,
that could happen to me.
It's like my whole world could fall
apart.
And so that's one fear my whole world
could fall apart.
So that's sorta the fear of societal
catastrophe that the collapse of the
structure.
And then the other fear is often,
oh my god,
I,
I couldn't be dying of a heart attack.
And so what happens to people who start
to develop panic disorder is that they
ended up going to the emergency room all
the time to be checked out by
cardiologists.
And the cardiologists are used to this
and they generally check people up quite
extensively.
But most of the time if there's
something up with your heart,
there's nothing wrong,
but there could be.
And so then the sort of.
So what happens is
the
the person who has is developing a
phobia,
starts thinking perhaps about what would
happen if her husband died or if they
got divorced and then she starts
thinking about the fact that while she
doesn't really know what she do and she
doesn't really know how to take care of
a bunch of things and how,
how she might take care of the finances
and so forth and so she has no real
place to turn.
And so then then she makes the fatal
mistake.
She goes out and she starts to panic and
then she goes home.
That's not good.
So if you ever develop severe anxiety,
one thing you don't want to do is avoid
because of it.
Because as soon as you avoid because of
it,
it gets worse.
and the reason for that is imagine her
anxiety systems are trying to figure out
how afraid she should be.
And it ranged from panic stricken to
none.
Well,
the anxiety systems have all sorts of
sources of input because they're trying
to calculate a very difficult problem.
Like if you know,
when this thing flickered,
one of the things that everyone does is
look around and the reason you do that,
it's called a referencing social
referencing.
It's like how upset should I be about
what's going on?
You look at everyone's face and you see,
well they're upset or not upset and
everybody kind of comes to an average
agreement about how upsetting this
isn't.
We do that very,
very rapidly,
you know,
and we estimate how anxious we should be
by our default neuroticism,
you know,
so I would say generally speaking,
if you're,
if you have higher levels of negative
emotion rather than lower levels,
what happens is that you,
the severity that you estimate have
given uncertain event to exist to,
to,
to have is higher than the severity.
Someone else might estimate if they were
more emotionally stable.
And then there's another input,
which is,
well,
how roughly how competent do people
around you and you think you are,
because you know how afraid you should
be is actually somewhat proportionate to
how competent you are,
right?
I mean if you're.
If you're a well practiced hunter and
you're out in the forest and a bear
charges you,
it's like,
well maybe you've seen 100 bears and you
know what to do and it's like it's a
bear and all that,
but you're not going to run.
And so then the bear probably won't
think you're prey because the bear
thinks that if you run that,
your edible.
Now the thing that's really interesting
is that if you watch yourself run,
then your brain thinks you're edible
too.
So that's another input.
So because.
So the anxiety system is doing this
terribly difficult calibration job,
which is okay,
something happened.
How upset should I be?
Well,
how upset or other people,
you know,
what's my physiological response?
How does it compare to other times I was
upset.
What are my options?
That's a good one because one of the
things the anxiety system really wants
is it wants you to come up with a plan.
He doesn't really care what the plan is,
although you have to believe it because
it's not really a sophisticated
cognitive system.
It's an alarm bell and it says,
look,
some things up here,
you have to knit up your world again and
put it to rest.
We need to be able to ignore everything
again.
If you can't do that,
that thing will just go off forever,
but that's what happens.
At least in part to people that have
post traumatic stress disorder.
There are soldiers,
you know,
and maybe they've gone out in battle and
they've watched themselves do terrible
things because that's actually one of
the most common precedents of
posttraumatic stress disorder and they
have no idea how to represent that in
their hierarchical world model.
You know,
because part of your world model,
a huge part of it,
the what is part,
you know,
it's who you are.
It's like you might find out that you're
not who you are,
who you think you are.
You're not even who you think you are,
a little tiny bit like there's corners
and nooks and whole unexplored rooms
inside of you that contain things that
if they ever come out like you,
you,
you're,
you're done.
You don't know what to do with it.
You know,
and if you're,
if you've dealt with someone who has
post traumatic stress disorder,
it's very frequently the case that you
have to,
they have to learn a philosophy of good
and evil in order to recover.
and it has to be sophisticated because
seen these terrible destructive forces
at work and their old world model is
just,
it's just not handling it,
you know?
So.
All right,
so what happens is the agoraphobic
person runs and then their anxiety
system says,
oh,
well what's chasing and ms dot obviously
a flesh eating predator and you know,
it isn't exactly that.
It thinks that they might have dreams
like that.
You know,
they could easily have dreams of being
pursued,
but it's the same system like the,
the system that we use to run away from
things that aid us when we were 30 pound
mammals is the same system that we now
use to process relatively abstract
threat and why wouldn't it be ready to
look as far as I'm concerned.
This isn't even a hypothesis.
It's like we know evolution is
conservative.
Everything builds on what was there
before.
So what else are you going to use when
you're threatened by some abstract
threat except the system that you used
to use when you were threatened by a
crocodile.
So it's,
it's only,
it's exactly that.
It's exactly the way it works.
So then,
you know,
she ends up question
both effect of exercise on anxiety.
Like in mean some people go for a jog
and they feel better like stress relief,
but if you're saying if you run in that
trigger zero,
oh no,
no,
you have to run from something just
running.
That's irrelevant.
You like.
It's a huge difference if you're running
toward something that's way different
than if you're running away from trying
to say you're like anxious about
assignment and you go for a run and then
come back,
more clearheaded to work on it.
You're not running from the Assignment
or you know you're just going out for a
run.
That's okay.
Like,
look,
let me give you an example.
It's a good question.
Let me give you an example.
You take a stressor of a certain
magnitude and you and you are interested
in the response of two groups.
If you let one group handled the
stressor voluntarily and you forced the
other group to handle the stressor in
voluntarily,
the second group will produce much more
cortisol,
which is the primary stress hormone and
so voluntary approach.
You use different psychophysiological
systems for voluntary approach than you
do for retreat and you know part of what
you're doing when you're training
someone or when you're doing using
exposure,
say with someone who has a phobia,
is that you're teaching them that the
voluntary approach system.
If you activate that,
that's a very good way of coping with
anxiety.
Now they they don't know that this
situation that we're describing,
because they're not autonomous,
they haven't ever moved to rely on that
system.
So you know if you're,
if you're faced with a threat,
there's friday things you can do.
You can just panic,
but panic is usually distress.
You know,
maybe a child sort of does that.
When it starts crying,
what happens when the child starts
crying?
When someone comes its rescue,
right?
So one of the things you can do is
admit,
distress cries and social resources will
come and be gathered around you and
maybe that'll solve the problem,
but that doesn't work when your heart is
palpitating because who's going to fix
that?
Well,
often these people,
If you look deeply into their thoughts,
maybe they're afraid to ride a subway
and actual reason they're afraid to ride
the subway is because they think,
well,
what if the subway gets stopped between
stations and I'm trapped on here and I
have a heart attack and I can't get to
the hospital.
So that hospital thing is running around
in their head all the time because their
default strategy for dealing with threat
is to seek authority.
And one of the things that often sets
people up for development,
a negative or a phobia is that the
authority that they rely on suddenly
becomes uncertain for one reason or
another.
Maybe the person is going to leave and
then they're isolated.
Or maybe the person like if it's a
husband,
say the person is what good is that if
your heart's palpitating you're going to
have a heart attack.
It's,
it's a problem that can't be solved that
way.
And then you're faced,
you know,
people might think about that as a whole
existential crisis and it is an
existential crisis.
It's like you're coming face to face
with your own mortality.
And that's certainly the case.
Say that if,
if you're,
if you,
if you're going through menopause at the
same time because that's another
profound life shift that indicates that
you're sort of halfway done or two
thirds of the way done,
something like that.
And that's of course,
you know,
you can think about that in terms of
terror management as well.
So it is an existential crisis and the
question is how do you deal with it?
And the answer to that generally is by
becoming a lot tougher than you are.
And the way that you help people do that
is you teach them that there are certain
dangerous situations they can approach
and they can approach them,
you know,
and generally people learn this quite
quickly,
you know,
and so the psychoanalysts believed that
if you just,
this was the early criticisms of
behavioral exposure was that,
you know,
if you expose someone who's afraid to
say just to an elevator that that will
help the other fears or maybe the fear
will be substituted somewhere else
because it's just symptomatic.
But that'd be cool work.
It's not right.
And it's because when you expose someone
to an elevator,
you're not exposing them to an elevator.
If they're afraid of that elevator,
you're exposing them to their own death.
So the elevator,
you could say,
well the reason that behavior exposure
works and it generalizes is because
it's not easy to specify what the
stimulus is.
I mean,
when I'm in front of an elevator,
it's an elevator.
When someone with agora phobia is in
front of an elevator,
it's not an elevator,
that's the problem.
If it was just an elevator,
they just get on it and away they go.
So you know,
I had one client who was afraid of
elevators and the elevator opened up and
she said that's a two,
and it was just an immediate response,
you know.
But you could say,
well that was the symbolic
representation that came to mind.
But you could also say that,
well,
there are similarities between an
elevator in it to when you can get
trapped and started an elevator and you
could get trapped inside an elevator and
die,
in which case it would be a two.
And the logical conclusion from that is
that everything could be a two.
And so you might think,
well the stimulus isn't too.
It's like,
yeah,
wrong.
It can be too.
It's unlikely.
But then you might ask also ask yourself
this
if the chance that you're going to die
somewhere as 100,000 to one,
should you be upset?
Well no answer to that as well.
Dying is of infinite magnitude and if
you multiply one in 100,000 byte,
infinite magnitude,
you get a very,
very large number.
And so one of the things that makes you
wonder is why the hell are people
terrified out of their skin all the
time?
And that is a very good question because
by no means obvious why people aren't.
And I actually think,
I often think that the mystery with a
condition like agra phobia isn't that
some people have agoraphobic.
It's that everyone doesn't have it all
the time.
So because you know,
when the terror management people talk
about this too,
is that because we're always confronting
our own mortality and in a world of
infinite complexity,
why aren't we constantly in a state of
panic and you know now and then you
realize that you think,
jeez,
you know,
why aren't we in a state of panic?
It's a very unsettling realization.
And why it isn't more common.
That's a very,
very complicated question.
I think a lot of it is because we
imitate other people and so a lot of our
faith,
let's say in the stability of our lives
and the utility and meaning of our lives
is actually instantiated at an embodied
level where it's not subject to
criticism.
So.
So for example,
I'll give you an example.
There's a child two years old and
there's a mother and they're together in
the kitchen and the most runs across the
floor.
Okay.
The child orients towards the mouse,
watches it zip across and then looks at
his mother or her mother.
Why?
Well,
because something anomalous has
occurred,
the significance of which is unstated
and it's arousing.
It's like,
whoa,
look at that.
You know,
you can be startled by that.
Okay.
Wow.
Could that sip?
Well then you think,
what does mom think of that?
And mom is thinking,
oh,
that's him.
I was having.
Maybe she'll tell you about mice or
maybe she'll send a trap or something,
but she's calm.
And so the child imitates that and then
you know,
they've got a sense in their body that
human beings can deal with mice and
that's no problem,
but you know,
the alternative is that the most comes
up and mother on the table,
he starts screaming.
It's like,
well you could be sure what the child's
going to do in a situation like that is
burst into tears and be extraordinarily
upset,
you know?
So a lot of what we're doing when we're
little and we watch people around this,
they modeled being calm and so we just
adopt the implicit assumption.
It's an embodied assumption that you can
be calm in these circumstances.
And luckily enough we generally don't
have,
generally doesn't come unglued.
But you can unglue it even by deep
thought.
And I mean that,
that happens to people quite frequently.
That would be an existential
catastrophe.
All right,
so let me show you something else here.
So
same idea.
Now this has changed a little bit.
She's going from point a to point b.
And what can happen while you can
encounter tools and you cannot encounter
obstacles and use zero almost everything
out.
But you can look at it this way too.
When you're moving forward,
you can encounter what you predict that
should really be desired rather than
predicted.
It's an old diagram or you can encounter
something that you didn't predict or
desire and if you in,
if you encounter something that you
predict and desire,
then you have positive emotion.
We know why that is.
You're getting to where you want to go
and it validates the whole structure.
But then you run into something
unpredicted.
Well then you get that's a threat and
you get anxious.
Well,
you also get exploratory and so then you
might say,
well,
how anxious do you get?
And how exploratory do you get?
And I would say,
well,
it's proportional.
imagine the hierarchy.
Again,
if you feel that it's just
a inconvenience that you can make a mild
alteration in direct action and go over,
you'll be mildly inconvenienced and
maybe you'll be a bit curious.
But what happens is that as your
suspicion that the error is occurring at
higher and higher and broader and
broader levels in the hierarchy,
the probability that you're going to be
anxious and quite anxious compared to
exploratory,
at least initially starts to mound.
So,
and then all those other factors that I
talked about also play a role like you
know,
your social status,
your neuroticism,
your sense of self competence,
how much you've explored,
all of those other things.
It's very complicated thing to,
to,
uh,
address.
And so,
all right.
And so then we're going to concentrate
on what happens if you experience an
unpredicted outcome.
because here's the complicated question.
If you experienced an unpredicted
outcome,
can you have a weird problem?
The problem is,
is that you have to figure out what to
do about something that you don't know
what to do about.
And that's
a big problem.
So
let's start with this one.
Alright?
So
you're going,
you're in the top left hand corner,
you're in this little frame and you're
going from point a to point b and you
encounter,
I'm calling it now and uh,
normally and normally it's something
that shouldn't be according to your
model of the world.
Now
what that does is it destabilizes that
model at some level of resolution.
Now,
what we're assuming here is that this is
a relatively high order disruption.
Okay?
So I can give you some examples of that
are the heart palpitation example is a
good one because that kind of,
that will kind of unglue you.
Maybe you take your child to the
hospital because they have a minor
illness and you find out that they don't
have a minor illness,
they have a major illness or you find
that out about yourself or you find that
out about your partner or maybe the
stock market crashes or you have a car
accident or you write the cat and you
end up in the 25th percentile,
like a quarter of the people who take it
do.
And then all of a sudden,
bang.
You're not where you thought you were
and you're not going to where you
thought you were going and you don't
know what the hell's going on,
and that can be,
as we said,
a small revolution.
Yeah,
just have to make a detour around it or
it can just sucker punch you and that's
as far as I've been able to determine.
That's alice down the rabbit hole.
That's a descent to the underworld and
what's down in the underworld.
Well,
partly what's don't everything is down
there in the underworld and the the
reason for that,
it's very complicated,
but part of the reason is is that when,
when things fall apart,
you don't get to ignore things anymore
because you had this model that told you
what was relevant in the world and what
wasn't.
And the real important part of that
model was that it told you what wasn't
relevant and then all of a sudden you
know,
something pops up and takes you down.
It's like everything's relevant.
Everything is potentially relevant and
that's terribly stressful because
everything is.
Should I be angry?
Should I be upset?
Should I cry?
Should I get divorced?
Should I run away?
Should I commit suicide?
It's like,
how am I going to come up with a new
plan?
Where am I going to get money?
Who's going to help me?
What's my future going to look like?
What is my past look like?
What am I going to do today?
What am I going to do tomorrow?
It's like all of these things come up in
some of that weirdness in the external
world,
right?
And that would be,
well,
let's say that you decide to discover
that your child's sick and let's say
that the doctors really don't know what
to do about it.
Okay,
So you've just handed a problem of
infinite complexity and a problem of
infinite,
infinite complexity is like a journey
through a maze that has no end.
It'S a branching maize,
and so what you'll find yourself doing,
for example,
is going on the internet and spending
hundreds of hours.
If you've got a research oriented mind,
hundreds of hours looking up every
single research article you can possibly
find on this condition,
and that'll range from like the farthest
out new age ideas to the most cutting
edge science.
If you can handle that,
you know,
so good luck with that.
That's,
that's an infinite search and then
that's not the only problem because.
So the fact that it's an infinite search
is very bad for you because there's no
way you can calculate how much time and
energy it's going to take before you
solve tHe problem.
So,
so that's,
that's stressful.
Why?
Well,
obviously it's stressful.
It means that you have an infinite
journey towards an uncertain goal and
you can't even handle that.
You know what I mean?
Your journeys have to be such that
they're self sustaining,
right?
I mean,
generally speaking,
when you're on a journey of some sort,
you have to obtain as much matter and
energy as the journey costs and maybe a
bit more because then you're storing
some,
uh,
for the future.
But if you've got this path of infinite
complexity laying out in front of you,
it's like
your body can't calibrate that.
And so what it does is it throws you
into emergency reaction mode.
And emergency reaction mode is prepare
for everything.
And that's not good.
And so down there in the underworld,
the world itself turns into a maze of
infinite complexity,
but you turn into a mass of competing
models and a lot of them are based in,
in very low level motivation.
I mean,
you're going to be angry.
That's for sure.
You might be angry.
God only knows for how long you know,
if it's a particularly nasty disease,
you might be angry for the rest of your
life and you know you could be angry in
a small way and accept fate or you could
be so angry that it completely consumes
you and you're.
You're out for revenge against being
itself mean.
And that happens to people.
And that's the only one of the emotions
and motivational states that are going
to be hyper activated by the response.
And so what happens is that your system
collapses into the underlying basic
motivational states.
And so you're anxious and afraid and
angry and exploratory and upset and all
of these things all at the same time.
And that is your reaction to the
unknown.
Your reaction to the unknown is stop
because you aren't where you thought you
were.
and then the next thing is prepare for
anything and the way you prepare for
anything is by getting ready to do
whatever it is that you can do.
So I kind of think about it as you're in
a car and you've got the gas pedal
pushed right to the metal and you've got
the brake on at the same time.
SO the car is roaring away.
But,
and you know,
if you take your foot off the brake man,
it's going to move,
but your foot off the brake because you
don't know where to go,
but you're still running at full tilt.
And that'S not psychological.
Exactly right.
It's psychophysiological cause you.
You're on energy and material burning
system and when you crack yourself up
into high gear,
then you're going to be burning a lot
more energy and material.
And what happenS to people is that,
well,
one of the things that happens is that
you'll shut your immune system off
because if you're being.
Because it's costly.
If you're being chased by a tiger,
who the hell cares?
If you get flu in two weeks?
It's like shut that thing off.
Everything that has to do with longterm
survival,
even your ability to think into the
longterm is going to be shut off because
your ability to think in the longterm
failed and so you default back down to
instantaneous,
impulsive modes of action and it's,
it's the right thing to do.
You know,
you might take all of this is a hell of
a time.
You have a cloudy mind,
but,
and,
and sometimes that's the case,
but you're,
you're wired up,
you're trying to solve this impossible
problem,
which is what the hell do you do when
you don't know what to do?
And the only answer to that is prepare
for everything because you're going to
gather some more information and that
might tell you what needs to be done
next,
but you have no idea how fast it's going
to have to be done.
It might be like,
you need to do thiS right now or,
or you don't get It done at all.
So.
So then you're down there in the
underworld where all the,
you know,
the great motivational beasts,
lurk and where there's an infinite pop
in front of you.
And It's.
And maybe you don't get out.
And that's the thing too,
is that that's the thing is,
is that this isn't psychological and one
of the real problems with modern
clinical psychology and modern
psychiatry just conceptually is that
people automatically assume that if you
have a problem,
like if you're depressed and unhappy and
anxious,
well then that's a,
that's a mental problem.
It's A psychological problem.
It's like it's a problem in so far as
it's not pleasant.
But what if you're in a horrible
situation?
Well,
you know,
the cognitive people would say,
well,
you know,
you just have to reconstruct It.
It's like,
yeah,
if you can reconstruct it,
man,
you're not in a horrible situation.
You know,
and one of the things you see with the
cognitive behaviors for example,
is when they assess depression,
they use the beck depression inventory
and I'd given the beck depression
inventory to hundreds of people and
their criteria for when you should be an
outpatient in a psychiatric ward is
probably the level of depression that
one third.
Have you experienced the first year that
you were in university?
Because I've given this instrument to
lots of university students in one slash
third of them,
at least In the first year meet criteria
for hospitalization with the back.
So the way the cognitive behavior is
people,
what do you call,
evade this issue is they just set their
diagnostic instruments so low that the
people that they described as depressed
actually don't have a problem.
You know?
So I think the cutoff for,
for outpatient is 15.
You know,
you're not happy when you're,
when you get up 15 on the back.
But if you are depressed,
you get a 60,
it's like your depressed.
And then you talk to someone like that
and you find out,
well maybe you're depressed,
but maybe you just have a terrible life
and the terrible life is and good luck
reconstructing that man.
So you're not very bright for,
for example.
And that's a big problem.
So maybe you have an iq of 85 or maybe
you have an iq of 80.
It's like good luck finding a job.
And if you do find one,
it's not going to pay.
So.
And it's not going to be stable and
you're not going to get good hours.
And so then,
well,
you know,
your only friend is crazy.
And then your family is like distorted
and twisted up beyond belief.
You know.
So maybe your mother is a chronic
alcoholic with dementia.
That'd be,
that'd be a nice touch.
And you know,
maybe your friends are only not very
good for you.
They're actively bad for you because
you've,
you know,
you've fallen in with some bloody
psychopaths and because you're not
particularly bright,
they can get your money every time you
get your support,
check your unemployment check or
something like that.
And you know,
well,
you know,
you get someone like that in your
practice and you think,
well,
they're unhappy.
It's like,
are they depressed?
Well,
no,
they're in the underworld and it's not
the same thing.
Here's depressed,
depressed is someone comes in,
they're reasonably well educated,
they have a job.
And when you ask them about the job,
they say,
well,
I,
you know,
I used to like my job or maybe I even do
like my job,
but I just don't find that I'm motivated
right now and I can't understand why.
Then he asked them about their marriage
and they say,
well,
you know,
I have a good marriage.
And then you ask them about their family
and they say,
well,
I've got the average number of family
problems,
but it's,
you know,
all things considered,
it's not too bad.
And So,
and then they don't have a drug or
alcohol problem,
but they score lIke 30 on the back.
You think,
hey,
you could take some antidepressants.
You're depressed,
you don't have a terrible life,
you know,
and they know that they often don't have
any real cognitive symptoms either.
although they might be reacting
negatively to some of the negative
things are happening with those people.
Something's gone astray,
you know,
maybe their sleep is upset.
That's often the case.
So when what they're suffering from is a
disequilibrium of,
oh,
fall,
sleep,
wake rhythms.
And so it's,
it's got out of whack.
And so you straighten up your sleep in
their better or sometimes they need
antidepressants,
but for the fIrst person like
antidepressants might take the edge off
and maybe not too.
But.
And what are you going to do?
You're going to get the person to
reconstru that assumes they have
options.
You know.
And the problem with educated smart
people is they think everybody has
options because they do.
It's like,
no,
that's not right.
Some people have,
some people have no options there,
like trapped in a corner.
And no matter how hard you try,
you cannot get them out of the corner.
You know,
sometimes it takes a virtual miracle
before that can happen.
So the thing about the underworld is
the,
it's a real place.
It's a real place.
And depending of course on how you
define place,
but that's exactly the issue.
How should you define plAce?
Well,
no,
I would say for the sake of argument
that you mIght as well define it two
ways.
You might as well use the standard
newtonian view that you know the world's
made out of inanimate material entities
arrayed in a certain manner because
that's a very useful approach for many
problems.
But then there's another perspective
which is no,
no,
no.
The meAnings that are arrayed themselves
in front of you in the world.
Those are real,
and I would also say just mentioned this
very briefly,
it's something that idea I've been
working on for a long time.
Is it,
there is an implication of darwinian
theory and the implication is that
we talked about this a little bit,
environments very complex and it's
transforming unpredictably and so what
that means is
you cannot ever be right about the
environment.
So righT.
Correct.
Is out to reach.
The best you can do is come to partial.
You can partially accommodated and so
you'd say,
okay,
well how have we partially accommodated?
Well,
here we are.
We've been evolving through three and a
half billion years,
given it our best shot and here we have
these bodies and there are a solution to
the problems posed by the transforming
environment.
And you might Say,
well,
how good a solutIon are those?
Well,
you got 70 years.
It's the best we've been able to manage
him.
Managing three and a half billion years
is to generate up a biological platform
that has enough flexibility to keep up
with the environment for about 75 years.
So then you think so there's no final
answer to the problem.
The environment presents.
There isn't an it's because it actually
changes unpredictably.
So there's no way of being right now.
Well then you might say,
well,
what does right mean?
Well,
from the darwinian perspective,
in some sense there's no other right
then that you're alive and that you're
likely to reproduce.
That's the best you ever get.
Okay?
So let's say,
well that's your pragmatic definition of
right?
Well then what that means is that if
that is right as far as right can be
determined as far as being human is
concerned,
then when you are reacting by fleeing
freezing,
when something terrible is chasing you
because you perceive it as a threat,
the fact that it's a threat is right.
It's not an overlay on reality.
It's like if you didn't perceive a
predator as a threat,
then you would get eaten.
And so I think,
you know,
you could think of the darwinian world
as nested inside the newtonian world,
which is how most scientists think,
but I don't believe that.
I think it's the other way around.
I think the darwinian world is the
ultimate world in a sense.
And the newtonian world is just a tiny
subset of that and it's,
it's useful.
Subsidized,
it's a tool.
It's a useful subset,
but the real world,
the darwinian darwinian takes precedence
over all knowledge structures.
That's how it looks to me.
And I don't see a way out of that
argument.
So I mean,
it,
it depends to a large.
Yep.
So are you saying,
I'm
trying to understand saying,
are you saying that
our,
our
estimations of the deterministic
material,
like a missionary,
a ride to find truth so that we can make
assumptions about our.
Yeah.
So,
well here,
here's another example.
You guys can think about this for a
minute if you like.
So
let's say that one of the logical
consequences of pursuing science from a
newtonian perspective is that you learn
how to create cross ebola with small
pox,
which is what the kgb was trying to do
it in the 19 eighties.
Okay.
So you manage that and everyone dots.
It's like,
how's that for a validation of science?
No,
it's like,
because this could happen,
right?
Our,
our technological capability which is
fostered by this particular model could
easily enable us to produce something
that will wipe all of this out.
And then.
Well are you going to say,
well yeah.
Apart from that it was right.
And,
and then I think,
well it's a tricky argument because
okay.
So let's say
here's,
here's part of the problem.
And I also thought the same thing about
hydrogen bonds.
It's like,
well obviously the quantum view let's
say is accurate because if you follow
it,
you can make a hydrogen bomb,
but then you can step back from that and
you can say,
yeah,
yeah.
but the thing is to make a hydrogen bomb
or to cross ebola with smallpox,
you have to treat the matter that you're
interacting with as if it's actually
separate from everything else.
And the thIng is it's not actually
It's actually connected to everything
else.
Now you can say,
well,
if you treat it as if it's separate,
here's some operations you can
undertake.
You can cross ebola with smallpox,
but then you've ignored a bunch of
things like maybe that's not a good
idea.
And then everyone dies.
And so the reduction is in the model
which helps it specify its target and
increase its accuracy.
has the corresponding negative
consequence of pretending that the
context within which these enterprises
are being conducted can be ignored and
that that's actually appropriate.
And that's a big problem.
It's a big problem
framework.
Well,
it's it.
It's not only,
it's not only because of what it
provides us.
I think the reason that the evolutionary
perspective has to be the one that
supersedes is because you cannot model
the environment.
It's not possible.
All you can do is keep up with it.
And the only way you can keep up with it
is through darwinian processes.
Random.
I mean,
I know it's not a complete theory,
but for the sake of argument,
you have to generate random alterations
and you know,
you say,
well,
in principle we could understand
everything scientifically.
It's like,
no,
in principle we can't.
Everything's too complex to understand
that's right.
Confined
that it's,
it's,
it's more in line with reality.
Yeah.
Well,
and and you,
when john was talking about the origin
of the scientific mindset and he traced
its development back to alchemy,
here's another reason why the scientific
mindset is necessarily nested in the
mythological mindset.
So whAt the outcome is we're trying to
do was to mess around wIth matter and to
produce something they argued for
centuries over what this thing was,
this philosopher's stone and what the
philosophers stone would enable the
holder of it to do would be to transmute
elements into gold.
So that would make you rich and it would
provide
immortality and perfect health for the,
for the person who discovered it.
Okay?
Now what young said,
it's,
we'll talk about this.
If I have enough energy,
we'll talk about thIs two thirds of the
way through the class because it's so
damn complicated that some years I can't
muster up enough energy to to discuss
it,
but
you don't believe that,
you know,
people have always been trying to cope
with their mortality rate and their
vulnerability.
okay,
fine.
That makes perfect sense.
And so he did an analysis of western
history,
roughly speaking and said,
well,
what happened?
There was a christian app poc maybe that
lasted about 1600 years roughly
speaking.
And there was an idea at the base of it
and the,
the,
the idea was that through spiritual
discipline,
man could transcend suffering,
but there was a problem with that was
that all this suffering kept happening,
you know,
and,
and there was some warps in the idea
because as nature pointed out,
while this
seizing of suffering was only going to
happen after you die and okay,
fine,
that's,
then you're,
you live forever in blast.
But still there's like black plague and
babies dying and crops failing and he
just doesn't seem that you can just
Ignore that.
And so you've got 15,
16,
hundred years of christianity,
you know,
and the whole history of christianity
behind that,
grinding away on this problem,
trying to produce a system of redemption
and it and it doesn't work or it works
partially and,
and it also ignores certain things.
So partly what it ignores,
you know,
one of the presuppositions of say,
medieval christianity,
is that the world roughly speaking,
is an evil place and that matter is
corrupt and unworthy of attention.
Well,
one of young's hypoThesis is that if you
ignore something long enough,
then it starts to demand your attention,
you know,
it's like a re repression and then,
and that's especially the case if
there's a problem that you're trying to
solve,
that your current worldvIew really isn't
solving.
It's like your attention is going to be
drawn unconsciously to that which you've
ignored and put down.
And so yom saw the development of
alchemy as a parallel to the development
of christianity.
But alchemy studied matter,
which was for being in a sense,
it was damned from the christian
perspective,
the alchemists we're studying,
the transmutation of matter.
They had an intuition that there was
information locked in that in matter and
that if you could just figure out how to
interact with it property,
then you could free up the information
and they symbolize that in a dream like
manner that dreamlike manner was you
could discover the philosopher's stone
and that would give you,
you know,
wealth,
health and eternal life.
Well,
as far as human was concerned,
that was a century's long dream and it
was,
it was like an artistic production.
It wAs like the.
It was the scaffolding of the scientific
perspective because it doesn't like
people went from medIeval christianity
to full fledged scientists and like
overnight it took hundreds of years for
this to occur and there were,
there were changes in the substrata of
thought that were occurring.
As this was happening,
you trace that back more than 1600 years
in the development of alchemy.
And so the dream of alchemy was that you
could discover,
you could master the transmutation of
matter such that there'd be no disease,
that no one would die and everyone was
wealthy.
Well,
okay.
That as far as young was concerned,
that provided the motivation for science
because one of the things you might ask
is,
well,
why do people do science?
I mean,
most people never have,
right?
It's not very old,
600 years.
It only emerged in one place.
Roughly speaking.
It's very fragile and not.
And plus just think of what you have to
do if you're a scientist,
you know,
if you're a scientist and use a
microscope,
a high powered microscope,
you have to spend 10,000 hours looking
through that damn thing before you can
see what's there.
And so you think that's a weird thing
for a tree dwelling ape to be doing,
you know,
you know what I mean?
It's such a war pub.
our natural of our natural instincts and
our,
you know,
our desire to make contact with other
people and to be doing something
exciting and you're looking through this
damn too,
you know,
and it's even painful.
What the hell is motivating you?
And the answer would be,
well you think you're doing something
good.
You think that science is going to
benefit mankind.
So it's nested necessarily in a
motivational system.
It isn't that you do science because you
want to discover facts,
it's that you do science to discover
facts so that things improve isn't it,
and you just,
you just kind of ignore the fact that
you're doing it in the hopes that thing
will,
things will improve.
You can't just take that out of the
equation and say,
no,
I'm purely objective.
It's like,
hey,
you're not and you better not be,
you know,
because a purely objective person
wouldn't be a person you couldn't even
communicate with someone like that.
Plus they wouldn't be able to.
Someone like that wouldn't be able to
determine what was relevant.
Just distinguish what was relevant from
what wasn't relevant.
If you need motivational systems to do
that,
and I can tell you when you're looking
at a data set,
there's an infinite number of things
that you can,
that you can look at in that data set.
Literally.
I mean there's no end to the statistical
procedures that you can,
that you can implement.
It's like fiddling,
fiddling with a photo in photoshop.
It's like,
man,
you can fiddle with that damn thing for
the rest of your life.
And so what that means is that the
complexity that's there can't be dealt
with objectively because if you deal
with it objectively,
there is no way of separating the one
path through the data from all the other
millions of paths through the data.
It's not like when you're doing
statistics,
man,
it's not like you take a bunch of
numbers and you feed it through a meat
grinder.
Outcome results like it is absolutely
nothing like that.
You're making ethical choices at every
single level of the decision.
And you know,
if you're,
am I teach my students this too,
so I want them to be straight scientists
and there's lots of things that can work
you as a scientist and one can be.
You want to have a career.
And then the other is that you want to
climb up the dough,
the primate,
the scientists,
primate dominance hierarchy and you
know,
fair enough,
you need to have a career and maybe the
ambition,
it's worth it.
But the problem with that is that that
can make you do things that violate the
principles of the entire enterprise.
And that's happening.
I mean it's been scandalous particularly
in social psychology because people do
what's called data mining and they just
keep doing their analysis till something
significant pops up and then they write
a story about why that's important.
And like,
I'm not cynical about that.
I understand why it happens.
I think it's inevitable that it happened
some because lots of people who are
publishing,
it's like the first bloody finger,
second thing they've ever published.
They don't know whAt they're doing,
you know?
so there's going to be error like map.
But I,
what I tell my students,
look,
if you're going to do statistical
analysis properly,
you have to get yourself oriented.
What the hell are you do it?
What is it that you're really doing?
And you think,
well,
I'm trying to discover something solid.
And the reason I'm trying to do that is
because there should be benefits from
that.
Otherwise the whole enterprise is
foolish and you might as well be a
bloody.
You might as well go work in finance if
you're not interested in that because
you really,
you're not going to make any money as a
scientist and you can make lots of money
in finance and you're smart enough to go
into finance.
So if that's what you want,
if you want power and money,
and I'm not complaining about that,
it's like goal where it is,
but science isn't it?
If you want to discover facts maybe,
and that may be of some benefit at some
point,
then you become a scientist.
Okay?
So that you've got to keep your eye on
the ball and then you have to decide if
pursuing that line of truth and benefit
supersedes whatever you might do to
build your career.
Okay?
Because you're always playing that game.
Oh,
it's your whole life.
And that's actually why so much of
scientific research is wrong if there's
an error too,
and there's all sorts of other reasons
and you can't expect the system to do
much better than produced five percent
of useful output anyways.
So.
Okay,
and then the other thing is you have to
also be afraid and here's what you
should be afraid of.
Let's say you discover something that
isn't there.
Okay,
then you're going to spend your next 15
years studying it.
So if you want to spend your next 15
years studying this thing that you've
conjured out of nothing,
then go right ahead.
But if you don't want to do that,
then you better be properly oriented
when you do your statistical analysis
and that's because statistical analysis
is an ethical process and so it's
science because it's,
it has to be.
If it isn't nested inside ethics,
fundamentally then it who god only
knows.
it could be completely destructive.
It could be counterproductive.
Like so.
Oh.
so then there's a variety of reasons why
that darwinian bucket is sort of the
outside.
It's the outside.
You don't get any farther out than that
as far as I can tell.
So.
And it's the darwinian world too,
which were adaptive,
you know,
that's why we perceive things as
threats.
That's why we perceive things as
positive.
negative,
you know,
when we tend to think that those are
overlays on a deeper reality,
it's like that is not so clear and you
know,
I didn't know this,
but when I was working out these ideas,
I'd never,
I'd never read anything that heidegger
had written.
Although you know,
his influences wormed its way into many
fields and I undoubtedly picked up some
of his ideas because they get embedded
in other places,
but certainly one of heidegger's claims
was the western philosophy got off on
the wrong foot right at the beginning
because he didn't study being it started
to think about thought and what's the
real issue is being and what is being
well being is what you experience and
for the high to ian's.
That's,
that's realIty.
There isn't a reality underneath that.
Now requires a real shift in perspective
to start to try to think that way.
And I think the easiest way to do it is
to think both ways.
You know,
sometimes you think like a newtonian,
fair enough and then other times you
don't.
And you need to know when to think.
Like an antonio and when to think like
someone who understands that the
phenomena of meaning that surround us
are legitimate and it's a very
interesting thing and this is one of the
things that's really driven me through
this material is okay,
so we can make a case that like lord or
meanings are real.
Like if you perceive a bear or a cliff
as a threat,
then that's so you don't die.
And it's worked really well for things
that have been chased by bears for ever
since there's been bears and,
and wavy before that.
So,
but then there's another question that
emerges.
Okay,
so here's the question.
So you've got all these underlying
motivational systems that are built into
you as a consequence of evolutionary
processes.
So let's say it's your body and the
manifestation of your body in your,
in your brain and your mind,
your,
it's your,
it's your basic mammalian wiring.
And it's been.
You'd been working on that ever since.
We've had nervous system's a very,
very long period of time.
So that sets you up.
Now you have to add complexity to that,
right?
Because when you're trying to.
Or because those systems only have a
finite time range,
so when you're angry,
for example,
you're angry right now and in fact,
part of the utility of angry is that
it's right now because it's a problem
solving mechanism for dealing with some
obstacle that you can't get rid of any
other way than to say to hell with the
future,
roughly speaking and deal with it right
now.
Now it's dangerous obviously,
but it's also necessary because
otherwise you get.
Maybe you get locked into an argument
and you just stand there arguing for the
rest of your life.
You know,
at some point you say,
I'm not talking to you anymore,
and the anger does that makes you
impulsive and you can walk away,
you know,
and sometimes that's the right
conclusion to an argument.
You don't get a when you don't want to
keep arguing.
So why do you stop?
You get annoyed.
It's a solution.
They got all these basic biological
systems.
Now obviously no one of them has that
answer and you know that because if it
did,
you wouldn't need a bunch of them and
you have a whole bunch of them.
You have pain and anxiety and
exploration and play and sexuality and
hunger and thirst and you know you can
come up with probably 12 basic emotional
and motivational systems.
Okay,
so you need all 12 of those in order to
orient yourself properly in the world,
just like you need your five senses,
but then another problem starts to
emerge in that problem is okay,
those things have to be regulated
properly,
but they have to be regulated across
multiple spans of time and then they
have to be regulated across multiple
different complexities of social
environment.
So you don't just have one system of 12.
Now you have a very large number of
cyst,
so 12 for very long spans of time and so
then you think,
well out of that emerges a solution.
We talked about that already with the
evolution of games.
Out of that emerges a solution.
You might think about those as higher
order meanings.
So when you're,
you know that and you do it and you
believe it.
That's the thing.
That's cool.
So here you are in university.
While you ask yourself why you might
think,
well,
what do you have to believe in order to
be in university?
Well,
at some point your beliefs run out and
you're just here because you've made
that decision.
But I could ask you,
you know,
why are you were in university and most
people have about five reasons and then
they,
then they don't know what to say.
So what,
what that means is they have reason a
and reasonably and reasons see and
reasonably and then they're just acting
it out after that.
And if you keep questioning them,
they get perturbed and they'll get
annoyed.
Sometimes they'll cry,
sometimes they'll get angry.
Like if you're ready to go in after
someone's like,
what the hell are you up to and why?
You know,
sometimes you have to do that to
untangle something very complex.
At some point people just get angry or
they cry and that means to hell with you
or you're bullying me,
leave me alone.
And that's supposed to get rid of you.
You know,
but it doesn't work if you really want
to get down to the answer.
Well,
partly what we're trying to figure out
is why the hell are you in university?
You know,
you might say,
well,
to get a job,
but I might say,
well,
why in the world would that make you
satisfied with life?
What?
Why do you think that would make you
satisfied with life?
And you might say,
well,
it's better than not having a job.
It's like,
yeah,
fair enough.
All right,
let's not forget the practical,
but it isn't the solution.
It's part of asp solution and then the
question is,
do you really believe that there's a
solution while you might ask because you
believe it enough so that you're here
and then you believe that has something
to do with the ability to think and you
have.
You believe that that has something to
do with the necessity of understanding
your history and you believe that it has
something to do with the,
with the,
with the utility of exposing yourself to
what in principle are great rate.
Historical and literary works.
You assume that that's all valid because
even if it's implicitly,
if it's implicitly,
it just means you're imitating someone
who assumes all that,
but either way,
here you are,
you're doing something.
And the question is,
and maybe this is the credit,
I think this was the critical question
of the 20th century.
Is there any reality to what you're
doing or is it just arbitrary?
If it's arbitrary,
well,
you know that's,
that's a path denialism because who
cares what you do.
You're your,
whatever you do,
you're rude and you can make a strong
case for that,
you know,
but the problem with that seems to be
that nihilism.
Try it for awhile.
You know,
it's what it produces is misery and
people generally believe in misery and
they genuinely believed that it's not a
good thing to have.
And so I would say nihilism is a self
defeating proposition.
If you assume that misery is actually a
source of valid information and you all
do because you know if,
uh,
if someone's jabbing you with the pen,
you're going to move your arm because
you feel that if you can avoid some
misery,
that's a good thing.
So you have faith in your experience at
that level.
Well then you might say,
well,
you know,
if you can,
if you can really make a solid case for
the believability of certain kinds of
experiences that they're real,
why can't you make a case for their
believability of higher forms of
meaning?
Maybe they're not arbitrary,
we don't know,
but I tell you,
if you act like they're arbitrary,
you get into trouble very,
very rapid because you either become
nihilistic or halfway down the trip,
denial this nihilism.
You adopt some horrible etiology and
then you know you're possessed by it and
then you're,
well then you're,
you're not going to live your own life
because you'll live the life of the
ideology and you're going to be
dangerous to everyone around you and
also impervious to any sort of
reasonable communication.
So if those are the two consequences of
making the presumption of arbitrary
meaning at a higher order level,
then to me they've invalidated
themselves already.
We've already had that experiment,
it didn't work.
And so then the question is,
well,
what's next?
Well,
that's partly what we're trying to
figure out right now.
So let's take a break until 3:15.