Yeah.
So I want to talk about some more
attributes of this structure.
Okay.
Now,
broadly speaking,
what we're going to say is that a
motivation sets up one of these
frameworks.
I'm going to call this framework a
story.
Nope.
There's a lots of things you could call
it.
You can call it an expectancy model.
You could call it a game.
I'm going to call it a story,
and we're going to say,
well,
what you do is you,
you have a life story and your life
story is composed of nested some
stories.
You could also think of it as a
personality,
but a story is like a personality
action.
So we'll just stick with story.
The story has a starting place.
That's where you are,
and the story has an end point.
That's where you're going and you're
always in one of those stories,
or you're asleep.
So you're either pursuing something in
the real world that is a value or your
pr,
like that's directly motivated,
or you're pursuing another situation
where the reason you're pursuing it is
because it fulfills a bunch of
motivational states now and into the
future.
So that's what you're doing.
Say when you pursue a career,
and if you're not doing that,
then your mind is wandering.
And what it's doing is it's wandering
through the space of hypothetical worlds
where you could play hypothetic
hypothetical roles.
And if you're not doing that,
then you're asleep.
So you're in one of these all the time.
Now the shift and that,
that's one of the things that's quite
interesting about them.
The shift can take place on all sorts of
levels.
You can differently conceptualize the
way where are you are you can different,
we conceptualize where you're going and
you can different,
they conceptualize how you're going to
get there.
Now
I won't go into that for the moment.
So let's say you're going from point a
to point B and at the highest level of
resolution,
that means that you're acting.
And then other things that happened is
not only are you acting,
you're configuring your perceptions,
we already talked a little bit about
this.
You know what you should highlight what
you should bring your high resolution
thinking to bear on and you know what
you should ignore and what you should
ignore is those things that are likely
to remain constant as you pursue this
set of transformations and or that
aren't going to interfere with what
you're doing.
And so you just have to concentrate,
especially if you set your environment
that properly.
And that's another thing,
part of the way that people deal with
the complexity of the world is by just
not having it around,
you know?
So for example,
even if you look in this room,
a lot of things are radically simplified
so that you don't get overwhelmed.
How many of you have computers here?
Okay,
now what does your computer look like?
Keyboard screen.
What about the rest of it?
Flat.
Shiny aluminum.
Why?
Because you want to act like that's one
thing you don't want to act like it's
how many transistors are on a chip now.
Okay.
Billion or more.
A lot like they're down to molecular
size.
Those things say they're so small.
Now,
this is a really funny,
there are so small now that,
so imagine electrons reading along the
wire.
Now the weird thing about an electron is
it might be there and it might be
somewhere else.
So it's got this vague nonlocality about
it.
You know,
like maybe it's supposed to be there,
but it's actually over there.
That would happen now and then,
but the wires are so damn thin now that
there's some good probability that the
electron will be outside the wire and
that causes short circuits.
So that's quite well.
So you got quantum level complexity,
mucking up your,
your circuitry in your computer.
But look,
look,
the computer is designed this way,
right?
It's designed so you can ignore it.
The outside of it's a flat shell.
It's a low resolution image and not the
keyboard because you have to move it,
not the screen,
but everything else.
It's like flat.
The designer,
the primate designer of this computer
does not want your poor primate brain to
be overwhelmed by the fact that this
thing is incomprehensibly complex cars
are the same.
They have that nice shiny shell on them.
And so that you can just sort of low
resolution at and that's good enough.
The walls painted roughly the same
color.
Like we're doing a lot of things around
us to to reduce the sensory load.
Plus there are people beating away at
the background,
like mad,
making sure the lights stay on,
making sure the heat stays on,
you know,
making sure that you have Aaron here.
The place isn't burning down,
there aren't crazy people wondering
around here with shotguns and rifles and
like there's a lot going on so that you
can sit here and pretend that you know
enough to stay alive.
So we're also removing a tremendous
amount of complexity as a consequence of
social cooperation.
Okay,
so,
so these are all parts of the way that
you simplify the world.
You're in a radical simplification
structure.
That's the external society.
Then within that there's only certain
things you want.
And then within that there's only
certain things you can detect.
And then with it in that there's only
certain features that pop out is
necessary to contemplate in the realm
that you're dealing with.
Now,
one thing you might ask is,
well,
what time span are you usually dealing
with?
You know,
cause what the world's made of depends
on the timestamp.
And that's a tough one.
We know that it's more than one 10th of
a second,
but you can think years into the future,
right?
So I might say,
well why are you going to university?
Or I might say,
what are you doing right now?
And then the answer would be,
well,
I'm sitting in class and then the
question would be,
well why are you sitting in class?
And the answer to that would be,
well,
because I,
I want to take this course and why?
Well,
it's because I want to get my degree.
I said,
why?
Well,
because I want to be prepared for a
career and uh,
you know,
a productive and high quality life when
I get out.
Well,
why?
you know,
you can keep saying why pretty much
indefinitely.
And as you answer,
you go farther and farther out you and
timescales.
Now,
it's a tricky thing because one of the
things I might tell you,
this is a very complex cognitive problem
is,
well,
where should you stop?
Okay,
so for example,
um,
I could say to you,
do you want $100 an hour?
Do you want 50,000 years?
In 75 years you're going to think,
wow,
probably take $100 now.
Well,
how about 200 years?
It's like,
well I'm not going to be there.
I'll take the hundred bucks now let's
all,
obviously thinking out 200 years is not
that helpful.
Now you might think,
well no,
you should calculate the effects of your
actions on a,
the Va,
the fastest time spam possible and
include the largest number of people if
you're really good and calibrate it.
But the problem is you can't do the
computations cause you get,
you get this thing called combinatorial
explosion happening,
which is that it's like a chess board.
You make one move,
okay fine.
But then you could make four and then
with each of those you could make four
more.
And then with each of those you could
make four more.
And soon if you're looking 20 moves
ahead,
it's like there's so many moves that the
other person could possibly make.
That looking that far ahead is
pointless.
You can't do the computations and so we
don't know how far you should look into
the future.
It depends on how stable your
environment is,
but one month seems okay.
A year.
Yeah,
three to five years.
That's what I'll have you do when you do
the future authoring program.
20 years.
Hmm.
Probably not.
And the reason for that is the margin of
error in your prediction grows so large
that your prediction is worth anything
and you can really see how that's the
case now cause like what's going to be
like in 20 years when I was a kid,
I used to read science fiction.
It was like plausible accounts of the
potential future.
It's like now who knows?
Anything could happen.
You know,
you could be three quarters robot in 20
years.
You could have a lifespan of 10,000
I mean we just do not know.
We could be living in caves again with
everything in ruins.
We don't have a clue what's going to
happen.
So 20 year span I would say,
you know,
get friendly with computers,
20 year spans too long.
So okay.
Anyways,
what I'm,
what I'm pointing out is that you have
to calculate,
you have to calculate what you're doing
across multiple spans of time and in
that combination in combination with
many,
many people.
And that makes things very complex.
But that's how he,
that's how you're building the
structures that you live with it.
All right.
So back to this,
you're ad point a,
you're going to point b.
So you are somewhere now that's
interesting.
You are somewhat now generally what
people think about when they think about
being somewhere is that they're in a
place but you're not just in a place,
you're in a place at a time.
And I really want to stress that because
we know that universe,
we know that the environment is for
dimension,
not three dimension.
And that's important because you can,
you can be in the same place and in the
next second you're still where you were,
but you were in a completely different
place.
So,
for example,
if someone walked in here with a,
with a pistol,
this would not be the same place.
Okay?
So there's a reason I'm telling you
that.
And then there's the future and that's
also a place in time and a place in
space.
Okay,
now you're getting from one point to the
other and you're going to do that by
implementing certain behaviors.
Now you might say,
what can happen while you're doing that?
Well,
here's three things that can happen.
The thing you want that can happen,
something you don't want,
but that you understand and something
you don't understand at all.
Something completely beyond your
comprehension,
and that would generally be a
traumatizing event of some force.
So you can even know what's going to
happen or you can not know,
but still be able to cope with it or you
can not know and not cope with it and
have the negative ones,
they correspond to that hierarchy,
right?
If it's a little thing that you don't
understand,
you just modify a little behavior.
If it's a big thing that you don't
understand,
well then what?
Well then everything falls apart.
You don't know where you are,
don't know where you're going and all
the behaviors you have are not helpful
and that's when your world falls apart.
Okay,
so generally that doesn't happen.
So I want to walk to the,
let's say I set my target on the door,
I'm going to walk through the door.
So here's what happens instantly.
I'm slightly,
I have slight negative emotion about the
fact that any of you people in the way
exist because what my brain is doing is
reconfiguring the world to chart a
straight path and anything that's in the
way is going to make me uneasy,
frustrated,
disappointed,
anxious.
And you can think about this when you do
house designed by the way.
So when you're setting up a room,
what you want to do is figure out what
the room is for.
Then you want to clear the paths for
that because then when you walk into the
room,
the room will say,
welcome.
You can do the things you want to do
here easily.
And if you don't do that,
it's all cluttered up.
It's like
there's no difference between that and
being confused mentally.
It's exactly the same thing.
So,
okay,
so let's say now I stand up and not
works and then I walk that way.
And that way,
in that way I keep my eyes on the door
and I'm getting towards the door while
I'm more modest,
Ma moderately positive about that
because I'm getting where I'm going.
But I'm also moderately positive about
it because the fact that I'm getting
where I'm going validates my whole
theory.
So one of the things that the
behaviorists didn't get right when they
were thinking about punishment,
like if an animal lays out a behavior,
new punish,
it will stop manifesting that behavior.
But,
but that isn't all that happens.
You think about punishing a human being
and they start manifesting the behavior,
but the behavior isn't the whole damn
thing.
The thing you're in is this.
It's the whole thing.
It's a conception of where they are to
conception of where they're going and
it's all the behaviors that they might
need to get there.
So,
you know,
maybe they'll try to circumvent the
punishment,
walk around it,
maybe they'll try a few more behaviors.
But what happens,
you know,
so I'm tied by a chain and I don't know
what,
I'm tied by a chain to the wall.
I started walking that way and I figured
out that I'm chained.
Well,
so much for that stupid theory.
I'm not getting to the door.
I'm going to let that view of the world
disintegrate.
I'm going to be very upset about that.
And then I have to come up with another
one,
which might be,
well,
how do I get rid of the chain?
So when you fail,
two things happen.
The behavior that you're manifesting
doesn't work.
That's the old behavior is routine.
But it's worse than that because the
whole little personality that you're
using to construe the world falls apart.
And the more important the thing is that
has fallen apart,
the more of a catastrophe it's going to
be for you.
Okay?
So let's say you're going to medical
school.
That's what you want to do.
All right?
So you're taking the course to write the
exam,
to pass the course with an a to apply to
medical school,
to get into medical school,
to become a doctor.
You've failed the test.
What just happened?
Well,
did your whole future fall apart?
Okay,
or did you just failed the task?
Well,
who knows?
Right?
Maybe your whole future just fell apart.
It's like now you have a gpa of 3.3 it's
like,
nope,
you have to go to,
you have to go to the Caribbean to a
private medical school.
You're not going to get in anywhere in
Canada or the United States.
It's like,
okay,
so your life over,
you jump off a bridge.
Well,
sometimes people do and it's because the
little subpersonality that they created,
which is the me that will be a doctor.
It's one of these things,
a little story.
It's so integral to their entire
identity that when it collapses,
they're done and people get suicidal
when that sort of thing happens.
Okay,
so,
well,
what are you supposed to do when that
happens?
Well,
that's something that we'll talk about.
You know,
from the perspective of mental hygiene.
One of the things I would recommend is
that when things go wrong for you,
will you start at the highest level of
resolution in your hierarchy and work
upward.
You don't say,
well God,
now everything's over.
You know,
you might say,
okay,
what can I do to ensure that I do better
on the next test?
So then you could,
you could analyze your sub routines,
your micro sub routines,
like how much do you study a day?
Well,
sometimes people will tell me I study
six hours a day.
It's like,
no,
you don't.
You sit in front of what you're supposed
to be doing for six hours a day.
But if you actually study for more than
three,
I would be shocked because I've met
almost no one in my entire life who can
sustain high level concentration for
more than three hours for more six days
a week for more than a year,
you'll just burn yourself to a crisp.
So No,
you're deluding yourself into thinking
that you're studying for six hours a
day.
You'd be way better off to cut it down
to two and a half and actually do it.
Like there's micro routine analysis that
you can do,
so that might be helpful.
Then you can implement that and run it.
That's what you do.
If you're a behavioral psychologist,
hey,
someone comes and says my life's over.
And you say,
well let's go for the micro routines.
What do you mean when they say,
well I can't be a doctor?
Well,
okay,
could you be a nurse?
Would that work?
Could you be like a medical technician?
You know,
could you be,
what else could you be?
Could it be a social worker?
Et cetera.
Like okay,
so your,
your domain is helpful.
Medical type of person.
Well,
one element of that is doctor,
but it doesn't exhaust the entire realm
of possibility.
So I'd say like slacks up a bit,
you know,
it's not the only path.
And so that would be a more high level
adjustment.
That'd be more cognitive adjustment if
you were in cognitive behavioral
therapy.
It's like let's check out your sub
routines,
make you more effective at studying.
But you know,
let's loosen up your top level
abstractions.
You should be a good person.
Let's say whatever you decide that means
one element of that is be productively
employed in a way that doesn't make you
bitter and nasty.
Okay.
Doctor might be one way of solving that,
although I wouldn't be so sure about
that,
but it's not the only way of solving it.
So all right,
you go from point a to B,
you go from point a to point b and
things can happen along the way.
Things you like,
positive emotion you're getting there.
Plus you write things that produce
negative emotion,
you're not getting there.
Okay?
You can either solve them easily,
small behavioral adjustment or you have
to go up the hierarchy of value and
adjust it with the least possible
damage.
Generally speaking,
cause that's another rule of thumb in
therapy.
It's like
I can't be a doctor so I'm going to be a
an engineer.
It's like,
well no,
you've got three years behind.
You don't just throw it away,
you know,
use what you've already got and make a
minor course deviation.
If you can do it.
And you know,
maybe we could talk about broader scale
transformations,
but they're costly.
You know,
stick as close to the path as you can,
well altering it enough so that you
proceed on to your final goal.
And so,
and that leads us and they think this is
where we'll stop today.
That leads us to the next part of the
story.
So here's the kind of story that someone
can tell.
I was at point a and I went to point B
and here's how I did it.
And you're pretty happy about that
story.
Maybe you go on to youtube.
And I found this a year ago,
I had this old car and I wanted to put a
stereo in it.
And so I typed in how to put a stereo in
x old car and there was some helpful
retired southern guy who'd,
you know,
made a youtube.
And I was interested in his little story
cause I,
well he put a car stereo,
he didn't have a car stereo in his car
and he wanted one.
And I didn't have a car stereo in my
care and I wanted.
So here's a little story about how to do
that was very interesting to me.
So I ran that little tape and I did it.
It's like,
great.
Not particularly
transformation,
but good enough.
Good enough.
I got some information.
All right,
so that's an all right story.
And you're running around all the time
interfacing with other people and you're
telling them your little story and
they're telling you their little story.
But you know,
so that's one thing that interests
people,
how to do something successfully.
But in a lot of what people talk about
is something different,
which is I was trying to get from point
a to B and it didn't work and now I'm at
a place where it didn't work.
And so it's a problem,
right?
It's like the world's opened up around
me.
I don't know what to do.
And the reason you talk to people about
that is because they have brains and so
to you,
and you might as well have two brains
working on the problem if you can.
And if you're reciprocal,
you know you're in trouble.
You come to me and we talk it out,
maybe I can help.
And then because we're playing a
okay
iterative game,
now you owe me a favor.
Now you know,
I'm not going to be too restrictive
about that.
But you know,
socially intelligent people are
reciprocal.
And Ben Franklin once said,
you're new to the neighborhood.
What,
what,
what should you do to get integrated?
He said,
ask a neighbor for a favor.
A small favor.
It's right.
It's like,
don't,
will you build me a new house?
It's like,
no,
that's not gonna work.
But you know,
um,
okay,
would you watch my,
here's my is on the law.
And when you watch them for two minutes
while I run down to the corner store,
it's like,
okay,
they can do that.
Well why would you do that while it
opens up the possibility of reciprocal
exchange,
it's very,
very smart because now they can ask you
for a favor.
So you got the,
you get the train thing going.
And people who are highly social are
really good at Maine,
identifying and maintaining reciprocal
obligations.
So we use each other as problem solving
resources.
And a lot of our communication is
exactly that.
And so basically the story you're
telling isn't,
I was at point a and I went to point b
and everything worked.
The story is this.
Instead
it's half of this,
okay,
I was at point a,
that's the top left hand corner.
I was at point and I was going to point
b,
but something didn't work and then
things collapsed,
you know,
to a greater or lesser extent depending
on the severity of the event you're,
you know,
and the closeness of your friendships.
So you're telling the story,
you're not going to tell cause
catastrophic stories to someone on a bus
that you just sat down beside unless you
have a mental illness.
And sometimes,
well,
really it's the truth.
Sometimes you'll sit down on a bus and
someone who has a mental illness will
come and sit beside you and they will
immediately tell you horrible things
about their life.
And the reason for that is that they
have to,
they don't anyone to talk to,
they can't sort out their brains.
They're so desperate,
they're soul ruined any chaos.
They're so rude that they're,
that the proclivity to proclaim the
chaos absolutely overwhelms them.
And you're,
you know,
you just can't deal with someone like
that most of the time because the
magnitude of the problem they're facing
you with is way beyond your capacity to
solve.
So it's just awkward.
It's not good.
Anyways.
You say,
I was going from point a to point b
didn't work.
Now I don't know where I am.
I don't know where I'm going and I'm
lost.
And you say,
well,
I know what I experienced when I was in
a situation like this.
I did this and I know someone else who
in that situation did this.
And maybe you could try those.
Or maybe you just shut up and you let
the person talk.
And that's often extremely useful.
And the reason you do that is because
they're thinking because people think
they think,
but they don't.
They talk.
Thinking is hard,
right?
It's a very complex,
abstract cognitive operation.
And I don't think that there are many
more people who can think.
Then there are people who can really
read.
And that's probably two,
two to 5% of the population at most.
And so most of the way that people deal
with that is that they talk and that's
their thinking.
And so they have some ideas about what
might be going on,
but they're mixed and muddy.
So they're basically throwing out these
ideas,
you know,
did this happen?
Is He liked this as she liked that.
It's like,
did I do this?
and then they watch you and you know,
if you,
if you're nodding about one and they
think,
oh well,
you know,
that seems plausible and they allowed
another and you go,
you don't even notice.
And they think,
no,
that's off the table.
I didn't think that was a very good
idea.
But now I've got some social,
um,
what do you call it?
Validation.
And soon they talk it out.
And instead of having 60 vaguely defined
problems,
now they have like five fairly tightly
defined problems.
They're feeling a lot better about that,
right?
Cause it's five snakes instead of 60.
And maybe they can deal with five
snakes.
So you've already helped them a whole
bunch just by listening,
you know?
And then maybe you can be an active
listener and they lay out their story
and you say,
well,
he said something here that doesn't make
any sense with this thing that you said.
So you know,
how would you reconcile those?
And you know,
it's this dialectical process and so the
person collapses into chaos and they
come and tell you about it and then you
rescue them if you can out of the chaos
and then they pop back up the other
side.
Clinical practice as actually a
formalized version of an ideal
relationship.
So the ideal is you think,
what's an ideal relationship?
Well,
I would say it,
the ideal relationship is where both of
you are trying to get better than you
are and you're helping each other do it.
It's something like that and the lines,
because you know,
if I have a good relationship with you,
I would rather that you're the best you
you can be.
And Vice,
I would assume that you would also like
that for me.
I mean,
things interfere with that because he
might say,
well,
if,
you know,
given how horrible I am,
if if my partner of a sudden got a clue,
they'd leave.
So I bet her interfere with that as much
as I possibly can.
And people do that all the time.
You know,
one of the things they'll do is make
sure their partners and to attract it,
but you're so attracted,
why are you with someone like me?
It's like all criticized.
He wouldn't,
you look attractive and that'll fix
that.
So if people do that sort of thing all
the time,
this is the revolutionary story.
This is the real story.
People tell I was here,
I got bloody well knocked off my perch
and then for a while things were not
good.
And then,
you know,
I reconfigured myself.
I learned some things,
I did some exploration,
I made some changes and poop off the
other side.
I come and I'm a better person for it.
And if you listen to the way people talk
about their pasts,
especially with regards to traumatic
events,
they'll often tell you that.
They'll say,
well,
you know,
in retrospect,
that was the best thing that ever
happened to me.
It's like those are the people who come
out the other side,
I'll tell you,
because lots of people,
they fall into the belly of the beast
and they never come out.
You see that in fairytales sometimes say
so there'd be a hero and heal,
conquer,
some sort of dragging or some sort of
monster.
And when he cuts it open,
a bunch of people who come out,
it's like,
yeah,
they're the ones who've got swallowed by
the thing and it isn't till that person
came,
comes along and solves the problem that
all those other people get to come out.
So I have to revolutionary store.
It's the archetypical revolutionary
story and it's the story of human
progress socially,
politically,
economically,
and psychologically.
And you see that reflected.
For example,
one of the things I could tell you about
Christianity is that it's a
revolutionary narrative at the
beginning.
So if you look at the Bible structured
as a piece of literature at the
beginning there's a fall.
Everyone was doing fine.
Then they wake up and they find out that
the bottom has dropped out and then the
whole rest of this book is about,
okay,
how do you get back there?
And actually it is in this all Italian,
partly what the Bible is,
is the attempt by broadly speaking,
Western civilization.
So that would be all the way from the
Middle East,
West.
It's the west attempt to figure out
what's wrong with life and how to fix
it.
And it's,
it's,
it's the collaboration of thousands of
people over thousands of years.
Of course you can say that about any
ancient moral tradition.
So the question is,
well,
is there an answer to the question?
Well that's,
that's one of the next things we're
going to try to figure it out.
Well,
let's say,
okay,
you're,
you're driving down the floor of one car
breaks down,
you're off by the side of the road.
It's like,
that's not,
maybe it's snowing.
I was like,
how bad is that?
Well,
you don't know.
Like maybe someone slides on this.
No one runs over you with your dad.
It's really bad.
So you're freaking out.
Maybe your phone isn't working,
so can check your phone.
That's not working.
It's like all of a sudden things have
got worse.
So this person drives up behind you and
they stop.
You're a bit nervous about them because
what are they up to?
And they come up,
they opened the,
they open the hood and they say,
well this thing is loose.
And they put it in there.
It's like,
are you happy?
Well,
yes,
because what's happened to you?
It's magic.
So first of all,
you're not in a car as soon as it stops
working.
By the way,
it's only a car when it's working,
when it's not working,
it's a,
it's a bag of snakes,
right?
It's like,
oh,
this car isn't working.
What could be long wrong with it?
Oh,
an infinite number of things.
None of which I understand.
And then those things are on attached to
people who are going to fix the car and
like,
can I trust them?
Do I even know who they are?
Are they going to empty my wallet?
Do I need to have a new car?
You know?
So you don't know.
And then while your day's gone,
and then,
you know,
so all of a sudden what happens is your,
your environment complexifies radically
and you get all nervous because there's
a lot of paths in there that you might
have to traverse to get back to where
you're going.
Someone comes along and goes tap.
It's like you're happy.
It's all the complexity has collapsed
and the one path and Poof,
you're poof,
your story is now implementable again.
And you'll pay people for that.
You do it all the time.
It's like you got a problem,
you take it to an expert and they say,
well,
it take you an infinite amount of time
to traverse all these possible paths.
So you're basically screwed.
But if you give me $100,
I can tell you how to do it in five
minutes.
You think,
yes,
that's worth it.
So,
so,
you know,
of course it's efficient.
That's why we trade.
It's exactly why we trade.
It's like things are gonna go wrong with
you that I could help and vice versa.
What a deal.
That's partly why we're social and why
we maintain it.
Like,
as a collective,
we're way more intelligent than we would
be,
you know,
as one person.
So,
all right,
that's a revolutionary story.
That's a collapse into the underworld
and rebirth.
And so as soon as you know that,
it's so cool to know that because now
whenever you read a classic story of any
sort,
you can think,
oh,
that's a voyage to the underworld.
I've been there and you have,
everyone's been there.
The underworld is where that's chaos.
It's chaos.
It's where you go when your life falls
apart.
It has a structure.
And what's even cooler about that is
once you know this,
there's actually guides through it.
It's like,
okay,
your world fell apart.
What do you do about it?
Well,
dying of stress is a bad idea.
You don't have to do that.
So I was talking to one of the students
during break and uh,
we were talking about character and I
said,
well,
the best thing you could do is build
your character.
Here's a test of character.
It's like a family members dying.
Okay,
are you useful or useless?
That's the first question.
And then a deeper question is,
do you make it as good as it can be,
which isn't going to be that good by the
way?
Or do you turn it into hell because he
can,
and lots of people do.
So one of the tests of character is,
okay,
there's a crisis.
Like,
really?
Are you going to respond?
Are you going to be helpful?
Are you going to be useless?
Or even worse,
are you gonna make it worse?
I would say helpful.
And the thing that's so cool about human
beings is that we can do that.
People are so tough,
it's insane as long as they put
themselves in a position.
My sister in law works is a palliative
care nurse.
It's like all she does is work with
people who are going to die at two
weeks.
Like she's a happy person,
partly cause she goes home and thinks,
hey,
this isn't a palliative care ward.
Well really man,
you know,
things can be worse.
So,
and she knows that and she's reminded of
it every day.
It's like that's a person who does not
take things for granted.