There'll be an exam on Thursday,
I presume it'll be multiple choice.
Like the last one was,
um,
you've already taken one exam,
so you kind of have some idea about what
they're like.
So,
um,
it'll be here,
like the last one was,
um,
and this lecture will be covered.
So.
Okay.
So we talked a little bit about
motivation last time or quite a bit
about motivation and what I,
I told you that I was basically teach
you,
teaching you a personality,
neuroscience approach to personality.
And um,
part of the reason that I have to go
into the biology to give you is to give
you the kind of foundation that you need
in order to understand,
I would say what's essentially the
cutting edge in personality research.
You know,
I mean,
I know that what we're going,
what we covered last lecture and what
we're going to cover today are
relatively complicated.
But if you get them right,
then you're right at the forefront of,
of,
of our ideas about brain function and
emotion and about personality.
So you get all that at the same time.
And today you'll get a little bit of
learning theory thrown in as well.
So the learn learning theory is
basically what used to be,
what's what's alternatively described as
behaviorism.
And I don't,
I used to teach behaviorism in this
class,
but I've subsumed it underneath the
biology because the old be a lot of the
old behavior of presuppositions,
although they were extremely useful.
We're not right is,
which is exactly what you'd expect.
They were formulated in the 1950s.
Um,
and it's actually the sign of the
progress of a science that theories that
are 60 years old or no longer.
Right.
So,
um,
we'll also cover a little bit of
behavioral theory today too.
So,
okay.
So the hypothesis we've been working on
so far,
or we'll call it the working theory,
is that motivations set goals or more
accurately that they defined a
conceptual space within which you
perceive the world and within which you
act towards some goal and,
or to some endpoint and the endpoint in
some sense as specified by the
motivational system.
It's a hypothalamic system are often,
but not always,
but not only is the goal specified but
they,
the underlying motivational systems also
tune your perception.
So you're only looking at the things
that you know to be relevant to the
pursuit of that goal.
And they also either disinhibit or
activate the behavioral schemes that you
would normally use to pursue the goal.
And sometimes those are the,
let's say the motor schemes cause that
would be more accurate.
When you think about behavior,
you tend to think about voluntary
behavior,
but a motivational state will disinhibit
or activate depending on the situation,
autonomic responses.
So for example,
when you,
when you were food deprived and you
start to think about food and start to
organize your behavior towards food as
an end and to perceive the world that
way,
your body also prepares for.
And so the motivational state is an all
encompassing psychophysiological
phenomena.
It's not something as simple as chain
behavior,
which was an early be behavioral theory
or as simple as something that's merely
setting a goal.
It's much more complicated than that.
It's,
it's useful to think about as we've
already talked about with regards to
psychodynamic theory,
it's useful to think about a motivated
state as a micro personality.
I mean it's,
it's got one aim in mind fundamentally.
So it's,
it's not particularly sophisticated,
but it has all the other elements of a
personality.
So now,
so motivation establishes the framework
within which goals are pursued and the
goal itself,
and then roughly speaking emotions or at
least many of the motions track progress
towards goals.
And so they kind of tell you whether
you're on the right tracker or not.
So that's a reasonable way of
distinguishing them.
Even though there is no single
motivation system or a single emotion
system,
there's some basic motivations.
These are the sorts of things that Freud
would have associated fundamentally with
Id.
So,
and he thought of those as primordial
and that's exactly right because pretty
much all of these motivational systems
we share certainly with other people
also with other mammals.
And then of course with animals that are
farther down the evolutionary chain than
mammals.
So some of these systems are
extraordinarily old.
In fact,
all of them are extraordinarily old
hunger,
consequence of food deprivation,
obviously thirst.
Obviously people are very dependent on
water.
Pain,
pain's complicated.
There's,
there's physical pain and then there's
it's mental equivalents and the mental
equivalents of pain are grief,
disappointment,
frustration,
roughly speaking.
And so you can,
the way you can think about that as you,
you know,
you saw the picture of the nervous
system that I showed you last time with
the branches going up into the brain
obviously,
but with all the branches or the roots
say going down into the body.
So we discussed the central nervous
system as a sort of all encompassing
system distributed throughout the body.
Imagine that part of that network
throughout your body is associated with
pain reception and that would be roughly
equivalent to systems registering levels
of input that are high enough to
potentially damage them.
That's,
that's where pain seems seems to come in
and that different pieces of that can be
activated at different times.
So if it's psychological pain,
as I said,
grief,
frustration,
disappointment seems to fall into that
category.
Uh,
loneliness as another one.
Um,
then maybe it's primarily the cortical
circuitry for paying that's activated.
Although people who are depressed,
for example,
or who are grieving often have somatic
pain as well.
And depression really looks like it's a
pain state.
Um,
we know loneliness is because if you
take like little chicks or little
kittens and you make them loan and
they'll cry,
you know,
which is,
uh,
or,
or peep if their chicks,
and you can stop them from doing that by
using opiates.
And it's not because it stops them from
vocalizing.
Cause that would be a possibility.
Just get them so stoned on,
you know,
morphine that they can't peep.
And you think,
well they're now they're,
they're not lonesome anymore sites.
The experiments have been done carefully
enough to factor out the effect of the
opiates on the vocalization.
So,
and that's also led to some suspicion
that people who have have had to have a
history of extraordinarily painful
personal relationships might be those
who are more prone to opiate use.
And so opiates,
analgesics are,
they basically dampen out pain and
frustration and disappointment and grief
and loneliness.
So there's an anger and aggression
system.
It's complicated.
There's probably two of them.
One is defensive aggression,
that's probably more associated with
neuroticism.
Technically.
The others probably predatory aggression
and you know,
human beings are definitely predators
were meat eaters and you know,
uh,
our closest relatives,
chimpanzees for example,
they're,
they're pretty good hunters.
They,
they'll,
they'll pack,
gathered together and packs and bring
down 30 pound colobus monkeys and,
and the meat is very popular among the
chimps.
And so predatory aggression seems to be
a separate circuit.
And as we'll discuss further along,
I think the predatory aggression circuit
and the maternal solicitude circuit,
because there's also a care circuit have
evolved to be at opposite ends of the
same distribution.
I think that's the agreeableness
distribution in the big five.
So on one end there's maternal
solicitude and the other end,
there's predatory aggression.
And you could imagine how those things
have to inhibit one another.
Um,
because well with,
with many mammals,
bears for example,
the males are so predatory that you have
to keep them away from the cubs because
they'll kill them.
You human beings.
I mean there's some aggression towards
children,
especially if the children aren't
biological relatives,
but men are pretty caring for male
mammals and women are actually quite
predatory for male mammals.
So thermal regulation,
your hypothalamus takes care of whether
you're hot or cold,
panic and escape that those are circuits
that also seem to be associated with
with pain fundamentally.
Although threat can maybe trigger them
as well,
and the panic escape system doesn't
exactly seem to be the same system as
the anxiety and fear system.
Even though they sound they sound
roughly equivalent,
right?
You might think of panic as just the
extreme level of fear.
I think fear can trigger panic,
but panic seems to be a more primordial
circuit and if you're panicking,
there's an immense impetus to to escape.
So that's a different circuit
affiliation of care.
We covered sexual desire,
exploration and play.
Both of those seem to be separate
circuits,
so Jaak,
Panksepp,
Jaak Panksepp actually who wrote a great
book called an affect of neuroscience.
By the way,
if any of you are interested in like the
psychobiology of behavior and
motivation,
Jaak Panksepp book is one of the best,
I don't have a paper by him in,
in our collection,
but he's a very smart guy.
He wrote this book called affective
neuroscience and it's actually given its
title and the relative complexity of its
of its thoughts.
It's actually quite readable even though
it's a text,
it's a little more personal than your
typical texts.
Might be.
An panksepp is also very interested in a
psychodynamic and personality idea.
So he's a very broad thinker.
And so if you're interested in,
you know,
uh,
an approach to psychology that sort of
crosses the threshold from personality
into emotion and biology Panksepp as
well as gray.
There's a great paper that you're
reading.
Panksepp's are very,
very good source.
He's a very,
he discovered the play circuit for
example.
Um,
and he also discovered that rats laugh.
So if you take a rat,
it laughs.
You can't hear it though because it
laughs ultrasonically like a bat.
But if you record the rat giggling and
then slow down the tape,
then you can tell that the rat laughs.
Rats need to play in.
Most mammals need to play in order to
uh,
socialize them.
So,
so one of the things you can think about
this when your parents do,
and this is probably especially relevant
for the man cause one of the things you
might ask is what role do men play in
the socialization of children?
And one thing that men really do seem to
do with kids is to engage in rough and
tumble play,
especially once they're a little older
than to say two to five or something.
And kids love that.
They absolutely love rough and tumble
play gets them so excited that you know,
they get out of control.
Fundamentally rough and tumble play is
an excellent mode of socialization
because it teaches the child that just
the distinction between aggression and
too much aggression,
right?
Cause if you're wrestling with the kid,
the kid has to keep their behavioral
output under a fair degree of control to
keep the game going,
to make it rough enough to be exciting.
But not so rough that they get hurt or
you know,
that they stick their thumb in their
dad's I or something like that.
And you can think of that from a
Piagetian sense too because it's a game.
But imagine that if you're trying to
figure out how to configure yourself
around other people,
if you haven't had that rough and tumble
play,
you don't really know where the
boundaries of your body are,
you know?
And,
and you don't know how much you can take
and how much you can be stretched and
how much you can be thrown around and
when something actually hurts rather
than this frightening.
And so all of that intense sort of play
that,
um,
that boys in particular are likely to
engage in all the girls also.
Like,
it
seems to be very useful for teaching
children about to engage with the world,
but,
and with other people in a physical way.
And that's one of the physiological
foundations for higher order
socialization.
So it's very useful.
I mean I've,
I've often noted the children who
haven't had the opportunity to engage in
physical play.
They're kind of awkward,
you know,
they,
they're not,
they're not seated well in their body
and it's like they're kind of vague
physically.
Whereas the ones who've been twisted
around and Banton thrown up in the air
and you know,
wrestled in general,
there are a lot more conscious of their
limits and their abilities and their
body and they're also much more able to
invite other kids to play.
You can think about this with regards to
dogs.
You know,
if you have a dog,
you know the dog,
you can tell when the dog wants to play.
Right.
What does the dog do?
Yeah,
yeah.
It jumps around and it puts its rear end
in the air often and its head down,
it looks up,
which is a little bit submissive and a
little bit friendly and it wags its
tail.
It might bark and it moves back and
forth and like little kids that want to
play do well.
They don't put their tails in the air
obviously,
but they,
they,
they engage in like play invitation
behaviors like that,
you know,
a little bit of teasing sometimes and
they were trying to get some play
initiated down.
It's also practice for later dominance
when chimps play the males in particular
as they approach adolescence,
the play behavior cause they'll all,
they'll throw sticks at the old chimps
who were laying down and sleeping or
come up and poke them or tease them.
And then as they become more and more
powerful and more and more adolescents
say you need to at all,
because I did not play will become full
blown dominance challenges as you don't
no doubt noticed if you were in junior
high school because that's exactly what
happens to teachers,
right?
The little elementary school kids,
they're kind of cute when they
misbehave.
There's sort of playful but by the time
grade eight or grade nine comes around,
the pushing on the teacher is a lot
harder.
And so you can see how play shades into
dominance dispute.
But it is a separate circuit exploration
that's a separate circuit.
And one of the things that we'll talk
about today is Swanson's elaboration of
the fact that half of the hypothalamus
is fundamentally devoted towards
exploration,
which is quite cool.
It means exploration is a really,
really,
really old system and it's sort of like
if you haven't got anything else to do
so you don't want to play,
you're not hungry,
you're not thirsty,
you're not angry,
you're not too warm or too cold,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Your default isn't sort of quiescent
sleep,
right?
You don't just
run out of batteries and lie on the
floor unless you're of course,
obviously,
unless you're very tired.
What will generally happen is if the
other fundamental motivational states
have been satiated,
then you'll engage in exploration and
some different people at different
rates.
If you're an extroverted,
you'll engage in exploration in the
social environment and if you're open,
then engage in exploration at a more
cognitive level.
So that would be with regards to
artistic creativity or to fiction or,
or the expression of some sort of
intellectual or philosophical pursuit.
And the reason that you're wired up that
way is because if you have a little
extra energy,
you might as well use that to map out
more of the environment so that when
push comes to shove,
somewhere down the road you'll be in
possession of more information and more
flexible and more knowledgeable in your,
in your,
in your conceptual and perceptual
structures and also in your actions.
So people have a pretty strong tendency
to default to exploration,
but there's variability in that.
Um,
you can also sort of divide up these
motivations as ingestive or defensive.
That's not a bad way of looking at it.
And then there's reproductive
motivations as well.
That's unlikely to be a full map.
It kind of depends on where you put the
emotions because we know,
for example,
that there's a separate discussed
circuit and that doesn't seem to load
with anxiety or with pain.
It's,
it's,
it's its own biological
system and it seems to be associated
with trait conscientiousness maybe and
also with political conservatism in
orderliness.
So those things are all quite
interesting.
We all kind of clumped together and,
but whether that's an emotion or
motivations,
not exactly clear,
but um,
we'll talk about it a little bit more.
So there's the hypothalamus and as you
can see,
um,
it's not one thing.
Of course,
nothing at the macro level in the brain
is one thing.
Obviously it's this layered thing just
like everything else in the world except
even more so because the brain is so
incredibly complicated.
And you can see by looking at that
there's all those little,
all the things that are colored.
They're basically hypothalamic,
um,
modules I guess would be a reasonable
way of putting it.
And you can tell they're even an
anatomically distinct,
so obviously they're not doing exactly
the same thing.
So you might think of brain anatomy as
sort of a fixed,
what would you call something that we've
already managed quite well.
And we have all the categories.
Systems down in the structure of the
brain is quite well known.
And that's really not true at all.
Like the brain is truly terra incognita
and it isn't even like our naming a
rituals let's say,
or conventions are not necessarily
appropriate for one to one mapping of
say structure onto function.
So,
um,
they're,
they're sort of anatomical,
they're markers for anatomical
convenience in some ways.
Okay.
So,
so here's a way of thinking about it.
So you have your frame which specifies
your lack.
Say I'm hungry and then a goal pops up,
which is,
well I should have something to eat.
And the hypothalamus is modulating
perceptual and cognitive circuits so
that you think that and so that you
start to up the world into a place where
a hungry person like you could become
satisfied and then the behaviors kick in
that are relevant to that,
um,
pursuit.
And so you can think of yourself as
popping through these sorts of frames on
a fairly sick like basis throughout the
day.
You know,
obviously you get hungry,
you get thirsty,
you get tired.
And so your consciousness is being
modulated by subcortical circuitry that
is basically charged with your self
preservation.
And in some ways you come along for the
ride.
I mean your consciousness is mostly
there in some sense to detect deviations
from not so much expectation but from
desire,
right?
Because you lay out one of these little
maps on the world and then you want
something to happen and what your
consciousness does more or less is more
monitor and if something that you don't
want to happen happens,
then consciousness will take a look.
In some sense.
You remember that hierarchy of goals
that I showed you from,
you know,
motor output up to high order goals.
Your consciousness kind of moves up and
down that thing.
If you've made an error trying to figure
out at which level of abstraction that
error should be rectified,
which is sort of what you do when you
think,
and so that process is going to kick in
whenever you're moving towards your
desired end and something that you don't
want to have happen happens,
right.
Do you usually stop that sort of an Eng
anxiety response?
The stopping and then if nothing else
happens,
that's too bad.
Well then you'll,
you'll start to explore it in,
animals often do that by moving around,
but people will do that just as with
with equal facility just by running
simulations in their mind and trying to
calculate what went wrong.
Right.
To try to think about it.
That's a form of exploratory behavior as
well that would be more associated with
trait openness and with intelligence.
So,
so there's how m Swanson divides up the
hypothalamus see the a little pink
things there on the left are part of the
defensive circuits.
And then the red things on the laughter
part of the reproductive circuits.
And you know,
obviously those,
the fact that those circuits exist lays
onto Darwinian theory quite nicely.
The defensive circuits obviously protect
you from dying and the reproductive
circuits,
you know,
facilitate your reproduction,
which is not much of a
fairly obvious conclusion.
Okay.
And so those are all located in this,
in this,
you know,
essential part of the brain,
the hypothalamic hypothalamus.
Now this is something little that's a
little more complex.
So I'll go through it a little bit more
carefully.
So if you look on the right,
right,
this is where Swanson perfectly onto
piaget and I put this once in paper in
as a optional reading,
but if you're interested in the sorts of
things that we're covering this class,
that's a great paper to hack your way
through even though it's very hard
because you learn a lot about the
underlying biology of some of these more
complex clinical and developmental
theories that we've covered.
So basically what Swanson is pointing
out is that at the lowest level,
at the highest resolution level of your
central nervous system,
your your,
you have motor output circuits that are
enabling you to move and those are
communicating in large part with your
spine but also with lower parts of your
brainstem.
So those are fundamental movements of
the sorts that piaget would call
reflexive.
And then the locomotor pattern
generator.
I think the best way to think about this
from an analogical perspective,
and actually Alexander Luria used this
analogy,
he called behavioral patterns,
kinetic melodies.
And it's a lovely phrase say,
because you know how obviously a song is
made out of notes and then the notes
combined into phrases and the phrases
combined Santa's passages.
And then,
well even more interestingly then if
it's an orchestral piece of music,
multiple instruments are playing at the
same time.
So it sort of extends right into the
social domain.
But your,
your actions are sort of like that.
They're made out of micro routines and
then those are chained together and
those are chained together in higher
order abstractions and so on,
all the way up to the cortex.
And so
Swanson points out that the,
the motor system has three sets of
inputs.
So the cognitive system that sort of
weigh up,
that's our level of abstraction that's
way up in the brain.
So the cognitive system is where you
know,
you might do a voluntary action.
So you look at something and say,
well I'm going to pick up this piece of
paper.
And so that's talked down cortical
control and then the state system input
to the motor system.
The state system is your body monitoring
what's going on inside of itself.
And the autonomic nervous system is part
of the motor output system.
And so the state monitoring system takes
a careful look and the hypothalamus does
a fair bit of this,
takes a careful look at what's going on
inside you and then activates different
parts of your digestive.
And you know that the gut system
fundamentally that,
that you have no conscious control over.
And then obviously their sensory system
inputs too.
So,
so those are the three main inputs into
the,
into the motor system and that acts on
the environment.
And then the motor system has this
hierarchical nature that's built from
the spine upwards.
And so you can think of like the brain
as a collection of ever expanding
control systems that allow you to what?
Learn and undertake evermore complex
motor schemes of action.
You know,
and one of the things that people think
about human beings is that we're very
good at thinking,
right?
What,
we're not just good at thinking like
work.
We're crazy,
crazily adaptable in terms of our motor
output.
I mean if you watch the watch the
Olympics,
you know when you see human beings can
do things that no other animal could
even think of doing.
I mean we're completely crazy when it
comes to the sorts of things we can do
with our body.
Like we're good on ice,
we're good in the water,
we can ski.
People are really good at jumping,
they can climb across buildings.
I people who train themselves can climb
like mad.
I mean human beings are unbelievably
variable in terms of their motor output.
So that's another part of our
intelligence that's not just abstract.
And so in part that's because we have
this very well developed cortical area
that enables us to chain ever more
complex patterns of behavior together
and also to develop patterns of behavior
that are sort of outside instinctual
specification.
So you imagine with an animal that has a
less complex brain,
a lot of its behavior is going to be
limited to those cause a instinctual
patterns of behavior that are devoted
directly towards the solution of basic
biological problems.
But you know,
we can kind of solve those without too
much effort.
And then we have all this spare motor
capacity leftover and people do the
weirdest things with it,
you know,
and,
and really remarkable.
Absolutely remarkable things.
So that's,
that's pretty cool.
We're pretty cool that way.
We don't get enough credit for it,
I don't think,
because human beings think about human
being as an animal,
which,
you know,
people are kind of loath to do.
We are definitely the most interesting
animal.
I mean,
if you saw like a what a pygmy
hippopotamus skateboarding,
you'd think that was pretty remarkable,
you know,
but people,
they do those sorts of things all the
time.
And you know,
we just take it as a matter of course
the lowest of motor neurone pools,
the lowest level,
the locomotor system,
it's locomotion and an action is foreign
by a subset of motoneuron tools.
That's wrong.
Motor neurons in the spinal cord,
ventral horn that innovates the limb
muscles responsible for locomotor
behavior.
I dictated this with dragon dictate and
now and then it does weird things.
Hey,
so tools,
God only knows where that came from.
So a set of motor neurons in the spinal
cord,
ventral horn.
So it's way down in the spine that
innovate the llamas limb muscles
responsible for locomotor behavior.
When you start to think about the brain
as something that moves your body,
it's a lot easier to conceptualize.
The brain is something that's
distributed through the body,
you know,
and your spine is actually quite smart.
So even though in some sense you don't
think with it,
it's capable of very complex sensory
detection and also motor mapping.
And so,
um,
mostly are relatively automated and
relatively reflective one level up the
existence of a spinal locomotor pattern
generator.
So this shows that the spine isn't
responsible just for the most basic of
motor outputs or sensory inputs.
It can actually generate patterns is
demonstrated by the fact that whereas a
spinal animal displays no spontaneous
locomotor activity.
So if you sever an animal,
it's nervous system.
So it only has the spine,
it'll just lay there,
you know,
you'd think it's paralyzed.
That's what you would think.
But coordinated limb movements,
characteristic of locomotion may be
elicited when the limbs of such an
animal are placed on a moving treadmill
that's providing sematic sensory input
to the pattern generator.
And so they've done this with people who
are paraplegic.
If you take someone who's paraplegic and
so they can't obviously walk and you
hoist them up and you put them on a
treadmill and you lean them forward,
their legs will walk and that spinal
controlled.
So that's what you're doing with your
spine,
you know,
because you're not thinking when you
walk you're or you're not thinking about
walking unless you know,
unless you're one of those people who
can't chew gum and walk at the same
time.
So anyway,
so it just shows you how complex you
are,
even at the,
you know,
the sort of the base levels of your,
of your intelligence hierarchy,
level up,
locomotor pattern controller.
So it's controlling the
locomotor pattern generator
in contrast,
undisturbed chronic hypothalamic
animals.
Okay,
so now one of the ways people figured
out how the brain works was by
sectioning animals,
nervous systems when they're alive at
different levels of complexity.
So a spinal animal is one that's
basically paralyzed.
It's brain is separated from it spinal
cord,
but then you can separate the
hypothalamus with the intact spinal
cord.
So it's one unit from the cortex and
even from the memory systems and even
from most of the emotion systems.
And so the animal in some sense hardly
has a brain at all.
You know,
I mean the hypothalamus is,
you saw it's a little tiny thing and
everything that's on top of that can be
separated from it and the animal can
still act spontaneously.
So,
so here's an example.
If this has been done with cats and if
you have a female cat and it's in a cage
and it's only a hypothalamic animal,
it can basically manage like it can't
learn new things very well and it,
it can't remember anything.
Like it doesn't have episodic memory and
so,
but it can,
it can maintain its temperature,
it can eat,
it can engage in sexual activity.
It's got defensive aggression.
Like most of the animal in some sense is
still there from an,
from an input output perspective.
Um,
it's also hyper exploratory,
which is quite interesting.
Hey,
because you wouldn't think,
well,
animal with no brain is the most
exploratory kind of animal.
Well,
it happens to be the case as long as it
has a hypothalamus.
So that shows you a how old exploration
is,
but it also kind of gives you some clue
about what the rest of the brain is
doing.
I mean
you,
you explore new things we'll say.
So what that means is you have to be
able to tell the difference between
what's new and what isn't.
And so what you need to tell the
difference between what's new and what
isn't is memory.
And so a lot of what the higher order
parts of the brain you're doing is
basically keeping track of where you've
been.
And so if you've been somewhere before
then the exploratory circuit is
basically shut off as long as everything
that you're doing there is working and
you need the whole brain basically to
shut off the hypothalamus in some sense.
That's how the thing works.
It's like you're kind of a default on
system.
You know,
your,
your motor systems are ready to go and
you're kind of,
you're alive and you're ready to go like
a wild animal.
But the cortex dampens that down.
And it does that by only allowing the
activities that are relevant to that
area that might be none of them to
function at any one time.
So you take off the cortex while the
animal can still do a lot of things,
but you know,
its ability to match its behavior to
novel situations and to learn new
behaviors is very,
very limited.
So it,
it becomes hyper exploratory,
but it can't remember anything and it
becomes very limited in the flexibility
of its behavior.
And so as you move farther up the
hierarchy of complexity,
then you're able to do more and more
novel and more and more complex and more
and more situation specific things.
So in the sense of providing a certain
level of endogenous activity,
which means self-generated activity.
So the hypothalamic thalamic animal will
move by itself without being stimulated.
The hypothalamic locomotor region can be
thought of as a locomotor pattern
controller,
which generates spontaneous inputs
ultimately to the spinal locomotor
pattern generator.
So there's,
there's hierarchy.
Um,
I already talked about behavioral state
inputs.
There's another picture of the nervous
system just to remind you of how it
looks,
um,
counts distributed through the body.
Oh this is very interesting too.
I didn't learn this until I read this
paper by Swanson.
I thought,
that's so dumb.
How could I have not learned that?
Like 30 years ago Swanson said that,
um,
let's go back one.
Did I?
Yeah,
Ray Moncayo.
Kal was like the world's greatest
neuroanatomist.
He was the guy who really established
the field,
so did a tremendous amount of
investigation into the fine structure of
the brain like 110 years ago,
a long time ago.
And he pointed out that sensory systems
have a dual projection within the
central nervous system.
I told you guys about blind sight
already,
you know,
and I in fact that your eyes map onto
different levels of the hierarchy,
say of sensory input and motor control.
Kal basically outlined the for that one
branch goes directly to the motor
system.
So it's,
that's for I to output mapping.
So that's fast cause there's not a lot
of thinking in between.
And you might think that's bad because
you want to think,
but it's good because sometimes you know
what to do and you don't want to thank
you just want to execute it as fast as
you possibly can.
So these lower orders,
simpler inputs are good for that sort of
thing.
One goes directly to the motor system
and the other goes more or less directly
to the cerebral cortex where sensations
and perceptions are elaborated and
voluntary motor impulses are generated.
So this sort of explains for a long time
experimental psychology was dominated by
behaviorists who thought of the animal
as a stimulus response machine and never
paid much attention to the function of
things like thought or emotion or
complex internal states.
And you know,
the behaviors got an awful long way with
their idea of the animal as a sort of
simple stimulus response machine.
And that's partly because of this
hierarchy that we're describing.
You know,
cause you,
you can treat an animal as if it's a
pretty simple machine because it has all
that simple machinery in it.
It's just that on top of that simple
machinery,
there's a lot more complex machinery.
And so,
but the simple machinery does a lot more
than people generally think and can do
more than people think.
And so the fact that there are these,
at least two projections,
they branch more than that gives you
right away a sense of why the behaviors
could have been right and the cognitive
psychologists could have been right.
And even the cycle dynamic thinkers can
be right because they're analyzing the
system at different levels of
hierarchical complexity and extracting
out slightly different,
um,
what would you call,
uh,
observations and some of these things,
or even like the simpler systems can
have quite complex output.
So,
so one of the things that the simpler
sensory motor system does is it detects
snakes because primates don't like
snakes.
In fact,
there's a woman named
Lynn is bell wrote a nice book on
primate vision and snakes and she was
very curious about why human beings
could see so well.
And,
uh,
she also noticed that we're very good at
detecting,
um,
the sort of camouflage patterns that
snakes used,
especially in the lower half of our
visual field.
And she did this cross cultural survey
around the world and found out that
where there's more predatory snakes,
the primates have better vision.
So we sorta coevolved with snakes and
snakes gave us vision just like it says
in Genesis,
which is pretty damn funny as far as I'm
concerned.
And it was snakes in trees even so,
and fruit of course gave us color
vision.
So the whole genesis story nailed it
pretty well.
But you know,
snakes have been around long enough and
have been our enemy or say predatory
reptiles,
you know,
if,
if you don't really want to go with the
little snake thing that are,
we've,
we've evolved,
we've coevolved with them.
It's like 60 million years.
It's a very,
very long period of time.
So Darwin used to amuse himself in a
Darwinian way.
He'd go to the,
there is a zoo or a rep place that shows
reptiles,
I don't remember what they're called,
but they had one glass cage where there
was some kind of poisonous snake,
I think it was a cobra.
And Darwin would put his face right up
against the glass and the kroeber would
go whack.
And he jumped back.
And he,
he did that many times because he was
curious about whether or not he could
actually bring the snake avoidance
reflex under conscious control.
And he couldn't,
every time the snake jumped,
he jumped backwards.
He couldn't control it.
And so that's because all the primates
that could control it when there were
snakes biting them are dead.
So it was,
Darwin was the beneficiary of the
Darwinian process in that,
in that sense.
So,
so the point is your body's conserved,
all these low level,
fast operating circuits.
And so you're a simple machine in a sort
of complex machine and an extremely
complex machine.
And then something that's so complex
that you can't even think about it as a
machine and you're all those things at
the same time.
And there's Swanson's take on how the
motor system and the hypothalamus are
integrated,
so it's quite nice.
He shows that the hypothalamic
controller,
so that's one of the circuits that we've
been talking about that are responsible
for a basic motivated state,
gets sensory input,
behavioral state input.
That's about the body and the input from
the cerebral hemispheres.
Hypothetically that's thought or or
voluntary action plan,
something like that.
And then it has output to the motor
pattern initiator,
the generators and the motor neuron
pools and then you act lovely.
It's a beautiful,
beautiful model.
And so you can see that it maps very
nicely onto that with the sort of higher
order levels of the,
of the hierarchy of sensory motor
framing associated with cognitive
abstractions in the lowest levels
associated with the sorts of things that
you do with your spine.
And this,
I flip this upside down here because
it's,
I,
I've been very interested in how people
get traumatized and it's easier to think
of trauma when you flip the thing
because once you develop the higher
order abstractions cortically,
you know,
he'd say,
well,
I'm a good person,
let's say.
Then that's sort of the,
the fact that you're a good person or
what constitutes good starts to become a
box.
The box within which all the things that
are associated with it are put,
it's one of the dangers of abstraction,
right?
And categorization.
Because if you couldn't think of
yourself as a good or bad person,
let's say you didn't have that capacity
for that level of abstraction,
which is like a binary abstraction,
right?
Good is,
you know,
one in and bad is zero.
So it's a really,
it's a really simple,
and so if someone,
if you do something that a good person
wouldn't do,
well clearly you don't fit into the one
category because a good person wouldn't
do that.
So maybe you fit into the zero category.
And that's that capacity for abstraction
is also precisely the sort of thing that
allows human beings to undermine
themselves with thought.
Because once you have that capacity for
abstraction,
you can make these ridiculous over
generalizations.
In fact,
they're really simple.
I'm not a good person.
I'm a horrible person.
It's like that's what how someone who's
really depressed thinks whenever,
whenever anything goes wrong.
And so it's the danger,
the powerful danger of abstraction is
that you can make a terrible mistake and
overgeneralization this is partly
because,
well,
let's say a hard know you're out with
your girlfriend and you flirt with
someone else.
Um,
so what does that say about your
character?
Well,
she might think that puts you in the
zero category like now,
right?
You're not a good person.
It's like,
well,
it's complicated.
Is that or is that true?
Do you,
do you belong in that zero category?
She might treat you like that for a week
or two.
I mean,
should you be taking yourself apart
completely because you've made that
error?
Or should you seek farther down the
chain of abstractions for a more
specific mistake and or should she help
you do that?
It's like,
well,
you're not a complete zero.
You're more like,
uh,
you know,
0.1,
she could help you figure out exactly
where in your personality hierarchy you
have this fault.
So being that it's a fault,
you know,
maybe it's an indication that the
relationship is over who,
who knows.
So anyways,
I wanted you to show you that because
then you can develop a sense of how this
hierarchical system can also lead to
cataclysmic overgeneralization and
that's associated with lots of different
mental illnesses,
especially depression because depressed
people generally go from a small mistake
while a mistake,
hard to parameterize,
right to the highest level of
abstraction say,
well,
I've made error a,
therefore I'm useless,
you know,
are therefore I bad?
It's not good.
It's a two undifferentiated,
I put that in there to remind you that
all these little things
are informed
by the underlying hypothalamic circuits.
So you know that whole hierarchy has to
be managed and how it's conditioned.
That whole hierarchy of motor output,
part of it is conditioned by,
and this is sort of like an output or an
input system that Swanson didn't talk
about,
sort of sensory,
that whole motor sensory,
sensory,
motor hierarchy,
sensory motor perception,
action hierarchy will say has to be
constructed so that your basic
motivational states stay satiated,
right?
Because otherwise you get thirsty enough
and you die or you get hungry enough and
you die.
It's like you have to organize your
behavior so that those basic motivations
stay fulfilled.
So each of the little,
okay
ovals that make up that hierarchy have
to be organized and laid out with that
set of limitations in mind.
But then of course there's a higher
order limitation,
which is more the one that piaget talked
about,
which is that not only do you have to
organize your internal hierarchies to
take care of all of your basic
motivations,
but you have to do that well,
everyone else is doing the same thing.
And so in some sense the hypothalamic
system that's generating the impetus for
these layers and layers of motor output
also has to do so in a social context
because otherwise,
you know,
you fight to the death over a stick of
bread,
which seems like a very
counterproductive thing to do.
So
I'm trying to point out to you how many
parameters those,
that hierarchical organization has to
meet simultaneously.
Also that one of the implications of
that is that it's not an arbitrary
system.
Again,
this is one of the problems I have with
the radical moral relativists stats.
It's like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
For you to set up your perceptual and
behavioral system,
it has to solve a whole bunch of
problems.
Like in they're really complex problems
and they're,
and they're kind of arbitrary in some
sense.
Like you get hungry and you need deet.
It's arbitrary.
So what that means is you can't fill
that hierarchy with just any old thing.
You know,
not only does it have to work to keep
all the complex parts of you functioning
here and now,
but it has to keep them functioning here
and now in a way that doesn't disturb
them functioning tomorrow or the next
day or the next week or the next month.
So that's integration across time spans.
That's a killer,
right?
Cause he can't just go out tonight and
drink 40 ounces of vodka and then,
you know,
write the test on Thursday.
So there's a probably not.
So some of you might try.
So,
but then you also have to organize your
behavior in the here and now with your
behavior spread across timeframes in the
presence of other people who are also
organizing their behavior across
timeframes.
It's like once you put that many
parameters on the organization of a
personality,
you can see right away that it can
hardly be arbitrary.
You know,
it's tightly constrained.
Okay.
So here's some basic emotions.
We talked about basic motivations.
And so the web we're going to do in a
simple way is we're going to divide them
into two positive emotions and negative
emotions.
Okay?
And that basically gives you
extroversion and neuroticism.
So positive emotions,
they kind of fall into two classes.
The one class is the positive emotion
you feel when you,
when you run a motivational frame to its
limit.
So you're hungry,
you go have a peanut butter sandwich and
then you're no longer hungry.
Okay.
So what's the state?
How do you define the state after you've
eaten your peanut butter sandwich and
you're no longer hungry?
Well,
you know,
you're not jumping up and down and
cheering like someone who just made a
touchdown,
right?
So it's,
it's not that kind of enthusiastic,
positive emotion that you see when
people are celebrating,
you know,
it's more like satisfaction.
And that's actually technically what
it's known as satiation.
And so when a motivational routine runs
successfully,
what happens is it eliminates,
it eliminates the necessity for it to
exist temporarily.
So basically what happens is you run A,
a framework to its logical conclusion.
Poof,
it disappears because it's done.
And you know,
you might be satisfied about that.
But that's the next thing that happens
is another motivational framework pops
up and you're,
you know,
you're in the same game.
It says office fundamentally.
So anyways,
it's satiation.
That is t the term satiation is
technically use to describe the state of
being.
It's characteristic of the successful
execution of a motivated frame.
It's also known as conservatory reward,
consummation consume.
And that's associated with
unconditioned.
That's an unconditioned response
it,
which means you don't have to learn it.
So it's a,
it's an unconditioned positive response.
So,
and that means that satiating stimuli
when delivered to a creature in the
proper motivational frame have the
properties of unconditioned rewards.
So you get three things there.
You know,
the satiation brings the moated frame
motivated frame to an end.
The satiation is also known as consumer
Tory reward.
Conservatory reward is very similar to
what the behavior is described as
unconditioned reward,
unlearned.
So you can,
you can stack each of those things to
know on top of each other.
And then you've got the,
the other kind of positive emotion is
the positive emotion that you feel when
it looks like you might get a
conservatory reward,
right?
Right.
Hope,
curiosity,
anticipation,
excitement,
enthusiasm,
all of the positive emotions that we
think of as really like happy,
happy usually has to do with evidence
that your pursuit of a valued
conservatory reward is going well.
Okay?
Now that this,
that's incentive reward and the reason
it's called incentive reward is because
you're incentivized to move forward to
the reward and the moving forward.
The impulse to move forward towards a
desired goal.
That's what your positive emotion
systems,
the dopaminergic systems that are
nestled have the roots in the
hypothalamus.
That's what they motivate you to do.
That's what positive emotion is.
Fundamentally positive emotion is
there's something good,
I'm going to go get it.
It's the,
I'm going to go get part that's
associated with excitement and positive
emotion.
It's what you feel.
Maybe you're an extrovert,
you want to go to a party and so you're
probably more excited about going to the
party.
Then you will be when you get there,
you know,
because it's the,
it's the apprehension of the reward
that's with human beings because we're
such weird creatures.
So often the apprehension of the
conservatory ward is a more powerful
emotion than the emotion that's actually
felt as a consequence of gaining the
reward itself.
And that's partly,
and this is where it gets a little more
complicated.
That's part of it because we're so
bloody exploratory,
you know?
So there's things that you can learn
about that are associated with the
conservatory reward.
Those are conditioned rewards.
So an incentive reward and the condition
reward are in the same category.
Although not all incentive rewards are
learned.
This is where the behaviors went wrong
because the behavior's thought there are
consumer Tory rewards.
Those are unconditioned rewards to get a
conditioned to come.
If you condition a stimulus to an
unconditioned reward,
you get a condition stimulus with a
conditioned reward as a response.
But the problem with that line of
thinking is that there's actually
incentive reward circuitry.
It's not just secondary learning.
It's like incentive rewards have been
around so long.
So those are things that indicate that a
conservatory reward is coming.
They've been around so long that your
brain has developed its own circuit for
that.
And that's the one that produces
positive emotion.
And so that's also produced by the way,
if you,
when you're taking a drug of some sort
that you really like,
that's because it's activating this
dopaminergic incentive reward system.
If you take a drug that activates
conservatory reward,
you just like lay in front of the fire
like a sleeping dog,
you know,
it's,
it's not exciting.
It's cocaine,
amphetamines,
alcohol for lots of people nail the
incentive reward system.
And that's the dopaminergic exploratory
system that emerges out of the
hypothalamus.
And it's also the thing that learns what
to associate with conservatory rewards.
So I know that's a lot to take in,
but well it doesn't matter.
That's how it is.
So,
so the approach systems respond to cues
of consumer Tory reward.
And they also,
they also respond to a large set of um,
biologically prepared stimuli smells,
for example.
So
now you should approach good things,
but if a bad thing happens,
what should you do?
Well,
one thing you should do is stop.
Another thing you should do is get the
hell out of there.
So there's a constellation of negative
emotions that are associated with
defense and avoidance,
and we kind of ran through those
already.
Pain,
grief,
frustration,
disappointment,
and then fear,
which is sort of what you learn.
You learn that things to be feared.
Signal,
primary pain,
stimulus,
you know,
so a child is going to be afraid of a
needle,
especially if the child's got a needle
before.
Most children are smart enough to figure
out what they should be afraid of the
needle even when they haven't had it.
But the thing is is that if you come
into contact with something that's
already caused you pain and now there's
something that only signals that that's
likely to happen,
that's when you experience fear.
Okay?
And fear is its own circuit again,
which is where the behaviors in some
sense wind a little bit wrong to cause
they thought of unconditioned
punishment,
which produces pain as the primary
motivational system.
So it would be unconditioned punishment,
unconditioned reward.
Then there were things you learned about
those that produced conditioned
punishment.
Conditioned reward.
Okay.
But all of those have circuits,
independent circuits.
So the defense and avoidance,
negative emotions seem to be roughly
pain,
anxiety and fear.
But then there's discussed and people
have been looking at discussed a lot
lately and it doesn't load on
neuroticism,
it doesn't seem to load on neuroticism.
So it's its own circuit.
So,
okay,
so here's another one.
Other complexity that you need to
grapple with,
which is there are things that hurt that
cause you pain.
There are things that are satiating and
letter our conservatory reward.
Then there are things that signal each
of those,
but there's one class of stimuli,
so to speak,
or things that you're going to encounter
that or a paradoxical,
and that's the class of things that you
don't understand.
That's novelty and novelty.
It's,
it's,
it's novelty itself that sort of
associated with what the
phenomenologists are primarily concerned
about.
The idea of the revelation of meaning
because the revelation of beating is
mostly associated with you encountering
something that you haven't already
understood.
Right?
You explore that new information comes
out of it,
a new you comes out of it.
Okay,
so you're going from point a to point b,
what might happen?
Well,
things might happen that that appear to
demonstrate that you're on the right
track.
So that makes you happy.
That's the yellow box,
positive emotion.
You know,
your,
your pathway is being facilitated.
So that's why tools are sort of sort of
in that category.
Or you can be moving towards point b and
you get something gets in your way.
And that might be something that hurts
you,
that'd be,
and that hurt would be pain or
disappointment or frustration or grief
or something that signals that you might
get hurt,
which is threat not produces fear.
And so the positive emotion is moving
you towards the desired goal in the
negative emotion is protecting you.
And so if a negative things happens,
you'll stop and then you'll reconfigure
the behavior that you're using or the
framework in order to get around the
obstacle and to continue.
Or if it's a bad enough obstacle,
you'll,
you might say,
well,
I'm not,
I'm too tired to eat and I'm too hungry
to sleep.
That happens to people,
right?
It's a conflict of motivations.
And so if you get up and you go into the
cupboard and you find out that there's
nothing to eat,
you might say,
Oh,
to hell with it,
then I'll just go to sleep.
You know?
So sometimes the way you solve a problem
is by flipping the problem.
It's like we're not going to solve that
problem right now.
We'll turn to another problem some.
And that's an explorer.
That's an exploratory move.
Sometimes you operate within the frame,
you know,
you go to the cupboard,
the cupboard is bare.
Yeah,
but you're hungry.
So you walked down to the corner store
and you get something to eat.
And so that way you've sort of stayed
within the frame and altered.
You know,
you've altered your behavior to too,
you've thought up another path and
altered your behavior so that that
motivated state can run to completion.
Here's another way of looking at it.
You can be moving from point a to b and
what you predict or want is happening.
That's a good thing that keeps your mood
straight and you happy and that makes
you whoa.
That's a promise with the promise is
you're going to get what you want and
that fills you with hope.
That's positive emotion.
Or you can have an unpredicted outcome
when you're,
you know,
you uh,
[inaudible] you're supposed to be going
out with your friend,
you go to the door,
you knock and there's nobody there.
So it's like,
what's up with that?
And so it's in a sense when that
happens,
there's like a hole in your framework,
you know,
cause your framework was predicated on
the presence of your friend,
right?
It was a presupposition.
And so now,
and then you'll run out of behavioral
routine and one of your presuppositions
is wrong.
And it's sort of like there's a hole in
your theory and the whole,
you sort of drop into it.
And when you drop into that hole,
you get anxious because you don't know
exactly what this unexpected thing
means.
And behind that you get exploratory.
So with most people,
they're going to get afraid first.
They're going to have negative emotion
first when they're little plan is blown.
And then if nothing additionally awful
happens and if they don't drive
themselves crazy with some hypothesis
about he doesn't like me anymore and so
no one likes me anymore,
so I'm a terrible person,
you know,
then the x,
once they calm down a little bit,
the exploration circuit will come up and
maybe they'll walk somewhere else,
go to a bar,
or maybe they'll stand there and think,
well,
you know,
this didn't work out,
so what else could I do?
And emotionally stable person say a non
neurotic personnel flipped it out really
fast,
especially if they're extroverted and
open.
Where someone who's heavy and negative
emotion,
you know,
the fact that their friend wasn't there
when they told them they would be,
that might just produce a hole that they
fall into and it's,
you know,
so deep and painful.
They just go home and cry.
So,
so the neuroticism and the extroversion
are in some sense,
they vary with the degree to which the
negative emotion system is strong,
or the positive emotion system is strong
and they're two different systems.
And so you can think of them in some
sense.
You can think of the mass
units of positive emotion per unit of
promise.
It's,
I mean,
it's a weird thing to try to quantify or
units of negative emotion per unit of
threat.
So,
you know,
if someone,
maybe someone,
there's a rumor going around that you're
going to lose your job.
Well how much should you worry about
that?
Well,
God,
you don't know.
So how do you decide?
Well,
you don't,
you're,
you're wiring decide.
So if you're high in negative emotion,
you're going to get all anxious and
freak out about it,
which might be the right thing to do.
Maybe you will lose your job.
And if you're emotionally stable,
you're going to thank God.
I probably won't lose my job,
but even if I can't,
even if I do,
I'm,
I'm not gonna worry about it.
It's innate or lot of it's innate.
So,
okay.
So to recapitulate learning theory,
behaviorism,
there are unconditioned rewards.
Those are rewards you don't have to
learn.
Those are the things that bring a
motivated state to its closure,
roughly speaking,
and that makes you satisfied.
Satiation.
That by the way,
is associated with Serotonin.
Serotonin is a satiating neurochemical,
so if you're high levels of Serotonin
are high,
you're kind of satisfied,
which means you don't experience a lot
of positive emotion or a lot of negative
emotion.
You're just kind of satisfied.
It's a high dominance thing.
It's like all of the consumer.
Tory rewards are there when you need
them.
You don't have to worry and you don't
have to get too excited.
Conditioned rewards or incentive rewards
indicate progress towards a consumer,
consumer Tory reward.
They can be learned or condition,
but they can also be a nate and they're
associated with dopaminergic activation
and that's the exploration circuit that
comes out of the hypothalamus.
Half the hymen,
hypothalamus does goal specification
and the other half does exploration,
and so again,
if you're pursuing something that's an
identifiable goal and you fail,
well then you're going to back off.
That's negative emotion.
Then you're going to start to explore
and that's that dopaminergic circuit.
What's associated with dopaminergic
activation,
exploration,
extroversion,
happiness,
play,
enthusiasm,
assertiveness and the positive element
of novelty.
Okay,
so that makes sense.
Anybody have any questions?
I know that's a lot of information,
but I kind of designed this part of the
course so that at this point the levels
of analysis would stack up so that you
could understand them simultaneously.
So the hypothalamus sets up your frames
of motivation
running one of those two,
the co two.
It's positive conclusion.
That satisfying.
That's innate.
It's because it's consumer Tory reward.
You'll work for that.
Anything that indicates that that might
happen,
that's incentive reward.
You can learn that.
But some of it's also a nate,
which is where the behaviors didn't know
that cause they thought of all the,
all the secondary stuff that condition
stuff has learned.
It's not all learned.
Some of it's already prepared.
You see a snake,
that's a threat.
You don't have to learn that.
So fire is sort of like that as well.
Um,
blood is like that.
Teeth are like that.
Staring eyes are like that.
Predatory postures are like that.
Um,
loud,
loud vocalizations,
especially if they're like low,
low in frequency,
they indicate a large animal.
All those things are things you don't
have to learn to be afraid of because
they've been so consistently dangerous
in the past that you've built up a
circuit that aren't responds
automatically to the question.
It seems like there will at least.
Yeah,
it's complicated,
you know,
because they do play a bit of an
inhibitory role,
but they're separate circuits,
you know,
so you can be very extroverted and very
high in negative emotion.
Okay.
So,
and you can be very emotionally stable
and very low in extroversion too.
So,
but they are definitely separate things
now.
It's hard,
you know,
you can flip from laughing to crying
very rapidly,
you know?
So people are very much capable of
experiencing mixed states of positive
and negative emotion.
Plus there are forms of manic depressive
disorder where people are manic and
depressed at the same time,
which I wouldn't recommend the people I
know that have had that they,
they seem to think that is certainly not
fun.
So
yeah,
agitation,
tremendous agitation.
So you're probably just sorta like that
when you're deeply confused and you're
really bothered by it because then the
threat circuits are going,
but you're also sort of wandering around
going,
oh,
what am I going to do?
That's all.
That's all like approach behavior
approach.
Motivation isn't always positive a,
I mean most of the time it is,
but intensity managers and
controllability matters too,
so,
okay.
Unconditioned punishments,
fundamentally they produce pain.
They also tend to Ha if you ran a
behavioral routine or a motivated
framework that results in punishment,
you're less likely to run it again in
the future.
That's learning.
If you run a motivated frame and it
works,
you're more likely to run it in the
future.
That's learning too,
so I'm conditioned.
Punishments decrease the probability
that you're going to run to give and
motivational frame because it failed.
Right?
Do you run out?
You got hurt.
It's like,
don't do that again.
That's part of the purpose of memory and
the pain,
like emotions,
just to say it again.
Our pain,
frustration,
disappointment,
grief,
sadness is in there as well,
so those are paying like states of
emotion,
conditioned punishments.
Those are things that indicate that a
punishment is likely.
Some of them you can learn.
Some of them you don't have to because
they're already built into you.
The negative emotions are dampened by
Serotonin.
That's the brain system.
Fundamentally,
it's the serotonergic system is like a
conductor of the orchestra.
It keeps everything in,
in balance and Gabba.
Gabba is a anxiety lytic.
It makes people less anxious.
It's endogenous.
Your brain produces it.
If you take valium or barbiturates,
they act on the Gaba system.
It's so does alcohol.
That's part of the reason why people
like alcohol because it dampens anxiety.
Now for some people,
alcohol or also produces dopaminergic
activation.
So they really like alcohol because it
calms them down like they're not anxious
anymore.
And it also feels it produces incentive
reward activation like cocaine for.
So for some people,
alcohol is and absolutely deadly drug.
You can probably find out if you're
susceptible to alcoholism quite
straightforwardly.
If you want to find out,
sit in a bar,
take your pulse.
Yeah,
down five shots,
four shots.
If you're little,
you gotta get your,
you got to get your blood alcohol level
above legal intoxication or you won't be
able to tell and then take your pulse
again 10 minutes later.
If your pulse has gone up,
eight beats are more,
watch it because you're probably
producing an opiate response to alcohol.
Secondary consequence of the opiod
responses are dopaminergic response,
reasonable probability that you'll like
alcohol enough to find it difficult to
stop drinking.
Once you start,
some of you are probably like that,
right?
You have a few drinks.
It's like ha,
that's how we do it in Alberta anyways.
So,
so part of that's killing the incentive
reward system.
And because it's an approach system and
it's being cued by the alcohol,
you just continue to hit it.
And the dopamine kicks only occur as
your blood alcohol level is rising.
So you have to keep nailing it,
nailing yourself with alcohol because
otherwise your blood alcohol level won't
keep rising and you won't get that nice
enthusiasm and assertiveness that goes
along with the positive element of
alcohol.
Neuroticism.
So this is the neuroticism dimension.
Um,
there's this gender difference in
neuroticism.
Women are about half a standard
deviation,
higher negative emotion than men.
It's seems like a cross cultural
universal,
the differences more enhanced.
And he galitary and states like
Scandinavia,
which is exactly the opposite of what
you'd presume,
right?
If you were say us.
Um,
a radical,
I can't remember the name.
If you are someone who believes that
everything occurs as a consequence of
socialization,
as you equalize the society,
the gender differences in personality
become larger rather than smaller.
So,
which is,
you know,
not what anybody expected.
But that's what happened.
So boys and girls seem to have about the
same level of negative emotion.
But as soon as puberty hits,
women become higher negative emotion
than men on average.
There's still a lot of overlap between
the genders and it never goes away again
across the life course once it kicks in,
in puberty.
And the reasons for that,
women are smaller,
they're,
their upper bodies are weaker,
so they're more physical,
they're there at a physical
disadvantage.
If they're in a dominance dispute,
they're sexually vulnerable,
plus they have to take care of infants.
So I think those four things are
probably enough to tilt the nervous
system of women more towards negative
negative emotion.
I've often thought maybe that women's
name,
emotional systems,
the negative ones in particular are
actually not tuned to the woman.
I think there are tuned to the woman
infant combination.
So you know,
if you think about it from an,
if you think about it for bit,
it almost has to be that way because an
infant has to be carried around for like
a year and a half.
And so at that point when you have an
infant and maybe you're going to have 10
you know you guys won't,
but in the evolutionary past,
that would have been the case.
You'd have an infant for a bunch of your
life and then you'd be a grandmother and
have an incident.
It's like,
why wouldn't your nervous system be
tuned at puberty for the two of you
instead of one of you?
So how could it be any other way?
Anyways.
All right,
I'll give you one more.
What time is it?
This clock says one 46 is that vaguely
correct?
Okay,
wonderful.
One 48 five okay,
now I'm going to run you through a
problem that took me
like
yes,
yes.
Two 48 ts.
So let's see.
Oh yes.
Okay.
Two things.
So you've got your hypothalamus and then
on top of that you've got some circuits
that deal with memory and emotion.
So I'm going to run you through the
hippocampus and the Amygdala relatively
quickly.
So this is a theory that was basically
put together by socal [inaudible] who's
a Russian neuropsychologist back in 1962
but it's a variant of a theory that
Norbert Wiener developed back in the
forties so here's the idea.
You wander through the world and you,
if you're in a place that you know,
okay,
your memory systems,
they hit the campus,
looks inside your memory systems to see
what it is that you want to have happen
based on your understanding of the
world.
Okay?
So
you're in a motivated state,
but you have certain expectations that
makes sense within that state.
So the hippocampus is watching what you
think is going to happen.
But remember that's motivated.
It's not just expectation.
And then the hippocampus is also looking
at the world.
Now it's looking at an interpretation of
the world because you can't help but
interpret the world.
But fundamentally the hippocampus is
looking inside you and outside you.
And then it seeing if what's happening
inside and what's happening outside are
the same,
which means you know what you're doing
and you know where you are.
And if they're the same.
So if it detects a match,
then the hippocampus inhibits the
Amygdala and the hypothalamus,
roughly speaking.
Now what did it actually seems to do?
There's a little circuit in your brain
stem called the reticular activating
circuit,
and it's the thing that turns your brain
on at night.
If you're sleeping and you hear a noise
that you shouldn't hear,
it's like bang,
you're awake.
It's the reticular activating system.
Way Down in your brainstem,
puts your cortex into a high arousal
state and Poof,
you're conscious.
Now the hippocampus tells the reticular
activating system to basically remain
calm as well,
as long as what you're expecting and
desiring and what's happening are the
same thing.
So it's sort of like it's saying,
I know you could jump up and freak out
and run about,
but you don't have to right now because
everything's going according to plan.
But as soon as there's a deviation
that's an normally say,
then the hippocampus says,
Whoa,
something's wrong here.
And the it does inhibits the reticular
activating system that turns on your
emotions,
especially your negative emotion,
but it primes your positive emotion and
it prime some of the hypothalamic
circuits to or disinhibiting them.
Because one way of solving the fact that
something isn't going well is to switch
to something else.
So it's sort of like it's a bunch of
circuits on underneath you,
but they're being held back like race
horses in race horse and then something
that you don't expect happens in the
gates come up a little bit because then
you're prepared.
Now a lot of that's negative emotion.
Oh,
you don't know where you are.
But a lot of,
a lot of the rest of it is be prepared
to do whatever the hell you might need
to do next.
And so normally the hippocampus detects
the,
normally that's something unexpected.
And then it disinhibiting your lower
circuitry and it gets you ready to go.
Now the problem is
this one.
How?
How worried should you be when something
that you don't expect happens?
An answer to that is you don't know.
That's a big problem with life because
now something went wrong.
Here's the possibilities.
You're not looking at the world,
right?
So it's actually a perceptual problem,
Gray,
for example,
believes that you just see the world
just like it is cause he's sort of a
behaviorist.
It's full of stimuli.
You don't have to interpret them.
That's wrong.
You have to interpret them.
So if something goes wrong,
it might be that you're looking at
things wrong.
Your perceptual systems are out.
It's unlikely.
But sometimes that's the case.
But forget that.
Let's say that you're looking at the
world correctly and you know your
inferences about what went wrong,
what went wrong isn't the consequence of
you misperceiving it's a consequence of
some stupid problem with your stupid
plan.
The problem is you don't know where the
error is located and that's why I think
there's temperament.
Sometimes something unexpected happens,
you should really freak out.
Other times you should ignore it,
but you can't tell which of those is
true right away.
So what happens is there's a
distribution with a little thing
happens.
Some people really get upset about it
and other people hardly care at all.
And sometimes the people who get really
upset about it or write,
and sometimes the people who don't care
at all are right.
And that's why there's variability in
neuroticism.
Okay?
Now what you do when you were exploring
is you start to decompose your plan,
right?
If you're,
if you,
if you can manage it,
if you're not so like grip by anxiety
that you're paralyzed,
then you go into your plan and you
think,
well,
am I a complete like loser or is it some
micro thing that's gone wrong?
And then you can start to decompose it
and reconstruct your plat.
Okay.
So
yeah.
Oh,
there was something else I want to tell
you about that.
Yeah.
The other,
the other thing that this little diagram
helps you understand.
It's like,
look,
what happens is when you're laying out a
plan,
a motivated plan,
and a hole appears in it,
you have to figure out why you fell in
the hole.
And then what you have to do is you have
to take that motivated plan that's kind
of running on automatic and you have to
remember what it's made out of.
And so what opens up underneath you
when,
when you've made a mistake is the
complexity of the plant.
And then also potentially the complexity
of the world on the off chance that you
misperceived it,
right?
You're just,
someone might say,
you're not understanding me properly.
You know,
maybe there's something wrong with you
that's interfering with the perception.
And then you have to do this massive
search to try to figure out where there
are lies.
Now,
part of the reason I believe that people
stick to their beliefs so hard is
because people don't like it when the
hole appears in one of their big
abstractions,
right?
So they've got these high order
representations of the world that are
shorthand ways of representing
something.
They're sort of like axioms of faith.
And if they,
if a hole appears in one of the axioms
of faith,
then all this complexity comes rushing
up and it's overwhelming.
And so people hate it when you undermine
one of their high order abstractions.
And so I think I told you this before,
don't do that in relationships,
right?
It's best not to do it to yourself as
well.
Okay,
I'll start with this.
These are Medusa's and what,
what happens when you see the Medusa?
Okay,
so what,
what,
what might that mean?
You bet it's a,
it's a prey response.
And so that's a sort of,
that's the sort of thing that occurs
when,
okay,
you're moving towards your goal in your
frame and the bottom drops out.
It's like,
oh,
what's there?
You don't know.
So what's the logical first response?
Well,
if you're high in neuroticism,
it's going to be this,
you know,
freeze.
And then,
and only then,
if nothing else terrible happens to you,
you'll start to relax a bit and then
maybe you'll start to investigate the
structure of your planet.
Maybe you'll start to investigate the
structure of the world.
And then from a constructivist
perspective,
say once you start to do that,
you gather information from the world,
and then you remake your plan and you
remake your conception of the world,
and then you could move on.
So you do that under the guidance of the
positive and the negative emotions.
Okay,
that's good.
We'll see you Tuesday.