Got It.
So it's a so people are taking it
seriously.
That's good.
It's good.
I say that.
But you're the one who has to deal with
the pain and the pressure.
So
yeah.
Well I'm in a permanent state of being
freaked out,
so
when I woke up this morning with all
these ideas that I wanted to talk to you
about.
All right.
Okay.
So let me pull up the emails that I sent
you.
Yeah.
Okay.
So one of the things,
did you want to talk first just to,
just to get her ideas to or what maybe I
can.
I also want to comment on some of the
things you wrote.
Go ahead.
One of the things,
one of the difficulties,
by the way,
are you recording this already?
Yeah,
well I can always edit it afterwards.
Okay.
Um,
well maybe you should,
maybe you should speak first because
that way when I talk about the,
the,
the kind of,
the questions that I have a,
especially in regard to the cross.
The Cross is really complicated.
It's a complicated.
It's like it's meant to be a to be a
mystery and so the way it's presented to
us it,
it kind of breaks all the categories in
a way and so or it unites them together.
You can rather see it that way and so
it's difficult to.
It's difficult to,
to talk about the cross because it's
both totally on the inside,
you know,
it's the center of the world at the
access of the cosmos.
It's all those things,
but it's also,
you know,
at the edge of the world because even in
the story it's brought outside.
His crucifixion happens outside of the
city.
It happens on the mountain of the skull
and also there's a,
there's a verse in the Psalm that says
that the just will never hang on a cross
and so I will,
will never hang on a tree.
It doesn't say cross,
but no,
they're just,
will never hang on a tree.
And so there's a,
there's an area in the cross which is
that Christ is the,
just who's hanging on a tree.
So that's actually one of the reasons
why Jews have never accepted Christ as
the Messiah because they can't deal with
the,
the absolute,
uh,
like a paradox of having,
you know,
the,
the perfect man hanging on a tree.
And so it's like how do those two
things.
But,
but for a Christian,
it's really bringing together that the,
the extremes.
You know,
I talked about that before.
Well,
I think that Christ really isn't the top
of the hierarchy,
but he's really the stretching out of
the hierarchy from the,
from the top to the bottom.
Yeah.
Yep.
Okay.
So,
so.
Alright.
So we'll get to that.
All right.
Yeah.
Because I think that's,
that's,
that's an interesting way of
conceptualizing the potential solution
to this problem.
Yeah.
Okay.
So Derrick had this concept of
undecidability,
right?
There were these things that existed on
the margins that didn't fit into a
category system.
Yup.
And
we've talked about that before and now
it to me to be very much associated with
the idea that I developed in maps of
meaning of anomaly.
The anomalous is the monster and the
reason the anomalous is the monster is
because there's a very large number of
things that won't fit into any category
system.
Doesn't matter what the category system
is.
There's the things inside the category
system or the category and there's
things outside and there's a
multiplicity of the things outside.
Yes.
And so the monster images,
appropriate image to represent that
because monster is a camera that's made
up of parts.
Yes,
exactly.
Okay.
And you always have to confront what
stands outside the category system.
Yeah,
and it looks to me like we use our
Predator a detection and defense systems
as the first defense against that.
The first reaction against that because
it's,
it's an archetypal reality that there
are things outside the category system.
Yeah.
And it's actually,
I think that in terms of phenomenology,
I would say,
uh,
I don't know,
maybe you can actually,
you can eliminate this in terms of
evolutionary biology because I'm not an
expert in that at all,
but it seems that there is both the
predatory aspect where it's,
where the,
the,
the monster or the anomaly is seen as
something to defeat.
But there's also,
there's also an aspect which is the
desiring.
Yeah,
right,
right.
Well that's the dragon with the,
with the gold.
Yes.
Or,
or the,
the siren,
the siren.
Noah.
The monster itself.
Like there's something about the siren
and about the,
um,
the idea of Lilith.
For example,
in Jewish mythology,
this notion of like the or the um,
or the,
um,
the incubus,
you know,
the idea of the female demon,
uh,
which lures and brings you out of
yourself and kind of makes you kind of
waste your seed.
And in a Christian and religious,
uh,
idea where it says if there's a,
there's something about the outside or
the foreign or the which elicits a
desire to move out towards it.
I think you kind of talk about that when
you talk about this notion of the snake
that appears,
let's say about a amongst a group of
chimpanzees get on one hand.
Yes.
Yeah.
That's the fascination of the unknown
and neuro biologically that's associated
with the positive aspect of exploration.
Yeah.
So that's.
So you,
yeah,
it's a paradoxical situation because if
it's unknown you want to be afraid of it
because it might eat you,
but because it contains new information,
let's say you also want to approach it.
Yeah.
And,
and it,
that's really,
I think it's important,
especially now in our and like our,
our situation to understand the desiring
aspect.
Good.
Because if you can explain a lot of the
strange phenomena that,
you know,
the turnaround sexuality in terms of,
of all the strange fetishization of
sexuality into,
into,
uh,
you know,
sometimes it's opposite,
like the weird,
the weird scatological fetishes that
people have in the strange,
like it's as if there's something about
the,
the or the monster ious or the
discarded,
which can also in a certain instance,
if people let themselves go,
we'll pull them into a,
a desire,
a relationship with that.
Well,
one of the things you do find is that
sexual release like orgasm is
potentiated by novelty.
So that's a good example of that.
Yeah.
And if you kind of go down that route,
it can lead you into,
there is no limit kind of to where it
can lead you and,
and,
and it can explain it.
I think it can also explain kind of like
now we're in this weird paradoxical
situation in terms of society where
since the sixties people have been
telling us,
you know,
that in emphasizing that aspect,
the idea that novelty will increase
pleasure,
let's say bring you further into
pleasure.
But then realizing that if you go down
that road,
now we're kind of realizing,
you know,
it's like,
oh,
now we're surrounded by sexual perverts
and we're wondering why we're surrounded
by sexual perverts.
It's like,
well,
maybe you lead them down that road and
that road doesn't necessarily lead to
just sunshine and rainbows.
Like it leads to very dark places which
include a lot of violence and a lot of,
of,
uh,
of an exploration of,
of animosity and,
and a,
and a mixture of desire and hatred and
all those,
those very strange things that people
kind of let themselves fall into.
Yeah.
Well you might say that that's in some
sense the story of food life.
Yes,
exactly.
I mean,
yeah,
we've talked about that before,
that if you look at full codes,
if you look at [inaudible] life,
he's almost like a microcosm of what's
happening today in terms of his,
he's like radical exploration of power
and sexuality,
but also like the idea of the constant
stranger and the constant anonymous
anonymity of,
of sexual encounters.
Um,
I think that for sure I see him really
as a,
as someone to look at in terms of
understanding the,
the,
um,
the tone of what's happening
today.
It seems to me to be the case.
It's interesting too,
because Foodco dirt,
I didn't care for each other.
No,
I'm,
you know,
foodco basically regarded dared as a
trickster,
as a wordy,
excuse me,
as a wordy trickster and um,
but they,
they are,
their ideas fall into alignment with
regards to the notion of the excluded as
far as I can tell.
Yeah.
Well,
the thing that,
the difference I would say with the,
I,
I find that more useful in terms of,
you know,
I've talked about this in my different
talks about this notion that what's
upside down can be turned back on his
head back on its feet.
And I think that data is more useful to,
to play that game where you can use him
and some of these categories to include
them in a larger frame,
let's say,
so that his ideas are included in a more
complete vision of reality.
Uh,
because he has like,
he really shows the real,
his,
his way of thinking really shows the
real danger,
the real problem of postmodernism.
Like,
you know,
you talk about that,
like how is it that there's this
contradiction,
for example,
his philosophy has been described as
like the philosophy of hesitation,
you know,
and that makes total sense because,
when your face he,
he has this notion that you're faced,
uh,
you know,
and in this slipping and sliding a
analysis of the world where all the,
all,
you know,
reality is,
multiplies itself,
is deferred,
you know,
that,
uh,
things always point towards the future.
So you never know exactly what something
is because it keeps changing and it
keeps,
it keeps slipping into something else.
And so that actually leads to which is
true things.
Exactly.
And would that actually leads to this,
this,
uh,
this hesitation.
And if you've ever seen an interview
with Dr,
you'll see it in his,
in his demeanor.
He's constantly hesitating.
He's hesitating to speak because he's
always kind of like,
he doesn't know.
He,
he realized that he doesn't know the
total implications of what he's about to
say all the time.
So he's always like,
he's,
he's like,
he's constantly cautious and conscious
and cautious.
Um,
and so it seems like that's actually
what should be normally derived out of
the kind of postmodern idea that,
that,
that meaning cannot be contained.
Whereas Fuko,
he really,
he really used the kind of inverted idea
of truth,
the idea of the truth of the marginal,
where you can use marginality as a
weapon to destroy the,
uh,
let's say that the current order data
you think.
Okay,
so you think that's more attributable to
Foodco them to Teradata?
I think so.
What did he do that does it too,
but when he does,
it's weird because he,
he'll use the marginal to kind of
deconstruct the,
uh,
the center,
let's say,
but then he'll also kind of in a set in
the same way,
he'll also say he'll also heal,
like reverse it,
and then an ilet his reversal.
So he ended up really in this slippery
slope where you don't even know where
he,
where you're standing.
Um,
and uh,
and so in my opinion that's useful
because it helps you to see the,
the,
the actually it kind of Indiana did
points back towards logos.
It pointed back towards logos in the
sense that we can,
like we talked about,
you can't live in a world like that.
Okay.
So that's.
So that's,
that's exactly what I want to develop
today.
Okay.
So the first thing that I thought of
today is that,
okay,
so we have this issue of undecidability
from daredevil,
the thing that doesn't fit in the
category.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now.
And we know that if you have a category,
there's way more outside the category
then there is inside the category
because otherwise the category isn't
very useful.
Right?
Right.
And so if Derek talks about that as an,
I think food co two at least alludes to
it,
is that they kind of make the case that
the purpose of the category system is to
exclude and then they make a political
case out of that as well.
Now the thing is,
is the purpose of a category is to
exclude.
It's to exclude an infinite multitude
because you can't deal with an infinite
multitude,
and so you have to simplify the world.
You have to categorize the world in
order to act on it.
Okay,
so
then the ultimate question has to be
something like by what principle do you
or what principal guides your
categorization of the world,
and that seems to me to point back to
the logo in exactly the way that you
just described because I would say the
logos is the divine principle of
categorization or something like that.
Oh,
there.
There are two.
There are actually two ways to do it
there.
I think that I talked about that,
talked about how.
Talking about this in Vancouver,
it's like there's either.
There's three possibilities,
there's either the logos,
there is either absolute dissemination,
which is this kind of the,
the,
the idea that something will just kind
of dissolve.
It dissolves into uncertainty and and
it's important to understand the result
of that.
The result of that isn't that it'll just
stay in this kind of shaky uncertainty.
The result of that is that something
else from the outside,
which has solidity is going to ran
through it and I think that's something
that Dickie that didn't account for,
you know,
for example,
I don't think Dick and die accounted for
Islam for example.
It's like he thought,
well,
if we're all,
if we all,
if we're all kind of in this slippery
slidey situation without from
identities,
then we have no reason to fight.
Right.
That's kind of like the positive
infinite number of reasons to fight.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Exactly.
Or maybe we have an infinite number of
reasons to fight,
but he didn't see that something on the
outside which has strength will just
then just come right through that and
get.
Absolutely.
Well I think he thought he,
he was probably Eurocentric in his
outlook.
Yeah,
that's hilarious.
It is.
It's really hilarious.
Okay,
so.
Alright.
So we've talked about that.
Decide to build it or thinking about
undecidability that we need to mention,
which makes it more complicated is that
undecidability also has to do with time
and so it has to do.
And this is something actually that you
have in common,
I think,
with which you might be funny to say,
but the idea that you,
that something,
let's say you talked about that,
an example of you said like when,
when,
when Ford created the car,
he didn't know what it was because that,
that,
the,
uh,
say the totality of what the car
represents it is,
is,
is manifesting itself in time
manifesting itself in like urban
landscape in the way we understand
economy and in a way.
And so the,
the,
like the ramifications were so big that
you could never know what a car is
that's called talks about in terms of,
of,
uh,
the deferral of meaning in,
in,
in time.
So there's that idea of,
of difference in terms of,
of um,
you know,
like that there's categories in debt,
they're defined by their opposites and
either their outer categories,
but then there's also this idea of time
that makes it more complicated to.
Yeah.
Well,
what that means is that what it is
depends to some degree on the spatial
and temporal context within which you're
interpreting it.
Yeah.
You can say that way.
Yep.
I had a dream about that at one point.
I don't know if it's a digression,
I don't care.
I'll,
I'll tell you.
Anyways,
so I dreamt this is such a strange
dream.
I dreamt that,
um,
there was this ball
floating above the Atlantic Ocean and
uh,
it was just zooming log about,
you know,
six feet above the surface just cruising
along and uh,
it was so powerful that it was
accompanied by four hurricanes,
one in each quadrant surrounding the
ball.
It was only a little ball.
And that was the first part of the
dream.
The second part of the dream was a,
like a view of satellites and a bunch of
scientists who are monitoring the hell
out of this thing,
trying to figure out what it was.
Um,
the third scene was this thing was
trapped in a room.
It was like in a Victorian Museum case,
you know,
what would case with glass and it was
sitting up there like suspended in
midair are inside the case and the same
ball.
Yeah,
there.
So they captured it.
And so then,
um,
it was in the room,
the room had no doors or windows in the
room,
there was the president of the United
States and Stephen Hawking and so that,
and then the room was made out of
titanium dioxide.
I remember that from the dream,
which turns out to be the stuff that the
hall of the starship enterprise is made
out of.
Something like that.
Yeah,
yeah.
It was something like that.
And so the idea was that this intensely
powerful thing had been put inside a
category system.
Right?
So the inside a museum display case,
and then there was the president,
there are sort of representation of
social order and Stephen Hawking,
he was a representation of disembodied
intellect.
And then there was the room itself which
had impenetrable walls.
They were like six feet thick.
So we,
it was like,
we got this thing and then then I was
watching it.
It turned into a Chrysalis.
So obviously,
which is something that can transform.
Right,
exactly.
And then it turned into a mere sean
pipe.
It took me about a year to figure that
out.
It was an illusion to a famous painting
by Magritte.
Right.
This is not a pipe.
Isn't that a pipe?
Yeah,
that's cool.
Actually,
like quite a bit.
Yeah.
And then it shot out of the broom,
like there was nothing there.
Interesting.
Yeah,
that's a great dream.
It was a great dream man.
And so,
and it,
it,
it does allude to this idea that you
can't capture the thing in permanently
in a category system because it shifts
and turns.
Yeah.
So,
okay.
so fine.
So we're on board with that.
Alright.
So now the category has to exclude
because reality is so complex that you
have to categorize it because otherwise
you're swamped.
It's a good metaphor for it.
Yeah.
And I think that's something that the
postmodern is our you that didn't
totally see the extent to which that
could be.
Right?
I think so.
Right.
Absolutely.
I think he,
he,
he put,
I think he thought that order was a lot
more solid than it was.
Yeah.
So,
so,
or then it is.
So then I was thinking,
okay,
so now in with identity politics,
you have the politics of the excluded.
All right,
so,
so then you have people excluded because
of race or because of gender or because
of sexual identity or whatever.
And one of the problems we've seen with
that is that the number of excluded keep
multiplying.
That's why you get that extension of the
letters in the lgbt acronym.
Right.
And there doesn't seem to be any limit
to that.
And the reason for that is there is no
limit to the number or excluded because
it's the category of excluded is the
category of all things that don't fit in
the category system.
And that's an infinite set,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
So,
but then I woke up this morning and I
thought,
well we could do,
we could calculate that mathematically.
So because,
because I was thinking about the rise of
intersectionality,
because the rise of intersectionality,
is that actually the reoccurrence of the
individual within the collective ideas
of postmodern neo Marxism,
because you might say,
well,
I'm excluded because I'm black or I'm
excluded because I'm a woman,
and then someone puts up their hand and
says,
well,
those two categories don't include black
woman.
They don't include the intersection of
the,
of the two categories,
and that there's no reason that black
and woman is more important than black
woman.
Okay.
So then I thought,
all right,
so that's fine.
So the problem is,
is that you start to get smaller and
smaller numbers of people as exemplars
of the categories that are excluded.
So then I thought,
well,
how many categories do you need to add
in an intersectional analysis before
you're actually down to one in a
billion?
Because you do fractionated down to the
individual.
So now it's kind of screwy
mathematically because it depends on the
grid nations of your category system,
right?
I mean,
I could call you old or young,
that'd be binary,
right?
But I could say,
no,
you're on a scale from zero to 100,
so that would,
that would be,
that would give you a point zero,
one probability of there'll be 100
groups that you could belong to in age.
So I thought well let's just use 100 as
an example because it could be two or it
could be 10,000.
It's arbitrary because we could say
that,
well I'm 41 and there's advantages and
disadvantages that go along with that.
But someone else could say,
well I'm 41 in six months and there's a
slightly different set of advantages and
disadvantages that go along with that.
So anyways,
if you have six categories with a
probability of point one,
then you're one in a billion,
so you just need six dimensions of
intersectionality before you
fractionated the population down to the
level of the individual.
So just so that,
that means the individual comes sneaking
back into the collective ideas of
postmodernism once you hit six
intersectional categories.
That's interesting.
That was,
I thought that was really.
Well,
it's ridiculous music.
So I said this will do the trick.
So if you're multiracial woman who's
bisexual,
27 years old,
smart 30th percentile for
attractiveness,
10th percentile for familial wealth and
80th percentile for education.
There's,
there is the.
Oh,
you're the only one in the world like
that.
So,
okay.
So then I was thinking,
okay,
so now then I was also thinking about
this from a scientific perspective.
So the reason you assigned,
if you're going to do an experiment on
two groups,
you know you do something to one group
but not to the other group,
but to make the control group proper,
you have to assign randomly to each
group and the reason you do random
association is because there's an
infinite number of variables you can't
control for.
And so you assigned randomly so that
infinity cancels,
cancels itself out and the only
difference you're left with is the
experimental condition.
And then scientists sometimes try to get
around that.
Like we used to study people who were
sons of alcoholics and multi and they
had a multigenerational family history
of alcoholism.
And then we were trying to figure out
what might distinguish them from a
normal person,
let's say.
So we try to get a control group to
contrast them with,
so we bring them into the lab,
say and give them alcohol and give the
control group alcohol.
But the problem was we didn't know what
to control for,
like,
because alcoholism goes along with
antisocial personality disorder.
So do you control for that?
Um,
do you control for education?
Do you control for Icu?
Do you control for socioeconomic status?
Like the answer is you don't know
because you don't know how those are
associated with the alcoholism,
you can't know.
And so you gas and then you do an
analysis of covariance.
But the problem is,
is that you don't know what to
covariate,
which is why you need random assigned to
groups.
It's the only way of solving that
problem.
Okay.
So the same problem of undecidability in
some sense pops up very,
very frequently in clinical research.
Right?
Same thing happens if you're trying to
figure out schizophrenia,
you need a control group.
Well,
how about siblings?
The siblings who don't have
schizophrenia?
Well,
yeah,
except they have a different geno type,
you know,
it's an,
it's an impossible problem to solve
fundamentally.
Which is why you need random association
to groups because you can't control for
all the variables.
You can't know in advance what's
relevant.
Alright.
So then I had this.
So I thought that was very funny that
the idea of individuality comes back
with intersectionality.
It's,
it's just you just push
intersectionality to six dimensions and
Bang,
you're down to the individual.
All right?
So then I had this little vision,
so I'm going to tell You the vision.
Okay?
Alright.
So imagine a pyramid,
like imagine a plane first,
like at a place in a place,
a land but flat,
and then imagine a pyramid and then
around the pyramid,
some distance from it is a wall.
Okay?
So think about that just as the basic
scheme of a walled city.
Okay.
Now the pyramid is the group that's in
there,
let's say,
and the value structure that that group
orients itself by.
Okay.
Now outside that wall,
there's a very large number of other
pyramids and that's basically the
postmodern world.
I would say that's kind of the world
that they're described and is set
reasonable.
I,
I don't.
Yeah,
I mean could continue or example I
think,
I think that for sure that he did,
he would say would say something like,
when we talk about the problem of the
contain,
even the contained space,
you know,
the,
the idea of the wall and the pyramid,
I'm like,
he would,
he would have,
he would have a problem.
You would have a problem with that
structure itself.
Like for him that would be,
that would be a,
it wouldn't be a solid structure would
have been flooded with time.
Yeah,
right.
That's okay,
we'll get to that.
That's fine.
No problem.
Let's say that is
the problem.
Right?
Okay.
So you added another dimension to it.
The problem is there's an insight and a
wall and an outside.
That's problem number one.
Outside excludes,
we could call that problem number two.
Problem number three is that the center
will not hold.
Right?
Right.
And that's the same problem as far as
I'm concerned as the serpent in the
garden of Eden.
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay,
good.
Good.
So,
so let's say that really is the problem.
I mean fundamentally
yeah.
Usually if you go back to the garden of
Eden and you find the problem somehow,
so
now,
now imagine that outside the,
um,
outside the wall,
all those pyramids fragment and fragment
down to the level of individual people
so they decompose to the level of
individual people because that's how
much variability there actually is
because those groups were artificial
constructions and so you can fragment
them down to the individual.
Okay,
so now the question is you want to let
some of those people into the enclosed.
Okay.
Now,
next part of the vision,
the pyramid grows across on top of it.
Now it's a church,
it's the center.
And the cross represents whatever the
ordering principle of that center is.
Okay.
So then I would say an,
and you're going to add to this because
you did at the beginning of the talk
already,
the cross is the center point of the
world.
It's the axis of the world.
So it's the world tree.
It's also the place of suffering and
it's the place of suffering,
excepted voluntarily and transcended.
It's all of those things.
Yeah.
Okay.
And so that it crosses also assemble of
the hero and the hero is the person who
confronts chaos and gain something of
value from it.
So that's voluntary and the hero is also
the person who recasts the archaic
structure of the structure when it's
necessary.
Right.
And so you see those hero themes
developed quite regularly across any
reasonable historical span of time.
So that's the redeemer,
the Messiah,
right?
It's that makes order out of chaos and
then takes order when it's too rigid and
breaks it apart.
And recasts yeah.
Yeah.
You see that in the story of King David,
you see that actually really well,
like very,
very well.
He,
he breaks like he acts as the pool and
as a,
as someone who is actually a kind of
thief,
trickster figure while the tyrant is in
power.
And then when that tire and fall,
then he comes in and creates a new
centralized order by bringing the Ark to
Jerusalem.
So he has that whole arc and his story.
It's a very good version of it.
Good.
I'll keep that in mind for when I get to
that story.
In my biblical lectures,
all right,
so now you have to open the door on on
the on the wall,
and the question is who do you let in?
So here's the idea,
okay,
so you need to have a center and the
center has to hold because things are
too complex without a center and a
category system,
and then the question is,
let's say that your category system has
to exist in accordance with the process
that creates it and revitalizes it
because otherwise it can't maintain its
stability across time.
It degenerates into chaos or it
rigidified into too much order.
Right?
Okay,
so the only people that you lead into
this,
the inside the wall or those who agree
to live by the rule ethic at the ethic
that symbolized by the cross.
That's two things.
That's the willingness to abide by a
certain level of social organization,
but it's more importantly,
it's also the ability to transcend that
and to participate in the process by
which chaos has confronted and
voluntarily,
voluntarily confronted and reordered and
also to participate in the process by
which order is
broken.
When it's too rigid and brought back.
That's the death and resurrection
essentially.
Yeah.
So those are the only people that you
can let inside the structure without
pose,
without imposing a fatal threat to the
structure itself.
And then if the walls fall,
then the infinite multitudes stream in
and we're done.
No,
I mean we,
it ceases to exist.
It's like you just cease to exist.
That's all,
you know that that's all.
That's all it is.
Right?
Well,
and you'd also say that that's,
that's the problem that's being thought
about in some sense with regards to the
border issue in Europe.
Do we have a right to have a border?
Right.
And then I was thinking today about a
store,
like just take your typical grocery
store and you say,
well it's a,
it's a category system.
Only those with money are allowed to
bring food out of this place.
Right.
And you might say,
well that's,
that's a terrible imposition of
capitalist a patriarchy on and an unfair
imposition of capitalist patriarchy.
So you throw the doors open and you say
everybody come and take what they want.
Yeah.
And that works really well until the
store is empty.
And then that's the end of that,
because if everyone could do anything
they want whenever they want,
then not then it's complete and utter
chaos.
Yeah.
And then what happens is what happens in
it,
because I've lived in a place that is
absolute and utter chaos and chaos
doesn't,
cannot sustain itself.
And so usually what happens is the rise
of a warlord of a tyrant,
the rise of someone who will by sheer
force,
by sheer physical forest,
impose their will on others because the
others will be,
will have nothing to unite them.
And so it's not,
it's not true.
That know a lot of,
you know,
you unique anarchists and people who
think that,
that there is such a thing as like a,
you know,
there's just kind of free anarchy where
everybody's equal and everybody can do
whatever they want.
That doesn't exist because the end,
that anarchy comes a tyrant,
inevitably there's no,
there's no stopping it right
into anarchy comes a tyrant.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
And that's the,
that's the problem with that is that the
fundamental organizing principle,
the tyrant is tyranny.
Yeah.
Pure,
pure power,
pure power.
And pure also a personality cult,
like the,
it's that it's that person instead of
being an ideal onto which we,
we serve,
you know,
our,
uh,
our mythic figure or a or a divine
figure.
It becomes a guy,
you know,
it'd become,
become Hitler or it becomes a,
you know,
it becomes a napoleon or it becomes
solid or become whatever.
Like it's,
it's that person.
Everything is embodied in their
personality.
Like I always say,
like I always have this image of,
of,
of a functional system is,
is the person who in some manner is able
to,
to at least symbolically stepped down
from their power.
They always say that,
that George Washington,
what made him so great is that he,
he really,
he stopped being president.
What created the impetus for the system
to work and in the same,
in the Roman empire like Augustus,
you know,
people will,
will,
will say that he didn't really do it.
But when Augustus became emperor,
he stepped into the city as a citizen
and he gave away all his power.
And by giving away all his,
in a strange way,
he actually became the most powerful
person in Rome,
but his power was not illegal power.
It was like a,
it was like there was something about
his capacity to not be the tyrant,
which,
which stabilized the empire and made him
very powerful,
but in a,
in a strain,
in a very kind of strange way.
It's different.
Right?
So,
so like a legitimate ruler has to be
bound by proper sovereign authority.
Yeah,
exactly.
I can give themselves to the,
to the,
to the Senate and said,
I'm at your service.
And so it made him very powerful.
But you also kind of bound his power in
the Senate,
right?
Right.
Well,
you see that emerging as early as
Mesopotamia,
where Martech or where the emperor had
to act out his,
his embodiment of Marduk in the New
Year's festival in Martech was the go
out hero who went out and confronted the
dragon of chaos and made the world.
And so the reason that the emperor had
a,
it's not sovereignty legitimacy,
that legitimacy is because he was acting
out in architectural pattern that
transcended his own personality.
And then the question is,
well,
what's that archetipal pattern?
And the answer to that is that's the
hero who recasts the tyrannical state
and who confronts chaos.
So the structure that the answer to the
problem of how you maintain a structure
in the,
in the flow of time is that you make the
structure itself subordinate to the
principle by which the structure is
generated.
And that means that the,
the sovereign needs to be responsible to
the word essentially.
That's,
that's how you would think about it from
a Judeo Christian perspective.
And that's above everything.
And it's the thing that does the
categorization initially.
That's when God creates the world
because of the word.
And when Adam named the animals and all
of that.
So,
but also maintains that across time
because it does slip and slide.
Yeah.
So,
you know,
it wasn't really.
See we've been talking about a post
postmodernism,
right?
And,
and about a logo centrism.
And we've been kind of laughing about
that too,
because of,
because of it's referenced to Derrida's
fellow go centrism.
Um,
but it's funny too,
you know,
because if you look at Hindu
representations of the center,
they're not fellow go centric.
The fellows is embodied in the Lingam
and the Yoni,
the Fellas is conjoined with the Yoni.
It's,
it's a masculine female duality that's
at the center.
It's not just the masculine.
And so the idea that that center is
necessarily fell logo centric is,
is also wrong.
Right?
But it,
it,
you know,
the thing is that,
um,
okay,
this is going to get explicit I guess,
but,
but it is foul logocentric,
you know,
the,
even if you imagine the,
the fallis inside the inside,
the,
the woman,
the foulest is the center and the woman
envelops the,
uh,
the center,
the Phallic Center,
you know.
But I think that that would,
I have been trying to get to.
And I think what we've all been trying
to get to,
what you've been trying to get to too,
is,
is to be able to speak of a logo
centrism as in the proper manner that
is,
to understand that to say logo sent,
logo centrist means that we also
understand like the,
uh,
the power of the,
the,
the power of the frame,
let's say.
So the image I have of the,
of local centrism is really,
there's a,
there's an image of the mother of God,
Mary with our hands up like this.
And in her center there's a,
there's a,
there's a circle and out of her
colleagues coming the Christ child and
inside that,
that,
that circle,
you see the stars as if it's like the
entire cosmos,
which is the frame for the logos to
manifest itself in.
And so the idea that
nose open virgin to 14th century where
Mary is holding a globe,
I think generally speaking,
and then she opens up and inside you
have God the father and he's holding
Christ on the cross.
So it's a,
it's a,
it's a similar sort of similar sort of
notion,
right?
And so I think that if we understand it
that way,
it,
there's like an implicit in the notion
of the law of logo centrism there's an
implicit,
a kind of secret mentioned of the power
of the feminine in that very term,
if we understand it fully as the,
the,
the need for the kind of,
the kind of chaotic outside or the
chaotic potentiality which frames the
manifestation of the logos and to
understand that those two things need
each other.
Like the,
you know,
the logos doesn't manifest themselves
without a question,
right?
There has to be a question for there to
be an answer.
And the question is a frame for the
answer.
It's definitely one that's really
important.
That's like super important and it,
it shows how powerful the feminine is
because it actually acts as the,
the,
the category that like,
let's say the frame in which the answer
is given.
Okay.
So,
so let's,
let's develop that for a minute.
So,
um,
let me,
let me see.
I had made me think of something that I
also wanted to tell to talk to you
about.
Oh yes.
So okay.
So you said the frame is determined by
the question that's answered.
Yeah,
if it's asked that.
Good,
good,
good.
Perfect.
So,
so this is where I'd been butting heads
with Sam Harrison,
where you butted heads with Weinstein
in.
In Vancouver,
right.
Okay.
So because the question is,
okay,
so you have to have a category system.
Now Harris basically claims that you can
derive the category system from the,
from the fact.
Right.
But the objection to that is there's an
infinite number of facts and they don't
tell you what to do with them.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I would say instead that you derive
the category system from your aims
because categories are there to,
to help you fulfill your goals.
That's how category systems work.
That's why I think of the mess.
Pragmatic.
Okay.
So now the question is,
given that your,
your category system includes and
excludes and defines the world,
what should be the aim of the category
system,
and so I think that's what the sermon on
the mount talks about because it
basically says what you should aim at
the highest possible good.
You should aim at union with God.
Let's say whatever that might mean,
that you aim at the highest possible
good with fully right,
fully right down to the bottom of your
soul.
If you could manage it so that you're
not broken and band top and twisted in a
bunch of different subpersonalities.
So you try to unify yourself as a force
for the highest good and you do that in
large part by deciding that being is
worthwhile.
Right?
So you pledge allegiance to the concept
of being so you're not.
You're not like Cain and then you speak
truth in the service of that Ba and then
that from that your category system
flows.
So that's another reason that the
pyramid with the cross is the center of
the category system.
Because then you get a category system
that includes what it should include,
if the goal is the establishment of the
Kingdom of God,
let's say,
which is the highest of possible goals
and excludes what it should exclude.
Yeah.
One of the things too that that kind of
differentiates,
let's say Christian a ontology or like a
Christian,
a Christian cosmology,
is that we have this idea that there is
an intimate relationship also between
let's say the highest and the lowest.
There is a.
There is something which which unites
them together completely so that.
So that.
So that even beyond,
let's say there's this capacity to move
outside.
How can I say this to to unite things
together and so there was this idea,
let's say like for example,
there's an idea like the idea of a,
of a normal of a Christian family.
Let's say the,
you know,
the father is the head of the household,
like this idea that people hate today,
but there's this really this sense that
the,
the head or the or the,
the king or the chief
exists
for the,
for the benefit of those that are
dolores,
that are the lowest,
right?
Right.
So that's continually insisted upon in
the Old Testament.
Yeah.
Because the prophets always come up and
say to the king,
you're not attending sufficiently to the
widows and the orphans.
And that means that you've become
corrupt.
Yeah.
And so in a way you can kind of see the
hierarchy moving up in the sense of
things looking up towards,
you know,
into the hierarchy.
But then there's also a really important
men in which the hierarchy moves down.
And so the idea is that the top of the
hierarchy exists for the bottom of the
hierarchy.
It's like,
so the,
so the top of the hierarchy and in a
really important way as a sac is a
sacrificial existence.
So the highest thing is,
is,
is there,
the highest street is the one that
sacrificed itself.
For those that are,
that are,
think about that,
you can think about that practically as
the willingness of a father to care for
an infant.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
So because the infant's obviously the.
And of course the infant also has that
potential,
which is why the infant is made sacred
as well.
And in that,
in that symbolic rail,
so the highest disserving,
the lowest,
the lowest is the infant,
let's say because it's most helpless.
But the infant is also the future of the
hierarchy.
And so the,
I mean I think that that really,
and we've talked about this before
slightly,
is that the,
the,
the notion that the Christian hero,
you know,
I is slightly,
is actually slightly different from the,
the pagan hero for example.
So the night,
let's say in western Christianity,
the night would be the,
the,
the archetipal image of the Christian,
a hero,
which is the notion of an Aristocrat,
a,
a warrior.
You know,
a soldier whose purpose is not to.
It is not only to gain honor on himself,
but in a way he gains on or on himself
by sacrificing himself.
For those who can't do it,
and so he,
his honor is based on the fact that he's
willing to fight for the,
for the widow,
the orphan for those that,
that don't have the strength to fight
for themselves.
And so obviously in reality that doesn't
always play out.
I mean,
but,
but the ideal is there and the ideal is
real and it's the basis of all our,
all our hero movies,
all our hero stories always had this
idea of the hero is the person who is
willing to use their strength and their
power to defend.
Yeah.
To sacrifice themselves for the,
for the week,
which is very different from the pagan
hero.
Like I,
you know,
Achilles.
Yes.
Weakness was contemptible under those
circles.
Right.
And also it's like the only purpose was
to attain honor on ourselves.
So Achilles is sitting in his tent and
he's moping and whining because we've
taken away his sex slave and he won't go
back to fight until it affects him
personally,
you know.
But he,
he,
he's actually not,
he doesn't care that much about helping,
you know,
the Greeks in there,
cause he's really doing that,
doing things for his own honor.
And so he's perfectly heroic and sitting
in his tent and moping and not going
back into,
into battle,
you know,
because his honor has been attained.
Whereas in Christianity,
you know,
in,
in stories like,
uh,
like if you see Sergei one and,
and uh,
you,
you read,
um,
the,
the night and a cart,
for example,
that idea of Lancelot who is willing to
be seen as a,
as a,
as a criminal,
you know,
as the worst kind of person in order to
save the helpless Damsel in distress.
You know,
he's,
he's willing to sacrifice all his honor
in order to help that,
that person who is in danger.
So it's a really,
it's a very different way of seeing the
world.
Okay.
Well,
I don't know what to say after all of
that fit into the whole thing,
but he did have the cross that.
No,
absolutely not.
I'm not.
I'm not suggesting at all that that was
not relevant to the,
to what we've been discussing.
It's dead relevant.
I really liked the idea.
I know we've talked about the fact that
the,
you know,
I've been conceptualized Christ as the,
as the apex of the hierarchy,
symbolically speaking,
but the apex to such a degree that it
actually detaches itself from the
hierarchy,
sort of like horus,
the,
uh,
the uh,
Osprey or the what,
what the hell is he a falcon in Egyptian
symbolism,
right?
He's the thing that flies above
everything that can see or the Egyptian
I add.
Your correction was that it's not
exactly.
Once you're detached in some sense
you're not at the top anymore.
You're everywhere spread throughout the
entire structure,
which,
which is a very good way of looking at
it.
Right?
And the story of Christ is his story and
his symbolism.
You see that he,
he's at the top of the Dome that say in
the church where he's really exactly
what you're saying.
This kind of,
this kind of detached a top of the
hierarchy,
but then he also stretches all the way
down into death,
into Haiti's,
into chaos.
And the cross is the other side where,
you know,
he is,
he's outside of the city being being
killed by,
by his friends,
by the,
you know,
he's the,
the outcasts,
he's all of those things.
And so he,
he unites the two extremes of the
hierarchy together and fills the
hierarchy with logo,
the idea
that he transcends depth.
Again,
I'm just going to take this from a
psychological perspective because the
theological waters are getting too deep
for me here.
Well,
they are because I don't understand it
exactly.
I'm really trying to work it out,
but I don't understand it well enough
yet.
But the idea that Christ descends into
hell and rescues people from hell and
death,
that can be quite straightforwardly
psychologically because the consequence
of not of erecting a,
um,
our category structure that isn't
predicated on the hero is that everyone
will be inhale and die.
So,
I mean,
that's what happened in the Soviet Union
as far as I'm concerned.
And so those health stories are real
enough as far as I'm concerned about,
that doesn't speak to their potential
transcendent reality.
Now there's a whole different issue.
I mean,
here's something else that's been,
that's been bugging me and I'm just
starting to think this through.
You know,
I do think that there's,
there's an idea that if you're in the
right place at the right time,
that everything comes together and lines
up,
you know.
And I was wondering,
you know,
how a story like the story of Christ is
told many,
many ways like from the cosmic to the
microcosmic,
right?
So,
and one of the macrocosmic stories is
the relationship between the
astrological speculations and Christ
himself.
And so there are 12 constellations,
like there are 12 disciples and the
sudden is Christ essentially.
And that story really works and even
maps onto the calendar properly.
And so then you think,
well that's because people have one
interpretation of that is that's because
people have retold the story at each
level of analysis.
But another possible reason for that is
that it's synchronous in some sense.
It is the fact that everything comes
together around that central access in
a,
in a,
in a real way,
and that the story can't help but be
represented at multiple levels of
reality simultaneously.
Yes.
That's what the story is.
That's the,
that that's exactly what it's about.
The whole thing is about this,
this,
this lining up of everything,
of everything.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's hard to see that.
It'd be hard to see the fullness of
that.
When you look at it,
it always kind of jars you because it's
so,
you know,
the story of Christ.
I always tell people like,
if you pay attention to it,
it will constantly be knocking you down
because it,
it,
uh,
it seems even at a first glance
sometimes it seems like it's
contradictory because Christ is all
these things like,
you know,
he's,
he's the teacher,
he's the king,
he's the shepherd,
you know,
he's the outcast.
He's the,
he's,
uh,
he's the,
the,
uh,
the technician,
you know,
he's the artist.
He's.
And so it's like,
how is it that a story can income?
And the more you look in the story,
the why he's a fisherman,
you know,
he's.
And so all these things,
how did all these things can fit in one
story.
It's easy to glance over it because it's
so short.
You're read a gospel,
you kind of go through it.
But then if you really look at all the
aspects and you understand the
traditional categories,
let's say that in the normal world,
the,
uh,
let's say the,
um,
the shepherd and the,
uh,
the agriculturalists usually are not the
same person,
but in Christ they're the same person.
He's able to.
He's,
but we're fish exact.
He's finished,
but he's a fisherman and he is.
So he's the stumbling stone,
but he's also the capstone.
So he's stretched like,
we talk about this idea of stretching
out the entire hierarchy.
So He's,
he's like,
he,
he's,
that's,
he's the stone that doesn't fit that the
builder.
So here's.
Yeah,
right,
exactly.
The builder rejected.
Yeah.
Okay.
So one of the things I've,
I've come to understand about tyrannies
is that if you have a tear tyrannical
person at the top,
the top isn't just at the top.
The tyranny is mirrored the entire
hierarchy,
right?
It's like a,
like a,
um,
what are those three d,
holographic,
a hologram.
It's like a Hologram.
Every part is a reflection of the whole.
And so I wonder if that's analogous.
If you have a pyramid,
say with the principle of the divine
hero at the top,
then what happens is that's reflected at
every single level of the,
of the hierarchy would be with the
tyranny,
right?
Yeah,
it should be.
Except that.
Yeah,
except that the,
the,
yeah,
the tyranny is,
will be just that,
that kind of up down like that top down,
you know,
light that shines down and kind of puts
everything in place.
And then when it reaches the things that
it doesn't,
that it can't absorb,
it'll just,
it'll completely cut them off,
you know,
like it'll kill them,
it'll burn them off,
you know,
it will just destroy them.
Whereas there's something about
Christianity or,
or like a traditional,
a hierarchy which is a stretching out in
so,
so you could imagine,
let's say in terms of,
of,
of all of Christianity.
It isn't
like they're really,
there is,
there's like a,
a,
a place,
let's say for,
at least in in the world there's a play
until the last judgment,
let's say,
until the last judgment.
There's a place for that buffer to be
there and to be slowly assimilated.
Right?
And so,
so it's not,
it doesn't,
it doesn't totally shut itself off a,
there's a,
there's room,
there's a gate,
you know,
like you said,
and there's always people that can come
through the gate and that are always
kind of entering and slowly being a
signified assimilated.
But I've just assimilated but also
transforming it.
You have to,
what it's going to be into what it's
going to become.
But it's a,
but it's not,
it's not a radical process.
It's like this organic transformation,
let's say.
That's a huge part of what we're arguing
about right now.
Culture,
which is,
um,
how is it that you handled the
integration,
let's say,
and the answer is no integration?
No,
because what that does is rigidified the
structure because if you,
if you close it off completely,
you also rigidified inside.
Yeah.
And so what that means is the chaos is
going to break forth inside.
So because you can't get rid of the
chaos.
No,
no.
You know,
one of the things we talked about,
so for example,
with the idea of gay marriage,
so now there's the excluded are
included.
Then the question is well,
what,
what is then the responsibility of the
get included and the responsibility of
the included is to not break the
structure of the system that included
them.
You'd set that yet,
you know,
that's a really,
that's a really good way of seeing that
because that's an,
that's actually probably the best way of
understanding a understanding it in
terms of how it works itself out in real
life.
It's like,
you know,
if you come in,
if you come in as an assimilated margin,
you know,
as,
as a margin that wants to participate
in,
in a country or in an identity or in a
group or whatever it is,
like in a club,
like your responsibility is,
like you said,
is to not break what makes that
something like,
do you know if you want to,
if you want to be a,
you know,
if you want to join a,
a,
I don't,
a baseball group and a baseball team and
you come into the team and you're the
Newbie on the team and you and you all
of a sudden expect everybody to,
to play basketball,
play basketball.
It's like,
well then why,
like what,
what does it destroyed?
It destroyed the club itself.
Exactly.
No,
you think that's a very simple way?
Yes.
Well,
we talked about that a little bit with
the abrahamic stories,
if I remember correctly,
because there was the problem in the
abrahamic stories of how to deal with
the marginal.
So,
um,
I can't,
unfortunately,
I can't recreate that on the flight.
It had to do with hospitality,
hospitality behavior,
right?
So the rule is I show you hospitality,
but that's my rule by obligation,
but your obligation is not to do,
not to make passes at my wife and
disrupt my household.
Yeah.
And then a relationship builds with the
stranger and then,
and then slowly the stranger,
uh,
you know,
it becomes a friend,
and then maybe you then maybe the
stranger,
Mary's your daughter at some point,
right.
It's like,
you know,
there's the,
the,
the possibility of creating a
relationship which will integrate the
two identities together,
but it's a gradual process and one which
has to be done,
you know,
uh,
with mutual respect.
That's right.
Well,
even the proper spirit that would,
I would say that would be the spirit of
the logos because the logo's is also the
thing that goes outside the boundaries.
Like,
so let's say you have a person from
group a here in person from Group B
here,
and then they decided to communicate.
Both of them have to go outside their
group and meet in,
in the junction between the two groups,
which is a different place and they have
to make peace,
but they make peace there under the
guise of themselves as individual.
It's exploratory individuals and then
maybe the groups can integrate as a
consequence of that and they've been
without falling apart and without
fighting.
And if something appears like something
will manifest itself as whatever is,
is holding,
you know,
the two groups together,
the two families are the two people and
so,
so that logos will,
with the coming together,
let's say to families is a good example.
You have two families,
uh,
you know,
and then they and then people in the two
families intermarried and so there's
something that unites them together,
you know,
and,
and it's the coming together that,
that logos will appear and will hold,
hold the relationships in place.
That marriage is a recreation of that
masculine feminine une.
Yeah.
And that's,
that's associated sometimes with the
Androgyny of Christ in sometimes with.
There's an old idea and I can't remember
where it comes from that,
that Adam before eve was a for right?
Yeah.
Or androgynous.
You draw or Androgynous,
right?
And that Christ as the second Adam
recreates that androgyny in the proper
manner.
Yeah.
No,
I think so.
I think that,
that,
uh,
there's a,
um,
there are some use funded in some of the
church fathers where they'll say things
like,
just to help you to understand it and
understand it.
They'll say things that like,
uh,
that God separated Adam and Eve,
Adam into two in view of the fall,
right in the sense that it wasn't the
fall,
but it was the idea that it had to,
it,
it has to do with the,
the idea of living outside the garden,
let's say.
And,
and,
and having them to come back together
and that coming back together in,
in terms of sexual union and in terms of
procreation then is,
becomes a little microcosm of what was
in the garden,
let's say.
And so,
and that's why also,
you know,
like
Adam and I wondered to what degree
that's actually.
Let's see.
I wouldn't say neurophysiologically
true,
but I'm going to say something like that
because it seems to me,
and I made allusions to this when we did
that talk about logos meant people maybe
thought that it wasn't the most
appropriate thing to say,
but sexual union produces this,
this brief union in paradise.
Yeah.
I think that that's.
That's the highest,
that's the highest point of sexuality
and that's why sexuality is used as an
image for the Union of the soul with
God,
and it's used as an image of the Union
of the church with Christ because the
idea that that the unit,
that the Union of the masculine and the
feminine is a glimpse of eternity.
It's a glimpse of.
I'm not sure.
That's just an idea.
Yeah.
I'm trying to think that that's.
That actually happens.
Yeah.
I think that it actually happened.
Yeah,
I think so.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and that's why also,
I think that in,
in Christianity,
the idea of taking that lightly,
it's very dangerous.
The idea of uniting yourself with with
all kinds of people and is very
dangerous because you,
when you unite yourself with someone,
you're actually creating a very powerful
spiritual unity,
you know,
and then if you kind of wonder that
shallow then,
right,
you're,
yeah,
you're devaluing it.
Yeah.
And it also will rip you apart because
you leave a part of yourself with that
other person and you leave a part of.
It's like you leave,
you're kind of still attached to someone
and you're leaving a part of your soul,
whatever it was
that person and they ripped apart.
So you ended up making it might say it
makes you cynical.
Yeah.
Which I would say I think that sleeping
with 100 women would leave you cynical
for sure.
I don't see how it couldn't turn it on.
See how it went.
Yes.
Well that's the question.
Do I think that's a very good way of
thinking about that?
Yeah.
So we
sleeve you in a,
in a position of,
uh,
of,
you know,
like the person who only eats caviar,
let's say,
who,
who doesn't understand how precious
things are,
you know,
and to not understand how precious
things are as to devalue them.
Like if you,
if you,
if that's the highest thing that you're
devaluing,
then you end up like Cain with Abel.
He kills Abel is highest,
and then he says the punishment is more
than he can bear.
So if you take what actually is the
highest value and devalue it,
that you're left without hope.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
I mean,
that's why.
That's why,
I mean,
I don't know,
but it's like the people that I've known
in my life who,
who,
uh,
who sleep around a lot,
they tend to,
to have a kind of nihilistic tendency,
let's say you have a tendency to not.
Yeah.
Well,
things can be discarded.
Yeah.
And,
and,
uh,
and uh,
and that moment of union,
let's say,
is also pretty much devalued to just
brief pleasure.
That's the only way that it's
conceptualized.
You know what it is the case too,
that if you look at early promiscuity
and teenagers,
it's associated with antisocial
behavior.
Yeah.
It's a strong predictor or a strong
correlate of anti social behavior.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Now I'm not saying there was a causal
relationship there,
but I am saying it's part of the same
constellation.
That's quite clear.
So yeah.
Alright.
Well that's probably enough of that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well that was good man.
I was thinking about these things when I
woke up this morning,
you know,
like for about an hour they were just
around in my mind like crazy.
You've got that six.
I did look on you.
I can,
I can kind of discern it now.
Yeah,
well it's too much.
You know,
it's too much is sort of thing really.
So it's like Christ I'd like to get up
in the morning and think about raking
the backyard or something like that.
So.
Oh well that was really good.
Jonathan.
Take things that you think that's good.
Like you think that we've got to what we
wanted to go farther than we have.
If you,
if you want like think about it,
I mean because we,
we had a whole bunch of things that we
said we wanted to talk about.
Um,
I mean maybe we could,
we could make it like a whatever every
two months or every month or something.
So while I'm sure that all have the way
my mind is working right now,
I'm sure that they'll have some ideas
that you will be the right person to
talk to about.
So like I said,
I see you're one of these weird
intersection people.
A,
you're a Greek Orthodox rabbi,
wrote a French Canadian icon carver who
knows a lot about postmodernism.
It's like,
I think there's probably exactly one of
you in the world.
Pretty sure I'm pretty.
So
that is why like I've always been a
marginal person.
That's why I understand it so well.
But I think that the,
the key,
the key to my situation right now is
that I,
I kind of saw it,
but now I also see how it conserve the
center,
let's say.
And so that's my job in life.
I think that's pretty much,
I think what I'm supposed to be.
Well,
that's a good way of ending because the
postmodern claim,
the postmodern Neil Marx's claim is that
the center should serve the margin,
but the counterclaim is the margin
should serve the center and both those
claims are right?
Yeah,
and that's associated with that idea
that you already described of of the
image of Christ as the perfect man
saturating the entire hierarchy.
Yeah.
No,
I agree.
And the first will be the last and the
last will be the first.
There's something about that in
Christianity,
which is absolutely true,
that there that there is even something
at.
There's even something weird that
happens at the end or at the bottom
where there's a mirror reflection
between the bottom and the top where
like the lowest thing would be the fool
for example,
and the highest thing would be the holy
fool,
and so there's this strange completion
that happens in the whole thing,
but it's really a very.
It becomes very mystical at that point.
It's hard to describe in in straight
categories,
but the,
the marlow was kind of a good example of
that while I'm asking myself and asking
myself that for months,
you know,
I did that interview with Dr Rachel and
Brown about Milo and by the way,
she really liked.
We'd like to talk to you anyways,
so that,
that the thing I'm wondering about him
is that in the,
in the holy fool,
usually there's a lot of self
depreciation and so St Francis,
you know,
he would go out into the public space
and strip naked,
you know,
and he would,
he would pass for a,
for a beggar and all those things.
And so I think that that might be a
requirement for the holy pool is,
is that the,
the,
the humor is not only against the people
around them but also it turns back on
themselves constantly.
And so that's what makes them,
the holy fool is that,
is that you can't criticize them because
as,
as much as they're criticizing the ruler
or the structure or the order,
it turns back on them and then they act
as the lowest of the low.
So there's,
that's what is,
is,
uh,
is able to hold them to,
to hold them in that high place.
So something to think about.
Okay.
Alright.
Alright,
well I'm gonna cut the front of this off
maybe a little bit and then it's going
to post it.
So.
Alright,
cool.
Alright.
Alright,
good luck with everything.
Yeah,
I've got another lecture tonight.
Oh,
the electric end of Jacob's ladder.
Yeah.
So now I have to go prepare that.
Huh?
So wait,
let me,
let me think about Jacob's ladder two
seconds.
Did you ever watch that talk on,
on uh,
on Moses and the assent of my talk I
gave on the,
on,
uh,
it's called,
the life of Moses,
Saint Gregory,
Saint Gregory of Nissan.
The life of Moses.
You should watch that.
If you have time you should watch.
It's like it's like 45 minutes and it's
really about the ascent of the mountain
and the ascent up the holy ladder.
Would you email that to me?
Yeah,
I'll send you the link.
I'm completely out of brain.
How send.
I'll send you the link right now,
I think.
I think that might be helpful for you
for your talk tonight.
Can I get some rest?
You'll get.
All right.
Bye.