Really,
you should have read by now.
Well that little book that,
uh,
what's it called?
Thought emotion and memory should have
read the three or so papers in here.
Maybe there's four of them.
Four and also the first,
well the chapters in this book up to the
end of the neuropsychology section,
which is basically to page 80.
So that's what we've covered today.
Yeah,
sure.
I showed you a simpler diagram of this
sword last week and that's
okay.
The model of the known normal loud
amputation.
Let me show you a little cartoon here
that I think is kind of funny.
All right.
So as far as I can tell that's a decent
but simplistic model of what it is that
you know,
when you say that,
something with regards to its
implications for behavior or its
meaning,
because remember,
that's what we're,
that's what we're trying to specify in
this class,
right?
The initial introductory discussions
hinged on the notion that when we map
our environments as a consequence of
active exploration,
we mapped them for two reasons.
We want to specify the sensory nature of
the things that we encounter.
And we also,
more importantly,
more fundamentally,
perhaps not more importantly,
but more fundamentally,
we really want to keep track of where
the meanings reside.
Now this is coopera coded by something
that we'll discuss to some degree today,
which is that things aren't simply given
in the environment.
I mean it's,
that's the case with sensory things even
although there's a lot of dispute about
this.
I mean that was coons fundamental point
as far as I can tell him.
His book,
the sign,
the structure of scientific revolutions
in that what constitutes the object of
objects seems to shift as we shift our
techniques of exploration,
which is why we have new scientific
theories.
I mean,
theoretically there's something at the
bottom of it all towards which were
towards,
which are ideas are approximating.
But anyways,
it's a difficult,
it's a difficult idea,
but it's much more clear in the case of
our maps of meaning because how you
approach something really does determine
in large part,
it's an effective significance,
right?
We can all,
you can all see this fire for animals is
dangerous,
pure and simple,
but fire for people is liberal,
has been liberating.
That's,
I mean that's the most sort of the most
dramatic example I can think of,
right?
You switched the motivational category
of the object by altering your approach
to it.
It's dangerous if you let it burn you.
If you control it,
then it cooks your food and it heats
your cae and et Cetera,
et Cetera,
and it's something I'll buy an
alteration in your action.
You've completely transformed the nature
of the object,
at least with regards to its utility and
that's a big part of what we consider
creativity.
Anyways.
One of the things I've been trying to
figure out is what's this?
What is the structure of our knowledge
when we say that we know something and
that's this,
the gnome and it's a bounded domain
basically that's characterized by
specification of the emotional
significance of what's going on in the
present,
at least as far as that's interpreted
and specification of what we would like
to happen in the future and then the
construction of motor plans to turn one
into the other.
Now I've appended or updated this
diagram,
someone from its original simpler form
to show that,
well,
you were attempting to transform this
into this things that you don't expect
might happen,
which is,
and that's pretty obvious if you think
about it,
because fun expect that things didn't
happen.
That would mean that you knew everything
and you don't know everything.
So that means it unexpected things are
always happening
if you're undertaking a behavior that's
designed to meet a certain end and
something unexpected happens.
Well,
hmm.
That activates a chain of phenomena
that I described later that we're going
to discuss today as the orienting
reflects.
But basically the bottom line is that
anything unexpected is the UN in and of
itself intrinsically meaningful.
That's really,
really important.
MMM.
We don't assign meaning to things so
much as we do restrict the meaning that
they already offer us to it,
to a specified domain.
And,
uh,
if you think about that,
that kind of reverses has a,
as I've mentioned before,
that reverses many normal psychological
presuppositions,
which is that we have to,
that things are neutral until we
discover it useful to them.
Okay.
So I told you this story or you read the
story perhaps about the guy who's
thinking about his performance.
At some meeting he's thinking about how
well he's going to do and how he's going
to dominate the meeting and so on.
He runs and he runs into a number of
obstacles on his way to the meeting,
including an elevator that won't
function and people who get in his way.
And the reason I told the story in the
book is to just to show you how this
sort of thing operates in day to day
life.
It's a pretty boring story.
I mean nothing particularly exciting
happens I suppose until the end.
Nothing exciting.
Happens means only unexpected things
occur,
nothing exciting happens.
Meaning means no emotion is released in
the course of the story until the end
because all of the things that are
unexpected are trivial,
unexpected things that all occur at the
level of of minor lea plan.
So my guy is upset by the fact that the
elevator doesn't come,
but that's not such a catastrophe
because he can always take the stairs
and if someone's
ahead of you on the sidewalk and you're
in a hurry,
while you can always go around them.
These are pretty minor deviations and
they're interesting and they do inspire
a certain amount of emotion.
But all they mean is that you have to
shift from one sub goal to another.
And then at the end of the story,
well,
events of a different magnitude to
occur.
And the idea there is that,
well,
the protagonist of this story that's
outlined in the book,
he's expecting a commendation for his
performance in the recent meeting and
instead he gets fired.
And in a sense you could say,
well,
all hell breaks loose as a consequence
of that because that information which
can be easily denied,
blows his whole world.
It isn't something as simple as an event
that interferes with a particular plan,
a sequence of behavior.
It's something that demonstrates
incontrovertibly.
And this whole notion of the ideal
future is impaired in some nontrivial
manner.
And that his viewpoint of himself in
relationship to the world is
dramatically and drastically flawed.
Well,
the thing is,
you don't need to know a lot of the
things that we've been talking about to
start to make sense out of this thing.
You know,
that if you get fired from a job that's
a catastrophe or something ochres to
make you a really quick question,
your own abilities or,
or where you're going or,
or where you've come from,
that people find that very emotionally
disruptive and well,
the,
the answer to,
well,
what does it mean by the fact that
people find that emotionally disruptive
is to say that well,
things that aren't predictable have
their own effect of valence and you
render things predictable using a Schema
of this sort.
And if something comes along to blow
your Schema,
then all those things that you've
rendered predictable with regards to
your current patterns of behavior are
all of a sudden unpredictable.
And if they're unpredictable,
most particularly,
they're frightening.
That's the first thing that comes up.
His reaction to the elevator and the
traffic.
All right.
Absolutely.
The
distinction between,
uh,
losing,
not the scenario now working anymore,
like losing confidence in this scenario
and losing confidence in himself as a
scenario maker.
I mean there seems to be
very,
yeah,
the perfect,
perfect.
Yes.
That's perfectly reasonable be,
is that a useful way?
Because I was trying to go yes.
Rotated.
Just think it really different.
No,
no,
that's a,
that's a perfectly reasonable,
uh,
that's a perfectly reasonable comment.
Exactly.
The thing,
think about Tom Punishments.
You know,
we know that punishments produce pain,
for example,
they produce hurt.
That's a,
that's the effect of state,
I mean formal punishments and we'll
define what they are later.
Um,
the thing about people though is that we
can generalize and,
and in animals you can punish out
particular patterns of action and human
beings.
You can punish out hierarchies of action
right down to the level of the action
that generates action.
And that's basically what are the action
that generates patterns of action.
And that's what you're talking about.
See if you really punish someone,
then they lose faith in their ability to
adapt.
And well,
when that happens,
while you're depressed,
well,
you're not just depressed,
be depressed,
doesn't,
you're not just hurt.
Depressed doesn't just mean you're hurt.
Depressed means while you're in pain.
This is literal by the way,
it's,
it's not.
It's not metaphorical.
About 70% of people who are chronically
depressed have chronic pain syndrome,
low back pain,
migraine,
et cetera.
The two things look very closely
related.
Phenomenologically you also lose all
hope,
but what does that mean when all,
we're going to talk about that a little
later,
but these aren't metaphors.
Look,
whenever you put in this box is a
consumer Tory reward.
It's a satisfaction by definition.
This is what I want to talk about this a
little bit more than the neuro psych
section.
We know about satisfaction,
but there's four classes of
motivationally relevant phenomena.
There's punishments and there's
satisfaction.
Those are primary positive and negative
reinforcers in somewhat archaic
behavioral language,
punishments and satisfactions,
and then there's cues of punishments,
accused of satisfactions and cues of
satisfaction give you hope,
but they're always conceived of in
relationship to some goal.
You lose the goal.
Well,
you lose hope.
That's what,
that's exactly what happens literally.
So if your goal has come tumbling down,
and the thing is,
the other thing you have to realize is
that your goal is always conceived of in
relationship to your conceptualization
of yourself because you always view
possibility in relationship to what you
think you can accomplish.
So these two things can't.
That's why this is a system.
You know,
this cannot be conceived up except in
relationship to this.
And vice versa.
You always construe where you're going
with regards to your conceptualization
of your current level of abilities and
possibilities and so on.
And you evaluate the utility and
desirability of what you have currently
in relationship to the best that could
possibly be.
So it's a system,
it's a system.
This is the known.
As long as you're operating in this
territory,
you're aware exploration has already
taken place fundamentally.
So you're protected by your culture.
That's one way of looking at it.
You're protected by your particular
story anyways.
That's assuming nothing really
dramatically unpredictable is going
wrong.
So you referred to a scenario,
so it would be right.
Would it be right to say that whole
thing is a scenario.
I mean that's a story is absolute.
That if that's something that that's a,
we have a representation of it,
then it's,
and that's abstract.
So in that sense we are a scenario
makers we made.
Yes.
Right?
And this is the thing that's
interesting.
I think one of the things that's
interesting about that is that the
scenario from a mythological
perspective,
that's the world.
That's how,
that's like myth from the mythological
perspective,
which is concerned with meaning and not
with sensory qualities.
The world is what you know,
what you don't know,
and the mediating process between the
two and the mediating process,
by the way,
is what you were referring to because
the mediating process is the thing that
creates order out of chaos or upon
occasion that turns chaos and door or
order into chaos as well.
It's the transformative process.
Anyways.
If you lose faith in that transformative
process,
that's the end of you.
Fundamentally.
I mean life comes to a halt and that's
why,
well as we'll find out many,
many,
many religious systems,
if not all religious systems attempt to
catalyze identification with the
transformative process as their aid to
the good life.
Anyways.
Um,
okay,
so this is a story.
It's a story.
The story is,
well,
things aren't so good now,
but they're going to be much better in
the future and this is how we're going
to bring it about.
That's just your straight linear story.
That's a scenario and you have your
particular story and do you have your
particular story to the degree that you
share cultures,
there are some elements of your stories
that are identical.
So I was thinking the mark this other
day,
you know,
like if you read in the newspaper that
Congress is going to cut off funding to
a cognitive psychologists who specialize
in vision.
Then all of the cognitive psychologists
who specialize in vision,
to the degree that they share that story
going to be threatened by that
particular piece of news because it's
interfering with their scenario.
They're are going to band together as a
group and they're going to do whatever
they can to to Perry the threat.
Now if you read that we'll all cognitive
psychologists funding is going to be
cut,
then your reference group is all of a
sudden expanded because you pulled in a
larger number of people who share the
presuppositions of your story and then
you could say,
well,
if it was all psychologists,
that would be a larger group and if it
was all uh,
academics,
that would be a larger group and so on.
And you can see that as,
as the threats are more and more
fundamental,
the groups that are effected get larger
and larger and well anyways because
you're including more and more people
under the rubric of the same story.
If your country is under attack from
foreign forces,
then it's the constitution in a sense
that's at risk and everything.
That's kind of the trunk of the
presupposition tree so to speak.
And everyone's going to unite against
that
threat or virtually everyone is going to
unite against it.
This is like a shared experience for
normal adaptation,
snare and can help.
And thinking like people with anxiety
disorders,
like the ideal future would be to get on
the elevator and know and that it would
come and it would go down and there
would be no problem with that.
And that's the unpredictable,
that's the big problem.
Like so if the LDL number comes or they
get stuck in the elevator or something,
that's chaos.
Like that's,
that's the end.
Predictable expense.
So I was just wondering on this chart,
like how would you map
oh well the,
okay.
The thing is is that any,
hmm.
Phenomena have ambivalent meanings.
And this is something that I referred to
in the chapter.
Neuropsychology,
is it an event that can be construed
with a particular motivational relevance
from one frame of reference can be
construed from a different frame of
reference in,
in a completely different matters.
So let's say you're on your way to the
meeting and you have an anxiety disorder
soul,
you're afraid of elevators.
Okay.
So the elevator doesn't come well with
regards to the story that says,
I want to go to the meeting.
Then the fact that the elevator hasn't
shown up,
it's very anxiety provoking.
And perhaps frustrating and punishing,
but from fruit with reference to the
frame of reference that says,
well,
I'm the kind of person who can't
tolerate taking elevators.
It's relief that not that the elevator
not showing up brings about and then
your neck motor output so to speak,
is a function of the competition between
between those two frames of reference.
I don't know exactly how that
competition plays out,
but like virtually everything that you
can possibly conceive of how has
motivational significance is that vary
with the frame of reference and you do
this to yourself like you can look,
this is really not complicated enough
unfortunately,
and I'll draw the map that we'll use
later.
This is just the note.
Well anyways,
this is actually more like how this
diagram should look.
You get the picture,
okay.
Now
these are more or less comprehensive
stories and damage to the story can take
place at any level of analysis.
The higher up on the or the the more
inclusive the place at which the damage
takes place.
The more behavioral adaptation is a
rendered useless and the more phenomena
are transformed.
Once again back into chaos from,
from from whence they came from the
mythological perspective as you'll find
out.
Cause the next thing you're going to do
is read the Sumerian creation myth and I
tried to map it onto the kind of just
descriptions that we'd been talking
about,
the Sumerian creation.
I had a good dream about this last
night.
I'll tell you about it can benefit the
Sumerian creation myth is particularly
relevant because,
well it's been said that history began
in summer.
So in a sense it's the most ancient of
creation stories that we have extent
that it has been transmitted down into
our culture along the line that our
culture came from.
Basically I dreamed last night that I
told this class,
although the class was like slightly
different in my dream that we all have
Sumerian skeletons.
Just in a weird way of looking at what
their point is.
This,
you know,
it's only been,
it's only about 5,000 years that
separate us from the Sumerians and you
had to take who are,
you know,
that's a long time.
We have nothing in common with them.
But there's a bunch of ways to look at
that.
Like that's only 60 80 year old men,
so we're not,
which if you think about that 80 years
old and then another 80 year old man and
so on,
that's only 60 entire,
moderately long lifespan.
This is nothing,
you know,
and it's nothing when the evolutionary
perspective,
because we'd been around as well as a,
as a species.
Exactly like we are for 150,000 years
and something similar to what we are for
at least 2 million,
so like 5,000 tears.
That's nothing.
That's yesterday.
We're still scenarios.
When you read that creation myth where
you want to think about it with relate
in relationship to the things we've been
talking about,
the Sumerian say,
well everything emerges from chaos.
Like what the hell does that mean?
Well it means
it means most basically that everything
that you understand comes from the
domain that has not yet been explored.
That's a chaotic domain cause he can't
say anything about it.
There's no distinctions drawn.
Plus it has infinite motivational
relevance.
You can specify it.
That's very chaotic.
Ken.
Those things that you haven't yet
explored are simultaneously punishing,
satisfying,
and threatening and promising all at
once and none of those as well.
Anyways.
So anyways,
when,
when I say things like,
well,
um,
interference with a structure of this
sort of reduces everything to chaos and
that chaos is in some sense equivalent
to the chaos that existed before the
creation of things.
That's what all that means is kind of
the,
you know,
you just think about it as a
metaphorical language,
I guess.
Anyways,
this is a better model.
So,
uh,
you know,
to use the university example,
all cognitive scientist specializing
envision would be here and all cognitive
psychologists would be here and that all
psychologists would be here.
That's one way of looking at it anyways.
Okay,
so
recipe,
yes.
When you're talking to,
you were talking about how much anxiety
is caused by the absence of the
elevator.
Yeah.
You're referring to it as a function of
what your interpretive scheme is,
but also how much of it has to do with a
sort of more basic biological function
of how much tolerance,
I mean,
given individual has or unknown.
I mean that's a tough question.
I mean it looks like there are all
these,
these four systems so to speak.
Well that's the satisfaction,
punishment,
promise and hope systems.
From the subjective perspective,
they all seem to have thresholds for
activation.
So if your threshold for activation of
your incentive reward system is low,
it looks like you're likely to be
extroverted.
You're very happy and social situations,
you smile easily,
you talked a lot,
et cetera.
And that's something that's biologically
determined.
And the same with regards to your
response to threat.
You could have a high level,
a high threshold or low threshold and
you make dilla well,
but then it really gets complicated
because the problem is is that what you
construe as threatening or promising
depends on your framework of
interpretation.
Nobody knows how that plays into the
biology.
So
whether those two things can be
separated because well I think in
principle they can be,
because I think it would be possible.
Say if I,
if you and I both went into the lab,
a lab,
you could say,
well,
we're under the same,
more or less the same set of precepts.
We're governed by the same set of
presuppositions in that laboratory
circumstance.
So say they give us both a goal directed
task that's very bounded and uh,
a set of phenomenal occurs and,
and I get more,
more anxious by physiological measures,
then you do well,
assuming that we've held the framework
of reference constant,
we might be able to say something about
the intrinsic biological differences,
but it's very,
it strikes me as very difficult,
isn't the interpretation.
We have pastors that are going to be
dependent on what we imagined,
how we naturally react anyway.
I would suspect so.
Yeah.
So I,
I don't know,
like I really don't know the answer to
your question.
Um,
I mean it's obviously the case that you
can modulate the motivational
significance of phenomena merely by
shifting frameworks of reference.
I think you can say,
well,
if you're very upset,
save just a relationship you had is just
broken up and you think,
you know,
while this is finally going to kill me.
And so you have very temp temporally
bounded interpretation of this,
this is absolutely catastrophic and what
am I going to do tomorrow?
And then you think,
well
is this really going to mean anything in
five years?
And you know from that perspective like
how relevant is this phenomena with
regards to my five year plan,
for example,
it's relevance is going to shrink
dramatically.
And you might say,
well how much is it gonna mean to me in
40 years?
And you think,
well under those circumstances it
dwindles to absolute triviality.
And you can say,
well what does any of this going to mean
in a thousand years?
And then you have an existential crisis.
But the thing is,
because you can,
that's an,
it's very interesting because you can
modulate the motivational relevance of
phenomena by shifting your framework of
reference.
It looks to me that paper by John
Duncan,
the first paper in here,
me in a sense that's sweet.
But he says the frontal cortex does,
at least in part,
is that I think,
well,
going back to the neuro psych,
I think the near the frontal cortex says
hijack the more motivational systems to
give us increased adaptive flexibility
like animals.
Oh,
this gets us into a big argument,
a big disagreement about what
constitutes an unconditioned stimulus.
You know,
lots of behaviors think there are such
things as unconditioned stimulus,
which are just those things that you
will respond to automatically.
Like electric shock,
you know,
that's bad.
It's anxiety provoking.
While more particularly it's punishing
if it's of sufficient intensity,
it hurts.
But the problem with that is is that you
know,
you can take a dog.
Yeah.
And if you give it food just after your
shock,
it soon,
when you shock it,
it wags its tail.
Well that means that the effect of
relevance of the unconditioned stimulus
is at least modifiable by learning.
And almost all I'm conditioned so called
unconditioned stimuli,
have that property.
So,
and we know that,
you know,
people,
people have an immense amount of
disagreement about what constitutes good
goods.
For example,
like anorexics don't like food.
And they starve to death.
So it's a bad decision.
But the point is is that even something
as fundamental as food,
the motivational relevance of that can
be shifted by shift in the framework of
reference.
So you can say,
well the anorexic is caught in a
situation where her unvariable present
his,
you know,
my terribly fat body,
although no one else might construe it
in,
in that,
in that manner that's hers and her ideal
future is I'm thin,
thinner than anyone else and that
there's an associate of network around
fin so to speak,
that includes beautiful,
well liked,
admired rich,
you know,
whatever the hell you want to throw in
there.
And in relation that makes food in
relationship to the movement from here
to here,
something punishing and threatening
because it interferes with it.
So then it takes on the motivational
significance of a threat or a
punishment.
And of course,
well she still gets hungry.
Okay,
so there's going to be a heavy,
heavy dose of internal conflict.
That's an internal conflict.
Means in part is you're internally
conflicted about a stimulus.
If it has one significance for one of
your plans.
And an alternate significance for
another plan and you have an integrated
the two plans into something that's
into a higher order construction where
there's no conflict.
So that that's a problem.
You're saying how if you're too rude by
your ideal future,
crazy anxiety
or if you're an,
you don't have cause you sense of how
the teacher and if you don't move.
All right,
is there some kind,
and then even talking about about
relativity perspective a year,
four years,
four years and is there such a thing as
a balance because there's what four
universally,
what is enough of just sort of move you
on?
Yeah.
Well you know this is,
this is one of the things we're going to
hope cancer over the course of the whole
course.
I mean I said,
well in a sense I said everything is
relative because you can shift the
motivational significance of phenomena
by shifting your frame of reference.
But also said that if you think food is
evil,
you'll start.
So obviously there's those two arguments
in a sense or in conflict.
I mean it is possible for you to believe
that food is a punishing item.
But if you do believe that there will be
certain consequences,
like you won't be able to pursue any
other plans because you'll be dead.
So
I'm interested in trying to resolve the
argument that those two arguments are
resolved.
The problem that those two arguments set
up on the one hand while we need to eat,
although people can regard food as a
punishment,
on the other hand,
you can switch the motivational valence
of things by an with an act of will,
so to speak.
So it strikes me that there's a high
probability that certain phenomena will
be regarded as satisfactions and we'll
take on the aspects of consumer Tory
rewards.
One of those high probability items,
for example,
is food.
You know,
that's why I have a quote here.
We'll show you this quote
from Nietzsche.
Nietzsche said,
anyone who considers the basic drives of
man,
it's a very sophisticated idea.
It's a 100 years old.
We'll find that all of them have done
philosophy at some time and that every
single one of them would like only too
well to represent just itself as the
ultimate purpose of existence and as the
legitimate master of all the other drugs
for every drive one is to be master kind
of attempts to philosophize in that
spirit.
So I've been trying to resolve this,
all these dilemmas that are posing the
dilemma,
for example,
that shock has this significance of an
unconditioned stimulus,
but it can be shifted.
It looks to me that what happens is that
these underlying biological systems like
the one that governs hunger,
has the capacity to grip,
to gain access to the representational
system that constructs these futures.
So for example,
you say,
well,
you're basically doing your homework and
you haven't eaten for a long time.
So now your warp rating within a
particular frame of reference.
So you're,
the action of doing your homework is a,
it's a motor program that's part of a
larger series of goals and sub goals,
right?
Graduation,
career and all that.
That's what you're busily pursuing,
but you haven't eaten well.
So what happens is that your attention
starts to get diverted,
which basically means that the system
that's responsible for ensuring that you
get enough calories has started to,
has started to take control of the
representational system and the
constructs your ideal futures.
So you start thinking about food.
It's like that's another,
a fantasy that's making itself known in
the theater of your imagination.
And if you keep doing your homework and
don't eat long enough while you're going
to start feeling conflict because you're
switching between these two control
systems basically,
and sooner or later in all likelihood,
the system that mediates food intake is
going to get the upper hand and you'll
say,
oh,
to hell with it because that's your
interpretation from the perspective of
finishing your homework and you'll go to
the fridge and get something to eat.
So when nature says,
all our drives a template,
philosophize basically,
see this is the way you fit.
The reason I'm trying to tell you this
is because it gets away from the notion
of stimulus response because it's not,
your hunger isn't driving you towards
the fridge.
It's not like it's gripping your
behavioral output.
What it's doing is positive,
a potential future towards which you can
plan and it has the capacity to grip
that future.
That's Nietzsche's attempts of the
drives to philosophize.
So you'd say,
well you think about this,
so we defined pathology in this way.
Often say,
well if you're,
if everything in your life boils down to
food,
that's your God.
Say That's your ideal futures,
you eating as much and as often as
possible.
Well then we would say somethings
something is pathological about your
scheme of representation or your
behaviors.
Something's pathological about your
personality.
While part of the reason we say that is
because food is a good sub goal,
it's necessary sub goal,
but it's a bad ultimate master.
While the question in part that we're
going to try to address in this class
is,
well given that food saying sex and
water and heat and shelter and all these
other things are necessary sub goals,
what would constitute the ideal master?
Well,
you read this,
you want to read this Sumerian creation
myth with this in mind.
So I say these are gone.
So that's one way of looking at it.
It's a little bit more complicated than
that.
Um,
they,
well,
here's another quote.
This is quite funny.
I think too,
this is from Eliana with regards to
Sumerian mythology.
It is true that man was created in order
to serve the gods who first of all
needed to be fed and clothed,
not such a,
you know,
not such a foreign conception really.
Well,
the guards are construed as
transpersonal processes that are eternal
fundamentally,
and a man mortal man is created in order
to ensure that their needs are
fulfilled.
Anyways,
of course,
you're going to think at least some of
you're gonna think that that's a bit of
a leap.
But
it's quite interesting to read the,
the Mesopotamian creation myth,
and part of what it entails is
hierarchical competition between the
gods and the eventual victory of one God
who's,
as part of the movement towards
monotheism.
And Marduk,
by the way,
is the one God who reveals himself as a,
at the top of the hierarchy.
And what more Martech represents is the
capacity to explore.
So the Mesopotamian creation myth based
because Marduk it's very interesting.
MARTICA carves tie mat up tire.
Matt is a dragon.
She represents chaos.
She's also the mother of all things.
Marta carves tie that up and makes the
world out of her.
It makes the sky,
it makes the earth,
makes the Zodiac.
He makes one.
In fact,
one of this is very amusing,
one of Mark's names cause he has like
200 names because actually he's a,
he's a mixture of gods.
Mesopotamian culture was made up of a
whole bunch of subcultures that mailed
it over a long period of time.
And all those subcultures had their own
gods and they all got sort of mixed
together to make Martech.
So Murdoch had a whole bunch of names
and one of his names,
for example,
was the maker of ingenious things from
the combat with Tire Mat,
which is very,
very interesting.
But anyways,
the Mesopotamians figured out,
although they didn't know they had
figured it out,
they figured out that the thing to which
all these other drive should be made
subordinate was the thing that was Marta
and Martin was the thing that carve new
territory out of unexplored territory
because basically they manage to presume
that if you didn't arrange your life so
that you could constantly generate new
information,
everything would come to a halt.
So everything should be made subordinate
to this capacity to encounter the
unknown and generate new information on
it because all of the other drives were
necessary dependent for their
fulfillment on that particular function.
So it's,
it's very,
it's very interesting.
It's once you understand,
if you understand that,
I think you understand something that's
unbelievably important.
That's part of the reason why I think I
dreamt last night we had Sumerian
skeletons because now there's more to it
than this of course,
because Marduk was also the ritual
mortal of emulation for the Mesopotamian
emperor,
which basically meant that the
Mesopotamian emperor was emperor because
in a sense he was Marduk and only to the
degree that he was Marta was he granted
any sort of divine status and the
emperors,
the embodiment of the state,
and of course our state now as a body of
laws and not a,
not a human body because we don't have a
monarchy anymore.
But the point is is that states only
work too if they recognize that the
property that Marta incarnated is,
is the thing of most central importance,
which is the capacity of the capacity
for exploration.
Anyways,
that was a good digression.
Alright,
neuropsychology,
but you have to bounce around these
things in order to get a picture of them
and
now the question,
right,
right.
Well they,
well that that's the ideal solution at
least as far as the Sumerians were
concerned.
And like we're going to explore the
consequences of that solution as a
solution because it has a whole,
a whole series of important
implications.
It's a solution.
Now I happen to think it's really a good
solution,
but we'll,
we'll,
we'll see how plays out.
But
yeah,
the thing is
you're not determined so to speak
because the stimulus doesn't control
your behavior.
Nonetheless.
There are certain you are constrained,
which is to say you have boundaries and
I can say with a high probability in a
broad variety of conditions,
what you are likely to consider a
conservatory reward.
And I can say that because you're
composed in part of specialized
subsystems,
each of which have a stake,
each of which have their own job pluses,
stake in maintenance of the whole unit,
which is you.
So they want what they want,
but they also want you to stay around so
to speak,
because without you nothing happens.
And that's what the Sumerians meant when
they said that men were created to serve
the gods.
So the relativity is modulated by the
fact that you have a number of competing
tasks constantly to perform.
Uh Huh.
So well that's why that's one way of
construing it anyways.
So question
systems or these,
can they ever,
in cases of really extreme severe
deprivation,
can they directly grab control of the
motor output or must they always go,
they always affect behaviors
that,
I don't know.
I suspect,
I suspect that there's probably,
there's both operating like in
situations that are so extreme that
thought would be an interference rather
than an aide,
then I suspect there's direct output.
Um,
but I,
I can't say anything because that's the
problem with trying to reduce the brain
to one system of operations.
There's evolutionary redundancy in the
brain and often for a given type of
response,
there's more than one system that has
the capability for that response.
And there was some circumstances under
which I suspect behavior is directed,
directly controlled,
but I think this is more relevant when
you're trying to weigh potential
alternatives.
Like,
let's say if you're hungry and thirsty
and you haven't been engaged in a
romantic relationship for like a year
and uh,
uh,
your job is under pressure and you're
not getting along well with your
children,
well then you have a whole nest of
problems to solve and uh,
an almost infinite number of potential
solutions to those problems.
And I think the role of the higher order
critical systems is to modulate the
fantasies that all of these underlying
systems so to speak,
might produce in order to construct the
optimal outcome.
And that's well here you'd say,
again,
this is a story I keep telling you.
This is a story.
Well,
that's a vision of paradise.
That's what's up here as the archetype
of ideal future and a vision of
paradise.
Well that's the land of milk and honey,
right?
Where everything is bound to fleet
provision where every
motivational system is,
is properly addressed.
While there's a problem with that
viewpoint that Dostoyevsky pointed out
and all of that,
that is this,
that well,
if everything's perfect,
everything's predictable and
everything's predictable,
then you're bored and bored.
Boredom is not part of perfection.
So perfection is not perfection and
that's a big problem and that's not a
problem.
Hopefully that will be able to address.
It's a big problem because it's a big
problem because incentive reward,
which is what the unknown producers,
that's a cue for a reward incentive
reward is a more potent driving force
for people.
I think.
Then satisfaction and you think,
think about this in with regards to your
own behaviors.
Like often those things say you have a
goal in mind and you obtain sub goals
with relationship to that goal.
You're very,
very excited.
You actually attain the goal and it's
nowhere near as exciting is
participation in the process.
That led up to the goal,
which is to say you're more activated by
incentive reward.
Then you are by satisfactions and that's
the thing about people.
That's what we're like.
That's why we like novelty.
So static conceptions of the ideal
future have an intrinsic
problem.
Well the problem is is that getting what
you want is not enough to make you
content because contentment is something
that transcends the attainment of
determinant satisfaction.
So that would be,
there's more to the story than the
attainment of a goal that's conceived of
as a final goal.
And that has something well that,
Yup.
Well no I think,
I think you're making a valid point.
I mean the [inaudible] and fair enough,
I mean I guess what I'm talking about
our systems that postulate like
political utopian systems that postulate
that there is a particular manner of
organizing society that will provide a
final salute,
final static solution to all our
problems.
A lot of more or less simplistic utopia
notions do in fact promise that like
Marxism I think would be,
that'd be a system that fits well into
that sort of conceptualization.
It's just reorganize the essential
building blocks of society will
inevitably produce a future that
everyone will find ideal and that will
be the final solution so to speak.
So yeah,
I mean if you know that incentive reward
is one of the things that motivates you
and and in a really profound way,
again,
as I've pointed out before,
cocaine activates our incentive reward
systems.
People really like,
okay,
so the animals for that matter,
Bill self administer cocaine.
Until they die.
They like incentive reward.
We like incentive reward money is an
incentive for example.
Bit.
Once you realize that a lot of things
start,
a lot of weird things start to happen
because you say,
well for example,
a perfect world therefore would have to
contain novelty.
Now that's a strange thing to say
because novelty also induces anxiety.
So you've instantly said in the sense
that a perfect world is also one that
makes you anxious,
which is of course not really in
accordance with the kinds of things that
we would normally consider a perfect.
So
are you making the claim that ideal
future is,
is uh,
is is a world of unlimited exploration?
No,
not,
not entirely Daniel.
Because see,
I kind of thought that in the past,
but it's more a matter of balance.
You say,
well if this,
if you can represent this as the known,
which is the thing that's transformed
necessarily by the appearance of
novelty,
it's also a precondition for the
capacity to assimilate novelty.
So you have to know something,
which is to say that part of what makes
you capable of exploring and
assimilating new information is the fact
that you're already composed of static
structures of knowledge.
So you could say the ideal has to
therefore con be composed at least in
part of a balance between what static
and what's normal.
So it isn't just exploration,
it's also,
it's also the security that makes known
terrifying exploration possible and the
security that gives rise to the skills
that make creative exploration possible.
So you get someone like Einstein,
I think it was Einstein who said he
could see so far cause he stood on the
shoulders of giants.
And that's a good mythological image
because basically what Einstein said was
that he stood on the ground that was
prepared by his dead ancestors and
that's why he could see so far.
So it's a matter of balance and you
know,
that's what the oriental yen and Yang
symbol basically states too is that you
know,
order is necessary and chaos is
necessary.
And the ideal is some balance between
and that's where you're supposed to
walk,
would that's,
that's an eye that same uh,
ideal mode of adoption.
Yup.
Which is answering,
when you say ideal in that context,
you're not talking about the box top
runners.
No.
Well then,
okay,
that's fine.
Absolutely.
That's why I said,
well,
in that,
in their little story there's,
there's a grammar of,
there's a simple grammar of the story
which is,
which is the,
which is this,
which is,
you know,
this is your kingdom.
Why is that or your culture?
Well,
you're a part of the same culture with
someone else.
If you share their story,
it's as simple as that.
And their story is the manner in which
they have fixed motivational
significance.
Though I'm going to this including you
as an on going in there and to the
degree that you share that scheme of
interpretation,
they are,
you are a part of that culture and
that's because,
well,
it's quite straight forward.
I guess that's it.
If you and I share same vision with
regards to the value of a goal and the
means for getting there.
I can predict your behavior and you can
predict mind knowing that you can rely
on me and we can cooperate.
So we've just drawn a magic circle
around ourselves so to speak,
that it eliminates the,
the unpredictable and novel from our
interactions except in very connected,
very constrained matter.
So you're a defined territory as far as
I'm concerned.
And vice versa.
We are from the same culture and you can
make very,
you know,
you can make very trivial distinctions
within cultures.
For example,
we're both psychologists,
but we're practicing in different
domains.
That could easily mean we could split it
into some cultures depending on the
event that's going on.
Because if something threatened your
room subgroup and benefited mind,
instantly we fragment because our
stories,
what does the switch,
so anyways,
this is the law.
This is the more comprehensive story
because you have a story.
But then there's this story about how to
transform your stories when that becomes
necessary.
And so this is a fixed story and this is
another fixed story.
You notice I've structured it so that
this one's a square here in a circle
here,
which is the idea that this is the metal
structure remains the same,
but the details shift not to stage
transition from the Piagetian
perspective or a revolution from the
Cuny and perspective.
And uh,
this is blown apart by the appearance of
anomalous information.
And you can think of anomalous
information as the agent of chaos,
particularly weird way of looking at it.
But anyways,
it's anomalous information that follows
this structure apart.
And in initiation rituals,
for example,
they catalyze this sort of
transformation.
I face you with something anomalous.
I blow apart your story.
You are reduced to chaos.
But what does that mean?
Well,
it means that you have all of the
determinant motivational significance is
that you have a fixed two events,
including yourself and other people.
That's all up for grabs again.
So you're by turns,
depressed,
anxious,
elated,
et cetera.
Your emotional systems are in flux.
And the reason they're in flux is
because the metal structure that kept
them integrated has been destroyed.
So you're now subject to the war of
competing emotions basically.
Yeah.
So that's,
that's a descent into chaos.
And if it's an initiation ceremony,
the members of your culture will give
you a new story.
Say this is the story for these things
usually happen to men,
but not always.
This is your story for being a man bag.
Well that's a new framework of reference
that makes your new position now
determinant.
So then you're up here when you could
say,
well there are different ways of
construing the ideal.
If you're a patriot,
you say
to the degree that I identify with this,
I'm perfect,
I'm moral.
If you're identifying,
that's one form of perfection and you
can see the utility to that.
Do people do that all the time?
Even when they're identifying with
football teams for
there's a more profound type of
identification and that would be
identification with the process,
with the capability to undergo this
process identification with the capacity
for transformation.
And that,
again,
that that ties back with your earlier
comment about viewing yourself as well
as someone who's capable,
not only of adhering to stories,
but if generating and modifying them.
That's a much,
and again,
well,
I want you to read this next section on
Marta with this sort of thing in mind
because again,
that's what the Mesopotamians positive
as ideal.
In fact,
the k,
the emperor of Mesopotamia,
every new year when the year is
regenerated,
you can view this as the year,
by the way,
from the Mesopotamian perspective.
Anyways,
the king was ritually reduced to chaos
and reconstituted at the beginning of
every new year from the Mesopotamian
perspective,
that was equivalent to reduction of the
world,
the cosmos to its constituent elements
and then renewal.
That's a comment that's the most common
of mythological themes by the way.
Okay.
Uh,
yeah,
exploration is necessary because you and
everything else is going to change
whether you like it or not.
Uh,
then wouldn't,
wouldn't be ideal,
would be not necessarily active
exploration,
but exploration when you need to
explore.
Yeah.
Fair enough.
You're talking about the ideal is the
ideal state that you are,
the ideal future is wanting to make sure
you're always actively,
it's no or no,
no,
you're right.
You're,
you're alternative.
Reformulation is more accurate,
has its exploration when it's necessary,
which is to say that you need to know
what you know so you don't have to go
looking for trouble necessarily or be an
agent of change for the sake of being an
agent of change.
But if you detect an anomaly which which
you do it voluntarily,
that's the thing about how your brain is
set up.
If something anomalous happens,
you notice it.
Once you notice it,
then it's incumbent on you to alter your
story,
but it's not necessarily the case that
you have to be actively going about
that.
While I would exhaust you,
in fact,
I think in some ways that's what happens
too.
Paranoid schizophrenia.
You think this is,
you might think that this is kind of
another leap,
but if you read graze article in this
book,
Gray has a theory of the neuropsychology
of schizophrenia.
What happens to schizophrenia is that
novelty starts appearing over where it
shouldn't,
which is to say that the inhibitory
structure that stops meaning from being
experienced has been disrupted.
So for the poor schizophrenia,
meanings are popping up everywhere and
meaning means this signifies something
usually something threatening.
It's something promising that attracts
your attention to the poor
schizophrenia.
His attention is always attracted.
It's part of the reason that paranoid
schizophrenia or hypervigilant and what
happens to them is that I think is well
if you,
if something appears as meaningful to
you,
that activates your exploration system
and that's dope and surgically mediated.
Well that explains in part the hyper
dopamine Nirjah,
that's characteristic of schizophrenia
and the hyper vigilance.
But the problem with that is that if
you're on all the time,
you'll kill those systems.
I think that's what happens to
schizophrenia when they go into second
stage schizophrenia,
which is characterized by no flat out
effect and,
and uh,
Parkinson light symptoms.
So,
uh,
it's not so good to be on all the time.
You know what's funny because a common,
a common,
mythological ideal is piece,
right?
I mean,
and that would seem to be,
that would seem to be specifically not
upset maybe when you're here to to
maintain peace.
Yeah.
Yes.
That's a,
but then there's this the contrary
argument.
That's a perfectly valid point.
But there's the contrary argument and I
think this is an argument that the red
queen and there wasn't wondering,
I was,
she said you have to run as fast as you
can just to stay where you are.
So which is to say that a static mode of
adaptation is not,
is no adaptation at all systems age all
by themselves.
So you have to stay very active in order
just to maintain things the way they
are.
So what's,
you don't necessarily have to be
running,
running all the time.
I mean absolutely come to a sort of a
peaceful existence with yourself and
you're living in the woods or something.
Yeah know and Y'all are in here and they
were completely happy with it.
Well you're not going to have to,
you're not going to have to do a lot of
active change in less.
Your situation changes or you change.
Yeah,
I think that,
I mean it's a complex,
it's a complex issue because you can
also by expiration you can also produce
a normal,
he's,
it's not necessarily the case that they
just happened to you.
So,
but you know your,
I've got no argument at all with what
you say.
It's a matter of balance.
I mean the point is is that,
well Egypt,
Egypt for example,
stayed stable for about 3000 years,
which is to say that as far as modern
archeologists are able to determine,
there was a 30 century period where the
fundamental substructures of Egyptian
society state exactly the same.
And the Egyptians were convinced as are
many traditional societies,
that change meant death.
And you can understand that because any
cultural innovation is all cultural
innovations have the capacity to
undermine the cultures that produce
them.
So many cultures off for restasis.
But the problem is is,
and three,
because they think,
well we have a good thing and that sort
of play around with it.
It's like biological mutations.
It's a good analogy.
Most biological mutations kill you.
Can you think every innovation is in the
cultural sphere and analogy to a
mutation,
but the one in every thousand mutations
that doesn't kill you,
it's necessary for the survival of the
species.
So it's a very strange balance.
Does that,
does that argument make sense?
Does that didn't know what to you?
Makes Sense.
So
how do you explain things like marriage?
Like why isn't the divorce
was seriously,
or even if you love like a have a
favorite song or like a rarity,
the same person or decades that's got
like that's gotta be boring after a
while.
I mean there's no,
maybe it does,
I don't know if it has to be meaning you
also have the capacity to shift
frameworks of reference.
It's also,
right,
so you,
I mean especially with something as
complex as another person,
if you think you know someone else,
that's only a delusion that you have
about this,
the extent of your knowledge.
So if you,
if what you see is what you have
habituated to,
then what you see is what you have
not what's there because you don't know
what that other person is like.
And perhaps they've fallen into the same
damn game,
which is they play out the rule you've
specified for them.
But that's your tough luck,
you know?
So that's,
that's a good answer with regards to
marriage anyways.
So I mean with regards to simpler
phenomenon,
well you know,
you can move from,
from thing to thing and people do that.
But so part of,
part of the human capacity for
expiration is also to see what hasn't
been mapped.
Where are you,
where people think everything is
understood
and uh,
but her point,
uh,
brings up something interesting to me
when you boil into chaos and then you go
and then you go to any place,
can you take part of the old system?
Oh,
absolutely.
I've looked,
look with,
this is another thing you want to read
when you go through this next chapter
because part of the,
uh Huh.
That Pharaoh,
the Egyptian Pharaoh for example,
who's a nice Mesopotamian emperor
analog,
although a little later down the
historical chain,
he was simultaneously the,
the Pharaoh who had died and the new
pharaoh always.
And that meant basically that he was
both ocirus and horace.
This is how the Egyptians construed it.
No,
no,
serious was the old pharaoh who
basically was confined to the
underworld.
And Horace was the process that gave new
life to the pharaoh or Cirrus who was
confined in the underworld.
So the new pharaoh was simultaneously
everything that had already been
learned,
plus the process that allows you to make
use of everything that's already been
learned in a creative manner.
So,
hey,
so of course this,
that's why this is the structure is the
same.
So if this is composed of this,
plus this,
so which is to say that when you make,
when there's a revolution in your
thought,
what you use is everything you already
knew,
plus the information that has been in
gendered by your contact or your
assimilation up via normal ist
information.
So here,
I'll just give you,
this is kind of funny.
I think this is often represented as a
serpent,
the serpent of chaos for the Egyptians.
That was Adam and Adam.
What was the most primordial of gods who
ruled at the beginning of the time and
who will once again rule at the end of
time.
So he's sort of the place that
everything came from.
It's a serpent anyways,
when you can see,
for example,
the structure of the story in genesis of
Adam and eve in this,
in this little as well because,
well,
anomalous information,
maybe I'm jumping ahead and man,
I'll tell you anyways,
anomalous information is often given a
feminine form.
So you'll see when we go through
because,
well,
because anything anomalous,
this is a hypo hypothetical state is
chaos.
You can say it's,
it's all the unknown that you haven't
encountered.
It can't say anything about that because
it's not actually part of your
experience.
It's just a hypothesis about the source
of all those things you don't
understand.
It's not those things themselves.
When,
when something anomalous actually makes
itself manifest,
which is to say that you're,
you're,
uh,
following your story and something
unexpected happens,
then something has something actually
unexpected has happened to you.
Well,
it's in exploring that unexpected thing
that you generate new information.
So you could think of the unexpected
that you experience as the Matrix of
everything that you know,
because it's the source.
It's the source of everything that you
know,
you have to explore it,
but it's still the place where
information comes from.
A matrix.
I use that word because it said in the
logically related to mother in any ways.
This is often given feminine feminine
form.
Yeah.
The Matrix of things absolutely matters
as well.
Um,
but anyways,
so,
well it's a complicated thing.
The serpent gives the crude to even the
story of genesis and producers of a
complete collapse.
That's the rise of self consciousness
and the genesis story in Christian
morality is the attempt to get from here
back to here.
Well in a sense that's,
anyways,
that's just,
that's another example of how these
sorts of things tied together.
Let me just show you this cartoon
because I might otherwise forget it.
This is quite funny.
This is,
this is just a cartoon.
It sort of illustrates how we do respond
to things that we understand.
Things that we don't
know.
The reason this cartoon is funny of
course,
is because you don't sit around the
campfire at night and talking about the
things you understand,
right?
They don't have any motivation with
significant steps.
That's why you think you understand the
tales of the note.
It's also,
it's also well in embedded in,
this is also the notion that the things
you have explored don't have a lot of
effect of valence anymore.
So they're not very interesting and it's
unknown things that are interesting
around the campfire and make it more
effective to tell a story arc all
around.
Right,
right.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Yeah,
sure.
Penn Penn rules around the campfire at
night,
right.
Pans the God who lives,
who lives in the forest and who causes
panic basically.
And uh,
he's the God that inhabits the forest
because the forest is unknown territory
and unknown territory produces a seizure
of ongoing activity is associated with
anxiety.
So,
so if you have this conception of the
future,
which is,
you know,
being perfect and happy and that has
some goals of being successful and being
an academic and being a psychologist
and then something happens that disrupts
you or your interest in or your faith
and your ability to do cognitive
psychology and so that,
that particular style going,
we'll get plunged into chaos.
And you come back up with this idea of
being a developmental psychologist.
Right?
Right.
Absolutely.
That without affecting your larger goal.
Sure.
You just did it in that example.
That's exactly what happens.
Sure.
That's fine.
I mean,
does it,
and can it ever happened in isolation,
Justin and support?
Absolutely.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Sure.
And then it doesn't provoke that much
anxiety.
That's,
that's why,
well that's all the time,
right?
Like when all the time for the meeting
and that's just a disruption.
It was absolutely right.
Absolutely.
And that's a tree.
That's the thing that's so neat about
this and like a tree by the way,
is a very,
very,
very common figure in mythology.
The tree of life,
for example.
I really believe that's what it's
referring to is this.
It's the tree like structure that holds
your motivational systems in check.
So you can lose like minor league
branches or you could lose things that
are close to the trunk,
which is a,
that's a very big catastrophe spend you
looms whole Schema is of actions in an
interpretation,
interpretations that whole entire
sections of your experience in
motivational check.
So given that they have any priority
significance,
you're try to restrict that significance
to some useful domain always when you're
trying to do so,
can you own it,
have adapt to things that affect some
goals on some level,
I you,
because if you,
if something happens that draws into
question like let's say your most
fundamental like the trunk of the tree,
right?
And you adapt from that or do you just,
that's part of what we're trying to
address in this class.
See,
because you can say,
well,
the best story is the one that addresses
the widest range of potential
phenomenon,
right?
Say,
well,
mythologies,
collect mythologies,
distill the best story.
So what we're going to try to do is to
understand what the best story is
because the best story is the one that
has the largest domain of potential
relevance.
So you could say,
well,
what's the big problem?
Well,
the big problem for example,
might be,
uh,
the fact of human mortality because that
would be the,
the,
the anomalous phenomena,
which puts the determinant significance
of everything into dispute.
So how can you adapt to that?
Well,
again,
that's the question.
Say That's at the bottom of Christian
morality.
You view it,
I'm using Christian morality.
Just as an example.
If you view the rise of self
consciousness,
for example,
one of the concomitants of the rise of
self consciousness is the knowledge of
death.
And that the two things are very closely
linked.
If you're self conscious,
that means you can conceive of your
boundaries.
That's what it means.
And you have spatial boundaries and you
know,
they kind of bother you,
but you can move from one place to
another.
So that's not such a big deal.
It's the temporal boundary.
That's the big problem.
So the question is,
well,
can you adapt to the fact a temporal
boundary?
Well,
obviously this is a very tough,
very difficult question about talk.
It's the sort of thing that we'll see.
Part of what,
okay,
part of what I'm interested in trying to
understand is why people get so horribly
twisted as they mature.
I mean,
there's lots of reasons for it there.
They're pretty much plainly evident.
Like in many ways the world is a
terrible place and there's sufficient
reason all the time for people to get
twisted off the path.
And in fact,
I think often it's more surprising that
that doesn't happen all the time.
Then it is surprising that it sometimes
happens well,
well
if you're growing up in a family that
maybe doesn't have this normal
adaptation,
I've seen these things are,
you know,
caught up in stuff holds or maybe
something traumatic happened that
affects one of your fundamental Schema.
That's prob definitely,
yeah,
well the,
but that in itself is not enough.
Like I think that's it.
That's a necessary but not sufficient
precondition.
So you can say,
well,
some people never like,
if you're lucky you at least start here.
Some people never bloody well even get
here.
They just,
they were born and this is where they
stay and that's terrible for them,
but if it possible to stay there without
being entirely insane,
I mean because anyone who functions at
all how good the Schema,
because you have to have a go.
I mean you are working toward something.
I have no idea what it is.
Not necessarily don't necessarily,
you have to allow yourself the
possibility that there may be something
that you're working towards even if you
don't understand what it is and that's
the thing that you can hold on to in the
darkness so to speak,
something you don't.
That's faith from the religious
perspective and he might,
I'll,
I'll get to you right away.
You might say,
well,
what's that faith in the answer to that?
And it's says possibility.
He said,
even if you don't know like this
revolutionary adaptation,
that's some,
that's what this morning represents.
You can say,
well,
this is an image of the hero from the
mythological perspective to say,
well,
you may identify with that figure,
even if you don't know you're doing it,
which is to say that when you were here,
you may say to yourself,
well,
it's possible that if I pay attention
better things will come about.
Well,
I'm gonna say it's that what you're
doing,
whether you know when you're not,
is identifying with the capacity to
undergo this process.
So then you'd say,
well,
even when you're in chaos,
you still have a story.
Well,
that's true.
You do.
But you don't have to like people.
This is,
this is the problem with notions like
Joseph Campbell,
for example.
Most new age philosophy.
They say,
well,
you know,
follow your interests.
Well,
there's a lot of the,
normally wherever your interest take
you,
that's perfectly fine.
They say,
follow your interest in.
You'll get to hear,
well,
that's loaded.
That's uh,
uh,
what would you say?
A very over simplistic and naive
conception of development.
Because if you follow your interest and
you hit a big anomaly,
which you will,
you'll end up here.
And this is the,
this is by definition,
the most unpleasant place that you could
imagine to me.
And so it isn't just a matter of,
well,
things are pretty damn good now and if
you're just real good,
they'll get a lot better.
It's well things or you know,
however they are right now,
I don't know how that,
each person determines that personally.
And if you do what you should do,
they're going to get a lot worse before
they get better.
So
that's,
that's part of it because you need an
explanation,
you know,
it's like,
why don't people do this?
Why don't people pay attention to a
normalcy information when it doesn't
take that much cognitive work to realize
that if you ignore something that's
real,
sooner or later it's going to cause you
trouble.
Well,
why do people ignore it then?
But it must be a reason because some
interpretation is better than them,
that's for sure.
Even a bad one,
That's for sure.
Yeah,
that explains a lot of the persistence
of forms of psychopathology.
So like you say,
well,
you know,
when someone has,
someone has a real cockeyed story and
it's obvious to them that it's cockeyed
because their story transforms almost
everything into the determinant
significance is off anxiety and pain.
But they'll still hang on to that like a
lifeline when you offer them an
alternative story that would allow the
motivational states of hope and
satisfaction to emerge.
Because even though this is terrible,
this is worse,
I think it's at the new one,
they'd have to go there right now
because they're not being a hero.
Like they're escaping.
Escaping just perpetuates the anxiety.
So if they're stuck in anxiety,
pain,
then
yeah.
Well this is what,
this is why I want you to read paradise
lost because Milton's paradise lost is a
description of,
of uh,
the,
the feedback process that refusal to
admit to a normally necessarily
produces.
So question,
is there a qualitative difference or a
difference in the degree damage to the
branch?
Well,
it depends on how you look at it.
Like though,
if you look at it from this perspective,
there's a qualitative difference because
uh,
damage to a branch would be damaged in
here.
It's just a matter of means.
And then the qualitative difference,
the qualitative shift would be damaged
here or here.
But if you look at it this way,
it's really quantitative.
And I think this is actually a more act
by,
by the way,
Daniel Higgins helped me with
substantial load developing this
particular representation by talk.
This makes it appear quantitative.
And then
the thing is you can,
you could say,
well maybe there's a qualitative,
sorry,
a quantitative difference between damage
here and here,
but there's a qualitative difference
between damage here and here because
anyways,
that's how I,
that's how I look at it.
So
it's a quantitative process that has the
appearance of qualitative shift from
time to,
so
using this is a lot more
difficult to handle.
But I'm,
I'm wondering why Maddie,
if I'm part of the leap of faith is,
is
simply accepting that even if you don't
understand what you're doing,
you're doing it for something that the
possibilities,
it will still make you feel better.
How exactly that
maybe fit in there.
Well,
often pain is bounded.
So like let's say you're on,
you're operating under a system of
presumptions that always interferes with
your interpersonal relationships.
So they always end in catastrophe,
but it's very predictable.
The point of the story,
remember the point of having a story is
to render things predictable.
Now,
predictable pain is a hell of a lot
better than unpredictable pain.
And it is possible depending on your
attitude towards anxiety,
that predictable pain is better than
unpredictable pleasure because the
unpredictable aspect of the pleasure
means anxiety.
And then of course,
whether you,
whether where you would prefer anxiety
to pain in a sense depends on how you
construe your potential relationship to
anxiety.
Unpredictable.
Yeah.
And that's,
yeah,
it's intermittent reinforcement.
Yeah.
It's very hard to extinguish.
Well,
the thing about the thing about novelty,
this makes it complex,
is that it's an intrinsically,
it's an intrinsically ambivalent
stimulus.
The thing is novel stimulus or not
really stimuli there,
their cloud,
there were a class of stimuli and they
produce both anxiety and incentive
reward.
So the circumstances of the problem,
like the gambling d determined in large
part,
like whether it's incentive reward or
anxiety that predominates and and that's
very situationally situationally
dependent.
So in the case of gambling,
this situation is set up so that at
least for those who gamble,
the incentive reward outweighs the
anxiety.
But they both produce it while a
heightened state of arousal,
for example.
But lots of people won't gamble too.
So that that would,
that would have something to do partly
with scheme of interpretation and partly
with biological differences.
So similar,
it seems it biologically that we respond
more to it than to actual reward.
Well,
I think that you can make an argument to
that end.
Yeah.
So would you say the same thing then for
threat and anxiety versus punishment?
What would you say like,
look,
it's a lot easier for us to adapt to,
to the fact of punishments.
We just eliminate them like very rare
that any of us are in pain,
but it's not rare at all that were
anxious.
We haven't been able to do much about
that at all.
Partly because there's the existential
aspect of anxiety,
but whether,
whether anxiety is more motivating than
pain is kind of a moot point because
it's situationally dependent.
But it is certainly more difficult to
rid ourselves of anxiety on any
permanent basis.
So for,
for,
for people who have already solved the
problem of subjugation to pain and also
the problem of most basic satisfactions
and,
and that that's the case in our culture,
we're still very much governed and
almost entirely governed,
I think by anxiety and incentive reward.
So
there,
it's funny because there are secondary
reinforcers so to speak,
but they're in some,
in many ways,
more fundamental than the primary
reinforcers.
I wanted to go back and forth on for a
second because I was thinking about this
the other day and it,
a board of them just doesn't make sense
to me except in terms of not moving
toward some goal or rather,
because I was just thinking about this,
if you're,
uh,
important,
boredom is essentially results from
being in a,
in,
in monotonous situation.
But if,
if in that situation you,
you didn't have any,
you didn't have any other goals,
you'd be perfectly happy just sitting
there.
I mean I was just thinking if,
if I'm,
if I'm just sitting around,
I'm sitting,
I'm sitting alone in a room,
in a chair with nothing going on.
It's all only if that doesn't conflict
with some other drive,
like to go get food or something more
complex or,
or you know,
I dunno,
but only if it conflicts with some other
drive.
Am I going to be unhappy sitting there?
Am I going to feel what people refer to
as boredom.
Yeah.
Okay.
Because otherwise if I don't,
if I don't want anything in particular
at the time,
I'll be perfectly happy just sitting
there,
you know,
if it doesn't conflict with some
movement toward whatever ideal future I
have,
I'm going to be,
I'm not going to be bored per se.
Well,
yeah.
Well here we are.
Yes,
we do seek out novelty.
Absolutely.
And that's partly because,
well,
it ties back with what I was describing
earlier,
is that if you have nothing better to
do,
seeking out some more information is
useful per se.
So not only for any goal that you,
that you actually have,
but for all conceivable goals that you
could have.
So if you're sitting around doing
nothing,
then that's worse in a sense.
Then doing something new and generating
new information on there was one of the,
one of the most metal drives is simply
to look for novelty so that maybe you'd
be able to take sitting around for a
while because I drive hasn't really
kicked in,
but you know,
eventually door because you need a rest
or eventually,
but eventually you get restless and
you'll go cruising around even if it's
not,
even if it's aimless,
even if you have nothing particularly I
did do just simply because of that
drive.
Is there just to cause trouble leaving
often?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's to produce,
well actually it's to produce new
information,
I guess you could say.
That would be the,
that's kind of the,
the final,
that's the final explanation.
So you will feed on information,
right?
Just like food.
So it's not so much a question of not
being bored is how long you can,
you can wait before you get bored
because you will necessarily,
and there seems to be individual
differences in that too.
But novelty,
novelty is very motivating and uh,
well it's also,
it's also anxiety provoking,
so.
Okay.
Are there other issues or,
yeah,
if I had,
if I asked you what was the ideal future
in the middle of the last century,
you might have said that the ideal
future at the cultural level,
one that was that uh,
the trunk of the tree,
the all encompassing,
the ideal future of that story.
The answer might have been that it would
have been identification with Christ
or else it would have been
getting to the new Jerusalem.
Both of them seem,
and the first one is
the identification with Christ is the,
the ideal as the way and the new
Jerusalem would be a ideal as a static
state,
which may,
which may be prolonged over time.
And I came across,
I came onto this cause I was wondering
what,
what's the implications for the ideal
future if you throw away the five
unconditioned stimuli as the
unconditioned stimuli,
because the new Jerusalem is the,
is the five unconditioned stimuli
optimally dealt with,
always
taken care of.
Whereas the,
uh,
the Christ is,
well that's a different one.
That's,
that's a more sophisticated ideal
future.
So
what is the ideal future then,
are there to decide?
Well,
I mean it's,
it's still a reasonable way of
conceptualizing things mean you can look
at it from a,
within the system perspective,
because there's a anthropological terms
for this that I always forget and make
an EP ethic.
One means or within the system
perspective.
And the other means that between the
system perspective and a
well,
so that you can construe your ideals
either from within the confines of a
particular story,
if you accept the story or you can
construe it in terms of always being
able to update the story if necessary
with the story.
This identification with Christ as the
ideal future.
It doesn't,
is not surrounded by chaos.
No,
no,
no.
That's not exactly,
well,
yeah,
that's a complicated issue.
It's surrounded by belief in the
capacity to deal with chaos.
If it arises in a sense that's what gets
rid of it,
or at least gets rid of the negative
aspect of it so it doesn't eliminate it
permanently.
It just transforms it in a sense into
something that can always be dealt with.
It's internal,
so if you draw,
if you the story,
if you construct the story with
identification with Christ as the ideal
of future and you put a circle around
it,
chaos is inside the circle.
Yeah.
Okay.
I see what you mean.
Yeah,
well that,
okay,
that's a good point,
Dan.
Danielle.
Well,
that has to do with the,
well,
that has to do with put that whole
scheme that if you were,
if you can taste this as your model,
what's your take Christ Cynthia,
ideal future.
Then that would put that,
that whole diagram in yet another
diagram.
Okay.
Yes,
yes.
Okay.
Hey,
yes.
Okay.
Hang on a second.
First of all with regards to board of
which we talked about earlier is the
thing is,
is that we know that that,
that the problem with a perfect static
state is that there's no novelty and
that's a problem because all the
incentive reward disappears.
But if you want novelty,
then you will then you necessarily take
anxiety.
So you could say,
okay,
so that's part of the argument.
Then the other idea here is in part how
do you deal in the final analysis with
the fact that there are normalist events
too,
which you can't adapt like death.
Well,
the,
the point that you're driving out in
park is that if you got,
if you think about
the
one way of looking at the ideal future
is it's a place where there is no chaos,
which is,
that means it's permanently eliminated.
Okay.
Everything's predictable.
Everything is random,
unpredictable and theoretically perfect.
The other way of looking at it just to
say,
well no,
because that wouldn't be perfect for
there.
For things to be perfect,
there has to be some chaos.
So on the chaos might be the type,
for example of this,
of the anomalies that we can't solve.
So then the ideal type of adaptation
would be the construction of a mode of
being in which the fact that there are
permanent anomalies,
even a very terrifying sort of makes
sense and is acceptable.
So hope so.
And that's again,
that's kind of,
that's part of what we want to drive
that in this course.
I mean people find with regards to being
twisted,
people find the fact that very unfair
and threatening and hurtful things
constantly happen and that turns them
against life because they think,
well there can be no possible story,
there can be no possible justification
in which that category of events can
attain an acceptable determinant.
Meaning therefore life is cruel and
unreal and unreasonable in its intrinsic
aspects and deserves spot under those
conditions.
I can take revenge against it,
which I think is what,
that's a non simplistic explanation for
anti social behavior.
Because as psychologists,
we tend to think about these social
people,
they like novelty and they like to break
rules,
but we never really get at the fact that
they're like very hostile and very
revengeful and they like hurting other
people and so on.
Because we don't know how to understand
that category of emotions say
to,
to start that sort of thing from
happening.
You need a story that says,
well,
yeah,
unreasonable things always happen,
but in some sense they're absolutely
necessary.
And what a story that's believable so
that their effect of valence has
shifted.
So we'll talk about,
there's this section later in this
manuscript that talks about I then
there's a section in the grand
inquisitor or in the brothers Karamazov
Ivan,
who's an atheist,
is talking to his younger brother
Alicia,
who wants to be,
uh,
who's st like it wants to be a priest
and Ivan as a committed atheist.
And he says,
he tells a bunch of stories about
torture of children in,
in Russia at the turn of the century.
He says,
I'm world,
like there can be no god in the world
like this.
And basically what he's saying is that
if you look around you,
the valence of things is such to
demonstrate unequivocally that things
are meaningless in the final analysis.
And,
uh,
some people regard that that particular
section of the brothers Karamazov is the
most potent argument for atheism that's
ever been constructed.
And well,
that's the kind of argument that you
have to address if you want to deal with
phenomena that twist people up.
You know,
if you beat someone and torture them
when they're a child,
it's not that surprising that they might
turn against the world in regard to that
something that should be obliterated so
that,
that might be the moral thing to do.
So you need a story that can address
those sorts of possibilities.
So are you,
would it be fair then to say the pure
asking us to,
to modify our current state,
our current view of the world,
um,
from one where we will do absolutely
anything to avoid chaos into some,
into one where we posit an ideal future
which has,
right.
We'll do as the anything to avoid
as a necessary constituent element of it
and can hopefully,
and hopefully also that you will come to
understand from the rational perspective
why the existence of that is a
precondition for the fact that there is
existence.
Because that's the,
that's another thing that these
mythological stories are very good at
outlining.
They say the cosmos is actually
constructed of the division between
chaos and order.
If you obliterate that dividing line,
then everything returns to this
hypothetical state of no one being in
which there is no pain,
but there's nothing,
there's nothing.
So then the question is,
is the fact that there is something,
despite all its negative motivation will
implications preferable to nothing?
Of course.
That's the,
I think it was Khumbu didn't come who
say that the only question worth
considering is whether or not to commit
suicide?
Well that's the question.
That's the same question is,
is life in with its intrinsic
limitations preferable to a state where
there's nothing.
Well that's,
that is the bottom line.
That's the bottom line question.
So I'd like to address this because I've
been listening for the past hour or two.
It seems like a lot,
many attempts to,
to reconcile an ideal future would just
like a utopia perfect society or on Fox
and static sense.
If I just sit in the chair,
when will I get bored with an ideal
life,
which is identification process or
identification with Christ,
which is not the same thing as ideal
society.
Right.
And somehow that those are not the same
thing.
Right.
But that's what I hear people trying to
do is to make an ideal society the same
thing as an ideal life.
Well,
people constantly confuse the state with
the process.
But this is also true as we'll see with,
with regards to conceptualizations of
evil because people presume that evil is
a state rather than a process.
And the state might be aggression or
cruelty or jealousy or you know,
we can list a whole bunch of
motivational states that people tend to
value negatively.
So I say,
well,
you know,
uh,
people fight,
people produce social conflict because
they're aggressive and therefore if we
can socialize boys in particular to not
be aggressive,
then the capacity for war we'll vantage,
which I think is like truly an idiotic
theory.
But that's what happens when you confuse
the process of evil with,
with,
with uh,
what you make an idol of evil
fundamental.
And we say,
well,
it can be identified as this set of
phenomena,
which basically turns it into an idol.
Well,
it's just as bad.
It's just as significant a philosophical
error as doing the same thing to good.
And the reverse saying,
well,
uh,
pieces good or happiness is good or
contentment is good.
It was,
those are all context dependent
evaluations.
Sometimes happiness is very bad so to
speak.
Like if you're experiencing it well,
uh,
torturing someone else for example,
which is certainly a possibility.
So what we'll come to at the end of the
lectures is a Mrs Taletha had slightly
as a conceptualization,
well if,
if the conceptualization of good is the
capacity to admit to the existence of an
anomaly when it manifests itself and
then to act accordingly,
then evil is the precise opposite of
that,
which is not aggression or hostility or
jealousy or anything that people
normally sort of label evil but,
but the process of refusing to admit
that something has changed.
So and you can say,
well that leads to aggression in
situations where it might not be
desirable,
it leads to hostility and so fine,
but it's still a process,
not a,
not a state.
So question
to the limitations,
but actually not
concerning it
and still have something attractive.
That's why they like you see this in
American movies very,
very often.
It's like the anti hero,
the gangster for example,
is actually viewed as a hero.
Although his,
his paths of action produce well,
disruption and chaos,
there's still something very,
very attractive about that.
So that's,
that's one example of that as a,
Yup.
It's also the case that the agent that
produces the disruption of this system
can be viewed as something positive from
this perspective,
but as something entirely negative from
within here,
which is part of the reason you know,
you know,
people don't like geniuses very much.
For example in science,
no,
there,
there's a lot of resistance to truly
novel theoretical formulations to truly
creative activity.
Well that we all presume like if we're
evaluating how those in the past
responded to creative genius,
say like the Catholic priesthood
responding to Galileo,
we always make the presumption that we
would have been on Galileo side had we
been there because viewing the past we
can take sort of a,
uh,
a higher order view point.
But the point is,
is that for the Catholic priests who
were stuck in this story,
Galileo's discovery was the,
normally at the highest order,
it had catastrophic consequences.
I think that's improper primarily
because they actually misunderstood the
import of the,
of the information.
But still from in here,
Galileo looked like an agent of the
devil.
Now we would say,
well,
no,
in actuality he was providing the kind
of anomalous information that leads to
this.
But you know,
I think at least in part thinking,
oh,
this is that the excesses of the Soviet
Union could be regarded as the
inevitable historical consequence of the
process that Galileo set into motion
because the Russians lost their Orthodox
Christianity around,
you know,
in the late 18 hundreds that laid them
wide open for an invasion of,
for the invasion of rationalistic utopia
notions and,
and the death of the consequent death of
66 million people.
And it wasn't as if the Catholic priests
were entirely wrong.
What Galileo had to say was dangerous
in,
in the,
in the highest order has taken.
It's how long since Galileo made his
discovered 300 years,
something like that.
Does anybody know anyways?
400 years I can say.
Yeah.
Well,
we all think that was just perfectly
positive and understandably so.
I mean,
it's sad.
It's sad that the real danger.
Wow.
Yeah.
But you know,
it's more complex than that because the
Catholic priesthood and religious people
in general ever since then have not been
able to figure out what to do with
Galileo was information.
The perceived motivational significance
was this is a death blow to everything
that we believe in,
and this is not trivial because as
Nietzsche points out,
clearly in Western society,
at least our morality,
which is our behavior,
has Judeo Christian roots,
has a Judeo Christian trunk,
so to speak.
If you chop off the trunk,
then the rationale for the morality
disappears.
Now you might not know that and you
might not accept it at a cognitive
level,
but that doesn't stop it from being
true.
Now,
I would say that the,
the religious of Galileo's time in the
modern times for that matter
misconstrued the motivational
significance of Galileo's discovery.
I mean,
because they were under the presumption
that they're religious theories of the
nature of the universe described the
same universe that Galileo is
describing.
I don't think that's true.
The religious stories,
we're trying to describe how the world
was constructed with regards to its
implications for action,
which is absolutely vital.
You have to know that whereas Galileo
was doing something related but
different.
So there they are conflict,
a death conflict.
Definitely conflict was seeing where one
did not actually exist in sense,
but they could scarcely avoided since
the tumor had been combined right before
previously.
Right?
Absolutely.
It was inevitable.
There wasn't any need to separate
before.
No and no methodology for doing so.
So it's not surprising,
but it's worthwhile to consider that
some of the intelligence was in fact on
the side of the Catholic priesthood in
which is something we tend not to think
about.
I mean they were at least for all of
their flaws,
which are the flaws of any organized
system.
They're on the side of a certain amount
of stability,
which is also necessary.
So you can say what you want about the
kind of stability that they provided.
But the thing is stability always comes
at a cost,
always,
always.
So,
okay.
Um,
I want to show you a couple of things.
This is like,
I would rather have the class go like
this actually then for me just to
outline during the lectures what you're
going to be reading anyways.
So we,
I would rather use this as a forum for
discussion of the issues that the
reading brings up that would make it a
much more participatory enterprise.
So I got,
what I would hope is that,
you know,
we could as a group get immersed in the
material that we'll be discussing and
hack away at it critically in,
during the course of these classes.
I just want to end with a very brief
summary of what I was going to discuss
in part today.
I think it looks to me like your brain
is organized to react to the universe as
if it's constructed of three things.
And these are things that constantly are
described in mythological stories of the
nature of the world.
And one of the things is the territory
that you have explored and the other is
the territory that you haven't explored.
And the third is the process of
exploration itself.
And those,
those,
those three things you can regard as
environmental constants,
they're always there.
As long as there's been human beings,
those three things have always been
there.
And as far as we can tell,
as long as they're human beings,
those three things will continue to be
there.
That's right.
Cause there's always things that you've
mapped and things that you haven't,
and there's always the process of doing
the mapping.
That's the world from the mythological
perspective.
And it appears to me also from the
neuropsychological perspective.
Um,
I want to show you a picture,
say from the neuropsychological
perspective,
you could construe us as specialized
primarily for exploration and for the
communication of the things of the
knowledge that we've generated as a
consequence of exploration.
And to buttress this,
I want to show you some diagrams of the
representation of the body and the
brain.
Nope.
Okay.
Here,
that's,
let me just show you where it is first.
Okay.
This is the motor unit of your brain and
this is the sensory unit,
how the motor units is about half of
your brain.
And it's also the part that we haven't
been able to figure out what does,
we haven't been able to figure out what
it does very well.
Um,
lesions in this part of your brain
produce snow decrements in static Iq
has,
you will know if you read that paper by
Joan Dunkin that's in the collection of
papers for a long time.
People weren't sure what this part of
the brain does anyways.
What it does is sequence abstractly
sequence motor activity at least in part
that's a big part of its role.
This is the motor strip right there and
damage to that part of the brain
interferes with your ability to actually
move your body and you could.
This part which is the prefrontal cortex
grew out of the motor strip during
evolution and that provides a clue to
its essential function.
As evolution progressed in that part of
the brain gain in size,
which you did in a tremendous to a
tremendous degree,
much more,
he was,
by the way,
than any other form of animal.
We became able to abstractly act and
abstract action is very useful because
if you can act abstractly,
you can think your way out if novel
situations without actually having to
put yourself in them.
And obviously that's useful because then
you can get the damn information without
getting killed.
And you can also,
you can also watch other people for
example,
and imitate them,
which means you can get their behavioral
wisdom without,
without actually having to go through
all the aggravation of learning what it
was that they are encountering,
what it was they had to.
Well,
they were formulating those patterns of
motor behavior anyways
were specialized for exploration and uh,
well let's take a look at that.
This is how your body is represented in
the motor and the sensory cortex.
I want you,
it's pretty similar really,
but I want you to pay most attention to
the motor cortex.
All right?
It's quite interesting because this is
how what your brain thinks of your body
in a sense from the perspective of you
being a thing that can do things.
All right,
and as you'd suspect,
well,
what's a human being?
Well,
first of all,
we're all thumbs.
I look at that.
I mean the thumb is bigger than the rest
of the body by a substantial well,
thumb and ham.
They,
that's the,
that's what we are.
And also Tom,
that's the tongue there and face.
Well that's what we're like.
All right.
Let me show you kind of have a better
representation of this.
Um,
oh,
there is,
this is,
this isn't quite right does this is the
sensory homonculus but you still get the
basic idea.
Okay.
That's now the motor homunculus is even
more exaggerated than this,
which is to say that the motor
representation throws even more weight
on the hands and the face.
Well that's our capacity to pick things
apart and put them back together to
manipulate the world.
And this is our capacity essentially to
communicate.
You can't see the tongue representation
in here,
but
we're creatures who are specialized to
encounter things that we don't
understand and to make of them something
that we want,
which is not the same as exploring them
by the way.
Precisely that we have another kind of a
cockeyed notion about what expiration
means.
We tend to think that when we explore
something unknown,
we discover its properties.
But that's a strange notion because
usually what we're trying to do when we
explore something is not so much
discovered the sensory properties of
something,
but to turn something that has
indeterminant significance,
which means it could be threatening or
promising into something that we can,
that we can either ignore or use.
And well,
you'll have to think through that
argument I guess on your own because we
don't have enough time to discuss it.
But the point is,
is that the universe that we inhabit is
not entirely given.
It's also something that we erect as a
consequence of our actions.
And there's um,
yeah,
which is to say that it's the process.
It's the process of exploration,
which is in large part linguistically
mediated that brings into being the
world that we regard as familiar and the
world that we inhabit.
And that's why,
for example,
in,
well,
I can tell you for example,
in the Sumerian,
most primordial of Sumerian creation
myths,
there's a god goddess sort of of
indeterminate sexuality that represents
chaos,
who's divided into the male sky.
And the female earth and who is
separated.
These two daddies are separated by the
god of the atmosphere.
So you could say,
well again,
from the Sumerian perspective,
the universe is composed of the
primordial chaos,
then a masculine principle that in this
mythology is represented by this guy and
a feminine principle that's represented
by the earth and the process that
separates them or distinguishes between
them.
And that's the god of the atmosphere.
And that's,
that's a,
that's a wholly triad,
basically father,
mother and divine son.
In Christianity,
there's the doctrine of the logos,
which is the word and the word is the
thing that in gendered creation and the,
the,
the derivation of the logos,
while the idea of the logo schools all
the way back through Egyptian society
into Mesopotamian society and reflects
people's intuition that there was some
integral relationship between the nature
of the world as we inhabited and the
process that generates that world in the
context of exploration.
So the myths say the capacity for
exploration is a function of that which
already existed.
And simultaneously the thing that brings
both chaos in order into being,
so it's both,
it's the offspring of chaos and order
and the thing that creates them that
we're not used to thinking in causal
loops like that.
But well,
mythology could care less whether you
can understand it.
That's basically the bottom line.
It's just a representation of in a sense
of the way that things are.
So,
uh,
that x except even more exaggerated.
That's what we are from the perspective
of our brain.
And you say,
well,
this might you think this might be a
trivial,
uh,
a trivial statement.
For example,
you know,
I just picked the motor strip in the
sensory stuff.
That's not a very big part of the brain,
but you have to realize that the
prefrontal cortex is the thing that
provides abstract programming for the
motor strip.
So the prefrontal cortex is concerned
with the programming of movement and the
sensory cortex well is mostly taken up
by the visual system.
So this is,
this is a good picture of who we are.
And I want to extend that argument by
pointing out that people have made much
of the supposed intelligence of dolphins
and whales.
And the reason they'd done this is
because,
well,
your intelligence is dependent on part,
on the area of the gray matter of your
cortex.
And we have about a meter of gray
matter.
If you spread it out on you,
spread it out in a sheet,
um,
the more gray matter,
the more intelligence roughly or new,
or you could say the ratio of brain
tissue to bodyweight.
That's the encephalization.
Quotion is a rough estimate of animal
intelligence and dolphins have very high
encephalization factors and tremendously
convoluted cortex,
isn't it?
So people think,
well,
they're extraordinarily intelligent,
but this,
this is simplistic thinking as far as
I'm concerned.
Unless dolphins are doing something that
we just can absolutely have no
conception of,
they don't have hands.
And that's a,
that's a nontrivial difference because
it's the hand that makes us in large
part who we are,
its primary exploratory tool,
right?
It's the thing by which we construct the
worlds that we live in.
And I don't mean this in the
mythological sense.
I mean it just makes us able to build
tables and houses and so on and to
modify to modify the environment to
suit,
to suit us and dolphins,
whatever else you might want to say
about them.
They don't do that.
And that's a non trivial difference and
it's the difference is immense and all
you have to think about it for a few
minutes to to realize that well the
snake,
does anybody have any idea what the hell
they're doing when all that brand?
Not a lot that they can the same very
complex songs and they also seem to use
some of,
well I don't know how that's how that's
attached to the intelligence.
No is the answer as far as I can tell.
So they are very intelligent.
There's no doubt about that.
You can teach dolphins to do lots of
things,
but you have to,
you have to realize that your brain is
not a disembodied spirit.
I mean it's integrity attached to your
body.
In fact,
you might even regarded as part of your
body.
By the same token,
your body is the environment to which
your brain has adapted and vice versa.
And the fact of the structure of your
body is,
is very relevant to how your brain
functions.
And it's obvious that a dolphin and
human being are very different in terms
of morphological structure.
It's not like they just have two brains
that are the same,
that could easily be transposed at the
structural level.
The,
the organs are much,
much different.
So we're specialized to tear,
tear things apart and put them together
and to tell other people what we've
done.
That's what we're like say,
say well that's the process of
exploration and that's the thing.
Well,
in a sense that's also the thing that
mythology tells us that we should be
doing at least when it's necessary.
Now the other,
there's another reason why I brought
this up.
And that's because art of the part of
the question that sort of underlies this
course is,
is it possible to come up with a
definition of what constitutes the good
life,
that source of stable across different
cultural presuppositions?
And,
but one of the things that's quite
interesting as you know,
is that novel phenomenon are cues for
satisfactions,
which makes them incentive rewards and
incentive rewards make us feel as good
as we can feel fundamentally.
They also have very analgesic
properties,
which is quite interesting.
Cocaine is a profound analgesics and
that basically suggests that,
well,
you're involved in the voluntary
exploration of novelty from the aspect
of perspective.
Your brain is functioning in a sense at
its optimal level,
at least from the effect of perspectives
you're interested in things and you're
also relatively immune to,
to pain.
So he can make of that what you want.
But I mean we can just lower this,
you know,
down to a more pragmatic level of
discussion,
you know,
perfectly well from your own experience
that if you're involved in something you
really find interesting that uh,
well that's about as good as you can.
That's as good a feeling as you can
possibly hope to generate.
I mean,
basically what people tend to do I think
is arrange their lives so that
everything else feeds the possibility of
them doing something that they really
want to do.
Although people will sacrifice that
often because they are afraid.
But,
uh,
well the reason I'm bringing up this
discussion is because it has employee,
well,
it has implications for all sorts of
things.
And um,
it's also curious,
and this is something you might want to
think about because it really,
it's very strange for me.
I think that the world that myth
describes,
so let people would say,
look,
if you had to make a distinction in
terms of the description of reality
between the scientific
description and the mythological
description,
while there's no contest,
the scientific description is the
description of the world and there's
lots of evidence on that.
To that end,
right?
I mean,
science is a very poor,
powerful technique,
but the peculiar thing is,
is that you would also say,
say as an evolutionary biologist,
that the world to which your brain has
adapted is the real world.
And from my perspective,
the world that your brain has adapted to
is the mythological world because your
brain construes things as the territory
that you've explored,
the territory you haven't,
and the process that mediates between
the two.
And
you can see why that might be.
If you think about where danger exists,
for example,
hello,
I'll close this with one interesting
fact that I learned long after I had
figured out that
that tough people identify those from
different cultures as agents of the
unknown.
The Egyptians,
ancient Egyptians would not let
foreigners into their temples because
foreigners,
we're agents of chaos and the temples
were microcosms of the entire state and
they didn't want the state disrupted by
the presence of foreigners in the
temples.
Know.
Lots of religions still construe the
world in that matter today.
I mean,
think of marriage restrictions for
example.
But that's one interesting thing.
The other interesting thing is that the
Egyptians,
and it wasn't just the Egyptians,
he actually identify five cultures that
did exactly the same thing.
They use the same symbol for the dragon
that ate the sun at night
and for foreigners for barbarians that
an inhabited,
unexplored territory and the dragon that
ate the sun at night,
by the way,
it was the dragon of chaos.
The daddy that rule prior to the
division of the cosmos into chaos and
order.
So you could say human human word has a
natural category.
And that category is the category of all
things that have yet to be explored.
That's the unknown.
And the unknown has a priory,
motivational significance.
It's frightening.
But it's also interesting and it's,
it's natural to us to not to associate
foreigners with that category,
but to presume that they occupied the
same domain,
which is even more fundamental.
It's not like the Egyptian stock
foreigners chaos equivalent.
What the Egyptians thought was that
these two things were the same thing.
They hadn't yet been distinguished.
It's more fundamental than a mere
association is that the foreigner is the
ancient of chaos.
And that basically means that your
response to the foreigner is going to be
integrally tied into the manner in which
you approach chaos as part of your,
as part of the nature of your being.
So your attitude towards the terrible
unknown is the same as your attitude
towards the stranger.
Oh,
that's something to think about.
All right,
well questions.
Oh,
um,
okay.
What exactly do you want to know?
Look all I'll tell you about it.
Generally.
I want you to pick something that is
interesting to you.
That's,
and it's relevant to the topics that
we've discussed in the course.
And those are the two major criteria.
Um,
I don't just want a summary of what
we've discussed.
I want you to take what we've discussed
and apply it to a problem that you find
compelling.
MMM,
yeah.
That's basic.
I mean that's basically the bottom line.
MMM.
During the next class.
Yes.
Yeah.
The dates are screwy on the syllabus,
but the class times when they're
supposed to be handed in.
That's right.
So next class is class four.
It's going to summarize really quickly
the way you just said in like two
sentences.
Okay.
So the world is set up into,
for us as a known,
the unknown and the process which,
which,
which mediates between the two.
Right.
What we do after that process then is
to,
they will think is something we use in
that process and things that we don't
use for that process.
Well,
that the latter part of that isn't quite
right.
Basically what we're trying to do when
we explore the unknown is to manipulate
the things that we encounter so that
they take on the effect of significance
that we want,
which is now what people would normally
say as well.
When we explore something,
we discovered their properties,
but that's not exactly right because the
properties of something depend very much
on how you approach it,
which is the example I used with fire
and you say before people had mastered
fire,
it was something unknown and dangerous.
Mastering fire means erecting a sequence
of behaviors in the presence of fire
that allow the fire to shift
motivational category from intrinsically
interesting and threatening to useful in
some determinant manner.
So when that's what we do when we
explore,
it's where assigning us fixed domain of
motivational relevance to something that
only exists as possibility.
And we're doing that by rearranging our
behaviors.
That's what adaptation means.
So you can see this too.
For example,
if you're trying to adapt to the
presence of another person,
the other person is a very complex and
you can say,
well you,
you explore someone else,
you get to know them.
But really what you're doing when you
explore someone else is in large part
matching your behaviors.
If you,
if you like the person matching your
behaviors to their expectations so that
in your presence they only manifest
those phenomena that you want.
That's exploration.
It's not mere evocation of all
possibilities.
Like if I want to get to know you,
for example,
one of the things I probably won't want
to know is how you react.
If I put a knife in your foot.
That's,
that's one category of the phenomena
that compose you that I'm not interested
in eliciting.
So it's not random.
Our exploration is not random.
We're attempting to transform what has
in determining significance,
which means meaning into something that
we want,
not something we expect,
something we want.
That's what they,
that's what adaptation means.
So most things I just tried to be
neutral.
That's true.
But that's,
I would say in the sense we want lunch.
Well that's also a failure because it's
better to transform something into a
satisfaction or a promise that into
something irrelevant.
Although that's the way that thing most
things end up.
So it's the best kind of failure,
but it's still a failure.
You know that because it's often the
case.
For example,
if you're conducting an experiment,
you define something as irrelevant and
10 years later someone else comes along
and says,
well no,
that's not irrelevant if you treat it
this way,
it has this set of possibilities and
well you know,
so irrelevant is a dangerous
categorization as well.
Cause it probably,
it may mean that you've overlooked
something important.
So I know that's how things turn out and
you can understand why and all that.
But still really successful adaptation
means you turn possibility into desired
actuality.
Can you do that by rearranging your
behavior or your scheme of
representation?
That's
so
okay.
And one of the other classes you told us
a story about,
um,
it was talking about the drive that we
have to explore new things.
And you said like babies will fight for
the chance to explore a toy on the floor
they've never seen before.
So they're not fighting for the toilet
or fighting for the chance to be the one
to explore it.
And I was wondering how,
well,
how does that kind of change when you
get to a level of an adult or a culture
or something?
And how has that affected by,
well,
I guess you'd have to know this is a
presumption,
but if it seems that we're running out
of objects and things to explore,
like aside from space,
I mean we don't know.
No,
I would say that's a presumption.
We're not running out of things to it.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I think the nature of the things that
we're,
that we have to explore is changing in
some way.
I mean it's like what we can explore now
is more likely,
I don't know,
like the properties of the ocean or like
we can fight about it appears to explore
it now.
It appears to us that that's the case.
More of an idea.
I mean,
I mean it's,
we recognize it as more of an idea.
Like let's say that,
you know,
if rushton psychologists are studying
one thing and American psychologists are
studying,
you're not as likely to physically fight
over that as if we're fighting over the
country or a territory or something that
we can conceive as the object.
It's like we're running on an object and
we're thinking of more ideas.
And even in the case of space,
it seemed that we saw space.
There's more of an abstract idea because
space is something that it's not very
likely to,
to be,
um,
a dangerous unknown to us unless we go
into it.
So as long as we stay where we are,
we can think of it as an idea rather
than as a place.
And so we had,
you know,
this little space race,
but it wasn't,
it didn't seem to be as,
we didn't get as involved in it as we
did in previous conflicts.
Well,
okay.
There's a lot,
sorry,
go ahead.
And through that,
our environment is much more
constructive.
I mean,
as much less that we have to worry about
and mean we're exploring more of our own
construction
and you're billing,
for me it's more of them because you
don't know all the implications of that
change sort of title anyway.
I mean not to look at your lifespan and
that the position that you're in right
now,
you're in a position where people try
very hard to make everything was
predictable for you as possible so you
can focus on ideas,
but that may not be what your life is
like.
And it also may seem that in comparison
to things that have been discovered in
the past,
the things that we're exploring right
now are more subtle.
But I think that's only because we have
the advantage of viewpoint on the past
to us because of those things have
already been explored.
They seem obvious.
But to the people that we're exploring
them,
when they were still undefined
territory,
they were as obscure it to them as the
things we explore art us with this
mysterious.
So yeah.
Yes.
Which is to say that if you answer a
question,
you answer a question,
but you generate to new problems as a
consequence.
It's like the introduction of the
computer.
Well,
it seems like the things where it's
going now are things that we're not as
likely to see it as a competition for
resources.
Like if I want to study something,
it doesn't mean that the other person
can't study it.
It's sort of like you want to own
America,
you have to fight the other countries
and keep them away from it.
Otherwise you can't be the one to the
sport.
But if people want to explore,
you know,
psychology,
you don't have to keep other people from
doing it.
Oh yeah.
Did your education,
like other countries think academics is
extremely competitive because you don't
want somebody else who told us your
idea.
You want to be the one to define the
terms to set the
day with.
The questions are,
does that transcribed into the conflict?
Do you actually try to keep them from
studying it or is it just that you,
you hope that they don't see?
I mean,
are we having cross generational
congregation the,
we don't fight each other,
but we,
yeah,
but we do fight too.
Yeah.
But also has or cultural
generalizations.
The level at which is actually my skill
level of the individual.
Some people work with another country
over.
Those things are just over oil.