Okay,
so
last week we spent a fair bit of time
assessing
the structure of the first two stories
in genesis and I made the case that
they were stories about
the rise of humanity into self
consciousness or the descent of humanity
into selfconsciousness,
depending on which way you look at it.
I should also point out that there's
been a lot of debate
among religious traditions that were
associated with those stories about
whether the fall was an improvement or a
catastrophe.
Today we're going to discuss at least to
begin with,
we're going to discuss the
story of the Buddha.
And the reason I want to do that,
it's two fold.
Well first,
because it's an interesting story in
second because the parallels between it
and the story in genesis are I think
they're quite remarkable
and it's not that easy to understand
exactly why they're there.
So here's the story
[inaudible]
so a long time ago,
king got news that he was going to have
a son and an angel visited him and said,
your son is going to have one of two
destinies.
He's either going to become a great and
powerful world ruler or he's going to
become
a spiritual leader.
And the king thought it was a very
practical man,
thought,
well,
there's no damn way my son is going to
become a spiritual leader.
And so we thought all make sure that he
falls in love with life.
Okay.
So the king built a city before his son
was born and wall did the end and made
it as beautiful as he could possibly
make it and then decreed that within
that city there were nothing but joy.
And so there were no people who the only
people that were allowed in were young,
attractive,
and healthy by express demand.
And so the Buddha grew up in that city
and fell in love with life just as his
father had hoped.
Now
the analogy that I see there,
we'll pursue it in more detail,
but the first analogy is the idea of a
safe and segregated like a wallet space.
So parodies of paradise means walled
garden.
And I mentioned that Eden means
well-watered place.
So the idea is the same,
that if you want to produce a paradise
for someone,
you all in a space and you keep
everything that's not acceptable or that
might cause existential distress let's
say.
And You keep that out.
And I would say,
well it's also,
there's also a very interesting analog
between that and the genesis story,
but also between that and the role of
parenthood in general.
Because what you essentially do with
young children is you wall off the space
and you try to make the conditions
within that space optimal.
And the reason that you do that is so
that the kids,
your kids fall in love with life and so
they have to be cared for properly and
attended to and cajoled in some sense
into living.
I mean we know for example,
that
children who don't receive proper
physical care,
proper love is the right way of
describing it,
don't thrive and sometimes they die.
And so it isn't enough to provide
children with food and shelter
and to protect them from the elements
they have to be interacted with
physically.
They have to be touched because
otherwise they don't live.
And they have to be interacted with
continually.
And you know,
that became very clear.
Well it was first learned in the late 18
hundreds when the mortality rate for
orphans under one was 100%
this guy in New York whose name
unfortunately escapes me,
was very curious about why this is b was
because the children were,
you know,
at least receiving what you might think
of as the bare minimum of care.
And he journeyed to Germany,
he had heard about a nurse there named
fat Ana who had the miraculous ability
to keep children under one alive,
at least in her ward.
The mortality rate was much lower.
And so he went there to observe what she
was doing and all she was doing was
taking the children out of their little
infant cribs and putting them sort of on
a carrier on her hip and just walking
around with them.
And then she'd put that child back in
the crib and take another one out and
walk around with the child.
And so the child got,
you know,
surface contact and a bit of
stimulation.
And that seemed to be enough.
I mean that's pretty minimal,
but it was it a lot better than nothing.
And that was the first time that people
understood explicitly that there were
necessities to childcare other than,
you know what you might regard as the
bare minimum
with little rats,
rat pups.
If you take rat pups away from their
mother and you feed them and give them
enough water and warm fail also guide.
The other thing that you have to do with
them,
what are what the research is do with
them as they take a pencil with an
eraser on the end of it and then they
massage the little rat pups with the,
with the research end of the pencil.
And that's enough to make them feel
loved,
I suppose.
And Ben,
they thrive and,
and there was a woman named Tiffany
Fields,
I think this work was originally done by
Jaak Panksepp,
the massage work with the rat pups.
And there's a woman named tiffany field
who started the program in Florida where
they massaged premature infants who are
in the incubators for,
I believe it was three times a day for
10 minutes.
And what happens with children,
these are premature infants generally
who are in incubators.
What generally happens to them is first
of all,
they lose weight.
And that's really not good because
children,
infants near birth are supposed to be
packing on a lot of weight.
Um,
so any loss is not only the loss but
also a decrease from the gain.
And so,
you know,
it,
it raises their mortality rates
substantially.
And what fields and her researchers
found that was that three minutes of
three sessions of massage for 10 minutes
a day would the babies who were given
that would gain weight as fast as
children who were still in the womb and
that you could detect positive
physiological,
psychological and so forth,
emotional benefits six months later,
which is a very long time in them in the
life of an infant.
So,
so that's all to say that,
you know,
the role of parents is to set up a
protective wall for all intensive
purposes around their children so that
they're not subjected to,
you know,
the unabated harshness of life.
And then to cajole them into living and
thriving.
You know,
we need know that children have a place
circuit that separate so they need to
play.
And the touch circ seems to be mediated
by all opiates.
And so one of the consequences of that
is that if a child has scraped his or
her knee and comes running up to you and
says fix it and you give them a hug and
pat them,
that fixes it because the touch is
actually analgesic.
And so it's also a useful thing to know
if you're ever dealing with someone
who's grieving because there's not much
you can do about grief.
From our cognitive perspective,
you know,
I mean you can help allay people's guilt
is if they're suffering from undue guilt
about the circumstances.
But if they're grieving,
they're are in pain because grief is a
pain response.
Technically speaking,
you can leave it with opiates.
You can also alleviate it with
antidepressants to some degree,
which is also something else worth
knowing because sometimes you'll see
someone who's so deep in grief that
they're going to hurt themselves because
of it.
You know,
it's traumatizing.
It'll produce brain damage.
It'll really do the men.
And that's just not helpful.
So it's useful to know that
antidepressants can ameliorate that,
you know,
and you might say,
well,
people still have to go through it.
Natural grieving process.
It's like,
well actually the grieving process is
the pain that the healing process is the
rebuilding of a life outside of the
person who saved who died.
And that takes time and effort and the
antidepressant isn't going to interfere
with that.
So it's not self evident that people
have to suffer themselves three quarters
to death in order to begin the healing
process post grief,
but conscious also very helpful
directly.
And so one of the things I recommend to
my clients who are grieving is that they
go get massages because it's comforting.
You know,
that direct human to human contact
actually has a antique grief effect.
So all right.
So anyways,
the Buddha grows up in this beautiful,
attractive,
safe place.
But of course he'd be,
he develops into adolescence that makes
them curious.
And so he notices more and more
consciously the existence of the walls
and starts to wonder what's outside.
MMM.
And so he starts to play,
gets farther.
He wants to go out and he wants to go
out and he wants to go out.
And of course that's a developmental
story too because that's exactly what
happens with children,
right?
Is that once they hit,
oh it's probably 11 something like that
there,
I mean even at for their orientation
starts to move away from the parental
unit out to the social community.
So
a child should be socialized
with regards to his or her ability to
interact with nonfamilial with people
who aren't part of the family between
the ages of two and four.
So at two a child is still pretty
egocentric.
It's hard for them to play with other
children.
They can play beside them and you know,
they,
they can play to some degree.
Two year olds are actually often quite
good at playing with babies,
which is quite interesting.
You know,
it seems to be part of their inbuilt
capacity,
you know,
but between two and four they have to
learn complicated lessons.
Like how to share.
That's a tough one.
And because it kind of,
you know,
it involves taking the place of the
other person to some degree.
But it also involves comprehending the
future.
You know,
the idea that if you lend something out,
someone else can play with it and you'll
get it back.
And that'll be okay.
And that's a complicated one.
And then they also have to learn how to
negotiate a script,
which is a ridiculously important thing
to learn,
right?
So
they can either do that
formally when they play,
say a board game that has rules,
a simple board game or a game like
marbles that actually has rules to which
they have to subordinate themselves.
So basically what's happening is they're
moving from a egocentric perspective
where they're only playing their own
game under the guys,
you know,
under the control of their own
motivational,
uh,
structures to playing a game that two
people or more conjoined into under the
rubric of a higher order system of,
of rules and goals.
So what they're basically doing is
learning to subordinate their motive,
individual motivational states to a
state of being that allows multiple
people to integrate their motivational
and emotional states across time.
It's very,
very sophisticated,
very complicated thing to learn how to
do.
And then of course they also learn how
to do,
how to pretend,
play and pretend and play is far more
important than people generally realize.
The typical pretend script will be,
there's a number of kids,
you know,
two or more and they're going to play.
They're going to have a little dramatic
episode,
like maybe they're going to play house
or,
and then they're all assigned roles.
That's all from mutual agreement and
then the kids basically negotiate what
the script is going to be and then they
play it out.
It's,
it's a form of thinking,
right?
It's a,
it's a form of embodied thinking,
but what's really interesting about it
is that
they have to agree on the structure of
the gay man,
the roles.
Well,
when you negotiate with adults for the
rest of your life,
especially in an intimate relationship,
that's exactly what you're going to do.
If you're negotiating properly.
It's like,
okay,
what do we want to have happen here in
this space that we share and how are we
going to conduct ourselves mutually?
So that occurs and people are really,
really not good at that,
you know?
But it is an extended form of play.
And if the relationship is going well,
then there's all,
there's an element of play in it because
that's one of the things that makes it
enjoyable instead of just,
you know,
tyranny and necessity so well so the
child starts to move out into the world.
But that increases,
you know,
the,
the voyage length in some sense
increases.
Cause the other thing children do,
and this is often but not always with
their mothers,
they use her as a marker of defined
territory.
I think that's the easiest way to think
of it.
And then they screwed out from that
marker and do some exploring until get
tired or overwhelmed.
Then they come back and they get
comforted and pat and you know,
put back into a routine and then they're
all put back together and then they go
out next time a little bit farther and
they run batch.
And so a big chunk of what you're doing
as a parent is not so much 24 seven
monitoring as making yourself available
as a resource when the child deems
necessary.
So that's part of why it's useful to be
around and well,
I mean,
if you're a parent,
your place can be taken by another
adult.
But that's only true really.
If the child knows the adult,
like children can make multiple parent
like bonds.
But one thing they hate is having their
primary caregiver changed because that
the primary caregivers,
their whole world.
And so when you change that on them,
you just flip them upside down.
And so they can tolerate multiple
caregivers,
but they have a really rough time
tolerating transitions in child
care givers,
especially the younger they are the
worst that is so well then you know,
as the child progresses towards
adolescence,
then there's another burst of
independent seeking activity pretty much
at puberty for obvious reasons.
And you know,
that's when the child is going to turn
their attention almost entirely to
fitting into the social world.
And so that's a form of apprenticeship.
We talked about that earlier in class.
So you can think the child goes from
dependence to like dependence on the
familial structure to interdependence
with other children.
And,
and then that sort of would transform
into in culturation and the development
of an idea of a cultural identity.
And then perhaps there's a stage past
that where morality is defined as
something outside of pure cultural
identification.
And that would be something more akin to
an individuation.
And that's the stage at which,
and this is a pay as Jedi and idea,
the person recognizes themselves as a
creator and modifier of rules as well as
a follower and adherence of rules.
And you can even think to some degree
that the divide between conservative and
liberal is a divide if that sort,
now the mapping isn't precise,
but the conservatives tend to be low in
openness and high in conscientiousness.
So they're not that interested in
transformation.
They're interested in maintaining the
rules of the game and doing well within
that set of rules.
And the liberals position is,
well sometimes the lip,
the rules themselves need to be altered
and so you can't blindly accept the game
and follow it.
You have to be willing to adjust it when
it's necessary.
And so there's a constant tension
between those two positions.
That's somewhat like the tension between
it was cyrus and horrors.
If it's all conservative than things
stultify and that's not good because the
world changes and if your static
cultural system doesn't change,
then it falls by the wayside.
But the Conservatives would say,
well don't be changing more things than
you have to because all you do is invite
chaos in.
And so you could say in some sense that
there's a pant on both sides of the
political continuum and the pit on the
conservative side is stultification and
the pit on the liberal side is chaos.
And so the whole polity is trying to
continually maneuver between chaos and
order.
And the way you do that isn't by having
the Liberals or the Conservatives win.
The way you do that is by having the
Liberals and conservatives talk.
And as soon as they can't talk,
then there's trouble because they both
stand for principle that can't be
abandoned.
So,
and because the balance between chaos
and order shifts with time as the
environment shifts awake and aware,
people have to continually negotiate to
determine exactly where that line is
because it's not in the same place all
the time.
So,
and that's not going so well at the
moment,
especially in the u s you know,
that's not good and who knows what will
come of it,
but it's definitely not good.
So all right,
so that by the time you know a child is
adolescent,
then there's a fair bit of impetus to
move out into the world beyond the
confines of the familial structure.
Um,
if that doesn't happen,
then generally you could infer that
the child has not had it easy.
Either the child is quite dependent in
terms of its fundamental temperament or
that its independence has not been
properly fostered by the parents.
Now.
So there's,
there's,
there was literature now,
and I haven't looked into this for,
it's probably 20 years now,
but there was literature that I was
aware of when I was doing research on
drug and alcohol abuse,
that there were two populations at risk.
If you look at how children,
adolescents use drug and alcohol,
drugs and alcohol in junior high and
high school,
there were two populations at risk.
One population was those who
experimented with everything and used
everything to an access and all you can,
it doesn't take much description to
understand where that might lead to
antisocial behavior and,
and whatever damage you might accrue by
formulating your socialization around
alcohol for example.
But the other group that was in trouble
with those kids who never experimented
and so it was,
you've got two kinds of pathologies
there and one pathology was a chaos
pathology basically.
And the other one was an order
pathology.
And the kids in the middle were ones who
had experimented to some degree.
You know,
because partly what adolescents are
doing this poking the social world,
the world of law,
really to see where its contours are.
You know,
cause part of the question is,
well is it necessary for me to follow
these rules?
And you can't be told that you have to
experiment and see what the necessity is
for the rule following.
And that means that your parents have to
allow you,
at least in principle,
there's a certain amount of freedom that
you need to be allowed,
or at least that's one way of looking at
it.
So there's at least some freedom that
you have to be allowed.
If the goal of parenting is the
production of someone who's capable of
taking care of themselves.
Now,
you know,
it isn't obvious that that's always the
goal of parenting,
because some cultures are more
interdependent and there's no necessary
presumption on the part of the parents
that the person is going to live.
The person is going to have to be
capable of living in a fully independent
existence.
But
okay,
so what happens is the king's son gets
curious now at this point,
he also has a,
a retainer,
a guy who is with them all the time,
who's teaching and things,
but
the gods had got wind of it,
the father's plan,
and decided that they weren't going to
make things as simple as he wanted it to
be.
So the retainer is an agent of the gods.
And so,
and he's always whispering in the,
in the son's ear.
Well anyways,
Buddha,
the future Buddha gets curious and
decides I'm going out,
I'm going out there.
And so his father realizes that some
point that there's just no way that he's
going to be able to be kept inside.
So he pulls a fast one,
it goes out to the city surrounding the
walled city to the area surrounding the
walled city.
And he chases away all the homeless
people and he chases away all the
elderly people and he chases away all
the sick people and he has everybody
spruce everything up so that it's in
perfect shape.
And then he aligns the streets that the
Buddhists carriage is going to go
through with the most attractive people
he can find all cheering.
And so one day they opened the gates and
the Buddha rides out in his,
in his chariot,
his cart and his,
his retainer is behind them.
And you know,
they go down the streets and the
Buddhist,
they can,
this is just a final day.
And then someone who's ill wanders out
onto the road in front of him and he's
looking pretty rough.
This guy,
he's very sick and it's evident just by
looking at him that things are not going
well.
And you know what the Buddhist stops his
chariot and the shock watching this
person,
you know,
stumble across the road and he asks his
retainer,
what the hell's going on here?
And the retainer says,
well,
you know this,
this person is ill and he's,
he's not,
something has gone wrong with him.
He's not functioning well.
And illness is the law of mankind and it
happens to everyone.
And so the Buddhists not very happy
about that piece of information and
bang,
he goes back into the walled city and
that's just like he's running back to
his mother,
roughly speaking.
It's the same idea,
right?
It's,
it's a piece of information.
He's just being offered an anomalous
piece of information that's sufficient
to shatter the structure of some of his,
his,
his value hierarchy.
Wow.
Back.
He goes,
you know,
and it takes them like six months to
digest that piece of information,
but he manages it.
And then his curiosity starts to grow
again.
And so he starts harassing is farther
again about going outside again.
So the father tries to pull the same
trick,
but he's extra careful this time.
He makes sure all the sick people are
rounded up and put somewhere where no
one's going to see them.
And he lightens the streets again and
the Buddha goes out and it's a beautiful
day and the streets are lined with
cheering people and all of a sudden the
gods are involved in this.
They're playing tricks on the father.
So they're the random,
that's the random uncontrollable
element,
you know?
And I would say that's roughly
equivalent to the snake in the garden of
Eden.
So it's the Buddhist curiosity that
drives him out.
You know,
even though his father tells him that
it's his set it up so that he shouldn't
go.
And when he goes out there,
the anomalous thing,
oh,
occurs and fractures.
So he goes out,
well this time someone who's really
agent hobbles out into the road,
you know,
all gray and wrinkled and bent over and
not move and very well.
And the Buddha is shocked out of his
mind again.
And he says to his retainer,
what's,
what's up with this?
And His retainer.
He says,
look,
you know how you've,
you know,
going from small to larger and you know
how you grow.
Well people continue to do that,
but at some point they start to age and
things don't go so well and event and,
and that's the law of mankind.
And so the Buddha is like,
that's enough fun for one day and bang,
he goes back into the walled city and
this time he stays inside for a whole
year.
It's just like the rats who go out there
and see that cat,
you know,
and then go back to their burrow and
scream for two weeks.
He's exactly the same idea.
And so far in a year later,
he's more or less put himself back
together and he decides to go out again.
And as father pose exactly the same
trick for exactly the same reasons,
but this time the butsudan encounters a
funeral procession and he can see the
body and it's lying there still in cold
and everyone is weeping and dressed in
black and it's a terrible situation.
And the Buddha asked his retainer,
what's up with this?
And His retainer says,
well you know,
you saw someone who was sick and you saw
someone who was old.
And like the worst case scenario for
both of those is death.
And the Buddhist says,
well what's thought?
And the retainer explains to him as best
he can.
Well this time this is such a shock that
he can't even go back to the,
to the wall garden so to speak.
So as farther,
so this is the sort of shock that
completely collapses his belief and his
say infantiles paradise.
It's the death idea.
Then it's the same idea that comes up in
genesis,
right?
Is that when Adam and eve are driven by
their curiosity to interact with this
snake like entity,
you know,
their realization is one of death and
that blows paradise permanently.
They don't go back.
In fact,
God makes it impossible for them to go
back,
which is a variation in the Buddhist
story because Buddha himself decides
that he's not going back well as farther
has one more trick up his sleeve.
So he calls on the most attractive women
in the kingdom to go into a forest
nearby and to disrobe and to dance
erotically and to attract and you know,
to bring the boat of there,
to attract them back into life,
to make him feel that the pleasures of
living are sufficient so that this
unfortunate incident can be put behind
it.
But when he goes into the forest,
all he can think about is the
transformation of flesh into decay and
death.
And that's that done.
He can't go home again.
And that's what starts this journey.
And so the next thing the Buddha does as
he becomes an add depth at all sorts of
different disciplinary traditions,
you know,
so he becomes an ascetic and he starves
themselves so thoroughly that you know,
you can see a single grain of rice
passed down his throat and he,
you know,
so he puts himself through martial arts
traditions and ascetic traditions and
all sorts of religious traditions trying
to in some sense put himself back
together.
So the idea is that his fundamental and
naive non self conscious early belief
system is fractured completely by his
discovery of sickness,
old age and death.
And then as a fractured entity,
he then submits himself to various forms
of discipline trying to reconstitute
himself.
None of that really succeeds.
And then the story ends with him going
under a tree,
the Bodhi tree and adopting that classic
boot oppose and trying to attain
lightman enlightenment through
meditation and self examination,
which he actually manages to do.
And then he attains enlightenment and is
in a state of Nirvana,
but decides that he can't,
he,
he decides that it's immoral to stay in
that
mode of being unless everybody can be
there.
So he leaves Nervana,
which in some senses it's final
temptation.
He leaves Nirvana and then goes out and
starts to teach.
And so that's the story of the Buddha.
So now you know the off the most obscure
part of that is what happens underneath
the bow tree.
No.
Now there's an,
there's an,
there's also an analog between that and
what happens in the,
the whole,
what would you call it,
and narrative of Christianity because
what happens with Christ is that his
identity with God is fundamentally
manifested when he ends up on a tree.
It's different,
right?
Because there's a crucifixion on a tree
and it is regarded as a tree in a,
what would you call it,
in the mythological tradition.
So there's an idea in symbolic
Christianity that Christ is crucified
on,
on this,
on the same tree where Adam discovered
that he was going to die.
And there's a reason for that.
Like there's a reason for that.
And the reason fundamentally is that,
okay,
both genesis and the story of the Buddha
make the proposition that it's this,
it's the,
uh,
ultimate extension of self consciousness
that
devastates people existentially.
It's the discovery of death,
let's say.
But it's not just that,
it's,
it's vulnerability per say.
It's not just death because there are
worse things than death and that it's
that discovery of ultimate vulnerability
that turns people into the creatures
that they are.
And that one response to that is to
build culture,
which is exactly what happens with the
Buddha.
He,
Trevor's has multiple cultures,
right?
Becoming a master of many specific sub
cultures.
And then what happens in the old
testament is that after the fall and
after the story of Adam and eve and
after the story of Noah,
those are all that really before the
flood story.
So those are the really ancient stories.
Then you fall into history and you have
the continual creation and destruction
of the,
of the Israel lights,
states and,
and you know,
then there's a break in some sense
between Judaism and Christianity.
And it's an interesting break.
You know,
I'm no expert in Judaism,
but Aye.
Aye.
I think I've got this basically right,
is that the Christians make a decision
that whatever Christ represented was the
solution to the problem,
not only of emergent self consciousness
but also for the insufficiency of
history.
Because remember you get an empire
building and collapsing and then empire
building and collapsing and an empire
building and collapsing.
And you know,
one answer to that is a bigger and
better empire.
And another answer is there's something
wrong with the idea of empire as a
solution to the initial problem.
And I would say that the Jews and the
Christians basically split on that
proposition.
And so that's partly why,
I mean from the,
from the
position of Judaism,
there may still be a messiah buddy,
but that person is not someone who's yet
appeared.
And then there's another proposition
which is the state itself is redemptive
and that's played out at least in part
in Israel where the state is viewed as
redemptive,
that things will go well for the Jewish
people.
If an only if they can establish a
state.
Now,
a skeptic would say,
yeah,
but all the things that the state was
supposed to keep out,
start cropping up inside.
And I think that you have to be rather
blind not to see that that's happened to
a large degree in Israel.
I mean,
one of the things that's happened,
forget about the Palestinians and the
Arabs for the time being,
but even with in Judaism itself,
there's a major fracture between the
more orthodox Jews,
the ones who are very,
very,
very conservative in their beliefs and
habits and the more secular,
you know,
Westernized Jews.
And it's,
it's some sense,
it's the distinction between right wing
and left wing.
But that's been,
you know,
a very,
very dire advisive divisive battle
within Israel.
And what it shows in part is that you,
just because you establish a state
doesn't mean you can assume that the
kind of homogeneity that will eliminate
conflict will then rain within that
state because people within the state
can fragment into different groups just
like states themselves can be
representative of other groups.
Now the,
if you look at the symbolic meaning I
think,
or the psychological meaning of
Christianity,
the idea is that the answer to the
pathology of the state is the constant
renewal of the individual.
And so
that that
falls into alignment with the idea of
death and rebirth.
You know?
So if the problem is the balance between
chaos and order,
both at the state level and the,
and the individual level,
you might say,
well where,
where should action take place in order
to redeem the state?
And they,
I would say that the central Western
idea,
and this is something emerged out of
Christianity,
was that the way to transform the state
is through the transformation of the
individual.
So rather than the other way around,
which is you transform the state and
hope all the individuals follow,
we tried that for example,
in the Soviet Union because you could
say that the communist experiment was
precisely the attempt to modify the
state so that the individuals would
follow.
Now I've been reading,
I just bought a new book,
very cheerful book called the Black Book
of communism and it was published in
France in 1999 and the fact that it was
published in France is particularly
interesting because of all the European
countries with the possible exception of
Italy,
communists had the largest sway over
especially intellectual life.
And so I would say that the life of
intellectuals in France after World War
II was overwhelmingly radically left
way.
And,
and not just to have the socialist type,
but of the communist hype.
I mean both,
both Italy and France had communist
parties and the French intellectuals,
including people like Sartre,
were sergeant never did belong to the
communist party,
but he was a supporter of the Communist
Party and all the people,
all the French thinkers that are
worshiped,
so to speak,
in universities today were all radical
left wingers who were involved in the
student riots in 1968 and their beliefs
were tantamount to communistic
and that's not a good thing.
So this book was written by people,
many of whom were former French
intellectual communists.
And it was written in 1999 and I read
the foreword and two of the chapters
last night.
And
the first thing that the person who
wrote the foreword claims is that it
wasn't possible to do a real analysis of
the historical significance of communism
until 1999 until basically the end of
the century.
Because what the Communists had done was
so obscure and so secret that there was
no way to discover it.
And I thought that's complete rubbish
because by 1945 or there abouts,
George Orwell was already writing animal
farm and,
and he wrote,
um,
1984 in 1948,
he just reversed the last letters and he
knew perfectly well what was happening
in the communist countries.
And so if your eyes were open,
I would say by 1935,
you could tell because that's more or
less in the midst of the Ukrainian
famine,
which killed some four to 6 million
people.
So,
so anyways,
so there was the 30s then things were
complicated by the fact of the Second
World War because,
well,
first of all,
the radical left was fighting against
fascism.
Say in Spain to begin with,
and lots of European and American
intellectuals went to Spain to against
Franco and ended up on the side roughly
speaking of the communists.
So that complicated things because the
Frankel faction where it's definitely
bad news.
So it was like a prototype of World War
II because Franco was a fascist and he
ruled until wasn't very long ago.
Well,
compared to World War Two,
I think it was maybe 1989 somewhere
around 1980 he finally died and Fred and
Spain transformed itself back into a
democracy.
And I went to Spain just before that.
And it was,
it was an unbelievably poor country.
You could stay in Spain,
in the middle of Madrid for a dollar 50
at night.
So that would be probably equivalent to
about $5 now.
And that got you a private room with a
shower and breakfast and wine there was
cheaper than water.
It was about 75 cents a bottle,
which is something I remember very
fondly.
But you know,
its economy was entirely devastated.
So in the Spanish civil war,
the left wing rose up against them.
The fascists essentially in that was a
precursor to World War II.
And then when World War II emerged,
even though Stalin had made it number of
packs with Hitler,
you know,
the Russians joined the West as an ally.
And so for a while there,
it was counterproductive in some sense
too,
to be criticizing the,
the Soviet Union to intently because
there was something that needed to be
taken care of first.
So there's some excuse for focusing on
the Nazi horror first and then,
and only then focusing on what happened
in the communist countries,
but still by the end of World War II,
anybody who wanted to know could know.
And what that basically meant was that a
massive swath of the western,
until intelligentsia put their damn
heads in the sand and protected regimes
that were so pathological that they
defied description.
So there are,
there are relatively new figures in this
black book of communism that describe
deaths.
So you can attribute 25 million deaths
directly to the Nazi oppression and 100
million to communism.
So the bulk of that was the Soviet
Union,
where it's 20 to 35 million
Solzhenitsyn,
estimated 60 million.
And I should also say something about
soul Jeanette's.
So the French intellectuals who are
behind the publication of this book,
which by the way,
it was a hit in France.
It was a bestseller and very,
very controversial,
partly because people said,
well,
if you criticize the left,
then you,
you know,
the radical left,
then you give carte blanche to the
radical,
right.
And of course the radical right has
become an emergent phenomena.
Well,
you're going to watch it play out
because here it comes,
you know,
Sweden,
all the Scandinavian countries,
Germany,
Holland,
France,
the right wing parties are coming back.
And that's not going to stop.
And of course,
the same thing is happening in the
United States with trump.
So the left radical left wingers in
France were saying,
well,
you don't pick on the communists even
historically,
because that'll validate the claims of
the radical right wingers,
which I think is an entirely appalling
and pathetic argument.
You know,
it's like saying,
don't criticize the Nazis,
because that'll encourage the
communists.
It's just not an acceptable way of
comporting yourself.
And so,
but,
but anyways,
it was not politically correct shall we
say to criticize the Communists,
especially in France and,
but that turned around to some degree by
1999 but I should also say that it was
1974 that soldier knits and wrote his
book,
the Gulag Archipelago.
And if you own it to know what was
happening in the Soviet Union,
oh,
you had to do is read that book like
it's a hell of a book.
It's 27 I think it's 2,700 pages long
and it's very small type and it's,
it's one intense piece of work.
You know,
you don't read that as bedtime reading
because it's,
it's so draw jokingly appalling that
it's like permanently traumatizing.
But if you wanted to know,
you could've known in 1974 and more to
the point you could have known in 1945
he could've known in 1930 but the
western intelligentsia basically covered
up the communist pathology,
I would say for something on the order
of 70 years.
And we,
there's been no reckoning with that
whatsoever.
In America,
in,
in European,
higher institutions of learning.
And so one of the things I still see,
and I see this because I talk about this
quite a bit in my psychology to 30
classes that virtually every student
knows about the Holocaust and,
and for a good reason,
but very,
very few people know what happened in
Soviet,
in the Soviet Union or certainly in
China where the French estimates are now
65 million people.
Right?
So when,
you know,
that's so we'll pay to us.
You know,
I know some things about this,
but not very much.
I mean,
I know that you could certainly make the
claim that Mao was the greatest monster,
whoever lived,
you know,
even though he's still a revered figure
in China,
which is appalling figure,
you know,
an appalling thing all in itself.
Now,
I don't know if you guys noticed this
morning,
you probably didn't,
but one of the things that was trending
on facebook was Kim young ills.
I think that's his name.
I get all those horrible,
wretched dictators confused because they
all look the same and have the same
general satanic essence.
We basically like back in the,
I think it was in the 80s,
but it might've been in the 90s,
3 million or so North Korea and starve
to death.
And what's his name?
The dictator came out and announced
today too,
is North Korean population that they're
going to have to go back.
And he said this to sucking routes to
survive.
And not only that,
he's demanding that every family in the
capitol donate two pounds of rice a
month to the state warehouses.
So you can see where communist economics
gets you.
It's the warehouses that are supposed to
be distributing the food to the starving
people that are now tyrannizing them
into donating what they don't even have
to the state warehouses.
And so,
you know,
that's the last bastion of Stalinism
slashed Maoism and the Chinese of course
still support North Korea,
even though it is,
there's plenty of pathological countries
on the face of the planet.
But you know,
you'd have to give either the gold or
the silver metal to North Korea,
no where no one has enough to eat except
a tiny proportion of,
you know,
uh,
unbelievably corrupt aristocracy right
at the talk.
And you know,
he's treated as if he's a divinity.
He is a kind of divinity but not the
positive
kind.
So,
all right,
so back to back to,
so the idea there is,
you know,
if you're trying to figure out how to
rectify the plight of humanity,
that's,
that's a good way of conceptualizing the
problem.
So the plight is laid out both in the
story of the Buddha and in the stories
that we covered last week in genesis.
It's very straightforward.
People woke up and noticed that they
were going to die.
It's more complicated than that,
but it's because it's not just death,
it's vulnerability in all fronts.
So you could say death,
insanity and social judgment.
So death,
illness,
insanity and social judgment.
That's what being self conscious means
to people.
And I would say that two largest class
of fears go along with the mythological
categories that we've been discussing
because people are most afraid of the
terrible mother and the dragon,
so to speak.
That's chaos,
that's death.
And the other thing they're most afraid
of is tyrangiel judgment.
And you know those things are
intertangled because of course,
if you're rejected by your culture and
forced to the bottom of the hierarchy,
the probability that you're going to
confront it,
chaotic death radically increases.
So you know,
you can't really separate out rejection
from,
from chaos,
but those are deaf.
And you'll see this with people with
anxiety disorders.
They're almost always afraid of two
categories of things.
One is death and the illness,
and the other is social judgment.
So if you take the typical agoraphobic
her,
because she,
it's usually she,
her biggest fear is that she's going to
have a heart attack on a subway and make
a fool of herself while she dies.
And you know,
because that's,
well,
it's like the ultimate nightmare in some
sense.
It is.
It is in fact the ultimate
nightmare.
Now,
the problem with the story of the Buddha
in part is that the ending,
the enlightenment element is vague.
It isn't clear what happens there.
Now I have a suspicion that that story
grew out of a far older tradition,
which was the shamanic tradition.
And one of the things that's
characteristic of the shamanic tradition
is that the Sharman usually they take
some kind of psychoactive drug in the
Siberia,
which is where shamanism was most widely
spread and most established,
the drug was am anita miscarried,
which is a particular kind of mushroom.
It's the red mushroom with the white
caps on it,
quite white dots on it that you see in
fairy tales all the time.
And there's a reason for that.
And and you know,
uphold that would occupy that.
That connection between Earth and heaven
was often a central feature of a
shamanic ritual.
And one of the things that was happening
with the showman is that when they took
the psychoactive drug,
they would climb in the pool that
represented that connection between
earth and have,
and then they would go up into the
domain of the gods,
which is roughly equivalent to the idea
of Buddha reaching nirvana.
And so there's a,
there's a UN charted relationship
between the most archaic human
religions,
which were virtually undoubtedly
grounded in the use of very powerful
psychoactive chemicals and the Buddhist
tradition.
And I think part of the reason that the
vagueness is there is because the direct
connection between the,
what would you call it,
the theological use of transformative
substances.
And the doctrine per se is not being
well specified.
I mean now you see the same thing in,
in South America,
the drug there is usually Iowasca,
which is chemically actually
am Anita Mascara's different chemicals
from Iowasca.
IOWASCA is very much like psilocybin and
LSD.
It has the same ring molecular
structure.
But of course when the,
when the Amazonian Sharman take Iowasca,
they also communicate with the ancestors
and the gods.
That's a classic shamanically
pathway.
First communion with the ancestors,
then communion with the gods,
and it's actually based on the direct
experience of the people who are putting
themselves into this ceremony.
So there's also some very interesting
connections historically between
Christianity and the use likely of
siliciden mushrooms.
So there was a very weird book written
in 1968 or thereabouts called the magic
mushroom,
the sacred mushroom and the cross,
I think that's the name of it where it
was a linguist who identified linguistic
patterns between the theological claims
of Christianity and the language used to
describe mushrooms and their effect.
Now that book came out sort of at the
height of the hippie revolution and even
though it was a serious book,
it was sort of shunted off into the
hippies wrote this category.
It's not a hippie book at all.
I've read it a couple of times.
I have no idea what to make of the board
because,
because it's based on like with sticks,
it's far outside my range of of
competence to evaluate.
But you certainly can't brush it off
lightly.
And since then there's been all sorts of
evidence emerged that the use of
mushrooms might've been central to it
too early Christianity.
Anyways,
the fundamental split,
you could say that,
I think this is a reasonable way to look
at it too,
is that once the basic problem that
faces humanity is laid out rather than
clearly.
And so we'll say the s the problem
month,
painful self consciousness and knowledge
of which is a major problem,
right?
I mean the terror management people,
it's social psychologists who are terror
management theorists basically say that
that's rendered people permanently
pathological and that they have to use
illusion in order to defend themselves
against that.
Freud basically made the same argument,
um,
when he was criticizing classical
religion,
he basically said,
well,
people are using religious nonsense
roughly speaking as a way of shielding
themselves against their fear of death
because they're too immature to be able
to tolerate the reality.
You know,
and it's,
it's an interesting criticism and I
found it quite compelling for quite a
long time and I do think that people
hide in their belief systems.
But I think one of the basic
shortcomings of the Friday and ideas
that it doesn't really account for why
people would invent the idea of hell,
for example,
because that doesn't really seem to be a
lot more comforting than the idea of
death.
In fact,
it's a lot worse.
It's like not only cause you to die,
but you die permanently or you die
forever continually in the most painful
possible ways.
I can't really see that as a why.
Why bother with that?
If it's an illusion,
you can say,
well it's just to make the illusion more
believable.
But you know,
once you have to throw to conspiracies
together to account for a phenomenon,
I think you're,
you're,
the onus of proof is definitely on you.
You know?
So,
okay,
so then the question is,
well,
what's the,
what's the cure for the pathology that
self conscious pathology?
And I could say,
I could say,
well,
there's two answers to that.
And one is the building of a state,
you know,
and,
and that's obviously that's if some
utility,
because the terror management people
tend to think of culture as
psychological and as a defense mechanism
against the fear of death.
But that's,
it's,
it's an overly psychological explanation
because obviously one of the things that
culture does as well as protecting you
from the fear of death is actually
protect you from death.
You know,
in our culture does everything it can
not only to protect you from death but
also to protect you from any exposure to
death.
You know,
part of the reason,
and this is something the sixties
hippies jumped up and down about two,
part of the reason that we have
psychiatric nomenclature and an entire
psychiatric system is to take people who
are so crazy that they're disturbing off
the streets so that they don't,
you know,
rake existential have on the people who
are outside.
You know,
and you can debate about whether or not
that's appropriate.
But you know,
it's definitely the case that it's much
more difficult to walk down the street
if there's very many people who are
overtly damaged.
And expressive about it on that street.
And you can say,
well,
they have a right to be there.
And you can say,
well,
the public has a right to protect
itself.
And obviously both those claims are
valid and there's,
you know,
the right way through it as a
consequence of dialogue.
But it's still nonetheless the case that
we're almost never exposed to extreme
old age were never exposed to death and
we're almost never exposed to,
you know,
insanity and physical illness unless you
go into a hospital or a place like that.
So one answer to the problem that faces
mankind is the state as the answer and
the other,
well let's,
and then we can examine that.
But the problem with that seems to be
that the state can split into something
that's very pathological and something
that isn't,
those are the archetypal elements of the
state.
And then you could make a case that when
the state is fully pathological,
it's actually worse than the original
problem.
So then the question becomes,
okay,
well the state has utility what you do
to stop it from becoming corrupt.
That's the real question.
As far as I can tell.
And so I would say the Egyptians
partially solved that problem when they
started to build their mythology,
of course.
And no cyrus,
because they basically said,
well,
there's two principles that have to be
at work in order,
not only in order to maintain the state.
And so we'll say against Isis and the
forces of the underworld.
Isis being the goddess of the
underworld,
not the new isis is pretty damn funding
that.
That's their initials,
you know,
so
the states in necessity,
but it has to be updated as a
consequence of the careful action of the
citizen,
you know,
by the attention of the citizen
represented by Horace.
Now,
there are many critiques of
Christianity.
I would say most of these come on the
atheistic end of things,
who make the point that if you take the
mythologies of Horace and the
mythologies of Christ and you line them
up side by side,
they're virtually the same.
So many of the mythological elements of
Christ's cause.
He's half saying that the logical and
half historical,
though the evidence for his historical
existence is very,
very thin.
But it's heavily mythologized.
And a lot of the mythology that was used
to represent Christ was just taken
completely from the mythology of horace.
And so the atheist tick wing of
criticism,
critics of Christianity say,
well obviously that means that
Christianity is false because it's
central figure was just granted the
attributes of the previous Egyptian
Daddy.
But well,
but I think that that criticism is
fundamentally beside the point in,
in the most important of ways because
the ideas of what characterized horace
emerged as a consequence of a lengthy,
I would say evolutionary process to
define what constituted the central
redeem or rubbed the state,
roughly speaking.
And then that was just translated on to
Christ.
And that that is just a continuation of
the religious dream in a sense.
It's not indication that there's
something fundamentally fraudulent about
Christianity.
I mean,
unless you think that Christianity is
based on the kind of history that
empirical historic historians regard his
history,
and that's not the only kind of history.
So,
all right,
so then I want it,
I want to talk about something else in
relationship to that.
So,
and this is sort of
in some sense,
this is the last part of the course,
which is good.
Given that we're coming to the end.
When I was working on these ideas,
I laid out the logic that you just,
that I just described to you,
you know,
to mankind as a fundamental existential
problem.
I don't think that's a particularly
radical claim that's made.
The claim is made by all sorts of
schools of thought,
not least the existentialists.
But I would say that that problem was
already put very clearly in our most
ancient religious writings.
So it's not a new idea.
It's a very,
very old idea.
And then out of that emerged,
the idea that is state would emerge as a
medication for that fundamental
pathology.
And you see that in genesis right away
because as soon as Adam and eve have
their eyes open,
they put on tape leafs.
So the first thing they do is turn fig
leaf is an emblem of culture,
you know,
it's clothing.
And so clothing is certainly one of the
things that distinguishes us from
animals.
And so the idea that we could build
structures that would protect ourselves,
well that's what we do and they work,
but they don't necessarily solve the
fundamental problem or at least they
don't solve it permanently and they lead
to another set of problems.
And the other set of problems is the
pathology of the state.
And so the state then instead of
becoming a defense,
a genuine defense or let's even say an
adaptation to our vulnerability starts
to become an exploiter of our
vulnerability.
And I would say that,
you know,
there are roots.
So the communist idea was a utopian
ideal.
And the idea was that,
okay,
the idea was that the pathology that
characterized human beings could be laid
at the feet of the state.
There was no notion whatsoever that part
of the pathology of being human is an
inbuilt part of being human.
Now that's kind of an original sin claim
in some sense is that we could keep all
the culture we want,
our new,
it's not going to solve your problem
now.
So the Marxist utopia and idea had its
roots in surgery,
strains of Christian Utopian thinking.
So because it was Saint Thomas Moore who
wrote the first book on Utopia.
And so,
you know,
Christianity in some sense influenced
the Utopian element of Marxism,
but it was the Marxists in particular
who decided that the reason that human
beings had problems was because of the
organization of the state
now.
So that,
and then there was a conclusion from
that and the conclusion was,
well,
if you just got rid of the apparent
pathology of the state,
then people would enter into a utopian
mode of being.
And so what are the pathologies in the
state?
While there are still the things that
radical egalitarians are opposed to
hierarchical structure,
differential,
uh,
distribution of resources,
that's pretty much,
you know,
private ownership is part of that.
But you know,
I would say that that's more like an
intake really that's tied integrity
within the first two problems.
And so then the Marxist idea was
basically on the one hand eradicate
prior to private property,
distribute resources equally eliminate
the distinctions between the classes
because they thought of classes as the
fundamental dividing,
you know,
categories of people not race like the
Nazis,
but class.
And then you'd usher inna an endless
utopia.
Well,
you know,
stated like that.
It just sounds stupid and you know,
because I,
I,
okay,
maybe that's too harsh,
but I don't really think it is in,
in the late 1800 stores get dusty Husky,
he knew all this was coming.
He absolutely knew this was coming and
God only knows how he knew it.
I mean human would say he was very much
in touch with the collective unconscious
and you could think of the collective
unconscious in some senses.
Like imagine that you have a system of
ideas,
you know,
think you are,
that you articulate and you are aware
of,
but they rest on a dream,
you know,
which is the place where the ideas are
coming from.
But also like the matrix out of which
the ideas emerge.
It's a dream like fantasy and it's
something that's more or less shared by
everyone.
And you could be farther away or closer
to that underlying dream like structure.
And the more artistic you are,
the more open,
I would say the closer you are to that
dream.
Like structure or Dostoyevsky was
immersed right inside of it.
And I think that was partly because he
was epileptic.
So because epileptics have transcendent
experiences often and,
and suffer from an overwhelming
intensification of emotions.
And so that did something to,
Dorsey has keep it sort of put them into
a different category.
That's what it looks like to me.
But anyways,
he knew this was coming in in his book,
the Devil's aptly named or the
possessed,
he says,
this is what's wrong with Russia.
Here's what's happened.
As a consequence of our belief system
falling apart,
here's the sort of person who is
destined to emerge and this is what's
going to happen.
It's exactly right.
So,
so,
and at the same time,
Dostoyevsky was thinking this through
and he and miss,
he did most clearly in the book notes
from underground,
which I would highly recommend that you
read because it's very short.
It's very interesting.
And it's an ultra bleed.
Brilliant.
And the reason it's brilliant is because
Dostoyevsky's main character in the
book,
you know,
who's partly informed by
autobiographical experience,
is a failed civil servant who is a
nobody.
And who was super resentful and he's a
coward.
He's angry,
resentful and cowardly.
But he's very,
very smart.
And of course he's very proud about the
fact that he's smart because that's
pretty much what he has to cling on to.
He doesn't have a family,
it doesn't have anything else,
but so he's an appalling person.
You could say he's caught the
underworld,
but what's interesting is that right
eat
being caught in the underworld,
in that chaos,
he doesn't degenerate right into someone
who's not allistic or totalitarian.
He kind of tolerates the tension and
there are certain things that emerge
for,
for him as potential truths.
And so one of the things he says was
that he sort of toyed with the idea of
utopia and he talks about,
he talks about the palace of crystal.
And so in the palace of crystal,
it's a perfect future utopia and
everyone has provided with what they
need.
And Dostoevsky says there are so well
provided that all they have to do is eat
cakes and busied themselves with the
reproduction of the species all day.
So you could think about it as a
realization in a sense is a concrete
realization of an economic utopia.
You don't have to work.
Everything you want is provided for you.
So everyone's happy.
And Dostoevsky says,
well,
you have to be out of your mind to think
that everyone would be happy under those
circumstances because people are
fundamentally insane.
And so that if you gave people
perfection,
the first thing they would do once they
got bored,
three quarters to death,
which would take about a week,
is run around looking for something to
smash,
just to cause some trouble,
just so that there'd be an interesting
problem.
And I think while you can see the,
the,
the relationship between that and the,
and uh,
uh,
the events in,
in the,
in the book of Genesis at the beginning,
you know,
because God tells eve don't mock up out,
be satisfied with what you've got and
her curiosity and to go interact with
the one thing in the whole place that
she shouldn't interact with and then all
hell breaks loose.
And then you have to ask yourself,
is that a good thing or a bad thing?
And what Dostoyevsky concludes is that
that's a good thing is it's that that
fundamental experience seeking
disruptive element of the human psyche
is actually the best thing about it.
And the idea that we could quell it's
operation,
but by providing what's essentially a,
you know,
a,
a return to the womb is something,
you know,
you could think about it that way where
you have no problems to think that that
would actually solve the problem is not
only absurdly immature but also just
false on the face of it.
You think,
well,
first of all,
that's an amazing conclusion.
I mean,
think about that.
Dostoyevsky's thought that through.
He figured out what was wrong with the
idea of communist utopia 40 years before
the Russian revolution.
I mean,
it's unbelievable.
Not only did he see what was coming,
he saw what was wrong with it,
you know,
and you could say the same thing about
Nichelle though,
I don't think Nietzsche ever read road
anything that has the like concentrated
narrative punch of notes from
underground.
And what happens in the [inaudible]
notes from underground.
In some senses it's a novel about
someone attempting to take niches,
route to being a superman,
a lot of Dostoyevsky's novels or both
that so risk gallman caught for example,
in crime and punishment who heads up
being a murderer essentially tries to
transform himself into a Nietzschean
Superman beyond good and evil,
making his own values and Dostoyevsky
plays that out in his conclusion is
don't break rules that you don't
understand because if you do something,
we'll take you down.
And that's basically what happens to her
skull Nichol.
He kills his,
the pawn broker and the pawn brokers.
Slave slash nice kills them with an ax.
He gets away with it,
he gets away with it.
No one has any idea that he does it and
he has access to all her money,
which he promptly bernease and I think
in an abandoned lot and wants absolutely
nothing to do with,
but you know,
it's constantly haunted by what he's
done and keeps revisiting that area,
you know?
And then a prosecutor starts to suspect
him even.
There's no reason to.
And basically subjects him to a Chinese
water torture.
He just taps him and taps him and taps
him and tapson and taps him until he
starts to break down and eventually can
facets and the cat and mouse game played
by the prosecutor and risk call Niqab is
absolutely psychologically terrified.
I've never seen anything like that in
any piece of literature because
Dostoyevsky was smart enough to figure
out exactly how you would torment
someone with a guilty conscience and to
confess and the prosecutor is patient,
he just plays them like you'd play a
fish well and were scolding the cog
undergo so we won't worry about the end
of the story cause it's not that
relevant
in notes from underground.
A similar thing happens is that this
narrator who is so pathological and
railing against his own cowardice and
his own resentment and so weakness,
but also not having any,
not granting any credence to the idea of
a future modern utopia.
He,
he tries to reconstruct his own
character.
And the way he does that is he ends up
in a relationship with this woman who's
been forced into prostitution,
which is,
was a very common consequence of female
poverty in that era because,
well,
because everyone was absolutely dirt
poor to begin with.
And because the alternatives were few
and far between,
if you fell out of your social class for
for any reason and he decides that he's
going to redeem her,
he's going to improve her life,
he's going to rescue her.
And so the last part of the book is
about him trying to rescue her buddy
fails because he just doesn't,
you know,
he takes on this job,
which is to help someone in real trouble
and like helping someone in real trouble
I would say is you bloody well better be
careful before you try that because real
trouble is real trouble.
And the probability that you'll have the
wherewithal to help instead of making it
worse is very,
very low.
And that's exactly what happens to him.
He sort of,
he attempts supposedly most both.
He sort of becomes narcissistic in his
estimation of his redemptive capability.
But there's a part of were part of him
is motivated by a general,
a genuine desire to help.
But when push comes to shove,
he can't tolerate the responsibility
that would take to follow it through and
he ends up betraying her.
And so of course she ends up in worse
condition than she was to begin with.
So it's an absolutely amazing novel and
there's more to it.
And I should tell you about this too.
So the palace of crystal was actually a
reference to an actual building.
And the building was a building that was
erected in England,
in London for the world's fair that was
held at that point.
And it was the first steel and glass
building of any size.
And so it was a forerunner of,
you know,
our,
our modern downtowns.
And the reason in part that every
downtown in the world looks the same.
If it was built say between the 1950s in
the 1970s 1980s the seventies where in
particular,
absolutely appalling.
But you know,
that was the new international style.
And,
and it was,
was originated in Germany and it was
predicated on the idea that the worker
would want a bare bones structure,
glass tower,
completely devoid of in the
ornamentation because that was all
birdwatch nonsense.
And that that style should be imposed
everywhere in the world as a movement
towards this sort of workers utopia.
Well you can see what that did.
You know,
so these,
you know,
I'm telling you that because these
ideas,
they stretch out and they have their
tentacles everywhere.
You know.
So that new international style that was
certainly responsible for things like
the housing projects in the United
States,
which were absolute catastrophes.
You know,
all came out of this dream up the
workers socialist paradise.
Well,
so Dostoevsky goes on the rampage
against that idea and on a psychological
basis he just says,
well,
don't be,
you really think that human beings are
constructed so that if you give them
enough to eat,
they'll be satisfied.
It's like,
that's not what we're like at all.
We're not even close to like that were
full of snakes and twists and insanity.
And he makes that case very
straightforwardly and says,
not only are we like that,
but that it's a really,
it's the best thing about us that we're
like that some re remarkable,
remarkable book.
So,
okay,
so,
well then we might say,
well,
what happened when these utopian schemes
were put into action?
All right,
so,
and describe what happened in the Soviet
Union and the girl in the Gulag
archipelago.
And he estimated that the stent,
the Soviets killed 60 million people
between 1919 in 1959 roughly speaking.
Now people have taken them to task for
that estimate,
but there's no good records.
And certainly the,
it's between 25 and 60 million.
And you know,
you might say,
well,
really does it matter?
Is that actually the point?
Once you're past your first 10 million,
you've already established your,
your character,
I would say.
You know,
and,
and Stalin said,
one,
death is a tragedy and a million deaths
is a statistic,
which pretty much gives you some insight
into how stellan thought.
So
what happened in,
in,
in the USSR?
Well,
here's the stat for you.
So czar,
you know,
before the USSR,
Russia was czarist,
right?
And so it was a monarchy like most
European countries were monarchies,
except it was more futile than most
European countries,
certainly far more than England say,
or France.
And the radicals regarded the czar as an
oppressor.
And so it was the oppression of bizarre
risks,
the czar and the aristocracy.
That was partly what provided the
impetus for the workers slash peasants
because they were mostly peasants in
Russia to rise up against,
let's say,
for the sake of simplicity,
they're class enemies from 1825 to 19 I
think it was 1900 it's right around
1,975 years.
The czar tourists sentence 6,000 people
to death for political crimes and
executed thousand in the years for 1919
to 1959 the communists killed 30
million.
So when we're thinking about the
communist revolution as a revolution
against tyranny and a justifiable
revolution against tyranny,
we should be very careful what it is
that we're defining as tyranny.
Now,
if you want to know what the Russian
camps were like four prisoners,
you can read Dostoyevsky's house of the
dead.
Because what happened to Dostoyevsky is
he was one of those people who was more
or less sentenced by the czar.
He was a student radical.
They throw him in prison,
took him out one day,
pretended to shoot them in a firing
squad,
used blanks,
shorter them out completely there.
There's some evidence that that's when
his epilepsy either started or really
became intense,
and then they banished him to a prison
in Siberia.
And the prison was full of thieves and
murderers and rapists.
And it was a rough place.
And you know,
Dostoyevsky was an aristocratic guy,
an educated person,
a young man.
He had no idea what to expect.
And so he wrote a book called the House
of the dead,
which is a very interesting book.
But if you read the house of the dead
and then you read the Gulag archipelago,
you think that like the house of the
dead was up.
I was up Caribbean,
Caribbean holiday camp compared to the
ghoulag.
I mean,
when the prisoners in the prison camps
in Dostoyevsky's prison,
sorry,
used to go into the villages,
which they did,
they could go into the villages.
I mean they regarded and all that,
but they could go there to work and
people would come out and give them
food.
Little kids would come up to them and
give them food because one of the
characteristics of Russian culture at
that point was that the peasants in
particular felt that the people who were
in prison were unfortunate,
you know,
and they felt bad for them.
It was part of their Orthodox Christian
charity.
And they also felt that maybe they were
only one step from the same thing.
And so their basic attitude was
charitable.
And you know,
they were fed in the prisons.
Like,
I mean,
it was hardly gourmet fair,
but of course everybody was so damn poor
at that time that that's not even a
reasonable comparison.
And you know,
it was rough,
but it wasn't,
it wasn't the most imaginative Roth you
could possibly imagine for the most
pointless possible purpose ending up in
your death and likely your family's
death.
It wasn't that.
And you know,
you got out of those camps,
you got out,
you do your sentence,
and then they would let you go.
They might exile you,
but even if you were Exxon,
you could have a life there.
So that was the extent of the judicial
and penitential tyranny of the czars,
you know,
and you know,
I'm not saying that the czarist system
was all sweetness and light,
but I don't think that's relevant.
It was part of the feudal system.
It had developed organically in some
sense across history.
The Russians were sort of on the slow
end of the developmental curve,
but,
but it wasn't handled a lot better than
what came afterwards.
So
after the,
the Soviets after Lenin took over,
now landon stepped in when,
when,
when Lennon stepped in to take power,
Russia was basically in chaos.
What had happened was World War One,
which was,
you know,
a frenzy of insanity and basically mark
the end of the monarchical system in
Europe.
It also marked,
by the way,
the dissolution of the Ottoman Empire
and the fragmentation of the Middle
East.
And so part of the reason that the
Middle East is parsed up the way it is
today is because the Ottoman empire
collapsed.
England and France still had some
dominion there as victors in World War
One and they created the Middle Eastern
countries out of the wreckage of the
Ottoman empire.
So,
you know,
we're still playing out the consequences
of that,
but it's something useful to know.
That's how that came about.
The empire collapsed,
but all the monarchical empires
essentially collapsed after World War
One.
Russia was devastated,
the soldiers were,
were deserting the trenches on Mohs and
coming home.
Part of it because the czar had
abdicated after he took control of the
armed forces,
things went south even further,
he abdicated and the new parliament,
which was sort of half democratic and
half socialist I would say,
was starting to divide up the land among
the peasants.
And so the soldiers were very motivated
to get the hell home so that they could
get some of this land.
But the whole country,
the overarching political system had
collapsed and the Russians were starting
to organize themselves from the bottom
up at that point.
And there was the hints of a new
governmental structure in,
in Moscow in this was this democratic
socialist alliance,
but there was still a terrible power
vacuum and the central authorities in
Moscow never really seem to get control
of the country and it was into that
mass,
that Lennon step.
And so,
you know,
sometimes when there's an
extraordinarily chaotic situation,
it just takes one seat of orders,
so to speak,
to spread itself out everywhere.
It's like the Yin and Yang symbol and
that's what happened.
But so the Marxist idea was that the
thing that made people's lives
intolerable was basically differences in
distribution that had been stabilized
into class differences.
And so the classes were basically that
proletariat and the bourgeoisie and the
virtual Z,
we're the owners.
And so if you owned anything,
the theory was that since everything of
value was created by workers,
the only way you could have any excess
value was essentially if you stole it,
if you took it.
So you were by definition an oppressor
by definition.
And that part of the move towards the
socialist utopia was that the Burj waze
would dissolve as a class.
Well that the communists were a little
impatient for the spontaneous
dissolution of the bourgeoisie.
So what they decided to do was just
proactively dissolved it.
And so what the Nazis did to the Jews
and the other people that they
persecuted for the manner in which they
were born,
roughly speaking,
the Communists did to people who to
people by class.
And so essentially if you were educated
and you own any property or if someone
just didn't like you and you were a
little richer than anywhere,
anyone else,
you were going to be dead.
And so they sent wave after wave of
radical brutalized,
resentful mobs into the Russian
countryside and raped and pillaged and
killed everyone who was competent.
And so part of that was direct so that
you know a mob would storm your house.
Now you have to understand that often
wouldn't,
these outside agitators came into the
village.
There was enough outside agitator so
that they could do the storming by
themselves,
but they would pick up adherence in the
village and those would be the adherence
who wanted to go out to someone's house
and you know,
strip it of all its valuables and have
their way with the people inside.
And so you can imagine what sort of
people that attracted the obviously the
highest quality of person.
And so they'd go out to a Kulak house
and surrounded.
Now often the peasants would fight them
off with pitchforks trying to defend the
people inside the house.
And you know,
that works sometime.
But most of the time it didn't work.
And then they'd go in and they take
everything absolutely everything out of
the house and leave it with nothing and
then leave the people with nothing.
And then eventually those people,
the ones that survived,
which weren't that many,
the government offered them the
opportunity to be taken out to Siberia
to start a new life.
They could bring two months worth of
food in their families and go out there.
But of course they didn't have two
months worth of food because everything
had been stolen from them.
And then when they go out to Siberia,
there was nothing left,
nothing there except crowded camps that
immediately produced typhus and killed
all the children.
So that was,
that was the beginning of the Russian
revolution.
And it was lennon who did that.
So if you,
if you read communist revisionists,
they'll basically say,
well,
things were going all hunky dory under
Lennon because he had everyone's best
interest in mind.
And then that monster,
Stalin,
God,
control of the party.
And that's when it became a cult of
personality that had nothing to do with
true communism.
You know,
that's the rationale.
But Lennon was just as good a monster.
Astella he just didn't live very long.
He died in about 1920 to 1923 something
around that.
And He'd already produced style and as
his followup monster at that point,
you know,
and that was just,
things just barely got going at that
point.
You know,
the next thing was after they got rid of
all the Kulaks,
they collectivize the farms,
which meant if you had a farm,
you're some damn peasant.
You just got some
land,
you know,
because your,
your parents were basically,
they weren't,
they were basically slaves.
For all intents and purposes,
they were attached to the land.
And so you just got some land and some
of you were smart enough so that you
made something out of it.
You were growing food at the same time
to feed everyone.
So,
and you know,
in any,
in any creative enterprise,
any creative enterprise whatsoever,
it's a minority of the people who do all
the productive work.
So,
you know,
if you have a hundred farmers,
10 of them grow half the food.
If you have a thousand farmers,
30 of them grow half the food.
So you go out there and you wipe out
your most productive people.
It's like,
well guess what happens next?
Well you,
you wipe them out and then you forcibly
collectivize and so everyone who had
nothing and who is completely useless,
it's thrilled about that.
But the next thing that happens as well,
hey,
you don't grow any crops.
And so that's what happened.
Food production plummeted.
And then
yeah,
for a variety of reasons,
the central Soviets weren't very happy
with the Ukrainians.
And so what they decided was that they
were going to take all the food that the
Ukrainian collected,
this farmers managed to grow anyways,
which wasn't very much and ship it to
the cities.
And so they did that and then they
pursue prosecuted women who would go out
into the fields with their children to
pick up individual grains of wheat that
the gleaners that the threshers had
missed.
And the punishment for that was that you
were incarcerated in a death camp and so
6 million Ukrainian starved and
cannibalism was so rife in the Ukraine
in the 1930s that the Soviet government
printed posters saying it is barbaric to
eat your children.
So you might say,
well that's a little too little,
a little too late.
So that was the first 6 million deaths,
not counting all the Russian civil war
and all the desks that went along there.
And that just basically got the ball
rolling,
you know?
Well,
that was happening that the Gulag camps,
that style or that Solzhenitsyn wrote
about were well onto being established.
And that's where it was in slave labor
camps,
roughly speaking that the Soviets
produced enough of their economic goods
to keep lumbering along with these
forest five year plan projects that made
everyone into a liar.
And so that's the next part of the
story.
So
Solzhenitsyn probably has done a better
job of documenting this than anyone else
I ever read,
but it's,
uh,
it's also something that orwell talked a
lot about.
You know,
I think that the best introduction to
this idea is probably 1984,
because it's a short book,
you know,
and basically what happens in 1984 is
it's a,
it's a satire of communist
totalitarianism,
clearly.
And I mean expressly,
that's exactly what it is.
And basically the rule was in the
society of 1984 that you are not allowed
to think or say anything that wasn't
part of the prevailing dogma.
The Times.
And one of the things that happens,
1984 is that there's three big blocks,
power blocks,
and they're always at war with one
another except who they're at war with
shift.
So at one point it's,
I think one of them is called Oceana,
I don't remember exactly,
but these two power blocks are at war.
And then all of a sudden that switches,
these two power blocks are at war.
And so then all the history textbooks or
revised and all the news stories or
revised.
So it's as if we were always at war with
that particular block.
And you know,
that can change on a whim.
And so everyone is required to pair it,
the beliefs of the state and to praise
it continually.
No criticism whatsoever.
And everyone in the entire state is an
informer or at least enough people so
that the probability that you're going
to get nailed,
if you ever say anything that you
actually think it's near 100% and the
informers are continually rewarded,
which is exactly what happened in the
Soviet Union.
So if you were some nasty bit of work
with your three families in your 150
square foot apartment,
which would have been about what you
could expect and you were hoping that
maybe your son and daughter could have
their own place and you saw someone down
the hallway that you didn't like or had
an animus against her or whatever,
couple of words to the proper
authorities.
And they come charging in at two in the
morning with their Jack boots and you
know,
take everyone out,
bring them to the central prison,
shave them balled,
strip them of their clothes,
put them in ill fitting uniform,
and they were gone.
And then you've got their apartment.
So that was the basis of the Soviet
state.
So,
you know,
you should just imagine for a while what
that would be like.
And so one of soldiering instance
points,
and this was something that was echoed
by Viktor Frankl,
but soldier knits and does the best job
of documenting this,
was that,
first of all,
he takes the Marxists presuppositions as
a set of axioms.
And he says,
well,
one possibility is that these axioms
were never put into practice property.
So let's look at that idea.
And then he says,
well,
you know,
there's a couple of problems with that
because here's how the axioms were put
into practice in the Soviet Union
directly as a consequence of the
accident themselves,
which is like private property is theft.
You know,
the Burj waze is a,
is a parasitical class that um,
you know,
that,
that everything should be collectivized
in equal among everyone.
Those are the basic presuppositions.
And that was exactly what was put into
practice and used as justification for
everything they did.
So that's a non starter.
And then he also points out,
well,
we don't just have the Soviet Union as
an example.
We have the Soviet Union,
we have China,
which was even worse.
We have Vietnam,
we have Cambodia where Pol Pot,
who was trained in France at the
Sorbonne by French left wing
intellectuals,
went back through everyone out of the
city and killed one in four people in
Cambodia in the space of about 10 years.
And then of course we still have North
Korea.
And we also have the fact that the only
countries in Africa that suffered like
deadly famines in the 20th century were
those that were running by communist
dictators.
So how much he evidence do you need?
You know,
and so people say,
and I've had people say this to me,
is that,
you know,
that wasn't true communism.
And I think what that means is that
person has the following delusion.
If they were the leader of the Communist
Party at that time,
things would have turned out better.
And the probability of that is,
first of all,
if you were the sort of person who was
good,
the chance that you would live through
the massacres and get to the top was
zero.
There wasn't a chance of that,
you know?
So the system basically produced its own
breed of horrible monster to lead it.
And there is no standing in its way.
You know,
if you had an iota of compassion and
dared to express that,
I mean,
think about what you're doing.
If you stand up in a system like that
and act compassionately,
you're an immediate judge of every
single person around you who doesn't
want to do that.
Well,
you're not going to live through that,
that's for sure.
You know,
they'll kick call you an enemy of the
state or whatever the hell it is.
You're going to be gone in no time flat.
So what soldier Nixon,
so,
okay,
so orwell made the proposition that
states like that could only exist if
everyone in them was trained to lie.
And the training was the idea of
training isn't exactly orwell's notion
willing to and punish if they did both
of those at the same time.
And so that's where the idea of
Orwellian doublespeak comes from.
You know,
and that's when you say one thing but
mean another.
You say something that is in accordance
with the,
you know,
the tenants of the time,
but it's a euphemism to cover up
something terrible that's going on.
And so 1984 with the story of a person
who basically gets tangled up in that
and they find his worst fear,
he's afraid of rats and they punish him
with his worst fear.
And the way they punish him is by
putting a,
uh,
like a muscle,
like a goalie mask or like an umpire's
mask on his face,
except it's this long.
And they put a starving rack inside that
and tie it to his head.
And so that's 1984.
But that's exactly the sort of thing
that happened in the ghoulag prisons.
No,
I mean perhaps not the rap thing
precisely,
but it doesn't really matter.
And the other thing the Soviets did was
that if they throw you in one of their
prison camps,
you had to sign a confession admitting
that you were wrong,
which was its own particular kind of
evil.
You know,
the Nazis,
if they gathered you up and
the lines were clear cut,
it was irrelevant.
Your innocence or guilt as a person was
irrelevant.
You know,
you were the member of a racial group
deemed unacceptable and so you were
dead.
But the Soviets,
they actually managed to figure out how
to make that even worse.
So that not only were you destroyed as a
consequence of your birth but class,
not race,
but you had to also that you
are an enemy of the state and sign that
before they would kill you.
And so most people did,
and I'm surprising,
you know,
there were people who didn't,
but,
but they were few and far between.
And you know,
of course that's not surprising.
I mean,
how much punishment do you think someone
can take and soldier Nixon's book,
there are stories of people who didn't
give in,
you know,
and those people are so damn tough,
you just can't even,
he said that was actually what transform
social and it's an an accounts cause he
was,
you know,
a moderately committed,
although somewhat cynical communist on
entry into the counts.
But then he saw people in there who were
absolutely unwilling to falsify any of
their experience and lie no matter what
happened to them under any conditions
whatsoever.
And he was so amazed by that,
that it actually produced a
transformation in this character.
And part of what the Gulag archipelago
is about is exactly that transformation
and his discovery of the,
what you might describe as the
individual responsibility to truth in
the face of state tyranny,
you know,
and soldier Knutson's basic conclusion
was,
and this is a conclusion by the way the
Dostoyevsky had drawn 70 years
previously,
was that an individual who stops lying
could bring down a totalitarian state.
And so it's a very interesting claim.
No Cause Solzhenitsyn's inclusion from
his detailed analysis and all his
personal experience inside the camps was
that no matter how powerful the
totalitarian state was,
that in the final analysis,
he couldn't stand up to actual truth.
Now it's a very radical plane,
but it's born out in part by his
experience.
Because of course Solzhenitsyn did tell
the truth and his book,
the Gulag Archipelago was one of the
things that,
well it was the book,
but demolished the credibility of
communism as a political structure.
So he managed it.
No.
The first book that he wrote called the
a day in the life of Viabahn,
Denisovich was published in 1962 so what
happened was Stalin died or was killed
in the late 1950s I think it was in 1957
but it was somewhere between 1957 in
1959 and cruise chef took over.
Now there's some evidence that
Khrushchev and two other people killed
stolen because they thought it was going
to invade Europe,
which is hydrogen bombs.
And started,
it already demonstrated quite clearly
that if he had to,
you know,
drop a hydrogen bomb on Paris in London
to make sure that the Europeans got the
hell out of the way,
that that wasn't something that was
certainly,
that he was certainly willing to do.
So Khrushchev was one of the people who
was involved at Stalin's death and he
took over,
but cruise ship was also one of the main
architects of the Ukrainian famine,
but Khrushchev had actually developed a
bit of a conscience about all that and
he loosened things up substantially for
a period of time,
for about five years.
And during that time social and released
a book called one day in the life of
Ivan Denisovich,
which is a story about himself and it's
just one day in a gulag archipelago cap.
And so it's a very dreary and,
and wretched and horrifying book.
But it was the first of anything like
that that was seen in the Soviet Union.
And add another bit of evidence that was
disseminated out into the West in 1962
which the bloody French intellectuals
could have picked up right there.
And then and said,
oh look,
you know,
our,
our glorious leader has a lot more
problems than we think.
But of course that never happened.
But then,
and Khrushchev was actually loosening up
the strictures in the,
in the USSR,
but he got wiped out of power in a coup
and taken out of power.
And the clamps came back down and
Khrushchev was sent off to live in,
is in exile in this Dasha.
I don't remember which one says his
vacation home until he died in about
1980 so,
but you know,
there were a few cracks that appeared it
exactly,
not time.
And of course that was also at the
height of the Cold War because it was
1962 when Kennedy and Khrushchev faced
off over Cuba.
And you know,
that was one of the places where we got
this far away from,
you know,
total annihilation.
Okay.
How soldier Nixon's proposition was that
had people refused to lie,
the Soviet government could have never
taken hold or maintained itself.
So he believed that,
you know,
cause there's a lot of theories about
how a society becomes corrupt,
right?
So like let's say you take the example
of Nazi Germany,
you might say it's the following orders
idea,
right?
The power structure is taken over by
thugs and then what you're doing when
you carry out the orders of the thugs is
merely responding out of fear.
You're a good person,
but you know,
you'd be put in a terrible situation and
there's terrible pressure being brought
to bear on you.
And that's why you go do the things that
you do.
And so that theory is predicated on the
idea that there's no real relationship
between the populous and the government
and that the government is basically
taken over by [inaudible] and the people
who organize the coo are well
distributed enough and aggressive enough
to maintain authority by punishment
under all circumstances whatsoever.
The problem with that theory is that it
doesn't seem to be true.
So the first issue is did Hitler create
the Germans or did the Germans create
Hitler?
Or could you say that they were involved
in a dance?
Well,
you must take on that because you can
spend a lot of times stuff what the hell
was going on in Germany and by his own
admission got caught up in it for a
short period of time.
But he said when he was there that the,
um,
the illness so to speak,
was so overwhelming.
That was virtually impossible not to get
caught up there.
And I,
you know,
I think people underestimate the degree
to which what they think is true and
false is a consequence of the mill
you,
that they'd be placed here.
But I think,
and this is partly from reading young
Hitler and the Germans cocreated each
other and the young Ian explanation for
that with something like,
I'm going to update it a bit,
modernize it in a crowd.
You have dispersal of responsibility.
Everyone knows about that.
And that means you can do whatever you
want in a crowd.
You can say whatever you want,
you can act however you want because
you're not going to be held individually
responsible for it.
So young would say the crowd has the
capacity of allowing the shadow to
emerge.
And then he believed that what happened
was the crowd shadow had a dialogue,
often nonverbal with Hitler,
with Hitler's imagination.
And so Hitler who was a great retro
Titian,
I don't know if that's a word,
um,
what talk and his emotional oratory to
the crowd and the crowd would respond in
one way or another.
And so Hitler would be guided by their
response and being an imaginative
person,
cobbling together what the crowd is
encouraging and him to speak.
That produces a kind of a theory.
And you know,
Hitler is able to flesh out that theory.
Populous leaders do that.
You know,
it's,
so I talked to Preston manning at one
point,
Preston manning started the reform party
in Alberta.
Um,
anyway,
it eventually merged with the
conservative.
So it was kind of an offshoot of the
Conservative Party.
There's always been left and right wing
off shoot parties that are generated in
Canada,
almost always sit in the west.
And I invited them to talk to a group of
people that I brought together to tell
us how he managed to create a whole
political party in like 10 years now.
He was the son of a premium who is the
right way and premium.
So we had this connections and that was
part of it,
but he said,
you know,
he'd go to,
there was a lot of
western separatist
agitation at that point.
And and people in Alberta,
yeah,
some of the political leaders thought
that that would become powerful enough
so that it would actually be a movement
to contend with.
And partly what they were doing with the
formation of the reform party was to
take some of the pressure off that side
of things.
So anyways,
they started to go around to talk to
people in arenas mostly,
and manny would give a speech,
but he said the thing that he liked best
was the question and answer at the end.
And then what the Reform Party did was
derived its policies from the question
and answer sessions.
So you could imagine that,
you know,
the crowd had concerns which were
allowed to be expressed in an
articulated fashion.
And the party built a lot of its
doctrines as a consequence of that
conversation.
And of course that was partly what
accounted for it's rapid popularity
because it was actually addressing the
desires of the crowd.
And so,
you know,
you could even say,
well,
that's how a democracy should function,
you know?
But,
but that also assumes that the
democratic systems and conventions are
in place to protect against,
you know,
let's say just a mass movement that goes
off radically to the laughter radically
to the right.
It was still all taking place within a
perfectly functional monarchical
democracy,
but by his own admission and we'll,
the policies were shaped by the crowd.
Okay.
Well,
the same thing happened with Hitler
except it happened in an underground and
pathological way.
And the people he was addressing,
we're in a hell of a lot worse shape
than Albertans in 1980.
You know,
because they just got back from the
trenches,
all,
you know,
a huge chunk of the young men were dead.
The rest that weren't,
were brutalized beyond belief.
The economy was in shambles.
The friendship imposed an incredibly
punitive,
um,
okay.
You know,
peace treaty,
Germany and lost most of its industrial,
uh,
centers as part of the redistribution of
land after World War One.
And then the whole bloody economy
collapsed because the German government
inflated the currency to wipe out their
debt to the,
to the allies and just reduced its
failure to zero.
So people were not happy,
they were seriously not happy.
And so that was the crowd that Hitler
was addressing.
So
now one of the issues might be,
well,
where does the,
this is where things get so tricky when
you're trying to figure out exactly how
these things are caused.
My sense,
I took a political science degree before
I became a psychologist because I was
interested in this sort of thing.
But I became aware quite early that
almost all the explanations that the
political scientists were offering where
economic and you know,
to me that means they were all derived
from theories on the left,
roughly speaking because it's the left
that constantly claims that the primary
motivations for people are economic.
You know,
I mean the right does this,
I won't talk about that for the moment
cause it's,
it's just not relevant in the context of
the university.
And I thought that's just not right.
There's all sorts of motivations that
people have that are economic.
It's not,
there's lots of things.
It doesn't take into account.
It doesn't take into account,
well it doesn't take into account the
fact that people will have a psyche and
that psyche is perfectly capable of
desiring good things as well as terrible
things.
It's like,
well what,
how are you going to account for that?
I mean,
economics make someone into a suicide
bomber.
I don't think so.
Like economics plays a role obviously,
but there's lots of people who are under
severe economic pressure.
Do you not become,
you know,
mass shooters in the United States are
suicide bombers.
You need a hell of a lot more
explanation than that.
And so I was very,
very interested in the uh,
in the moral questions that underlying,
especially things like what happened in
Nazi Germany in the concentration camps
because it seemed to me that the moral
question was paramount.
How could people do the sorts of things
that they did in the concentration
camps?
You know,
there's a psychological issue there.
Okay.
So that's when I started to read young
and,
and Social Netsim in particular in
Orwell.
And a lot of the people that I've been
talking to you about in this book,
I started last night,
the block book of Communism
in the introduction.
And they talked about different
approaches to history,
you know,
and
there,
there is a positivist approach to
history where there's never any moral
judgment rendered,
you know,
and that was the position putatively
taken too many people who conducted an
analysis of the 20th century.
But my sense is is that there's some
things that have happened that are so
brutal and terrible,
but to treat that from a positivist
perspective is in itself a form of
complicity.
It's like because at some point you have
to make a decision was what happened in
Auschwitz,
wrong or not?
It's a simple question.
You can say it wasn't,
it wasn't wrong because the standards of
right and wrong are generated locally
and there's no ultimate standard against
which they can be judged.
And so there,
there are constructions,
they're local constructions of
convenience.
And even if you're not happy with the
results they produce,
that doesn't mean you get to say they
were wrong.
Or you can say to hell with that.
I don't care what your rationalization
is.
If you perform this kind of action,
then what you're doing is wrong.
And then I should also say that
that was actually formerly determined
after World War II,
right?
Because after World War II,
the Nazi leaders were subjected to the
Nuremberg trials.
And that's where the idea of crimes
against humanity emerged.
War Crimes and crimes against humanity.
And the basic principle,
there's a few of them,
but the basic principle between the eye
behind the idea that there can be crimes
against humanity is that it's wrong to
kill someone for the manner in which
they were born.
Okay.
So that's the basic principle.
So that could be race obviously.
Um,
it could be language,
it could be gender,
could be class,
whatever.
It's wrong.
Well,
okay.
A cynic would say has to say,
yeah,
yeah.
Had the Germans won the war,
the laws would have been different.
So that was just the law written by the
victors and the,
and the cynic would also say,
well Dan,
I don't know exactly what you say.
I guess the next thing you say is you
cannot appeal to universal principles
that transcend culture because people
are cultural creatures only,
which is by the way,
also the claim of the radical left
because one of the things that the
radical left wanted to do in places like
the Soviet Union and China and Cambodia
and so forth was to produce the new man.
And the idea was wipe out the past,
really wipe it out in the model.
We went a long way to doing that because
part of the cultural revolution involved
the wholesale destruction of almost all
of the China's history prior to 1960 so
that's another thing that we can thank
the,
the radical communist sport is they
destroyed Chinese culture,
all that history
done.
And part of the reason for that was that
they idiot logically presumed that that
culture was transforming people into the
wrong sort of person.
And so we're going to wipe the slate
clean,
which smile was perfectly willing to do
and generate the new human being out of
the ashes.
And underneath that is the
presupposition that there's no such
thing as human nature.
It's all cultural.
And the logical conclusion from Matt or
Al logical conclusion,
he has a,
people are completely malleable.
So that's the radical social
constructionist position,
which I would say is also the position
of most academics at universities.
Now you know that things like gender are
socially constructed.
It's like,
okay,
it's fine,
right?
Take your goddamn argument to its
logical conclusion.
Oh No,
I can't do that.
Why not?
Cause you don't know anything about,
I don't know anything about history.
I'm completely ignorant of anything
outside of my little narrow domain of
specialization.
And who cares about the hundred million
dead people.
So you know,
you can't adopt a philosophical or an
ideological position without being
willing to see what it's done to think
that,
to think through the consequences.
And so you say,
well,
people are completely malleable from a
cultural perspective.
What that means is that I can decide if
I have the power to make you into
anything I want because it's just
arbitrary after all.
Or you can take a different position.
And the position is fundamentally,
I would say this is the fundamental
position of Western democracy is that
human beings have in Nalia inalienable
rights and an inalienable character.
And as far as I can tell,
that's predicated on the,
roughly speaking on the idea of horace,
it's that idea is that the person is the
center of the kind of consciousness that
creates the world as it acts.
You know,
because one of the things I was curious
about when I was working on these ideas,
I thought,
okay,
look,
the communists have one world view and
the Western democracies have another,
and you could say it's just a battle
between ideologies.
And you would also say under those
circumstances that all belief systems
are nothing but an ideology,
and that's the radical social
constructionist viewpoint,
right?
It's like a,
it's,
it's behavior isn't in some sense taken
to its extreme right?
Human beings are a blank slate.
Well,
first of all,
they're not.
We know that there's enough biology
being we've studied enough biology over
the last hundred years so that we can
just dispense with that idea.
It's raw.
But anyways,
we'll give the devil his due.
Okay.
It's an ideological conflict between
communism and and the West.
Okay.
It's arbitrary.
It doesn't matter who wins,
but the war is,
the war is between these two belief
systems.
Well,
why is that a flawed argument?
people weren't flocking into Soviet
Union as immigrants.
They were trying desperately to escape,
which is why there was a wall in Germany
and if you go went over the wall,
they shot you.
Okay,
that doesn't look so good.
Well then there's all the deaths,
35 million of them that seems to
indicate that,
you know,
there's a bit more happening on the
pathological end in one society.
Then on the other.
And then the next thing I was curious
about is,
okay,
where the hell did the idea that needle
animal rights come from?
Like is that just something arbitrary?
Is it just an invention or is it based
on something that's real and you know,
what is real meat?
And so that's when I started to trace
the emergence of the idea back as far as
I could trace it.
And so first of all,
that was political.
So maybe that manifested itself in the
most articulate it for him during the
enlightenment.
But that isn't where it started because
in the 13th century,
the English should come up with the
magnet card already.
And so there was an idea that,
you know,
the people had some sovereignty that the
monarchy was not allowed to steal.
And that was the origin of the idea of
parliamentary democracy.
But that emerged out of another idea and
that was the Judeo Christian idea that
everyone had value before God.
I thought,
okay,
well what the hell does that mean?
You know,
because you might say,
well,
if that's the case and we've dispensed
with the idea of God,
then the whole idea of natural rights
falls,
which by the way was niches prediction.
He thought as soon as we wiped out the
classical underlying structure that the
whole idea of rights would just
disintegrate.
Well,
that's exactly what happened in the
Soviet Union and China and so forth.
You know,
and we'll see.
It might not happen here,
but it wouldn't surprise me if it did.
Okay.
So then I thought,
well,
is there anything that might lead,
lend some validity in any way to that
claim?
First of all,
what is the claim mean that people have
value before God also?
So I went back to the,
to the,
you know,
the theological stories.
And the religious history and tried to
figure out exactly where this idea had
come from and what it meant.
And I found that you could just trace it
farther and farther and farther and
farther back.
So you know with disappears that
Mesopotamia,
but then it doesn't disappear.
Because if you look at wolf packs and
chimp troops and social animals in
general,
they organize their societies as if each
of the individuals in the hierarchy you
have value and the wolves for example,
like if there's a dominance dispute
between two wolves,
one wins,
one turns its neck over and says you
don't tear up my throat.
And the other wolf says,
now you're annoying,
but we'll keep you around because you're
useful.
Well,
it's this,
it's the same idea.
The idea is that the individual has
integrity worth in relationship to the
group and then that's not an ideological
idea.
That's an idea that's based as far as I
can tell,
an evolution and it's really,
really deep.
It goes back as far as you can chase it.
So that means it's not just an
ideological conflict.
Well,
okay,
maybe that's wrong,
but I can't see anywhere that it's
wrong.
Are you always using
our
missionary?
Okay,
so,
so that's a good question.
Okay,
so the question is,
you know,
I parceled off one set of beliefs as
specifically grounded in evolutionary,
in evolution.
Okay.
I'm going to make two distinctions.
First,
there's a difference between an idea
that's grounded in that evolution and an
idea that's grounded in evolutionary
theory.
Okay.
So the Marxists we're,
we're grounded and evolutionary theory.
They have psychobiological
justifications for their claims.
I know,
I know what it is.
I just want to dispense with that first.
Okay.
So then I was thinking,
well,
what exactly do ideologies do?
Because obviously they're also not
constructive just arbitrarily because
they wouldn't be attractive to people if
they work.
They have to be.
And I thought,
well,
like if you look for example at Mao or
sorry,
marks Stalin and Lenin,
so you could think of them as the
trinity of the USSR.
Well,
I think part of the reason that the
trinitarian idea worked as a,
as a,
you know,
as a means of propaganda was because
Russia was an orthodox Christian country
and it had the trinitarian idea already,
you know,
lay down and it's unconscious.
Well you remember I showed you that
diagram of chaos on the outside and then
the great mother and then the great
father and then the individual and the
valence of each of them.
I think what happens with an ideology,
and I,
I didn't point this out that out at the
time,
but it's worth revisiting is that the
ideology capitalizes on certain aspects
of that story.
It doesn't tell the whole truth.
So it stands,
for example,
the individual is all good,
the state is corrupt and mother nature
is good.
Okay.
That's Russo and that's the
environmentalist movement.
Okay.
Cause it's grounded.
We were so in thinking via thoroughal
for example,
and then you have the officer at which
is harms and Hob says the individual is,
you know,
a catastrophe of conflicts and
aggression.
The state has to be,
the state is the only thing that can
possibly keep the individual in check.
And that protects,
it protects us from the ultimate chaos
of nature.
Well,
those are both true and you can derive
ideologies from them.
But I think their weaknesses is they
don't take the other side into account.
And I don't think that you can say that
about the traditions that I've been
describing.
I think they've been around toola.
So when you look at Egypt,
for example,
the story has all the elements.
It has the adversary,
so that seth,
right,
it has the good king and not so cyrus,
and it has isis as queen of the
underworld.
She's gone to pot like she's,
she's not as well differentiated in the
story,
but the elements are still there.
And you have horace,
and it says says,
look,
life is this landscape and all these
characters are participate.
Yeah,
that's,
that's as close as we can get to a
narrative truth.
And part of the reason I wanted to teach
this course once I thought I'd figured
these things out,
was to provide people with a defense
against ideology.
It's like someone tells you it's a story
that's causal.
Here's how history laid itself out.
Okay.
It's plausible.
Like the Russo story is plausible and so
is the,
um,
hobbsy and story.
Now,
not only their plausible,
they're true,
but they're only true like this.
You know,
and the other one's true like this,
but you want to know where's the other
half of the story?
People are inherently good in society
corrupts them.
Yes.
People are inherently evil in society.
Regulates them.
Yes.
And it's,
it's hard on people because you know,
the classic idea of Western logic is
that one thing can't be itself and its
opposite at the same time.
But that only applies to unitary things.
And like a human being is not a unitary
thing and neither is a state.
So,
so well,
so that's the best answer that I have to
that question
is like,
hmm,
it's exactly what it is.
That's why it has its power because it
can extract it's motive power from the
underlying archetypes which,
which relates to them to the motivations
that you just described.
Like there is a pronounced demand for
egalitarianism in human beings.
It's agreeableness,
the trading,
agreeableness.
So the more agreeable you are,
the more egalitarian you are.
Why?
Because people should share and get
along.
It's especially true within the confines
of a family or tribal unit,
right?
Where everyone's pulling together and
cooperate.
It isn't obvious to me that it's useful
ethic.
Once you get beyond like a kin group
size,
I think you need conscientiousness then
because conscientiousness is more like a
cold virtue and it's the thing that
supports,
um,
success in bureaucracies.
If you're conscientious,
you go into a large landscape of
unrelated people.
So maybe a functional bureaucracy and
conscientiousness predicts your success.
But conscientiousness and agreeableness
are orthogonal to one another.
They do not have the same value
structure.
And the truth of the matter is,
is that they both wouldn't exist if they
weren't both necessary.
Egalitarianism is necessary because
otherwise the hierarchy skitzo damn
steep that the people at the bottom die
and the whole system collapses.
But agreeableness is as a universal
ethic is no good because it doesn't
allow for distinctions of quality and it
doesn't allow any decisions to be made
because if a hundred people have to come
to a consensus before action can take
place,
well someone with a hierarchy who's
invading you,
they're just going to wipe you out.
You're so slow.
So there's this tension and it is partly
the tension between,
it's the tension between the far left
and the right because the best marker
for the far left is agreeableness in
terms of a personality dimension that
predicts question.
You can say,
um,
if you have a license to sell as an
element of the culture that butter the
nature,
why can't you say that's also one side
other side?
Well,
I think the reason that that I don't
think that that's appropriate is
precisely the reason that I told you the
Egyptian and the Mesopotamian stories in
the first reason I told you those
stories was to show you that those
stories exist and they can't be taken
lightly because those stories are the
products of tens of thousands of years
of thought.
Like they're not just any old story.
And so,
and what the story seemed to indicate is
that there has to be a dynamic
relationship between the vision of the
individual and the integrity of the
state.
It isn't saying that one of those is
more important than the other at all.
It's saying that in order for one to
remain healthy,
in order for both to remain healthy,
there has to be a constant dialectic of
communication.
And so then you could say,
and people have said this,
how do you know this isn't just another
radiology?
Well,
I,
I tried to,
I tried to explain why that is.
It looks to me like ideologies only take
an hour.
I don't know how to define that because
I'm trying to figure it out.
Part of that was grounded in the
question,
was it just the ideology that drove the
distinction between the West and the
Soviet Union?
For me it was hopeless if it was because
if it was just in theology,
there wasn't right on either side and it
was just an endless battle.
It was an endless battle because one of
the things I realized was,
and this is was the most dismal part of
going through all this material for me
because I thought that that it was done.
Like I came to the conclusion at one
point,
I mean for whatever relevance it has,
that the problem was unsolvable.
Technically people were pathologized by
their self consciousness.
Completely understanding.
It's like when someone comes to me with
an anxiety disorder,
I never ask why.
I think no kidding.
You know?
It's the healthy,
anxious people that are the mystery.
So it is.
It's like,
why the hell aren't you freaking out all
the time?
It's a really good question.
You know,
it's like you're like the rat that's in
its burrow.
You've explored the territory and you're
calm.
That does not mean you're calm.
It also does not mean you're safe.
It just means that for some weird
reason,
you can act like you are and you can
undo that.
Like people have that undone all the
time.
They get traumatized and then they start
questioning and that whole protective
structure falls apart and they're
screwed.
They're,
they're anxious.
They're in pain,
they develop bag or a phobia,
you
know where they develop obsessive
compulsive disorder and you think,
well yeah obviously it's like someone
comes to me and says,
well when I go into a new building I
always check out the fire exits.
What are you supposed to say about that?
It's like,
well what if the building caught on
fire?
Well then your dad,
cause you don't do that.
And you might say,
well what's the chance of that?
And the person says
1% chance of an infinitely bad outcome
is an infinitely large risk.
And there's no arguing with that.
It's like how safe should you be
Ken?
You can't argue about that.
So
yeah,
I think the reason that I think this
isn't an ideology is because I think you
can make a distinction between stories
and met a stories.
And a story is generally an ideology.
It's a partial representation of the
whole.
And a Meta story is an observation about
the set of all possible stories.
And that's what I was trying to do in
this class.
And in the book it's like,
okay,
what's the,
what's the landscape of the set of all
possible stories?
And that's,
you know,
the structure that I laid out.
Now maybe that's wrong,
but it's an interesting structure
because everything has its place order
and chaos,
masculine and feminine,
but even more importantly good and evil.
And that's the landscape.
And then we can say,
well,
you can parcel out partial stories from
now and they have functional utility and
potent motivational force,
but they're dangerously one sided.
Unless you've covered the entire
territory.
We see that
they suggest by a part of this,
is this the way he's like Cyrus?
Yeah,
well that's exactly,
that's exactly how it looks to me.
It is.
It's,
it's something that's outside
rationality.
It's embedded nodding rationality but in
biology and then knows essential claim
that you'll made with regards to the
collective unconscious and part of his,
believe me,
part of what human was doing,
and this was partly in response to what
was happening mostly in Nazi Germany,
but also to some degree in the communist
countries,
is he was asking,
does do human beings have a nature?
Are we a certain way?
Because if we are,
then that should be taken into account.
You know,
when you're trying to construct our
political systems and if we do have a
nature well what is it and how does it
manifest itself and what should we,
how should we take stock of that?
Well,
here's a question for you guys.
Okay.
You can think about this for a minute
now.
There was a paper published a week ago
and it was in the International Journal
of Psychology,
which is the world's psychology journal
for whatever that means,
but it was a large scale analysis of
gender differences across culture and it
concluded the same thing that all the
large scale analysis of gender
differences across culture have
concluded in the last 15 years,
which is that the differences taking
trade by trade are rather small
quarter to a half standard deviation,
which isn't,
it's not trivial,
but it still means that along any single
trait dimension,
men and women are more the same than
they are different.
And those differences maximize as
societies become more egalitarian.
Now you have to,
that should have been front page news
when that was first discovered because
it completely,
if it's true,
it completely undermines everything that
students have been taught by radical
left wingers since the 1960s it
completely invalidates the claim that
people are constructed by society.
Because if they're constructed by
society and you make the state
egalitarian,
then the gender differences disappear.
But that isn't what happens.
Not only do they not disappeared,
which would be bad enough,
they maximize,
okay,
that's it.
Theory done.
Now you could say,
well,
the research isn't that good.
It's like,
well,
that turns out to be wrong.
Most of it's done with the big five
personality model,
which I hated until like broop necessity
made me accept because they're kept
coming.
And why wasn't an interesting theory to
me it's like it was annoying.
Bloody statistician's figure out the
structure of personality,
how boring,
you know.
But when you,
when you analyze the psychometrics
you're done,
it's like personality as encapsulated in
language has five dimensions now it's a
little rough around the edges.
Yeah,
yeah.
Whatever.
It's there.
Okay,
fine.
So how big are those differences?
Well if you add them up,
which you could,
the overlap between men and women is 10%
that's it.
So that means if you constructed a
regression equation using the big five
personality differences to predict who
was men and women,
men and woman,
just on the basis of the responses to
the personality traits,
you could identify the genders with 90%
accuracy.
And it's worse than that because the new
study showed that not only do there are
other differences that exist in
personality that are that small
individually,
but that large in combination.
But there are differences,
differences in blood pressure,
maximize in egalitarian societies,
differences in the market,
in the dark triad traits,
the Makaveli Ism and I don't remember
what the other two are.
Maximizing Egalitarian states like all
sorts of differences maximize.
And then you might ask,
well why is that?
And then there's a simple explanation
and the simple explanation.
Yes.
Differences between men and women have a
partial basis in biology.
Yeah.
If you eradicate the cultural,
you know
the environmental variability by making
the state egalitarian all you leave or
the biological differences which
maximize,
it's like
dispute that.
How can you dispute that?
It's not like something that someone
planned,
no one was aiming at that.
It just,
that's how it happened.
Okay.
So there is evidence we could say,
well there is powerful evidence that
people have a biological nature and
inbuilt nature and then we could also,
and then you can say,
okay,
let's take that set of data.
Okay.
The biggest difference between men and
women is an interest
and the interest dimension seems to be
people versus things women are more
interested in people and men are more
interested in things.
And the difference there is about a
standard deviation.
It's a big difference by by
psychological standards.
And it's a nice finding because you know
for a while one of the claims was that
there were fewer women in stem
disciplines,
science,
technology,
engineering,
mathematics was because the standard
deviation of male intelligence was
larger because the curve was flatter.
So there were more intellectually
impaired men and more sort of super
genius men.
And there's a biological rationale for
that.
And then one of the consequences of that
was that if you went five standard
deviations from the mean and you needed
that to be like an expert physicist,
that was so rare that the only people
who were out there were men.
You know what it's like the reason that
most of the people in prison are manage
because the distribution of
agreeableness is skewed and there's way
more disagreeable man at the extreme,
so they all end up in prison.
That argument has not been settled,
but I think you can just put it aside.
There's a lot of debate about it.
So Larry Summers brought it up at
Harvard and got fired as a consequence
and then a variety of female
psychologist scoured the ICU literature
and made the claim that that finding was
questionable to say the least.
And maybe it is,
maybe it isn't,
but it doesn't matter.
It's,
it's debatable.
What you do find though is that if you
look at male and female performance,
say in mathematics in junior high or
high school,
you can find a chunk of three to four
standard deviation above the mean
females and none of them go into stem
studies.
And why is that?
It seems to be because they don't want
to,
no,
I like that explanation because you
know,
if you had to have an explanation that
was palatable,
that would be a good one.
It doesn't,
it doesn't make a claim for anything
that has to do with the intrinsic
differences in ability.
So that's kind of Nice.
It wipes out a whole deep politicizes a
huge chunk of the argument.
But then you could say,
well,
maybe men and women are like different
things because of socialization.
It's like,
no,
you can't say that because that isn't
how it worked out in Scandinavia.
So that's the end of that argument.
Unless you can figure out how those
studies are wrong and like,
good luck to you.
But I've never seen a credible
explanation.
And then the next thing you could say
is,
yeah,
regardless about men and women should be
the same.
Fine.
No problem.
You could do it if you want to make,
if you want to take,
say you have two kids that are,
that are adopted out at birth and
they're twins,
and you assess their Iq and you look at
it in relationship to their
socioeconomic status.
One kids,
it ends up in a family that's poor that
95% of other families and other kid ends
up in a family that's richer than 95% of
families.
So it's a big difference.
The kid in the richer home,
we'll have a 15 point Iq advantage.
So what that basically means,
I'm,
I've got the statistics a little bit
wrong here because I can't translate it
onto the normal distribution,
but roughly speaking,
what it means is that you need a three
standard deviation move in socioeconomic
status to produce a one standard
deviation move.
In Iq,
what it implies is that you can buy
transformation of Iq,
but what it also indicates is that it's
bloody expensive.
It's extent that makes sense,
right?
You could,
you could imagine that being the case.
If you spend enough money you could
switch something.
But I would say no.
The farther you want to switch it,
the more expensive it's going to get.
And it's probably a curve like this,
a diminishing return things so that
maybe the first five points would be
pretty easy.
The next five things are getting
expensive.
The five after that,
it's really expensive and then each
additional one point is going to cost a
lot.
Alright,
fine.
So what that means is that even if the
differences are biological,
you can shift them.
The question is two questions,
how much effort are you willing to put
in?
And then the next question is how much
effort do you put in before it's a
tyranny?
And that's the real question.
So we could say,
well,
radically transformed the socialization
of boys and girls.
Now this is being called for it.
Before there was a guy psychologist and
appalling,
it was an appalling article.
I think he was a social psychologist,
which would make sense because most of
what they do is appalling.
And so he proposed that the way to
decrease the radical difference in
aggression rates between men and women
was to socialize little boys,
like little girls,
and that's been put into practice a lot
and it will not work because what will
happen is that you'll,
you might reduce the aggression of the
average guy,
but you're going to pop up the
aggression of the pathological guide by
such a degree that it will completely
overwhelm whatever minor gains you make
for the typical.
So you're just going to produce more
guys that are so bad that they're like
hell band for for revenge fundamentally.
So,
okay.
But you could make that case,
you know,
like from a,
from a scientific or political
perspective,
you could say,
look,
it's worth investing in the
transformation of the socialization
process.
So we get rid of those differences.
Okay.
The next thing you got to ask yourself,
yes,
yes.
Why?
What's the end game?
Now here's the end
game.
Men and women will be represented 50% in
absolutely every occupation and there
will be zero differences in economic and
political power.
Okay?
That end game presumes that that outcome
has a value.
We know,
I don't know what the value is,
but some valid and then the more
resources you're willing to dump into
attain that end,
the more valuable your acting as if it
is.
So you could think about it as a utopian
or Utopian in state.
And I'm not complaining about the formal
proposition that that would be a utopian
end state.
What I'm complaining about is,
or what I'm commenting on is who says
that's the desire blow come and how much
are you willing to risk to test it out?
So because what you'll have to do,
especially for things like interest,
is you'll have to punish boys for being
interested in boy things and reward them
for being interested in girl things and
punish girls for being interested in
girl things and reward them for being
interested in boy things.
Now I think you could do that,
but,
but
what if they're,
you know,
they're,
the differences exist.
Why eradicate them?
Do you want them eradicated?
Do you really want them eradicated?
And you know the word eradicated?
That's a rough word because you just
never know how far you're going to have
to go to eradicate.
Thanks.
So,
all right,
let's see,
what time is it with their habit break?
Yes.
Oh,
it's three 30.
Well,
there's no more,
not much point in a break.
Okay.
So let me,
Yup.
Neurobiology.
So they started doing experiments very,
they basically tried growing neurons,
different hormones,
and I found that neurons growing
estrogen,
they're like,
they grow completely differently than
other things,
which makes sense,
right.
If gender differences of biological,
uh,
but the upshot to that is,
it works with sort of that theory,
but you have to add on is that,
you know,
there are men and women with different
levels of hormone.
It's not uniform across sex.
So when you look at how you're going to
raise a child,
you can't just say,
you know,
it's a girl.
You raised him like a girl.
You have to look at either a hormone
levels,
but because you can't access those,
you'd have to look at their,
their,
their gender identity.
Yes.
While they're there,
but to see that,
but that's an individual relationship
issue.
Okay.
So,
um,
I've had children and
they seem to have turned out reasonably
well and you know,
there was a variety of differences
between them temperamentally that I
observed as they were growing up.
Um,
it turns out my daughter is quite tilted
towards a feminine temperament.
I tested her personality multiple times.
She tests all the personalities,
she tests the personalities of all her
potential dates,
which I think is really funny.
Yeah.
And my son has a very masculine
temperament so he's very low in
agreeableness and very high emotional
stability.
Again,
so I can see that manifesting itself and
what you do if you have a relationship
with your kids as you adjust your
interactions with them according to who
they are.
Because in principle you want,
maybe it seems to me then in principle
maybe you want who they are to be
allowed to emerge.
Now I think there's some evidence that
that's what good parents do.
And the reason I think that is because
when you're looking at influences on
children,
you can look out genetic influences,
non shared environmental,
various and shared environmental
therapy.
So shared environment.
Well variants would be if you and I were
brother and sister in the same family
shared environmental,
various would be what was common across
our upbringings.
Unshared environmental variance would be
what was specific to you in our family
and what was specific to me.
And then the biological stuff is
biological.
What you almost always find in the
studies is that non shared environmental
variance is the most powerful after
biological predisposition depends on the
trade.
And so what that seems to indicate is
that the general mill you in which
children is raised has hardly any effect
whatsoever on their,
on their treat outcomes.
Now you can be pessimistic or optimistic
about that.
If you're pessimistic,
you say parenting doesn't matter and
people have drawn that conclusion.
There was a famous book written about
that a while back.
Um,
but if you're optimistic,
what you say is,
no,
you don't get it.
If you were a good parent,
you were radicchio the shared variance
because what you do is have an
individual relationship with each child
that takes into account their
temperamental,
you know,
idiosyncrasies and you tailor the
environment to them.
And so the shared the shared
environmental various disappears because
there is no shared environment.
You know,
it's like go on 10 dates and treat each
man you meet or each woman you meet as
if they were exactly the same and see
how far you get,
right?
You're going to be one annoying person
and you know probability you're going to
get brushed off.
So what you want to do is,
you know,
take the gender into account as a broad
template.
You know,
cause you need to set up your
expectations and then rapidly Taylor the
hell out of that as fast as you can to
indicate that you've got some social
sophistication.
Right?
While you do the same thing with
children.
Okay.
So then,
but that still begs the question and
this is something that you guys can
think about.
It's like
what do you do about the differences?
Do you leave them?
Do you encourage them?
That's another thing you could see.
You could say,
see the thing that I,
one of the things I really dislike about
the social constructionists
stances,
that there was an implication that comes
with it.
Here's the implication.
Men and women are the same.
Okay,
well why is that necessary?
Well,
because that similarity is valuable
because otherwise white pursue it,
right?
Because it's valuable.
So people are better off with near the
same fine.
People are worse off when they're
different.
Ah,
why are they worse off when they're
different?
How about because differences are not
acceptable.
Okay,
well play out if you want.
Differences are not acceptable.
Well,
you could see where that would leave in
no time flat.
You know?
So the mere proposition that men and
women are the same in a world where
there are differences,
has the implication that the differences
are substandard and maybe even
pathological.
And you might say,
are they really,
is that right?
Is it the case that to the degree we
defer,
we're not mutually complimentary and not
acceptable?
I mean as individuals and gender.
It is true that I feel like
they want to pretend that we don't have
to force it,
but at the same time,
and I feel like they're are also very
um,
like encouraging like other people,
especially their culture,
they're also be about the same time of
like say well what?
All the same,
there are no differences there.
Also like,
oh,
we should multicultural.
We,
we have a theory about that now.
So we just did a study of political
correctness because we wanted to find
out,
oh,
I'll get to write with,
we wanted to find out if political
correctness existed,
right?
Is it a margin,
a set of values because it might not be
the left planes that the idea that
political correctness exists as a
homogenous set of constructs is a right
wing idea and that it's just wrong that
this the belief side,
it's so diverse.
You can't characterize it under a single
label.
It's easy to test.
What you do is you get a bunch of
statements that appear to be on the
politically correct side and you can do
that relatively objectively.
We had a bunch of people generate them
and we took clips from news items and
all of that.
So over generated to set,
asked a thousand people factor,
analyze the results.
And we've got two factors.
One was sort of radical egalitarianism
and the other was language control.
Okay.
And we've already done this for liberals
and conservatives.
Okay.
So the liberals are high in openness and
low in conscientiousness,
particularly orderliness.
The conservatives are low in openness
and high in conscientiousness,
particularly orderliness.
So they're actually mirror images of one
another.
The politically correct people.
The first dimension,
which is radical egalitarianism,
they're primarily agreeable and low in
conscientiousness.
Okay.
So that's different.
They're not hyper liberals.
They're off on a different axis.
Okay.
The second dimension was high
agreeableness.
Okay.
Low conscientiousness.
Is that right?
Well conscientiousness,
I hope that's right.
It doesn't exactly matter.
And low verbal Iq.
Okay.
So
there was a reason I was telling you
that
can ask me your question again.
Oh,
the fact that a lot of left wing people,
they're all one had they tried to claim
that every day.
Oh Great.
Good,
good,
good.
Okay.
So the commonality.
So we've always,
we felt that and people make this claim
that there's something about the pc
stands that leads itself to a kind of
authoritarianism.
But it's weird because a lot of the
research on authoritarianism and there's
historical reasons for that was
predicated on the claim that
authoritarianism was necessarily a right
lane phenomenon.
Yeah.
Okay.
So the authoritarian scale,
for example,
which was derived by Theodore Adorno,
who was part of a left wing think tank,
um,
what were they called?
They were in Germany,
I'll remember their name.
It was after World War Two.
And they had every reason for assuming
that authoritarianism was the right way
phenomena,
except for all the things the communists
were doing.
But you know,
forget about that for a moment.
And then there was a huge debate in the
psychological literature,
really tilt,
still going on about whether only the
right can be authoritarian or whether
the left and the right can be
authoritarian has never been sorted out.
Okay.
But what we found,
so the conservatives were high in
orderliness and low and opens.
Okay.
So orderliness seems to be the
authoritarian aspect because
conscientious people like structure and
they'd like to compete with instructors
and conscientiousness predicts,
right wing beliefs.
Okay,
but it isn't industriousness,
which is another part of the
conscientiousness.
Its orderliness.
Okay.
The second dimension of the politically
correct people.
The language control was agreeable and
orderly.
And then then the Iq.
Okay,
so this is what we think.
Now this is Beckman but,
but it's a good study and we'd been
trying hard to pin this down and this
isn't my idea by the way.
This is my graduate student's idea was
not very smart idea.
She thought authoritarianism is driven
by orderliness.
Okay fine.
If you are agreeable,
you are authoritarian by inclusion.
And if you're disagreeable and you're
authoritarian by exclusion.
So the,
the,
the goal is homogeneity,
but the right way you say all you
different people screw off and the left
wing says all you different people come
in here and be the same.
Okay?
So now I think the way that that
pertains to your question is that I
think the left wing manages that weirdly
paradoxical viewpoint by assuming that
whatever differences exist,
our cultural and so they can just be in
time,
they can just be ameliorated.
That's what it looks like to me.
I mean,
it really does seem
paradoxical,
right?
That you can,
you can be for an egalitarianism and
celebrate differences.
And you see this turns out very weirdly.
So let so many people,
well let,
let me you an example of what happened.
So do you guys know who I Ayaan Hirsi
Ali is?
Yes.
Do.
And how many of you know,
okay,
now if you could keep it.
Good.
Look,
she's quite the day I'm character.
You know,
I hadn't heard the elite.
I would look her up.
I think she's a real hero.
That woman,
she is tough as a bloody boot.
She came from Ethiopia,
she escaped from an arranged marriage
and she was in a very hierarchical,
you know,
authoritarian Muslim family.
So she had to run and she did.
And so that was tough man.
To get away from that.
You know,
she had to forfeit or familial ties and
all of that.
And then she went to the Netherlands to
study and the Netherlands shocked her
and she said a couple of things that
shocked her that I thought were so cool.
The first thing that shocked her was
that she was at a bus stop and there was
a little digital sign there that said
when the bus was coming and then the bus
came like right at the time it was
supposed to,
she couldn't believe that that could
actually happen.
And if you think about how many things
have to be going right for that to
happen,
you know that her detection of that
miracle was accurate.
And the fact that we just assume that
that's just shows you how well things
work.
And the second thing she was amazed
about was that if you ask the policeman,
they would help you.
Because in most countries policemen are
like,
they're just an extension of thug,
right?
They don't get paid anything.
So all the money they make,
it's from you.
And they're not there to maintain order
or to help you.
They're there as a control arm of the
state.
Anyway,
she went and go to liberal arts
education and she was very taken by the
idea of individual sovereignty,
roughly speaking and the enlightenment.
So she turned into a really pro
enlightenment person and then she got
into the Dutch parliament and she also
had,
there was a bit of a scandal about that,
which I won't go into.
She also had a relationship,
I think it was just a friendship with
this guy named Van Gogh,
who was actually a descendant of found
gold.
And he made this video that have naked
women in it with verses of the Quran
written on them.
And it was very,
very,
very controversial because these were
anti female versus at least that's what
he thought.
And so he got stabbed and what happened
was the guy that stabbed him,
it was a Muslim extremists took the
note,
it explained why he was being killed and
stabbed it into him.
Okay.
So that was nasty.
So I ended Hirsi Ali.
Eventually she,
her life was in danger.
[inaudible] to such a degree and a
variety of things happen at home that
she had to move to the United States
with bodyguards.
And so she lives there now and she's an
outspoken critic of patriarchal
oppressor in the best sense.
Like she experienced it.
It was terrible.
Like she got away from it and you know,
and in a really remarkable and honorable
and admirable way,
and I read,
I in Herzliya lead before she was
politically controversial except in
Holland.
Well,
last year Brandeis University offered
her a honorary phd and the students set
up a petition saying that she couldn't
be granted that phd because of her
objection to two Muslim too radical
Muslim faith and they disinvited her.
So that's a good example of this weird
paradox.
It's like I read,
I Ayaan Hirsi Ali and I thought,
Jesus,
if anybody ever had a case to make about
the oppressive nature of the patriarchy,
like as someone who had personally
experienced it,
it's like you read her story and you
think,
Oh yeah,
there's no doubt about that.
And so then she makes this immensely
complex and sophisticated case for the
individual rights of women.
And Brandeis invites her to give her an
honorary degree and then they resend it
because the students complain about her.
And that was the radical left students
who were complaining.
I just thought,
well I thought first of all,
that's amazing.
It's,
I just can't believe that happened.
It's second.
I couldn't believe that that pathetic
university cave and withdrew their,
their invitation to her.
She's a tough cookie man.
And I think she's a real hero and that
was irrelevant.
It's like some students were upset,
they made a petition.
So like who cares about Ayaan Hirsi Ali
and her,
you know,
amazing journey.
I've noticed that like if I,
if I bring up friendship infringements
on women's rights that contradicts like
the liberal narrative of like a straight
white
person maybe like,
it's like some poor people,
you know,
in a very like,
a Muslim majority country oppressing
women,
if I bring that up is I feel like a lot
of times like the gifts cause like it
contradicts that,
the main narrative,
which is impressive.
Well,
the prog,
you know,
generally the problem,
the problem with a set of axiomatic
presuppositions is that you'll find
situations where they conflict.
I can give you another example.
So,
um,
that's definitely one,
you know,
so you say,
well,
diverse ethnicity and diverse cultural
background is a plus,
but then you think,
oh,
well some of these practices look like
they're not exactly commensurate with
what we would regard as appropriate.
Okay.
So we have a problem there.
Here's another problem.
So as a of the same sort,
and I'm using this as an example just to
show you how axiomatic systems produce
internal conflicts.
So,
um,
the access to abortion has become
increasingly universal in western
countries,
although it's backtracked a lot in the
US over the last 10 years for a variety
of reasons.
But there's a,
there's a weird consequence of that.
And one of the consequences is that
female fetus get aborted at a much
higher rate than male fetuses worldwide.
Okay.
So what do you do about that?
Like is that acceptable or not?
Because if it's not well then,
then there's a problem because you know,
you have to face,
you have to face what do you have to
face?
Exactly that there is an ethical
question that when it comes to abortion,
because I,
how if abortion is not wrong,
how could selective abortion pro
possibly be not wrong.
Like maybe you could come up with an
explanation for that,
but I've never seen a credible one.
But that's just a good example of how if
you use an axiomatic system,
there's inevitably the case where the
axioms collide and it's sort of like,
am I free to offend you with my speech?
Two axioms,
freedom of speech and,
and you know,
integrity of person.
At what point am I,
am I in citing aggression?
So,
oh,
and it's also the case,
I think,
where the,
why the horace.
So Cyrus thing is absolutely necessary.
So you can take a vote,
cyrus as a set of axiomatic moral
presuppositions,
like a list of rules like the 10
Commandments.
The problem is,
is that not only do the rules get out of
date over time,
you know,
um,
we don't worry very much about coveting
our neighbor's goat for example.
You know,
so,
so they become obsolete across time.
But worse than that,
there are situations where if you apply
both,
they conflict.
So then what do you do?
Well,
the answer is you pay attention.
You know,
you pay attention because you have to
mediate between the conflict.
Well,
horace is also the thing that mediates
between the conflicts.
And that's partly why in the
Mesopotamian story you have Marduk.
And one of the things that Martech
demands when he's elevated to the
highest position,
which is,
you know,
so that makes him ruler of all the gods.
And you can think about those as,
you know,
integro motivational forces are
principles.
He gets the tablet of destinies,
which means that what he represents is
the thing that makes the decisions.
And that's often the decision between
two rigid approaches to right and wrong.
And so you say a chaotic approach to
right and wrong,
that's a catastrophe.
And then you say,
well you replaced that with a system of
rules,
which is better,
but the system of rules has two
potential problems.
One is it will age and the other is that
it produces internal conflicts.
So then you need a third principle.
And the third principle to me seems to
be what the Egyptians represented with
horace.
And then you get into a car,
you get into a communicative dialogue
between the horace factor,
which is attention and the culture like
this.
They mutually inform one another and
that keeps things structured but also
flexible enough to adapt across time.
And then the system has to build in
recognition for that.
And that's where I think the idea of
individual rights comes from.
It's like you have an individual,
right?
Because you are a necessary player in
the process that keeps the forces of
order and chaos balanced across time.
And if you're shutdown or oppressed or
not allowed to speak,
then the society denies itself,
that corrected action and the correct of
micro corrections say,
and then what happens is it gets more
and more and more rigid and more
tyrannical because people have to
falsify their experience to adhere to
it.
And then the bloody thing collapses
precipitously.
And that's what happened with the Soviet
Union.
So you either make micro corrections or
you accumulate error
and collapsed.
And I think that,
so when I looked at that
psychologically,
and I think,
I think the way that people do that in
their own life is that they adjust their
own psyches with micro corrections and
then they communicate about freely.
And then that's enough to keep the
society dynamic.
But you have to let people speak.
So that's why the,
you know,
freedom of speech is a critical
characteristic of modern democratic
states.
It's like it doesn't matter what the
person says,
it's irrelevant whether they're right or
wrong.
It doesn't matter if they're offensive,
it's not the point.
The point is,
is that you have to let the chatter
emerge so that you can sort the wheat
from the chaff.
And if you suppress it,
then the error correction mechanism goes
away.
Let's take the lid off political
correctness.
There's absolutely no doubt about that.
I was looking today,
they just fired a professor at Marquette
University.
Yeah.
Okay.
So what
was it,
mark hat?
It was a marquette.
Okay.
So what this guy did,
he's,
he's a self proclaimed conservative.
He has a blog and he,
he,
uh,
ta was teaching a course where the idea
of gay marriage came up and a student
approached her afterwards and said that
he had opposed gay marriage and she said
there wasn't something like there wasn't
going to be any discussion of that in
her class.
And,
and he recorded that and then that was
released.
And then this character,
um,
wrote a blog and criticized the graduate
student for,
for not letting this guy speak.
Okay.
So far.
So you can read the blog.
That caused quite a lot of trouble and
eventually he got fired.
Okay.
So fine.
Whatever.
I read opinions on both sides.
You know that the conservative critic
said,
uh,
this is just another case of someone
being hounded out of his job.
And the people on the left said he
misused his position of authority to go
after this graduate student in public.
And that wasn't due process.
And so it wasn't his opinions that got
him fired.
It was his failure to observe university
regulations.
So fine,
whatever,
something can be said on both sides of
the argument.
But then I looked at the comments,
well,
20 to one they were,
this is why we're voting for trump.
Yeah.
And I do believe that because trump has
disagreeable,
and that means he'll say anything.
He'll shoot off his mouth,
he'll say anything.
And the thing is,
people don't care what he says.
What they care about is that he'll say
anything.
That's what they're going after.
And they definitely see that as a,
uh,
a gesture of hostility towards the PC
left.
They say that.
So the problem is,
is,
you know,
when you,
extremism always calls the devils out of
the closet.
So if you move too far to the left in
any way,
you Carl,
the demons of the right out and vice
versa.
It's a psychological principle.
It happens within people's character.
So
you know,
I,
I was privy to a,
a line of communication between a bunch
of people who,
who weren't poor,
white trash,
so to speak.
You know,
the stereotypical trump's supporter.
These people were well ensconced in the
middle and upper middle class and
virtually,
and they were almost all men virtually
to a man.
They said something like,
the system is so raw and we're going to
bring it down.
And I thought,
really that's what you guys are
thinking.
You're that reactively angry.
And
you know,
if you're in a marriage shape and then
you refuse to let your partner speak for
decades,
you body bit well better be careful with
make decided to speak because you're
going to come home one day.
I used to tell this children's story in
this class about a guy who there's a
little dragon in the house and it's
ignored by everyone and it eventually
runs away with the house.
And so Mr Bixby,
who's the head of the household,
the guy who's all working comes home and
his house is gone and he's surprised the
house is gone.
He asked the neighbors where it went.
And you know,
the basic story is something like,
well there was something not going on so
good in that house.
And people ignored it and got bigger and
bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger.
It's finally it ran away with his house.
Well that happens to people all the
time.
They come home and their partner has
packed up taking the kids and left.
It's like,
I didn't see that coming.
It's like see is the right word.
You know,
what did you have a million warnings?
Likely,
you know,
now,
now and then someone gets screwed.
They're married to someone who's
psychopathic and you know,
they're just doomed from the start.
But generally it's not that.
It's the accumulation of a million
unsolved on had arguments and finally it
explodes.
And that's what happens when you
suppress free speech.
The the,
for the reason you support free speech
is not because people,
it's not even because it isn't.
Because people have a right to be heard.
That isn't a dig it exactly.
It's the people have a right to be
stupid and ignorant and you need to
listen to them because then you know
where the stupid and ignorant people are
and you can,
you can have a discussion with them.
Instead they feel oppressed and they go,
hi,
and then that's not good.
That is not good.
Because they can say,
well,
we're all pressed.
And that justifies their stupidity and
ignorance and it's like they are
oppressed.
Whether that justifies their stupidity
ignorance,
it's a whole different question.
But you don't stop destructive morons
from talking ever.
Because the fact that you don't let them
talk doesn't mean that what they think
goes away.
Plus you don't have a chance to confront
them.
So
anyways,
we'll,
we'll finish up
on this next week.
But here's the central idea.
People have an ethical responsibility to
embody horace,
let's say,
because we can take it out of the
religious context that way.
Because like none of you guys are
ancient Egypt worshipers,
right?
So it's,
it's irrelevant from a,
from a cultural perspective.
But what the Egyptians carefully laid
out was the idea that it's the,
it's the force that pays attention,
especially to corruption and evil that
revivified as the state at its own risk.
Because of course horse loses nine and
the conflict,
it's,
there's never any indication that the z
easy,
you put yourself at risk to do it,
but the risk you avoid by doing it is
the ultimate degeneration of everything
into hell.
So there's a risk to be taken to say
what you think,
but it's a moral obligation.
And the consequence of not doing it is
that the system deteriorates into hell.
And you might say,
well,
is that prove it?
Okay fine,
it's approved.
That's what happened in the communist
countries.
And the documentation is,
it's so clear that the formal rat,
there are many who are form were former
Lee radical lefties and communists in
France who have written a book saying
that it's true.
So you know when you completely convert
reconvert the converted,
you have to think,
well maybe there's some power to that.
And Social Net since basic point
continually was there's no way the
Soviet system could,
it kept its talons in people if they
would've refused to lie and the lies
were always,
you'll face this in the workplace,
you wait and see it's going to come.
Because what'll happen is someone will
come and there'll be a bit of a bully
and they'll come to you and they'll say,
well,
how about if you do this work and you'll
think,
hey renee,
that's your work and it's not kosher
that you're giving it to me,
but you won't say anything.
You'll say,
okay,
because you'll think,
well,
I don't want to cause any trouble.
It's like,
Hey,
no problem,
but the next time that we're comes your
way,
you can just remember that you
facilitated that process because you
didn't say anything to begin with.
And when you get your 10000th piece of
work and you're crushed right over and
you think,
why is the system so damn corrupt?
You might remember that you opened the
door this much with your first response
and people do that all the time and it's
a,
it's a minor falsification of their
experience.
And one of the things I've learned about
that,
and you can think about this as a good
guide.
If you're resentful about something,
you're either immature or you have
something to say.
If you're immature,
well then you should grow up,
you know?
But if you have something to say,
you should say it because the pathology
of the system has manifested itself
within the domain of your experience.
It's right there in front of you and
it's only gone,
it's only tilted just this micro tilt,
you know,
off kilter.
And you might think,
well,
I'm not going to make a fuss out of
because of other that because it's so
little.
It's like there's a book called ordinary
Germans,
ordinary man,
sorry.
It's a famous book and it's a story
about this troupe of German policemen
who are taken to Poland once the Germans
had marched through and they were
birdwalk guys all race before Hitler
came to power.
Just,
I think you could just think about them
as middleclass suburbanites that's
basically who they were.
You know,
average gums.
Okay.
Banded up by taking naked women out into
the field who are pregnant,
shooting them in the back of the head.
And so you think,
wow,
how does that happen?
And the answer is one tiny little step
at a time.
And this is well documented in the book
because the guy who wrote the book was
curious.
It's like,
well how do you take ordinary people who
in principle are no worse or better than
anyone else and get them to commit
unbearable atrocities.
And then he walks you through it.
It's like they're asked to do x.
And they say,
okay.
And then they're asked to do x plus one
and they say,
okay.
And they were asked to do x plus two and
they say,
okay.
And by the time they're an x plus a
hundred things are looking pretty
dismal.
And it's getting hard to step back,
you know?
And then then the descent instead of
being like,
this goes like this,
and there's no bottom,
there's absolutely no bottom.
And so the trick is to nip it in the
bud.
And the way you do that is by being
very,
very careful about what you say.
And then when something is not going
right and you know it,
you have to say something and you might
say,
well maybe I'll get fired.
And I would say,
how the hell do you know that's not the
best thing that could happen to you.
You know?
Cause if you're in a system that will
not take your feedback when you're being
reasonable,
then you're in a nascent tyranny and it
could be easily the best thing that ever
happened to you to get out of there
before you're crushed.
Completely.
So,
so,
you know,
the most sophisticated political
philosophers of the 20th century in my
estimation,
came to the conclusion that the reason
that horrific genocidal crimes take
places because ordinary people lie.
And that's a radical conclusion.
But
a,
how could it be any different?
I mean,
if people start,
if people let the system deteriorate by
not opposing it when it does,
how could things end up being different
than that?
Then I would say,
well,
that maps perfectly onto classical
religious ideas.
So let's,
we could say,
talk about horace and we could talk
about,
uh,
a martyr.
But the idea of logos that's underlying
Christianity is exactly the same thing.
Because what logos basically means is
truthful communication.
That's what it means.
And that's the thing that in the Judeo
Christian tradition,
identify as people with the part of God
that creates order out of chaos.
It's,
it's,
it's laid out clearly in the theology.
And the other part that goes along with
that,
and this is where the story,
because the story rolls to a conclusion,
is that if you manifest
the logos,
you end up being crucified and reborn.
But in principle,
that can happen in small enough way so
that it doesn't actually have to happen.
You know,
because if you learn something,
you know,
if something,
if something's bothering you,
it's bothering you need to take it
through.
What inevitably happens is that as you
think it through and incorporate the
information,
all presuppositions are forced to die.
And that's painful.
It's hard on people because you have to
reexamine your principles.
You know,
at a high resolution level or a broad
level part of you is going to die,
especially if you need a radical change.
But maybe if you let the part die and
revivified,
then the whole doesn't have to die.
And I think that that scale,
it's like it works within the
personality,
but it also works within the
personalities organized into a
hierarchical state.
If you don't allow that
death and resurrection process to occur
and you suppress it enough,
the whole state has to die and then you
know,
the probability that that's going to
take everyone with it is very,
very high.
So that seems like a bad long term
outcome.
Well.