These are stopping Jordan Peterson.
Thank.
Are there differences between men and
women?
Yes.
Perfect.
So the first thing I've noticed,
and I actually mentioned this at the
University of Toronto,
the baby with someone who was
thinking about this for quite a while
and there was an overwhelming majority
of men in the room at the University of
Toronto and if you look around
you'll see that it's probably running,
I wouldn't say about 1910 and that's
remarkable because there are more women
than men in universities now and so it's
been quite interesting to me to see the
public parks.
The vast majority of people are also the
people that are watching on youtube.
It's about 90 10 as well.
I'm not exactly sure why that is.
Although I think maybe that nobody is
actually speaking to,
you know,
maybe I'm doing a bit of that and I will
say that's probably also really good for
women because men aren't doing very
well.
You can be sure that women aren't going
to do very well because as it turns out,
you actually meet each other.
So anyways,
I don't need to start again.
I guess talking about bills,
she's 16 and I know I made some videos
back at the end of September.
I suppose most people you know that one
of them,
unless I'm expressing my concern about a
piece of legislation at the federal
level called Bill Sixteen and it was
boring to do,
was to add gender expression and gender
identity to the list of protected
groups,
predictability to the relevant human
rights legislation and also making it
harassment and discrimination,
something intentionally addressable
under the hate crimes,
permission of the criminal code on a
surface of it very skirt,
shorter bill wasn't turns out on the
surface it looks,
although it's very bad with formula,
the first major errors of course the
gender expression,
which is fundamentally fashion choices
defined onto her human rights
conditions,
websites.
It's how you present yourself,
how you present yourself in terms of
your clothing and your fashion and your
hair and makeup and that sort of thing
in day to day activity.
It's shouldn't be too unreasonable
walked out with it.
That does not constitute a group and I'm
actually a bit of a stickler when it
comes to language.
I think especially when we're making
legislation that we should be laws that
say exactly what they should say and
nothing else,
and since gender expression is not
approved,
it strikes me as very difficult to
determine exactly how it's going to be
added as a group to the protected groups
under the relevant to human rights.
But more than that,
um,
it's,
it's quite self.
It's quite almost,
and I've talked to a number of people
about this,
so I know it's not just my imagination
then bill [inaudible] and legislation
like it are going to be interpreted in
light of the policies that the Ontario
Human Rights Commission has developed a,
the urine absolutely incoherent set of
palsy,
never seen one.
And that's why the,
the first video,
the second video I made because
University of Toronto and its wisdom,
the HR and equity people decided that it
was okay to force their employees to
undergo mandatory anti unconscious bias
training.
Which is something I have a big problem
with given that you can't diagnose
someone's unconscious bias first of all.
And even if you couldn't,
there's no evidence whatsoever that
unconscious bias retreading will help.
And find them,
there's no reason whatsoever by your
employer,
no matter who they are,
should be messing about with the
fundamental perceptual structures of
your,
of your psyche,
especially when they're looking at
things that aren't even volunteered.
So it's appalling on multiple
dimensions.
And one of the things I would seriously
recommend to all of you is that if
anybody starts to suggest that you need
to undergo mandatory retraining through
your unconscious racial biases,
that if you go along with that,
you're immediately admitting that you're
the sort of biggest who needs to be
retrained.
And I would think very carefully about
admitting them because first of all,
it's possible that it's not true.
You know,
I mean,
people carry with them.
Every carries with them,
certainly in the,
in group preference.
That's quite common.
What exactly that means in terms of
their overt behavior.
Uh,
proclivities is completely undetermined
by the relevant science.
And there's absolutely no excuse for
social psychologists to be putting
forward tests like the implicit
association task which purport to
measure unconscious bias as a diagnosed
against them because they don't have the
validity and reliability that we put
forward as such.
In fact,
if you are a clinical psychologist and
you were using tests that sort of to
diagnose individuals,
you'd be in violation of the statutes
that are governing private practice.
So I have my reasons for objecting to
these studies.
Now.
What I really don't like about bill see
16 and its surrounding policies is that
it's.
It's putting into our law a sequence of
presuppositions that actually happened
to be false and it was me and pointing
out that they were false.
That's got me in whatever trouble I've
been in and generate the accusations of
such things as Trans Phobia and racism,
which are.
I don't know how racism got into the
picture at all because.
Because I complained about the insane
individuals who are running black lives
matter Toronto.
Then I have,
since I'm not a racist,
I don't care if you're black or
breathing if you're crazy.
I've never made the point that you're
crazy to people who run the black lives
matter are really reprehensible
individuals and so I was objective to
that.
I don't see how that makes racist with
regards to being a transport.
First of all,
I object to the terminology because
phobia has specific terminology,
which is partly why also object to the
word luck,
Islamophobia,
because phobia is a medical term and you
don't just get to pull in medical terms,
uh,
away from their proper context and apply
them to those people whose political
opinions you don't happen to agree with
misuse of language.
It's misuse of medical terminology.
And I would also like to tell all of
them,
just so you know,
that there are a number of.
First of all,
there aren't that many transsexual
people in the world.
There aren't that many in Canada.
So whenever you hear from any of them,
it's actually a reasonably substantial
portion of the overall population.
There are a lot of videos on youtube put
up like transsexual people,
including the person I talked to you in
Vancouver.
His name is Tara Meyer who,
who stayed quite vociferous with that.
They don't agree with any of the,
uh,
of the activist.
The trend is that the so called Trans
activist political agenda that's being
put forward as hypothetically
representative of their approval.
First of all,
they're not a group.
The fact that you happened to have a,
what would you say,
gender dysphoria or,
or an indeterminate gender identity does
not make people a margin to screw.
It certainly doesn't.
It doesn't situate you such that some
member of your group or some so called
ally,
let's say,
can stand out and stand purport to speak
for you on mass as if you were a,
a modular scrutiny as completely
nonsensical.
I mean,
you can talk to a man and assuming that
he speaks for all man,
man,
you can't tell.
Talk to a black woman and have her say
that she speaks for all black women and
inserting the can stand up and say that
because you're a transsexual,
you speak for all transexuals
department.
Why?
We have the idea of legitimate
representation for people to
legitimately represented a group.
They have to have some legitimacy.
Perhaps they have to be elected.
At least they have to pull the people
that are purporting to represent because
he can just come up and say it.
It's inappropriate on after receiving 30
letters from transsexual people and then
29 and the more positive and I can tell
you why with regards to what I've been
doing,
I can tell you why the first is they're
not very happy with,
uh,
the idea that they're being represented
by these noisy activists groups because
they don't regain at each individual
because these are all individuals who
wrote me saying that they're not happy
about being represented.
They're not having because that isn't
how their political view of the world
actually helps to lay itself out.
In fact,
most people were turning sexual,
are perfectly happened,
for example,
with the pronouns he and she,
they just want to be called the other
one.
And so the people who are,
who want the gender neutral pronouns,
pronouns say,
I don't know,
a very small minority of a very small
minority.
It's hard to say how many of them are,
but the idea that they're somehow valid
representatives of the whole group is
observing.
They're also not very happy because they
believe that,
that that because this has become such
an issue,
there are actually likely to face more
prejudice rather than less prejudice,
you know,
because generally what people want,
regardless of whatever kind of visible
minority status they might have,
what most people want is to live
relatively peacefully and invisibly
among other people.
And so then whenever a political
movement comes out to exaggerate or or,
or otherwise draw attention to the
reporting differences,
there's real danger in that.
So I'd like to put to rest the idea that
somehow the transactive as to who are
accusing me of all the things that are
accusing me of are somehow more
legitimate representatives of
transsexual identity and,
and that say well being than I am.
I don't believe that for a second.
I've dealt with all sorts of people in
my life more than more than most people.
That you'll need that for sure.
Big Span,
different sort of person.
You can imagine that I worked hard to
make all of their lives better
regardless of their,
of their particulars,
of their identity.
And so to cast me as an enemy of,
of,
of an identifiable group,
I believe is completely observed them.
I think I can be confident in stating
that too because I have the good fortune
of having about 500 hours of my public
statements to university students
online.
I tape everything now.
Everything that will say to students,
pretty much,
you know,
at least in the classroom if there is
anything even remotely reprehensible in
any of that content and can be sure that
someone would have called it out and put
it on youtube with big exclamation
points that are going to be called
property to task for it.
And none of that has happened at all.
And the reason for that is that there
isn't any of that.
None of that exists.
So I'm not saying that I'm completely
without bias.
You have to be a fool to say that,
you know,
everyone is biased in their perceptions
to some degree.
But that's,
that's not the point.
That doesn't mean you're racially biased
or that you're racist.
It means that you have your own
particular viewpoint.
And then that comes with with
idiosyncratic St,
St Lucy's and peculiarities of your
character and your ethnic heritage and
your race and your culture and all of
that.
So I'm not going to say for a moment
that I don't have my own viewpoint
because I do,
but I'm a certain things that,
that their comments directed at me that
you're trying to target with some,
some of these half winded epithets that
are continuing to direct it after you're
completely without any standing
whatsoever.
So.
All right,
so let's go into the background that
Bill [inaudible] and why I objected to
it.
So I looked at quite deeply into the
legislation as it was originally
formulated in Ontario.
And that was the legislation that was
designed to provide protection for
people who,
whose gender identities,
let's say nonstandard.
And the original legislation wasn't too
bad,
you know,
it.
It basically attempted to do perhaps
what it should have if it was going to
be reasonable and merely add,
let's say the people who have a
nonstandard gender identities to the
list of protected groups.
And they actually defined the known
standard gender identity fairly
carefully,
but they shot the legislation out to
activists groups and what happened was
that by the time everybody and their
dog,
so to speak and have their shot at
modifying the original terminology was
absolute mess and it's an absolute mess
now and I'm going to tell him why and
also why it's dangerous.
There first thing in the policies that
surround those [inaudible].
There's a claim that's been instantiated
law in Ontario and will soon be
instantiated into law in Canada.
Anatomy is and it's a technical and you
need to pay attention to it because of
the technicalities matter.
So the claim is the biological sex,
gender identity,
gender expression and sexual proclivity
very independently
and that was a false claim.
Now,
that's actually what I said in the
original video and that's why people
originally and instill accused me of
denying the existence of transsexual
people.
There's no point in doing that because
obviously transsexual people exist and
they've existed for a very long period
of time,
but that has very little to do with
whether or not biological sex,
gender,
identity,
gender expression and sexual proclivity
are independent and they are certainly
not independent.
They're not even close to a dependent.
There are so highly correlated that the
correlation is almost perfect.
And,
and these things matter when you put
them into,
into,
into a legal framework.
And so what's really happened is because
the social constructionist types of lost
the intellectual battle as the
biological evidence for the grounding of
identity has become stronger and
stronger over the last 50 years because
they've lost the scientific argument.
They've taken the back door and they're
trying to instantiate legally it's not
gonna work because you can make false
facts law.
I mean you can hurt people by doing
that.
You can cause all sorts of trouble,
but it isn't going to work for any
length of time.
So let's take apart the client.
First of all,
the first thing is that biological sex
and gender identity are actually
different and you know you can make a
case for that in a weak way because
because there is quite a range of
personality expression,
let's say,
and interests among people who have the
same biological sex,
so there are masculine limit,
let's say,
and there are feminine now and there's
quite an overlap,
although you can distinguish the
janitors quite,
quite accurately using nothing but
personality information and interest so
you can separate them even at the level
where there is some similarity,
but so you can make a weakened case for
that,
but it's difficult to make a strong case
and the reason for that is that
virtually every person who was
biological sex is male,
expresses themselves in mail or has an
identity that's now.
It's only about one in 300 people for
whom that I get the difference.
Now you can say,
well that's because the,
the,
the degree gender,
what would you say?
Amorphousness has been suppressed by
sociological phenomenon.
I suppose that's true to some degree,
but it doesn't matter.
It's still going to being a very tiny
minority and he's narrowed to exceed
more than one percent.
I don't think so.
What that means is that 99 percent of
people at the same gender identity as
biological sex,
so how has that independent?
It's the very opposite of independent,
so it's wrong.
It's a simple as that and then now that
doesn't mean there aren't people who
don't wear.
Those two identities don't match and
those are the transsexual people
obviously,
but two,
to extract from that,
the statement that those very
independently is a intellectual sleight
of hand and it's really been pushed
forward by people who are radical social
constructionists who believe that every
single aspect of human identity is
determined by culture and that was
patently false and not only that,
it's dangerous politically because one
of the ideas that characterized the most
reprehensible movements of the 20th
century was the human beings can be
molded in any manner possible by the
state that we didn't have any intrinsic
identity,
that any sort and that were only
creatures of coalition.
And that's not the case.
There's a very distinct human identity,
and I'll talk a little bit more about
that as this progresses.
Okay,
so gender identity and biological sex do
not very independent.
That's the first thing that clamp as
well,
that's moved to gender expression.
Well,
you can address in any manner in what
you can express yourself in a feminine
manner,
culturally speaking,
if you're a male or you can express
yourself in the mascot.
Now culturally speaking,
if you're female,
but the truth of the matter is that the
vast majority of people whose biological
sex is male and whose gender identity is
male,
presented themselves in their fashion
choices as male and the same can be said
about females.
So the notion that there's independence
there is also interact.
They can vary,
but they don't vary independently.
And finally,
with regards to sexual proclivity,
the vast majority of people who are male
who a,
who identify as a male who presented
themselves as male,
are also heterosexual.
And that doesn't mean that there are new
people who are homosexual.
The percentage varies,
but it looks like it's somewhere between
two and five percent or maybe between
one and five percent depending on the
statistics,
but that means that at least 95 percent
of people who are male who identify as
male and present and present themselves
as male are also heterosexual,
so those four levels of analysis do not
very independently and that's that.
So the law is incorrect,
it's badly formulated and it's poorly
put forward and that's what I was
objecting to.
Now is worse than that as far as I can
tell,
because it's social construction is dale
and the social infrastructure element is
the insistence that all those things are
culturally are culturally constructed
and they're not.
So let's do that.
Let's review that a little bit.
It's like elementary biology I suppose.
What's different between men and women?
All right,
well there's a variety of things.
You know the classic human embryo
logical for is female xx or x,
y,
and the males are a masculinized in
Utero by testosterone.
So that's the first difference.
And testosterone exposure in Utero has
quite profound effects on later on all
sorts of phenomena.
Psychological and physical,
so for example,
one of the things that higher levels of
testosterone in Utero seem to predict is
less interest in people that more
interest in face and so,
and that's been well documented research
teams in the UK in particular,
but,
but in any case,
so this Feminine Female Morpho the
Standard Morphology is female,
but it's translated into male,
a male morphology by testosterone.
And so then what do you get for standard
morphological transformations while
there's the evident genetic ones
speaking technically a,
obviously male and female genitalia
differ substantially as you all know
there are,
there is some variation in that,
although it's very rare.
Um,
and then there are also other
differences that kick forward,
especially when puberty hits and some of
those are physiological and some of them
are resectable.
So one of the things that you see have
you for example,
is that there aren't very many,
there aren't very large personality
differences between boys and girls
before purely doing with regards to
negative emotion.
So that's trading neuroticism for those
of you who are interested in big five
trait terminology.
And so people who were high on
neuroticism are more sensitive to
anxiety and emotional pain and women are
more sensitive than men to anxiety and
emotional pain on average and the effect
is massive.
It's about a third to half a standard
deviation,
but it's massive enough so that if you
look at the end of the distributions
were the extreme and people are almost
all the people who have extreme problems
with anxiety and emotional pain.
Our window,
it's running about four to one in terms
of depression and anxiety disorder
diagnosis worldwide and there's no
evidence that that's cultural.
Now on the other end of the spectrum,
so to speak,
there are male pathologies as well,
so males are much more likely to
manifest every social personality
disordered.
They're much more likely to be
characterized by alcoholism and they're
also more much more likely to manifest
and attention deficit disorder and
various learning disabilities.
And so that also seems to be biologic
dedicated to a large degree.
So and interestingly enough,
those differences,
the personality differences between men
and women with regards to trade negative
emotion emerge up puberty while,
while.
Well,
let's think about it for a minute.
Now,
these are speculations,
but you can,
you can think about that until you tell
me what you think.
I mean,
they're reasonably grounded
speculations,
but um,
I'm not certainly going to state them as
fact,
although I would say that the,
the idea that these differences in
personality between men and women exist,
that's fast.
How powerful those different those
differences are and precisely what they
consist of is still subject to some
investigation,
but it's extraordinarily well
documented.
So what happens to men and men at
puberty,
while the men get bigger,
they get stronger,
especially in their upper bodies and
human beings are quite impressive.
Were prey animals as well as we're
predators,
as well as what are the,
what are the ways that we defend
ourselves aggressively is using the
upper body strength.
So we punch like Kangaroos.
There's other evidence to do that.
So,
and we punched.
And so what that means is that men are
quite a bit more dangerous than women in
say hand to hand combat.
And that's an American actual actually a
real problem.
You see one of those,
you see that manifest itself in part in
a strange statistic because it will come
as news to most of you,
but why is it their husbands more often
than husband see if their wives quite
quite a lot actually,
but it's.
It's a misleading statistic to some
degree because women lack upper body
strength.
They can hit their husbands and they're
not really going to hurt them that much.
I mean there are men who are abused and
neglected that,
but one of the problems with having much
harder at upper body strength is that if
you hit some your life Bible to hurt
them,
and so a male aggression in the context
of a dyadic relationship,
physical aggression as much more likely
to be dangerous or lethal than the
female version of the same sort as part
of the reason.
I think that women are more likely to
hit their husbands or wives more likely
to interest us that the reverse is
because both have wives and the husbands
know perfectly well that the wife is
going to hurt as much.
So there isn't as much inhibition
against the aggression.
Okay,
so now what is it?
What is it mean for women that men are
stronger than them?
Starting at puberty means that women are
at a disadvantage in physical combat and
that's part of the reason I think that
their nervous systems make them more
nervous or anxious and more susceptible
to emotional pain is because the world
is actually more dangerous for them.
Now the world is also more dangerous for
women's sexually.
Now that self evident,
I really think I have to explain that.
I hope no one is foolish enough to try
to disagree with that.
Definitely the reason that sex is more
dangerous for women than for men
obviously because women can get pregnant
and that changes.
That changes their life completely.
I mean,
they may choose to have an abortion,
but that in itself is no trivial matter
and as soon as you have a child and that
child is dependent on you,
then your whole life is changed and in
in more traditional societies,
if you had a sexual adventure outside of
the standard traditional structures and
you ended up pregnant,
now you are in serious trouble and so
for women to be more anxious and more
susceptible to the emotional pain
because of their increased sexual
vulnerability is perfectly reasonable.
Then the final reason I think that that
women are more susceptible to anxiety
and emotional pain than men is because.
Let me see now.
I lost my train of thought for that.
I'll have to come back to that for a
moment.
Oh yes.
That's it.
No,
it's not obvious to me that women's
nervous systems are actually actually
serve to function in the best interest
of women.
I think that they actually serve to
function in the best interests of women
and infants because you think,
do you think about our evolutionary past
and for that matter are present?
No,
you're quite a different creature when
you're single person,
male or female,
then you are when you're a female as an
incident,
especially the intent that's under the
bolt hole on soul because human entrance
are unbelievable.
Know they're born in some sense of way
before they shouldn't be in that.
That's part of an evolutionary problem
too because our hands are so fake that
babies are.
Babies have to be born very young
compared to other mammals that are our
size.
Roughly speaking.
The gestation period shouldn't be longer
for human being.
So because our heads are so big,
the babies have to come under early and
that makes them route relatively
underdeveloped.
Um,
and so they need a tremendous amount of
care.
They're very fragile.
And so it seems to be quite likely that
women's nervous systems are optimized so
that they're more threat sensitive and
more sensitive to emotional pain because
they have to be more responsive to
infants and they have to take care of,
especially in your most fragile state
and happen to be in the first nine
months.
And I think that tilts women's nervous
systems hard in the direction of what
men might regard as excessive negative
emotionality,
but you have to be sensitive to threat
and danger if you're going to have an
infant because they're very,
very fragile.
So I think those are the reasons,
and there's lots of other personality
differences between men and women.
You know,
I can give you a list of them and these
are well documented it,
so you might as well know about them.
Um,
there's not a lot of difference in men
and women in terms of extroversion.
Extroversion as a whole.
Extroversion is roughly the dimension
that bring in the dimension of
personality that's associated with
positive emotion.
And extroverted people are gregarious
and enthusiastic and assertive.
They like to party.
They like to have a good time.
The social environment is their
environment and extroversion breaks down
into enthusiasm and assertiveness and
women are more enthusiasm,
which means that not only do they have
more negative emotion than men,
they also have more positive emotions.
And so,
um,
so that's the positive emotion
dimension.
The negative emotion dimension is
neuroticism,
as I said,
somewhat pleasantly named,
I guess,
but it basically index is anxiety and
emotional pain,
frustration,
disappointment,
grief,
that sort of thing.
All logo,
the same dimension that breaks into
volatility and volatility,
volatility.
People are rather irritable and and
withdrawal and withdrawal are less
likely to do things that are threatened
and women are higher by about a third of
the standard deviation in both
agreeable.
This is the dimension that men and women
differ on the most and agreeable people
and this is I think,
the most fundamental dimension of
matching it at that characterizes human
being so agreeable.
People are compassionate and polite and
warm and kind and giving,
but they're easy to.
It's easy to take of
standing up for themselves and actually
if you look at one of the things that
predicts wage differential across time,
male or female,
there's more agreeable.
People get paid less and the reason for
that is that often salary negotiation
negotiations,
that zero sum and if and if you're not
aggressive,
you don't get paid because people aren't
just going to give you money because
they're going to be nice to you.
That is not how it works.
You generally have to fight for status
and position and movement forward
careers and in order to that,
you'd have to take a relatively,
I would say self centered attitude
because they all sent in some sense the
opposite.
The opposite of being agreeable is to be
self centered and I'm also not saying
that in a particularly negative way.
There's advantages to being self
centered and to fight for your own
territory and so and men are more likely
to do that and you might say,
well,
what's your evidence that those
differences in personality aren't
culturally constructed and the evidence
for that?
It's quite clear.
You can go online,
you look up the Scandinavian studies.
Let's go online and look up gender
differences in personality
cross-culturally.
You'll find the relevant studies.
They've been done with tens of thousands
of people and what they showed quite
clearly is that in those societies where
the most is being done to move,
move to social world,
into a position of radically quality,
and so that would roughly be the
Scandinavian countries because they've
done more than that more than any other
country.
The personality differences between men
and women maximize,
they don't minimize,
they maximize.
And I'll say that again at in the
countries where the most has been done
to equalize the playing field between
men and women.
Men and women get more different rather
than more of the same.
So for all your social constructionists
out there in the audience,
and there's probably not that many of
you because you wouldn't come in here
and be talked to or social
constructionist.
You're actually wrong.
Yeah.
Well,
and the thing is,
thank you.
Don't
be.
So.
One of the things you might be
interested in is that it's all the same
to me in some sense,
like when I was looking into this to
begin with in this group started
probably 25 years ago,
looking at differences in personality
between men and women,
you know,
it doesn't go at all whether they were
fundamentally biological,
biological are fundamentally associate,
large boiler or mixed produced the
differences,
you know,
no one knew and the most logical
hypothesis really the ipod was that as
unique as this society that men and
women would become more of the same,
but that is not what happened,
and so we've actually looked the social
constructionist hypothesis with regards
to gender differences in insects and
personality.
We'll put that to the test and you're
very intense way and the social
constructionist viewpoint fail.
So it's very strange because no one
really believed that,
right?
If you make this make society one of the
same in men and women get more
different.
Sorry,
what's up with that?
Well,
the answer seems to is that there's
fundamentally two sources of variability
in personality,
right?
There's perhaps more,
but you can categorize them as roughly
genetic and roughly sociological.
Well,
if you take out all the sociological
differences between the landscape in
which men,
women are raped and all you have left
are the biological and genetic
differences so they maximize or that's
exactly what happened.
This actually matters.
It really matters.
And this is why the demands for equity
or so.
Well,
there's 15 reasons why demands for
equity.
This is between men and women should not
be overlooked.
Partly because it's wrong to overlook
the junior with differences between men
and women.
It's not good for the man.
It's not good for the women.
So one of the things you see in
Scandinavia,
for example,
is there's an overwhelming preponderance
of female nurses and there's an
overwhelming preponderance of male
engineers and actually the data on,
on personality differences.
Um,
there's,
there's the standard traits which I'll
continue to go through.
Um,
I can do that quite quickly.
There's no much difference in trait
conscientiousness between men and women.
If you break it down into the aspects,
women are a bit more orderly than men,
but there's no difference in
industriousness.
And then with regards to openness,
which is the intellect,
intellect,
creativity,
dimension overall,
there's no difference between men and
women,
but if you break it up into the aspects,
then the differences are actually quite
pronounced.
So what you have is the openness to
experience is the technical trade and it
roughly breaks down into something
that's sort of like create creativity
and aesthetic interests versus the
interest in ideas.
And what you see is that women are a
third of the standard deviation higher
than men in terms of,
of creativity and aesthetic aesthetic
proclivity,
let's say,
and men or month or the standard
deviation higher than women in terms of
interest in ideas.
And it's not a trivial difference and it
makes a difference.
So,
but the biggest difference between men
and women as it turns out,
and this is almost one standard
deviation,
which is a walloping difference.
You never see that in social sciences.
And massive difference is um,
difference between difference in
interest and the masculine interests.
Roughly speaking is in things.
And then female interest,
roughly speaking is in people.
And that's what underlies the
differences.
Say in,
in career choice preference between
things like nursing and psychology and
social work and that sort of thing and
engineering and uh,
because engineering is perhaps the most
male oriented about the disciplines and
the evidence that that's a sociological
history period.
Now I should also point out,
because this is important,
people have wondered for a long time if
they,
if the differences between men and women
say with regards to the sciences and the
engineering had anything to do with
intelligence and the former prison
department.
There is,
summer's gone in terrible trouble at one
point.
In fact,
I think he had to resign because he made
a very technical claim and he said that
if you look at the distributions of
intelligence for men and women,
imagine you have a normal distribution.
Right?
So almost everybody's at the average.
There's some extremely,
extremely intelligent people,
but not very many.
And there are some people who are very
intellectually imperative.
Not very many.
If you map the distributions of many
women onto one another,
there's two hypothesis.
One hypothesis,
roughly speaking,
is that they're the se and the evidence
for that as is reasonable.
I would say the other,
the other theory is that the means are
the same,
the meaning is the same.
So both men and women have an average Iq
of 100,
but the standard deviation is different.
So it's larger amendment.
It is in women.
And what that means is that if you're
way the hell out into the hyper genius
rates,
they're almost all men.
But also if you go away,
they log into the range where people are
incredibly intellectually impaired.
They're also all men.
And that's the increase male variability
hypothesis.
And you see increased male variability
in and a number of different species,
partly because men are more expendable
than limit.
And the reason for that,
biologically speaking,
the reason for that is that,
well,
you don't need that many men to
impregnate a lot of women,
but women need women.
Women are a bottleneck with regards to
reproduction.
So every woman task,
although not every man's house and,
and that's true many,
many species.
And so you see more variability and male
behavior because of that across species
frequently.
And um,
that comes often added costs with
increased male illness.
And you know,
look at it guys,
you're going to die.
It's been eight years sooner than the
typical woman and that's partly the
price you paid for,
for,
for running,
parking on testosterone because it's
quite toxic over the long run.
So men are men in do page for their,
for their,
whatever advantages they might have and
they paid for that with the lifespan
that's decreased by about 10 percent.
It's a nontrivial disadvantage.
But anyways,
what Larry Summers said was,
well,
if the ICU distribution is flattering
for men than for women,
maybe one of the reason that almost all
the outstanding men in science,
technology,
engineering and mathematics or mail is
because it takes a genius level of Nike
level of say 150 or a hundred and 60.
And when you go way out on the
distributions,
when the distribution is different like
that,
then there's massive differences at bms.
Now he didn't say that was by the way he
said that that was one possibility.
And by the way,
it is one possibility because nature
doesn't arrange itself so that
everything in presents to us is in
keeping with what we would like to be
true political,
in fact,
quite the contrary.
Now I'm kind of agnostic with regards to
that because I've looked at the data on
both sides and I can.
I don't think that we can make a
determined them statement about the
differences in science,
technology,
engineering,
mathematics over representation of men
on the basis of variability and
intelligence.
But I do think we can make the case in
terms of interest because it is the case
that the biggest differences between men
and women are differences in interest.
And the question is,
well,
do we have a problem with that?
Because that really a problem.
Now you know,
you couldn't.
You could up your culture to eradicate
those differences.
You know,
because you could make cultures very
coercive.
And so if you punched boys from the time
they were born for being interested in
things and insisted that they become
more interested in people,
then perhaps you could do that.
It would,
it would come at some cost.
And you could do the same thing for
girls,
you could make them less interested in,
people are more interested in things,
but you know,
to the degree that those differences are
real and to the degree that they're
actually bombed or grounded in biology,
you're going to have to turn your
society into something pretty damn too
radical to produce those differences.
So when you to do that,
that makes you do,
what do you want to do it?
Is it not the big problem that men and
women actually have different interests
and this is read that biggest surprise.
Is that something that you want to
eradicate?
All right.
So I also felt back to bill's scene.
16,
okay.
The policies surrounding it are
incorrect and they're dangerous and
they're dangerous partly because they
are predicated on the insistence that
all of these,
these levels of analysis with regards to
human identity associated with
culturally constructed and they're not.
And there's implications for that too
because one of the things that this is
happening,
particularly with regards to the equity
movements.
So I'll define equity for you used to be
quality and more opportunity,
but it shifted to equity and in many
universities now,
like human resources department is human
resources in their equity.
They should be absolutely ashamed of
themselves for that is.
It is.
It is absolutely appalling.
It's reprehensible.
I actually thinking,
well,
I want to say it.
There's almost no political stance.
It's more reprehensible than the stamps
that demands equity.
It's very informed and it's being tried
very many times in very many places and
the net result of pushing the equity
from a political perspective was not
good.
And if people have any stats of 20th
century history at all,
the first thing they realized is that
political systems based on the notion of
equity become murderous very,
very rapidly.
And so
thank you.
So
here's how you diagnose in an
organization as racist and pathological.
So the first thing you do is pick your
key dimensions of identity and whatever
they happen to be in the common ones are
gender,
race,
ethnicity,
sexual proclivity,
fine,
but there are enumerable,
right?
That's one of the problems is that you
can continually in some of our people
into groups
and the groups are relevant and also,
for example,
if you were concerned with the
representation,
let's say of Hispanic women,
are you going to be equally concerned
about the representation of Hispanic
women from economically deprived
backgrounds and for rich backgrounds for
privileged about reasonably going to
Hispanic women into those who came
through privileged and those who came
from privileged backgrounds and further
stuff divide them by.
Well,
how about attractiveness?
How about that?
How about wait,
how about that?
How about Iq?
How about disability?
No,
you can fractionating populations
endlessly with regards to their group
identity in it so that,
that's one of the fundamental problems
with the notion of equity just because
you can never attain it because you can
keep fractionating the groups and so
you're not going to attain equity.
But apart from that,
let's say that you just start with the
major categories,
you know,
um,
gender,
ethnicity,
race and sexual proclivity,
that's fine.
So here's how you diagnose an
organization to find out if the people
who run it are unconscionably biased and
prejudice.
You look at the strategy of the
organization,
right?
The power structure.
Then you take each strata and you map it
onto the demographics of the general
population according to your particular
way of breaking down that population.
You have to keep in mind and if there's
any lack of concordance between the
general population and representation at
each of those levels of the hierarchy,
then you described the whole hierarchy
as unconscionably a biased and racist.
It's like,
well that's convenient except that it's
wrong.
And I mean,
well,
the thing is,
you know,
most organizations do have their share
bikes for historical reasons and for and
for reasons that are perhaps a lot more
unseemly that historical reasons,
but the idea that you can categorically
state that every single difference at
every single level of the hierarchy as a
consequence of the racial bias and
announcing the thoughts of everyone in
the organization is absolutely appalling
thing to think,
you know,
it's a multifaceted problem,
right?
Why are people represented differently
in different organizations?
While there's probably 20 reasons not
what you can't just say,
well,
it's racism or it's prejudice.
It's like,
yeah,
sure,
yes.
It's probably racism and it's probably
prejudice,
but that isn't the only reasons.
There's lots of reasons and you have to
do a differentiated analysis first of
all,
to understand understanding and then you
have to be very careful not to mock
about stupidly with the organization to
make it worse than it already is,
and so the idea,
and let me go up the University of
Toronto,
her department is teaching.
It's just this straight out that's
adequately.
If they.
If the organization doesn't produce a
population equivalent outcome,
then it's racist or sexist or whatever
you want it to be.
There's something wrong with it and then
where's the that?
Everybody in the organization needs to
be reeducated.
It's like,
come on,
that's just nuts.
It's not sensible and well,
no,
these are not sensible.
It's.
It's downright dangerous.
And so that was the other reason that I
made the videos to begin with is because
I don't believe that that's the least
bit appropriate and I think it takes our
society.
Does your path,
so all right,
so let's.
What else do I talk to you both?
Oh yeah,
so,
so this was the last thing I was asked
to about.
So we're in a rather chaotic political
period right now and as you may have
noticed,
that certainly manifested itself in the
American election,
which is still causing all sorts of
preservations,
but you can see the same thing happening
in let's say in Europe for the time
being,
right?
What do you see happening?
Roughly speaking is that the divide
between the left wing and the right wing
is growing and extremism on both ends is
also growing.
And really that's not a good thing
because we've had extremist right wing
movements in the last 50 years.
We've had extremely left wing movement
centered.
They weren't pretty and maybe we don't
want to bring them back and so we have a
serious problem.
All right,
so let's take a look at that for a
minute and look at it seriously.
So let's look at the left.
And so I'm going to tell you some things
about the left.
The first thing is that people vote
their temperament and you need to
understand this because when you're
talking to people who are across the
political divide from you,
and I'm assuming they're relatively
reasonable people,
we're not going to talk about the
extremist for a moment.
If you're talking to people who are
liberal,
left leaning,
then you're talking to people who are
high in trait,
openness and low in conscientiousness.
Okay,
and so that makes them roughly speaking,
interested in ideas and creative but not
very good at implementing things.
And then people who are on the right or
the opposite,
they're lower loneliness and they're
high in conscientiousness,
conscientiousness,
and that makes them not very good at
thinking up new things,
but pretty damn good at implementing
things that already exist and so and so.
The thing about that is that both of
those ways of interacting with the world
are necessary under different
conditions.
You know,
sometimes you have a good idea and
you're running on it,
and what we need are people to implement
the idea just as Indian as efficiently
and effectively and in an orderly map.
And away you go,
but sometimes you're efficient in order
to restructure is not working anymore
because the environment has changed
dramatically around it and you need
troublemakers with new ideas to come in
and break things up so that you start
moving in a different direction and new
I'd for yourself or when is the time for
the chaos of the left and when is the
time for the order of the right and the
answer to that because we don't know
and that's why we have to talk because
the like the environment moves around on
us,
right?
It's constantly shifting underneath our
feet and sometimes it's shifts so that
we have to shift to the left to stay in
the middle and sometimes it's shifts so
that we have to shift to the right to
stay in the middle.
And the only way we can figure that out
is by having political dialogue.
And that's part of the reason why I'm
strong free speech advocate isn't test
if I shouldn't have to defend myself for
such a foolish steak.
No,
please.
Thanks.
What
freedom of speech,
first of all,
freedom of speech isn't a cornerstone of
our is I don't think it's reasonable.
You can have a debate about that and I
think the reason for that is that free
speech is how people fake.
Now you might think you finished,
but generally you don't want to do is
rehash temperamental prejudice is over
and over again in your mind and you
actually know that much until you write
for other people or to the tarp that
people could.
They make you think because your
assumption is just going to be that
you're correct gen unless you've been
really think and Hartland.
Many people can think because it really.
It's hard.
In order to think,
you have to fragment yourself up into
multiple personalities,
each of which hold about opposing
perspective and then you have to let
those opposing perspectives have a
battle in the theater of your
imagination.
That's a very difficult thing to do and
so don't confuse having your
idiosyncratic prejudices with thinking.
You have to be technically trained in
order to think and it's very
uncomfortable and painful and so people
don't like it at all.
So generally what you do though the
speed is that you put forth your view of
the world,
perhaps invest in internet you can,
but also loaded with your own prejudices
and biases because how in your ignorance
as well,
because you have to speak from your
restricted perspective,
knowing as little as you do know and
with your personality,
you know first and foremost in your
utterances and then other people correct
you and hopefully you as you enter into
a real dialogue whereby you can
transcend the your own bias limitations
and expand the toolbox with which you
use to work in the world and everyone
benefits from that and then you modify
your viewpoints so that they actually
work better in the future because that's
kind of what it means.
What it means to have a a useful and
correct viewpoint is do you have a
toolbox that is going to enable you to
work effectively in the world?
And if you're too biased and too narrow,
too ignorant,
what that means is that your toolbox is
only going to work and very narrow
environment.
If you go out into public and you hammer
yourself up against other people,
especially those who don't agree with
you,
you could formulate the problems more
clearly.
You can discuss the possibility for
consensus and then you can negotiate an
implementation strategy and the
alternative to that is that you're
silent.
You're a slave or your retirement.
That's it.
We devolve into conflict and fighting
and that's not a good idea and we don't
have to do it because we do actually
know how to talk to each other and
although perhaps we forget very
frequently why we should have to know.
The other thing to think about is you
know you don't exist just for who you
are.
Now.
You also exist for who you're going to
be next week,
next month,
next year,
five years down the road and so on,
and so you're actually a collection of
people that extends out into the future.
And so what that means is that you not
only have to get along with yourself,
you have to get along with all the
people that you're going to be,
and one of the ways to determine who
those people that you're going to be is
to talk to other people around you
because you're actually a collective
that extends across time and in so far
as you're only speaking for yourself
right now.
You're not speaking for yourself as are
distributed across time,
but if you talked to a bunch of other
people,
then what you're doing is approximating
yourself distributed across time.
So it's actually even in your selfish
best interest to talk to a bunch of
other people because they did help you
represent yourself better than you were
going to do it by yourself.
And then you know why we also say it
well,
there's other reasons that you want to
be.
Want to talk to other people to get your
toolbox in order,
because we might want to say to him,
well,
what do you.
What should you be aiming for in your
life?
I can.
I can tell you that roughly speaking,
if you're looking for something that
will give your life,
meaning,
that's,
that's actually quite straightforward as
far as I'm beginning to town.
This is where the Ios App,
it's so wrong that it's almost
unbelievable and as far as I'm
concerned,
fundamentally they're just escaping from
responsibility anyways,
even though they are perfectly rational
arguments for their nihilism.
It's like everything's meaningless.
It's like,
no.
First of all,
no pain is not meaningless.
You're never going to meet anyone who
will tell you that their own pain is
meaningless,
so we can just forego the whole meeting
was argument right off the bat.
It's like there may be no positive
meeting advice.
We can have a discussion about that,
but south after the negative meaning
exists and everyone knows it,
and even someone who's in Archicad,
nihilistic to the core drug,
a spike through their hand,
they're going to get like that has
meaning and since I've been an
existential
and look at how people are instead of
what they say,
and they'll act out the idea that that
has meaning very,
very rapid,
so we'll just go with that.
Now you might say,
well,
there's all sorts of now,
but that's not the kind of meaning that
I believe doesn't exist.
I believe that only positive meaning
doesn't exist,
which is,
you know,
a little on the negative side.
I would say the beginning,
but I can understand that people have.
People can have a pretty directional
lights,
you know,
and you can easily get yourself in a
situation where it seems like there's
nothing at all to your life except
suffering and that's what happens to
people who become suicidal,
for example,
and it's no joke and they have the
reasons.
Now you know,
sometimes those people have been hurt in
ways that are absolutely unimaginable
and so when they see a horizon that's
full of nothing but suffering,
you can't just wave that away.
But I would say
the first thing we might hypothesize is
that sending paid is an alternative fact
of meeting and certainly seems to be
negative,
but one of the things you might want to
try to orient yourself in relationship
to is the reduction of human suffering.
Now,
because I think that's the goal.
You know the answer to what do you do
about a child who stopped wearing in a
concentration camp?
Is it who the hell is going to care in a
million years?
Right?
That's not the right answer,
and if it's not the right answer in that
situation,
then perhaps it's not the right answer
at all.
And the right answer to who the hell's
gonna care anyways in a million years is
why in the world when you frame the
mistake that idiotically mean anybody,
anybody.
This is kind of a trick of the
imagination in some sense.
Anybody who's quick witted can come up
with a frame of reference that makes
anything that makes almost anything lack
meaning within that frame of reference.
Well,
all that means to me is that you picked
a stupid frame of reference,
right?
Why should you?
Why should you accept without doubt the
consequences of your stupid algorithm?
Who's going to care in a million years
gone?
Really?
You got to be able to do better than
that.
If that's what you're going to wipe out,
meaning.
Well,
so what do you want from me?
Alright?
Reduced software,
that'd be a good one.
You could devote your life to that and I
would say start locally and I think this
is the alternative to right wing
nationalism,
which is too much order and chaos,
which is too much chaos.
We don't want to go down that rabbit
hole again,
either of it.
So what's the alternative?
I thought about this for a very long
time.
It took me decades to come to this
conclusion.
The conclusion is just that you
straightened yourself out and you do
that humbling.
There's this idea that the new
testament,
which I get quite a kick out of,
that you're not supposed to pray in
public.
It's a little more complicated than
that.
Actually,
you know what?
I'm supposed to pray until you like
sorted out the dispute that you have
with your brother.
For example.
I really like that idea because what it
means is that you shouldn't make a
public display of your virtue until you
straighten up your damn life,
and this is one of the things I really
don't like about protests and I really
don't like the fact that university
students are tired.
They're halfway and professors that the
way that you changed your world.
Thank you.
You don't change the world by going and
waving signs of that you've defined as
more evil than first of all,
the probability that they're more useful
than you is actually quite low
because they may be you're in the same
damn boat and if you divided the world
up convenience so that you can identify
the innocent and the and the dam or the
oppressor and oppressed and you think
you're in the positive category,
then the probability that you're a part
of the solution and not part of the
problem was zero.
So it's just not that easy.
You know,
in the most profound people that I've
ever read,
he said the same thing over and over.
It's like the line between good and evil
runs down the middle of every human
heart and the first thing that you're
supposed to do is with that bag on your
own territory.
And that's bloody Joel.
That's a difficult thing to do because
it means that you have to recognize
that.
Recognize yourself as a perpetrator of
gravy and that is what you are and
that's a terrible thing for me to learn.
You know when you look at the 20th
century and you think,
well,
who brought on the horrors of the
communist systems and the horrors of the
Nazi system is the answer is people just
like you.
That's the answer,
but if you don't understand that and you
think that answer is wrong,
then you're not very biased and it's not
surprising because the price that you
paid for wisdom,
this is radically dissimilar.
Disillusionment and the confrontation
with evil and no one wants that.
Really.
It's a terrible thing to confront and
that's because human beings are terrible
or preachers.
Now,
I think we're also absolutely remarkable
creatures and wonderful creatures,
but we have an unlimited capacity for
brutality and evil and every one of us
carries it,
and so what you do is you try to sort
that out in your own life and you start.
I haven't talked to me just a while back
about about his life.
Haven't been going very well.
He decided to put himself together and
he started doing this little ritual
thing,
which I thought was quite cool.
He was in this kind of an isolated guy,
very overweight guy.
When I talk to him,
he lost about 130 comments,
which was quite impressive for this part
of him putting himself together,
but he started doing it by bill.
He had a bunch of labels leftover from
his childhood and the first thing he
did,
because he was feeling very nihilistic
and hopeless,
he,
he found that he got a little bit of
satisfaction out of building little
things on the blade bills,
you know,
and I thought,
well that was pretty interesting.
And so he built a bunch of these things
and then he said,
well,
I got a bunch of these things built.
Then I had to figure out how to organize
them in the room.
They were.
I thought that's cool because he started
higher resolution at the level of
detail.
You know,
what he was building something that was
trivial.
He knew that he was just playing a game,
but then as soon as he had a collection
of those,
then you have to sort out the space that
he was going to organize them in many
figured out,
well,
yeah,
just sort of the room that they were
going to be in,
so we started organizing and beautifying
the room and at the same time he
modified his diet and he was putting
himself together and that's the right
thing to do.
That's the right thing to do is that
there is.
There are responsibilities that are
awaiting you,
right,
that are in your own grass and you know
what they are.
This is also something that no one can
preach to you about.
It's something you have to decide for
yourself and you can do it quite
straightforwardly and it's something
that I do on a regular basis.
You sit down in the or in the morning
and ask yourself like you're asking
someone that you want the answer from,
like genuinely needed,
want to have the entrepreneur telling
yourself none of that.
You're asking yourself,
right?
There's a bunch of things about my life
that aren't in order that aren't
together and I know it and they're
making me suffer and they're making me
less than I am,
and there's some of those things that
are staring me right at the face and I
know what they are and there's some of
those that I can put in order today with
a little bit of work so that when I wake
up tomorrow,
the domain of my experience,
which is basically being itself,
that the main point experience will be
more pristine and better put together
than it is today,
and you asked yourself that you'll find
right away.
You know what they are,
five things that come up,
Bang,
and they'll all be things that aren't
very heroic.
They're kind of trivial and that you've
been avoiding.
You've been avoiding.
Those are little dragons of chaos
though.
And you know,
they're just little.
That's good because you're not much of a
hero warrior and so maybe a little tiny
dragons are all the ones that you've
been put up.
You know,
do search those things out and it'll.
First of all,
they will order your order,
the being around you in a more pristine
and productive way and they can just a
little bit more focused in together and
what that would mean is that the next
thing you can do is ask yourself the
same question in the end of the problems
that will emerge will be slightly larger
and more complex,
and then you can try to put those in
order and that will make everything
around you more pristine and benefit
together and it'll make you a little bit
stronger and more clear habit.
And then another set of problems will
emerge that's a little bit larger.
If you continue to do that,
you know you're asserting yourself.
I'll clean up your room and you put your
house in order and then you could start
to work in the community and by that
time you'll actually have some power and
some and some self confidence and some
competence and some creaminess and
they'll be much more,
much less likely to stupidly hit
something complicated with the stick and
say that you fixed it,
but you have to start low.
You have to be Carl Jung said,
very uninteresting.
One is fairly interesting phrases.
He says that the reason that monitor
people can't see is because they won't
look low enough.
I really liked that.
I mean he is an extraordinarily wise
person than what he meant by that was
something like what I'm telling you,
this,
that the secret to your existence is
right in front of you and it manifests
itself as all those things you know you
should do,
but you're avoiding because one of the
things you might ask yourself this
curse,
you're useless and weak and miserable
and and cruel than all of those horrible
things,
but partly that's because you're also
not what you could be an part of.
The reason for that is not doing what
you know you shouldn't be doing,
so you might ask herself,
because this is a very interesting game.
If you started doing the things that you
know you should do,
this is a discussion with your own
conscious.
If you started doing those things that
you know you should do and you did that
diligently,
what the hell would you be like at 10
years?
Now?
That's an exciting game.
That's an interesting game and if you
play that,
we'll find that you're a hell of a lot
more than you were and that's something
at least you might not hit the pinnacles
that you're going to be a lot lower than
you are,
and then if you're not leaking miserable
and wretched and sovereign,
dismal and self pitying and all those
things,
you're going to be a lot less resentful.
You're going to be a lot less broom.
You're gonna be a lot less cruel to
yourself and to other people.
Well,
that's pretty good start.
You know,
even if you're not a positive force for
good in the world,
if you just weren't wretched horrible,
that would be a good additional
contribution.
No,
I would say too,
there's a corridor that goes along with
that
and I,
and this is so,
so,
so you could look at it this way.
This is something that I tried to
explain.
I did a video on Pinocchio,
couple of Videos About Pinocchio,
which I've been fascinated by it because
it's a very good illustration in poplar
culturally of how archives manifest
themselves and how people understand the
archetypes even if they don't know they
understand them because it was a very
interesting movie and think about it.
You know you,
you might ask,
well,
with modern people,
think about people going to church.
They think,
how can people believe those
superstitions?
Fair enough.
Question,
well,
what the hell do you think you be
moving.
What are you doing here?
Here you are.
You're probably on seem to Nokia,
but whatever.
You're an adult,
you bring your five year old to see,
to know you.
You're just as interest is here,
so think about what you're doing.
First of all,
you know what?
Those are drawings.
They're not real creatures or draws.
Second tuck wouldn't topic.
Who actually happens to one who is being
guided to cricket was highest goal is to
sell for reasons no one can understand
and somehow that makes it very turn them
into something that's real.
It's like that's strange people,
right?
The fact that you're doing that is very
peculiar and it says something about
what people are means that we understand
the things that we don't normally
understand,
and so now it's a very interesting
movie.
I can tell you what it's fundamental
presupposition here,
so I'll just guide you through it very,
very rapidly.
So the beginning of the movie,
Japan,
who's who's the archetype of the good
father,
by the way,
which is an archetype that we've
forgotten about.
It does exist because our culture isn't
just a tyrannical patriarchy.
As you can tell by the fact that we're
comfortable with.
We're not tearing each other to shreds
at the moment,
which is what you do in a state of
absolute chaos,
right?
It's made freezing and starving,
And that is what one cap.
We have a piece and it's rare and it's
amazing that we have and we shouldn't
take it for granted because it's not the
normal order of things.
The normal order of things is
destructive chaos and if you're
fortunate enough to live somewhere
that's peaceful,
productive,
you should thank your lucky stars every
second of your life and if you don't do
that,
all that means is that you don't know
anything about history and you know
nothing about it because things can get
out supposedly monsters and it happens
all the time and there's always a
fraction of the population thinks that's
how they like things to be and perhaps
there's a fraction of you that's like
two and I wouldn't nurture that fragment
if I miss you,
unless you want to go where it will take
you.
Anyways,
back to
no
thank you,
and then you can tell that he's got a
warm allison.
It's full of toys and it's full of music
boxes,
scar little kit and then these goldfish
and he takes care of them and so he's a
good guy.
It makes this pocket and then he puts us
on the puppet announced the final act
and the pocket kidnap his capacity to
speak.
And that's what you want.
If you're a good father is you want to
take your son,
turn turning into someone who can speak
right,
who can speak his soul,
and soldier paddle puts a smile on his
son's spaces as,
wouldn't it be wonderful if he could be
a good boy?
Yeah,
wouldn't it be wonderful,
right?
Because that's what you do.
You're a good father.
You think,
wouldn't it be possible with this puppet
could actually become something genuine
and independent with its own voice?
While he says that sounds likely it goes
off to bed and then star appears up in
the window to be wishes on a star and
you think,
well,
what does that mean?
What does it mean to wish on a star?
It's like,
well,
the star is the light that that gets in
the darkness,
right,
and it's something transcendent.
You go shopping to the night sky and
it's.
It's inspiring whether you're religious
or not.
You're looking into the Internet while
you make a relationship with the
infinite.
By wishing on a star,
you raise your eyes above the horizon
and point at the light that beckons in
the darkness
and you say,
I wish more than anything else that my
son can become a real person.
That's what you do.
If you're a good for the employer may
come into a slave.
You don't want to be a tyrant.
You don't want them to be a puppet.
You want them to be something strong and
independent.
Also,
often over it goes out into the world.
He faces all these different moral
problems.
He's armed with his conscious.
It turns out to be a bug,
right?
Well,
why?
it's because things bug you.
You know you're conscious bugs you and
the reason that the conscience is
jimminy cricket is because that's the
same initials as Jesus Christ and
Jimminy cricket is southern US Slang for
Jesus Christ and no doubt the other
mangers thought that was very commonly.
I'm not telling you that the bug is a
very strange representation of Christ.
That's for sure.
What would make it into a cricketer and
he's also rather error prone into
movies.
So he gets the movie doesn't have
precisely the affordable Christian
structure,
but part of the reason this took me a
long time to figure out too is that you
have to have a dialogue with your
conscience,
but it has to be a dog because it's
actually not 100 percent right.
It has to be something that you build by
having a discussion with it across time,
and that's actually worth Mq.
With junior cricket,
as the movie progresses,
both the puppet and the conscience get
wiser by begging themselves against the
world and the pop.
It has to resist the temptation of fame
and celebrity.
That's the first temptation,
right?
Because he's asked to be an actor,
which is an easy way to be celebrities
like the Kardashians,
right?
It's,
it's established without responsibility
or or competence,
and so that that exists and attraction
and then he's,
he's.
He learns that lying is a very bad idea.
Right?
That's what he's knows grocery as,
to get that sort of.
No.
And then he said he's asked to present
himself as a victim of circumstances.
That's what the Fox and the coyotes.
And when you decided that he's too ill
to go back to school,
they take them to pleasure it degrees
trained to be a jackass that works for
slavers into soul lines,
right?
Not Bad for animation,
I would
say.
And then at the end of the movie,
he tries to go back home because he's
terribly lost and he's half Jack asked
because the people that pleasure island
have told him,
taught him to do nothing but break,
which I can help with
offers or what would you.
What would you say is,
is an appalling parallel to what's
happening?
To educate people who are being educated
in modern universities,
which are increasingly play houses where
you're taught to break in.
Listen,
I can't listen to protest is just.
It just.
It's just painful.
Is this constant repetition of a soul.
It's nonsense.
Thank chanted this because the
protesters,
they're trying to convince themselves
even more desperate than they're trying
to convince them.
So anyways,
Pinocchio goes back home,
half jackass and half again.
Then he tries to find his father.
There's no going home right now.
Once you're an adult,
it's your young adult.
You don't get to go back because there
isn't anyone there that can tell you
what to do anymore,
and so they go and allocate those homes
and his father isn't there and then
finds out that he has to go to the
bottom of chaos itself to rescue his
father,
and that's what we have to do it right,
because our civilization is in this
state of crisis now is predicted long
ago by people like Nisha Dusty Dustier,
and partly what you're trying to do with
you go to university is to go to the
heart of darkness right to the place
that terrifies you the most and define
your values,
your culture really has,
and that's what it means to go down to
the bottom of the desk.
The thing that terrifies you the most,
integrative before your father to very
little story.
The Egyptians were telling that story
for a thousand years ago.
It's one of the oldest stories of
mankind,
and so that's what you have to do.
You and you united yourself with your
culture,
so you're more than just a week and
simple minded individual,
right?
You dedicate yourself to the study of
what's great about the past and you
incorporate it so that there can be
something to you and then you bring your
father back up to the surface so that
the culture can see and live yet,
and then that makes you into a real
individual.
Well,
that's the movie.
we watch it were captivated by it.
Now it's time to understand.
It takes time to understand that in an
articulated and conscious map because
it's too late for us to be unconscious
anymore.
And so we have silla and shrimp.
This,
we have the chaos of the left.
The left says,
well,
we need to tear down structures because
they press.
Obviously structures will press because
something's good at the top of the
structure and also good at the bar.
So if you have any values dropped you,
it's going to privilege somethings and
exclude others,
but if you scrap the value structures
then there's nothing to live for.
So we can't do that.
That's just chaos.
And then the radical right says back to
the nations like really?
You know,
we went back to the nation a couple of
times,
so it doesn't really look that great.
Part of the reason
for that is that the purpose of the
nation isn't the nation.
The purpose of the nation is to produce
citizens who transcend and rejuvenate
the nation and so the nation should be
probably properly subordinating to the
individual,
right to the divine individual for that
map,
and that's what we figured out in the
West.
Now it is that we only figured that out
in the west,
but so far we've been fortunate enough
to put it into a reasonable practice in
our political institutions and thank God
for that.
At least it's worked somewhere and we'd
be completely foolish to give that up
because look at what it's provided us
with.
It's remarkable for free,
as free as we can,
but that doesn't mean that we're happy
because freedom and happiness are not
the same thing at all.
But we did figure out that the state
should be subordinate to the wisdom of
the individual,
to the site,
and the wisdom of the individual puts a
heavy responsibility on everyone.
That mean to you.
Have to be the wise individual who can
see at speed,
that's your job,
and if you do that,
the thing that's so cool about that is
you know you need a meaning in your life
that enables you to bear to the
suffering of their life without becoming
corrupted.
That's the basic rule and you have to
build yourself into something that you
can actually respect so that you can see
yourself bearing that terrible
existential burden properly and then you
don't lose hope.
Don't lose meaning because you can see
that you're strong enough to stand up
underneath that burden and then there's
something about you that you can respect
and then maybe other people can respect
that will help bring suffering in the
world to an end and that will help
people develop fully as individuals and
that will enable us to avoid the
dehumanizing rigid a stair I'll
uniformity of the nationalistic left and
a hallway chaotic devouring chaos of the
radical left.
How about no
the individual?
That's the secret to the world and
you're all individuals.
You're all the secret to the world and
then all you have to do
to discover that is picked up in your
damn responsibility.
Stop listening to people who keep
burdening you with rights.
How many Goddamn right steel?
Why do you need some responsibility?
So pick it up,
open your eyes and learn how to make
yourself articulate and that way the
world will just send them to the series
of health that it already descended into
in the 20th century.
Thank
you.
Well that's probably just as good a
place as any to end.
I think in principle we have time for
questions.
Is that correct?
You?
Okay.
So we'll start with you.
Do you want to use the Mike?
Yeah.
Okay.
So I'd ask you to try to keep your
questions relatively short,
so,
so see if you can get them,
articulate it out to the point where
they can be relatively concise.
So I'm weirdly you.
We're talking about the idea that like
when you see a distinction between
gender and sex and like I'm not saying
right,
like you need are.
You said they are connected and I'm
wondering like the idea that because we
can find an example of a non connected
that means that they necessarily are
connected,
like where does that idea come from?
It comes from wishful thinking.
It comes from.
There's a deep question underneath that
and the wishes that human nature for the
infinitely malleable and that the state
will determine the direction that that
malleability should,
should take.
That's the fun.
That's the unreliable.
Now I suppose there's also a wish to
some degree that we can all burst the
bonds that define us,
you know,
in a particular way that you can ask
yourself if you already want to do that.
One of the things I see happening to
young people that I think is terrible is
that they're asked to abandon their
identity before they even have one,
and so then they turned to these group
identities which are extraordinarily
shallow or very,
very shallow.
How important,
how are we going to get through life
being a transsexual?
It's not an identity.
I'm not saying there are no transexuals.
I'm not saying that,
but you don't get through life as a
black person.
You don't get through life as a white
person.
You get through life by having a
differentiated identity.
That's the toolbox that you use to
interact with others and part of now,
part of that means that you have to
accept certain limitations on who you
are,
but you want those limitations because
there's nothing worse than total
freedom.
It's like you're dropped someone out in
the ocean right in the middle of the
ocean with no direction and you say,
you're free to swim any way you want.
What are you going to do with that?
You're going to have an identity,
so that's good.
Thank you.
How about here?
My blessing.
I just want to say
thank goodness I'm actually a
transplant.
If you put English language,
orange,
apple,
you think any of us could actually be.
Well,
so the question is about gender neutral
pronouns.
Do you think any of us would be here?
The issues that we're discussing would
come up in another way?
No,
because I think.
I think everyone knows that whatever
we're talking about has very little to
do with gender pronouns mean and people
have asked me why I chose deliver data,
let's say on that particular amount.
And it's like,
well the answer to that is you have to
pick some place that's actionable to
stamp.
Right?
And the problem with that is that it
might be somewhat observed while you've
been in a battle.
You know,
it's like,
well,
who cares if you take the next yard of
ground,
why would you die over that?
Well,
when you think about it that way,
it's fair enough.
It's foolish,
but you have to make the abstract
concrete before you can actually engage
with it.
And so it just so happened that this was
the issue.
I do believe that if,
if there were gender neutral pronouns in
English,
then then this will just come up some
other way because political correctness
and the and the polarization between
right and left were occurring long
before this particular issue manifested
itself.
So
yes,
with the glasses,
I'll repeat the questions and then
everybody can hear them.
It'll be a little faster.
Just to start off,
are you familiar with?
Yes.
Okay,
great.
What do you think my medic period,
a usefulness is an understanding our
components that go into how violence is
created.
And then,
um,
can you offer some examples of combating
or opposing the norm of scapegoating
individuals?
Uh,
uh,
because it correct,
and societies and social groups or
strengthened into their violence.
Uh,
how do we drive the wedge between them?
No.
Well,
I think you have to escape the right
thing,
you know,
because the reasonable level,
it's in the world.
That's another thing that we've
forgotten about in modern parlance.
You know,
I've talked about for a very long period
of time is my,
my colleagues tend to look askance at me
because they don't believe in such a
thing.
And I think,
well,
well first of all,
yes,
you do believe in it whether you do or
not.
If you don't bring your heaviness end,
unless you're willing to say for
example,
I think it was unit seven,
nine one,
you guys who don't think distance of
evil,
you go online and read about them at
seven,
nine months and then you see what you
think about that.
If I told you about this done in China
before World War Two by the Japanese,
uh,
scientific investigative squads,
let's say,
that's the sort of thing that the things
that were done by that unit were so
terrible that I would not discuss them
before an audience without a trigger
warning,
because they would burn themselves into
your imagination and you would never
forget them for the rest of your life.
And if you can invest,
I think it was 7:31,
by the way,
if you can investigate that and come to
the conclusion that there's no such
thing as evil,
then that's fine.
You go ahead and live that way and just
see how far it gets.
Um,
so we need to localize malevolence luck.
And the other thing I want to tell you
too,
is that people have encounters with
malevolence in their lives.
And it often produces posttraumatic
stress disorder,
so very frequently soldiers develop
posttraumatic stress disorder,
not because of what they observed,
what they observe themselves doing,
so they observe themselves doing
something absolutely vicious on the
front and they think,
where did that come from?
I didn't think that's who I was at all.
It's like you didn't think so because
you were never in a situation like that.
You've never had a chance to reveal to
yourself exactly what you were light and
then other people can develop.
Post traumatic stress disorder are often
people who have been encountered with
someone who is truly malevolent,
who really truly wanted to hurt,
and there's no room in their philosophy
of being for that sort of that sort of
event or action.
It just fragments them and they never
recover.
They often never recovered.
They have to develop a fully fledged
philosophy of evil in order to recover.
Understand that there are people who are
malevolent and that malevolence exists
in the world.
When you can put it on someone else and
even punish them for it and you can
chase them away and then you can pretend
that it's got,
but it never goes away and the right way
to deal with it is to find the thing in
you that that into work,
to comprehend them,
to control it.
It also,
one of the things that's very
interesting about that is it also makes
you extraordinarily tough if you do it,
and I can give you a pop culture example
of that.
So Harry Potter obviously has an nmp
right,
and that's voldemort and if you can't
see the sale Christ and safety lurking
behind those figures,
then you're really not using your
imagination to any great degree.
There.
Archetype will fingers.
Right?
And the thing about Harry Potter is that
the only reason that he can face photo
artist because he's,
he's got a touch of evil inside of it.
It's embedded inside of it and that's
extraordinarily useful to know that
because it's very useful to be a monster
or more importantly,
it's very useful to be able to be a
monster because if you can be a monster,
you can stand up for yourself or for
anything else.
So the trick is to take that monster
inside of me,
went to incorporate it into using it,
and then you don't have to escape to go
to other people and you can constrain
the spread of eagles starting with
yourself.
And um,
you know,
the people that you admire,
whether you're men or women,
have exactly that.
Ask it because women do not like armless
man.
They like dangerous men who were
civilized and men have no respect for
armless man.
They like dangerous men who are
civilized.
And so the trick for madness to turn
yourself into a dangerous man.
Civilized.
And I would say that the most dangerous
man is the person who can speak
properly.
So I mean,
there's other forms of dangerousness.
There's nothing with physical products.
There's nothing wrong with all of the
multidimensional ways that you could
learn to be dangerous.
But the highest,
the highest order danger is articulated
speech and wealth.
For all these reasons,
it's speech Buddhists in the world.
And so get your scapegoats.
Right?
So you think great deal of time talking
about free speech and political
correctness on campus in the United
States,
we see places like University of Chicago
stand against political correctness,
free speech on campuses in Canada.
Would you say that our universities in
particular and a particular university
departments that have done a good job at
standing up for free speech and standing
up against political correctness on
campus?
Well,
I would say Canada or the sort of
question is that Jonathan Heit and his
people at the end or the Arts Academy
have attempted to rank order American
universities in terms of their
allegiance to classical ideals.
Liking that idea of the people that
enlightenment ideals or free speech free
discourse and the narrative social
justice,
and they put the University of Chicago
at the tall and I think brown was at the
bottom growing university or the talk.
If you're thinking about social justice.
And then
the question was,
what do I think about Canadian?
My answer to that would be Canadian
universities have done such a good job
over the over the decade standing up for
free speech that everyone just takes it
for granted,
but now it's come under threat and I
think it's come under threat because the
postmodern movement,
which basically started in the 19
seventies in which is deeply nested
inside of a matrix of Marxism and
accountant.
The postmodernism themselves poses a
substantial threat to the very idea of
free speech because they don't believe
in free speech.
The postmodernist.
You got to understand these.
The like.
I'm not saying that every social justice
activist is a committed postmodernist
because most of them aren't educated
enough to be that
by saying,
I'm just saying that
it takes a substantial amount of
education before you're the incarnation
of the political philosophy,
right?
You have to do a lot of reading and so I
would say,
you know,
Michel Foucault or Jacques Derrida that
are fragmented up into their tiny little
book suffers no equal pieces of
voldemort soul,
and then they're distributed among the
people who are possessed by that
ideology.
So if you take a particularly someone
who's hyper politically correct,
you'd say,
well,
95 percent of them is normal person,
that's five percent of them is like
Michelle Foodco.
It's the evil offspring of Michelle Fuco
and Jacques Derrida,
and so,
but if then if you put 20
of them together and their mop and you'd
get the whole philosophy blasting
forward,
happy.
Well what?
What's,
what is the philosophy?
The philosophy of commodity?
It's quite straight forward from the
postmodernist perspective.
Value structures exclude,
which of course they didn't,
but they take it further.
They say,
well,
that's the purpose of abandoned
structures to explain.
So if you're an Italian structural
hierarchy,
let's say,
and you have the top positions,
then you're privileged for doing that,
but the reason that that and that you
fight for it is because of privileges
you and does have a part by excluding is
that know that's pushing it a bit too
far.
So like value structure is excluded and
they have because they're not
instructors if they don't exclude.
But to move from that,
to say that the only reason value
instructions exist is to exclude is
palpably observed.
Look,
if you're going to go get your brain
operating on,
you're going to make it a presupposition
that there's a hierarchy of competence
among brain surgeons that's independent
of their desire for power at least
partly,
and you're going to look for the best
brain surgeon just like you look for the
best auto mechanic or or if the best
plumber for the best carpenter,
anything that's worth doing by by by
definition has a value structure
implicit in it,
and of course if there are good
carpenters,
they're also people who aren't good
carpenters.
It's like prejudice to point that out.
It's not prejudice to point that out.
They're just not good carpenters.
Luckily they might be able to be good at
something out well,
so most of our is that now I just
dropped his excluded and that's why they
exist and then what we should do is
flat.
You are limiting things or more
perversely,
I've been saying we should
know that this is where the marks of
Marxism comes into it.
It's very strange,
intellectual slightly that your identity
is defined by your gender or your
sexuality or what ever happens to the
identity issue.
Do sure and and because you're
identifying with that idea and other
people are identifying with other
identities,
there's no way of having a dialogue
between them because well,
for the postmodernists dialogue doesn't
even exist.
There's no way of developing a consensus
between groups that are predicated on
different identities.
The whole idea of consensus through
dialogue is actually a trick that was
generated by the people that you the
most dominant positions and those are
the fellows enter transitions that
they're under always arm about.
Well,
so.
Well it's,
it's,
it's an interesting idea because value
structures are prejudicial.
There's no doubt about it and one of the
ways of thinking about that,
you think you're not prejudice.
It's not yet.
You swimmed with anyone who asks you to
you.
Now,
some of you might say yes and ask very
often,
but,
but I make it very,
very straightforward.
The point here is that in our most
intimate relationships were precisely
most
prejudicial.
You want to take that away from people
or do you want to start knowing that
certain kinds of prejudices and things
that are desirable or valuable or
actually being taken apart,
making intelligent choice so.
Well that was a bit of time for one more
question.
Okay.
So according to what you said earlier,
you pointed out differences between men
and women
and
just following from what you said,
it stands to reason that different ideas
are going to resonate more with women
versus men in general.
So I'll give you the woman studies and
say seek help from therapists a lot more
than men do,
which allows me to positive or negative
feelings you're experiencing and move
through prices a lot better than me
on this.
Another.
Another advantage we have generally
trump dramatic
sort of
crazy situations,
but to what extent do natural
propensities legislatively versus
correct?
Absolutely valid.
Just because man is less likely to.
Doesn't mean that that's
just because of the woman's consent.
Central
judge everyone.
Well,
it's very complicated question,
but if
you listen to the central question is
that given that there are differences
between men and women that say to what
society is structured so that the
negative consequences of those
differences might be in this specific
example,
it was perhaps that women are more
likely to seek medical attention and
psychological health,
which does happen to be the case and
that that's perhaps beneficial.
What would it be better if family we're
more prone to seek help as well and they
have called.
We don't know,
but we could assume that might be the
case.
Well,
let me just think about that for a
second here.
See if I can figure out how to answer
that properly.
I think the way you started this by
trying to figure out what the
differences are first,
you know,
because I always think I'm very leery of
broad scale social solutions because I
think there are so low resolution that
they tend to cause more trouble than
they than they.
They tend to cause more trouble than
they forestall.
We're just at the beginning of starting
to understand what the differences
between men and women actually are.
You know,
like the Scandinavian studies that I
talked about,
there are only about 15 years old and it
isn't,
takes about
15 years for scientific information
generally sort of leach out into the
general public if it's going to do so.
And so the question to what degree the
differences between men and women exist
and to what degree the biological versus
sociological.
It's something that we're just starting
to sort out the next question might be,
okay,
well what did we do in the face of those
differences?
And that sort of that is like I don't
know what we should do about it.
I do think that we should,
we should for,
for go the temptation to jump to
premature conclusions and we have some
real problems with this.
So one of the things that's happening in
many of you may have noticed it is that
men are bailing out of the humanities
and social sciences like map.
You know,
if you,
and this has been happening for about 15
years,
20 years,
I mean overall enrollment in the
humanities is declined substantially and
that's because I think most of what's
being,
and this is all simplified postmodern
nonsense and it's very,
very hard employment and go there and
they have whatever cherished assumptions
they might have fragmentary as they are.
They bring to a humanities class and
have those demolished.
It's like a giant hits your raft with we
have an emerging problem which is what
we're going to do when there's no men
left in the social sciences.
Is that actually going to work because
that I'm not sure of the work.
I guess we're gonna find out and then we
have the inverse problems say with
regards to engineering and women.
Women don't go into engineering well
should it?
Well,
the first question might be who said
that they should come in?
My sense is that what we should do is
open up opportunities for people because
I think the idea of leveling the playing
field to the degree that's possible to
equalize opportunity is a good one from
a sociological perspective because you
don't want talent to go to waste.
Now,
that doesn't mean that doesn't mean that
the way that's done commonly is
intelligent or appropriate because it
often doesn't work at all,
but it is best if we can open up society
so that people can let their talents
flourish.
I would say we remove unreasonable
prejudice to the degree that that's
possible.
When you do that by constraining it in
your own life and then you let people
make their own decisions and let us sort
out the way it will.
And you know when you see that in
Scandinavia,
so you have 19 female nurses to one male
nurse in 19 female engineers,
female engineers,
or maybe that's okay.
Maybe that's all we don't know.
I think individually people that so do
we have time for one market?
We should be stopped.
I think we're just about to
thank you.