This is Jocko podcast number one 55 with
me,
Jocko willink
on the island.
The dead were piling up.
Yeah.
In the mission report,
the head of the convoy wrote at 2:00 PM
on May 20th I went to the island of Xeno
with commander taps golf.
There was a terrible scramble.
People crowding and fighting around the
bags of flour,
dead bodies everywhere.
A hundred or more and lots of people
crawling about and crying give us bread
boss.
It's been two days since we've been
given anything to eat.
They're trying to make us die of hunger
and the cold.
They told us that people had begun
eating the dead bodies,
that they were cooking human flesh.
The scene on the island was dreadful.
Appalling.
On May 21st alone,
the three health officer's counted 70
additional dead bodies in five cases.
They emphasized the liver,
the heart,
the lungs and fleshy part of bodies.
Yeah.
Had been caught off.
On one of the bodies,
the head had been torn off along the,
along with the male genital organs and
part of the skin.
These mutilations constitutes strong
evidence of cannibalistic acts.
In addition,
they suggest the existence of serious
psychopathology.
He's on the same day.
May 21st the deportees themselves
brought us three individuals who had
been caught with blood on their hands
and holding human livers.
Our examination of these three
individuals did not reveal any extreme
NACAC one
and there's an elderly,
local peasant woman who reported the
things we saw.
People were dying everywhere.
They were killing each other.
There was a guard name Kostia the Nico
off a young fellow.
He was courting a pretty girl who had
been sent there.
He protected her.
Yeah.
One day he had to be away for a while
and he told one of his comrades,
take care of her,
but with all the people,
the comrade couldn't do much.
People caught the girl,
tied her to a tree,
cut off her breasts,
her muscles,
everything they could eat.
They were hungry.
They had to eat.
When costs are you came back,
she was still alive.
He tried to save her,
but she had lost too much blood.
She died.
That was the kind of thing that happened
when you went along the island.
You saw flesh wrapped in rags.
Okay.
Human flesh that had been cut.
Yeah.
And hung in the trees.
Okay.
And that right there is from a book
called Cannibal Island by Nicholas
worth,
who's written books about communism.
I think his most famous as the black
book of communism and Cannibal Island
specifically breaks down one of the
small individual nightmares of the
Soviet gulags.
But the nightmare was not small and it
certainly was not specific.
It was widespread and it was broad
and it was almost incomprehensible.
Yeah.
And very little about it would be known
or not for one man,
Alexander Solzhenitsyn,
who not only survive the gulags but
lived on to write incredibly detailed
and very well researched to books about
the gulags.
Some of them were fictionalized
like a day in the life of Ivan
Denisovich and for the,
for the good of the cause,
but most comprehensively in his three
volume tome,
the Gulag archipelago
and this series is,
is a massive series and it's been cut
down to an abridged version that was
actually approved by the author himself.
And the abridged version has just been
rereleased in Europe with a forward by a
man that I think repopulate [inaudible]
that book a man that is here today to
discuss that book.
And among other things,
I'm sure a man that I needed to give an
introduction to the first time he was on
this podcast,
but now who needs no introduction
whatsoever,
a man by the name of Dr. Jordan B.
Peterson.
Jordan,
thank you for coming back on.
How's it rough beginning Jocko.
Jesus.
Uh,
yeah,
I remember when I started listening to
you,
you would say something along the lines
of that,
you know,
we are quite capable of creating hell
for ourselves as human beings and that
clearly that situation.
I don't know.
I mean that's,
that's,
that's hell yeah.
And close enough.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's,
it's created by us.
It's created by us,
which I think is,
um,
obviously horrific and the Gulag
archipelago,
um,
you know,
you,
you talked about that book a lot and,
and one of the things that on that book
hits you hard obviously for me,
uh,
there's a book called about face by
Colonel David Hackworth.
I'm from a different world,
I guess the you in many ways.
The book that hit me hardest in my life
was,
was that book about face and it's,
it's one of those things that when I
read it,
I started putting it together.
It's like things started to fit and
I remember that and I was wondering,
I guess from my perspective,
at what point did you read the Gulag
archipelago and at what point did you
start to say,
okay,
there's something really,
really important here for me to try and
understand?
Well,
I read it back in the 1980s,
early,
I would say I'd read some Solzhenitsyn
before that.
I read the late Dave Dave,
a day in the life of Ivan Denisovich
when I was about 13 or 14.
And then I read the Gulag archipelago in
my early twenties.
When I was reading a lot of
psychological material too,
when I started reading young and Freud
and the great clinicians and uh,
or is reading a fair bit about what had
happened in Nazi Germany at the same
time.
And also Viktor Frankl's man's search
for meaning and Solzhenitsyn's book is
in some ways like an elaborated
extension of Frankel Frankel of course
described what happened to him in the
Nazi concentration camps.
And it's a relatively short book and
it's a great book.
But soldier Nixon's book is,
it's,
it's much broader and,
and I would say deeper.
And the thing that affected me most
particularly was the psychological take
on the,
on the totalitarian states.
You know,
I had been studying political science up
to that point and the political science
scientists and the economists who I
would say we're under the sway of
Marxists thinking,
although not nearly to the degree that
are now,
we're convinced that the reason that
people engaged in conflict was basically
a consequence of argumentation over
resources.
You know,
it was basically an economic argument
and I never bought that.
It never made sense to me.
I mean,
obviously there are circumstances where
that's true,
but it didn't seem to be fundamentally
the case.
Like tribal warfare isn't precisely
about resources.
It's maybe it's about territory or maybe
it's about identity.
But it never seemed to me to be simply
about resources.
Um,
partly because,
well a resource is something that people
value,
but it isn't obvious why people value
what they value.
And so it doesn't solve the fundamental
problem.
Anyways.
When I was reading Frankel and
Solzhenitsyn,
I started to more deeply understand the
relationship between the individual and
the atrocity.
And that's what I found most interesting
was that Frankel's claim and
Solzhenitsyn's claim as well,
that it was the moral corruption of the
citizenry that allowed the totalitarian
catastrophes to occur.
And that that in some sense was the
responsibility of every individual in
the system who looked the other way or
who participated actively.
I mean,
even in the gulag camps themselves,
they were almost all run by the
prisoners.
There wasn't enough administrative
manpower to run the prison system
without the cooperation,
so to speak,
of the prisoners.
So it is,
it is a surreal sort of hell.
Were you in prison yourself and
Solzhenitsyn's fundamental claim,
and this was true for Franklin as well,
and also for Vaclav Havel who eventually
became president of Czechoslovakia,
or at least of the Czech Republic,
I don't remember which,
you know,
they believe that it was the individual
proclivity to accept lies that fostered
the ability of tyrants to destroy the
state.
And then
well,
and that also led to complicitness with
regards to all the absolute atrocities
that were occurring in both the Nazi
state,
in the and in the Soviet state.
And I think that's true when I read,
like I read soldier Knutson's books in
that a lot of the books I read about
Nazi Germany to not as a victim and not
as a hero,
but as a perpetrator,
you know,
which I think it's really important.
It's something that's really important
to do when you read history is that it's
easy to cast yourself as a victim.
It's easy to cast yourself as the person
who would have been heroic in the
circumstance,
but it's also unbelievably useful to
understand that there's a good chance.
Had you been in those situations that
you wouldn't have been on the side of
the good guys and,
no,
and that's a terrible,
it's really a terrible realization,
but it's,
it's necessary realization.
Again,
just going back to this idea of what you
out of reading,
because people
ask me now because I read books all the
time on my podcast and what you just
said,
it struck me as something that's,
people have told me,
I read that book before but I didn't
really get out of it.
What you got out of it and when I heard
you read it I,
I was saying,
wow,
how did I need to go reread this book?
And I think one of the key things is you
looked at these books as you were not
the victim,
but the perpetrator.
One thing that when I read books,
I know I read a lot of books,
mostly about war for me,
I always think about the,
the people,
I don't know.
We see myself as the person that goes
and heroically storms the beaches and
survives every,
you know,
in a war book.
There's these people that get mentioned
for it,
for a half a paragraph,
for,
for two sentences.
And that sometimes they don't even have
a name because you know,
you're the battalion commander is
storming the beach of Normandy.
You don't,
you're not going to name every single
person.
But for some reason,
and maybe it's just my experiences of,
of being in combat,
when I read about that two sentences of
that guy,
that that gets shot,
that gets killed,
that gets blown up.
I completely understand and relate to
that person.
Like I,
I don't just see it as me being the guy
that is always winning and always doing
okay and always surviving.
I feel and relate to those guys that
didn't.
And,
and part of that is just because of my
friends that I lost in combat.
Like those guys,
they're their people.
And I think that key thing of,
of reading it and going,
man,
every single person,
like when you read about these groups,
you're talking about millions of people
that were tortured,
died,
murdered.
Every one of those people.
Keyword is people.
Every one of those people is a person.
And to your point,
every single one of those executioners,
every single one of those murderers is
also a purse.
You know,
there's a great book called ordinary
men.
Oh yeah,
we,
we reviewed that on this podcast.
Right,
right.
And so,
you know,
it's,
it's one of the greatest books written
about what happened in the Second World
War,
I think on the end of,
on the atrocity and [inaudible] because
the author does such a lovely job of,
well,
it's a strange way of putting it in this
context,
but you know,
it's about this police battalion that
was moved into Poland after the Germans
went through and,
and occupied the country and they were
there to establish order like police do,
but also to participate in the mopping
up,
let's say.
Uh,
that was part and parcel of the war.
And you know,
these were ordinary policemen.
Um,
middleclass guys,
most of whom had been educated and
socialized before the Nazi propaganda
machine really got rolling.
So they weren't like Hitler youth types.
Um,
they were ordinary men and they were
brought and they had a commander who had
made an explicit case that if they
weren't able to tolerate the conditions
in Poland that they could go home.
So there was no top down order that you
had to do this or else.
And then they were,
you know,
first of all they started rounding up
while mostly Jewish people,
men between 18 and 65 and then,
you know,
they started to participate in the
entire atrocious mess and they were,
they ended up many of them taking naked
pregnant women out into fields and
shooting them in the back of the head.
And what the author does is outline how
that happens to you,
you know,
one step at a time.
And so it's a really horrifying book and
it's a brilliant book because there's no
attempt to make the perpetrators like
some creatures that aren't human,
like just pure psychopath.
And of course in in,
in an situation like Nazi Germany and,
and in the horrors of the communist
states,
there was no shortage of places for
psychopaths to prevail.
But that's not really the issue.
The issue is,
well,
how does an ordinary person come to
participate in a global horror,
let's say?
And what does that mean about being an
ordinary person?
And then the next question is,
well,
what does it mean about how you should
conduct your life?
And one of the things that,
I mean,
I think what happened to me when I read
all this material in the 80s was that I
became convinced that there wasn't
anything more important to do in the
aftermath of what had happened in the
20th century than to try to build people
who were responsible enough as truth
telling courageous,
responsible citizens so that the
probability would increase,
that if they were in a position to make
a terrible choice,
that they would make the right one.
And I would say this lecture tour that
I'm doing,
which has now extended over more than a
hundred cities,
is an extension of the same thing.
Well,
I think it's the same thing that you're
trying to do with your book.
Like we were just looking at your Mickey
and the dragons book,
right?
And you're trying to lay out,
um,
uh,
psychological pathway that guides people
towards responsibility and courage and
truth and all of that.
And that is the bulwark against tyranny.
And it's actually the,
it's actually at the individual level.
And we kind of know that we,
we know that in the West.
I think that's part of the core ethos
of,
well certainly that of the English
common law system certainly of,
of the American way of looking at the
world is that each citizen is the
bulwark against tyranny.
And that's actually true.
It's,
and,
and that's a terrible thing to,
to think through because it means that
you are responsible for the integrity or
lack thereof of your state.
And it's,
it's on you,
you know,
and,
and there's something great about that
because it means that your existence
actually matters to you and to your
family and to the broader community in a
really major way,
in a way that's much more significant
than you might think.
And that the,
your proclivity to abdicate your moral
responsibility echoes way farther than
you might consider,
especially under some circumstances,
you know,
and soldier Nitsa.
And one of the things that's so amazing
about the Gulag archipelago is his
stories not only of the absolute bloody
catastrophe of the Soviet state and his
incredibly astute documentation of the
role that the utopian,
political and philosophical assumptions
of Marxism played in creating the
system,
right?
It wasn't an aberration,
it was a direct,
logical consequence of that collectivist
viewpoint.
And to document all that,
but also to tell endless stories about
people who were able,
at least to some degree,
to not become corrupted,
even under unbelievably horrific
conditions,
you know?
And,
and that's something you also get out of
Viktor Frankl's book man's search for
meaning,
you know,
and um,
and so the,
the Gulag archipelago is a story about
horror in some sense,
but it's more a story of the triumph of
the fundamental triumph of the human
spirit and perhaps no more,
uh,
perhaps most evident in the case of
soldier.
And it's an himself because he memorized
this book in some sense while he was in
the camps and then wrote it under
extreme duress afterwards.
And it's an immense undertaking and it's
unbelievably emotionally intense.
The entire book.
It's like one,
you know,
1700 page scream of outrage.
He just can hardly believe that someone
can write at that white hot intensity
for such a long period of time.
And you know,
his book had an unbelievable global
impact.
I think it's sold 30 million copies and
it definitely,
for at least a reasonable period of time
made it completely untenable for,
um,
utopian resentful,
Utopian intellectuals to ethically
justified their radical leftist
collectivism.
It,
it just blew the slats out from
underneath any ethical credibility that
communism,
that,
that remained of the communist doctrine
by the 1970s and that that's a hell of a
thing for someone to manage on their
own.
Pretty big task.
Uh,
so while you were going through that,
I was thinking myself,
so as I was talking to,
I still talk to military folks and I was
talking to some military leaders,
young leaders,
so like platoon level and company level
leaders.
So these are guys that are in charge of
you know,
40 guys or maybe 150 guys
and,
and you know,
you can have some real ethical problems.
And,
and one of the things that I said to
this group was I said,
hey,
in your s in your platoon,
you've got a murderer in your platoon,
you've got someone in your platoon that
is a sadist.
And the,
they were kind of looking at me,
um,
suspect,
you know,
a little bit like,
oh come on now,
come on.
What are you talking about?
How big is the platoon?
A platoon is 40 guys and stuff like
that.
And I was,
I was actually going to ask you how
accurate I was and then I was going to
actually say that no matter what you
say,
how accurate is even if it was,
even if it was one out of every
thousand,
you have to act as a leader,
as if in your platoon you've got one of
those guys are two of those guys.
That's a way you need to look.
And there's another book called the Rape
of Nan King.
We've covered that.
So one of the things that was really
horrifying about that book is,
so imagine that there's maybe,
let's say that there's one in a hundred
just for the sake of argument that's
really got cruel and psychopathic
traits.
What,
what do you think professionally?
What do you think that number is?
I think 1% isn't unreasonable and it
could be higher than that.
I mean,
there's gradations,
right?
Yeah.
There's probably in a group of 40
people,
there's going to be one guy in there
who's proclivity in that direction is
sufficiently strong so that you better
keep an eye on him,
that's for sure.
And this is a group of people that
joined the military,
right?
So they're already,
you know,
you've already gotten,
you've already got a group that's okay
with,
with theoretically having to kill other
people.
So this is probably,
you know,
so if it's 100 islands,
that's likely an underestimate.
So I think your estimate is perfectly
reasonable and it might be conservative.
What happened in Nan king was that the
most sadistic people became the targets
of imitation and emulation.
And that's when things really get out of
hand.
Yeah.
Right.
So,
and that's the same thing to me,
Lai massacre and,
and that was it.
So,
so when I was talking to this group and
I'm getting it,
I said to him,
I said,
you're looking at me like right now.
Like,
I'm like,
I don't know what I'm talking about.
It like I'm crazy.
Who knows about the mee Lai massacre
and,
and you know,
all of a sudden it got quiet because if
you know anything about the mee Lai
massacre,
it was a normal group of guys.
It was a normal group of guys.
It was a normal company of American
soldiers.
And you know what,
they'd been through some stress they'd
been through,
you know,
they'd,
they'd had their friends killed and it
was in Vietnam.
There was no one really to react against
or to,
to,
to take your aggression out on because
the enemy,
you couldn't see them.
They would hide.
And it was,
but then they turned and they snapped.
And the same thing you had the leader,
um,
a guy named lieutenant calley who was
the platoon leader who eat,
Yo,
I'd love for you to do a psychological
profile media who used one of these guys
that was kind of like it was it totally
insecure about everything.
And so he got those shoulder boards on,
which is the way,
which is the way Solzhenitsyn,
he describes his,
his experience as being a platoon leader
and what it did to him.
And he goes through that.
This book is fantastic to hear.
When he talks about what he did,
he knew he was looking back saying,
oh,
I did this and I didn't listen to this
little rampage of things that he,
how he acted as a commander.
I ate the food,
the good food right in front of my guys
when they weren't getting for,
I was getting the good food and he did
took advantage of all the little,
all the little comforts that you got
being an officer and you know what?
Yeah,
well he was trying and in the whole
book,
and especially in that section,
which I think is in volume two,
which I think is the greatest of the
three volumes,
especially the last half of it,
which is just absolutely,
it's,
it's genius level writing,
unbelievably compelling and brilliant
and yeah,
I mean he,
he said that when he was in the camps
that one of the things that he did,
especially once he started to identify
people that he truly admired,
was to go over his life with a fine
tooth comb and try to try to remember
everything that he did wrong by his own
estimation,
and then try to set it right in some
manner.
And so there was a,
that's a repentance and then a
redemption,
right?
There's,
there's a real,
there's a real fundamental,
like a medieval Christian undertone to
all of that.
But it was one of the things that's
quite interesting is that when you talk
about issues that are this serious,
you're almost inevitably in a situation
where you're going to find yourself
compelled to use some kind of quasi
religious language because you end up
discussing good and evil and,
and issues of redemption in issues of
repentance and issues of conscience and
sin and all of that.
There isn't language that's deep enough
to get at it otherwise.
And what Solzhenitsyn did was scour his
conscience and try to put himself
together partly because he was shamed.
He was ashamed of himself in the face of
these extraordinarily extraordinary
people who seem to be able to keep their
moral compass under circumstances where
no one should ever assume that they
would keep their moral compass.
Because certainly,
like I said,
when I was reading this,
the Gulag and other books like that,
I never assumed that if I was in those
situations that I would have been one of
the people who kept their head.
And we're able to withstand the
temptation to become a trustee,
for example,
and to take things the easy way and to
Lord it over the other prisoners and to,
and to adopt that position of authority.
You know,
it's like,
it's like a head slave among slaves,
but you know,
you could say,
well better to be the head slave than to
be the bottom slave.
And while that's true in some sense with
regards to creature comfort,
but as Solzhenitsyn point out points
out,
it might be a little bit hard on your
soul.
And that actually turns out to be
something of,
of crucial,
not only crucial,
important psychologically,
but crucial importance sociologically
and politically.
Because if you sacrifice that,
then you work the structure around you,
which is exactly what happened in the
establishment of these camps,
you know?
And the,
the,
the Soviet Union was just one big lie.
What was their old joke?
They pretend to pay us and we pretend to
work.
It's like
the,
the whole,
the whole book and the whole Soviet
Union.
When you,
when you read about it now,
it seems like it's,
it seems like a bad joke.
It seems like a bad movie you could with
just the way,
the way that Stalin would do something
and,
and the way that that order would come
down.
It seems like one of those cheesy,
um,
you know,
comedic movies about these decisions
that they're making and it's surreal.
It's completely,
it's completely insane.
You know,
at one point he's talking about the,
there was a,
a new penalty for when they call it sh
clipping corn or,
or they're basically a 12 year old kid
would be starving and you'd go into a
field of wheat and clip a cure.
A,
a core,
an ear of corn.
Yeah.
That happened in the Ukraine during the
dq localization.
Right.
It was against the law to go out after
the fields were,
were harvested.
It was against the law to go out and
pick grain off the ground to feed your
family.
Right.
And the prison sentence was like a
tenor,
which is their little word for 10 years.
So you're going to get you,
you steal a piece of corn or you've
picked up corn off the ground and you're
getting 10 years.
Yep.
You can't comprehend that.
It's very hard to conation.
Yep.
Worked.
And they were the,
the,
you know,
he does in the earlier parts of the book
when he starts going through the trials
that they were doing on people,
it's completely crazy.
King Kong,
CAFCA.
Well that's why I hate to see the
kangaroo courts emerging all over,
all over the west,
you know,
and,
and with the university sort of at the
forefront of that.
So we're,
we're building these alternative court
systems constantly that don't follow
standard legal procedure and it's
really,
we're messing with things that,
that we shouldn't be messing with.
And Yeah,
the whole,
I mean,
there are,
there are accounts,
I believe it's in the Gulag of,
of,
of applause after Astellas,
the speech,
right.
Where people would stand up and applaud
and they,
and they'd applaud until,
until literally the old people were
falling over.
Because if you were the first person to
stop applauding,
then you were,
well,
it was off to the camps with you.
No,
he absolutely outlines.
So that sounds so crazy to say.
And he outlines a specific thing that
happened.
Is that right there?
These no one will stop applauding.
Yeah,
because they're afraid they're going to
get ratted out by there.
By,
by everyone else.
Yeah.
Well Ben and by the people who are in
fact watching.
And I mean,
you know what,
by by the end,
by,
by the,
by the collapse of East Germany,
one third of the people were in fort
informers for the state.
And so if you had a family of six
people,
two of your family members were direct
government.
Informers you know,
and it's,
it's,
so,
it's creepy in some sense.
It's a very weak word to use in this
situation.
But I'll go,
when I was at New York University
talking to Jonathan Heit about,
I dunno,
it was about few months ago,
um,
he just wrote that book called the
coddling of the American mind,
you know,
and uh,
he took me into one of the men's
washroom stair and there was a poster on
the wall asking students to turn each
other in four instances of bias or
offensive speech.
And they have a whole bureaucracy that's
designed to do nothing else but
adjudicate these instances of biased
speech.
And these posters are up on the walls as
if this is something to be proud of.
You know,
and the same thing is happening now in
Scotland with the Scottish police are
doing exactly the same thing.
They're asking citizens to turn each
other in for,
for hate crimes,
you know.
And the problem with that is the
fundamental problem with that and the,
the unsolvable problem is,
well,
who defines hate and,
and,
and where's,
where's the line drawn?
It's like,
well,
anything that upsets me that you say is
hate that.
And then it's worse than that.
It's like what happens is the people who
define hate ended up being those who are
looking to take offense so that they can
find someone they can define as a
victimizer so that they can persecute
them morally and justify that interstate
ism.
And those are the people who end up
defining the laws and then they match
this with the morality saying,
well,
we're doing this to make our society a
safe place.
It's absolutely,
it's,
it's absolutely dreadful.
And to see that happening in the UK was
just,
it's just awful because I mean,
you know,
the UK is a center,
a center,
the center point of,
of the idea of free speech.
I mean a lot of America,
obviously a lot of American ideals of
America is a great center of free
speech.
But I mean,
it's a variation on the English system.
So to see that happening in the UK is
just,
it's awful.
And to see the police doing this and
being,
you know,
I'm encouraged by the politicians and,
and,
and to see this put forward as some sort
of moral action.
It's just,
well,
it's,
it's an echo of this kind of catastrophe
that,
that we're discussing.
So I think about that sometimes.
And I also have a tendency to look at
things in La,
not be too worried about it.
Like,
Hey,
c'mon,
yeah,
but what's really going on?
Yeah.
Right.
And that's,
yeah,
that's actually part of my personality.
And part of that comes from my old job
where,
hey,
I can't worry about these little things.
Oh,
there's some little problem going on
over there.
That's not going to be,
that's not going to affect us.
It's not going to have,
you've got to pay attention a little
bit,
make sure it doesn't get out of hand.
But that thing about speech and,
and you just mentioned the,
uh,
the Kulak is that to lax?
Yeah.
Yup.
They were the Ukrainian,
they were the Ukrainian farmers who were
good at farming.
When I read this part,
um,
it got me worried about my own personal
lackadaisical attitude towards things
that I think all that's not big of a
deal.
Let me,
let me read this little section about
the,
about the escalation of the word Kulak
Yep.
And,
and where it started and where that,
yeah,
that's good.
So here we go.
Um,
in Russian,
a Kulak is a miserly,
dishonest rural trader who grows rich
not by his own labor,
but through someone else's.
Yeah.
In every locality,
even before the revolution.
Such cool acts could be numbered on
one's fingers and the revolution totally
destroyed their basis of activity.
Subsequently,
after 1917 by a transfer of meaning,
the name Kulak began to be applied to
all those who in any way hired workers,
even if it was only,
even if it was only when they were
temporarily short of working hands in
their own families.
But then that doesn't stop there.
The inflation of this scaling.
The term of this scathing term coop
Kulak proceeded relentlessly and by 1930
all strong peasants in general.
We're being so called all peasants
strong in management,
strong in work,
or even strong merely in convictions.
The term Kulak was used to smash the
strength of the peasantry and I got to,
I got to go a little bit further because
hell of a good thing for the workers
party to do.
Aim Crazy.
Yeah.
They went further though.
Beyond this in every village there were
people who in one way or another had
personally gotten in the way of the
local activists.
Okay.
This was the perfect time to settle
accounts with them of jealousy,
envy,
and insult.
These are the people you were just
talking about.
A new word was needed for these new
victims as a class and it was born by
this time.
It had no social or economic content
whatsoever,
but it had a marvelous sound pop Kulak
Nick,
and that meant a person eating the cool
acts.
In other words,
I consider you an accomplice of the
enemy.
Yup.
And that's all it.
Yeah.
Well,
one of the things I tried to outline in
my forward to the abridged version was I
was thinking about this idea of oddly
enough,
about intersectionality,
which is,
uh,
like social justice idea.
You know,
that the social justice ideas that were
best defined by our collective identity
and that the proper narrative in
relationship to our collective identity
is one of victim victimizer,
which is a replay of the old Marxist
doctrine of bourgeoisie and proletariat.
It's just in its new guys.
Um,
I mean in that new guys developed,
at least in part,
in response to the Gulag archipelago
because the old proletariat bourgeoisie
distinction became morally untenable.
So it just went underground and
underwent this transformation.
The intersectional theorists point out
that your status as a victimizer or a
victim is actually the intersection of
your multiple identities.
And so,
and that's actually the Achilles heel of
the collectivist notion.
And we can get into why that is,
but there's a horror that goes along
with that,
that people,
that's not obvious,
that I think contributed to exactly why
the Russian revolution went so horribly
wrong.
And that is that.
So imagine that I could characterize you
along five or six different dimensions
of group identity.
It's pretty easy.
And while you're male,
you're male of a certain age,
you're male of a certain age and
economic class,
you're,
you have a certain sexual orientation,
you have a certain ethnicity,
you have a certain race that's six
groups right there.
And we could continue,
you know,
your parents had a certain socioeconomic
class and so did your grandparents,
and then your ethnic group had a certain
privilege or lack thereof,
then you're attractive or you're not
attractive and you're intelligent or
you're not intelligent.
And there's temple men,
temperamental variability.
Like there's all sorts of ways of
characterizing you according to your
group.
Okay.
Now we might say that if we were
compassionate people that we would take
one of those group identities are more,
and look at where your dispossessed and
victimized.
Okay.
And we're gonna find some dimension
along which are less privileged than
some people.
Like maybe you come from a working class
background despite the fact that you're
like a straight male.
And so you can be a victim on that
dimension.
And so that's kind of,
that's at least in part an element of
intersectional theory,
right?
And that may be your,
your,
your oppression is the product of,
of your multiple victim,
like identities.
But that can easily be reversed because
it's absolutely the case that I can take
any person and I can do add
multidimensional analysis of their group
identities and I can find at least one
dimension along which there the
perpetrator,
not the victim,
they're the victimizer,
not the victim.
And as soon as I can identify a
dimension along which there a
victimizer,
then that justifies their persecution.
And so one of the things that you saw
happening in the Russian revolution,
and it's very much akin to what you just
described,
was that the,
the,
the borders of who who was validly
accused of being a victimizer
essentially expanded to include every
once.
And,
and that's actually right in,
it's in a,
in a perverse sense,
it's right.
Because if you position yourself
properly in the historical flow,
then you should see yourself as a
perpetrator and a victim equally.
Well,
it's not the right way to see yourself
at all.
But if you're going to play that game,
you're going to be on both sides of it.
And then that issue is,
and this is related to your idea about,
you know,
in your platoon,
you've got one person who sadistic.
It's like,
okay,
well let's even assume that at the
beginning of the Russian revolution,
that the vast majority of the people who
were motivated by communism were
actually compassionate with regards to
the dispossessed peasantry.
Now,
I don't believe that,
but we could say that that was even a
significant minority.
Well,
the question is,
do you just say on it,
what was your,
uh,
hypothetical percentage?
Well,
let's say,
well,
let's say it's 20% or let's even say
it's 50% of people who are genuinely
motivated by compassion for the
dispossessed,
but then there's another minority.
Maybe we could even say it was only 10%
to begin with who weren't motivated by
that at all.
They were motivated by the jealousy and
the spite and the,
and the,
and the resentment that Solzhenitsyn
describes.
And they were the ones who are after
those to be persecuted.
And the thing is they got the upper hand
really rapidly.
And it might be because the carnivorous
types,
the predatory types are much more
dangerous and powerful than the
compassionate types.
Like they'll take them out instantly.
We're,
we're,
we're willing to step up and smash
someone.
Yes.
Most of the people that are saying,
oh,
we just want to help.
Yes,
exactly.
Well,
and,
and there,
there's someone I actually cited a guy
named,
I think his name was walter lots us in
the forward who,
who wrote,
uh,
wrote in a journal called red terror
that if you were interrogating an enemy
of the state,
you didn't bother with niceties like
their individual guilt.
That was a barrage waze,
uh,
um,
conceit.
And that's,
that's really important thing to keep in
mind.
What you want it to do is to do a class
based analysis and find out,
well,
are they a member of let's say the Kulak
or the affiliates of the [inaudible],
which is a lovely way of expanding your
list of potential victims and then you,
you execute accordingly.
And that would mean,
well,
the person that you're interrogating,
right?
Or The class member that you're
interrogating and then their children
and perhaps also their grandchildren and
lots of himself was eventually executed
by the Stellan.
As somebody wrote to me after I wrote
the foreword and told me that that was
his eventual fate.
And I thought,
well,
talk about standing on a chair and
putting the new surround your own neck
and kicking it out from underneath you.
It's like,
you know,
he basically,
he murdered himself fundamentally and,
and you know,
you could say in some sense that was the
story of the Soviet Union to a,
to a tremendous degree.
There's one part going back to the ever
expanding,
um,
people that need to be destroyed.
There was a point in,
in the book where he starts,
he's saying,
hey,
look,
there's insects Stalin's describe,
or maybe it was lennon was describing
these certain people as insects that
needed to be destroyed.
And then he just,
that that just starts off with,
hey,
people that are rabble rousers yeah,
they're insects.
And,
and then it just expands and expands and
then it's got priests and then it's got
engineers and physicians.
Everyone in suckers.
Yeah.
Rec Records.
That's the,
that's the word that they use or that he
uses in the book for a,
for basically saboteurs.
Yeah.
And that expands beyond comprehension.
Because at every single problem that
there is,
is the fault of some person out there
that sabotage and,
and they,
they do this show trial and he talks
about it in the book for,
I think that,
I think the phrase that he uses or that
they use at the rush that the Soviets
used was organizers of the famine.
Meaning like,
Oh yeah,
you're starving.
And these people over here,
they're the reason you're,
these are the people that organize the
famine.
They're the,
they're the records of production of
food.
And you bet,
you bet.
Well,
it was either that,
you know,
you imagine that you,
you,
you adopt a worldview and that worldview
enables you to,
at least in principle,
organize yourself with other people and
to provide you with a certain amount of
psychological stability.
And then things go dreadfully wrong.
And then you have a choice which is to
reevaluate your worldview,
which is of course what social needs and
does in the gulag.
Archipelago in a very deep ways
reorganized his entire worldview.
Um,
or you can look for reasons why you're
right and,
and these things are happening.
And Solzhenitsyn talks a lot in the
Gulag archipelago about,
see he had a moral condone drum when he
was in prison and he started his moral
awakening,
let's say.
And he was trying to figure out how to
treat other people who were imprisoned.
He had a real moral conundrum when a
committed communist was dragged into the
Gulag system,
which happened all the time.
And he said those people were in
particularly dire straits because not
only had they been subject to the entire
tyrannical weight of the deceitful
state,
but it was at the hands of their own
comrades and friends.
And then the,
the,
the committed communists would enter the
Gulag and they would still be in there
morally superior phase,
right.
That,
that their incarceration was a mistake
and that things would be set right.
And that there was nothing wrong with
the system and they would attempt to
justify it.
And Solzhenitsyn was no,
never sure how to react to these people
ethically because on the one hand,
while they were,
you know,
devastated because now they were
political prisoners and maybe they got a
20 year sentence and they were in
terrible,
you know,
stripped of their family and just
ruined.
But on other hand,
they were still avid supporters of the
very fist that had crushed them.
And so his eventual conclusion was that
until they broke and repented,
they,
they weren't to be allied with,
they were still essentially on the side
of the wall of the perpetrator.
And it seems to me that,
that that's right,
that's,
that's unrepentant sin,
let's say.
And it isn't till you,
what would you say?
Until you take responsibility for your
own complicitness in your,
in your unfair interrogation that you
get to join the ranks of,
of,
of valuable in suffering humanity again.
And so,
yeah.
Yeah.
It's the,
the extension of the persecution is
really something that's horrifying to
see how,
who constituted a victimizer the ranks
of who constituted victimizer.
Just grew and grew and grew and grew.
One of the most shocking groups of
people that ended up in the gulags were
the dam Soviet soldiers that had just
got
back home fighting,
just including you can't make up.
They can't make that up on committing
assaults and mission,
who was like in close combat with the
enemy.
And he wrote a letter to one of his
buddies and said,
yeah,
this doesn't seem like to be a great
decision by Stalin.
Yup.
And next thing you know he's,
he's in.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well this stolen,
stolen,
decided that,
yeah,
this is something that you,
you,
you can't,
you can't believe this while it is,
there is this,
like,
it's like,
you know,
if there's something,
say titanic at the bottom of this,
you know,
mythologically speaking,
there's also something that's like a
cosmic,
it's like cosmic black humor.
It's like the sign on Auschwitz that
said work will set you free.
You know,
that's a joke,
right?
It's a whole,
it's a terrible,
terrible,
dark joke.
And so much of this has the element of,
of exactly that kind of surreal,
I hate to say humor,
but it's,
it's right.
I mean stolen decided that the,
okay,
so the Soviet prisoners of war were not
covered by the Geneva Convention for the
treatment of prisoners of war.
Castelan re refused to sign that
agreement.
So like if you were an allied prisoner
of the Germans,
it wasn't like you were having a great
time of it.
Like food was in short supply and you
were treated pretty brutally.
But the Soviets were kept separately and
they were doing so badly that the allies
used to throw food packets over the
fence when that was an option.
So the Soviet prisoners of war were
treated absolutely dreadfully and
Estelle and didn't care about that.
Um,
and then when they were released and
went back to the Soviet Union,
his dictum was that because they had
been exposed to the capitalist West or
even the Nazi west for that matter,
that they had now been intolerably
corrupted on ideological grounds and had
to be put in the prison camps.
So that was the,
that was your destiny as you know.
I mean,
first of all,
you were frontline Russian soldier,
which was just brutal beyond belief.
Their army was completely unprepared for
Hitler's invasion because Stellan
trusted Hitler in his strange way.
And so they were completely unprepared.
And of course then fighting the Soviet
Union with its winters.
I mean,
you just,
you just can't imagine what that must
have been like.
And then to be thrown in a prisoner of
war camp at the bottom of the rung and
then to be brought back to your country
and then to be imprisoned as a trader
because as a class you'd been exposed to
the wrong ideology.
It's like you just,
it's,
it's unimaginably vile and surreal at
the same time.
And it,
it,
you shake your head for me,
while it's such a shock to read the
Gulag archipelago,
it,
you just can't,
it's,
it's like a,
it isn't,
it's like Dante's inferno.
It's like a trip into hell
and,
yeah.
And I guess your,
that's what I was trying to say when we,
when we started this conversation,
I was trying to say that it's like
you're watching this,
uh,
like,
like you said,
it's like a bad comedy movie and you'd
think,
well that's,
that'd be really that you'd think,
you know,
when you,
when you take a comedy,
well,
one of the things,
one of the ways you can make people
laugh is take something ordinary and
maybe make it much more extreme in the
more extreme you make it,
the more funny it becomes.
That's what like happened here.
You're looking at this thing going,
hey,
oh yeah.
They seem to be trying to make this
funny because who in could ever conceive
that you could take your frontline
soldiers who were captured and in misery
and when they return home instead of
treating them like heroes,
instead you put them back into a prison.
Worst one,
you can't even,
that's just,
that's it.
You can't make this stuff.
You can't make it up.
Did you see?
I believe that movie was the death of
Stalin did.
I did not see it.
But that's
worth seeing because it's,
it's very interesting because one of the
things about that movie is that it
captures that surreal element because
it's a black comedy,
you know,
and,
and there are comical things happening
in the movie in that terrible dark way
constantly at the same time that in the
background,
genuinely terrible things are happening.
So it's that horrible.
It's that it's,
it's got that horrible satirical flavor
that runs through books like the Gulag
archipelago where you think,
well,
there's just no,
this is so absurd that there's no
possible way it could have occurred.
And yet that's not only did it happen,
there was like a contest to top the
absurdity,
you know,
to to,
to consider the engineers for example,
records is,
well these people were building the
Soviet system to the degree that it was
built and then to turn around and accuse
exactly those people of being the ones
who destroy and undermine it.
It's,
it's part of,
I really think that what's what
underlies this,
whatever this is.
And I think this is what manifests
itself in the worst of the leftist
collectivism is a real hatred for
anything that smacks of competence at
all.
Like I,
I tried to imagine those Russian
villages because I come from a small
town,
a small northern town too.
So I kind of,
I tried to imagine,
so imagine that you're in an isolated
village and um,
it's a peasant village and the peasants
weren't fried that long ago,
right?
They were basically surfs until,
until about the middle of the second
half of the 19th century.
And so they had been emancipated.
And then some of those people who are
emancipated,
God,
a little bit of land and started to have
a life,
you know,
it started to be successful peasants and
they were also the people that grew the
bulk of the crops.
Because what you see happening in any
productive domain is that a small
percentage of people do almost all the
productive work.
So there's a small percentage of
productive farmers who grow all the
crops,
right?
And then there's all sorts of farmers
who were only farmers by name and they
weren't successful at all.
So you have,
and then there was a certain
relationship between being productive as
a farmer and developing wealth.
Maybe you had a house and maybe you
could hire a person or two,
you know,
and which you'd think would be actually
be a good thing,
especially if you are also growing food.
Okay?
So you imagine you,
you get a village and now there's a bit
of a socioeconomic pyramid and there's
some people that are doing well and
there are really and there.
And it isn't the crooked people that are
really annoying that people who like the
genuine Kulaks,
let's say that that small percentage of
psychopathic types who were basically
profiting criminally off the efforts of
others.
Those aren't so annoying.
Those people,
because they're rich,
but they don't deserve it.
And so they don't stand towards you as a
moral ideal that shames you.
But the really annoying people are the
ones who are doing well and deserve it.
Especially if you're someone who's doing
nothing and is bitter.
Okay?
So now,
so there's the village and you've got
your people who are doing all right and
then you've got a huge strout.
If people who aren't upset about the
people who are doing well,
they might even admire them and be happy
that they're around because they're
making the community thrive and growing
some food.
Then you have this little,
this little,
uh,
strata at the bottom of people who are
ne'er do wells and on the more
psychopathic end of things.
And they are bitter and resentful and,
and waiting for their bloody
opportunity.
And then the communist intellectuals
come into town and say,
you know,
those people that are doing well,
they actually,
everything they've got is ill gotten and
they,
they stole it and they stole it from
you,
from you.
Like,
and look at how badly you're doing and
the reason you're doing badly.
It's because these,
these people who are lording it over you
and who have all this creature comfort,
they took that from you.
It's yours by,
right?
And so then all that resentment and
jealousy and hatred and rage,
alcohol fueled as you might well
imagine,
has this moral,
uh,
reason to go with pitchforks and,
and in a mob and surround those houses
and to strip them of everything they
have.
And to rape the women and to kill the
occupants or to ship them off to the
middle of Siberia when there,
where they froze to death because there
were no,
or died of dysentery or,
or,
or whatever other plague managed to,
you know,
weave its way through these camps.
And so you have the,
you have the intellectuals providing the
moral rationale for the worst ethical
actors in these small villages doing the
worst possible things under the guise of
compassion.
Right?
And that's part of that victim
victimizer narrative.
It's just,
and,
and you knew,
you could imagine that you can imagine a
dark night,
you can imagine the winter,
you can imagine the alcohol,
you can imagine the rage that fuels
these people who are drinking too much
in the pubs that have been sitting there
for the last 20 years.
Like,
what would you say?
Eating up their own souls with
resentment and bitterness.
And then someone comes in and says,
you're the true victim here,
and here's the people that you can go
after.
And then like,
if you play that on your imagination,
you get some real sense of exactly what
sort of horror that would produce.
You know,
you think about the rape for example,
or,
or just the theft or,
but,
but it's the rape that you can really
think about as,
as absolute revenge for all that bitter
resentment.
All fueled by the fact that,
you know,
you'd sat there for the last 20 years
being completely goddamn useless and
better and,
and,
and angry and,
and fantasizing about the day that would
come where you'd have your opportunity,
God and then the whole country,
then that was the whole country.
Oh,
it's just unbelievable.
Yeah.
And I,
I think,
uh,
he,
he spells that out very clearly.
And he says it's,
you know what he's saying?
You know,
I'm saying that you've got a psychopath
and your platoon,
he saying that psychopath,
all that psychopath needs to flip is,
is the someone to tell them that that's
the right thing to do.
And that's exactly what happened.
What'd you just say?
That's it.
Oh yeah.
Those guys that were slightly
psychopathic.
Yeah.
And then it becomes,
okay,
I'm the,
I'm the head psychopath and you're in my
village and you're,
let's say you're one of those people
that are in the middle.
Well,
whose side are you going to be on?
I'm a psychopath.
If you,
if you're not on my side,
I'm going to kill you next.
So you go,
well,
no,
I'm on your side too.
And that's definitely,
it doesn't say,
look,
it's not like it takes much pressure on
people to have them fold.
I mean,
one of the things you see,
you see happening right now in our
cultures that's happening to people all
the time with these twitter wars.
You know,
someone will say something,
they'll express an opinion and then
they'll get mobbed by and,
but only abstractly.
Right?
It's not like there's pitchfork wielding
mobs at their house and I'm not making
light of it.
It's,
no,
it's no pleasant thing to be mobbed on
twitter.
But that's,
that's an obstruction compared to these
people showing up at your house,
you know,
and you,
and what'll happen is that people will
go through an abject apology,
you know,
and they'll say,
well,
I really didn't mean it.
And,
and now I understand what my privileges
and I see how what I said could have
been very hurtful to people.
And you know,
they,
they wander through that entire apology
and fold almost instantly.
And,
and that's under almost,
almost no pressure compared to what real
pressure is.
A real pressure is when the wolves are
actually at your door rather than just
barking off in the distance.
But people will fold just when they're
barking in the distance.
So
there's one lawyer that he talks about
in here is the same thing as the story
that you describe,
and I forget the guy's name,
but this guy was like the premier
prosecuting lawyer for the Soviet
government.
And he just rips people apart over and
over again.
And as you read about what happened to
him,
sure enough,
he's one of the guys had been ended up
on the,
on the defensive and Yam being executed.
Yeah.
Like they have all these things,
these people they built,
they built,
uh,
um,
place of butchery and then threw
themselves into it.
You know,
that's,
and,
and you see Solzhenitsyn documents this
very carefully.
I mean,
Stalin killed all the people who,
who were foremost actors in the Russian,
right.
So,
I mean,
everyone was fed into the great grinding
machine.
So,
and,
and Stalin himself,
I mean,
it looked to me like,
see,
he got himself into something
approximating a positive feedback loop,
which is a very dangerous thing to have
happen.
And I think Solzhenitsyn does a lovely
job of detailing this as well.
So it's like,
imagine that I have a fair amount of
contempt for people to begin with.
And then I find that people are,
I'm not trusting person.
And I find that I'm very paranoid about
the fact that people are lying to me.
And then I develop a certain amount of
power and a reputation.
Well then people really do start lying
to me all the time in every gesture,
you know,
because every time they come near me,
they're absolutely terrified and they're
going to tell me anything that I want to
hear.
And of course then all that does is
validate my view of how pathetic and
contemptible everyone is and so on.
The more that view gets validated,
the more I think that it's okay to
destroy people because look at how
pathetic and contemptible they are,
how they always lie.
And all that means is that they lie even
more.
And so this whole thing just spirals out
of control.
And you know,
stellan basically started out as a,
as the brutal enforcement henchmen for
henchmen,
for Lennon,
right?
The,
the,
the killer for hire.
And not like Lennon was above that sort
of thing himself,
but,
but he trained,
stolen and,
and then Stalin's proclivity to be
murderous just kept expanding without
limit.
Right?
First of all,
it was individuals and then it was
groups and then it was nations.
And then,
well,
by the end of his life,
what was it,
the plot,
the plot to destroy the entire world.
Tu Tu,
Tu Tu Tu initiate the Third World War to
wipe out Europe to maybe destroy
everything and like there's no limit.
There was no limit to that,
you know,
and there's some evidence that that's
perhaps why he was killed,
you know,
because Stalin himself even went too far
for the horrible,
horrible,
um,
what semi
the corrupted compadres that he had,
he'd arranged around himself.
He went too far even for them.
And thank God for that,
you know?
But yeah,
it's,
it's absolute,
I mean,
the thing that,
that the Gulag Archipelago Gulag
archipelago did for me,
and this was also in keeping as a
consequence,
also have reading young at the same
time,
but,
but it was certainly the Goo,
like in,
in large part that did it.
I would say that in some sense it's
scared me straight.
I thought,
I see the,
the consequences of unethical behavior,
deceit,
the willingness to,
to turn a blind eye.
So even sins of omission rather than
sins of commission.
Just to turn a blind eye.
The consequences of that are so
absolutely dreadful that it's not
acceptable.
And I think that's the right lesson from
the 20th century.
It's that you,
you,
you have a much more moral role to play
in keeping things straight.
Then you want to believe,
you know,
people think,
well,
my life is basically meaningless.
It's like,
well that's quite terrifying.
yeah,
it's kind of terrifying,
but it means you don't have any
responsibility.
So there's a big advantage to thinking
that,
you know,
not if nothing you do matters,
then nothing you do matters.
And so you can do whatever you want and
that's horrifying and annihilistic sort
of way.
But there's another kind of horror
that's more associated,
I think with the horror of hell fire
that was characteristic of the Medieval
Christian view is,
which is something like,
and if you strip it of its metaphysics,
it's something like,
no,
you don't get it.
The things you do actually do the things
you do or don't do,
they actually do matter.
And they tilt the world towards
something approximating good,
let's say,
or towards something that very closely
approximates hell.
And that's actually on you.
It's literally your fault.
It's literally your responsibility.
It's like,
man,
that's a terrifying,
that's a terrifying idea.
But I can't see how you can read this
literature without coming to that
conclusion.
Like,
it wasn't one that I wanted to leap to.
You know,
it's like,
it's,
it's sort of the ultimate in horrifying
conclusions that,
that everybody who participated in this
system was at fault for all of it in on
Dostoyevsky made the same sorts of
claims in,
in,
in the last part of the 19th century.
I mean,
he was a very weird,
mystical sort of person,
you know,
and he,
he made claims are some of his
characters did,
but on his behalf that,
you know,
not only are you responsible for
everything you do,
but in some sense you're responsible for
everything that everyone else does too.
And you think,
well,
obviously there's a way in which that
isn't true.
You know,
it's delusional in some sense,
but there's another way in which it
actually is true.
You know,
and so well
I,
I wrote a book called extreme ownership
and it's,
it's very inner.
So,
so all this is as a whole,
um,
thought here.
So,
you know,
when I read the book about face,
which is not about leadership,
it's not a leadership book,
it's a book about a guy that was in a
leadership position,
but he doesn't say here's how you lead,
here's what you do here.
It's a book about his experience and
what I took away from it,
especially because I was in leadership
positions in,
in the military,
in combat situations that I started
seeing all these leadership things that
he did.
And there's all this crossover because
for instance,
and so for me the crossover was,
well I started learning about tactics
when I was a young kid cause I was in
the military and the seal teams and you
had to learn about how to fire and
maneuver.
Like that's what you do.
And then so you start learning about
leadership.
And then I started training a lot of
Jujitsu and so those things kind of all
fit together.
And it's very strange how those things
started to weave together in my head
that,
oh,
if
on the battlefield,
if you want to attack the enemy,
you don't do it head on you,
you flank them,
you distract him,
and then you flank them.
You come in from the other side in
Jujitsu,
if you want to submit your opponent,
you,
you don't just grab their arm.
No,
you start to choke them and while
they're defending the choke,
then you get their arm.
And as a leader,
if you want somebody to do something,
you just don't bark that order at them.
You flank them and you let them
understand why it's happening.
And,
and you know,
when I started this podcast that I do,
I would say I started off by saying in
the beginning I'd say,
yeah,
it's a podcast about leadership viewed
through the Lens of war and atrocity.
And the more I did it,
and it didn't take me very long when I
was saying,
well,
it's,
it's actually a podcast about human
nature really is what it's actually
about.
Because the better you understand human
beings,
the better you'll be able to do as a
leader because you'll understand what's
happening with those dynamics,
which I guess is now leading me into
some sort of psychology you and just
kind of where you ended up with him.
Have you read this book?
And you said you were studying political
science when you read this book and then
you said,
oh,
you looked at the psychology of it and
an example that you just brought up.
And this is just what you learn when you
read.
And when you understand history and when
you understand the way people think
stolen,
surrounded himself with people that
would say yes to him and anybody that
didn't say yes to him,
he killed them.
And I'll say this again.
I'll talk to military killed you if you
said yes.
Yeah,
the uh,
the,
I'll talk to eat military for sure,
but also any business leader.
We talked to business leaders all the
time.
And you don't want people,
you don't want your subordinates or your
superiors when you tell them what to do,
to just nod their head and say yes,
you don't want that.
Now the,
the,
the immediate thought,
especially for a military guy,
they think they're nothing would make my
job easier than if I bark an order.
It you,
Jordan,
you work from Europe,
private,
Nama,
captain and I barked an order.
You,
you just shut up and go do it.
And that seems like the best thing in
the world.
It's absolutely not true because there's
things that you know on the front lines
that I don't know.
And if I really want to be a good
leader,
I want you to push back on me and say,
Hey boss,
we don't want to do that.
Here's what's going on.
Let me tell you the situation.
And instead of making,
you want to be able to do that,
you want to be able to teach your
subordinates to do that without being
insubordinate.
Right?
Cause then it's not a power play.
It's that your,
your interests are aligned.
Our interests are aligned.
And I actually,
when I talked to the subordinates,
cause I talked to subordinates to yeah.
And I say,
listen,
when you say something to your boss,
you don't say,
why the hell are we doing that boss?
You actually have to be very tactful.
Yeah,
exactly.
Hey,
hey,
hey boss.
Um,
I want to make sure I'm executing this
exactly how you want it.
Can you explain to me why we're doing
this?
So I can really,
really make it happen out there in the
field.
And that's a key thing.
So,
so these ideas of,
of,
you know,
psychology I guess now as,
and I hate to use that word,
but because I was just calling it human
nature,
but these ideas,
they all kind of come together.
And so now you're talking about
ownership,
right?
Extreme ownership and this idea that,
hey,
I'm responsible for everything.
And so here's what I'll get from a
leader.
They'll say,
well,
whether it's a business leader or it's,
it's very easy to use a military leader.
So I'll get a platoon commander,
my machine gunner shot in the wrong
direction.
How can that be my fault?
Because my machine gun a shot in the
wrong direction.
I'm not,
I'm not holding his weapon.
I'm not pulling his shirt from it.
How can that possibly be my fault?
That's not my fault.
[inaudible] wrong.
Who's in charge of that machine gun?
Who's in charge of making sure he
understands what it's fields of fire?
understands when and where he's allowed
to shoot you are,
you're the boss.
This is absolutely your fault.
Had it.
Uh,
another interesting example of the
weather,
the weather's bad.
We couldn't execute our mission.
That's why we failed because we couldn't
launch our helicopters.
It's not my fault.
That's a hard one to argue against.
Yeah.
Except for the fact that if you're a
good leader,
you'll say,
hey,
here's our plan.
We're going to use these helicopters and
here's our contingency plan.
If there's bad weather,
if you don't take that ownership of
what's going on,
if you don't take responsibility for it,
you're not going to change it.
You're not going to fix it.
And that means you're never getting any
better.
You're not going to win.
Right?
But the minute you as and this,
and obviously this applies to you know,
people to purple,
then you know,
you tell people take responsibility.
I've,
you know,
tell him,
take ownership of what's going on in
your world.
It's this,
it's the same thing,
but
well,
it's also,
it's also seems to me to be the case and
I think that this is part of the ethic
that's embedded in,
in,
it's deeply embedded in Christianity
with the idea that
the idea that the ultimate sacrifice
that you can offer to the world is the
sacrifice of yourself.
It's like,
well,
imagine that you have to sacrifice
something to set the world right while
you do,
obviously,
because you have to give up things now
in order to make things better in the
future.
So the sacrificial ideas,
a very deep one,
then the question might be,
well,
if you're going to sacrifice something
isn't going to be someone else or is it
going to be you?
And I really think that's the
fundamental question and the right
answer to that is that it's going to be
you.
It's your fault,
right?
You take that on or at least you take on
that responsibility and it is,
it's a weird thing,
weird lead,
difficult to distinguish fault and
responsibility.
I think responsibility is the better way
of thinking about it,
but it's tied in with the idea of fault.
If it doesn't go right,
if it isn't going right,
it's because you're not good enough.
Now that can be crushing.
There is a problem with that like,
and you see sometimes people who develop
like psychotic depression and they um,
they,
they suffer from a delusional condition
in some sense that the entire moral
catastrophe of the world is literally
their fault and that's not there.
There's an element of that that's,
that's not productive.
Although there's a truth in it as well,
you know,
and,
and it's hard to,
it's hard to find the balance so that
you can take on that responsibility
without simultaneously being a crushing
weight because there's a lot of things
in the world that are really not good
and if they're your fault,
well that's rather hard on you.
I mean,
one of the things that the Catholic
church does to help people with that is
that it gives them the opportunity,
do sort of wash their sins off
themselves,
right?
You can go to church and you can say,
well look,
here's a bunch of ways that I've been
being not who I could be.
And the Church authorities say,
well,
you know,
that's not good and you should
straighten up and all of that and fly,
right?
But human beings are fallible and you're
fallible and,
and,
and we can't just crush you because of
your insufficiency.
So we'll wash the slate clean and you
can go out there and try again.
And it's very hard to get the balance
between those things,
right?
So that you can take the responsibility
on without being crushed by it.
But,
but it's still the case that it seems to
me that it's either your fault or it's
someone else's,
and as soon as it's someone else's,
then you better be careful because that
idea that it's someone else's is
definitely going to appeal to the worst
in you.
That's definitely going to happen.
And if you don't see that,
then you're naive or willfully blind
and,
and all that is going to do all that.
All that that is going to do is make the
situation worse.
Yeah.
Especially because
if it's not my fault and it's your fault
and I can't control you,
what do I do about it?
I sit there and just suffer the
consequences of the situation as opposed
to,
okay,
here's what's going on.
I'm going to take responsibility and
ownership for it.
I'm gonna Change it.
Make it happen.
You talked about turning a blind eye and
an earlier you talked about turning a
blind eye to the truth,
to a situation.
And I know there's a point in this book
where he talks about the,
he's got a buddy that says,
amnesty is coming,
right?
Amnesty is coming.
Let's just keep our mouth shut.
Let's do what we're told to do and we'll
get,
you know,
we'll get out.
Amazon's coming.
And you know,
Solzhenitsyn says,
he saying,
okay,
yeah.
And then he says to himself,
wait a minute,
if I'm not,
if I'm not living in order to live,
then is it worth it?
And this is a question that I get asked
a lot because people get themselves into
situations
where they've lost some kind of control,
whether it's they're in a crappy job,
but they've got a bad boss or whatever.
Maybe they're in a bad relationship,
maybe their families,
but they are,
they're in a situation and they,
and they don't know what to do.
And part of them I think anticipates the
answer from me to be,
listen,
Hey,
if you're not,
if you're not living in order to live,
then that's wrong.
But what I actually tell them
universally almost,
and there's a couple situations where it
goes outside this,
but you,
it's like the,
what I tell them is what you need to do
right now is you need to play the game.
You need to play the game to get the
situation to a point where you can act,
right?
So if you're,
you've got a bad boss,
right?
Yep.
Oh,
you okay?
You got to buy Boston.
I want to tell this guy to go screw
themselves.
Hey,
guess what I'm going to do when my boss
tells me something to do that.
It doesn't make much sense.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna do it and I'm going to do it
well,
and what am I doing on building that
relationship with him?
He started to trust me and he's gonna
tell me to do something else.
Now these things are massive cutoffs
catastrophes.
It's like he's telling me to do
something.
Maybe there's a better way to do it.
You don't even know how to do it that
way and I'm going to play that game and
I'm going to build up that relationship.
Now when eventually he tells me to do
something that is totally stupid or it's
gonna cost,
you know,
lives or money,
then when I say,
hey boss,
that's not a great way to do it.
I think I know a better way.
Can we try something else?
He actually will listen to me,
so I'm going to play the game a little
bit and I'll tell you my gut instinct.
If now I guess it's,
it's easy to look from the outside and
say,
hey,
if I was in this prison camp,
my gut instinct is like,
okay,
Jack would,
you know,
you've been through these kinds of
things before,
play the game.
You're going to play the game.
Which is horrifying because part of
playing that game to the fullest extent
here or in a Nazi prison camp would be
coming to capitol.
Oh,
you're playing the game.
Yeah.
You're playing the game.
So,
and that's really the outlying,
the things that I said that our
outlying,
I always make the caveat that if you're
getting asked to do something that's
immoral,
illegal,
or unethical,
then you actually have a duty to say,
no,
I'm not going to do that.
No,
that's,
that's the line which you know,
which you reach that line in the sand
with bill [inaudible] 16 what,
which is,
hey,
I'm not going to do this.
But the idea that sometimes you got to
play the game and sometimes even from
you,
when you just said to me,
he said,
well,
you know,
sometimes it's,
it's not right to turn a blind eye on
things.
And it's like
sometimes you have to,
if you want to get yourself to a
position like mine,
it seems to me that you're making a
distinction between discipline and
strategy,
like an end and and like impulsive moral
responding.
You know,
like let's say that you are in a
situation where you have a boss who's
intolerable and maybe what you'd like to
do,
you know,
the resentment is built up over five
years and you'd like to go in there and,
and yell at him and tell him everything
you think and you think,
well,
that's the truth.
It's like,
well,
it's actually,
it's not a very sophisticated truth
because you're doing as shallow and
impulsive analysis of the situation.
Like it would have been the case that
you've already compromised yourself in
500 ways.
And I'll get back to the playing the
game issue because you do have to
discipline yourself to,
and you have to discipline yourself to,
to some degree,
by allowing yourself to do arbitrary
things that are part of the system,
right?
That's a necessary part of discipline.
And discriminating that from a
compliance with unethical activity is
very difficult.
So that's a hard situation.
But let's say you're,
you're,
you're going to counsel someone who has
an intolerable boss and they come in and
they're right at the end of their tether
because maybe that's why they come for
counseling.
They say,
I really want to tell that son of a
bitch what I think of him.
And you think,
well,
wait a second here.
Okay,
first of all,
you've already eradicated from the list
of reasonable possibilities.
That decision by failing to say small
things that you could have said all the
way along.
And it's not like you can just all of a
sudden blurt all of that out now.
And that wipes the slate clean and that
constitutes truth.
It's too unsophisticated.
So let's think,
okay,
so what is it that you want?
Well,
I don't want this job anymore.
It's like,
okay,
now let,
let's actually have a strategy about
this.
Then you don't want this job anymore.
Can you get another job?
While I don't think so.
Well,
so you can't just quit.
no I can't because then I don't have any
money in my family.
Depends on the job.
It's like,
okay,
so you can't just stop.
This does,
that's not a viable solution.
You go out of the frying pan into the
fire or you know you suck,
you suck.
You substitute one set of unethical
actions for another set of unethical
actions that are even worse.
That's not helpful.
All right,
so let's start thinking about what
exactly it is that you want.
It's like,
well,
maybe I want a better job.
I want to work for someone who is more
reasonable.
Okay,
so what's stopping you?
Well,
I don't have my cv in order.
My resume isn't up to date.
Well,
why is that?
I haven't done it for five years and I
don't like doing it.
Well,
why is that?
Well because I'm kind of embarrassed
about it because it has holes in it and
it shows where I'm lackadaisical and
where I'm not prepared.
It's like,
okay,
how many things are there like that?
Well,
there's a bunch of things and they're
all associated with how I procrastinated
in the past.
It's like,
okay,
what are we going to do to rectify that?
So I'll say to people,
why don't you update your cv that that's
what we'll do first.
Because if you're going to look for a
different job,
I'm not saying you're going to look for
a different job,
but if you're going to look for a
different job,
you're not going to,
unless your cvs updated [inaudible]
unless you can get a good recommendation
from this boss that's a tyrant.
That's right.
There's,
you've got to play the game.
There's 10 of strategic actions that
you're going to have to take in order to
make yourself able to move laterally or
up.
And the truth is isn't going in and
yelling at your boss and telling them
everything you think about it.
The truth is trying to figure out the
very,
very difficult process of how you put
yourself in a better position.
And that that are like,
one of the things that's quite fun about
this lecture tour is the letters that I
received or the stories that people tell
me about switching jobs because they do
realize that there,
and I often talk to people about
consulting their resentment.
Resentment is a really useful emotion.
Like it's really dangerous.
It's one of the most dangerous
psychological states,
I believe.
But it's unbelievably useful because
resentment usually only means one of two
things.
It either means quit whining and,
and take it on because you're immature
or it means you're allowing yourself to
be taken advantage of and you have
something to say or do.
And so you want to sort out the first
part and find out if you're just being
immature and you can think that through
and you can talk to people.
Um,
but,
and then,
but if it's the second,
it's like,
no,
you've compromised yourself in a variety
of ways and you have to figure out how
to get out of that.
And if you're resentful,
that's evidence that you have in fact
done that.
Okay,
so now that issue would be,
well,
how can you set your life up so that you
can be without that resentment?
And so that's when you start to develop
a strategy for,
you know,
and,
and it,
there's actually an adventure in this
too.
I mean I've had a number of clients who
have been in jobs that they didn't like
it all and you know,
they were tyrannized by someone,
for example,
and they were also working below their
hypothetical level and we'd put together
a plan.
It's like,
okay,
you're going to make three times as much
money in five years.
That's the plan.
But like that's not going to be simple.
So you,
there's education,
you gotta educate yourself,
maybe formerly cause you've got holes,
you got to fix up your resume,
you've got to,
you've got to overcome your fear of
being interviewed.
You have to start sending out like 50
resumes a week on a regular basis and be
prepared for a 99% rejection rate.
You,
you're going to look for a different
job.
It's probably going to take six months
to a year and almost all of that is
going to be rejection and you got to
steel yourself from for that and prepare
and maybe this is going to be a three
year process.
It's no trivial thing,
but you know,
it's almost inevitably can't remember a
single example where the consequence of
that very careful,
detailed,
strategic thinking wasn't a massively
substantive improvement in socioeconomic
positioning and a great movement
towards,
uh,
improving trajectory and,
and,
and there's advantages even along the
way because even before that happens,
the fact that you're taking genuine
steps to put yourself in a better
situation immediately starts to reduce
your resentment,
even if it isn't having positive
consequences to begin with.
But you have to be realistic about it.
It's like,
look,
it's going to be hard to update your cv
because you're embarrassed about it and
you should be all right.
It's no wonder you're embarrassed about
it.
And then,
well,
of course you don't want to go be
interviewed because you're not very good
at it.
And,
and there's holes in your story and,
and your,
and you can be made nervous easily and
you're not a very good advocate for
yourself.
So there's a lot of improvement that
needs to be done there.
And,
and then you have to withstand the,
the,
the punishment of being constantly
rejected when you apply for jobs because
the baseline rejection rate,
you know,
for the,
for the typical job,
applicant is like 99%.
It's like the rejection rate for
everything.
Is this going to work?
No.
But if you do it a hundred times,
it might work once and that's all you
need.
That's exactly it.
It,
you,
you only need that once.
And so the truth there isn't to yell at
your boss.
The truth there is to get your life
together.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah,
play the game.
You've gotta play the game sometimes
too,
to get a strategic win to me.
And that's,
and another interesting thing here is,
as I say,
you don't want to surround yourself with
yes men.
When you're in a leadership position,
you also don't want to be your own
personal yes ma'am.
That he just thinks you're great and
agrees with everything that you're doing
and,
and won't tell yourself the hard truth.
You know,
you can't lie to yourself.
Everything.
Every little one of those things that
you just listed off are the kinds of
things that people does lie to
themselves and say,
ah,
you know what?
Well you don't really need that.
That person didn't learn anything in
that,
in that course.
Why should I go to it?
That,
you know,
it's like if you don't tell yourself the
truth about what your,
what your situation is,
it's going to be problematic.
Just like if you don't have people on
your team above you or below you in the
chain of command that tell you the
truth,
that's going to be problematic as well,
which is something which is something
that's easier.
So the playing the game thing.
So are you thinking about that as a
consequence of necessary discipline?
You know,
like cause,
cause there,
because it,
it seems to be you're making two cases
at the same time,
right?
One is that you should obviously not
undertake unethical actions,
but then by the same token,
and you have to subordinate yourself to
the realities of the situation.
And,
and I think that that's psychologically
true because you're always in a
situation where if you're in an
organization,
there's kind of an arbitrary and
tyrannical aspect to it because it's
never working perfectly.
And then,
and then there's the positive aspect to
it too.
And so whenever you're doing a job,
it could be that you're,
you're called upon to do things that
well,
what would you say that there are a
necessary part of the operation of the
machinery?
I guess that would be particularly true
in military.
Yes.
And let me give you these,
well,
just a broad example,
right?
Um,
you know,
my personality and my reputation is
that,
you know,
when I was in the military,
it's like,
oh,
it's Jocko.
He,
he's not going to,
you know,
he's,
if,
if someone tells him to do something he
doesn't want to do,
he's just going to say,
screw you.
We're not doing it.
We're doing it my way.
You know,
um,
I got the knock.
But that was kind of the impression
people would get from me if they didn't
know me from the outside,
they think,
oh,
this guy's a knuckle dragger he's just
going to go forward.
He,
he's just going to make things happen
and he's not going to listen to anyone
else.
That was the impression from the
outside.
The reality is a,
you,
you can't do that and,
and be,
the reality is w w what my actions I'd
have,
you know,
a young lieutenant would come to me and
say,
Hey,
you know,
my boss has to tell me to do this,
this and this.
And what they think I was going to say
is like,
Bro,
you don't do that.
Stand up.
You tell him,
screw you.
That doesn't make any sense.
And they'd be,
they'd get this look in their eyes of,
of surprise when I'd say,
oh,
your boss wants you to do that.
Do it,
do it well,
play the game.
That's what I'm telling you to do is
Because these things are meaningless.
It's some,
you know,
something is pathetic.
It's like,
Oh,
you got to fill out a form a certain
way.
It's like,
Hey,
shut up and play the game.
You'll look even my,
so is that a matter?
It'll matter of picking your battles.
It's,
it's certainly is a matter of picking
your battles and you as cause that's
part of strategy,
right?
Everything can't be the war.
Exactly.
And it's exactly what it is.
But you know,
a good example,
and we wrote about it in,
in a dichotomy of leadership,
which is,
you know,
my friend,
my guy that worked for me,
Leif Babin,
we were getting told to do all this
paperwork.
You gotta,
you gotta fill out these forms.
You've got to,
you got to have a serialized inventory
of everything.
It's got to be signed off this many
days.
We need to know the qualifications of
each and every person and when their
qualifications come up,
do and all these just ridiculous
paperwork.
And lafe came to me and with,
with the other platoon commander guy
named Seth,
he came to me and said,
Oh man,
this is bullshit.
Why do we gotta do all this paperwork?
We're,
we're here training for war.
We're getting ready for war.
Why we got to do this?
And you know,
life will tell you his expectation was
that I was going to be like,
you're right,
I'm going to go to the commanding
officer and tell him,
screw this.
We're not doing this stuff.
This is crap.
We're trying to prep because we were in
training,
getting ready to deploy to Iraq.
This is crap.
We're not doing this.
And I looked at him and said,
oh,
we're doing all of this paperwork and
not only are we going to do this
paperwork,
we're going to do it better than anyone
else,
and we're going to turn it in before
it's even do.
And you know,
we,
both him and seth were kind of taken a
back then.
The fact that I wasn't standing up and
saying,
we're not doing this rap.
And then I explained to me,
here's what we're doing.
We're building a relationship with my
commanding officer,
with a,
our commanding officer.
We're going to do these little things
for him.
We're going to play the game because at
some 0.2 things are gonna happen.
Number one,
we want to build trust with my boss.
I want my boss to look at me.
And when he tells me to do,
to fill out paperwork,
he knows is going to be filled out.
If he wants me to take down a building,
he knows it's going to get taken out.
If he wants me to execute,
uh,
a larger mission,
I'll go and get it done.
We're bill.
If I can't fill out paperwork correctly,
how can he trust me to go on an,
on a real operation and have guys lives
at risk?
So the idea is like,
hey,
we're gunna play the game.
And I think sometimes people start to
hear me,
they start to listen to me.
And their first instinct is Jocko
wouldn't put up with them shit.
And that's why these,
you know,
they'll hit me up the same thing.
They'll write me an email,
they'll write me a letter and say,
here's the situation I'm in.
Um,
whether it's a boss,
whether it's a military,
it's,
it's any of them,
whether it's their wife,
like,
like my wife expects me not to train.
Jujitsu is something as stupid as that.
Like my wife won't let me train.
It's driving me crazy.
It's really starting to bother me.
Why?
Why won't you?
Well,
what's the problem?
Hey,
have you taken her out for dinner?
You know what I mean?
Like play the damn game a little bit so
that you can win strategic.
And it's the same thing I think with
your,
with the 12 rules where you're like,
hey,
tell the truth or at least don't lie.
It's like I get it.
But there is a dichotomy in that
statement and that is if you run around
telling the absolute truth,
everyone is going to be like that Jim
Carey movie where he can't say anything
that's not a hundred percent true.
And he's,
you know,
a woman says good morning and he says,
you look fat.
You know what it's like one of those
like [inaudible] not good.
And so you got to learn to play the
game.
And I guess again going back to this
book,
it's like that's a tough call to make in
these situations.
How much do you play the game?
And there's an ethical line that you
could cross at some point.
If I become a Cappo,
hey you just,
you played the game and you went too far
with it.
And just like in a leadership situation,
if I,
if you're my boss and I'm just kissing
your ass and do one of my guys lose
respect for me,
yeah,
my team will lose respect from me if you
tell me to do something completely
stupid.
And I said,
hey guys,
that's what the boss says.
We're doing it.
My guys will lose respect for me and I
won't be,
I won't be able to execute missions the
way I should.
If when the pushback is proper,
I say,
hey,
Hey Boston,
that doesn't make any sense.
We shouldn't do that.
And I go to the guys and say,
listen,
I told,
I talked to him,
we're going to see what he says,
but trust me,
if we have to do this,
we'll,
we'll figure out a way to make it work.
Because if you're just the guy that's
totally on board.
If you're a brown noser right,
your P,
your guys will lose respect for you 100%
they will,
they'll lose respect for you if you
don't play the game at all and you'd
push back on everything that your boss
says you're going to,
you're not going to get fire.
Yeah.
That's another ethical situation.
Like if my boss and my boss and you told
me to do something that's I don't
believe in or it's like a bad plan and I
may I draw the line in the sand and say,
screw you Jordan,
we're not doing it.
You can fire me.
You're like,
okay,
fine.
You fire me.
You get some yes man to come in.
He takes my guys out on the mission and
gets them all killed.
He didn't mitigate the risk properly.
It's better for me ethically to say,
Hey,
look,
Jordan,
I don't agree with this plan.
I really wish we could do it another
way.
Is there any way I could flex on it?
You say,
nope,
you're doing it this way.
It is better for me in many situations
to say,
okay,
I got it.
I'll make an indication of the
complexity of the truth.
I mean,
one of the rules of thumb that I think
is worth abiding by,
and I guess this is something that makes
me somewhat conservative in some ways,
is that you should do what everyone else
does unless there's a very good reason
not to.
And then I think that's,
I think that's the same idea that you're
putting forward,
which is that if you,
if you do fight back against everything,
then you're just a rebel without a
cause,
right?
And you discredit yourself entirely.
And if you accept everything,
well then you're not even there.
And so there's some judicious analysis
of the situation that helps you
understand when the time for action is
right.
And most of the time what you're doing
in life is you're doing what other
people do.
And that's going along with the game.
That's part of being socialized.
But there's going to be times when the
right thing to do is to break a rule and
to do it very carefully.
And so,
and if there's a,
there's a,
there's a scene,
I think this is a new testament scene,
but it might be in some of the
Apocryphal,
right?
Apocryphal writings.
I don't remember.
So Christ is walking down the road
on the Sabbath and there's,
uh,
there's a ditch by the road and it's
very hot.
And in the ditch there's a whole,
and in the whole there's a sheep.
And so the sheep is stuck in the hole
and this guy shepherd is trying to get
the sheep out of the hole.
And Christ walks by and he says,
if you don't understand what you're
doing,
you're a transgressor of the law and
your curse.
But if you do understand what you're
doing,
then you're blessed.
So it's,
it's,
it's a perfect example of that.
A,
because it's,
it's like if you're okay now here's your
situation.
You're a shepherd and you're supposed to
be taken care of that sheep,
right?
But it's the Sabbath Day,
so you're not supposed to be work.
Now,
if you have decided you've thought this
through,
you think it's the Sabbath Day.
This is something that everybody needs
because everybody needs to take a rest.
And this is a rule I shouldn't break
because everybody needs to take a rest
or,
or things degenerate.
And I understand that and I have a lot
of respect for it,
but I think that in this situation,
it's still morally appropriate for me to
break that rule in this slight way and
get this poor sheep out of this hole
then,
well,
Christ's judgment was,
well then you're exactly on the right
track.
But if you're doing it carelessly and
stupidly,
you're breaking that rule,
then we are a transgressor of the law
and you're cursed.
And I think that's exactly at the
essence of what you're describing.
It's like you play by the rules,
but then there's a matter of rule,
which is now,
and then you break the rules.
And you do that very,
very carefully because when you break
the rules,
you're breaking the rules.
And the rules are what keep peace they
and what keep peace in order.
And so you break them only in the
service of a higher piece in order.
And so that seems to be,
and I think that's,
you see this in in well this sorts of
stories that are influencing even the
things that you're writing.
Like in the Harry Potter series,
for example,
Harry's,
um,
friends and compatriots are quite
disciplined.
Her mind,
he in particular,
cause she's an absolute master of her
craft,
but they still break rules when it's
necessary,
only when it's necessary.
And that's what makes them more than the
people who are just breaking rules all
the time,
the villains,
so to speak,
and also makes them more than the people
that are just being good by being
conformist.
So you need that,
that touch of rebelliousness,
but it's gotta be a flavoring and not
the whole diet.
Absolutely.
I've actually talked about that on this
podcast before.
There's people in the military that they
are like met are rule followers.
These are people that have been
following rules their whole lives and
they've got perfect grades and they
were,
the team came,
they were all of these things and
they're,
they're going to make really good solid
leaders.
Like they're going to be great leaders.
But then there's this like one group
above them have that same thing,
but they also have that little bit of
rebellion that they'll say,
you know what,
we're not doing that.
It doesn't make any sense.
And that is really a,
uh,
an important factor to have.
Yeah.
But you know,
it's one of the reasons I would,
this guy,
Colonel David Hackworth,
this guy was the ultimate rule follower
for his whole career at the end in
Vietnam.
He did an interview and said,
if we keep fighting this way,
we're not going to win this war.
And they drove him out of the army.
But that's,
that's the thing that,
cause all along the way,
there was other times where he do that,
you know,
his guys weren't getting taken care of.
He'd break a rule and bring them be,
or he'd do it,
you know,
he didn't,
he do that along the way.
Not,
not so far outside the bonds that it
would jeopardize his career because if
he would do that,
then you're not in charge of these guys
anymore.
Now you're not going to have any impact.
So let's not get fired.
Right.
Let's get stupidly fired.
That's not an improvement.
Exactly.
Well that's uh,
awesome.
Uh,
I guess we,
I know you've got to go,
so I can't think that we could get to a
better little crust of the a or little
capstone of the conversation then.
Right there.
Uh,
thanks for coming on again.
Hey,
my pleasure man.
And I'm glad we got a chance to talk
about this book.
This is a book that everybody should
read and,
and you,
you,
I ordered the,
well,
I ordered a copy of yours with the Ford.
Yup.
From Europe.
You can't buy it from Amazon here.
You have to buy it from Amazon,
so it'll be here.
When will it be?
I don't know.
We're still negotiating the rights
because the rights holders differ in
North America and so that's the issue at
the moment.
So,
okay.
So I worked with an English publisher,
Penguin in,
in the UK that put out the,
I think it's vantage books,
if I remember correctly.
I should just check and make sure that
that's exactly right.
Harper perennial modern classics.
That's not,
that's not the British won the British.
The British one hasn't gotten to my
house.
Yeah,
it has to be ordered.
It has to be ordered through Amazon UK.
And we're,
we're working on a couple of things
maybe to also maybe get the audio rights
to the abridged version because I'd like
to read it.
Nice.
And that would be good so that people
could listen to it.
And so because it's,
it's an absolutely necessary book.
Yeah.
And it's written actually.
I like it cause it's written very
conversation.
I mean he's cracking jokes in there.
He's making,
it's a brilliant piece of literature as
well as,
I mean it,
it's a very readable book,
although it's unbelievably harsh and
demanding and draining to read,
but it's,
it's brilliantly written.
It's an unbelievably engrossing read and
in the most horrible possible way.
But,
and,
and it is the case that it's written at
this white hot pace.
You know,
it's like talking to someone who's
righteously,
not self righteously angry,
but righteously angry for fur ball,
for,
for dozens of hours.
And he just can't believe the levels of
outrage that are,
that are being,
that are being so incredibly well
expressed and so effectively expressed.
And,
and,
and again,
I,
I think it's also worth emphasizing the
fact that,
you know,
Solzhenitsyn's real contribution in many
ways was to lay the catastrophe at the
feet of the doctrine.
And not to say no,
this,
this wasn't an aberration because of
Stella North in Oh,
Lennon being the great leader and then
Stella and being the monster because
Lennon was plenty monster himself.
Um,
and Stellan was the logical conclusion
to len and not,
not an aberration,
but to say that no,
the horrors of what happened in the
Soviet Union were,
were implicit in the collectivists
system utopian system that gave rise to
the philosophy to begin with.
And that that's also an explanation why
the same catastrophes occurred wherever
the Soviet system was applied everywhere
else in the world at something we really
need to know.
I mean we fought a whole cold war over
that.
We put damn near put the world to the
torch because of this and the idea that
these ideas are the fact that these
ideas are creeping back is really,
um,
it's unbearable as far as I'm concerned.
So we'll hopefully people reading this
book and the,
the rerelease of this book with your
forward will prevent that from
happening.
At least it,
hopefully it will be a drop in a bucket
that many other people can put drops
into as well.
And so I'm hoping,
I mean I think the book has sold 15,000
copies since the beginning of November,
which is pretty good for the reissue.
An old classic.
But like it,
it,
it's required reading for an informed
citizen of the 21st century.
It's not optional.
You need to know this material.
You're not,
you're not,
you don't understand your position in
society as an individual or a citizen
without knowing this material.
So it's like not knowing about what
happened in Nazi Germany.
It's not acceptable to not know.
So read the book.
Thanks for coming George.
Really good to see you again man.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
you bet.
I appreciate it.
And with that,
Jordan Peterson has departed the
recording studio and if you noticed that
Echo Charles was not present during the
recording with Jordan Peterson,
but through the miracle of technology
and recording,
echo has now joined us for the support
portion of this podcast.
So good evening echo.
Good evening.
All right.
So if people listen to this podcast,
which we appreciate and you want to
support this podcast and support
yourself.
So there are ways to do that.
Echo can fill you in.
Sure.
So first way is when you're doing
jujitsu cause we're all doing Jujitsu.
Yes,
it might sound a little bit repetitive,
but to me when you do this,
you going to be doing it every single
day,
every single week at least.
Even if you're doing the two times a
week,
three to get it.
Either way you're going to need a g and
a rash guard,
so there is no question which kind of
Geeky you get.
You get an origin in gay.
Straight up.
I made an America,
I watched one of their videos yesterday
and it was kind of an older one too,
but it made me like love origin even
more because it's like you'll see,
you know the people that make 'em and
all the ladies there and then Pete,
like he has like longer hair and stuff
like that.
It's like,
Oh man,
this is kind of more the beginnings of
origin,
you know?
Anyway,
I thought it was good nonetheless.
Again,
made in America quality stuff for
Jujitsu.
It's not like a blank gay they get from
over wherever,
some other place and them slap an
embroidered patch on it and say that,
no,
this is made for Jujitsu in America.
Made in America.
From where,
where we grow,
the material is grown in America,
woven in America,
woven in Maine.
As a matter of fact,
custom woven by origin.
We weave it up there and make the best
cheese in the world.
Also got some other stuff for,
you know,
you got t shirts,
you can get sweatshirts and also coming
in 2019 jeans,
denim origin denim.
I just call him jeans though.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I dig it.
That starts to like,
I dunno,
move towards a fashion thing.
What if you seek denim and denim?
Well,
I feel,
yeah,
I didn't feel that material.
Yeah,
I feel like it's like origin denim,
they make it,
you know?
Yeah.
And then yeah,
they make origin jeans for sure.
But what if they make like a Jean
Jacket?
Like a denim jacket?
No,
it'd be true,
but it's still be a Jean Jacket.
That's true.
Uh,
dig it.
Cool.
Either way.
Yeah,
that's,
and I don't get excited for jeans in
general in life.
Oh yeah.
Like you know,
you see it on TV.
I don't know.
JC Penny has a sale,
you know,
black Friday or whatever.
And you know,
some jeans,
I don't get excited.
You pry,
I'm assuming you don't need or maybe do,
I dunno.
But when pete posts little like videos
of the close,
you know,
close up of the buttons,
the jeans.
Come on,
Bro.
That's,
that's kind of exciting.
I'm just saying either way.
Either way.
The also,
we have supplements to affirmative
forigin labs,
which is expanding.
Yes.
Yeah.
We bought another building up there,
but yeah,
so they're making,
we are making supplements,
joint warfare,
Krill oil,
super oil,
by the way.
Discipline the Tri Fecta.
Yeah.
The,
my,
my wife went on a trip,
didn't take joint warfare with her.
Yeah.
She's there for three,
four days.
Her knee starts bothering her.
It bothers her the rest of the trip.
She comes home,
she goes back on drone warfare for three
or four days.
Nice.
Fine.
Again.
Yeah.
Same.
That's just a reality of it.
So joint warfare,
good for your joints.
Krill oil,
also good for your joints and good for
your,
for your whole life system.
Is that a thing?
Life system life says yes.
Okay.
Well,
yeah,
it's good for that to discipline when
you need that focus.
And also discipline go.
Yeah.
Which is my pre cognitive enhancement
tool.
Go to go to check.
Yeah,
the,
it's funny,
the Krill,
I had the same situation too by the way.
Krill oil and joint warfare.
It didn't bring it by the way in Hawaii,
which is the reason why I did,
didn't appear on this episode of the
podcast.
So,
you know,
I saw my father in law came,
I told them the story about how he'd
always talk about Krill oil and he's
just sort of looking at me like
whatever.
And um,
you know,
he used to tell me,
Oh yeah,
Krill oil is good,
good for you,
all this stuff.
And he said,
now listen,
cause you know,
he's more of like a health dude.
And then when you started talking about
it,
like literally the day you start
talking,
start taking it.
And he was like,
he didn't care.
It kind of went right over his head and
he was like,
oh,
so did you feel the difference?
You know,
like that's what he was concerned about.
What do you mean care respect.
Also on top of that,
as you got milk,
which is,
which is milk,
basically,
that's what it is.
It's uh,
it has protein in it.
You mix it with milk.
I got her back.
I to make that statement.
If you mix it with,
well,
you can mix it with almond milk.
You can mix it with coconut milk.
You can mix it with regular cow milk.
If you mix it with water,
it's not,
I'm not jumping up and down about it and
telling you it's the most delicious
thing in the world.
If you mix it with milk,
whole milk especially,
I will tell you it's,
it's a,
it's a dessert straight up.
It's a dessert that you will make you
stronger.
If so,
you know,
like hot cocoa.
You ever make hot?
Oh yeah.
Okay,
so I'm a fan that you can put in water,
right?
What do you put it in?
Water and milk.
That is not hot cocoa to me.
Okay.
I know what you're talking about.
You get the little,
the little packet that you're supposed
to mix with water.
It's got the little crappy marshmallows
in it.
Yeah,
that's not,
that's a nonstarter for me.
Yeah.
So that's kind of the point there.
They're sort of along the same lines
where it's like cool,
do it and it's okay.
You can do it.
Yep.
And,
and there's probably many,
many,
many people who do that and I'm not mad
at them.
But you put the milk,
that stuff and you know,
that's a good one.
That's my opinion.
You can't have,
you can't have hot chocolate milk.
It's good.
It's right up there.
She don't worry.
Your kid won the surrogate mint
chocolate peanut butter,
chocolate,
vanilla gorilla and the darkness.
And then there's the warrior kid mark,
which has a little bit less protein in
it unless you double up on your scoops
like I do for the strawberry,
cause it's a strawberry is ridiculously
good.
So give that a shot.
And by the way,
all these things are
available@originmain.com and that's,
that's the state of Maine.
Yeah.
Not just main,
like the main spot.
Even though it is a main spot check.
Cool.
Awesome.
Also,
if you want to represent,
you know,
get a discipline equals freedom shirt or
a rash guard,
you know,
get after it anyway.
You want to represent the path,
go to Jocko,
store.com.
That's where you can get all this stuff.
Uh,
hoodies,
you know,
hey,
Christmas is coming up.
Let's face it.
There's no avoiding it.
It's coming up,
you know,
so you want to grab something that's a
good place to grab something,
some new stuff on there too.
But yeah,
if you want to represent while on the
path,
Jocko,
store.com good spot.
Also Jocko white tea.
So these claims of dead lifting,
8,000 pounds,
I haven't did,
lifted it in awhile.
So it was like,
you know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna test it.
The cans,
right tea,
drink it straight up,
dead,
live,
lifted 8,000 pounds.
Just like that.
Don't warm up even know you don't need
it.
It's real.
The warmup is drinking some Jocko white
tea.
That is the one you're warmed up and
you're good.
8,000 pound deadlift.
So,
yeah,
that's,
you know,
this is the only product in the world in
any capacity that guarantees 100% 8,000
pound deadlift,
minimum
100% but yeah.
So yeah,
you get them wet and the dry tea bags if
that's your thing,
when you see Paul,
that's the word,
right.
Boom.
If you like that Gig,
hot,
cold,
whatever.
And then the cans,
which I recommend,
I recommend,
they can't actually,
I don't know if I'd recommend it,
but I prefer that I like them both.
Yeah.
Depending on the scenario of her boom,
there you go.
Also subscribe to the podcast on itunes
and stitcher and Google play.
Wherever you listen to podcasts is a lot
of new ones out there.
There's apps and there's a lot of
podcasts out there and listened to a
bunch of them.
Yeah.
And one of them that you can also listen
to in addition to this one,
if you want,
you can take out the warrior kid podcast
that's basically directed at kids.
But um,
I'll tell you that uncle jake has
lessons for everyone in that podcast.
And also we've got the youtube channel,
the youtube channel where you can watch
this podcast in its full length and you
can see what people look like if you
don't know what Jordan B.
Peterson looks like.
If you don't know what Echo Charles look
like or if you don't know what I look
like,
you can watch the youtube channel and
you can see all of us.
If you never heard,
if you've never seen before,
but you've only heard him,
he probably doesn't look like what you
think he looks like.
Yeah,
allegedly.
And I don't know if that's good or bad
enough.
That's a backhanded compliment or a
backhanded like derogatory statement
about you,
about your voice?
Probably both.
Yeah,
a little bit of both but,
but we'll,
we'll uh,
suffice it to say that he's not what you
expect when you see him in reality.
And he also makes videos that are
enhanced by imagery and music.
Yeah,
exactly.
And those are on there too,
so you can check those out.
You can subscribe to the Youtube
Channel.
Also,
we got the psychological warfare album
and that has tracks on it of,
well there are of me telling you
pragmatically why you should or should
not do something like skip a workout.
You should not skip a workout.
Eat donuts,
you should not eat donuts.
So just some little things like that.
You can check that out.
Psychological Warfare Echo claims that
it has 100% effectiveness.
Yeah,
it does.
100% should you go to the gym?
Yes you should.
And if you listen to the track,
you will go to the gym.
It's 100% effective.
And actually,
I mean a lot of claims being made about
effectiveness on this scenario,
right?
Hey,
it's if it's real,
it's real.
You know,
there's no double blind placebo tested.
Well you know,
single blind,
maybe that's,
you know what that means,
but that's not official and it is
official when,
okay.
And I kind of tried to psychologically
analyze psychological warfare.
Like why does it work every single time?
And he was part of it.
Even you,
you know how like when you get
hypnotized,
I'm not saying you should have,
I should have asked.
I should have asked Jordan this
question.
Yes.
And he did agree with this I think.
Okay,
well let's hear it goes bro Theory.
So you know,
like I'm being hypnotized for example.
I've never been hypnotized.
Yeah,
me neither.
So well,
but then again it happens to,
so have you ever said volunteered?
Did he admit okay,
me neither.
Same thing.
So hypnotism,
from what I understand is you have to
like be,
what do you call like successful,
open to it.
Open to it.
Yeah.
So if you're suggestible person,
that's like you have a certain kind of
mind.
And then on top of that,
even more consciously,
you have to volunteer to be hypnotized.
A guy.
I mean,
I'm sure there's methods that you can
sort of hypnotize someone without them
knowing it or something.
But usually,
I shouldn't even say I'm sure,
but,
oh yeah,
that's right.
So if you can hit a dead zone and they
or not,
nonetheless,
usually the hypnotic sequence goes from,
hey,
you volunteer like conscious of,
yeah,
sure.
I'll be hypnotizing you sit there and
your suit coat to 10 and you're closing
your eyes and breathing anyway,
so you consciously volunteer to be
hypnotized,
so you're open to being hypnotized and
then blah,
blah,
blah.
So psychologic warfare.
It's like,
Hey,
you recognize,
okay,
I have this weakness.
I'm about to skip this workout right
now.
You're basically saying,
hey,
I need to help.
I need you.
I need a little spa.
Volunteering for help.
Volunteering.
Yeah.
It's not like I'm like sitting in my
room.
It's not completely against your will.
Exactly.
Right.
You're not just busting in the door,
you know insane.
Hey,
don't skip the workout.
Meanwhile,
in your mind,
you already committed to keeping,
the way it's different is you're like,
you're not committed to skipping the
workout.
You just like are running the risk of
skipping the work.
You know that weakness just creeps in
and you're like,
hey,
I see you weakness you're creeping in
right now.
I'm going to get,
I'm basically,
I'm going to tell Jocko that you're in
here and he's going to,
you know,
make you leave and you played the track
or whatever.
You have it on your phone,
right?
You had,
you have all your playlist on your phone
anyway.
You just play the psychological warfare
one and boom,
you won't skip the workout.
See what I'm saying?
Cause you don't want to skip the
workout.
No one wants to skip to work on.
No one's thinking tomorrow.
I can't wait to skip this workout.
And that just not like that.
You know?
So it's,
you come in and you just give that
little nudge.
That's why it works so good.
It's true.
It's absolutely true.
I like it.
And then the less psychological warfare,
it's very effective.
Hundred percent also while you're
working out and if you're bored with
your squats bench,
get some kettlebells from on it,
in my opinion on it.
Dot Com slash Jocko good stuff on their
jump rope.
Battle ropes,
kettlebells,
clubs,
mic.
Be careful of the clubs because I was
watching a video of a guy doing this
club routine.
I was like Dang it,
eat.
It took a lot of coordination.
Like I'm looking at it and he had like
the 40 I think like a big one.
Yeah.
I can't even imagine trying to do
anything coordinated with the 40 yes.
Cause I only have the 20 yeah and yeah
and they come off real a lot more heavy
than they look like when you grab them.
I mean at the end of the day,
if it's 20 pounds,
20 pounds,
no,
there's no getting past that physically.
But when you pick it up it's like,
it's like,
you know when you pick up your friend or
your kid freaking and they weighed 70
pounds.
It's like I pick up 70 pounds with one
hand.
It's no problem when it's a dumbbell
should pick up your kid when they're 70
pieces of one hand can do it.
It's hard.
Unless that's how these clubs are.
Anyway.
So watch out for those.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot com slash
chocolate you can get some really cool
stuff on there.
Really cool.
Awesome.
Hey,
we got some books as well.
First off,
Mike in the dragons.
I know Jordan and I talked to about it a
little bit today and it was actually
sold out for a little bit.
It is now back in stock and have many,
many,
many thousands and thousands of copies
that are inbound that are being printed.
So if you want Mickey and the dragons,
go to Amazon and order it.
There's a little video on there if you
want to know what it's about.
That echo put together and it's,
it's,
it's a solid video from what I
understand the like kids like to watch
the video.
Oh you get like,
it's like a little mini show.
It's super fast.
It's two minutes.
Even even my kid,
so we're on,
I watched the video
send it to me.
I watched it like 14 times because
there's a lot of elements in it.
A lot of things going on to my son.
It's like a micro cartoon Kinda.
No,
it's like a micro movie.
Yeah.
Well it's a cartoon cause there's
illustration illustrations.
Yeah.
But yeah,
it's fun.
We put on the TV when I was in Hawaii,
you know,
you have the smart tv in there.
You can put youtube on there and you put
it on there.
I put on the TV and my kids are all
jumping up and down like in the gym.
If I have is,
you know,
it's two minutes long.
So No,
I,
you know,
uh,
Jordan I were talking about it
and you know,
obviously it's about facing your dragons
and there's obviously a metaphor there
and it's a,
there's real,
true pragmatic,
simple to understand lessons of how to
stand up and confront the world and
confront your fears that little kids
will clearly and easily understand and
it'll leave an impact on anybody that
reads it.
So Mike and the dragons that you can get
that book on top of that if you've got
kids,
you can also get them though the way of
the warrior kid,
which is another book about a young kid
who's going through the problems that
normal kids have.
And luckily his uncle Jake,
who was a seal in the seal teams,
it shows up for the summer and helps him
overcome those problems.
And then that series carries on.
And another book called Mark's mission.
You can pick those two books up and give
them to whatever kids you,
those,
those books.
When you read those books,
you'll wish you had that book when you
were a kid.
I know.
I absolutely wish I had that book when I
was a kid and I wish I had that book
when my kids were kids.
Yeah,
because it teaches them what it is they
need to know.
Period.
That's it.
Uh,
the discipline equals freedom field
manual.
That book,
that's how you,
it's just a field manual of how to be on
the path of discipline.
That's what it is.
Look at the path of discipline is not
easy and there's no field manual for it.
Oh wait,
there is now,
but there didn't use to be there.
Didn't used to be.
Look,
I know discipline will help me.
How do I get disciplined?
Where does discipline come from?
There's none of that.
Information was assembled anywhere.
I made a field manual for it.
It's called the discipline equals
freedom field manual.
It's not,
it's,
it's not like any other book you've ever
seen or read,
period.
It's not,
but it's very popular.
It's great if you want it.
This is another thing Chris,
did you get Christmas is coming
[inaudible] this is a Christmas
scenario,
right?
This is a Christmas scenario.
Give this book to somebody that needs
help or needs to stay on the path or get
on the path.
This book will be extremely beneficial
to them or people that are on the path
getting after it.
This will keep them there.
So that's the field manual.
If you want the audio version of that.
It is not an audible,
it's on itunes and Amazon music and
Google play as an MP three also,
the first book I wrote with my brother
Leif Babin,
it's called extreme ownership.
That is a book taking the leadership
lessons that we learned on the
battlefield and translating them to your
business and to your life.
And then the followup to that book is
the dichotomy of leadership,
which takes those lessons that we
learned in combat and goes granular in
teaching you how to balance the various
dichotomies that you experience as a
leader.
So both in all those books are available
on Amazon and wherever else you might do
buy books.
Also we've got to echelon front,
which is uh,
my leadership consultancy.
We solve problems through leadership.
That's what we do.
And we work with companies all over the
country and internationally.
If you want us to come and align the
leadership at your company for victory
and they go to [inaudible] dot com the
we are do,
we have a leadership conference called
the muster and we've done six musters.
We are doing three and 2019 we're doing
one in Chicago in the spring.
We're doing one in Denver in the fall
and we're doing Sydney,
Australia in December.
So if you want to come to one of those
events,
all the events that we've done have sold
out all of them.
These are all absolutely going to sell
out.
So if you want to come,
go to extreme ownership.com and register
and as quick as you can.
And then lastly we have f overwatch.
We are connecting special operations
veterans and Combat Aviation veterans
that are looking for work that are
proven leaders that are experienced
leaders and we're connecting them with
companies out there in the civilian
sector that need leaders.
So if you want to come at that from
either side,
whether you're a vet or whether you're a
company,
go to e f overwatch.com to get in the
game and if you have any more questions
for us or answers for us,
we are available on the interwebs,
on twitter and on instagram and on the
fee ease.
The bookie echo is adequate.
Charles and I am at jockowillink and I
started out this podcast today pretty
heavy,
pretty rough and I think it's important
to remember something that I always
refer back to and that is that evil does
exist in the world.
It's out there.
And with that,
I'd like to thank all the military
personnel throughout the globe that
stand up to evil in the world and thanks
to police and law enforcement and
firefighters and paramedics and emt,
ies and correctional officers in border
patrol and all the first responders that
stand up and face evil here at home.
And to everyone else out there,
okay,
if things are tough,
and I know they get tough,
life is hard,
but there's still reason to be thankful.
Be Thankful you're not in a gulag.
Be Thankful that you're not being
tortured.
Be Thankful that you have food to eat.
Be thankful you have a bed to sleep on
and then do your best to watch out for
those little seeds of evil that are
planted around you,
implanted in you,
and keep those seeds of evil in check by
going out into the world and doing good.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.