It happened,
so now we've got to the point where the
story says,
well,
human beings became self conscious and
here's,
here's the problem with that.
The problem is is that we're terribly
self conscious about our inadequacies in
or vulnerabilities and that that sets up
enmity between men and women and it
dooms women to pain in childbirth and
child rearing and a dooms men to work.
It's a big problem.
Okay,
so now the next story that comes up in
the sequences in the story of Cain and
Abel.
Now you know we talked about the dragon
of chaos and then the terrible mother
and the creative mother and on the
tyrannical father in the secure father
and then the adversary and the hero.
Cain and Abel are the first
manifestation of the adversary in the
hero and what happens is they emerge as
soon as the genesis,
the original genesis story.
And so what the story basically proposes
is that once people became self
conscious to modes of being emerged as a
consequence of that,
and one mode is represented by Cain in
the other mode is represented by Abel.
And that's echoed in the story of the
hostile brothers in stories of hostile
brothers everywhere,
but it's also paralleled in Christianity
by the idea of the relationship between
Christ and Satan.
So it's like Cain and Abel are
precursors to the idea of Christ and,
and,
and Satan.
Now what happens is that,
so kane is the older brother and that
makes him sort of the embodiment of
tradition.
He would also be the favored one in
terms of the traditions of the ancient
Israelites because he would be the one
that inherits everyone,
so everything.
So he's actually the one that's,
he's the embodiment of tradition.
And there's some advantages to that
because he's privileged because of it.
But there's some disadvantages because
to the degree that culture itself has
become sterile and inappropriate and he
manifests that.
That means that he manifests error by
merely being what he was.
Now what happens with and enable is the
young is the young brother.
So
Abel was a keeper of sheep,
but Cain was a tiller of the ground.
Okay.
So there's,
there's a,
there's a dichotomy of,
of professions here.
And people have read that in all sorts
of different ways,
but one of the ways that you can think
about it is that there are valid
different modes of being in the world,
you know,
so you can be in this situation,
you can be a tiller of the ground or a
keeper of animals,
but in the world in general,
you can adopt any number of roles that
suffice.
It can be a plumber,
you can be a lawyer.
Um,
and there are,
there's,
there's ways of acting within those
roles that transcend the roles
themselves.
And so that's part of what's being
exemplified in Cain and Abel.
So they can,
they can function in the world despite
their different.
They're different roles.
In process of time,
it came to pass that cain brought the
fruit of the ground and offering unto
the Lord and Abel,
he also brought of the firstlings of his
flock and of the fat they're up.
Now that's very archaic,
the idea of sacrifice.
Okay?
So basically what happens is that you're
trying to get God on your side.
And so God seems to want something from
you because he's keeps demanding this
and that,
so you might say,
well,
reality wants something from you once
you to behave in a certain way so that
you don't suffer any more than you have
to win so that things go well for you.
Now human beings at this point in time,
or trying to work out exactly what that
means,
and they've already gotten to the point
where they're conceptually sophisticated
enough to understand that that means
that sacrifices are necessary.
Now you remember that it's only prior to
this that human beings discovered time
itself,
right?
That's when they discovered that their,
they become self conscious and discover
their extension across time.
And so one of the consequences of
realizing that your extended across time
is that you also will come to the
realization that you may have to let go
of certain valuable things right now in
order to make things work better in the
future.
And you can't imagine that people just
woke up and figured that out.
I can took people.
God only knows how long to sort that
out.
It's tens of thousands of years to come
up with that realization.
First of all,
they would have acted it out like bees
do.
You know they collect honey and they
make it through the winter,
but they don't know what the hell
they're doing.
Or maybe they do.
Maybe they're little super computers
like these bloody adams,
but you know what I mean?
You can act as sort of thing out without
realizing what you're up to and the
motif of sacrifice seemed to be exactly
that.
People stumbled onto the dramatic idea
that if you gave up something of value,
there would be some reasonable
possibility that God would smile on you
in the future.
Okay,
so.
So that's why there's the sacrifices.
Now you might say,
well why did they burn them?
And the reason for that is,
well,
as far as I can tell,
people are trying to understand what the
ultimate fabric of existence is.
And I think that you can feel that
sometimes and one of the places that
people feel that regularly is when
they're out at night and they look up at
the sky and they see this immense
blanket of eternity that's laid out
before them and that induces a feeling
of all.
And I think that that archaic people
took the notion of that all that was a
consequence of this apprehension and
associated that with some something like
communion with the divine,
which is actually quite reasonable.
Because when you aren't looking out into
space,
you are looking into the farthest
reaches of being.
You can see back millions,
hundreds of millions of years back into
time and you see you gaze out into the
infinite expanses of being.
So it's not unreasonable to assume that
in some sense at that moment you have
some connection with what's infinite.
Whatever that happens to be.
And I think that you feel that rather
than thinking.
So anyways,
the idea basically emerged that the
divine was up in the sky and that
because the divine was up in this guy,
you could maybe communicate it with it
by sending messages up there and one of
the ways you could do that was with
smoke and so if you're burning these
things that you're offering,
you get to push the smoke up to God and
he can do a molecular analysis and see
if what you're offering is of any
reasonable quality.
And if it seems to me,
then Poof,
you know God's going to be thrilled
about that.
Or maybe he's not.
Now what happens is that keynes
offerings are rejected and ables
offerings are accepted and so what that
means is that cane gets the short end of
the stick and able gets everything good
happening to him.
So what you see happening is that
there's the notion of two paths of being
one that's favored in one that isn't
favorite.
Now the story is very ambivalent about
why Kane is not favored.
Enable is,
and you,
you can,
you can read it multiple ways.
You can just say,
well,
God's basically being a son of a bitch
and he's not going to give cane anything
just because he's not in a very good
mood that day,
or you can say,
well,
ables doing something right in Kane
isn't,
and I think that interpreting the story
in either of those ways is,
is perfectly illuminating because part
of the time in life it seems like
someone's doing everything right and
still they're just getting laid waste
left,
right,
and center and someone else is doing
something terribly and things are going
well for them and,
but then you also see the reverse where
someone who's doing well gets rewarded
and someone who isn't doesn't.
So there's an ambivalence about it.
Now.
I think the story does indicate that
Cain is doing something wrong,
but it doesn't do that until later.
So anyways.
Sorry,
let me just go down to the next section
here.
So what it came enables sacrifice in the
biblical version cited here,
the nature of cane sacrifices left
unclear except that it is over the
ground.
It's vegetative and therefore bloodless.
Every canonical tail,
however,
carries with it a surrounding cloud of
similar stories,
some derivative,
some the product of a different
developmental path and tradition,
some intermingled with other stories in
some variants.
Cane sacrifices not only of the ground,
but it's of low quality.
Cain is unwilling to offer up the finest
fruits of his labors to go out.
That's he does not really sacrifice
anything.
He wants to keep everything good to
himself,
so he selfish as well as faithless.
Able by contrast,
offers up the best of what he has.
What does this mean?
Once again,
we already know we say to our children,
do your best.
Do not hide your light under a Bushel.
We do not say conserve your baster or
hide your best.
We mean offer the best you have.
Do it in good faith.
You will not be absolutely assured of
success,
but your chances will be into increase
to the degree that such increased as
possible.
Certainly it's an overstatement to say
that if you do not believe this,
you at least wish with all your heart
that it was true.
This is hope to not believe.
This is to risk descent into the deepest
chasms of cynicism.
So what happens?
God accepts able sacrifice,
offers him respect and renders his life
acceptable despite its terrible
limitations.
Cane sacrifice,
however he rejects this drives cane into
a murderous rage,
rage.
So the Lord God had respect unto Abel
and his offering,
but unto Cain and his offering he did
not have respect.
So the idea basically is that Abel makes
these sacrifices.
He's gay,
he's putting forth the best that he has.
He's doing his best.
And because of that,
it's actually working.
Everyone likes able,
you know,
he has,
he's getting along with his wife's,
his flocks are increasing.
And so he's a good guy.
It's like everything's going well.
Whereas Cain,
things aren't going very well at all and
no one really cares for them.
And besides that,
he's burning with jealousy because you
know,
despite the fact that he's slaving way
raising all these vegetables and trying
to offer them to God,
nothing is going his way.
So not only are things going badly for
him,
but he's increasingly disaffected by it
and you know,
you,
it's not difficult to understand that
you know perfectly well that what
happens to you if you're working away,
you think diligently and properly and
nothing is going your way and some other
son of a bitches just flourishing like
mad beside you,
that that's going to make you vengeful
and,
and irritated and anxious and angry and,
and homicidal for that matter.
And it doesn't take very long before
people reached that stage,
at least not in their fantasies.
Now the story says,
and Cain was very wroth and his
countenance fell.
And what that meant is he's angry and
his face changes to indicate that.
So he's got this continual look of
perpetual dis affectation and anger on
his face because things aren't going
well for them.
So that's fine.
So then he goes and has a chat with God
because he's not very happy about the
whole situation.
And I think people do that all the time
to,
even if they don't necessarily formulate
it in those terms,
it's like they're thinking,
well,
what's the nature of reality?
I'm busting myself in half here trying
to make things work properly and
nothing's going well.
It's like what kind of stupid universe
is that?
And for all intents and purposes,
that's a colocoy with God because you
don't start thinking about the ultimate
fabric of reality without bringing
religious intuitions into it.
You can't even ask such a question
without acting in a quasi religious
manner.
So this is what happens.
It took me a long time to unpack this.
So he goes and has the cha chat with
Yahweh,
with God,
and the Lord said to Cain,
why are you angry and downcast?
Surely if you do right,
you ought to hold your head high sin
crouches at your door,
lusting for you,
yet you can master it.
Now that's very,
very interesting.
So I translated those.
I got a translation to those lines from
a guy named miles from 1995.
Now it's so what happens is the king
goes and has a chat with God about how
things aren't going very well and
basically what he's trying to do is hold
God to account for why he made such a
stupid universe where everything keeps
going wrong and what God says to him is,
why are you angry and downcast?
If you do right,
you ought to be able to hold your head
high.
So there's an intimation there that the
reason the cane is wandering around like
this is because there's actually
something he's doing that's not correct.
It's not that the structure of reality
has got a problem,
it's that cane has a problem and god
says,
well,
if you just do things properly,
then you could stand up.
You wouldn't have to be a defeated
lobster all hunched over and aggravated.
You could stand up and you know,
hold yourself properly and be the be
thoroughly integrated in a proper manner
with the way being is unfolding.
And then he says,
sin crutches at your door lusting for
you,
yet you can master it.
Now,
that's a very interesting line.
So I found out that there is a,
there is an under,
there's a metaphorical context within
which those lines are attorney and
here's the context.
So God basically tells Kane that sin,
which is misbehavior,
is a kind of personality and the
personality that he associates it with
is something like a sexually aroused
predatory cat and he tells Kane that
he's no canes in house and that thing is
crouching at the door and it's waiting
to jump on it.
And then he tells Kane that that that's
a real threat and it's right there,
but he could,
he could not have that happen if he
wanted.
And there's a,
there's a whole set of inferences in
there.
And one inference is cain invites it in.
Now you remember,
you may not remember,
you have to invite the vampire into your
house.
It can't just come in and of its own
accord.
You have to open the door.
And so that's the first thing God tells
Kane.
It's like,
yeah,
sure.
Things aren't going very well,
but that things at your door,
you invited it in and you could master
it if you want,
but you chose not to.
And then the next thing that that the,
the conceptualization of the CNS,
this sort of angry and lustful cap,
there's a sexual connotation to it and
so the thing pounces on cane and has its
way with him,
so there's an idea that there's a,
like a sexual interaction between Cain
and this force so that it's a creative
interplay.
It's not only that he's dominated by the
sin,
it's that he brings it in and enters
into a creative union with it and
produces something out of the,
out of the mixture.
And so for example,
when I was reading the column by kids,
right,
it's,
it's like you can see exactly that in
their behavior.
It's like he knew perfectly well what he
was up to.
He knew perfectly well what he was
inviting in and he put his own
extraordinarily creative twist on it.
It wasn't just that he was possessed by
an idea,
like he spent months planning with his
horrible little compatriot about exactly
how they were gonna blow up the school
and the town and they would have liked
to have blown up the whole damn city
that was part of their plan and exactly
how they were going to turn that into a
creative spectacle that would be covered
by networks all over the land,
perfectly consciously,
every single bit of this.
So they put their own twist on it as a
consequence of being angry and resentful
and unhappy,
you know.
So anyways,
so God tells Kane,
um,
you know,
why are you coming to complain to me?
There's nothing wrong with reality.
It's like you get your act together and
behave properly.
You can stand up,
Whoa,
hold your head up high and you don't
have to let this thing that's tempting
you have its way with you and enter into
a creative union with it.
You can just behave properly.
And so kane leaves and then he's really
annoyed.
And the reason he's annoyed just because
he's going in there hoping that he'll
straighten out with a little chat and
sent reality straight,
and basically what he finds out is that
as far as God's concerned,
the reason that all these terrible
things are happening to him is because
he's not anywhere near what he could be
and he's setting himself up for
continual failure.
And so that really annoys him.
So no,
not only is he mad about the fact that
he's failing,
but he's even more mad because he
thought it through.
He realized that it was actually his
fault and that the reason these things
are happening to him is because he's not
what he could be.
So then you might think,
well,
what does he do as a consequence?
You know,
you could think,
well,
he could say,
little apology to God and try to get
himself on the right track.
And that isn't what happens at all.
He goes and kills Abel with a rock.
Now you think,
well,
why does he do that?
Well,
that's very complicated.
It's partly.
Well,
Abel is obviously God's favorite.
So he's doing everything he can to pull
them down and you think people do that
all the time,
like if you're jealous of someone else's
accomplishments,
these things really played themselves
out in junior high and high school,
but they also play out in in adult life,
you'll do everything you can to pull
down the thing that's hovering above you
and making you look bad from as a
consequence of the reflection.
It's easier to destroy the ideal than it
is to try to live up to it and people do
that all the time and then they're
punishing each other for their virtues
and they do that because,
well,
first of all,
because they can pull down the ideal and
then they don't have the mirror that
makes themselves uncomfortable,
but they can also do that as revenge
against God.
It's like,
well,
if that's what you favor and you're
going to torture me to death,
then I'll just destroy what you've
brought up to be the best manifestation
of what is at this point.
And then we'll just see who's who's
winning this war,
who's winning the war of being.
And so that's what happens.
He goes out and kills Abel and so God
comes along.
It's a terrible thing because it means
he destroys his own ideal,
but he's perfectly willing to pay that
price as long as he can get revenge for
his misery and his revenge on God.
And it's interesting too because if you
look at the writings of people who
commit real atrocities,
you can see that they've gone far beyond
any desire for individual revenge like
the kids that people,
the columbine kids shot up in in the
high school.
They didn't even necessarily have any
grudge against those particular kids.
It was like mayhem for me,
him sake,
and it was actually better if they shot
someone that was innocent because that
was a lot more of a protest that is
shooting someone who is guilty.
You know,
if you're shooting someone who's bullied
you,
it's like that's just gel.
That's just justice.
I mean,
it's a warped and bent form of justice,
but if you go into the high school and
shoot someone who's been good to you,
well then you're really making a
statement about just what you think
about the world and if you're willing to
blow your head off afterwards,
well,
it's just that much more indication that
you could say to hell with everything
and that nothing is worth having,
and that's like,
that's a,
that's a demonstration of that mode of
thinking right down to the bottom.
So anyways,
he goes out there and he kills Abel.
I'll read you this paragraph.
Kane is faced with a very stark choice.
His pride,
his belief in his own omniscience,
compels him to repeat actions that do
not produce their desired outcome
despite yourself to find failure.
This breeds a deep resentment.
Once his pride and resentment grow past
a certain threshold,
he starts to fantasize about revenge and
then about murder.
The gap between fantasy and action grows
even smaller as resentment builds,
and one day the opportunity manifests
itself.
Able says something optimistic,
deserving and promising,
and that straw that breaks the camel's
back.
Perhaps it is.
At first it was just resentment of the
successful deep resentment,
but it does not have to end there.
There's no real end with enough
resentment.
You can kill once if you can kill once.
Why not 10?
If 10,
why not 100?
If 100,
why not 10,000?
Why not a million?
Sterling was just getting warmed up when
he killed 6 million Ukrainians in the 19
thirties.
There's evidence from the KGB archives
that Stellan was preparing for the Third
World War when he was killed by his own
people in the 19 fifties,
and who's to say that Hitler really lost
the war.
It depends entirely on what he was
aiming for.
Maybe he got just what he aimed for when
he blew his brains out,
all over his bunker deep underneath
Berlin,
while Europe burned to ashes around it.
Why do we assist upon believing that
every tyrant fights award to win?
Cane believed that the world was a
terrible and unreasonable place bent on
his suction,
suffering and destruction.
He thought that hard work and sacrifice
was for babies and fools.
This is from Richard the third.
Why should wrath be mute and theory?
Dumb.
I am no baby.
Alright,
that with based prayers,
I should repent the evils that I have
done.
10,000
worst that ever.
Yet I did.
Would I perform if I might have my will,
if one good deed in all my life,
I did.
I do repent it from my very soul.
Eric Harris.
This is from Columbine.
The most literate of the two killers
said,
I hate the fucking world.
Kill mankind.
No one should survive.
Most investigators of the columbine
killings claim they cannot understand
the boys motivations and they could
understand them.
They just don't want to.
Harris said,
I would sooner die than be trained my
own thoughts,
but before I leave this worthless place,
I will kill whoever id him.
Unfit.
Harris transformed himself into an
archetypal embodiment of Cain who's
ultimate prototype is motivated
according to girth.
That by the following principle,
so this is Mephistopheles.
The spirit I endlessly denies and
rightly to,
for all that comes to birth,
is fit for overthrow as nothing worth
were for the world.
We're better sterilized.
That's all that's here is evil,
recognized his game to me and downfall,
downfall,
runes sin,
very element.
Prosper in Harris the day before his
mass murder,
about 26 point five hours from now,
the judgment will begun.
Begin difficult but not impossible.
Necessary.
Nerve wracking,
and fun.
What fun is life without a little death?
It's interesting when I'm in my human
form knowing I'm going to die.
Everything hasn't touched of triviality
to it.
With Harris,
the leader.
Yeah,
so what happens then is God finds caden
has a little chat with him and he says,
when you tell the ground,
it will not hence forth yield on Unti
unto the her strength.
He'll be a fugitive and a vagabond.
And cain said unto the Lord,
my punishment is greater than I can
bear.
Behold though it's driven me out of this
state,
from the face of the earth and from thy
face shall I be hidden,
I shall be a fugitive and a vagabond on
the earth.
And that it shall come to pass that
everyone who finds me will slay me,
and the Lord said,
therefore whoever slayeth Cain,
vengeance shall be taken up on him.
Seven fold and the Lord set a mark on
Cain,
lest any finding him should kill him.
Now what happens in the,
in the aftermath of that story seems to
be something like that.
So there's cane and then Adam and eve
have another son who's name is seth,
and Seth produces descendants and one
and one of them down the chain is Noah
and he saves the world from the flood.
But cain produces descendants two and
each of the descendant generation seemed
to get more and more aggressive.
And the generation that produces a man
named Tubal tubilcain seems to be the
same generation as no on the other
branch and Tubal.
Cain is by tradition the first person
who produces our artifacts,
tools of warfare.
And so there's an idea in the old
testament in this story that it's the
individual murderous resentment of the
individual who won't make the proper
sacrifices that distributes itself into
the community and culminates in
increasing brutality,
atrocity.
And finally into war Tubilcain T U B a l
Dash c a r I n,
yeah.
And so lamb neck is one of the,
one of the,
uh,
Kane Kane's descendants.
And this is lamb economic kills two men
when he is wounded and hurt,
and Lamach says unto his wives,
Ada and Zillah hear my voice is wives of
Lamech Hearken unto my speech for why
have slammed a man to my wounding
and a young man to my hurt.
If cain shall be avenged sevenfold truly
Eq,
70 and seven fold.
So there's this,
the idea of the exponential distribution
of brutality into the community as a
consequence of this initial adoption of
a particular form of being.
Okay.
So here's the situation that's laid out
in genesis as far as I can tell,
is that people emerge as self conscious
and not produces a terrible burden on
people.
And then the burden is even either
handled in the appropriate manner with
the proper sacrifices or it's not.
If it's not,
the consequences are that everything
degenerates into brutality and atrocity.
And that seems to me to be approximately
correct.
And so you can understand both cane
enables motivations,
you know,
cain gets brutal and resentment full
because things don't go well for him and
because he's suffering and it might be
arbitrary,
you know,
and sometimes you're suffering does seem
to be entirely arbitrary,
but part of the moral of the story is
that if you allow that to make you
resentful and vengeful,
that you'll participate in processes
that make things absolutely unbearable
and make the entire situation much
worse.
And all the existential commentary I've
read on the things that happened in the
second world war and in the Soviet Union
and in China for that matter seemed to
lay out exactly the same story,
which is once individuals get corrupted
because they're unhappy with the
structure of their being,
they can corrupt the entire social
landscape and the entire world and
things go from bad to worse,
until they're as bad as they can
possibly be.
So that's how things go badly.
You might think,
well,
how do things go well?
And,
you know,
unfortunately we missed one lecture,
but there's some things that I can tell
you that I,
that I think I know about.
What,
what are you laughing about?
No,
no,
no.
Well,
there's,
there's other things that I wanted to
tell you about,
but I can tell you about this anyways.
I just can't do it in quite as much
depth as I would have liked to.
So it doesn't seem to me that it's
reasonable to try to impose an
ideological solution on the world.
And the reason that that's not
reasonable is because it leads you into
something that's akin to ascend.
The pride you think you have the damn
answer.
You think you know everything and you
can impose that answer.
But the problem with that is that it,
it seems to,
that's the kind of sacrifices that
produces the kind of sacrifices that God
doesn't find very acceptable and things
go from bad to worse.
So you might say,
well,
what's the alternative?
What's the potential alternative mode of
being?
And so here's something that you can
think about.
And,
and,
um,
there's one thing that I want to tell
you about Christianity that's relevant
in this regard.
So you know,
you can,
you'll see this in the last quarter of
the maps of meaning when you read it,
but there's,
there's images that have popped up in
the middle agents where the tree of,
of the tree in the garden of Eden is
there again.
And on the one side of the tree there
are skulls and those are being handed
out by eve.
And on the other side there are these
little things that are liked fruits,
but they're representatives of the hosts
that are given to people when they
undergo the mass in Christianity.
And so those little hosts which are made
out of wheat,
which is a dying and resurrected God,
are like the body of the hero.
And so the idea behind the masses that
in order to overcome death,
you're supposed to incorporate the body
of the hero and the body of the hero.
The hero is the person in this
mythological landscape who is willing to
voluntarily confront death and will as a
consequence be reborn.
Now I think that that can be ran at,
at a psychological level because we
already talked about the fact that one
of the things that happens when you're
in deep error is that you can allow the
erroneous structure to dissolve into
something that's chaotic and then have
it reemerged as something that's new.
The idea that's lurking behind this idea
of transformation is that you should
identify yourself not with the initial
state of order,
which is like a particular way of
looking at the world and you shouldn't
identify yourself with the state of
chaos that's there when everything
collapses around you,
but did,
you should identify yourself with the
process of transformation from order
through chaos and then into a new form
of being.
And so the way that you confront the
fact that reality is continually
transforming is by allowing yourself to
transform with it.
And that's the volunteer.
That's the voluntary.
That's the taking on of the voluntary,
um,
that have continual voluntary death and
rebirth in the service of higher being.
And we don't know the potential limits
to that.
You know,
I mean obviously in their current
situation,
um,
everyone is still faced with the
possibility of ill health and a finite
lifespan and all of the things that go
along with that,
but we don't know the limits of our
potential dynamic flexibility and we
sure do know that if you hold onto ways
of being that are counterproductive for
any length of time,
that,
that kills you faster and makes you more
miserable.
Well,
it's happening.
And the same thing happens as well when
you're,
you know,
wallowing and trapped in a chaotic
situation.
So.
So here's a hypothesis.
So you know,
one of the things that the new agers
will tell you is that you should follow
your bliss.
And I have a big problem with that
because first of all,
I don't think it's true and second,
because you pointed out that if you do
fall in what you find deeply meaningful,
it's likely to take you to a place that
you're most afraid of.
And so to me,
there's a barrier to enlightenment and
the barrier is that
you'll face things that will pull you
apart before you'll face things that'll
put you together.
And I think that what you faced that
will pull you apart is all the things
that you've done in the past that have
been Sabala suboptimal.
Those things have to be repaired and
fixed.
Now.
If you put yourself in a situation where
you're able to rectify the errors that
you've made in the past,
so that you straightened out the manner
in which you're organized,
then I think that it might be possible
to live so that your forthrightly
confronting things as they move towards
you and if you're oriented towards
making them better,
like assume that that's your highest
value.
Say Well,
what's the purpose of life?
And the purpose of life is to make
things as good as you can possibly make
them.
And that might be for you and it might
be for those around you.
And you might not even know exactly what
that means.
So sometimes you're going to have to let
go of what you think good is as you
progress towards it.
Well,
it seems to me that if you orient
yourself towards that and you allow
yourself to stop living in,
in,
in theories that you know to be false
and carrying false hoods,
that you're acting out and,
and believing in that you know to be not
true,
but you can start to live in a different
way.
Okay?
So here's the different way in some
sense.
So
the first thing you have to figure out
is that you don't know what the hell
you're doing.
The second you have to think to figure
out.
And that's humility.
I think the second thing you have to
figure out is what you want and you
either want things to be better or you
want them to be worse,
and there's reasons for wanting them to
be worse and the reasons are deep and
they're justifiable,
but they're not helpful.
So then let's assume that you noticed
the part of you that's devoted,
like cane to the destruction of things,
and you understand what that is and
you're willing to take it onto yourself
to repair.
Then it isn't other people's evil that
you have to worry about.
It's your own.
Then you might say,
well,
what should you do next?
And one of the,
one of the pieces of literature from
which I've learned from that seems to
address that is the sermon on the mount
in the New Testament.
And one thing that happens in the sermon
on the mount is this.
So Christ says to his followers that
they should,
they're there.
There isn't something specifically that
they should be pursuing.
What they should be doing instead of
just orienting themselves in a
particular direction and the direction
would be towards what's best and what's
true.
So that's the first step is you figure
out,
do you want things to be better?
Do you want them to be worse?
That's the fundamental question.
So are you working for the betterment of
being or for its transformation into
hell?
Then you think,
well,
I want things to be better than the next
thing you think is,
well,
you don't exactly know how to go about
that.
Okay,
so then what do you do?
Well,
it seems to me that that's the point at
time when you try to eradicate from your
field of apprehension,
everything that you know to be false and
unworthy,
you get rid of it as much as you can,
as fast as you can,
and part of the way you can do that is
by listening to what you say and
watching what you do and you can listen
to what you say and you can find out if
you're actually saying what you believe
to be true.
Now here's the hypothesis and I think
this is the hypothesis that's laid out
in the transformation from the Old
Testament to the New Testament
Christianity,
but I also think it's the same idea that
the Taoists were pursuing and the
Buddhists we're pursuing.
So the idea is this,
and it's based on the idea of logos.
What would happen if instead of pursuing
what you think you should be pursuing,
you did something else,
which is you say to yourself in a
position where you're trying to make
things better and the next consequence
of that is to try to say as clearly as
what you pause as you possibly can,
what it is that you believe to be true
in every situation,
and then to see what happens.
It's a different way of playing the same
game now in the sermon on the Mount,
what Christ tells his followers just to
Orient themselves towards paradise and
truth fundamentally,
and then to concentrate on doing
everything they possibly can moment to
moment as carefully and correctly as
possible,
and then to see what happens.
So there's this ancient idea that set
that root of Western culture that being
is spoken into existence and that's the.
That's the,
that's the speech of the logo.
And the idea there is also partly that
that inherits inside people if they,
if they're willing to utilize it and
that they know how they can utilize it.
And the way to utilize that is to
straighten out your speech and action
and to act as well as you can moment to
moment and to let go other than that and
see what happens.
Because,
and I think that that's the movement of
faith that the existentialist Christians
continually talk about.
You can't.
Because the thing is,
if you're aiming at something specific
that constitutes the good,
then basically what you've done is made
yourself a kind of idle.
You said,
well,
this is paradise and God,
but the thing is you don't know that
because you're not sufficiently
informed.
Understand the ultimate nature of the
good.
But I think you're sufficiently informed
to figure out when you're not using your
language properly.
And I think one of the things that you
can notice is that if you're not using
it properly,
it makes you ashamed and weak and
embarrassed.
And I think you can feel that.
You can feel it fully embodied.
And I think that's what Kane does.
And that's what God tells them to stop
doing.
And he says,
if you're doing things right,
you can stand up with your head held
high.
And if you're not,
you can't your downcast and angry and
resentful and murderous,
and I think that that's the case.
So,
and I do believe that it's a different
way of being because it's not aimed at
something.
It's not aimed something that's
predefined.
You have to under,
you have to allow what constitutes the
good and your understanding of the good
to continually be updated as you pursue
it.
And I think all you have to do to do
that is to speak words well.
Northrop Frye would say is that you have
to speak words with power and I think
you can learn to do that,
but you have to let go.
I think that that's the,
that's the cure for radiology,
you know,
because what's the alternative?
You can lay out a belief system and try
to impose it
or you can play along and see if you can
figure out what's going on.
And if you have a productive
conversation with someone that's what
you're doing,
you know,
you say,
well,
let's see if we can figure out how to
get along.
Maybe this is within the confines of an
intimate relationship.
It's like,
okay,
what do you want?
What do I want?
How is that going to fit together?
Can we communicate honestly about
exactly what that is and how we might
get it,
and it's.
It's a process of coe discovery.
It's not like you know the answer to
begin with and you're not going to find
it unless you tell each other the truth
and you're not going to be able to
pursue it unless you act out the truth
that you articulate and I don't think
you're going to be able to articulate
the truth properly unless what you want
is the good and that's a very difficult
thing to figure out.
But I think one of the things we do know
after the 20th century that the
continual attempt to make the world as
atrocious a place as possible seems to
be searching in the wrong direction.
No.
You know,
I've tried this sort of thing for a very
long period of time because I think that
what I try to do or why,
what I try to do is to say what I
believe to be the case in every
situation that I'm in and to see what
happens and my experience has been that
really works.
I get really works.
You can learn to get along with the
people in your family and help them
straighten out and you can start to have
a relatively beneficial effect on
processes that are outside of your,
you know,
of what's right in front of you and
within your grasp so you can practice
trying to figure out how to set things
straight and I have no idea what the
ultimate limits of that might be.
But I can tell you one thing.
It certainly makes your life and
ridiculously interesting and you know
that in itself is one of the things that
takes away the sting of mortality.
Because if what you're doing is so damn
interesting,
you can hardly stand it.
The fact that you have to pay a price as
you move along starts to become
acceptable,
you know,
because you'll pay a price if it's worth
it.
It's neat.
You said if you have a why you can bear
anyhow,
and I think there's some truth in that
and you know,
you might say,
well,
what's,
what's a good that sufficiently good to
justify voluntarily participating in
being that's bent on your misery and
destruction.
That's the fundamental question of life.
Well,
I would say you need a pretty elevated
vision in order to counteract that and I
think that's what a vision of paradise
is and I think that paradise,
something that people have to build,
I think if we built it properly,
it would justify everything that
happened on the way to building it.
Or at least that might be the case.
And I think you can do it locally first.
So.
And I can't see it.
I've watched people.
I've watched how people have lived live
now for decades and I have two clients
in my practice right now who've,
who one of them was pretty damn straight
to begin with,
but he's set up his,
his business.
It happens to be a firm and he's tried
to make absolutely straight decisions
that were really informed and proper the
entire way along.
And the bloody thing is running like a,
like a,
it's running,
it's celebrated.
It's extremely effective.
It's not wasteful.
Everybody who was inside the
organization is developing properly,
um,
no ones getting screwed over,
like it's,
it's an honest and straightforward
enterprise and everybody seems to be
benefiting from it.
And I have another client who was pretty
damn confused and arrogant and resentful
when he first started changing his life
and he put together a relatively small
business and I would say it's a low
status business,
but he's done it as honestly as he
possibly could.
And he tried to keep himself on the
straight and narrow.
Well,
he's doing it and he's trying to give
his customers outstanding service and to
be clear and straight with them at every
single choice moment.
And that's lifted his cynicism and it's
made his business very,
very productive and positive.
And so I can't see.
First of all,
there has to be some antidote to
theology because it's corrosive and
destructive and I can't see that there's
any,
any and that you can attain at any means
that you can implement that's more
meaningful and rich and deep than that.
And I do think it's sufficient to stop
you from being corrupted and genocidal.
And that's a good thing because you can
get corrupted and genocidal.
And if there's enough of us who were
corrupt and genocidal,
then things are going to get very bad
instead of very good
so
well.
So then you can think about that.
And I think it's an easy thing to to,
to start to try.
The first thing you have to do is decide
if you want things to be better or
worse.
And that's not a simple question because
there'll be a lot of you that's bitter
and resentful and vengeful and angry for
all of your inadequacies in the way the
world's treated you.
And so.
And the second thing is pay attention to
what you say and see if you believe it.
And if you don't quit saying it,
see what happens.
Like you can tell if what you say makes
you stronger,
if it makes you weak,
oh you have to do is feel it and you can
stop saying things that make you weak,
but it'll change you completely.
So
you'll find that you won't be able to
associate with people who only allow to
say things that make you weak,
for example,
because lots of people would be upset if
you say things that make you strong
around them because they don't want you
to flourish and grow partly because it
sheds a bad light on them.
Anyways.
This is more of elaborated in the last
quarter of the book or there boats.
And so you'll get a chance to read that
if you want to do it.
And I guess I'll see you guys when you,
when you have the final,
but in the meantime.
Well think about it.
You know,
I think we have more opportunity now at
this point in history to make things
good than we could have possibly
imagined 50 years ago and it's
necessary.
You know,
there's lots of things that are falling
apart and people get cynical about that
and that's the wrong attitude.
It's like you have no idea how much
power you might have at your disposal if
you used it properly.
And I think we could set things right if
we decided that it was worth doing.
And so it certainly seems to me to beat
the alternative because in the 20th
century we bloody well learned what the
alternative was and it is as horrible as
anything you could possibly imagine.
So it seems to me that it's very much
worth a while avoiding that even if we
can't make things perfect.
So
see you all.