Looks
like
everybody's here.
For those of you who were,
so does everybody have a copy of this?
I rewrote.
I'd been rewriting the introduction to
this bearing script.
I did.
I do do.
I mentioned to you before that it
terms of techniques for writing an
essay,
the essay that you should put aside what
you wrote.
I do that all the time.
So what you have here,
let's see,
in terms of payment
on the first page,
1616 and a half,
that stuff you've already read,
it's hopefully written more clearly but
from 17 and a half to the end of 18 is
actually an outline of the argument in
the whole book.
Hopefully
that will provide the transition to the
second part of the course which starts
today.
I tried to start the last week,
but I had a hard time because I wasn't
in the right sort of mood to discuss the
sort of material and also because I've
been working on the first half of this
manuscript for about a year.
I spent the previous year working on the
second half,
but a year ago was a long time.
Can I forgotten a lot of what I was
trying to say and it was really,
it took more effort than I was willing
to engage him last week and the week
before to make sense of the chapter or
contamination of the experience with
death.
I mean what I'm trying to do in that
chapter is to describe the difference
between consciousness and self
consciousness and also to portray how
mythology represents the consequences of
the emergence of self consciousness.
And I want to do that for a particular
reason.
It's not because I'm really necessarily
all that interested in that as a topic
is sort of a precursor to discussing why
it is that we differ in our emotional
response was from animals.
Why our emotional response to that I
think are are more heightened and also
maybe why do we were actually more
conscious.
So it's a lot of background work to
describe that.
Trying to figure out how self
consciousness differs from
consciousness.
That's difficult.
That's a difficult procedure in and of
itself,
let alone when it's just the basis of
another argument.
So let's go over the outline of the
manuscript and hopefully that help clear
up in your minds.
Some of the things that I've been
discussing.
How can me help clear them up your mind,
mind?
Okay,
so this is the basic argument.
We'll really can be construed as a forum
for action as well as a place for
things.
I want you to discuss that and be ready.
I would say,
well scientific methodology constitutes
the formal process whereby we described
the world as a place of things
narrative.
On the other hand,
myth,
literature and drama portrays the world
as a forum for action.
The two forms of description had been
unnecessarily set it odd because we have
not yet for the clear picture of their
respective domains.
The domain of the former that is the
world as a place of things is what is
from the perspective of interest,
subjective perception,
so we can get a description of the
objective status of things by comparing
a perceptions,
the domain of the ladder as the domain
of pathology describing the world as a
forum for action
is what he is and what should be from
the perspective of emotion than the
action.
You can see why those two things would
have been confused because both in a
sense are an attempt to describe what
is,
although myth also with to describe one
should be and you can describe what is
in terms of its implications for you and
behavior,
which is a perfectly valid approach.
Or You could describe what he is from
the perspective of objective
description,
which is also a valid approach because
in both cases you're engaged in a
process that looks similar.
It's easy to confuse one form of
description and its purposes with the
other,
and I would say,
well,
that's being basically that confusion
has led to the dissociation of
scientific knowledge from from moral
knowledge or for mythological going one
gen chem two they're unnecessary
opposition.
Okay.
I mean,
look,
either they're both valid and we don't
understand how that can be or one's
valid than the other isn't and it looks
like all the evidence suggests that it's
scientific if one's valid than the other
is all the evidence suggests that the
scientific knowledge it's smell seems a
bit unreasonable given that all human
conscious up to the European culture
essentially 500 years ago lived
according to the mythological
presuppositions.
We get pure science sciences.
We also have a lot of my clinical
psychology and in any,
in any in designs we talk about basic
research,
but also applications.
A sure.
Talking about that second domain.
I would say absolutely science is
meaningless if it doesn't imply what you
should do,
but the application of science
necessarily implies that you should.
But I would say as soon as you're
applying science to what should be,
it's not science anymore.
I guess since it's side it's it's
mythology that's operating under the
guise of science and this all this
explains for me at least why for
example,
there are,
I teach personality course though.
There's endless numbers of competing
personalities.
There's many of them predicated on
completely different presuppositions.
They all provide a coherent story more
or less fairly coherent.
As a matter of fact,
even though they don't agree and the
truth of the matter appears to be that
if you're a therapist and you pick any
of those stories and you apply it
according to the rules of that story,
it works about as well as any other
store.
I mean people don't like to admit that
if their adherence of one theory or
another and behaviorism seems to be good
for per some specify things better than
perhaps some other doctors,
but I think you can understand that not
from a scientific perspective.
So watch us from the perspective of
mythology which is to say that if you've
come to therapy and you have no story
whatsoever,
the provision of a coherent story for
you is already an improvement over your
current status even though you might not
be being exposed to the basketball
possible story so to speak.
But I'd also say that
this is part of the reason why there's
such a problem in constructing
psychiatric classifications from liberal
illness cause they're not scientific at
the bottom of them is some conception
implicit or explicit.
It's implicit in the DSM by design about
what constitutes mental health.
Because you have to define your own is
in contrast to hell and as soon as you
start talking about health,
whether it's mental or otherwise,
you're not in the objective domain
anymore.
You have to make judgments about what
Pumpkin to the ideals.
And I think this is part of the problem
that psychiatric diagnosis has has not
dealt with explorer.
It's part of the problem with
psychiatric diagnosis in general and has
a problem.
It's generally not dealt with
explicitly,
so if it's an applied science,
it's pulling in some mythological
presuppositions.
I don't think there's any way around
that.
I think we just have to,
we have to recognize that that's the
case.
Okay,
so you have the world as a place of
things in the world is a forum for
action
as a forum for action.
It appears to be composed of two,
the three constituent elements that
we've discussed in detail,
unexplored territory,
explored territory and the process that
mediates between the two.
If you analyze the characteristics,
emotional responses of the human brain,
that analysis reveals that the brain has
adapted itself to the world as a forum
for action as well as place of things.
This implies to me the fact that this
biological adaptation implies that the
environment is in reality a form for
actions.
We'll also place for things,
so that implies mean if you,
if you buy the argument that adaptation
does take place to the environment.
If we've adapted to the environment as a
forum for action,
then it applies.
The descriptions of the world as a form
for action are in fact descriptions of
something that's real.
I think that's a strange idea,
but it still strikes me as as if you
accept that preset positions,
then that's a necessary conclusion.
Each of the three constituent elements
of the world as a four for action has a
characteristic nature or personality and
it has garnered mythological or
narrative representations.
As such,
these representations have the
structural aspect of natural categories
and appear relatively stable across
cultural place in time.
It's unexplored.
Territory is the great mother source of
all determinant things.
Creative and destructive,
threatening and promising explored
territory is bringing father cumulative
ancestral wisdom simultaneously
protective and tyrannical.
The process that mediates between the
two is the individual son of the great
father and mother,
the hero word who creates the cosmos.
That's a Christian viewpoint and the
adversary who spitefully rejects that
creation about who we will talk for the
remainder of the course
group identification,
which I think might be conceptualized as
ritual limitation of the debt,
protects the undeveloped individual from
the terrible forces,
that rural,
unexplored territory,
which is only to say that when you're on
familiar ground,
you're not anxious.
You know what to do and the reason you
know what to do is because you're
imitating the actions of people who at
some point in the past figured out what
to do and transmitted that knowledge to
you across the generations.
And you also tend to act in the presence
of others who also constitute your own
culture,
who are also beneficiaries of the same
way as the men who therefore act
predictably kind of these,
the fact of the predictability,
in fact that protects you from
unpredictability.
By definition,
absolute identification with the group,
however interferes with the process that
maintains and updates the group and
increases the likelihood that protective
strategies designed to maintain the
integrity of the group with necessary
strategies will escalate into
uncontrollable warfare.
So then the question is,
given that if you identify with your
group too strongly,
it will actually come to your group in
the long run plus increase the
likelihood that you'll engage in perhaps
unnecessary and counter productive.
How do groups that surround him group?
So why do people do it?
What is it that motivates us to adopt
absolute identification with the group?
We know burke proof identification has
its problems.
I identified with a group and you
identify with a different group of stage
is set for our conflict,
but we also know that you have to
identify with the group.
Yeah,
so there has to be a balance struck
while people,
there are situations in which time
balance is on your mind and people I
talk to absolute identification with the
group and you get the construction of
totalitarian or authoritarian states and
the Mo,
the,
the motto of a totalitarian state,
his every one should act exactly the
same way.
So they're all,
we're all absolutely predictable.
That's what totalitarian means.
Act The same way.
You think the same way,
look the same way.
Believe the same things in your
individual.
These absolutely constrained by your
dogmatic identification and the
advantage to that has been everyone
becomes extraordinarily predictable
because everyone is a clone.
Fundamentally question is why would
people do that?
What's the,
what's the attraction of absolute
identification?
Given that it's evident that such
identification also has negative
consequences,
why would you bother with,
well,
that's what we're going to try to
discuss for the rest of the class.
What forces motivate us to subjugate our
individuality to the group?
Well then the question,
the question immediately rises
essentially what are the consequences?
Like first of all,
what is individuality?
What does it mean?
And second of all,
what are the consequences of that
individuality?
And that's what I'm trying to address in
the chapter on self consciousness and
the contamination of experience with
death.
Where would you put something like a
religious order in terms of group
identification and individuality?
Well,
I actually discussed this.
Emilia invited me for dinner last night
at the faculty dinner and this is
something that we discussed there.
I mean,
it strikes me that the purpose of a
religious order or any discipline for
that matter is partly that the erection
of necessary boundaries of order,
I mean you have to have boundaries of
order.
What those boundaries are can differ.
I mean to some degree there's,
there's variation across groups,
but the fact that the boundaries has to
be that it's partly so that you can
carve out a domain in which you're
comfortable to act.
But it's also partly because,
and this is niches,
observation primarily.
If you don't identify with the group,
you never,
you never disciplined yourself,
he never subjected to any discipline.
And as a consequence you're never able
to actually foster any sort of true
individuality.
So I would say voluntary slavery is a
precondition for freedom and a dogmatic
group or a doctrine,
let's say a doctrine because that's less
rigid,
a doctor and is something to which you
can adhere voluntarily.
And the purpose of that is that while
and excludes all sorts of possibilities
so that it's,
that's it's negative aspect in a sense.
But it also allows you to develop the
skills necessary to do something.
And so I mean,
the example I always thinking about
that's the apprenticeship or,
right,
so you want to be a concert pianist.
What you do first is learn how it was
that all other concert pianists
essentially behaved in the past.
Do you develop your technical skills and
that means your,
is that your individuality is
essentially subjugated to it,
to a discipline.
Once you've got the skills,
then you can transcend the limitations
that that that discipline placed on me.
So that's why I wanted everyone to read
the abuse use and abuse of history
because this is a,
this is a problem that gt dealt with for
a long period of time,
despite the fact that he was a radical
antichristian.
One of the things you constantly pointed
out in his philosophy was that
catholicism was net worth was a
precondition to European greatness in a
sense because although it was arbitrary
and unfair and authoritarian and
doctrinally bombed and destroyed,
all sorts of useful things,
it also forced people to discipline
their other spirits in a sense.
But their minds at least to,
he said if you could learn to think one
way in a discipline manner,
then once you develop that ability,
then you could use the ability to think
and all sorts of different ways.
But you never,
you could never do that.
You'd never have the freedom without
first of all having gone through the
disciplinary procedure,
so like the jesuits were the Franciscans
you would,
would you consider it a totalitarian
group?
Well it would depend on the particular
group.
I mean groups tend towards a
totalitarian
groups tend to worst totalitarian status
because partly because they have to for
a group to last for any length of time.
It has to protect its structure,
which means it has to exclude
information that would result in the
undermining of instruction.
So for a group to exist,
it has to say,
so to speak,
this group is the best group and if you,
and the best thing you can do is be an
eminent member of this group.
So that's a perfectly reasonable moral
statement.
It's just incomplete because at least as
far as I'm concerned,
because of the problem with that
statement is that it eliminates the fact
that in order for the group to maintain
itself,
at least some of the group's members
have to transcend this limitation so
that they can update the group,
but there's a tension,
there's a tension between the group and
the individual that cannot be resolved
or,
or I think that's a,
that's more or less reasonable
statement.
I mean,
if you're,
if you're a great newtonian physicist at
the end of the 19th century,
what that might mean is that you're
actually such a great newtonian
physicists that you undermine the whole
structure of Newtonian physics.
So there's a tension there and you'll
see this in mythologies as well.
Okay?
No New Testament,
for example,
Christ is presented as someone who had
mastered his culture,
his dark truck completely by the time he
was 12 that's why you could argue with
the elders,
the temple.
So there's,
there's tremendous theirs,
theirs,
theirs
recognition in that story of the fact
that before a doctrine can be
transcended,
it has to be absolutely mastered,
otherwise you risk otherwise your hero
is so to speak,
risks only me being surface heroism,
which is,
it's actually undisciplined rebellion
and you're just using the mask and here
was to hide the fact that you're on
discipline from yourself.
See this,
it's an important,
I think this is particularly important
for people and cultures like well like
the north and North American culture
because we tend to think,
we tend to have a notion in our minds
that I think was fed by humanistic
psychology.
Most pain in the 60s that groups are
necessarily tyrannical.
And what a group does is squash your
individuality.
That's true.
Yeah,
it does that.
But the other side of the coin as well
as its squashing it,
it's also fostering it and there's no
way that you can get one without the
other.
Although some groups are more
totalitarian than others.
So that's what it group does.
It has to do that or it will disappear
and if it disappears,
well we know what the group does is it
brings order to chaos.
So if your group disappears then there's
just,
there's nothing but chaos.
So you know,
classic,
ample viewpoint is that the cosmos is
supposed to be property now it's right
for there to be the proper meaning.
There has to be the right amount of
order and the right amount of chaos and
I both,
both things are absolutely necessary.
Okay.
So I said absolute identification with
the group is motivated by the negative
consequences of the development of self
consciousness.
So I guess you see,
all right,
I'm interested in,
I was interested in trying to answer a
number of questions sort of
simultaneous.
Why is it that you would say you're in
Neil Knox,
that's a good exam.
Just say that you're a Neo Nazi.
It's kind of a strange thing to say
because if you're a neo announcing that
the same as all the other agencies,
so the you is almost disappeared
entirely.
You pick this group identification.
Now the consequences of the group
identification are that you surround
yourself with a whole group of people
think exactly like you,
so there's no threat in the group
whatsoever.
All anomalous information is placed in
the outside of the group.
But the other thing that's interesting
about being a Neo Nazi is that,
okay,
you're in it theoretically at least as
far as your concern,
because that's the best group to be a
part,
so you're very moral and upright as a
consequence of your identification
thing.
That's peculiar is that it also gives
you an immediate target,
and the target is the target for all
your resentment and hatred and cruelty
and all those things that you wouldn't
really think that you would have as the
member of the most optimal conceivable
group.
Of course,
you justify that to yourself by saying
that all that cruelty and resentment,
hatred is necessary in the service of
the group ideals.
But to see this makes me very skeptical
and that's,
so that's a rationalization as far as
I'm concerned.
I think the person that situation has
constructed up the world so that
simultaneously they can be protected.
Although they're cowardly.
They can be protected from anomalous
information with the group
identification and they can have all the
advantage of those,
of retaining their cruelty and
resentment and hatred while justifying
the morally.
Now the question then becomes what,
where does that,
this is something I think psychology has
real problem with cause we don't have,
we don't have very good time grappling
with higher order emotions like
resentment or jealousy or cruelty.
And we have a hard enough time with like
base level emotions like anxiety.
So why or where does the resentments and
cruelty come from?
What's at the base of it?
Why is it that someone would turn
against,
well let's not necessarily say turn
against life,
although you certainly do see that,
but at least turn against large segments
of life and attempt to stamp it out of
existence.
But that's why I tried to write this
chapter on the consequences of the
emergence of self conscious
consciousness.
So this is the basic idea.
Development of human self consciousness
has contaminated the domain of
unexplored territory with the threat of
death.
It's not something that makes us
different than out can.
I think that the valence,
we know from a very early age,
it's hard to say how early or five maybe
that we not only are able to react
emotionally to phenomena that we can't
predict.
I mean we can do that when we're too and
animals do that like a long ways down
the phylogenetic chain.
We have added to that the possibility of
inferring from the mere presence of the
known that the possibility of our
imminent demise or painful demise one,
one of the two and that's something
that's unique to people and I think
that's a big,
it's a very large part of what it means
to be self conscious when that's the
sort of thing we're going to try to
discuss today.
When you're self conscious,
it means that you can view yourself as
an object,
although you're a subject,
you can view yourself as if you were an
object in relationship to other objects.
And the thing about an object is that
it's something that has defined
characteristics,
right?
If you,
if you can identify an object,
you know its borders.
So this book has four sides basically,
and it's certain extension in space.
That's what makes it an object.
Well,
if you're self conscious,
what that means is that you can view
yourself as an object that has
limitations.
And we know our spatial limitations,
they're not that hard to defined.
Maybe even animals are aware of their
spatial limitations in the sense theory,
extension space.
But the thing that really makes us
unique is that we're aware of our
temporal limitation,
which is that if you have a beginning
and an end,
and that is something,
I think there's no evidence for it all.
And you know,
we'll paint.
It's something that makes us absolutely
unique.
And one of the things that that's done
to us is height I think has heightened
the emotional significance of the
unknown.
Because w you know,
we know that well you see this say in
hypochondriacal conditions,
you know,
someone has a,
well maybe they have what a normal
person would regard as a backache.
And the normal person,
so to speak,
would say,
well,
my back hurts and the way they go to
work,
but the hyper can drive.
Gold person says,
my back hurts.
That's the phenomena.
But the inference is I might die.
And so you say,
well,
the anomalous information is the
backache,
but it's a window into a realm of
unknown phenomena.
One and t hen you know,
those are known phenomena have a range
of possibilities and the range of
possibilities defined by death
fundamentally.
So I think that's one of the,
when when we say that we're conscious
are much more conscious than animals
sort say self conscious.
One of the things that we're saying is
that the emotional valence of phenomena
is heightened for us because we can
understand cognitively the consequences
of things that strike as emotional.
So there's a theme that the way things
are supposed to work is that so to
speak,
same report,
you didn't exist it and recognizing
something as anomalous.
So you focus your attention on a message
goes out to your prefrontal cortex and
the messages,
anomalous information,
reconfigure behaviors so it goes away or
be configured mode of interpretation so
that it's no longer threatening.
That's perfectly fine.
But if your prefrontal cortex then it
says,
Oh yes,
that really is much more friendly than
even then you might think as a
consequence of your natural impulses.
Then there's a feedback group that
develops where you see this and panic
attacks,
for example,
heart palpitations.
Well No,
I might die.
Well,
right.
The whole system cycles out of control.
The point being that the inhibitory
mechanisms that have developed
evolutionarily to help us conquer our
fears can also be used to dramatically
heighten them.
And when we talk about the development
of self consciousness,
that's one of the things that we're
talking about cause that's one of the
things that implies
selfconsciousness passable.
Well it's much less possible.
That's the whole,
that's one of the underground purposes
of group identification.
That's that's that's like underlying the
argument that I'm trying to make all
along.
Why identify with the group subjugates
years.
That's exactly right.
That's now.
That's now,
you see the problem with that is,
is that,
well,
the question is in some part,
what's the architect of self
consciousness?
What's the hero?
Now this is a strange thing because it's
pretty,
it's very paradoxical,
right?
Because something that's self,
something like us,
that self conscious,
part of that self consciousness itself,
consciousness of vulnerability.
And you think,
well that's the opposite of something as
powerful as the notion of the hero.
But it's not at all.
It's a precondition for heroism because
courage,
which is an essential aspect of heroism,
is predicated on recognition of
vulnerabilities,
right?
You have to know you can be hurt before
you can be brave.
Otherwise you just,
well,
you're just stupid basically.
Hey,
saying two things.
One of which I agree with though in that
I'm going to show,
if that's what you're saying,
the first is that we can abstract a
death.
We can think about it and make racist,
emotional valence,
right?
It's also a defining characteristic of
our b,
the fact that we're vulnerable to it.
Okay?
And the second thing that I hear you
saying is that humans respond,
uh,
stronger to the presence of anomalies.
That's right.
That's the argument I'm making.
We,
we,
we react more strongly to the presence
of a normal knee in general because we
can make,
we can make inferences about what the
unknown might mean,
which is only to say your plan for the
future.
And why is that?
Well,
it's because you can draw conclusions
from the present,
from occurrences in the present about
possibilities that may happen in the
future.
For example,
you have a healthcare program.
Well that's because you've drawn the
inference that uh,
being such as yourself is vulnerable to
a whole class of phenomena,
which includes,
well,
certainly the possibility of illness.
Any,
any set amount of severity up to a fatal
illness.
So you,
you make plans to take that fact into
account.
The fact that we'll do that,
it's one of the things that drives us to
construct cultures,
I think.
And that,
and that's part of the argument I try
and make as well.
Why do people,
why are people engaged in construction
of cultures?
Okay.
I,
I still tend to to see it as I would,
I wouldn't say that humans react
stronger to the nominally because like
you said,
when a rat is presented with,
with an an endless something in the
cage,
it freezes.
And you rarely see humans phrase that's
like that.
But the reason is I think because
animals cannot,
don't have this cognition to be able to,
to,
they don't,
you know,
they can't necessarily remember or,
or make these natural category as well
as we can.
And so what we would say is anomalous
information,
it only breaks certain levels and when
it does break,
you know,
maybe we can break these levels
consciously what I thought,
but I wouldn't say that that,
look,
I'm actually stronger.
Yeah.
Well I'm not,
you're,
you're touching on another argument that
we'll get to really near the end of the
course,
which is that although selfconsciousness
heightens the effect of valence of
something like the unknown,
it also provides a mode of dealing with
it that,
that animals don't have.
That's why,
well,
fruit,
I can,
I don't want to get into that part of
the argument right now though,
because it's very complicated and it
sort of presumes that we've gone through
all of this as a presupposition.
So because self like I'll,
I'll put it in very quickly.
The Christian,
the Christian myth essentially
presuppose it's two things.
One is that I'll,
I'll,
I'll talk a little bit about Buddhism,
the here in a minute too.
What is it that it was the development
of self consciousness consciousness that
knocked people out of paragraphs.
So that's what number one,
into the normal world and mass,
the world is characterized by awareness
of as manifested as shame,
which I think is precisely equivalent to
knowledge of vulnerability.
What else would it mean?
And knowledge of death and knowledge of
good and evil,
right?
All those things are congregating
together and the genesis story,
but the rest of the Christian story,
so to speak,
the rest of the story is how heightened
consciousness can actually be used as an
antidote.
So the thing is is that although a small
dose of something might kill you,
a larger dose might curie and that's
basically the notion that's that's under
law that well that underlies adaptive
mythology in general as far as I can
tell,
so a little knowledge is a dangerous
thing.
That's the apple at the snake provides
this.
You're like,
God,
you know who you are and what happens
when you know who you are.
When the human cases,
you get all the knowledge of God so to
speak,
without any of the power so you can see
your borders.
All of a sudden you know that you're
going to die.
You have to start making plans for the
future.
That means you have to work,
which is another thing that happens in
genesis as well,
so you're condemned to work.
The why you worked was because you can
view the future as a place of negative
possibilities,
all of which are hypothetical.
All of which you attempt to conquer even
before they appear.
That's planning and when you,
when you start up grain for the winter
is because you can perceive anomalous
information where it hasn't even
manifested itself in a sense.
That's intelligence.
We don't,
we don't,
we don't tend to to emphasize the
emotional aspect of intelligence that
much,
but extraordinary anxiety I think is
part of the force that drives
intelligence.
So anyways,
we'll get to the other part of that
argument lead.
Okay.
So I,
I'm trying to make the point that the
fact that people are developed
selfconsciousness has made us much more
susceptible to anxiety and also the
curiosity,
I think as it turns out than other
animals are.
And it's also provided motivation for us
to try to reject the fact of our
consciousness in any possible way.
And that provides additional motivation
for adoption of an authoritarian stance
just to save me.
It's the fact of your ignorance and
limitation that bring about all the
painful things that are associated with,
with hall humility basically.
I mean,
you think about the occasions when you
have to admit to making a mistake,
for example.
It's very,
I mean it's absolutely necessary,
but it's very,
very annoying.
It's embarrassing as a matter of fact
because because what it means to make a
mistake is that you admit to yourself
that you know that an essential aspect
of your vulnerability,
which is that you're obviously you
perfect and so and so on.
You have to actually make a statement
about pattern.
It is the case.
If you want to embarrass someone in that
space,
what you do social ways,
right.
It's like there are doing a good job of
hiding their vulnerabilities and just
pop a little information that makes one
absolutely evidence.
They'll turn red
fall into themselves,
so to speak.
That's one way of dealing with that is
to try to read you one way of dealing
with it is to try to rid yourself of the
of your individuality as one of the
things group identification serves.
Okay,
and the contamination of the unknown
with the threat of mortality.
I can animal a deer or something.
It's in,
it hurt her and her dad.
If they see a why am nearby or honestly,
herds of envelopes will raise quite
quiet lions.
Your,
as a general rule,
the lions have to manifest a particular
pattern of behavior before the lopes
become afraid.
And that's not really because there are,
it's not because they're afraid that the
envelopes would kill them.
It's because they're hardwired to
recognize a particular pattern,
predatory behavior and responding to it
with fear.
And if antelopes were self conscious and
could think they'd get the hell out of
the way,
and whenever there was a line anywhere
near and they don't,
they're not afraid of death,
they're afraid of the,
normally we're afraid of anomaly,
but it's contaminated for us.
It's contaminated with the possibility.
It's not just death.
That's just the biggest aspect of it.
But it's all imaginable suffering
basically.
And that's what you know how your
imagination can grip on to things.
Say It's,
you know,
if you were alone at night,
that's a good example.
You a little bit less stable than you
might otherwise be that day.
Some little nagging thing is worrying
you.
It's easy for your imagination,
take that little chunk of information
below it up and you know any number of
possible ways.
So it seems like Brandon was the
anomalies either either gives you this
emotional balance or you're here,
but as humans had this huge array of,
of,
you know,
we're normally it down here because we
can track these,
these,
the stories that protect us,
but then the thought can,
can bring us,
can titanus to,
to the level where we might need it to
get us the heck out of.
Well that's,
I mean I,
I you're referring to the possibility of
moving the information stored of up and
down levels of stories.
While I think that's one of the things
that's another one of the things that
are cognitive flexibility has allowed
mean it's,
it's a negative thing in some ways
because it does,
it means that you can make a mountain
out a molehill.
It's positive for all sorts of other
obvious reasons,
but maybe look regards to her original,
what the threat of death does for
civilizations.
You think about the Egyptians in the
Egyptian spent their whole time
essentially dealing with death.
That was the basis of their whole
culture.
I mean,
there are civilizations were devoted in
large part towards construction of these
massive pyramids and that took a lot of
work.
It took a lot of cultural energy.
We know some of the methodology behind
that.
I mean for the Egyptians,
the Pharaoh was the intermediary between
heaven and earth.
And to the degree that you participated
in the life of the Pharaoh,
you were granted at least partial
status,
the partial status of having an immortal
soul.
Well,
that was a potent enough motivator for
the Egyptian so that,
you know,
they engaged in what was essentially a
recreational cultural activity.
You can't really define what they're
doing in terms of any simplistic notions
of,
of making sure there was enough to eat
or any rational economically motivated,
uh,
ideas as far as I can tell anyways,
a lot of work into building those,
those more than monuments.
It's the same thing was true for this
medieval Christians.
With regards to the cathedrals.
Often those were the constructions of
those cathedrals sort of equivalent to
in a sense to that can alter the space
program and the 1960s height of
technological endeavor and you know,
a lot of our cultural activities
motivated by fear of death because we
plan then it's not just,
yeah,
it's vulnerability in general.
All right,
so the idea is this,
the fact that the development of self
consciousness has meant that for us the
unknown is contaminated with threat of
death has much more extreme emotional
valence for us than it does for other
animals.
Now,
one of the consequences of that is we're
much more motivated to plan for the
future and to construct how to construct
cultural structures in general.
The other thing is we're much more
motivated to get ourselves away from any
information that's anomalous,
to reject it,
to protect ourselves from it.
And that's one of the things that
underlies our temptation towards the
adoption of authoritarianism as an
authoritarian says in what's that?
The basis of authoritarian is it is
either the personal adoption of
omniscience hit inhibitors cases,
Darlin's case,
or it's the secondary adoption of
omniscience and uneven,
more cowardly mattered in someone like
Hitler,
at least this is the way I look at it.
He was sort of out on the front lines of
the authoritarian struggle and someone
could have taken a shot at him at any
time,
but all the followers of hidden and
they've got to identify with his power
and his beliefs,
not actually putting themselves on the
line and that's the essential nature of
an authoritarian stance.
Yes,
I know everything that needs to be no.
So if you offer any information that's
forward to my foreign,
to my my particular theory,
it's obvious that you're an agent of,
while we say an agent of chaos,
way something to be eliminated as is as
efficiently as possible.
Hence adoption of omniscience.
That's where the authoritarian is a
means and the motivation for that is
that if you know everything,
there isn't anything unknown and if the
unknown has this sort of vantage,
you can understand why people are
motivated to get rid of it.
Now the problem with the development of
an authoritarian personality,
this is why I wanted you to read Milton
because the note in this parable,
paradise lost,
is about the consequences of the
adoption of the numbness in stance.
That's the devil sin,
right?
So as I will be like,
God,
I don't want to take the place of God.
As soon as that happens in Middleton
story,
devil's cast down into to help where and
you can get out of it at any time just
by admitting he was wrong,
but he won't have been.
He was wrong.
And the reason for that is that if he
admitted he was wrong,
you have to face all the chaos that he'd
been avoiding.
I think it's a good,
this is one of our fries meeting of the
same parable.
It's a good or a little about the rise
of states.
Like in union,
there's a cumulative evidence gathered
up over the course of it.
I mean it was certainly,
it wasn't evident by the fifth.
Harmony doesn't look at working with
certainly evidence by the end of the
sixties it still took another 2030 years
before the system.
Well,
it's not like people gave it up really.
It's just more like the,
it just,
it wasn't even self supporting anymore.
Couldn't go on any farther.
They wouldn't admit to any anomalous
information,
which was inflammation that would
suggest that there are particular theory
was wrong.
Having just not,
it's not as if it's a stance that only
characterized as communists that
certainly it's just this is the stance
of authoritarianism in general.
Hell,
you know,
while we've talked about so far.
Yeah,
and the constituent elements of the
world.
Okay,
awesome.
We've only talked about positive aspect
of the individual,
not the native aspect.
That's what we're going to talk about.
The positive aspect of the individual
methodology is the part of that
voluntarily admit to the existence of
the unknown and that admission is a
precondition for the next stage,
which is creative exploration of that
unknown and then its transformation into
something that's either irrelevant or
something beneficial.
And then communication of that among the
group while on the question is what's
the,
what's the pattern that's opposite to
that?
And you can't sum it up in a,
in a sentence or in a few words.
It's like these other,
these are all natural categories.
Natural categories are full of all sorts
of big related information so to speak,
and I actually think this is the reason
why mythology Ken's to present these
different domains of the world as a
forum for action as personalities
because the personality is something
that's very complex and it's got lots of
different levels of motivation,
lots of different potentials for action
and the adversary of the hero is a
personality.
Christianity left personalities,
the devil one,
it is the case.
This is a claim by yell yet anyways.
Then Christy I think has the most well
developed notion of the negative aspect
of the individual potentially arguing.
Anyways.
All right,
I wanted you to read Milton's.
Well,
the funny thing is if you look at,
if you look in the old and New
Testament,
there's,
there's almost no reference at all to
the mythological figure if the devil
just like a few sentences and that's it.
And the entire book.
I mean all of the methodology that we
all vaguely know about what describes
the devil,
that's all.
It's dreamlike imagery that sort of
surrounds the canonical writings of
Christianity.
It's all storytelling and mythologies.
Milton tried to codify it.
It's kind of interesting.
I would say,
well,
why did this develop?
And it's because people have always been
fascinated by what constitutes the
essential aspect of evil and the theory
that we'd be discussing in this class
suggested evil for the sake of argument.
It's a pattern of action and a pattern
of interpretation leads to actions.
We tend to those patterns of action,
although we see them in story form.
First of all emerged from the forms of
behaviors and people observe the
behaviors and told stories about the
papers and so on.
Until we got to the point of abstraction
where we could construct an image about
the pattern of the say,
well,
mythological representations of the
devil.
It's not just the devil,
but the negative counterpart of the hero
throughout history are our cumulative
attempts to formulate it.
Image of the pattern of behavior and
interpretation that characterizes all of
the negative aspects of the individual.
So we're going to try to figure out what
those attributes are.
Well,
one of them is,
this is the why.
I think perhaps the one milton stress is
above all else is pride.
And that's refusal to admit to error.
And what does that mean?
If you think about
it means that refusal to admit to error,
his refusal to admit to the existence of
anomalous information,
it's precisely the same thing.
Yes.
And you know,
it seems to me to figure out too,
because all you have to do is observe
yourself in the course of an argument.
So you're arguing about someone arguing
with someone about something that's
meaningful to you and,
and you know what you're wrong.
Because you know,
sometimes they'd be either their
argument is just so much more
destructive than New York or you know
perfectly well that the moral ground
they stand on,
it's much firmer than yours.
It says,
well,
the thing that stops you from admitting
to the anomalous information,
which is actually that you're nowhere
near as good as you think you are,
the thing that stops you use pride.
Why is it pride and arrogance for that
matter in the context of the devil and
who was telling the stories and what
context,
why is it simply the refusal to submit
to the authority well into the authority
of God?
Look often white interpretation instead
of the
well,
okay,
that's a good question.
Look,
there's been a lot of books written
lately by Elaine Paige Hills for
example.
She wrote a book about the devil and she
basically said that the whole concept
was extraordinarily dangerous.
It was primarily a Christian concept.
She said,
Perp,
the function of the image of the devil
was essentially to,
uh,
to allow Christians greater ease in and
defining and bills who didn't hold the
same beliefs as them as an entity in
there.
I mean,
you can see that,
you can see the rationale in that
argument.
I mean,
it's,
that's what happens.
As soon as there's a war,
the enemy gets demonized.
Well,
it's not as much of a leap because a
stranger is an of chaos anyway.
It's chaos has a reptilian aspect,
so to speak.
You don't have to push people very hard
before they're willing to buy that
interpretation.
What I'm trying to say is that basically
is that the least natural categories may
tend to merge and Meld and mixed
together sort of helter skelter in our
heads.
They're not very well defined and they
have fuzzy borders.
Now it's very,
it's very simple for someone to say all
those individuals who do not accept
established order our prime of facie
agents of the devil,
and you can understand why they would
say that because if you don't accept
establish order,
then you're a threat to stability and
you are an agent of chaos.
Fine,
but the problem with that line of
argument is that by that definition you
can't distinguish those who update the
group from those who want to destroy it.
Right.
Is that in fact quite often couch,
yes it is difficult to tell,
but if you want to make a categorical
statement about what constitutes the
essential aspect of evil,
you can't say that evil is the process
that undermines the group because you
can't distinguish the process that
undermines the group from the process
that updates it and you know the process
that updates it is the board.
So whatever evil is has to be something
else.
So like people also tend to like,
I would also say that in the Old
Testament,
one of the great sins for the ancient
Hebrews was making idols on go on,
which is essentially the say that it was
considered immoral to categorize
something light go on.
In terms of something that was actually
understandable,
you always had to allow for the
transcendent aspect of God.
But I would say that people make the
same mistake when you're discussing
evil.
They want to make an idol out of,
which is to say they want to make it the
thing that's definable.
So it might be the process that
undermines established order or it might
be a aggression,
might be jealousy,
might be whatever.
Because know there's all sorts of
emotions.
It might be sexual desire and that's
being demonized time and time again,
that's making an idler well,
I would say just as just as you have to
regard the individual,
no one has a thing that can be defined,
but as a process,
which is to say,
I would say in archaic language of
spirit,
you also have to do the same thing with
the negative aspect of the individual
process.
No one other thing,
and it's the process by which an almost
inflammation has rejected.
So is that a reasonable answer?
Does that satisfy your question?
Well,
the thing is low,
it's confusing and what we're trying to
do to some degree is clear up the
boundaries of these natural categories
because it's very easy for the figure of
the devil,
so to speak,
to take on the aspects of the tyrannical
aspects of a border and also the
negative aspects of chaos.
I mean Girtha described the devil knows
the strange son of chaos and we tend to
think of anything that's at the moment
negatively valence as evil.
That's,
that's an,
that's just an example of fuzzy thinking
and w w w what since we're trying to get
out the basis of what constitutes
motivations for social conflict here,
it's very useful to start clarifying up
the descriptions.
We can't say,
well the unknown is evil.
That's not any good because although
it's very dangerous if you don't have
any around,
you come to a halt and you can't say,
well cultures evil.
Although you can say,
well it tends towards authoritarianism.
That's a problem.
It also provides you with necessarily
security.
You can't say that the process that
transforms orders,
he believe it because although it can be
very upsetting if you don't have it,
you come to a halt as well.
So by process of elimination and sense,
your left to the questions,
what can you define as evil?
Where does it go?
Assuming need exists?
Assuming an exist is a good question.
Well it depends on your death.
It exists.
I mean,
cause there's some news.
No,
it doesn't just exist as a religious
abstraction and we know that it exists.
I mean that's why we have things like
the Nuremberg trials and that's why we
have things like Holocaust museum in
Washington.
I mean even though we're not very good
at defining it and we don't exactly know
what it means when it occurs
even in in terms of consensus,
people can tell.
So hopefully what we can do is try to
figure out what it is and what it isn't
because it's easy to say if I'm part of
Group Bank,
all members of Group B are Evil and you
can understand why there's motivation to
do that.
Like Group B poses a real threat to
group bates non trivial threat has
nothing to do with their moral nature in
a sense.
And it's very easy for people to make
that presumption.
So one of the things I want to do is
clear up the categories so that it's no
longer possible to rationalize the
notion that just because you're a part
of Group B and I'm part of Group A,
you as a member of group,
we are necessarily evil and I
necessarily all good.
So,
so in a sense when you label another
group,
when you say that group is the devil,
you're sort of taking on the devil more
protective stuff.
Well I,
I I,
I would say that that's necessarily the
case here as soon as,
as soon as you adopt because,
well that's one aspect of it.
Anyways,
it's the inappropriate adoption of
omniscience.
Like level,
let's say you can even know it is
necessary for me to protect my group and
also that my group is valuable to
things,
which for me,
whenever you would never create any
debate,
we know the function of group.
The problem is when,
when you say one,
I personally am actually,
uh,
what would you say the most admirable
possible exponent of wine group,
which means first of all that I actually
understand its structure and that given
such understanding,
I actually acted out both of which are
highly debatable propositions and also
that my understanding of my group
processes is sufficiently profound for
me to determine what the absolute
certainty that you're wrong.
That for me,
that's arrogance.
I think that's pride.
It's also,
it's the underground adoption of,
and I'm missing steps soon as you do
that.
Well there are certain consequences
which
detail.
Oh Man,
I,
okay,
I'm confused.
Um,
we have the positive part of the
individual as somebody who accepts a
nonlinear,
we had the,
the negative individual how do the
individual as a process that rejects
anomalies.
However,
and we've already discussed the positive
part,
uh,
update society and yet we've also
discussed how the negative part is a
process that also a bait society,
uh,
you know,
through,
through fire.
The devil,
uh,
updates.
No,
no.
The idea here,
the idea of essentially was that if
you're in a group,
like say you're the spoke of a
particular group from within the group,
it's very difficult for you to determine
the difference between the power of that
wants to just lay the group to waste and
the power that we'll update it cause
they look very much the same,
which is why revolutionary heroes who
are often heretical are so badly treated
by group members.
It's like it's because they're dead.
They're indistinguishable from random
maintenance of chaos from,
well at least for less than
distinguishable.
Usually I think you can tell the
difference but people are not
necessarily willing to.
It was minute.
Okay,
so it's,
so we're still saying that the negative
part of the individual is the one that
rejects anomaly,
right?
Knowing that it's there,
knowing that it's there,
which is the second one,
something occurs
and at least at one level of analysis,
you know that it's undermining one of
your theories and you say it,
well,
no,
it doesn't exist.
I think given that the individual is the
houses,
the positive aspect of the individual
would be an aggressive like means toward
the unknown which would be the hero and
then the negative would be the group or
the culture which is instant.
Well it's partly that.
I mean that's why in the diag for that
growing the relationship has always been
like this cause because the negative
aspect of the individual heightens the
catastrophic danger of the group,
which is to say that if you take a group
that's entirely composed of individuals
who reject it,
normally what you have is a tyranny.
So to the degree that the group is
composed of individuals who reject the
normally it will become integrity.
One of the things that we're trying to
discuss in this class and to formulate
overtime is it the relationship between
individual action and group
identification,
which is to say like what can you do to
ensure that your group does not only
your group tending towards tyranny as it
necessarily will,
will not absolutely transform itself
into tyranny over time.
And the only thing you can do as an
individual is to ensure that when an
anomalous piece of information pops its
ugly head up and makes you realize that
you're vulnerable and mortal,
that you admit to its presence and take
the necessary action,
whatever those actions happen to be.
Now the problem is under some
circumstances that doing so will be very
dangerous to you.
That's essentially what culture is.
Culture is protect is protecting.
You are denying that which you know,
um,
can threaten to you.
Well that's part of it.
It's also,
that's only part of it.
I think to think of it as a parent,
which is to put it in its personality,
guys is very accurate because of parent.
Both protects you but exposes you at a
rate that you can tolerate.
Now,
one of the things we're going to talk
about at the end of this class is how,
how you can tell if you're being exposed
to the unknown at the proper rate.
And I would say just in passing that you
can tell when you're doing something
that's interesting to you that's
meaningful.
That's the indication that you're
sufficiently secure so that you're not
going to fall apart,
but also sufficiently open so that your
stability will be maintained over time.
The way that manifests itself is in the
feeling of interest.
That's when self consciousness vanishes
in part and time tends to disappear as
well,
so therefore can the hero be part of the
group?
Well,
the hero's necessarily what the hero has
to be from
heroes,
the group.
Right,
right.
But the hero can't necessarily can know
of the hero identify with the group
while still being a euro.
No,
I don't think so.
I think it's a matter of recognition of
the value of the group and also the
necessity of its being.
Yeah.
Without saying,
without trying to get from childhood to
individually.
I think about any group intermediation
whatsoever or without saying that the
group is the be all and end all,
which is what all groups wanted you to
say about them or without saying that
the group is only an impediment to
individuality,
which is just not,
it's also a precondition so it's more a
matter of appropriate.
Look,
here's an example.
This is a really good,
this is a good little parable.
It's from the gnostic gospels that were
discovered in the late 1950s.
Christ is walking down the road and it's
Sunday or Saturday,
actually,
it's the Sabbath Day.
And uh,
there's a man in a ditch and his sheep,
his fallen into a hole and he's,
he's picking the sheep out of the hole,
which you're not supposed to do on the
sabbath because by prostitutes were in
Christ test.
And Amanda,
if you know what you're doing,
then you're blessed.
And if you don't,
you're a transgressor of the law and
you're cursed.
Well,
and then he wants you saw him down the
road.
And that's like,
that's really quite an interesting
philosophical position because he said
to the man,
if,
if you actually understand the
significance of your actions,
which has bit,
you're breaking a moral rule that's
there for a reason,
you know,
the reason why the rule is there,
you appreciate its necessity and you've
decided as a consequence of that
appreciation,
it's still worthwhile to par the sheep
out of the hole.
No problem.
But if it's just a casual gesture,
you know there's something wrong with
the way you think and you'll pay for it.
So really it's a nice little story.
So in fact,
there are a number of parables in the
New Testament.
They're very much like that,
but that's not so it's very simple.
It's a very powerful little story.
Anyways,
I want to read you a Buddhist myth
briefly because it will,
it will,
uh,
put into story form some of the ideas
I've been trying to describe to you
about the relationship between the
development of self consciousness and
the contamination of things with the
idea of death.
Uh,
before you start,
I just wanted to ask you something
because there's been bothering me,
which is,
uh,
our reference to the identification of
the individual with the process rather
than to the individual sort of as the
process.
Yeah.
The thing that strikes me is that the
group is,
can be no more than a bunch of
individuals.
I mean,
I grew group is a,
it's a way of,
it's an abstraction that that puts a
bunch of individuals who are similar
together there.
And furthermore,
an individual is not the process unless
it's already has something to work the
process on.
Yeah,
I'm saying,
I mean the,
the known is as much a part of the
individual as the process is fine.
That's a perfectly good objection.
This is the Arctic individual,
right?
Like
this is a map of experience in total,
the whole thing.
And you can say,
well you're the sum total of your
experience,
which basically means that there's an
aspect of you that's characterized by
both participation in the unknown and
the consequences of being exposed to it
and the group inside you and the
architect will individually inside you.
But as we are all these things and the
grow your experience or your
experiences,
all of these things,
and you can say,
I am my experience.
Okay.
And I think that's perfect.
The reason,
no,
but it's the architectural rep
representations of the individuals that
constitute the process because there's
archetypical representation,
the wise king for example,
that's an individual who just occupies a
part of the whole,
the whole of,
of all of experience.
So yeah,
I mean what got me into this to begin
with,
at least in part,
was the recognition that to the degree
that there's a group,
it's in your head.
Right?
Right.
I mean because it is an abstraction.
It's like people,
you know,
I see people,
you go to the Canadian,
the u s border,
they get out of the car,
they look at the border because they
think the motors on the ground,
it isn't.
It's in their head,
but they have it confused with actual
world,
so the group isn't in the same way.
I mean the group is an intra psychic is
something that has an interest psychic
incarnation and as part of the reason
that this course is called socialites
got a terrible title.
It's called social identity and
information processing because social
identity plays a role in the way you
process information.
It's incarnated inside you,
so to speak.
All right.
Yeah,
because I've just been seeing him every
once in a while in this class.
It seems like we're confusing the arc to
the archetypes with actual,
right,
right.
Well,
and then not to know.
That may be the case as well.
I guess part,
I guess maybe that emergency in part
people's natural tendency is to identify
them more,
particularly with the group and to
counter balance that.
I guess I'm trying to put more stress on
this,
this aspect and perhaps even someone on
the
negative,
the negative switched on.
You've gotten both from above of young
nuns are positive.
Oh,
nice.
That's a good problem.
Alright.
Um,
positive.
Right.
Thank you.
Okay,
so let me read you this story.
What I want you to do is to,
you maybe read it.
What I want you to do is to think about
it in terms of the categories that you
know,
because you should be able to figure out
what story means.
Now,
the father of Prince Gautama,
the Buddha savior of the Orient,
determined to protect his son from
desperate knowledge and tragic awareness
built for him and enclosed pavilion,
a walled garden of earthly delights.
Walled Garden,
by the way,
means paradise.
Only the healthy,
the young and the happy.
We're allowed access to this earthly
fair.
That's all signs of decay and
degeneration were kept hidden from the
prints.
Now you remember what,
what food,
his father had been visited by an oracle
and the Oracle told him that his son was
either going to grow up to be a great
religious leader or a leader of like an
earthly leader,
politician.
Basically his father wanted him to be a
politician,
so he was trying to keep him away from
anything that would lead them towards
more spiritual concerns.
So you could say in a sense go Thomas
Farley wanted him to identify with the
group,
which is perfectly reasonable.
So he built this wall enclosure and
inside it we're only things that were
good.
Everything terrible.
It was kept outside immersed in the
immediate pleasures of the census in
physical law,
dance and music and beauty.
Azure Gautama grew the maturity
protected absolutely from the
limitations of portal being.
However,
he grew up curious,
despite his father's most particular
attention and will and resolve to leave
is seductive prison.
He wanted to find out what was beyond.
So as far the main preparations to,
I think this,
you know,
there was a,
this was a procedure that was often
fault,
the fault in the Soviet Union,
I think it was called a Potemkin
village.
You've heard him correctly,
is that right?
Yeah.
So I'm from tech village was a village
that the Soviets would construct a full,
stupid,
gullible Westerners.
So the Soviets would say,
we have a wonderful society come and
looks that they construct this
beautiful,
whatever it happened to be,
prison camp.
And the Westerners would come with him
and everyone would look at that and
healthy and the western is,
would go back home and say,
this will be,
aren't so bad.
Look at this model prison.
Anyways,
that was a Potemkin village and Thomas
Farley as basically trying to do the
same thing here.
So he wants to get outside of the wall.
So his father like whitewashed yourself
all the shacks and gets the beggars and
everyone off the street and there's a
little root carved out.
And uh,
that's the first trip.
So he covers his path with flowers and
displays alongside the road,
the fairest women of the kingdom.
The print sets out with all of his
retinue in the shield and comfort of a
chaperone,
chariot and delights in the panorama
prepared for him.
So things fall outside world is not so
bad.
The gods,
however,
decided to disrupt these most carefully
laid plans and sent an agent man to
hobble in full view alongside the road.
Prince as fascinated gaze fell upon the
ancient into local compelled by
curiosity.
He asked his attendant,
what is that creature stumbling,
shabby bent and broken beside my revenue
and the attendant answer.
That's a man like a man who was born in
the infant became a child.
Youth,
a husband,
father,
fathers.
He's become old subject to destruction
of his beauty,
his well in the possibilities of life.
Like other menu,
say hesitantly acquired the brands.
That means this will happen to me and
the attendant answer inevitably with the
passage of time,
lots of piece of anomalous information.
What happens,
it's like back to the walled city.
The world collapsed in upon guitar and
he has to be returned to the safety of
home.
That's a story about creative
exploration and that's exactly how
children offered.
They use their parents as a stable base
and the explore outside that base of
stability to the limits of their
tolerance for anxiety and when that
cards is exceeded,
they go back to their parents and the
whole exploratory procedure,
which is in fact the procedure that
leads to maturation is a constant
interplay of moving out and coming back
and moving out and coming back.
Theoretically each move out,
being slightly farther out as the child
learns that he can in fact tolerate
exposure to the,
to the unknown world outside of the
family.
So you got home as far the bills,
him a walled city and only good things
are inside of it.
That's exactly what we do for our
children.
Fundamentally.
I mean what you do if you have a child,
if you treat the child properly,
is to protect it from all those forms of
anomalous information that it,
that it cannot by any stroke of
imagination deal with so you know the
for or even understand for that matter.
And there's all sorts of things that you
don't discuss with children unless the
necessity arises and it's absolutely,
it's absolutely necessary and that's
what it means to take care of them.
Fundamentally.
By the same token,
you don't shield them from those things
that they are capable of actually
conquering anyways,
he's back home in time.
His anxiety lessens,
his curiosity grows and the adventures
outside again because time to go,
it's sent a sick man to view this
creature.
He asked his attended shaking and palsy,
horribly afflicted,
unbearable to behold,
a source of pity and contempt.
What is he and the attendant answered
that is a man like other men who was
born hold but who became ill and sick,
unable to cope,
a burden to himself and others suffering
and incurable like other men,
you say acquire the prints.
This could happen to me and the
attendant answer,
no man is exempt from the ravages of
disease.
You see,
this is a story about the development of
self consciousness because what Gautama
has discovery are aspects that he
encounters in the external world that
are actually also characteristic of him.
So it's a consequence of being immersed
in society.
He sees that it is possible for people
to die knowing that he is in fact
person.
The inference is pretty easy to draw
that that changes the structure of the
world substantially.
So now he knows that he get died and now
you can become sick.
So back to back to the castle once
again.
This time,
however,
it doesn't work so well because he's not
so happy with the things that used to
make him happy.
So he goes out a third time.
This time,
the godsend.
Send a dead man in the funeral
procession.
This creature,
he asked his attendant laying so still
appearing so fierce.
I'm surrounded by grief and sorrow lost.
And for Lauren,
what is the intended answer?
That's a man like other men,
born of woman I loved and hated.
Who once was unl.
Is there like other men you say inquired
the prints,
then this could happen to me.
This is your ends and the attendant and
the end of all,
man,
the world collapsed the final time and
get time.
I asked to be returned home,
but the attendant had orders from the
princess father and took them instead to
a festival of women who concurring
nearby and Grove in the woods.
Prince was met by beautiful assemblage
who offered themselves freely to him
without restraints,
song and dancing play in the spirit of
central love.
Good time I could think of when we have
death and the inevitable decomposition
of beauty to feel pleasure in the
display.
So for him,
the consequences of the emergence of
self consciousness for the contamination
of all good things with the possibility
of death.
That's a funny story because it's a
descent from paradise right when he
falls out of the protected city and
that's a catastrophe.
But it's also a precondition to his
eventual regeneration as the Buddha.
So you know,
that story is the story that we've been
talking about over and over,
which is
this story.
So this is the wall of the city
and outside of the walled city,
and there's but chaos.
And if a piece of the Nautilus
information
knocks down your structure,
then you end up in a place that's
defined by chaos,
which of course appears to be a complete
catastrophe to you because your emotions
are dysregulated and there's nothing
left but anxiety and depression.
But it's also the case that this
descent,
which in,
in these stories,
it's,
it's absolutely inevitable.
This is so,
it's very interesting because the
concept of original sin isn't explicit
in Buddhism,
but it's very much explicit in that
story because the reason that Buddha
goes outside of the walls,
because he's curious like,
hey,
he's happy.
Everything's going real well.
So you might think,
well,
you know,
why spoil a good thing.
But the point is he does for the good
things,
like it's not good enough.
What's outside the wall?
Awesome.
And so it goes and looks and the
consequences are,
it's like that's the end of the paradise
foy.
And you're not going to get back.
He's,
you're not going to go back to the same
place to get it.
It's gone.
Well,
that's,
that's exactly the same idea as original
sin in Christianity as Adam's Adam and
Eve's sin,
right?
They take the apple as the forbidden
thing that makes themselves conscious.
It makes them,
makes them aware of their own death,
makes them aware of their own nakedness,
makes it necessary for them to work and
tosses the amount of paradise,
curiosity,
original suit,
miscarriage.
That's what it is.
And it,
while,
and it's a funny thing because it's
also,
well,
it's also the auto fill.
That's an original sentence.
Also,
the precondition for,
uh,
for the whole redemptive story because
although this was paradise,
so to speak,
this place is on a higher order of being
than this place was,
I guess at that.
I think that's because here,
the paradise that precedes the original
descendants characterized by complete
lack of consciousness.
There's no consciousness there.
And the paradise that re emerges as a
consequence of this whole story is one
in which self consciousness exists and
his whole,
so it's,
well I think personally I think that's
partly because here's one reason
in a sense,
this pretty conscious paradise is
nothing.
It's paradise because it's nothing,
which means there's no suffering there,
but there's nothing else either.
And here at least there's actually the
world,
but it's the war.
So there is a world,
there's the possibility for suffering,
but it also represents a sort of mode of
being where there can be a world and
simultaneously people can live in it.
It's just the question that gets that
everyone's always trying to figure out
how is it that there can be a world and
that it can be tolerable at the same
time.
So because isn't it also that story
because that's simply what those
happened.
Everything.
It's an explanation.
Well,
I mean how did we get,
we can't be were originally simply by
watching what does happen.
Right.
Well the other thing about this story
too is that it's the story of
maturation.
Like you can think of it as it's,
it is theoretically a description of
what happened at the dawn of time,
so to speak.
And in a sense that's accurate in a
sense because there wasn't time back.
Who knows how long ago when we weren't
self conscious.
And this is something that's emerged as
a consequence of,
of you know,
who knows what processes and it seemed
to emerge very quickly if you assume
that the development of self
consciousness is related in some way to
the expansion of the Cortex,
which seems to be pretty reasonable
hypothesis.
The human cortex expanded unbelievably
quickly from the evolutionary viewpoint.
So our development of self consciousness
was that historical event.
I wouldn't say the business,
an accurate description of historical
event is,
it's not really trying to be that.
It's trying to describe the meaning of a
series of processes,
but more importantly also it's a story
of what necessarily,
how it was when you mature.
Because the thing,
like when you're,
you're,
you're say you're very young,
two years old,
your mother does protect you.
I mean it is literally the case that she
shields you from your vulnerability.
It's right here.
You have a screwdriver and you're
heading towards the electrical outlet
and your mother says,
well,
no,
you know there's a wall,
there's a wall there.
She tries to make sure that you don't
fall down the stairs or at least that
they're soft if you do and the old stick
your hand on the oven and so on and so
forth.
She's always there as an intermediary
and that's a form of paradise and you
say,
well,
what drives you beyond that paradise
lost your curiosity.
As you mature,
you get,
you develop a larger and larger
repertoire of behaviors,
more and more interest in what's going
on and outside world who finally you get
to the point where the things you know
because of your own curiosity because of
your own exploratory activity are so
complex that your mother and father,
they can't protect you anymore.
It's like you're outside the walls.
That's it.
If you try to go back,
it just means you're sick.
That's all.
I mean it's not a solution.
It's,
it's really going to solution.
We'll just make things worse.
So this is this story,
which is a mythological story is a story
that characterizes everyone.
That's,
that's why you know,
it's not such a very,
not very logical idea too,
to make light of a notion like original
sin.
So you figure out what,
what is it a heritable
heritable characteristics kind of
humanity.
It's fair enough,
far as I can tell,
especially if you look at the
consequences once you're self conscious,
you know,
it's very easy to view the world.
There's an unfair place and we can look
at it.
It looks like a pretty ain't fair place
and think about it.
And it is the case that you know,
your tooling along doing just fine and
acting appropriately as far as your
concern.
And it's like one day bang of cancer,
something equally horrible.
It doesn't seem to be any justice in
that at all.
It's not very difficult to turn an
animal into something that's aggressive.
Oh,
you have to do is punish it.
Unpredictable and unjustly.
What does that mean?
Well,
it means that the animal can't figure
out how to avoid the punishment and also
that the punishment,
well that's the primary aspect of it.
As far as the animals concern and we're
in that position all the time.
It's like terrible things happened to
us.
That seems completely independent of our
particular behavioral patterns and
that's one of the things that turns
people against the world.
But that's what makes me,
right.
Absolutely.
That's in fact in an earlier version of
this manuscript,
in this chapter I had a sexual and
learned helplessness because it is the
case that if you punish an animal and it
can escape,
but what happens to them
also get aggressive?
Well Gretchen is one of the things that
might happen along the way.
I handle the circumstances.
For example,
like if you take an animal and you shock
it,
it's in a cage.
Well it Kevin you get aggressive cause
there's nothing to get aggressive about.
Like,
like let's say you take out,
take a wrap,
Nelson,
his cage and any shocked the wrath
killed him ups.
So to some degree the effects of
punishment or a situation dependent and
punishment does do two things.
It's an unconditioned stimuli for
aggression and it's also conditioned
stimuli for for extinction of behavior,
which she has learned helplessness.
So there's these two pathways to,
and it's almost the case.
Like you
say,
it's a thought experiment.
There's a cat here and you chase around
with a stick.
Any corner,
any neck if you're an you poke it with a
stick was going to hiss,
hiss and fight.
But if you keep doing it sooner or later
the aggressive response has been
extinguished and it'll just pass bath is
to lay there and take the punishment.
That a thing of the thing that's funny
about your example,
we are in that situation,
sorry,
the learn like our conditions of
existence are very much and now it gets
to those experiments that psychologists
and conduct that produced learned
helplessness.
We are close to at least some subjected
to um,
unpredictable.
Our problem is we have to learn how to
deal with it nonetheless.
Yes.
Part of what we're trying to just
discover in these messages.
Is there a possible way of doing that?
Also while admitting to the fact that it
is the case,
because one way of doing it is just to
deny it,
deny the fact that terrible things out
fafsa and the recent social psychology,
psychological literature,
there's a whole body of studies that
suggest that that's the best way to do
it.
That's right.
Has themself allusions.
Um,
I know it's only all these things that
happened to one or only
one thinks that there's some reason
they're not,
and then it wasn't there.
I missed the trend.
Is that a punishment because it's a
negative experience or it just happened
that I missed the train?
It's not anything can do well.
Huh?
See,
yeah,
I see what you mean.
I think the inference that we generally
drive that regardless of whether there's
a will behind it,
it's arbitrary and unfair.
I mean the training things slightly,
it's me,
it's too minimal to make a case out.
But I mean,
if someone close to you and develops,
like say someone that's close to you,
that's also universally recognized as
good,
develop some absolutely atrocious
disease,
which happens with a fair amount of
frequent frequency under conditions.
It's very difficult not to draw the
inference that despite the lack of will
behind the disease,
it's evident that the world as it's
constituted is a very unfair place.
It because it certainly those sorts of
things would run contrary to all our
notions of what constitutes fair.
Do you have an expectation that the
world is at their place?
That's how you define it as unfair or do
you think that,
I mean,
it seems to me,
nevermind.
No,
that's what,
go ahead.
Well,
seems to me that
until the current age where everyone
fairly well accepts the whole idea of
evolution.
Yeah.
When there's no real reason,
there's no meaning for us to be the
types of creatures that we are.
It just sort of happened before that I
think philosophers strove very hard to
find the meaning to explore why it was
the way it was.
Yes.
Um,
in,
in that sense that there was an
expectation that the,
the,
the world should be just right.
There's no reason for it not to be
unless,
unless there's,
if it's not just,
there must be a reason it was worth
uninsured now that,
okay.
I guess I would say that I see the logic
in your argument.
I guess what I'm trying to figure out is
that you like is it possible,
is it possible for us to exist in any
sane manner?
Which I would say saying being in part
not in adopting authoritarian
identification with groups and civil
tediously pa be able to accurately after
him the fact that the fundamental
structure of the world is falling,
neither fair nor I'm fair,
but at least it appears to us under many
circumstances.
It's very unfair.
And the answer that seems to be no,
I think all right,
is that people who are faced with that
sort of choice frequently take a route
out of the problem that actually makes
it worse over time.
For example,
they'll adopt,
uh,
in an authoritarian stance as a means of
protecting themselves against types of
information.
They kept tolerant.
So I guess part of what I'm trying to
find out is there,
is there a story that makes sense out of
things that we necessarily perceive as
unfair one?
And that's kind of one of the things
we'll try to discuss it over the rest of
the course.
So I'm just saying what are like I want,
I'm trying to do today is line some of
the consequences of did this.
I think people do have a implicit idea
that the world is fair because the part
they're given that when they're brought
up,
when their kids,
that's one of the things he tried to do
with the child's environment.
Sorry,
do you make sure the rewards and the
punishments are distributed in an
equitable and predictable manner and not
towards the twos justice in large part
and one of the things the child
discovers and it's necessary to do that.
The child would just completely like,
we'll be in developed by chaos and
terrible things will happen.
It's necessary to do that.
But if you do do that,
then when the child goes out into the
world,
he will discover,
she will discover in short order that
there are all sorts of things that have
that don't fit into that framework even
though the framework that has this.
So I would say that that is our natural
response is like this is unfair.
And that's,
I think that's part of the reason why
tragic things,
especially those things that appear
possibly unnecessary.
Like say someone that say something that
you're very close to is brutally
murdered,
sort,
sort of on a whim by something halfway
did psychopath.
I mean that's the sort of thing that's
not only seems incredibly tragic but
also completely pointless.
It is those sorts of things that really
undermine our ability to believe that
our existence is have any meaning at
all.
And then distance is predictable.
I'm not people in their hands very close
to uh,
develops cancer.
Saying the attribution could be that
this is unfair,
but what you're really saying is that it
was unpredictable.
There's no way.
Well that's one aspect that would be
unfair attribution.
It's unpredictable.
Plus,
I think it's also an unjust judge.
Yeah.
But if you're just not intelligent
enough,
you don't add that up.
It's not true.
If you don't have what,
you don't have.
The fact that it's adjustable because I
don't know if you do,
like what do you think?
You might say it's not logical to do so,
but I would say that if it happens to
you you will do it.
Yes,
I agree with it.
That is generally the way we work,
but I don't think that,
I don't think that's across the board
the case.
And I think,
I think,
I don't see why you couldn't,
why you can't get beyond that.
What I really wanted to say that was
something that you said about when you
were saying that children that you teach
children that the world is fair,
but it seems to me that that's often not
the case because I think chil children
often use that as,
as their complaint.
That's not fair.
You know,
is not fair.
And one of the things that I've always
heard parents say to kids as well,
well life isn't fair.
You know,
one of you say that to a child,
you're not actually communicating any
information.
You'll just rationalizing the present
situation because of the truth of the
matter is,
is that if you set up a stable
environment,
everything you've done has led the child
to believe that in fact,
the world is fair,
which means it is predictable and it's
just,
but I do think that maybe you're just
exposing them to that you're exposing it
to them slowly,
like in the small thing,
like you can't have the ice cream
because,
well,
I do think that's what you're doing
eventually.
Maybe they will learn that life.
Why shouldn't they learn eventually that
life isn't fair?
But the question is,
once they learned that life isn't fair,
what do they do?
Let's this fear.
Let's see the unabomber for an example,
because I know,
I know what I think.
I know what he's like.
He's someone who thinks that the world
fundamentally is an unfair place,
and then it's his moral obligation to
take revenge against it.
Now he's picked certain aspects of the
world to take revenge against.
But his,
like in his self consciousness,
he construes himself not only as a
victim of unfair then just forced us,
but as the kind of victim and who has
the right to cast judgment on is
victimization and to take action in a
vengeful action essentially.
So look,
where does he live in a cabin in
Montana?
Why is that?
Well,
I'll tell you,
it's so that he won't get contaminated
by the rest of the human race,
that's for sure.
So he might've been rejected,
but he's sitting there thinking like in
the back of his dark and stormy and
little brain that that,
that half
the human race is fundamentally evil and
the only appropriate thing to do is to
detach yourself from it.
And there's also an,
a tremendous amount of volume,
the scn posturing and arrogance at the
back of that,
which is why he could spend all this
time constructing bombs and sending them
off to more or less random targets that
he inappropriately identifies with the
natural methological categories that
make up this thinking.
You know?
So he's mad at university.
So we bombs individual professors.
I mean,
you know,
this is,
this is not,
this is not inappropriate.
So the question is,
if you construe the world he has an
unfair place,
what did you do?
Well,
I would say one of their,
I mean we can either change your action
or you can change your thinking.
Have an alternative.
Yeah,
but you need an alternative that you can
believe.
You can't just,
you can't just say,
hey look,
this is a problem.
I mean,
the,
the problems that self consciousness
pose,
it's an emergent problem.
Let's say it's only a problem that's
been around for a million years.
It's nobody's figured out what to do
about like,
because as soon as you become self
conscious,
it appears that the world is an
arbitrary and unfair place.
Then the question is,
if the world is an arbitrary and unfair
place,
how should you respond to them?
Now an animal subjected to evidence that
suggests that the world is arbitrary and
unfair develops,
learned helplessness,
just depression.
Now lots of people develop that like
they quit.
It was because why bother?
Which is a really potent argument.
Why bother if such and such is likely to
happen to you,
which it undoubtedly is.
Why do anything?
Well,
that's that.
Lots of people don't accept that our to
because they never think about it or
whatever.
For whatever reasons they're protected
from that line of logic.
But another line of logic is,
well,
let's take some revenge against the
world.
That's a potent line of logic as well.
Group girth that for goods and for
example,
his,
his notion of the,
of the fundamental philosophy of
Mephistopheles,
who's the,
you know,
literary incarnation of the negative
aspect of the archetypal individuals
west.
This is memphis off these credo.
The world is such a horrible place
intrinsically,
but the best thing you can do for it is
to work for its eradication.
Hey,
lots of people except that line of
argumentation.
I mean you say,
well,
why?
Like why did the Nazis killed 6 million
Jews?
Well,
it's hard to say exactly why,
but I suspect that at the bottom of the
individual psyches that participated in
that sort of act was the notion that,
you know,
after all the world isn't relatively
harsh an unfair place and it might not
be so bad to take a little bit of
revenge against it.
It's like balancing that,
you know,
it's done.
The world has done a lot of terrible
things to me.
It's like what's your attitude to that?
Revenge is one.
It's like all she'll do those all show
those whatever the hem to be.
I'll show those jeeps,
whoever you pick as your target for
having inappropriate be persecuted you.
So,
and I,
I,
what I'm trying to do is to get at the
bottom of that.
So why would people be like that?
I think it has something to do.
The necessary consequences of self
consciousness as soon as your self
conscious.
Well,
the genesis story says it quite clearly.
What happens when you cover yourself up
because you're ashamed and why are you
ashamed?
Because you know you're naked.
But what does that mean?
It means that you can view yourself as a
somewhat vulnerable pink thing.
That really could be
who's also subject to all sorts of
social pressures,
many of which are negative,
who needs a substantial amount of
protection just to ensure survival
continued from day to day.
Give an even that that survival is a
doubtful,
is doubtful in the long run.
That's the basis of shame.
The other thing that happens in the
genesis story is as soon as Adam and eve
discovery,
they're naked,
God comes walking through the garden and
they're hiding.
Why would,
this is a strange bit of the story is
why would you hide one?
A few things,
say maybe you could look at it this way
then
from the mythological perspective,
God's voice,
so to speak,
is the thing that calls you to do your
basket to perform to the maximum of your
ability,
and why wouldn't you do that?
Why would you hide from that?
And the truth of the matter of reasons
that we all hide from that.
Because what we recognize most
profoundly about ourselves as our
inadequacies and those inadequacies make
it impossible for us to believe that we
could do our master that would even be
worth doing.
And that's what the story about hiding.
And certainly the case that we do that.
So what happens if you hide from the
best in you?
Well,
we know if that's the archetypal hero,
you hide from that,
then you have no defense at all against
chaos because that is the defense.
Abandoned that because you're afraid
what's left.
The only thing that's left is the
protection of the group.
So if you abandon what's best in you,
the only thing you can do is become
authoritarian.
As soon as you do that,
while lots of things happen.
So you have to have the group that,
because if it disappears your gap
because there's nothing left of you.
Plus anyone that's out there that
reminds you of what you might've been
you hate.
Wow.
So then you have a good reason for
rubbing them out.
What's the job's doing through this?
Isn't this what Joe,
the book of job is been?
Well you don't view that book as a sort
of a narrative precursor to the story of
a Christian redemption.
So he said it was like the whole,
the whole Bible basically tells a
redemption story and that one of the
things that the story of job
necessitated was the emergence of a full
blown hero myth.
That's why fry says for example,
that the idea of Christ is embedded in
the old testament.
It's implicit in there,
which is to say that the Old Testament
is a story that cries out for a hero and
that's also why there are notions of
prophecy.
For example,
saying this person,
the millennium is going to arrive,
which is to say where we are in a
position,
which is this position that calls for
the,
we know the story,
we have to be here.
The rest of the story is the arrival of
something that will move us out of
there.
It's like these are all people that are
caught in the belly of the beast.
For example.
They're waiting for the hero to go down
into the belly and freedom.
So it's such a kind of unsatisfying
story.
The job's story.
Right,
right.
Makes perfect sense.
Right?
Yeah.
Well that's a chunk of on,
why is Joe Joe his story?
Well,
cause he never learned what to do.
That's right.
The arbitrary nature has this big speech
about how wonderful wisdom and isn't how
God created the world.
And since he created it,
he has the intimate knowledge of how
everything works and to wisdom.
And then God comes in a world when
instead it's like I'm God European on
suck it up.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
And then he gets all this stuff he ever
lost.
What would you rather suck it up or
figure out what to do for yourself?
Well,
there's nothing you can do.
It was it like,
oh completely.
But that's not the message.
The message of Christ is that there is
something that you can do.
But this was
the message of Christ and the story of
Joe,
the whole like,
look at what job's like predicated on
like Gods and God and Satan there.
Which is kind of an interesting thing.
Like,
okay,
sure.
Anyways.
Well there,
there,
there is a book,
there's a book that was written
specifically to address this problem,
which is answered to Joe.
I assume stealing spoke it.
Him.
Yeah.
Describes this issue particularly,
but we also want to make sure that we
can distinguish g,
uh,
or that we put the story of job sort of
on a broader perspective,
which is the story of someone who's
desperate fundamentally for very good
reasons.
And the thing about desperation in
general is that it calls out for a
solution.
That's all.
That's all off.
The only appointment I was making is
that the story of job is the story of
someone who's in as desperate as
circumstances as can be imagined.
And that's how the story is structured,
right?
I mean,
it doesn't get us and he doesn't get
solution.
It's a solution,
but it's not the best solution or one
they appeal to our sense of fairness.
That's exactly the issue though.
That's exactly this problem.
That's what makes it on satisfactory.
That's exactly the issue.
We demand.
Fairness exists,
right?
That's what we do to map that.
No,
we don't.
No we don't.
Because as soon as you get past that,
then you're like,
let's say we'll abandon fairness as a,
well,
you better
watch out for me then well then if you
look at it from God's point of view,
it was fair because God is God and you
can do whatever he wants and there
wasn't preexistent bet,
which it's very hard for us to separate
them.
And that's what religion is for.
You have to have faith.
There's some greater like plan out there
that we can only see a small snippet up
so we can't possibly understand so well.
Well
let's just consider for a moment that
some of the fundamental interpretations
of these things are culturally bound by
the Christian tradition that they're
necessarily universal questions are,
yes,
yes.
Well this is,
this is a problem,
but that's why I said that we should try
and look at the story sort of outside of
both traditions,
if that would be possible.
And to see it as a story of something of
someone who's getting the aspiration.
That's all
true enough.
I mean unless we got a very diverse
representation of peoples from all the
time.
Well that's kind of what we're hoping
seeped in the Judeo Christian.
True enough,
but that's what we're trying to do in
part in this class.
Even though in terms of personal
representation we don't have like we're
not as diverse a group as well.
You might be.
What are the things hopefully that we're
trying to do is contrast and compare
enough traditions so that we can see the
stories that are common to all of them.
Now this is going to be a problem in all
sorts of different ways,
but I'm hoping that the enough
information in general,
not just in the context of this class
has been gathered so that we can start
to see patterns that transcend
particular,
particular viewpoints without
undermining how do you avoid the problem
of seeking confirmation and other
conditions so that you have already
within one tradition a sense of what the
fundamental elements and then because
traditions are broad and inclusive you
can find good question.
Good question.
The ones that are most important to you
and how,
how do you avoid that problem of bias?
That's an excellent question.
I mean,
look,
that's an absolutely,
absolutely solid question.
The fundamental like I think one of the
reasons why there has been such a
discrepancy between scientific
viewpoints and mythological viewpoints
is because in science we have a mode of
determining what comes to or institutes
of truth,
at least provisional truth,
regardless of the desires of the
exponents,
of any given at any given truth.
Here's a methodology.
The problem with moral viewpoints is
that we don't have a methodology now,
and this may be in some ways,
in some ways it's an insoluble problem I
think because I don't think that we can
come to a conclusion about what is good
by the same sort of process of consensus
necessarily that we use in science
because it's hard to point to an object.
Okay,
so then the question as well,
so how do you get to,
what comes to mind?
What might constitute a fact?
Well,
the only way that I can see that it can
be done is by looking
at various cultures and various
historical traditions and also by
drawing in information from other fields
of endeavor,
if that's possible.
That's why I've been trying to look at
both the neuropsychology of the
emotional brought an information
processing plus looking at at various
historical traditions.
So the problem of looking for what you
want and finding it is a big problem and
maybe there isn't an entirely
satisfactory solution of the present
time.
But it strikes me that there's enough
data gathering so that we can at least
make some movements towards that end.
So
I think I have a solution.
Oh,
this is good training program.
Well,
the,
uh,
I think it would,
I think that would be the hardest way to
do it.
The way you're doing it now is I
presented it in a conscious level,
but I think you'd be presented on an
unconscious of them.
Create your own story.
And of course you have to have
confidence in you and what you've come
up with and see that it is,
you know,
something that is more right or
whatever.
But anyways,
you create the story and through the
behaviors that are embodied in the
story,
you are passing on this kind of wisdom
knowledge,
the same thing that Jesus did in making
his parables and other figurative
language stuff.
And he said,
well he was able to pass that on through
those stories.
Not necessarily.
This is also,
this is also an issue with regards to
the methodology.
The problem with with discussing truths
about how to add is that the only form
that you can actually test them out and
use it in your own experience.
It's like,
so if you say,
why should act such and such a way you
can't ask anybody else,
should I act this way?
Because they can't tell you.
I mean you might go to hell,
you should listen to them.
Maybe they have some good information
for you.
But in the final analysis,
you're the only one that can figure out
if the way you're acting is right.
And not only that,
it's worse than that because you have to
define the criteria by which you
determine if the way you're acting is
appropriate.
Right?
So you're,
you're kind of caught with decisions to
make the matter which way you look.
Well,
that's one of the things that I'm going
to try to address later in the later in
the course because these sorts of
things,
these sorts of things pop up being,
since you can't rely on anyone else in
the final analysis,
you have to rely on yourself.
And then the question is,
well,
how is it that you can be sure that you
can rely on yourself?
Why do you say that you can't rely on
anybody else?
You have to realize,
well,
partly because nobody else can feel your
pain.
I mean,
that's the basic,
because there's an aspect of your
experience,
the subjective aspect of no one else has
access to and what's right for you.
It's going to be,
it's going to share,
there's gonna be overlap between that
and what's right with other people and
what's always be going to be right.
But it's gonna be unique to you.
What about the what,
what about recap?
We cast a lot of this whole thing in
terms of interpersonal interactions as
opposed to an individual's actions
against the world.
So for example,
when you were talking about how the
child learns,
the child explores his territory,
it's a very,
yeah,
Jillian [inaudible] information and the
mother is there as sort of a protector
to protect you from the world rather
than using a whole nother way of looking
at that same child learns,
doing,
interacting with the mother.
I think absolutely top of the story of
Buddha,
Buddha goes out into the world rather
than anomalous information.
Part of the interactions with the sick
person,
an old person in a dead person,
but these are interactions that were
previously,
look at this diagram.
One of the ways that an individual
generates information is through going
back with the unknown,
but the other way that he generates
inflammation is through contact with
culture.
And in the case that you're describing
of the mother who is providing
information as an intermediary for
culture but also another person,
I mean people,
sure.
But a lot of cultural information is
embedded in other people,
not just in what they say.
Let me how many APP?
As soon as you interact with someone
else,
they're providing you with all sorts of
cultural information in the interaction
or is there still something else you
mean?
Yes,
yes.
Asking some of these questions that
asked a lot of these same questions,
but my area of concentration in social
psychology
and I spent a lot of time trying to
figure out what level to ask a question.
Um,
why does an individual harbored,
for example,
to create,
to do her ethic that or what is it about
a group?
Okay that needs the group to do
clarifications or what is it about the
dynamics between two groups that causes
one of them to do these things to the
other one?
And it seems to me that you can ask the
question at every level and it's hard
for me to understand why one,
is this views of all of those levels put
together or is it focusing on one limits
to things like it's an attempt to
integrate
ideas about group car.
The,
the,
the question really for me as an why do
groups engaged in cons?
It's why do the individuals that make up
those groups actually conducting
individual acts that make up the
conflict?
Okay.
And since I'm interested in,
in the individual as like the four
runner of the group,
what can the individual do personally to
reduce the likelihood that given the
preconditions they will engage in those
sorts of peripheric actions?
That's my,
like specifically that's my concern
in which individuals are doing these
things.
So for example,
if I were a Nazi teachers
Nazi in Germany,
German,
and my job was to,
I dunno,
throw the switch on the train line
somewhere down the line.
And you may ask,
now why would I do that?
Well,
one reason is because if I don't do it,
somebody else will do it.
Well,
that becomes irrelevant.
What,
why did I throw the switch?
Because the switch is going to get
thrown whether I threw it or not.
Okay.
Well that's,
you know,
that's,
that's uh,
uh,
well that's a very untoward or arguments
similar in some ways to also carrying it
on as a consequence of borders.
It's like,
you know,
you're a hierarchy.
Why did I throw the switch?
I'm asking why are you asking why did I
throw the switch?
I'm telling you,
don't ask me why I did it.
Ask me why the switch got thrown in.
To answer that question,
maybe you'll have to look at something
beyond me.
Maybe.
I would say you don't have to look at
something.
I would say that it was the pattern of
your whole life up to the point where
you threw the switch that made you into
the sort of creature that would think
that that was a normal app.
Like Kinda Rod said,
people has been out.
I think she was wrong actually.
I think that it's not valid.
It's just that many of the things that
we think are but now are actually heat.
So that's this things,
so to speak,
that we do every day that don't have any
immediate consequence.
We write them off.
So there've been out,
but they're not by now.
Because if you look at what you're
doing,
the consequences of that over time or
say why does society is going say well
it's because the individuals that
composable conduct the activities that
they think are saying no one notices,
no one said anything.
They're not saying they're completely
off the wall.
And the culmination of all those
[inaudible] actions is a society
composed of individuals that all things
are good,
who are acting on mass and an absolutely
boring way.
So say in part,
I mean one of the things I'd be trying
to answers,
they just question posed in the late 18
hundreds he said are their
psychopathology is of health.
And what he meant was,
was it possible for someone to be
perfectly normal and well adjusted,
well adapted,
and they did an admirable by the
standards of their society and still be
sick.
And you know from the perspective of
cultural relativism,
the answer's no.
But from the perspective of the number
of trials to answer is,
Oh yes.
So what I'm trying to figure out is if
you can be sick by doing what everyone
else is doing,
does that imply that there's some
universal standard by which being sick
can be judged?
I'm going to say,
well yes.
Three this says if you are open to the
existence of anomalous information,
you admitted it when it occurs and you
update your behavioral models as a
consequence,
then you're healthy.
If you're not well then you're not.
How can an individual do that?
How can I in the train station admit the
anomalous information?
Actually there's two preconditions.
What has been,
you have to admit that you're vulnerable
to even to being killed and to accept
it.
And the second is to to risk putting up
with the fact that the group might
actually do it too.
So that's what you have to do that
delete the group.
That's right.
No,
not only that,
you have to leave the group knowing that
if you do leave,
they might kill you and are very
motivated to do so.
And that's a classic hero myth as well
as the hero.
There's two things,
death weights at the end.
And so does the negative reaction of the
group.
So if you want to transcend the group
that's,
that's what you do.
Say can you do it?
And I was too much for any individual to
do.
Well that's the,
that's the question.
I would
say it's,
it's kind of,
there's a paradox.
It's a paradoxical solution.
Actually.
If you tried it is possible that if one
tried it,
it might be possible.
And if it were possible,
it may be that there were side effects
to doing it.
It might actually eliminate all the
things that appear negative about it.
So,
and I would say,
well look,
I mean the,
but the basic problem is how do you
adapt to the presence of chaos
when it's unfair and unjust aspects?
Cause what ways do you identify with the
group?
That's what the groups for the other way
is that you learn how to deal with it on
your own and the questions can you,
and if the answer is yes,
then that implies that you're a
different sort of creature than you
think you are.
And if you're a different sort of
creature than you think you are,
maybe the world is not configured it
unfair and unjust,
man.
It may be that it appears that it is
because you have an inadequate opinion
of your own power to adapt.
And I would say that the purpose of
pyramids generally is to provide you
with some evidence home from history.
Then there's far more to the individual
that meets the odd enough,
more so that the conditions of existence
that we normally regard as unjust and
unfair are.
But the only way you can find out is if
there's a big risk.
We know what the risk entails.
I mean,
what we've been trying to figure out the
whole time is why do people identify
with groups when there's a big good
reasons?
So helps them regulate their emotions
and protects them from terror.
So people are well motivated.
You can you get me on that?
That's the issue.
Okay,
so
that's that for this weekend.