The good news is that there was some
overlap.
So I think that despite all the cue
cards on here,
we will be able to,
um,
answer quite the cross section a.
So in some cases they've been split up
between Dr Pearson and Dr Doidge.
Uh,
in other cases it's just a generally
speaking.
So Dr Peterson,
I think,
nice way to conclude your remarks.
Um,
why are the postmodernists doing this
and to what end?
Well,
I think you should distinguish between
the postmodernists and postmodernism and
in some sense,
because you don't want to be thinking
that,
you know,
each radical person on the left,
let's say for the time being is a full
fledged Avatar of postmodernism because
they're not,
they're like,
you know,
60 percent reasonable human being and 40
percent puppet mouthpiece of a toxic
etiology,
you know,
and so it's fragmented across people and
that makes it,
of course much more complicated because
you get to know someone like that and
you think,
well,
they've got some good intentions.
Not nearly as many as they think they
have,
but they have some good intentions and
you know,
they have a history of really things not
so good that happened to them.
It's no wonder they feel kind of angry
about it,
so like,
but then that's why you got to get to
the bottom of things.
It's like,
and the bottom is very far down.
It's like
this is where things get crazy.
It's like,
well,
there's a battle between two ways of
being in life,
you know,
and I've taken that apart to some degree
in my lectures on Cain and Abel and one
way of life is to make the sacrifices
that you have to and to try to aim
towards the good and hope that the
sacrifices that you make please the
Lord,
so to speak.
It's how you bargain with the future,
right?
You make sacrifices in the present
toward something you hope will be good
in the future and you hope that pleases
the reality and it's smiles on,
you know,
and then,
and then the other way of being is that
you noticed that your hard work is often
ignored and that you don't get what you
want.
Well less deserving.
People do and it turns you against life
itself.
Like it turns you against more.
Worse than that.
It turns you against being.
I don't know how else to put it.
I mean because I've studied,
you know,
like why do you go into Connecticut into
a classroom and shoot a bunch of
elementary school kids and Ben Yourself?
I think he shot himself,
but it doesn't matter because usually
that's what happens.
It's like what stared of state of mind
do you have to be in to do that?
Well,
I knew what sort of state of mind you
have to be in to do that,
but the only way to describe it,
it's sold down there that,
you know,
it gets fundamentally.
It's like,
well that's the pathway of cane.
It's like being as something that should
not be despise every bit of it.
I'm going to take my revenge on it.
I'm going to find the most innocent
people I possibly can and make them
suffer and then I'm going to do away
with myself.
And that shows you exactly what I think
and you know,
people are like that man.
That's why that's the oldest story,
but it's basically the oldest story we
have about human beings,
Cain and Abel.
It's like a paragraph long that story
and it's just a punch man.
That's why I remembered it for God only
knows 10,000 years maybe.
So why are they doing it?
Well,
they aren't doing it.
It's like we're doing it.
That's the thing.
It's not them.
It just happens to be that there are
sort of more doing it now than you know,
maybe the radical right is,
you know,
but it could easily be flipped around
and well that brings me back to the same
issue.
It's like,
well,
what do you do about it?
It's like,
join the group,
engage in group conflict,
give up all your beliefs so that you
don't believe anything so that you don't
engage in group conflict.
Well then you're nihilistic and
hopeless.
It's like,
so what do you do?
Those are your choices.
Well,
no,
they're not.
The other choice is get yourself
together and every way like you want to
fight this,
whatever this is,
you want to fight it.
Well,
you got to be strong because you're
going to have to make the right
decisions at a moment's notice when,
when the tiny little bits of this
manifest itself in your own life,
it's like you're going to stand up at
work when they want to retool your
unconscious biases.
Well,
probably not because people don't.
why not?
Well,
it's no bloody wonder,
you know?
I mean,
look what happens,
you know?
I said,
no,
I'm not using those words.
It's like,
you know,
when I didn't do it blindly all the way,
certainly never predicted what was
going,
who the hell could have predicted what
was going to happen?
Like certainly not me,
but it's no wonder that people shut up
and you know,
hide like why not?
It's the smart thing to do in the short
term.
Well you know how you feel when you
hide,
you know you feel like a pathetic,
scared rabbit and that's what you are.
So you gotta be more than a pathetic,
scared rabbit and you do that by
you do that by facing the chaos that
exists in your own life and turning it
into order not stopped.
That's how it goes.
So it isn't them,
you know,
that's the problem.
It would be so easy.
You could just get rid of them.
It's like that's just doesn't work.
Dr Doidge have our young people have
been forced to overdevelop their left
brains or have their right side of the
been underdeveloped.
If so,
how do we avoid this?
No.
Is this better?
I'm going to defer to or bring you back
to Ian mcgilchrist book,
and so yeah,
the brain is plastic and arguably,
you know,
if you start using a suite of cognitive
skills over and over and they were more
left brain,
you could develop more left brained.
I'm a balance that was more left brained
or right brained.
And in the course of civilization,
according to Mcgilchrist,
there were certain times where they hit
the sweet spot and he goes,
he has a whole historical account in his
book of which times and civilization,
you know,
actually Athens,
500 BC,
all those incredible playwrights,
Euripidean,
[inaudible],
these plays like Medea and east Gillis
and sophocles.
It go deep,
deep into emotion in the unconscious.
That's,
that's being hit.
And that then you have aristotle
describing logic really for the first
time.
And then there are moments in the
renaissance where there's a nice
balance,
but mcgilchrist himself is very
concerned as am I.
That education has really taken a huge
turn to left brain function.
Um,
and I think part of that has to do with,
uh,
well,
part of it has to do with a
philosophical problem and that is modern
science is I think in general a very
good thing.
It's not a perfect thing and it has a
number of very materialist assumptions
and many,
many people
misunderstand the following thing.
I see this in medicine all the time.
They say,
well,
what are your statistics for that?
You know,
statistics are a means to an end.
We're trying to find out what works for
a particular illness or something.
If you can measure it in the current
mindset of modern science,
it is real.
But there are things of course,
that we were not good at measuring now
with computers and technology,
what's Ha and bureaucracy,
what we're seeing in society is certain
things are easier to measure and those
are the things that are taught that are
privileged.
Your job is often judged and you know,
for many,
many people buy these silly little
things that are easy to quantify.
And that pushes things more towards a
kind of left brain approach if combined
with some of the materialist
underpinnings of modern science and
certain aspects of philosophy.
Um,
now there's always a kind of a rebellion
against that and a lot of the interest
in aspects of the east or meditation
and,
and certain aspects of literature are
in,
you know,
in some ways,
often more right brained things.
And because if you live a totally left
brained approach,
and I realize I'm speaking with a vast
generalization here,
but it doesn't really become toxic and
it feels like your soul,
your psyche,
whatever you want to call it,
it's very much left out of it.
So,
to answer the question now with that
background,
uh,
I think that education is moving very,
very left brained.
Um,
and I mean,
I think it's a real problem.
I think that the skills that we're
working on are very,
very left brained.
And so the reason you want to have a
liberal education,
for instance,
uh,
we talked about mill and the role of
free people have to learn how to govern
themselves.
But you know,
there are
western books that really do hit that
balance very beautifully and those are
the things that are being dismissed from
the curriculum,
uh,
so often.
And it comes both from the left and from
the right.
I mean,
you know,
over and over,
people go after things like music for
instance.
That's one of the first things to be
taken out of the curriculum because what
does it deliver that's an immediately
helpful and so on or reading poetry and
things like that.
Those things get cut back.
So yeah,
I,
I have,
um,
I think that there,
there is,
the balance is not right now
I have a bit of a comment on that 1
million units and keeping with Norman's
reference to John Piaget mean one of the
things piaget pointed out was that the
precursor to moral behavior is the
ability to play with others,
to play.
Like technically,
I mean children set up a little fantasy
world and then they take their roles in
it and they play and they do that
voluntarily unless one of the kids
doesn't know how to play.
Right.
And so the kid that doesn't know how to
play says,
you better play my game or I will play
with you in any sensible kid,
just runs off and finds another play
partner.
But you know,
we don't let this is such a cliche.
We don't let her children play,
you know,
and that's a big problem because they
just learn how to play in a structured
environment that's not play because it's
a play is when you have to invent your
own game and invent your own rules and
negotiate the rules and know.
And so all these kids is that,
I think they're hyper protected because
they're born to older mothers and you
know,
there's hardly any of them.
And so the mother's heart over
protective than the sword,
the fathers for that matter,
but they're old and they're not going to
have another kid.
So they hyper value the child and
there's only one of them.
And so they don't have siblings and
like,
and then they structure everything.
So the kid has the best of everything,
which they do,
except they don't have any freedom to be
idiot children and to,
you know,
eat dirt and fall on their head and all
that sort of thing that you have to do.
And you know,
it's no wonder of the reason it's a
demographic issue,
you know,
it's no wonder it's happening.
But a lot of these kids that are
screaming and squawking about you better
play my game or else they just don't
know how to play.
They,
they really don't.
And so it's no wonder.
And
that's death to morality because it's
predicated on free play know.
So that's a problem.
And so
that's not something I knew what to do
about,
don't,
you know,
don't
you try to encourage your kids.
Sorry,
you try to encourage your kids,
you make them courageous,
you don't protect them.
That's different,
right?
You make them courageous,
you don't protect them.
So that's,
you just make them weak then.
Sure.
A lot of questions about,
uh,
human rights tribunals and human rights
councils.
So just to kind of summarize a bunch of
them into one.
Um,
is there ever a legitimate use for human
rights tribunal or counsel,
and if you could comment also,
I'm going forward in the fight over
gender expression,
gender identity,
um,
how do people combat or,
or,
or win that fight in front of human
rights courts and tribunals and um,
yeah,
we'll leave it at that.
Oh no,
there is no excuse for them.
That's why they're called social justice
tribunals in Ontario like that.
That's what they're called.
And so look it up yourself and that's
what they are.
So we had a court system that works
perfectly well,
which doesn't mean it worked very well,
but it means it works better than any
alternative.
And if anyone has ever be able to think
up and a human rights tribunal can
suspend nor normal jurisprudential
standards.
They use preponderance of evidence.
They don't assume individual innocence
and they can change the rules as they
see fit.
And so those bloody things are
pathological to the core and their,
their mouthpieces of the postmodernist
neo Marxists as far as I'm concerned.
And they're setting up a parallel law
system and they're also doing that.
They're also,
and this is,
this is the wind government,
they're also forcing the universities to
adopt particular deficiencies of sexual
harassment that make every,
uh,
let's call it complicated interchange
between human beings into a act of
violence.
Not that I'm trying to justify stupidity
or oppression,
but we're all stupid and we're all
oppressors and so the probability that
we'll make some sort of dopey sexual
errors,
100 percent and now that's become
grounds for,
you know,
accusations of rape and where they're
forcing the universities and the
colleges to become parallel legal
systems as well.
And that's already well advanced.
It's already being adopted at the UFT.
It's as a consequence of direct
legislation and you better look out
because even if the people who are
running those right now are reasonable,
which they're not,
they will absolutely be replaced by
people who exactly want that kind of
power and will absolutely use it.
So no,
those things should be abolished.
We have a legal system.
No,
the law society now,
I may not have this exactly right,
but I've got it mostly right.
The law society in Ontario has already
decided that lawyers are racist,
they're going to force them to undergo
on unconscious bias training and they've
come to,
and they're agreeing by the way,
um,
they've already come to the conclusion
that because the legal profession does
not have the precise representation that
you would expect if you did a
demographic analysis of the population
according to the terms defined by the
social justice warriors,
that it's racist and that they're racist
and that they need to be trained
unconscious first.
It's like,
so go ahead.
Lawyers like line up,
man,
admit your guilt.
You're done and you deserve that too.
So,
Yep.
Starting to become afraid of the answers
to these questions,
um,
can left and right wing people ever
meaningfully communicate with each
other.
And I'm wondering if you can comment a
little about temper mentality and the
differences there in
that's what they do in a democracy.
Look,
the lefties,
they're high in openness and low in
conscientiousness and that means they
don't like responsibility that much,
but they're pretty damn creative and
they're not very orderly,
especially they're not very orderly.
And that's part of conscientiousness by
the way,
and so they're good at being artists and
they're good at being entrepreneurs,
but they're terrible at running things.
But then the conservatives on the other
side,
there are low in openness,
which is the treat creativity.
That doesn't mean they're stupid by the
way.
It just means they're,
they're,
they're thinking isn't as free form,
let's put it that way.
And so it's more constrained and they're
high in conscientiousness,
especially orderliness.
So they're damn good at running things
that already work.
So you need the liberals.
There wouldn't be high openness,
low conscientiousness if there wasn't a
niche for it.
And you need the conservatives and
sometimes the liberals are right,
the border should be more open because
that's their fundamental claim.
And sometimes the conservatives are
right.
The borders between things should be
more closed and,
and because they're both right some of
the time.
And because the environment keeps
snaking around,
you have to have dialogue between the
two sources constantly,
constantly so that the,
the Paula de can orient itself as the
snake of the environment moves.
And that's why you need free speech.
And so the left and the right get along
perfectly well together,
as long as they can talk to each other,
but as soon as they can't talk to each
other,
then the alternative,
there's only one alternate to
alternatives to negotiation.
Simple as that one is slavery,
the other risk tyranny.
So those you cannot negotiate with will
either become your slaves or your
tyrants.
So you wipe outs free speech,
then that's what you're left with.
And that's why free speech isn't just
another right,
for Christ's sake,
it's not another right?
How dumb can you be to think that you
don't know anything if you think that
it's the mechanism by which people have
different opinions
talk instead of strangling each other.
So and,
uh,
but if you want them to strangle each
other,
which you might then really,
you might then take away the right to
express their opinion and watched the
whole thing go up in flames and go like
this because maybe that's what a big
part of you wants.
So
do you see any connection between
antisemitism and postmodernism
specifically on university campuses?
I had an insight the other day,
um,
and it actually came through some
psychoanalytic reading.
Um,
I googled anti Semitic images
and I invite you to all do that.
And three quarters of those images came
up as an old man with the big nose and
he was doing really one of three things.
He was counting his money.
He was torturing a child or in an
Israeli guys.
He was stealing territory and it just,
it was amazing.
And I thought of a picture of what Jews
look like and there's men and women and
they're all ages and there's lots of
children.
And that was interesting.
There was one picture of a woman who was
like a bad Jew.
She was witch.
And
there are some psychoanalytic concepts
that I'll share with you now that I
think relate both to postmodernism and
anti antisemitism.
And it's this,
you know,
analytically,
if things go well when we're in her
mother's womb,
you know,
there's a sense we,
we think of a kind of a paradise that
human beings beginning.
And of course there are many stories
about the expulsion from paradise.
But if our childhoods go well and we're
the apple of our parents die and they
hold us and they sued us and we imagined
we want milk and milk arises.
There's this early period where there's
this kind of narcissistic,
it's not in a negative way,
just wonderful thing where everything
works out where we're totally
egocentric,
but it's appropriate and we're in a kind
of a paradise.
And of course in the course of life,
we move in and out of that now then
reality hits and reality hits in terms
of discomforts.
And so it's,
it's a kind of natural biological thing
that happens.
But as we get older,
we learned that to go into society,
there are limits on us and there are
rules
and
if can't deal with that,
we develop an image in our minds of that
he or it's usually a,
he for mythological reasons.
Rules are often tied into,
um,
the masculine and nature is often tied
into the feminine.
And in many cross cultural mist,
the,
the representative or the symbol of the
rule giver that I don't like,
that I don't detest is often a male.
A father and old,
and one of the things about Judaism,
everybody who studied it knows is
there's a lot of laws and there's a lot
of rules and the picture of God in
Judaism is often depicted as a man who
can be angry or a times punitive and so
on.
So I think one of the things that has
happened is that's caused antisemitism,
is that the the Jew,
a pot onto the Jew is projected,
are discontent with the fact that in
life one of the things we have to do is
face limit and rules and even the French
psychoanalyst talked about the no of the
father and saw the superego is a
negative male image and one of the
things about
having had a very protective upbringing
or overprotected upbringing that Jordan
was describing and I was describing
earlier is as I put it earlier,
I said,
if you've,
if you've had a denatured existence and
then you come up against limits and
adult life,
it feels that all the problems are
caused by human beings and rules.
I'm,
I'm sorry for the long answer,
but it's,
it's,
it's a serious,
serious question.
You know,
I talked a lot about some of the very
good things in classical liberalism and
classical liberalism can be shared by
modern conservatives and modern
liberals.
There are liberal liberals and liberal
conservatives.
There are also a liberal conservatives
and liberals and I don't see anything
better than the classical liberal
arguments to keep us talking to each
other,
but that's not to say that liberalism is
perfect.
I'm liberalism to some degree because it
doesn't take a position on things and
stays open on things in ways that
certain traditional approaches don't.
They,
they will take a position on things does
slip easily into relativism and
relativism basically says a and
relativism is embraced by postmodernism
when they're not trying to change the
world in a particular way.
So it's,
it's on and off again.
Kind of relationship.
Relativism says that there is no solid
philosophical underpinning for thought
thoughts about right and wrong or good
and evil or how we should act,
and that creates a massive amount of
anxiety and when ever any of us in our
lives come up against the limit or
border or some kind of essential.
If we've been raised relativistically,
as many young people have today to
think,
well,
you know,
you're not really entitled to take your
point of view too seriously at all
because nothing's really right or wrong.
It's just a value judgment.
Um,
then you can start to resent or be angry
about rules or limits.
So part of the postmodern attack is on
anything,
uh,
certain things in biological which seem
akin to laws.
I'm not saying that there are laws of
nature of the way.
There are laws of human beings,
but there are these regularities or
patterns in nature that we see and we
often as a short form,
call them laws and postmodernism often
attacks those and says no.
They're just socially constructed,
which means imagined to in some way or
other appease or please a social,
a social group.
So this is a long roundabout answer,
but I think that many of us carry within
us a deep resentment in our narcissistic
parts of ourselves that in this life we
have to adapt to limit and law.
And that can come up as depicting an
image of an older man who represents
someone who's hidebound by law,
um,
and doesn't have a spirit and is
fundamentally greedy and trying to take
something away from you.
And,
uh,
that shows up in postmodernism.
And by the way,
you know,
the idea,
for instance,
that the Jew is greedy.
I haven't completely figured that out,
but I've got an answer for that.
Okay.
Well,
but I just want to say a few things.
It's very interesting.
The old man is often abusing a child in
those antisemitic images.
And of course there were stories about
Jews kidnapping,
gentel children and sucking their blood
and eating their blood and so on and so
forth is Passover.
I think that's a hint that this is the
child's view of a terrifying father
image that is trying to take something
away from you.
And of course
it's about patriarchy,
isn't it?
I mean,
the idea is this man represents the
tribe or some kind of control and,
and postmodernism is very much against
that.
So again,
today I spoke a lot about rational
things,
but Jordan has spoken about mythology
and you know,
they're very,
very deep archetypal and mythological
things that are driving a lot of this
and that's why it's worth,
you know,
Google antisemitic images and you'll see
what I mean.
We're also,
you know,
one thing to consider is if,
if you're a minority,
you should at least have the decency be
unsuccessful,
right?
You know,
what,
if you regard the system is corrupt,
then you're going to regard the people
who are successful say
disproportionately even as ultimately
corrupt.
And that's kind of convenient if you're
angry about the fact that you're not
successful.
And so,
you know,
that's not the only driving force,
but that's,
that's a good part of it,
man.
So,
you know,
there's nothing better than being
punished for your virtues.
So,
but you touched on this briefly,
but there were quite a few questions
about it.
So I think it's worth rehashing and
perhaps expanding,
uh,
on,
what do you make of this strange
bedfellows ship between the politically
correct,
left and Islamic activities?
Is there an element of cognitive
dissidence?
And I'm wondering if you could also
touch on bill 59 in Quebec right now.
This is kind of the Sharia compliance
bill that's going on over there.
Basically thought crimes against the
prophet.
Um,
we'll,
we'll see you legally reprimanded.
Oh,
I'll start.
Start.
So the first part.
Good.
Just tell him.
Just tell me the first part of that
question again if you would tell us.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's nothing,
there's nothing,
there's nothing contradictory about that
except you know,
arguments have layers,
very many layers and something can be
contradictory at one level and,
and,
and non contradictory of another.
It means you're thinking is disorganized
in some profound way,
but it happens all the time because
you're thinking is a disorganized in
some profound way.
But when push comes to shove,
you find out what the basic motivation
is.
And that's why I said already the enemy
of your enemy,
the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
And so if your fundamental goal is to
enhance women's freedom,
let's say,
well then it's going to be pretty rough
to be crop climb into bed with,
let's say the Saudis,
as I already mentioned.
But if your fundamental goal is to recap
havoc with Western civilization,
it's like,
well,
hey,
that's not a problem.
There's still cognitive dissonance
there.
That's you can sacrifice the whole
rights thing.
It's like,
it's not like you were ready for that to
any great degree anyways at the bottom
of your nasty little soul.
So there no cognitive dissonance there.
It's just another tactic as far as I can
tell.
And you know the fact that it also
allows for broad scale attacks on what
you might consider this.
Maybe as putting it a bit too bluntly.
The only country in the Middle East that
has any resemblance of of success,
then so much the better because they're
just representations of patriarchal
oppression.
Because how could they be anything else
since there's no such thing as
competence properly defined within the
patriarchy.
So forget about cognitive dissonance.
You just watch what people do when
they're,
when they face a
paradox.
And then you'll understand their deeper
motivations,
just
so
I've just been told that they're
actually going to be closing the
auditorium momentarily.
So I worried that's going to be the very
last,
uh,
question.
Uh,
however I will say that on behalf of the
entire audience,
thank you so very much to both of you
gentlemen and scholars for,
for,
um,
bringing together both nature and
nurture with all of your backgrounds and
forming our own opinions,
beliefs,
and hopefully acting as role models and
how we should combat political
correctness in our own lives.
So thank you.
Thank you.