Yeah,
maybe you're 35 years old and you've
never had a job,
and one of the things that's stopping
you is that you're so damn nervous that
you can't pick up a phone and use it
because if anything unexpected happens
while you're talking,
you get scared so badly,
you have to hang up and so that would be
characteristic of somebody with a severe
anxiety disorder.
So what do you do with that person?
So you say,
are they afraid of the phone?
Well,
no.
What are they afraid of?
Well,
they're afraid of a normally is in human
interaction,
right?
They're afraid of something unexpected
happening while they're trying to impose
a structure and the reason they're
afraid of that is because they never
learned that they were capable of
dealing with the emergence of something
new on an ongoing basis,
which meant that
while which meant in all likelihood,
that when they were children,
they were so sheltered from any contact
with those aspects of being the
transcend knowledge that they never
learned,
that there was something inside of them
that would reveal itself if they were
allowed the opportunity to encounter the
unknown,
to encounter fear them,
to master it,
then to extract out something of value
so they can't get a job because they
can't use the phone and it isn't because
they can't use the phone.
Right?
It's a deeper story than not.
It's because they're terrified of this
and they have no idea that they have
some resource they could draw on to
combat it and you could say,
well,
we can teach them to use the phone,
right?
Say,
well,
you know,
here's a.
here's a repertoire of stock lines that
you might use,
you know,
like small talk at a party.
And that would increase what they know
and enabled them to deal with the
unknown.
Or You could say,
look,
you know,
relax a little bit when the person says
something on the phone that you don't
understand,
pause a little bit.
Think about what they're saying.
Pay attention to them.
Allow yourself the luxury of formulating
a response.
You'll do fine,
and even if you do it badly the first
half a dozen times,
well you'll learn.
Eventually the person derives from that.
The notion that not only can they cope
on the phone,
but that possibly there's more to them
that originally met the eye.
We come into the world equipped with an
array of possibilities and limitations.
Those possibilities and limitations are
expressed most particularly in our
physical form.
The fact that we have a specific kind of
embodied form that us to do certain
things and that also doesn't allow us to
do certain other things loud too,
as pointed out that
it's the space inside a part that makes
the part worthwhile.
And what he means by that is that
those things that limit you give you as
much form and possibility as those
things that enable you.
What that means more broadly is the fact
that you come to a given circumstance
with a set of possibilities and a set of
limitations.
It's that that allows you to impose form
on what you encounter so that the whole
notion of forum is attendant in some
peculiar way that we don't really
understand yet on the necessity of
limitation.
And I think the best way to understand
that or to begin to understand that is
to give some consideration to the notion
of a game.
So for example,
if you're playing chess,
there's a virtually unlimited number of
things you can do and only a very narrow
number of things that you can do.
Yet when you're playing chess,
the arbitrary limitations that are
imposed on each piece don't seem to be
unfair in any sort of cosmic sense.
They seem to be part of the structure
that enables you to actually play the
game without the imposition of those
rules,
which are of course relatively
arbitrary.
And their structure,
there wouldn't be a game at all.
Now it's clear that for human beings,
games and fantasy for that matter,
shade up into reality so that the game
structures that we engage in and the
fantasy structures that we use to
undergird our stories and our pretend
play,
say when we're children shade
imperceptibly into real life,
we we play games because there's
something about games that make them
deeply analogous to what we do in day to
day situations and that means the
observation that the rules of a game
actually make the game possible is an
observation that's broadly applicable to
consideration of your own limitation.
Some of those limitations and
possibilities take the form of emotions
and motivations and we know I think
incontrovertibly
regardless of the claims of social
scientists who are more relativist in
their orientation,
that human beings come into the world
with a standard set of biological
predispositions,
emotions and motivations.
And furthermore,
I think we know that it's the fact of
those shared emotions,
emotions and motivations that allow us
to communicate at all.
And then imagine further that a
consequence of that lengthy process of
interpersonal negotiation is the
emergence of a tremendously complicated
game and not one that's arbitrary
because the game has to have certain
rules in order for it to be played at
all.
So for example,
we know that even with rats,
if rats,
they like to engage in rough and tumble
play,
and if you put two rats together,
juvenile routes,
one route almost always dominates the
other.
It only takes about 10 percent gain in
weight on the part of one rap.
For it to be pretty much stable,
he dominant and it's always the
subordinate rat that introduces play or
or,
or asks for play.
But it turns out that even among rats,
if the dominant rat pins or or,
or obtains victory over the subordinate
route,
more than 70 percent of the time,
the subordinate rat will no longer play.
So then you could imagine likewise that
if you're going to play a game with some
other person,
whether it's a game of fantasy or the
actual chance to engage in some
cooperative real world activity,
unless that person allows you a certain
amount of space for the manifestation of
your own emotional and motivational
needs,
you're not going to play the game with
them,
right?
You're going to look for another game
and that means that there's a certain
set of difficult to describe constraints
for all of you on games that you're
willing to play before you'll look for
another one
again,
well,
and then you can start to conceive of
revolutionary tendencies in that sense,
right?
Imagine the human society that Scott so
unstable that the vast majority of the
citizens within that society are
subjugated to starvation,
so the society never no longer provides
their basic needs and constant tyranny.
You could imagine as well that there's
going to be an innate tendency among the
members of that society to start
hypothesizing about what alternatives
might be possible,
right?
To start dreaming about alternative
societies and then also to take action
if the situation becomes too extreme,
and I think this is part of the reason
why you see stable mythological motifs
across different cultures.
It's not so much like young sad that we
have archetypes of what might constitute
social order deeply embedded in our
unconscious.
I think this situation is more
externalized in that in that what's
biological is what we bring to the
situation,
our hopes and our desires and the fact
that we have hopes and desires.
Now,
I think what happens with stories is
something like this is that as human
societies increasing complexity and
number so they become bigger and bigger
and more and more people engage in the
negotiating process,
exchanging emotional and motivational
information.
The pattern that the society takes,
if it's going to be stable across long
periods of time,
starts to become encoded in the stories.
So imagine you've got your emotions on
your motivations.
You make your case no one,
10,000 other people do that over a
thousand years and structure starts to
emerge.
That satisfies more or less all of these
emotions and motivational states and
there's also recognizable as a pattern,
so then you could say,
for example,
considering a story like Moses and the
imposition of the 10 commandments on the
ancient Hebrews prior to isn't in
position of those 10 commandments,
and of course there were actually many
more than 10 Moses,
according to the mythological story.
What was it?
Spent years,
literally years adjudicating conflict
between the people that he was leading
18 hours a day.
They'd come to him with their various
problems saying,
we have a dispute.
How should it be settled?
And he'd satellite.
Well imagine doing that for 10 years,
right?
Becoming an expert at evaluating what
constitutes an appropriate solution to
an emotional problem between two people.
Imagine as well that as a consequence of
doing that for such a long period of
time,
you start to became becoming able to
abstract out lawful regularities in the
manner in which people have to interact
in order for peace to be maintained.
Imagine further that those could be
codified in stories,
but even more codafide as law.
Eventually when consciousness became
capable of grasping explicitly the
nature of the interactions,
so my point is a point very much like
niches because Nisha said at the end of
the 19th century that it's a mistake to
presume that most of our philosophies
are rational in nature and I think
that's a mistake that characterizes
western philosophical thinking.
At least at least since the
enlightenment.
It's a mistake to assume that there was
a chaotic social state upon which a
rational order was imposed as a
consequence of rational action.
It's much more reasonable to presuppose
that the order emerged naturally over
lengthy periods of time and then was
interpreted and codified and given
structure in a secondary manner.
And so when I'm trying to outline for
you in in large part is the processes by
which that order comes to be.
So you say,
first it's behavioral,
emotional,
motivational people and even animals
communicate in a way that makes their
motivational and emotional needs known
to one another.
So even among wolves and chimpanzees and
and any kind of lower order social
animal,
you have the emergence of dominance
hierarchies fundamentally which are
stable solutions to the entire set of
emotional and motivational problems that
beset the group and no one would ever
say that the emergence of a chimpanzee
dominance hierarchy is a consequence of
rational deliberation.
So then imagine chimpanzees,
get the power to watch what they're
doing and to start to represent it and
then imagine furthermore that that
representation takes the form of stories
and then laws and then you have some
idea about how human social order comes
to be.
And this is an exciting possibility for
me because it offers,
it offers the potential solution to one
major question,
which is how is it that people should
act?
And because we're essentially
rationalist in our presuppositions,
we believe that there are rationalist
solutions to that,
but the solutions may be something that
are much more akin to biological
solutions.
First,
I want you to consider the following
hypothesis.
Okay,
so we're going to make the
presupposition.
A couple of presuppositions that I don't
think are unreasonable.
First is that we are essentially animals
that we've evolved in a Darwinian
fashion
and second,
that the consequence of that evolution,
much of which was pre-cognitive,
right,
did with it w we were around as
creatures before we were capable of
thinking in words,
say,
much of that evolutionary history has
conditioned the manner in which we
think.
So we think more like biological
entities.
Then we think like computers or we think
more like biological entities than we
think like rational machines.
And of course we already know that
rational machines cannot think very well
except in very boundaried environments
because they don't have access to and
embodied structure or to emotions and
motivations.
So let's.
So then you might say,
well,
why is it that like in the Mesopotamian
Egyptian creation myths are most
fundamental representations of the world
tend to take story for him and that not
only do they take story form,
but they tend to utilize certain kinds
of categories.
Now,
I've showed you this diagram before.
Um,
this represents what I think are the
three cardinal categories of experience.
So there's the great mother who was
holding the world in her hand here and
inside her subordinate in a sense is the
great father.
This is a Christian representation
obviously,
and then this tragic son,
of course in the crowd here representing
society is adoring the figure of the
tragic hero here because they regard his
motive being as necessary to their own
salvation,
so to speak,
their own proper motive living.
Okay?
So then you think,
well why these characters and I offer
you this possibility is first of all,
every human being that's ever lived has
lived in an environment characterized by
the presence of these three entities,
right?
We have mothers,
we have fathers,
and we exist as individuals.
And then you think,
well,
when you're a child and you begin to
comprehend the world,
the outside world,
everything outside of the family is of
course vague and ill defined,
right?
Nonexistent in a sense and to all there
is for you to observe is the mother who
for you really is the whole world and
the father,
a a secondary source of comfort and
troubled perhaps and the fact of your
own individuality.
And so you say,
well that's true from the perspective of
individual development,
but then if you go way,
way back in history,
maybe 500,000 years when our cognitive
capacities were first starting to
develop and we were trying to figure out
what the world was really like,
what categories would we have at our
disposal to start to modify and change
in order to represent the outside world?
And then you might think you can only
talk about what you don't know in terms
that you know.
And since for the child,
the mother is the world.
It isn't.
It isn't observed to presume that for
the human being the world is the mother
first as a projection,
right?
As a,
as a,
an April are cognitive Schema.
The hypothesis being the natural world,
which of course does manifest itself in
truth in the mother,
partakes in many ways of the same
properties as the mother.
It's a working hypothesis just like you
might presume if you date a new woman,
that she has aspects of your sister.
All things considered aspects of your
mother given that they were also female.
You take what you know to represent what
you don't know,
so we use our fundamental social
cognitive categories initially to
portray the world and the world's
nature's pours,
traded personified or metaphorical form.
And so then the question is what are the
primary categories?
Well,
we have three of them here,
but they're not the only three because
this is all good.
This category system,
the benevolent mother,
the benevolent father,
and the hero.
While we know the world is not only
benevolent,
it's also malevolent,
or at least we can say that because
we're equipped with certain emotional
possibilities in certain motivational
possibilities,
the,
the probability that we will encounter
despair and frustration and
disappointment and anxiety is just as
real as the possibility that we will
encounter elation and hope and
satisfaction.
So for us,
the world is by Vaillant.
It takes with one hand and gives with
the other,
and that's true for the natural world
which produces us and destroys us as it
is for the social world,
which fosters our development and
crushes.
Our individuality and as well for the
individual who in many regards is,
is admirable a creature.
As you could hope ever to proposed,
and at the same time someone who's
capable of unbelievable depths of
depravity,
so
a world that's not only divided into
three fundamental categories,
but each category divided into a
structure that's essentially ambivalent
and its fundamental element,
and of course that poses the central
existential problem for human existence,
doesn't it?
I mean we're faced with the vagaries of
the natural world and what we don't
understand the vagaries of the social
world and it's often arbitrary and
unreasonable demands on us and the fact
of our capacity for Tristan
transcendence tied to our own
vulnerability and you could say
perfectly reasonably that regardless of
where you're situated in time and space,
those are basically your problems and
your goal through life.
Your path through life is going to be
characterized by the solutions you
either come up with or don't come up
with to that set of problems.
Okay,
so there's one more categorical element
that complicates this picture and I
think in many ways it's the most
difficult thing there is to grasp.
So we'll take a shot at it first.
And I've showed you this representation
before.
This is the of chaos,
and you can think of the dragon of chaos
as a symbol of totality,
and furthermore,
you can think of it in relationship
to this structure
as the source of this structure
for even as the source of all structure.
So you see in the Sumerian creation
myth,
for example,
the character of Thai amount,
right,
and I told you that word tie.
Matt is associated with the later Hebrew
word tail,
which means chaos,
and Tom is the chaos that,
yeah,
well makes order out of,
makes the world out of.
So the idea lurking behind the Sumerian
creation myth and then later lurking
behind the entire edifice of Judaism,
Christianity and Islam for that matter,
is that something that can be best
represented by this figure is best
conceptualized as the ground of
everything that exists.
Now,
what in the world can that mean?
Well,
it means something like this.
Let's look at the concrete,
metaphorical representation.
First of all,
you have a kind of totality here,
right?
You have a thing that can live by
devouring itself,
so it has no need of anything outside of
it.
In fact,
there is nothing outside of it.
It's a figure of absolute totality and
it's characterized by a strange
intermixture of metaphorical real
representations of matter,
because a snake is something that crawls
on the ground and spirit because a wayne
serpent is something that can fly and
therefore partakes of the metaphorical
realm of Heaven,
heaven and earth,
right totality,
Yin and Yang from the Dallas
perspective.
That's the entire world and it's also
something that's characterized by the
capacity for transformation because a
snake can shed its skin and be reborn,
so it's something that's constantly
renewing itself despite its absolutely
archaic age and it's also something that
presents a terrible danger and
tremendous opportunity because a dragon
is something that will burn you if you
get anywhere near it,
but also hoards a treasure that's more
valuable than anything else.
Eliana has pointed out that in
traditional classic creation myths,
the Sumerian myth being one example,
when the hero,
whoever the hero is first encounters the
great dragon of chaos,
he either runs away or is paralyzed by
fright.
The world in itself is a complex array
of patterns and those patterns manifest
themselves in space and they manifest
themselves in time and I think the best
way to get a grip on what those patterns
might be like is to think of them in
terms of music and I think that's what
music represents.
Music is this complex,
three dimensional structure,
full of interwoven patterns of different
dimensions and and and length that
expends itself over time and if you
listen to a piece of music,
you can concentrate on one instrument or
another or you can concentrate on a
phrase.
You can concentrate on the entire melody
or the voice.
You can parse out different elements
from the complex background and that's
especially the case with very
sophisticated orchestral music rights
which is susceptible to multiple
reinterpretations and multiple
encounters because of its complexity.
And this is to say only that what you
look at is far more complicated than
what you see or to say.
Alternatively,
that there's more information in
anything you perceive than you could
ever get complete access to.
And that's partly because it's partly
because of your perceptual systems.
Delude you so we think you look with
your eyes or with your other senses,
but that's only true when you're looking
at what you already know what to look at
right when you've already built
perceptual machinery that enables you to
detect a particular object,
but when you're looking at what you
don't know what to look at,
the way you look is by getting nervous,
right?
It's not.
It's not precisely a perceptual
function.
It's something much more deeper and
primordial than that and it's more like,
oh no.
Something that I cannot categorize
either perceptually or cognitively,
something that I do not know how to
respond to has just occurred,
and the first categorization is this.
That's it.
There's,
there's nothing under that.
It's merely
fear plus heightened attention and that
prepares the ground for constructing a
more detailed representation,
but that first encounter,
that's the encounter with the dragon of
chaos.
So then you take this figure,
the source of all things,
the,
the Dow in some ways,
and you'll say,
well,
how does it manifest itself?
And the answer to that is something like
this,
and we see this both in the in the
Mesopotamian and the Egyptian myths that
I described to you.
The first division of the great dragon
of chaos,
or the primordial egg is always into to
subordinate elements.
The great father and the great mother.
Why is that?
Well,
it's illustrative of a fundamental of
the fundamental binary nature of
existence.
I guess partly you could say,
if you're a cognizant being,
a defined delimited being what you
perceive always has a binary structure.
There's the aspect of you that
structured enough to allow the
perceiving.
That's what you know,
that's,
that's the manner in which you are
structured so that you can even see.
You can even formulate a perception
something a child builds up over time
from the primordial aspects say of his
visual system,
has auditory system learns to parse up
the world by generating machinery that
allows the complex patterns that make up
the world to be turned into objects.
So there's the thing,
the structure that allows the
perceiving,
and then there's the thing that's being
perceived or the thing behind that.
This is a very complicated distinction.
You'd say,
well,
what's the difference between the dragon
of chaos?
Say either the representation of the
cosmos as such and the great mother and
I would say it's something like this.
The unknown that appears in relationship
to a perceiver is different than the
unknown as such,
so I would say this,
for example,
there are going to be things that
surprise you that wouldn't surprise me
and vice versa,
and the things that would surprise you
have to be construed in relationship to
what you to what you already know,
because you're only going to be
surprised by things you don't know and
likewise for me,
I'm only going to be surprised by things
I don't know,
but what we know is going to vary
somewhat.
So the unknown for you is going to be
different than the unknown for me and
the great mother is a representation of
the unknown for you or the unknown for
me.
Different for everyone in some sense,
because we're all going to
B,
we're all.
We're all going to be stymied and
stopped by different aspects of being,
but the same as well.
In that when you encounter things you
don't understand and you encounter
things you don't understand in many,
many ways,
you're going to react to those different
things the same way,
and I can give you a narrative
illustration of this King Arthur's
nights,
they sit around the round table.
They're all equal,
so that's why they sit around a round
table,
right?
They have a king.
The king determines their destinies like
Marta does,
but they're still all equal.
They determined they're going to go look
for the holy grail.
This is the symbol of redemption,
so they're off to find the highest value
like Pinocchio,
wishing on a star,
highest value,
and they all enter the forest to begin
the quest,
but they each entered at the place that
appears dark as to each of the rights.
That means they all go on different.
They all go in different directions even
though they're on the same quest and
theoretically they're inhabiting the
same space,
so.
So it's only to say that every person
has their demons,
so to speak,
and that those demons differ from person
to person.
Even though there are things you can say
about the demons that are common across
people,
so we know,
for example,
from clinical work,
from endless clinical work that if you
want to help someone,
you identify,
okay,
what do you want to do?
They need to know that,
right?
That's this.
What do you want to do?
Where do you want to go?
What kind of structure do you want to
impose on your world?
And then you identify,
okay,
well what things are stopping you.
So then you look back at the Sumerian
creation myth and you think,
well,
there's Appsu,
right?
God of the known timeouts consort,
Culture,
but there's also Marta.
Marta is the power of the spirit,
the entity representation of the
Sumerian savior who goes out to confront
this and to make the world and well,
that's what you teach people in behavior
therapy.
You teach them not so much that you
don't teach them habituation.
You don't teach them to get used to
things that they're afraid of.
You teach them that there's something
within them that can respond to the
things that they're afraid of.
That's as great a magnitude as the fears
themselves.
No.