Well Dave and I are here today to talk
about Patrion.
And so all start,
we've been engaged in lengthy series of
email exchanges with all of the people
in our network and no one is happy at
all with what's been happening.
And so we've been determining what our
options are and we looked at subscribes
to our,
but it looks like paypal decided to cut
funding out from them.
And so it doesn't look like moving to an
alternative provider and an alternative
commercial pro provider that's out of
our bailiwick,
out of our control is going to be
viable.
So Dave,
why don't you describe what we talked
about today?
Yeah.
Well first I think we should just make
it very clear for everybody how
significant what happened to Carl
Benjamin Sargon of a cod is it doesn't
matter what you think of him or whether
you agree with him or any of that stuff.
The banning of him for doing something
that was not on the Patriot,
on platform that wasn't even done on his
channel because of a word he said,
where he was using the word against the,
uh,
the alt right or the Neo Nazis or
whatever you want to call them,
is a massive move of that line of what's
acceptable.
Now there's all sorts of debates we can
have and we've had them of what lines
should be,
if there should be lines at all,
but the fact that this guy got booted
with no chance of recourse with no
warning,
just just like that.
It's just an extension of everything
else that we've all been talking
also.
And also given that it's also the case
that he didn't break patrons,
rules of engagement,
the ones that they stated and that Kanye
had talked to you about the fact that
that wasn't going to happen and that
Patrion hasn't responded well to this.
Well,
look,
Jack Conti came into my studio in my
home and said he,
he said a phrase that I had never heard
before.
Maybe you had heard it before.
Manifest observable behaviors.
So you had never even heard that phrase
before,
right?
I thought,
I thought maybe this was just something
that went past me.
Okay.
Now of course manifest observable
behavior,
mob mob you can make,
I mean that's,
there's a real,
there's a real beauty there.
But,
but so the point was that it had to be
about behavior and then in their terms
of service,
it also had to be about what was
happening on platforms.
So every firewall here of what would
have been acceptable patrion failed.
And they've put us in a position where,
look,
I told you I called you last Saturday
and when this was really catching fire
and I said,
you know,
Patrion is about 65 to 70% of my rep
that's,
I have a company now with employees,
you know,
full timers,
part timers.
I was actually considering deleting it
right then and there,
which no one in their right mind would
do.
No business person would do.
And I've,
I've taken big risks in the past.
You know,
before I was on Patrion we were at,
or tv I,
me and my producer and my director,
we all quit our jobs,
lost our health insurance,
all that to join patriots.
So I'm not,
I like taking risks,
but then I realized,
all right,
we have to figure out a plan and that's
exactly why we're doing this,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Well,
and we would have moved faster,
but we,
well,
and I did set up a subscribes to our
account,
although I never quite finished setting
it up,
partly because subscribes star seem to
fall apart almost immediately under
attack.
And,
and also it wasn't obvious that I also
read the terms of agreement and it
wasn't obvious that we weren't going to
be just in exactly the same situation
again.
And there's only so many mistakes you
can make before the mistakes start to
become fatal.
So we want it to come up with a serious
and,
and stable solution.
And I have been working on for months,
literally for months,
it's been six months.
I'd been working on a system to allow
authors and other people who engage
publicly on intellectually issues to
interact more effectively with their
readers and viewers and listeners.
And it occurred to me this week that
with a bit of modification that that
could serve exactly the function that
we're hoping it would serve.
So what we're going to try to do as fast
as we possibly can is to set the system
up on a subscriber model that's
analogous to Patrion.
It'll have a bunch of additional
features,
which I don't want to talk about right
now,
and I don't want to over promise,
but the system is,
is because the system is new,
but we're gonna try to get that rolled
out as fast as we possibly can.
So,
and we have a number of people who are
interested in hypothetically interested
in moving their,
their subscription service over to it.
Dave and I are very seriously planning
to do this as soon as we can do it in an
intelligent way.
And so what,
you know,
by the way,
one of the interesting things here,
and we haven't talked about this,
but I'm guessing you were experiences
just like mine,
the amount of emails that I have
received and kind of course tweets and
everything else,
but most of the emails from developers,
from investors,
from regular people,
from engineers,
I mean just anyone going,
this is the one,
because you know the issue with all of
these free speech things is it's like
you don't want to swing too early before
you realize that the problem's gotten to
critical mass as,
but then most likely you're going to
swing too late.
The lines will have so far that we may
be on the outside of them.
And that's why this one I think was so
interesting because Carl,
you know,
years ago,
five or six years ago when I started
waking up to what was going on with the
left obviously,
and then all of the free speech stuff,
everyone said you've got to talk to
Sargon of Akkad easy guide.
So this is the guy that's been ahead of
all of it.
So are going to was like,
he was big.
He was very helpful to me when I was
first under attack,
you know,
and he's a brave God and,
and so,
and it's a real mistake what patron has
done to him.
And as I said,
everybody in our network is extremely
upset about it.
Like we've been sending emails back and
forth,
well probably with 30 or 40 people.
And so as Dave said earlier,
we wanted to make this video today to
let everybody that we're communicating
with know that we have not been sleeping
on this front man.
People are trying to figure out what to
do.
So this stops happening and,
and so,
and we have a good plan and we're going
to try to implement it as soon as
possible.
So if I would ask everybody who's
listening to be in a reasonably patient,
imagine that this will take somewhere
between a week and a month to sort out
properly.
We're going to try to get something up
in the next week hopefully before
Christmas if we can't manage that,
you know,
cause when you implement something like
this,
there are technical complications that
might emerge that you don't foresee.
But I don't want people to get the
impression that we're taking this
lightly or lying down and that we're not
looking for a,
uh,
a permanent alternative because we are,
and I think we can come up with a better
alternative.
And that's the plan.
Yeah,
that,
that's exactly what I would say.
I would just add that it was like we
were,
we were waiting for a moment.
You know,
we've watched these doors slowly closing
on us.
All of us,
whether it's twitter,
whether it's facebook,
who's getting banned,
who's getting shadow,
banned payment processing,
everything else.
And we are taking this as seriously as
possible.
Of course,
you know,
Jordan,
who's working harder than anyone on the
face of the planet.
Somehow you manage to also partly build
the platform over the course of the past
year.
And in the middle of all of that,
I knew that this,
we knew that this was lurking in the
background and that this was going to be
a problem.
And Dave,
you've spent lots of time talking to
investors and developers about building
alternatives to these platforms that
seem to be willing to throw their weight
around it and increasingly arbitrary
manner.
But it's not like it's a simple thing to
do.
People want somebody to say enough is
enough.
And I,
I've mentioned this in a live stream I
did the other day,
but you know,
I've watched my patrion dropped.
We've lost around 600 patrons,
I think about 5,000 bucks a month.
But in a weird way,
I've actually been inspired by it
because I'm watching.
Yeah,
great for themselves.
So it's like on one hand people are
emailing me and they're saying,
I'm dropping my patronage and I'm really
pissed and it's not about you and I want
to support you.
And on the other hand,
my business side is going,
that's not great.
But yeah,
but we will,
we will solve this thing.
I have nothing.
Anyway.
I've lost a thousand subscribers and I
feel exactly the same way.
It's like,
well,
they're telling patron to go to hell.
And you know,
it's,
it's not so good for me on the financial
front,
although that's not too big a
catastrophe at the moment.
They're taking the right stand and,
and encouraging us,
let's say,
or encouraging someone to do something
about this.
So anyways,
yeah,
that's what I like.
I like what you said.
If we can just ask you guys to be
reasonably patient,
we're talking to everybody that you can
think of and some people that you can't
think of.
We're,
we're going to fix this.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well we're going to,
or at least we're going to do our best
to fix it.
There's going to be some bumps along the
way,
man,
because we're now,
we have to speed this process up to,
so you'll have to consider this a Beta
version,
but at minimum we hope to provide,
uh,
an easy way of switching to a new
subscription service within the next
very short while.
So,
and thank you everyone for your
continued patients and your continued
support and your attention.
And your thoughts and your reaction to
all of this and,
and it's,
it's very much appreciated and it does
help us,
I would say maintain motivation to
continue doing this constantly.
You know,
the fact that I have all these patrons,
subscribers certainly is one of the
reasons that I tried to put my youtube
channel.
I wouldn't say first and foremost
because it's had to take a backseat to
this lecture tour.
But man,
it's way the hell up there on my
priority list.
Absolutely.
And it gives us all sorts of flexibility
to do all sorts of things.
That gave me a little bit of flexibility
to join you on this tour.
So I'm incredibly humbled and
appreciative of everybody that does
that.
Fjord and I will,
I will see you in a couple of days in
west Palm Beach.
He's leading steak.
I will take you out for a steak.
Good,
good,
good.
Well I found a good steak place here so
we will,
I'm looking forward to seeing it.
Dave [inaudible] the tour a cause we're
going to continue the tour in in uh,
California.
Yup.
Great.
Three venues in California in January.
And then the two in Australia,
New Zealand,
and we're going to add additional dates
and hopefully soul and Singapore,
maybe the Philippines.
We've got all sorts of additional things
planned.
We doing anything on the moon.
Well,
uh,
not so far,
but,
but I have some connections to you log
in basket.
Okay.
Now we'll talk to you soon.
We'll get this up right away.
Great.
Okay.
Bye.