Hello there,
Mr Ruben [inaudible].
All right,
Jp January one we got anything good for
the people?
Well,
I don't know how good it is.
Um,
I guess we're going to find out how good
it is.
It's not something I'm thrilled about by
any stretch of the imagination.
So you and I have been talking for a
couple of weeks now.
Never since this scandal around Carl
Benjamin or Sargon of the cod broken.
We decided,
well a while back that we were going to
while do a variety of things,
right?
We were going to announce our departure
from Patrion,
which is what we're doing in this video.
I'm going to leave Patriot on January
15th
I also am going to leave Patriot on
January 15th which by the way,
we should just be clear.
This is not something that we wanted to
do.
We were both perfectly happy on
patriotic patriotic,
at least for me,
it's been the backbone of my show.
I mean that's,
it's somewhere between 60 and 70% of our
funding is through patriots.
So this is not something we wanted to
do.
I know we're going to talk about a whole
bunch of things in this reporting.
Uh,
but that New York Times article that
came out,
the implication was,
oh,
we're doing this for money.
It's like we're taking a major hit right
now and opening ourselves up to all
sorts of risks.
So I'm going ahead and doing that
because I believe we can do something
better.
We've got to figure out exactly what
that is and that's what we're working
on.
So we can say two things.
I mean,
I,
I'd also like to thank the Patriot on
people for what they did in the past
because they provided me with a
tremendous amount of,
or the ability,
the opportunity to generate a tremendous
amount of financial support at a time.
I really needed it.
And so I'm not happy in the least with
what has happened.
I have thought about it a lot and
believe that given patrons proclivity to
sensor and the reasons that they're
doing it,
especially as I've looked more and more
deeply into the reasons,
um,
particularly with regards to my
discovery of the website changed the
terms,
I've become increasingly convinced that
it's unethical to continue my
association with the company.
And I also agree,
Jack Conte said in that New York Times
article trying to justify,
say Sam Harris his departure and are
threatened departure that it was
motivated primarily by financial gain
and like,
look,
I've got nothing against financial gain.
You know,
I've said that from the beginning.
And if if things that I'm doing generate
an honest amount of money that I can put
two reasonable use,
then so much the better.
But
this is a major financial blow.
I'm using the Patriot on money for a
variety of reasons.
Most particularly to support this
educational endeavor that I've talked to
people about.
Right.
Our attempt to build an online education
system.
And so like it's a major hit.
Yeah.
And of course,
you know,
just to be clear,
it's like when,
when we're doing my show,
I mean I don't have to tell everybody
about Youtube d monetization,
but for example,
my show a week or two ago with the mom
to Iti was demonetized by the algorithm.
Then demonetized further after manual
review by a human,
so it's patriotic,
it's the,
it's the supporters,
the individual people that allow us to
go ahead and do more of these
controversial so to speak episode.
So yeah,
just nothing that we're doing right now
is against the people that have
supported us or our patrons or anything
like that.
This is,
this is about making a stand against
this ever moving encroachments on free
speech and free expression and the rest
of it,
and it's like this is one that we just
feel is the right one to make the move
on.
The reason that we jointly decided on
January 15th well,
there was a couple of reasons.
The first was we thought that we might
have something approximating an
alternative potentially available for
preliminary launch at that date.
Although we've decided to delay that
because the user interface needs work
because that's the other thing,
right?
Is that their needs perhaps to be a
replacement for patron,
if that's a possibility,
like it's not obvious to me that
corporations can run platforms for
untrammeled communication successfully
on the net in today's climate and that
food,
anything I might design,
let's not,
let's not gloss over that.
I mean it might be possible that the
Patriot method is not what's needed
exactly for the future of the Internet.
I mean this is what we're trying to
figure out right now,
which is why we've got every engineer,
I mean people from Google and facebook
and Yahoo and everybody reaching out to
us because it's like everyone's trying
to solve this problem and it's still,
I mean,
one of the things we've been talking
about now for the last while,
it's really for the last year,
but intensely in the last month is what
actually is the problem itself because
until we really figure out what the
problem is.
Well,
I think,
I think the problem is
how to regulate an incredibly diverse
range of opinions.
If such regulation needs to be
instantiated,
we could take a limit case,
for example,
the desire of companies like facebook
not to have their platforms used for
recruitment for Isis.
It's hard to make a case that that's not
a reasonable restriction.
Right.
But then,
but then the next issue is,
I think you could make an exception
there because maybe you consider that a
wartime exception or something like
that.
But then the fundamental problem to me
seems to be,
and I'll return again to that change the
terms website that a whole variety of
companies and organizations spearheaded
in not least by the southern poverty law
center,
that hateful organization,
the worst that has decided that they're
going to
compel encourage.
Uh,
what
if fame,
perhaps companies that don't band
together to what they see as hate
speech.
Yeah,
and this is where,
well,
this is where the moving line is.
The key part of this,
because you can always find the free,
the most fringe cases.
You can always find isis on one side and
you know,
the most fringe KKK white supremacist
group or whatever you want to call it on
the other side.
Well,
let's not forget southern poverty law
center.
They've written things about you.
They've written things about me.
I on Hirsi Ali and my gender wise and
Sam Harris and a litany of Majid sued
them to,
to and actually want.
So there,
there is a push back,
but this is just another level of the
stand.
It's like they cannot be trusted to be
on the boards of any of these
organizations that are deciding,
right.
What terms of services should have
access.
It's really who should have access to
the Internet isn't just about worse.
It's worse than outdated because when
they start to pressure the credit card
companies,
and I would consider this a warning to
everyone who's listening.
He's like,
okay,
let's think this through.
So the New York Times last week wrote an
article about the credit cards
complicity in loaning money to that
terrible tiny minority of people who
engaged in mass shootings stating that
it was the responsibility of the credit
card companies to monitor and
potentially prevent that activity.
It's like,
okay,
so what's the,
what's the idea here?
The idea is that the companies to whom
we have in trusted our monetary system
in large parts,
that would be the credit card companies
now get to review our spending patterns
to determine if what we purchased is in
accordance with that,
with what they regard as morally
acceptable.
Okay.
And we think that's a good idea that
that's where we're headed.
And Mastercard and visa and paypal are
already starting to block people like
they brought,
mastercard was instrumental in blocking
Spencer,
Robert Spencer,
right?
It's Robert Spencer,
not retreats fancier.
Yes.
It's the best selling author and the guy
who runs Jihad watch mastercard required
patron two d plot form him.
And just to be very clear,
they sent out a tweet,
which everyone can find.
I'm shocked that they haven't deleted it
yet where they said that they,
and they use this word,
which I think is the key to the whole
thing.
They said that they unfortunately had to
delete his patrion because of
mastercard.
So what are they actually saying?
There are these patriot and saying,
oh we didn't want to delete your page,
but mastercard forced our hand.
I mean that is some deeply scary.
Yeah.
Well then we have to talk about hate
speech because you know,
I think the whole concept of,
look,
obviously there is a,
people can be very nasty when they
communicate,
but the idea that there's an
identifiable category and you can put
boundaries around it and turn it hate
speech and then you can produce
committees or deal with people on a one
to one basis as patron is doing without
any central policy or let's,
despite their central policy or that you
could turn that into an algorithm that
could validly identify hate speech
without producing false positives.
Right.
Without accusing people who shouldn't be
accused of violating all of that's just
completely,
it's just beggars the imagination as far
as,
well,
of course.
And you're also just opening a Pandora's
box from hell because just in the last
couple of days,
I don't know if you saw this,
but the women's march in California
canceled their rally because they felt
that it was too white.
Yup.
Now imagine if they canceled their rally
because it was too black or too anything
else.
It's like,
so does that count as,
hey,
are you guys now being racist against
white people and now we know that that
wouldn't be a problem for these guys.
One of the things that I can't fathom in
some sense is the lack of imagination on
the part of the people who are engaging
in censorship of what they regard as
hate speech.
Like there's an old military adage which
is that if you invent a weapon it will
be used by your enemy within 15 years.
Okay,
so why?
What makes the people on the on the left
because they're the ones who are doing
this as you can clearly see in the
change the terms website,
what makes them so sure that exactly the
same tactics won't be used against them
like at the drop of a hat once,
once the tactics have been validated and
put in place.
I think it's either,
it's either just very shortsightedness
on their hand or they think that they
can actually stamp out enough hate
within that very small window before it
would turn on them.
Or they just don't think these things
fully through
or,
or there's another just another
possibility too,
which is that there are so opposed to
the fundamental structures of the West
that let's say and regard them as so
patriarchal and oppressive,
that they'd be willing to take the risk
of sacrificing their own free speech
just to have there what have their
destructive way,
something like that.
We should also acknowledge that in the
New York Times piece that was written,
which was written by Nellie Bowles,
who wrote the,
the now infamous piece about you and
Enforcement Origami,
uh,
that the quote that Jacqueline Hart,
who is the head of trust and safety over
a patriot.
No,
there's no hidden who has no grounding
in philosophy or any of the background
training that might be necessary to even
remotely begin to participate properly
in such a thing.
No,
of course not.
But,
so the quote that she gave Nellie in the
article said that you can't say these,
I'm loosely quoting this now.
You can't say these words on our
platform,
referring to Carl,
referring to him saying the n word in
that video,
which we,
which we know they were using out of
context and all that,
but he never set it on their platform.
He never said it on patriotic.
He didn't even say it on his own
channel.
That was you,
you know,
using Patrion for the funding.
So there was a,
it's almost the entire story was built
on quicksand that tried to put out there
on the New York Times.
Now,
of course myself and many other people
tweet the hell out of it and gets
hundreds and thousands probably of
retweets and comments to Nellie and she
doesn't respond.
Nor does the New York Times issue any
sort of correction about the most
fundamental piece of the story was alive
and they don't have,
they don't have a problem doing that.
So that's why this is so layered about
speech and finance
and journalists.
Amazing to see journalists take the
journey.
One of the things that happened in
Canada to me was that,
you know,
after I made the initial videos that
caused such a political furor was that
once the main journalists in Canada sort
of figured out what I was doing,
they all came out in my support.
Like the post media group,
which is 200 newspapers all came out to
support what I was doing because they
realize that,
oh,
they're journalists.
Apart from Comedians,
there isn't anybody who relies more on
the principle of free speech to justify
and allow their occupation even to exist
for the New York Times.
Not Too understand that this threat is
a,
also a threat to everything upon which
their entire organization has been
predicated is also an indication of that
same kind of willful blindness that
we've already been discussing.
But having said that,
I would still like to say I think the
biggest danger here I really,
and it's just made my jaw drop over the
last couple of weeks thinking about it,
is the fact that the credit card
companies are now taking it upon
themselves to potentially police the
activities of their users.
It's like my God,
is that really,
I just,
I just can't believe that
any sensible person would think that
through and then want to live in a
society where your spending habits are
being monitored by the company that
basically produces your money.
Well,
think of anything more totalitarian than
that.
Toso loosely quote our friend Eric
Weinstein.
Should Republicans be allowed to use
roads that,
that sort of where we're headed here,
that every public good will be
eventually decided,
can you access to it?
Will you have access to water?
It should,
uh,
should,
an avowed white supremacist right now
that is potentially watching this or
lives in America somewhere.
She,
one of the 50 of the,
one of the 42 of them should,
should they have access to water at
their home?
Should they allow to be able to get
electricity at their home or phone lines
or all of these things?
I mean,
this is where we're headed.
Especially when you ever expand the
definition of who that person is.
Yeah.
They won't in China.
Right?
Well,
that's where they're going.
Right.
So is that the test case?
Well,
I think it's,
it's an indication that the fact that
the Chinese have been tempted into this
is also an indication of the temptation.
It's intrinsic in the technological
power.
The credit card companies are in a weird
situation as far as I'm concerned
because the only reason they work at all
is because people actually trust them
completely.
I just like,
oh,
you're just a proxy for money.
Like you're a proxy for cash.
In fact,
that's basically how the mastercard
advertises itself,
right?
So you're a proxy for cash and the
government doesn't watch what you spend
your money on except an extraordinarily
extraordinarily limited cases.
I mean there are money laundering laws
and so forth,
but that's a direct violation of a law,
right?
That's part of tracking down criminal
activity that it has nothing to do so
far with with hate speech,
which by the way is protected by the
first amendment.
So or which means in some sense that it
doesn't exist.
You know,
as a,
as a legal,
as a legal
concept.
It doesn't.
This is my Canada,
which is,
we shouldn't gloss over that fact too
because you know you are and we just did
however many countries in Europe and
we're going to go back this spring and
it's like everybody that we met was
jealous of the freedoms that we have in
the United States relative to speech.
You know what I mean?
And everybody that would come up to us
after the show,
holy cow,
I wish we could say that.
I wish we didn't worry about this or
that or jokes or the rest of it.
And we did that video in Oslo where you
talked about Danky Ila and it's like
they're,
they're jealous of our freedom.
So we should be very clear here that
though you're right,
because we now have a payment processor
issue,
which is an indirect connection to
whatever it is that we're trying to
build out here.
And we're still,
it's a little a morphous
at the moment
is that it's changing because a lot of
people are saying,
all right,
you guys really want to solve this.
Then you have to go full crypto.
The video has to be hosted.
Crypto.
Yeah.
The finances have to be hosted or have
to be done via crypto.
All of these things,
these are,
these are major,
major things that we're trying to figure
out on every front.
Certain payment processors are a little
more willing to stand up to the mob than
others.
So we're talking to different people.
I mean we'll really going on everything
that's right.
Well,
the tentative platform that we're trying
to build and to build carefully,
we'll provide the possibility of
multiple payment portals in the hope
that they creators will be less
susceptible to being rapidly shutdown or
perhaps shutdown at all.
But you know,
only a fool would say that that problem
is going to be definitively solved.
I have some real increasing sympathy for
the crypto currency types.
No,
but the problem there is that as far as
I can tell,
their solution is still sufficiently
technically complex to keep it out of
the mainstream use and also not
sufficiently liquid to actually
constitute a realistic current
replacement even for credit cards.
Right.
So one of the things we've been
discussing is that it's almost like we
have to have several markers down the
road to figure out what the real
solution is because not everything can
be solved in terms of terms of service
tomorrow related to that exists.
Not Everything can be solved tomorrow
related to the payment processors may be
crypto really is the ultimate answer,
but it's not the answer tomorrow for
everything.
So we're,
we're really,
we're plotting out a lot here,
but it seems like a fresh and sort of
fitting way to start the year.
I think
so.
And so for January 15th I mean,
part of the reason that we picked that
date,
as I said before,
it was because we thought we might have
something to announce with regards to an
alternative platform,
but you know,
saner heads have prevailed in that
calmer heads.
Yeah.
And also we want it to give people an
opportunity to decide what they wanted
to do it without just springing it on
them.
I mean,
I have some real admiration for Harris
for acting so immediately.
Definitively.
Yeah.
It's funny,
you know,
I saw some criticism,
it's like,
all right,
well Sam dropped immediately and look
you and Peter said you're still there
and you're talking about this whole
thing and it's like we all have
different things to consider.
We all have different family situations,
different business situations,
different livelihood situations,
everything.
So it's like we were really trying to
just plot this thing out properly and to
be very clear,
we're still in the process of that.
So for any sort of,
for anyone watching this right now,
if you're supporting Jordan on Patriot
or you're supporting me on Patriot or
both of us or whatever it is,
it's like now we're trying to shift
people because at least by getting off
patriotic the moment we remove one of
the middlemen and you can now go
directly,
go to directly to Jordan b peterson.com
or [inaudible] dot com and you can at
least if you want to donate,
you can do that for now while we figure
out everything else.
And that way we removed one of the
pieces here because there's just too
many pieces here that are creating this
mess.
I think it's too much to hope for a
perfect solution to a very complex
problem.
And um,
we're muddling through the best we can
and hopefully people will regard our
decision joint decision too.
Leave Patriot as a step in the right
direction,
however imperfectly taken.
Yeah.
Well look,
I think I said it before,
but I really think that,
and maybe this will be the defining,
uh,
idea of 2019 is that I think we're
basically at the point where people have
to decide what sort of internet they
want and it's not only what sort of
internet,
it's really what sort of freedom do you
want in a digital world and either or do
you want any or do you want any,
and maybe maybe you don't or you don't
want to think about it and you just want
to play fortnight and watch porn and
never think it through.
I'm assuming that you'll be allowed to
watch porn,
right?
So that now you really are a pilot or
play for that matter.
Right.
So the
games of violence should be allowed.
What makes you think that credit card
companies should allow you to use their,
their funds to purchase first,
first person shooter games for example,
or any game where anyone has killed?
No,
you're totally right.
That's,
I mean that sounds completely dystopian
and yet it seems like that would just be
the next encroachment that we would see
here.
So the point at the end,
at the end of this is I think everyone
for for 2019 since it's the first day of
the year,
it's like you have to think about what
type of Internet do you want,
what type of ability to communicate with
other people do you want?
And if you want something that's a
little better than what we've got right
now,
we better stand up quick because this
window we,
we know it's closing slowly,
but we never know when it's going to
really slap shot quick.
So,
so we're working on it and,
and I think people are ready to stand up
with us.
I really do.
We might also suggest to people,
and this is of course up to everyone
who's feeling this to decide,
but you know,
couple of thousand letters to mastercard
and paypal and visa indicating
pronounced displeasure at their plans to
become a custodians of the monetary
supply for ethical reasons might also be
an order.
You know,
these companies are responsive to public
pressure,
which is perhaps partly why they're
determining to play the role of censor
to begin with.
You know,
they're,
they are facing pressure from these,
let's call them activist interest
groups,
who again,
are outlined on change the terms on the
website,
change the terms and they're responding
to public pressure.
And that's understandable.
MMM.
It's understandable,
but
yeah,
but inexcusable in certain in a certain
regard,
but the right way perhaps to begin to
push back is to let the credit card
companies know that there's a
constituency on the other side that I s
I suspect constitutes the vast majority
of credit card users.
The silent middle majority of let's say,
Western society who were neither
radically right nor radically left,
who would just as soon not have their
spending habits monitored by giant
corporations.
That's pretty funny too,
that the left is so opposed to corporate
entities,
you know,
on principle,
especially to sizable ones and you know,
have a certain justification for being
skeptical about the moral direction of
very large organizations,
um,
are so eager to hand over the reigns of
social control to precisely the
companies you'd think they would be
least likely to crawl into bed with.
I mean,
really mastercard visa,
it's like right.
Or at the same time they'll,
they want to hand over more control to
the government to handle these things.
And,
and we should be pretty clear that in
the last couple of weeks that we've been
discussing this,
every single discussion that we've had
about this,
I don't think once did we entertain the
idea of,
Oh,
we've got to get the government involved
to fix this thing.
I mean,
there,
there could be,
as,
as you referenced earlier,
there could be specific legal,
uh,
issues that pop up related to collusion.
And signed a couple of other things.
Cartel developed.
Cocked.
Yeah,
like that sort of thing.
But,
but the beauty of this,
and again why I'm so,
I'm watching my monthly rev of my
company go down even though we're,
we're making some of it back,
but as I'm watching that happen,
as I said to you last time,
I'm,
I'm incredibly inspired right now
because literally thousands of emails
are pouring in from people that want to
work with us,
that want to help us,
that want to figure out how to fund
things or that want to work as engineers
or the rest of it.
And that tells you that,
that people are,
people are afraid and they see this
problem and they just want some
solutions and,
and maybe there isn't an easy solution.
As you said,
there have also been talking with you
online with a whole bunch of the people
who've been loosely aggregated under the
ages of the intellectual dark web.
And that's probably 30 people that,
that we've been communicating with,
with a variety of peripheral people.
And it's also useful to let people know
that every one of those people is
unbelievably concerned about what
happened to Carl Benjamin to,
sorry,
go on.
And even more so
dumbstruck by the collusion payment
processing companies and,
and the emergence of this activist
infrastructure online that's devoted
specifically to the suppression of free
speech.
And also we should also note that within
that group of say 30 or so white people,
we all sort of look,
we agree on basic fundamental principles
related to free speech and things like
that,
but there's a lot of disagreement on how
to move forward with this.
I mean,
we're talking it out respectfully as we
always do,
but some people are saying,
stay in fight on Patrion because this is
how,
you know,
they're small enough say that you might
get them to change.
Some people are saying you gotta go.
That's when people are saying some
version of,
you know,
mixing those
and nobody's clear about the proper
pathway forward.
Yeah.
But that's again,
I mean I think this is what the
brilliance of human ingenuity is all
about.
It's like we're,
they're going to be some pitfalls in
front of us and staying would have its
risks and leaving would average risks
and we're all going to do what we think
is why we've already discussed that too,
right,
is that there's,
there's no,
there's no known risk option here and
like,
and so we're taking the risk of leaving
and then we're gonna make the best of
it.
I mean often when you take a risky,
often in life,
all you have is a choice between two
different risks and sometimes neither of
them are risks you would like to take.
Then in the aftermath of that decision,
a new field of possibility opens up in
front of you too and whether or not you
made the right decision is actually a
consequence of how well you manage the
aftermath of that decision.
So we'll,
we'll keep talking over the next couple
of months on like I've got good people
working on this alternative,
you know,
which,
which was,
as I mentioned in other places,
started seven months ago or so.
And good people supervising it,
whether it'll turn out to be a viable
product and whether or not we can figure
out how to implement it in a sustainable
way that actually addresses these issues
in a reasonable manner remains to be
seen
on a,
on a personal note,
just because,
uh,
you know,
I got to see you a couple of days before
Christmas in West Palm Beach and,
and we had dinner with uh,
with your family and your kids and
everything.
It hasn't,
it's sort of been nice cause I did a
week with,
uh,
with my brother and sister and nieces
and nephews over Christmas.
Also sort of circling back to family on
some of this.
Uh,
it,
it's given me a lot of perspective.
You know,
it it mean cause I'm getting,
I'm getting reached out by so many
different people on all different
fronts,
but then to have sort of a close knit
group of people that really do have your
interest in mind and all those things
with your kids at dinner,
it was like,
oh these are good people to
nymity on the part of the people around
me that the proper thing to do is
twofold.
One is to separate myself from Patrion
in accordance with our discussions.
And the second is to proceed with
exceeding caution and not over promise,
um,
or try to deliver to quickly a solution,
although to work on that carefully.
So that's what we've decided to do.
Yeah.
So let's just be crystal clear on that
latter,
latter part.
We are working on this.
We're going to be deliberate.
We are going to be cautious.
We understand that it can't be solved
tomorrow.
We understand that there's a financial
part of free speech part and everything
else and we're just going to lay these
things out in front of us and we're
going to keep working through it with a
lot of the people that you guys know and
trust and,
and,
and with,
with some other people.
And,
and hearing from random people that have
given us ideas.
I mean,
I've been forwarding you emails left and
right where people are like,
you know,
this might be the,
the pressure point you might want to go
after,
so we're just going to keep,
Yup.
Okay.
Well I got a couple of things to end
this.
I guess let's summarize it then.
I've got a couple of things just to let
people know about.
Uh,
well the first is,
so we're both leaving on January 15th
and the second is we're working on this
platform and the third is a warning to
people to keep a close eye on what the
credit card companies are up to because
that's a really bad thing in my
estimation.
I guess that's probably it on my front.
I have a talk coming up in Zurich.
I have a couple of talks in California
in January.
I'll be with you on those.
Yup.
And the tickets to those are available
on my website@jordanbpeterson.com and
the final thing is I also set up with my
partners as a new years token.
Let's say that future authoring program
from the self authoring suite and we put
it up at 50% off with the code and why
2019 and so if anybody's out there wants
to make some personal,
what do you call those resolutions for
the New Year,
then this program is an ideal way of
doing that.
And so that's also partly a thank you to
everyone who um,
has been so supportive and interested in
the last year.
And so I think that's basically,
I think that's basically that.
What do you think?
No,
I think that's basically it.
So I'll just quickly give a shout out to
Dave rubin.com/donate and what we're,
what we're trying to do,
and I know you're trying to do this as
well,
is that for whoever signs up now and
we're,
we're taking,
it's one time and monthly donations that
you can do.
There are going to be ways that we think
once we build out whatever it is we're
working on that,
that it'll all be able to be flipped
into that.
So it's not like we're going to have
people constantly having to start new
accounts or,
or,
you know,
sign up for new things or anything like
that.
We're trying to make this as easy as
possible for everybody.
And they'll look,
there's going to be some bumps,
but
this is it.
Say about 2019 there's going to be,
there's going to be some bumps.
Well,
I don't know if you know this Jordan,
but we got an American election come and
the year after that.
So
Mr Ruben,
happy new year.
All right,
happy new year,
brother.
Healthy and a in Cali and a couple of
weeks.
Bye for now.