Now,
you know,
I use this picture
to represent my class and you might not
know anything about this picture.
It's a picture of Jonah being thrown up
out of a whale's belly after spending
three days inside it.
It's an old biblical story.
It's a myth.
It's a fairy tale.
That's a,
that's one way of looking at it and,
and I don't mean that drug in a
derogative manner.
We know for example,
that some of the grims brothers'
fairytales are perhaps 15,000 years old.
It'd be traced way back.
They're really,
really old and old stories are strange.
They're strange because while they're
being told generation after generation
after generation,
so you could imagine that something
retold over such an expansive,
expansive time has been reduced to its
just many,
many times and nothing that's in the
story anymore is superfluous.
It's all meaningful in some sense.
It's sort of like a med,
a story.
That's one way of thinking about,
imagine that you took a hundred books,
hundred adventure books,
and you had to extract out the central
features of an adventure book.
Now it's hard to do that.
It's like you're averaging across them
or something like that,
distilling them in some manner.
Okay.
Then you'd get a,
a Meta adventure and it would be like a
myth upon which all adventures are
based.
And this story is actually one of those
stories.
And I'm going to tell you what I think
the story means.
And I'm not saying that this is all it
means,
because most stories of this sort are in
some sense inexhaustible,
just like great works of art are
inexhaustible there.
There's more information in them than
you can possibly articulate.
That's what makes them
profound.
That's why you go look at them.
Cause otherwise someone could just tell
you about the painting and that would be
the end of that.
But that doesn't work.
So,
so Jonah is being spit up by this whale.
And of course on the face of it,
that's an impossibility because,
well,
you can't live inside a whale.
That's why it's impossible.
Now,
you may remember and likely do that.
You all know a story about someone who
is inside a whale.
That's Pinocchio,
right?
And,
uh,
you know,
you go to that movie,
maybe even as an adult,
you watch that movie and Japan goes down
there in the whale and his little boat,
you know,
it's big cavernous inside.
You don't really care that that's,
there's a bunch of things you don't care
about.
You don't care that those are drawings
and not real people.
You don't care about that.
And you don't care that the inside of a
whale isn't a cavern and you don't care
that Pinocchio's a puppet for that
matter.
None of that matters to you at all.
And that's because you're really strange
creatures and you don't even notice when
you're doing something absolutely
absurd.
And that's one of those times when you
are in,
but if someone taps you on the shoulder
and says,
you know,
you're just watching drawings of a
puppet,
puppets can't really move autonomously
and now he's at the bottom of the ocean,
you have no idea why he's going to
rescue his father and you're just
sitting there and all and you're okay
with that.
And you'll say,
shut up because I want to finish
watching the movie.
And so that's interesting.
You See,
that tells you something about your
unconscious.
If you're a psychoanalytically minded
because you're doing something that you
cannot account for.
Now you might say,
well,
it's,
it's enjoyable.
Well that's deep man.
You really,
really going a long ways with that.
The question is,
hey,
why is it comprehensible?
B,
Why is it enjoyable?
See,
just exactly what are you doing there?
And you think that whatever you are
doing there is so valuable that you'll
actually pay to do it.
Weird.
Very,
very weird.
And you know,
when you read about
let's say the archaic rituals of tribal
people and you ask yourself just what
are they up to?
You might think,
well,
they're up to the same thing that you're
up to when you go see a movie.
So,
and then you might also notice that the
most expensive artifacts or among the
most expensive artifacts that human
beings create our movies,
it's been hundreds of millions of
dollars on them.
And we consider that a good deal.
And you know,
it drives our technology too because the
high tech movies like the marvel movies
that require so much computer animation,
they actually drive the demand for high
end graphics chips.
So our technological advance forward is
actually motivated in part by our desire
to represent things fictionally in
evermore spectacular manner.
So Jonah,
well,
let me tell you the story of Jonah
and I'll tell you why.
I'm going to tell you what this is from
Camille Paglia,
who is a critic of the modern university
and very brilliant woman,
I would say very controversial,
um,
credibly rapid speaker and she can think
so fast.
It's just unbelievable.
She's really fun to watch,
if you like that sort of thing.
Vicious adversary in an argument.
She says the number one problem in
academia today is not ignorant students,
but ignorant professors
who have substituted narrow expertise in
theoretical of preposterous term for
breadth and depth of learning in the
world,
history of art and thought art is a vast
interconnected web work,
a fabricated tradition and
overconcentration on any one point is a
distortion.
Here's,
here's the problem.
I had to,
I wrestled with this when I was trying
to understand some of the things that
I'm going to teach you about.
There's some things that you kind of
have to grasp as a whole.
You know,
sometimes you have a flash of insight
and a bunch of things that you didn't
know were related fall together that
that's supposed to happen in
psychotherapy when you link different
disparate patterns of behavior together
because you've linked them say with a
single cause and you get this like
excited feeling of illumination and
possibility
and there are forms of communication
that require the simile.
Tanium Lee,
the simultaneous realization of a
multitude of disparate.
So now I'm gonna like a movie can be
like that.
You know,
you,
you listen to a movie,
you watch a movie and then you don't
know what the hell is going on and then
something happens near the end and bang,
everything clicks together and it's
because you've sort of seen the thing as
a whole.
And a lot of the things that we,
a lot of the ways that we interact with
the world that are mysterious
are like that there.
And this is what Peggy is referring to
is that,
and this is a psychoanalytic
proposition,
I would say,
or a romantic proposition.
MMM.
Then the idea roughly is that
way out in the periphery of reality or
all those things that not only do you
not know,
but you don't even know,
you don't know right there.
You're completely blind to their
existence.
And then there's unknown things that you
have some suspicions about.
can start to imagine and,
and act out and dramatize.
And so all of that is on the periphery
of our knowledge,
not to psycho Hadley analytic dictum.
Where do thoughts come from?
Well,
partly they're nested in dreams.
Dreams are the birthplace of thoughts.
Fantasy.
It's not that surprising.
Fantasy is the birthplace of ideas.
You know,
if you're thinking about what you're
gonna do in the future,
you enter into a reverie,
a dream state,
and you contemplate multiple
possibilities and then you start
thinking them through.
Use your imagination to search beyond
where you are and the collective human
attempt to do that is are mysterious
humanistic,
artistic tradition,
which is very difficult to justify from
a formal articulate point of view.
What good is dance?
Like?
What is it that you're doing when you're
dancing?
Well,
you don't care because he liked to
dance.
Why?
Well,
you don't know like you do.
It's built into music.
Music's a human.
Universal culture is used music to
organize themselves,
right?
They use music to catalyze their
identities.
They use music to unite around no in
more archaic societies,
less differentiated society's let's say
no.
Uh,
a mask that represents part of the
family tradition will have a particular
design and there'll be a particular song
written for it and there'll be a
particular dance about it and the song
and the dance or something like the
symbolic representation of a mode of
being in the world.
Like maybe the mask is a wolf mask.
And so you act out the wolf and there's
music that goes along with that and you
think,
well,
what are you doing when you're acting
out the wolf?
And part of that is what you're trying,
you're trying to understand wolves,
you know,
it's an image,
it's imitation in part.
And you know,
if you live in the natural world and if
you haunt and if you're preyed upon,
then understanding the things that
you're hunting and preying upon is
useful.
And there's also pull out perhaps useful
things to learn from them.
And so we played this strange symbolic
game with the world,
like children pretending that's another
way of thinking about it.
And we do that to act out and to begin
to understand things we don't understand
like how to act.
That's now for me,
the most important question in life is
not
what the world is made of.
And in fact,
I would say that's a relatively new
preoccupation of,
of humankind.
You know,
we didn't really formalize,
you could say that the ancient Greeks
originated,
laid the groundwork for the emergence of
an empirical science.
And then it emerged more formally with
Bacon and Descartes and,
uh,
Newton
five,
600 years ago.
Not very long,
like a blink,
blink of the eye in human terms.
Before that,
people were engineers.
They could build things and so forth,
but they didn't know how to,
they weren't scientists.
They didn't really conceptualize the
world as an objective place.
We do that automatically because science
has seeped so far into our
set of presuppositions that doesn't make
us good scientists by the way.
But it does make us that the fundamental
reality of the world is an objective
reality.
And I'm not going to dispute that
particularly,
but leaves one set of questions on
answered,
um,
probably by its nature because it wasn't
designed to answer the question.
And that question is how should one
conduct oneself in the world?
And that's an important thing since
you're alive and hypothetically,
you'd rather stay alive and well,
you're alive.
You probably don't want to suffer
anymore than you have to and no more
stupidly than you have to.
And it might also be good if some of the
things that you wanted actually
happened.
And so you know,
you're motivated to know how to act and,
and people are always telling each other
how to act.
We're sending each other information all
the time about how to act.
We do that with are the expressions on
our face.
And of course when we talk to people,
we always look at their face and that's
because their face tells you what
they're up to.
You know,
if they're smiling and paying attention
to you,
well then you can assume that you're
doing something right and if they're
looking annoyed or disgusted,
that's a particularly bad one.
Then you might think he might take him
from that,
especially if you know,
three or four people are doing it at the
same time.
And so we're reflecting,
we're reflecting some ideal to one
another constantly.
And the more attentive you are,
the more likely you are to act in
accordance with that ideal.
And the more like you likely you are to
move towards it,
you may not even know what the ideal is
in an articulated sentence.
In fact,
you probably don't.
You know,
you could come up with a,
well,
you know,
a good person is nice and friendly and
cooperative and yeah,
yeah.
You know,
that's all just cliche,
but you don't,
you know,
your conception might be very hollow.
It's very likely that it's very hollow.
Even though you may be to act in a very
sophisticated manner.
All right,
so anyways,
this is a story I'd say.
What's a metes story?
It's,
it's what would happen if you collected
a bunch of stories and then you extract
it out a story from them and it's sort
of a story about destiny and it's
couched in a religious language.
Um,
but that's okay because most of these
distilled stories are formed.
The foundation of religious texts and
religious texts and myth and myths and
stories are,
as I said,
part of the outer perimeter of our
society.
They have a,
they have a coherent nature and it's all
it and the form of a foundation and it's
on that foundation that everything that
you take for granted rests even if you
don't understand the foundation.
So I can give you an example.
There's a metaphysical idea that
underlies western civilization and that
metaphysical idea is that the has
transcendent worth.
That's,
that's the idea from which the notion of
natural rights is derived.
And of course,
our legal system is predicated on the
idea that you have certain natural
rights.
They're enshrined in the bill of rights,
for example.
And in the states when the bills bill of
rights was being formulated,
when the legislation,
original legislation that founded the
state was being formulated,
the formulators said,
we hold these truths to be self evident.
What does that mean?
They're axioms of faith.
They're propositions and there's no
proof for them.
They're there or mode of operation in
the world.
And so the hypothesis is something like,
well,
if I treat you like there's something
about you that has transcendent value,
implicit intrinsic value,
whatever that might be.
And there are stories about that and
we'll talk about that and you do the
same to me.
And then we set up a body of laws that
recognizes the sovereignty of the
individual so that the law itself has to
act with respect towards every
individual.
Even if that individual has done
something reprehensible,
which is very weird.
If you think about it,
then our society will work better
and well,
perhaps that's true,
but for better or worse,
that is what this society is predicated
on.
And that's a very,
very,
very old idea.
And it's an idea that people came to
with great difficulty because it was
over thousands of years that people
learned how to take their little tribal
groups,
which are always squabbling with one
another,
right?
Cause there's human beings,
they're very violent and tribal groups
are by no means civilized.
It's,
there's no noble savage like the
Europeans thought.
If you study tribal groups in the world
today,
the murder,
the death rate by violence is
unbelievably high.
So
something unites a tribe within a tribe,
it's often kinship.
But then tribes come together to form
larger civilizations and they have to
determine some sort of med,
have principle that guides them so that
they can cooperate and come together
without destroying one another.
And they have to extract out of
principle by which the society might
function.
And that has to work.
And then as societies get bigger and
bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger,
they have to bring more and more of
these diverse traditions together and
extract out something from them that has
power and functional utility.
And that allows people to unite.
And so
this is one of the stories that talks
about that it's a story about individual
responsibility and what happens when
it's not heated.
So you know,
cause we could say you are a social
creature right to the core and most of
your environment is other people and
those other people want something from
you and you want something from them.
So you're going to play games with them.
You're either going to be good at it,
you're going to be bad at it,
but you're going to play games with
them.
And so the game might have rules,
really sophisticated rules in fact.
And you'd expect that because as your
behavior more and more approximates an
ideal,
assuming such a thing exists,
then you're more and more sophisticated.
And the nature of the ideal is perhaps
more and more complex and difficult to
understand.
You get a hint of this though.
You can get a hint of this because you
will see if you pay attention to your
own soul,
your psyche,
your unconscious,
you'll see that there are people that
you admire and that there are people
that you have contempt for.
And that's,
and it isn't necessarily that you're a
hundred percent accurate in your
judgment,
you know,
it's not such a bad idea to criticize
your first
impressions,
but those states exist.
And so there's a reason you admire
someone and there's a reason you have
contempt for someone.
There may be multiple reasons and that's
a hint to your intrinsic value
structure.
It's a hint about your intrinsic value
structure,
right?
You wouldn't admire someone unless there
was something about them that you valued
and perhaps that you would also like to
be able to do.
And you wouldn't despise someone or have
contempt for them if you didn't feel
that something they were doing was wrong
and that it would be wrong if you did it
too.
And so you're bringing to bear on the
situation and implicit morality.
And you have to do that because as I
said,
yeah,
it can't act without a morality.
Because if you're going to act,
you're going to try to make things
better that otherwise why bother?
And if you're acting to make things
better than some things have to be
better and some things have to be worse.
And that's a value structure.
So you have one.
All right,
so Jonah,
he gets a call from God and God tells
him that there's a city Nineveh that's
falling into moral disarray.
Now what does that mean?
Well,
it's a universal story.
It's like all cultures are always
falling into disarray.
It's their nature.
Just entropy does that,
right?
Things change.
The world changes the environment,
changes in the culture,
doesn't keep up very well.
And then of course it has corrupt
elements and so it's an enduring eternal
story.
The individual is always placed in
relationship to a culture that somewhat
corrupt.
And then the question is,
well,
what do you do about it?
And if the answer is nothing,
well then it'll just get more corrupt.
And if the answer is b corrupt too,
then it will just get more corrupt.
So the answer has to be to oppose the
corruption because that's the only way
it's going to stop.
Now,
God threatens to destroy this city
because of its corruption.
And I don't think you need to presume
anything particularly metaphysical about
that to understand it.
It's very straight forward that the more
corrupt the culture is and the less
trust is possible between individuals,
the less productive the culture is going
to be.
Because why do anything,
if some corrupt person is just going to
come and take it,
you know,
it might even be that the culture is so
corrupted.
If you are good for something and you
produce resources,
you're actually more likely to get
killed because you have something of
value.
So like there's just,
you're just not going anywhere with
that.
And why would you work if you didn't
have any sense that,
you know,
you could store up the value of your
work for some reasonable time in the
future.
So if the society is corrupt and there
no trust,
it's degenerating and you know it might
live for a while but isn't going to last
very long.
And so that's the idea.
Corrupt societies collapse
that leaves open what corruption means.
Anyways,
Jonah,
thanks.
No,
I would no bloody way.
I'm not going to that city.
They can go to hell as far as I'm
concerned.
And that's really what he thinks.
And why in the world should I do
anything about it anyways?
And these are good objections.
It's like,
why would you do that?
And you'll face this,
believe me in your life,
you will face this.
In fact,
you already do always,
constantly,
continually in small ways.
Perhaps when you're interacting with
people who aren't treating you properly
and when you're acting.
And those might be your parents,
they might be your friends,
they might be people at your workplace,
they might be professors,
they're playing a crooked game and you
don't like it and you know it's crooked.
And so then the question is,
well,
what should you do about it?
Well,
if you know your crib,
no,
it's crooked.
It's not so good to play along with it.
I mean,
we'll say that you know,
it's crooked by your own standard of
values.
It d degrades you to play along with it.
You're going to stand up and oppose it.
Well,
no,
probably not.
You're probably going to do what Jonah
did.
Jump on a ship and get the hell out of
there.
And you know,
that's a logical thing to do,
but it doesn't solve the problem.
And I think this has something to do
with human ethical responsibility
because there are other old stories,
and I'll tell you one likely where the
son of the king,
the lion king,
the son of the king,
he goes off and he's some pathetic
adolescent.
And then he shamed by the reappearance
of his old girlfriend into turning into
something vaguely useful.
And he opens his eyes and he goes back
and he fights scar and
no,
it's a scene of hell,
right?
Because there's fire everywhere and he
fights scar,
finds out,
scar killed,
his father casts him into the pit,
roughly speaking,
and then the rain comes and then you
know,
the movie returns to its beginning.
Fundamentally it's an paradise,
Paradise lost,
paradise regained.
That's the movie.
And,
and I mean that's the story of human
beings.
You know,
you're in that place that's working out
pretty well.
Something happens to knock you off your
perch.
You're down in the chaos for a good
amount of time.
And maybe you never get out,
but maybe you learn something down
there.
Maybe a strength in your character and
then you pop up to a new place and maybe
it's better,
better aim,
better.
You.
Now I'm not being overly optimistic
about this.
I know perfectly well that people
encounter
impediments during their life that they
find almost impossible to recover from,
but it's the best shot you have.
So anyways,
Jonah runs away,
but God isn't very happy about that
because it's actually joan is destiny.
It's necessary for Jonah to repair the
city.
So God sends a storm and the waves are
high and and,
and I think what that means is because
the water is often a symbol for the
unconscious and that's because things
lurk down there in the water and that
you could pull up that that are useful,
monstrous things that you can pull up
their useful,
you can fish for them,
you can go fishing in your own being for
answers,
which is what you do when you try to
think right.
You ask yourself a question and you
wait,
maybe an answer appears.
It's like where did that come from?
You didn't know what the answer was
before it appeared.
When it just pop into being out of
nowhere.
Who knows?
So you fish.
So anyways,
the waves come and the boat's going to
be knocked over it.
And that's what happens.
I think when you know,
when you know you should do something,
I mean everyone has the experience,
I believe perhaps you would be willing
to put up your hands if this experience
is foreign to you.
Okay.
There's party,
you're telling you you should do
something and it's hard to do it
effortful and maybe you're afraid of it.
And so you don't do it.
You just procrastinate.
Right.
And so how do you feel about that?
Good.
I mean,
so what do you feel that you're
betraying yourself?
Your anxiety actually gets worse,
not better,
even though,
you know,
you can put it off moment to moment,
but that doesn't help because every time
you put it off,
the anxiety just grows a little bit.
You're not proud of yourself.
You have a sense that
you're making things more chaotic than
they should be.
You know?
And if you do that long enough,
and I'm sure many of you have had that
experience,
if you do that long enough,
if that becomes habitual,
things will get so stormy around you
that you'll fall right into the,
into the chaos,
into the watery chaos and maybe you'll
drown.
So it's not a very good idea to run from
your destiny,
let's say
whatever that might be.
And you need a destiny.
You need it a place to aim out because
that's what gives your life meaning and
you need meaning in your life because
life is hard.
So you know,
you need something to buttress yourself
against that.
So anyways,
they wake Jonah up and Jonah says,
hey,
it's probably my fault because like I'm
running away from something I'm supposed
to do.
And you know,
God isn't very happy about that,
so why don't you just throw me over to
overboard.
And the crew isn't very happy about
that.
But the waves are really starting to
come up and Joan is pretty insistent
that he's the cause of the problem.
And so they draw,
they draw a lot and and Jonah is chosen
and so they decided to toss them into
the ocean and immediately everything's
calm.
So he's a center of chaos because he's
not doing what he's supposed to do.
Fine.
Well then a whale comes up and swallows
him and then he's in the whale for three
days.
Now.
That's a weird thing.
The whale,
that's the way all that,
the Japan Petrosian,
that's a dragon.
It's not thing that you have to go out
there and conquer to get something of
value now,
okay.
When you've made an error,
when you've
fallen off the,
the pathway,
when you've deviated from what you know
you should do,
it produces a state of internal chaos
and worry and concern.
You're,
you're thrust into the unknown.
You're thrust into unknown territory and
chaos.
You don't know what to do.
And that's often symbolized by the
encounter with a,
with a monster,
like a dragon or something that lives
under the water.
That's it.
And I think the reason for that is as
far as I've been able to tell,
is that human beings,
because we'd been prey animals for
forever and our battle with carnivorous
lizards for example,
and alligators and even dinosaurs
because there were dinosaurs around at
the time of our most distant ancestors.
And there was even a cat at one point
that was,
that was adapted with teeth to Paris
human skulls.
So it had a head that was exactly shape
to grab you here and put a two through
the back of your skull.
So like we've come through some rough
times,
man,
and we have,
uh,
a system in our mind,
it's a threat Predator detection system.
That's the thing that makes little kids
think about monsters in the dark,
right?
Because while there is monsters in the
dark,
parents always say,
well,
there's no monsters in the dark.
It's like,
that's not true.
The darkest full of monsters.
There might not be any in your room
right at that moment.
But that doesn't mean there aren't
monsters in the dark.
And crimes take place.
Like criminals don't get up at six in
the morning.
And like,
you know,
have breakfast and go rob a bank,
they do it,
they do that sort of thing at night.
People do the things that are fit for
the night in the night and lots of
predators are nocturnal and you can't
see very well in the dark and kids
aren't stupid.
You know,
they've evolved to stay pretty damn
close to the fire because the kids that
wandered away from the fire got picked
off by hyenas and lions and crocodiles
and whatever else the hell was out there
to eat the unwary.
So
the circuit that we use to,
to defend ourselves against predators
as we've evolved cortically that circuit
has,
has come to represent what we don't know
in general because the predators of
course in habit where we don't know.
And so evolution is a conservative force
and we use the circuits that we've
evolved to represent new things.
And so the unknown,
the chaos is often represented by a
monster that swallows you up and pulls
you down.
And you know when you're feeling
terrible,
you don't say,
well I'm feeling up.
You say I'm feeling down.
Well why is that?
Well
down is worse.
I guess.
You're flat on the ground when you're
down or you're in a hole or something
like that.
You're hiding in a hole,
you know it's down and you're threatened
by something.
You know?
Maybe you're threatened by your own
inadequacy.
That might be part of it.
Maybe that's partly what you imagine as
a monstrous force because you know your
proclivity towards prass procrastination
and your weakness of character is part
and parcel of why you happen to be in
the underworld and that's the
underworld,
the mythological underworld.
That's where you go when things fall
apart and if you understand that,
if you know that that's what that means,
then you have one of the keys that opens
up ancient stories to you and you
understand things you could,
your life can be an organized,
going very well,
and then something comes up and Poof,
everything changes.
Some axiom that you were up living by
it,
it might be the existence of a partner
might be a job.
That might be your health.
Any of those things
go on and
you go somewhere.
When that happens,
It's a state of being.
You're still in the same world,
but it's not the same at all anymore.
Everything about it is different.
It's all negative and dark and you don't
know what to do.
You're confused.
And so what do you do down there in the
underworld when things have fallen
apart,
especially if hope,
if it's the worst possible case scenario
and you realize that you actually had
something to do with your demise,
that's really annoying.
You know when something bad happens to
you and then you know,
you grind yourself into bits trying to
figure out what the hell happened.
And then you realize that,
well you are playing a causal role now.
Sometimes you're so depressed,
you assume you're playing a causal role
and you work.
It's not easy to figure out by any
stretch of the imagination.
And it isn't that everyone who does
something terrible is at fault for it.
But sometimes you find that you are off
the path somehow.
And maybe even that you knew it and they
didn't attend to it.
And that's why all of this hit the fan.
And so then down there in that chaos,
you decide that you're going to do what
you're supposed to do instead.
And then maybe you get to rise up again,
renewed if you're lucky.
And then you can go fix the city.
And that's what this story's about.
And that's why I picked the image to
represent the chorus.
Because really what happens,
you see with the psychoanalysts,
the road due to health,
if you're not doing well,
which means that as you act in the
world,
you're not getting what you want.
There's something wrong with your,
the match between your presuppositions
and your actions,
habitual and the way the world is
responding to you.
And so it's not turning out for you.
And the question is,
well,
what can you do about that?
And one answer might be to examine
yourself for presuppositions and action
patterns that are not serving you well
and to find out what they are and what
to do about them.
And maybe some of that is maybe you're
not moving forward because of fear.
And maybe that theory is grounded in
terrible experiences that you had in the
past that you've never been able to
understand and maybe one of the ways of
gluing yourself back together and
expanding your personality so that you
could in fact live properly in the
world,
is to go back to those terrible events
and untie them and straighten them out
and understand them and drop them.
And that's what psychotherapy is about
in large part,
psychoanalytic,
behavioral,
doesn't matter.
What are you afraid of?
What are you avoiding?
What are you failing to develop?
Maybe from fear,
maybe from avoidance,
God only knows maybe from disgust.
How can you get over it?
How can you reclaim those parts of your
self?
I sat in the first lecture that I was
going to try to provide you with a
Schema
into which you could place the theorists
that we're going to discuss and it
requires going down deep to do that.
And there are presuppositions.
My presupposition,
and this is a psychoanalytic
presupposition,
it's predicated
on a poetic tradition,
I would say on an ancient tradition.
I learned most of it from reading young.
It was Carl Young that
helped me understand that we're nested
inside a dream that we have to be
because we don't know everything.
We have to take things as givens and
that the things that we take it as
givens are nested inside stories and we
accept the stories as valid.
And then outside the stories is the
absolute unknown,
you know?
And that's partly,
the stories are tricky.
You know that one of the classic
stories,
it's a variant of the Jonah story I
would say is
Saint George and the Dragon,
that that story was represented in
during the renaissance and during
medieval times,
thousands and thousands of ways.
It's like the story of Saint Patrick who
chased the snakes out of Ireland.
Same idea.
And that the typical St George story is
the Hobbit or Harry Potter.
So in the second volume of Harry Potter,
correct me if I have any of these
details wrong,
you remember there's that snake,
the Bass lisc.
So this is magic castle,
right?
You guys have no problem with that magic
castle.
No problem.
There's an RF,
he's an orphan.
He goes to the magic castle to learn how
to be more than normal,
right?
The muggles,
he has a muggle family were not too
happy with the muggle family.
Like as representatives of normal
people.
They,
they have some blacks now of course the
reason for that is that,
well that's what teenagers often feel
about their parents,
right?
They failed Jesus.
These couldn't really be my parents.
I must have some other parents who are
like together and those are like magical
parents,
right?
Parents that live in the sky and of
course Harry Potter has earthly parents.
That's the muggles and Dursley I think
is the kid.
He's at what?
He's a wonderful piece of work and uh,
you know,
ill form day spoiled ill formed selfish
very far from the ideal.
He's a foil for Harry and of course he's
appreciated and doted on and Harry is
actually punished for his virtues.
Lots of classic story,
right to,
to be punished for your virtues.
I mean if you look at the story,
the central story in Christianity,
the central story in Christianity is
about someone who is precisely punished
in the worst possible way.
For the highest possible virtues.
And that's what it makes it an
archetypal story because there isn't
anything more unfair than that.
And so it's a limit in a sense.
It can't be worse than that being
punished for being,
you know,
unworthy.
It's like,
yeah,
I will at least make sense.
But to be punished because you have your
act together and you're a good person,
that's real punishment and that's what
happens to Harry.
So luckily he finds out that he's
magical,
which is quite convenient and off he
goes to wizarding school and you know,
that's actually like taking,
that's actually like going and studying
the humanities.
I mean it was when they still were,
you know,
because if it's through the humanities
that you,
that you make contact with the magic of
your culture and that makes you more
than merely the child of your parents
because you are more than merely the
child of your parents.
Here are the child of nature and you're
the child of culture.
And until you understand what that
means,
understand that you have two sets of
parents.
Like the divine hero always has two sets
of parents.
You,
you can't construe yourself properly as
an individual.
You're not situated properly in the
world.
You don't know what your
responsibilities are.
You Count Orient your values property
and you will suffer for that.
Because as far as I can tell,
because life is so difficult,
you have to do something that's truly
worthwhile in order to justify it.
And so well that's what all these
stories tell you.
That's what the story of Jonah is
telling you.
It's like you have an ethical duty to
straighten things up.
And if you don't do it,
you're going to be sorry.
And that story is echoed everywhere
while now Saint George.
Well,
let's go to Harry Potter.
That's what we were talking about.
So he goes off to the magic castle and
he's learning to be a wizard and he's
kind of an interesting character because
he's not really good.
And we find out,
I think that's because it doesn't have a
piece of voldemort in him.
He's not what happens.
Yeah.
And that's what that means is that
to be good,
truly good,
you can't just follow rules.
That's,
that's very clear in the Harry Potter
story.
And you also have to be able to
understand malevolence and in order to
understand malevolence so that you can
withstand it,
you have to understand that part of you
that's malevolent because if you don't,
you're naive and if you're naive,
you're easy pickings.
And so that's a union idea too.
And the union idea is that part of
personality development is to understand
your shadow and the shadow is those
things about you that you do not want to
admit to.
And
you can learn about your shadow by
reading history.
You know,
you can read about Auschwitz,
you can read about the concentration
camps in Russia and you can imagine
yourself as a guard
instead of as a heroic rescue or of
unfortunate victims,
which would be very,
very unlikely.
And once you can imagine yourself as a
guard,
which is a terrifying thing to do,
then you understand something about
yourself.
And I actually think,
and I think this is also from students
studying young,
that you cannot have proper respect for
yourself until you know that you're a
monster because you won't act carefully
enough.
You know,
if you think,
well,
I'm a nice person,
I'd never do anyone any harm.
It's like you're no saint.
You can be sure of that and the harm
that you do.
People can come in many,
many ways.
And so if you regard yourself as
harmless inoffensive.
Nice.
Well,
Marty,
you have any reason to be careful.
You're like a teddy bear sitting on a
shelf.
Even if you throw it at someone,
no one's going to get hurt.
But that isn't what you're like because
you're a human being and human beings
are some vicious creatures and there's
utility in knowing that because it's
also the case.
You know,
when the Harry Potter series,
Harry could stand up against voldemort
and understand them and speak his
language because he was instructed by
him to some degree.
Very,
very interesting idea.
Anyways,
in the second,
yeah,
the reason I'm telling you this,
and this is where thinking about,
it's like how long were each of those
books?
Like 500 pages.
There are long Hais and there was,
how many of them?
Seven and how many were there more sold?
I mean,
how many of you read every Harry Potter
book,
right?
How many of you read at least one?
Okay.
How many of you saw the movies?
It's like you're all in a cult.
You are.
I'm telling you.
Really,
that's the truth.
It's really the truth.
So in the second volume,
there's this snake that's zipping around
there,
the Basilisk,
right?
And it lives in the underground.
That's chaos.
And that's because wherever you are,
you're on thin ice and underneath your
thin ice is chaos.
And here we are in this unbelievably
civilized environment and everyone's
getting along so perfectly,
but you know,
we've got hot,
we've got lights,
we've got electricity,
sewage system is working.
No one's hungry.
It's like we can be peaceful,
but if any of that fell apart and it
could easily fall apart because it's a
bloody miracle it ever works at all,
then the chaos that's just underneath
the surface is going to come up right
now.
And it's useful to know that because it
makes you properly grateful.
If you really understand it,
it makes you properly grateful for the
bloody miracle it is that you can be
here in peace.
So anyways,
there's this snake that's underneath the
surface and it's still,
no,
no joke.
That thing.
It's big and it's ancient.
It's always been there.
And what happens if you look at it,
it turns you to stone,
right?
It paralyzes you.
Well,
that's the,
that's the Gorgon,
that's Medusa.
The woman with the head of snakes.
And if you look at her,
it paralyzes you.
What does that mean?
Well,
you're walking through the jungle and
big snake appears.
What are you,
do you freeze?
And no bloody wonder because you're a
prey animal.
And that's what they do when they see
things that are going to eat them.
And so the snake,
well,
lots of people still die from snake
bite.
And
our ancestors were,
I don't mean our ancestors like you
know,
tens of millions of years ago when they
were living in trees and weren't very
big,
they made a nice snack for a snake.
And there's a woman named Lynn Isabelle,
who's an anthropologist at Ucla who's
correlated the presence of carnivorous
snakes with the acuity of primate
vision.
And what she found was that the more
snakes around the better the primates
could see.
So,
and we're particularly good at picking
up patterns like snake camouflage in the
lower half of our visual quadrant.
You know,
and people generally don't like snakes.
You can learn to handle them,
but no snake fear appears to be a nate
to nate and chimpanzees.
And it tends to increase as you age
rather than decreasing.
You can overcome it,
but,
well,
my daughter had snakes and one day her
sneak bitter.
It was a fairly big snake
and she hadn't paid it.
Paid attention to it for a while.
So it nailed her.
And from then on she has had very
difficult time grabbing the snake.
It was like bitten once,
you know,
shy permanently.
She also told me years later she had
nightmares about snakes all the time
when she had a snake in her room.
It's like,
you know,
and I think it was probably the smell.
So anyways,
so Harry Potter decides he's going to go
after the battle.
It's great.
He's going to go out there and face the
thing that he's most afraid of.
So he does that way down in the depths.
So it's like Jonah going down into the
depths and he faces the bass lisc and it
bites him.
And you know that's uh,
that's right because if you go down into
the depths,
you can get bitten.
Like it's no joke,
and this is a hero story,
but the thing about the hero stories,
it's actually real.
The thing that you're facing is actually
dangerous.
And even though facing it voluntarily be
your best bet and is likely your best
bet,
cause that's the central story of
humanity,
that doesn't mean you're going to
succeed.
It's the real thing.
So anyways,
he gets bitten,
right?
And he's going to die.
Now he's rescuing ginny.
So that's the Saint George Story.
If you go after like dragon dragons,
like to capture virgin,
God only knows why.
I think it's because
I think it's because one of the things
that male humans have done from the
beginning of time is chase the damn
predators away.
And I suspect that the males from God
only knows how long ago who were
particularly good at that we're rewarded
with female attention and why the hell
not so it's deeply rooted inside of us,
that idea of facing the unknown and
freeing the woman.
So the idea there is that if you,
it's a male idea in large part,
I can talk about the central female myth
and I will as we proceed.
The idea is that if you're the sort of
person who can stand up against the
unknown and the frightening,
then you're also likely,
if you develop into that sort of person,
then you're also likely to develop into
the sort of person that other people
will find attractive.
So you know,
and that's why young believed that the
inside the shadow was the anima,
which is like a female figure.
And so his idea was something like,
you know,
if you look watch movies,
there's always this Beta male guy.
If they're romantic movies and he's a
nice guy and he's the friend and you
know,
the woman tells him everything,
but she doesn't like him a bit.
She likes the guy who's like got an
edge.
And,
and who's capable of,
I would say may him,
but at least of aggression.
Now that doesn't mean she wants him to
be aggressive,
but what it does mean is that she wants
him to be able to be aggressive.
That would be good.
And so he's the romantic target.
And so he's the person that's
incorporated the shadow and he's someone
that is respectable and perhaps useful.
And so,
well,
that's a very old story.
So let's,
let's think about this for a minute.
I've already offered you a proposition
and I think it's an important
proposition.
And I,
I'm offering you this proposition so
that you can make sense of art and
literature and mythology and religion
and dance and all those strange,
ritualistic things that human beings do,
which seems central to us,
including including not least,
the eradicable tendency of us to seek
out stories of heroes.
I should finish the,
the Harry Potter story.
So Harry Potter goes down there to
rescue Virginia.
It,
no,
it's,
that's not her name.
What is it Jenny?
Yeah,
but there's a,
there's a formal name for that.
It's a variant of Virginia anyways,
which is very divergent.
So,
um,
and he gets bitten.
Yes.
Genever that's it.
He gets bitten and the bite is poison.
And so there is dying,
which doesn't seem to be so good.
And then what happens,
and again,
you guys swallowed this,
it's no problem.
So what's his name?
The dumbledore character.
He's got a Berg,
right?
So he's the wise old man.
He's the ruler of the castle.
He's the ruler of the magic castle.
He's the magic king.
You know,
he's like God,
the father,
as far as Harry Potter is concerned and
he has a bird.
What kind of bird is it?
It's a phoenix.
Right?
And one of the things that's very
strange about a phoenix is that while
it's a mortal,
but in a strange way,
you know,
it lives and lives,
I think a hundred years and it gets
older and older and then one day,
poof,
it bursts into flames.
And it turns into an egg and then you
get a new phoenix.
So that's a symbol of transformation.
It's a symbol of transformation.
The bird is a spirit or psyche.
And so here's what it means in part,
you know,
you know how when you learn a lesson in
your life that that's not very pleasant,
right?
It's not like when you learn something
important,
it's the best day of your life.
It's often the importance of what you
learn is often proportionate to just how
wretched it is to learn it in.
Oh,
you learn things the hard way.
You learn things by getting hit because
obviously if what you're doing is
working,
you get where you want.
There's no learning in that and that's
happy.
It's when you're doing something and you
hit an obstacle and maybe a bloody well
hit it hard and then you know you recoil
and then you down into the depths you go
and you have to sort yourself out and
you realize that you're,
you know,
this particular kind of idiot and that
you should probably fix that.
And that's really annoying and
difficult.
And,
you know,
and maybe you're down in the dumps and
anxious for quite a while and then you
get it repaired more or less than,
you know,
you put yourself back together.
That's the Phoenix poof into flames,
Bang egg new you.
And so,
you know,
that's the ability to learn.
Now,
human beings are very strange creatures,
right?
Because we're very malleable compared to
most animals.
You know,
like grizzly bears now in Grizzly bears
a thousand years ago,
it's like whatever,
they're the same thing.
They do the same thing.
There's no transformation.
But human beings,
we have this massive brain and you know,
it's a pain because it means you have to
take care of human children until
they're 40
and that's a big burden.
And so,
you know,
we pay a big price for it.
It also makes childbirth very difficult.
And uh,
and it's costly.
You have to eat a lot because you have a
big brain because it uses up a lot of
energy.
And so,
you know,
you,
you pay a price for it,
but the advantage is your plastic.
You can learn.
Now learning is a strange thing because
you can think of it as just acquiring
more information,
but you could also think of it,
and this is more accurate as
finding out something that you're doing
wrong.
So that sort of built into like a
character,
a character element of your character,
a presumption of your perception or a
deep habit.
It's really built into you.
It's a neural structure,
right?
It's,
it's alive and you have to kill it
because this is working properly and the
pain that you go through in part when
you're suffering because you did
something stupid.
Is it something like you're,
you're the neurology,
I can never get this quite right.
It's the pain of the death of that
structure and that can be a huge chunk
of view.
You know,
if you really have to go through a
massive revision,
it's like the person that comes out the
other end might hardly be the same at
all.
You know,
that happens.
For example,
if you're trying to combat alcoholism,
which is just a ratchet thing to do
because well,
all your friends are alcoholic.
All your family drinks too much.
The only thing you know how to do when
you're socializing is to go to the bar
and drink too much.
You know,
and you spend like 20 hours a week on
it.
It's like,
it's not just that you're addicted to
the substance.
It's like that's how you live.
And so if you want to stop being an
alcoholic,
not only do you have to stop drinking
alcohol,
but you have to stop seeing all your
drunk friends.
And then maybe you've had them for your
whole life and you have to have
continual battles with your drunk
family.
And then you have to figure out
something to do with that 20 hours.
It's now like hanging around your neck
like an albatross.
And so you have to lift that whole part
of your personality die and a new part
house to spring forth.
And that's what the Phoenix is.
And the Phoenix is the capacity of the
person to transform.
And so when Harry gets bit by the snake
that freezes him,
he gets seriously injured.
The Phoenix comes in Christ,
some tears in his wound,
it prepares him,
Bang,
he's back to life.
And the strange thing is that that's
okay with all of the viewers now.
Why would that be?
There's nothing about it that's
rational.
Nothing,
right?
Magic castle that's not rational.
Giant snake underneath it.
That's a little more rational.
Turning you to stone going down there to
face it,
being rejuvenated by a phoenix.
It's like,
yeah,
that's okay.
We can,
we'll watch that glue.
We all swallow.
It will be completely engaged in it.
And the reason for that is because it's
a myth.
It's about how people,
yeah,
it's a Meta story about how to act,
about how to conduct yourself in the
world to face the things that you're
afraid of that would otherwise paralyze
you.
To let the death of what is insufficient
about you ochre and then to wait for the
rebirth.
Okay.
So science is about what the world is
and
mythodrama and dream and the
unconscious,
all of that,
let's say the aesthetic and artistic and
fantastic side of humanity.
That's more about how things should be.
It's more about how to act.
They're there lessons in how to act and
they're abstract glasses.
People are capable of abstraction.
Right?
So you say,
well,
there's something good about you and
there's something good about you and,
and there's some bad about you and you
and you.
And so we'll take all the good things
and make one good thing out of that.
We'll take all the bad things and make
one bad thing out of that.
And then we start to understand the
difference between good and bad and we
get better and better and better and
better at that over the centuries as we
distill that.
And then we have a figure of ultimate
good and a figure of ultimate evil.
And that helps us understand what those
two things are.
It was the hostile brothers.
That's a very common,
mythological motif.
And you could say,
well,
they're at war inside you.
And,
and I think that that's a universal
truth.
It's an existential truth.
The domain of ethics and morality is how
are we in the world and what,
how should we be?
What's the good?
And the reason I'm telling you all this,
apart from the fact that you should know
it,
because this is what you should know.
If you go through university is that it
bears directly on issues of health.
You're trying to accomplish something.
Say if you go see a psychotherapist,
you know,
you could say,
well I'm trying to get healthy,
but you know that's not really right.
What you're trying to do when you go see
a therapist is get your life together.
And that's not the same thing.
You know,
like mostly when I'm acting as a
therapist,
it's not like I'm directly treating
mental disorder.
Like mental disorders aren't.
They're just not neat little boxes.
It's not like someone has a fully
functioning life but they have an
anxiety disorder and then you bring them
in,
you treat the anxiety disorder and they
go back to their fully functioning life.
It's like,
it's not like that at all.
The disorders tangled out into their
life.
You know,
if you're well usually your,
your,
your workplace isn't going very well and
your relationships with the people
around you are damaged and you know,
you're connected in the actual world
with all of these things.
And so when you come to see a therapist,
you have to work on putting your life
together in a sustainable manner.
And that's certainly not just removing
the mental illness is very rare now.
And then you see someone who's
depressed,
whose life is together and they're just
depressed.
Something's gone wrong probably
biochemically.
And so with someone like that,
you can often give them an SSRI.
Yes,
I can't give them to them,
but I can recommend them,
recommend they go see a doctor anyways.
And uh,
that's sometimes just does the trick
because you know,
their life is actually pretty good.
They just can't see it.
But that's bloody rare man.
It's usually the case that someone comes
and sees you and things are in a serious
state of chaos and all of that has to be
addressed.
And some of it's psychological and a lot
of it's just practical.
It's embedded out there in the world.
That's what the behavior,
psycho behavioral psychologists are
particularly concerned about.
So anyways,
psychology,
especially the clinical end is
predicated on it necessarily predicated
on the question,
how is it that we obtained the good,
how do we aim at the good and what would
that be when my clients first come to
see me,
one of the things I often ask them is,
okay,
well let's say you look a year ahead.
What do you want?
What are we aiming at?
What would,
what would your life isn't the way you
want it to be?
How would it look if it was the way you
wanted it to be?
Or at least partly that way.
And we aim at that,
right?
And we look for impediments,
psychological impediments,
fears,
avoidance strategies,
that sort of thing.
And we develop strategies and we try to
move towards that.
I would say ideal.
All right,
to understand the categories
of myth will say you have to understand
something about the nature of
categorization.
Now,
categorization is a tricky thing and
we're going to run through some
complicated ideas relatively quickly.
You know,
you think you put things in the same
category because they're similar.
But the problem is is that first of all,
that's not an answer.
It's just a restatement of the initial
proposition.
And second of all,
you can put things in the same category
that are by no means identical and you
often do that.
And third,
it's things are things that are similar
are often also importantly different.
And so picking which element of
similarity,
you know,
like let's say you,
if you have a group of books while are
they the same?
Well obviously no because,
well,
unless they're,
you know,
all the same book,
but the category of books is a pretty
strange category because the content of
the books differs completely well and
you could still make a group of books
and you pick some arbitrary element that
unites them and consider that grounds to
make a category.
There's other categories,
more scientific categories and
scientific categories tend to actually
contain things that are very,
very similar in,
in Mo across multiple dimensions.
Like protons are like that.
As far as I can tell,
there's nothing that distinguishes one
proton from another.
And the same with electronics.
And you know,
the set of triangles is like that
because you can define it precisely,
but most of the categories that human
beings use aren't so neat.
And the problem with that is that unless
the categories are neat,
like scientific categories,
it's very difficult to investigate them
scientifically.
So for example,
you might do research on a group of
people with anxiety disorders,
but the problem with that is that the
anxiety disorder category is so
heterogeneous that it's almost
impossible to identify the commonalities
across all the people who are in that
category.
And that's partly because the category
isn't actually a scientific category,
it's a hybrid category.
It's a practical category.
I can give you an example of that.
Hmm.
Nope,
I can't because I must not have saved it
anyways.
Many of the dsm category,
so these are categories for
psychopathology require.
If you're part of that category,
imagine there's seven symptoms that you
could have,
or eight symptoms that you could have
that would put you in that category.
Like antisocial personality,
eight symptoms.
You steal,
you kick,
you hit,
you bite you,
you know you're abusive.
I don't remember the category categories
precisely,
but you can be in the category if you
have symptoms two through five and you
can be in the category.
If you have symptoms six through eight,
they aren't the same symptoms,
but you're in the same category and you
think,
well,
how the hell can that be?
Well,
that's a family resemblance category,
roughly speaking and lots of the things
that we use,
our family resemblance categories,
there's a prototype and then if you have
enough of the features of that
prototype,
imagine the prototype has 10 features
and if you haven't,
six of those pro features,
you get to be in that category.
But it means that the category is
actually quite diverse and that's one of
the problems that plagues.
Okay.
Psychology,
psychiatry as a science and clinical
psychology is a science.
It's a really big problem because if the
categories aren't homogenous,
then it's very difficult to draw
conclusions about the members of the
category and the psychologists and the
psychiatrists claim that those are
scientific categories,
but,
but they're not.
And they can't be partly because they're
aimed at the classification of health or
ideal versus no unhealth or no an ideal.
And partly because they play multiple
roles.
Say,
I mean the category isn't there just to
provide neat demarcations for scientific
study.
The categories there to give people a
language to talk about certain sets of
symptoms to diagnose.
Because you know when you come in and
you have a set of symptoms,
you might want to know what,
what they are so that you also know what
they aren't.
It's really a relief often to find a
diagnosis.
And then of course the diagnosis has
certain implications for treatment and
for billing and for all of that.
So the category has to play all of those
rules.
So there's multiple types of category.
Um,
and the categories that we're talking
about in relationship to mythology
aren't scientific categories.
Their categories about the world
construed as a place to act.
So here's the way to think about it.
You're always looking at the world
through a framework of reference.
And you have to do that because there
isn't very much of you.
You can't see the whole world at once.
And in fact the amount of the world you
actually see is so small,
you can't believe it.
The central part of your vision is
zipping around,
producing a pretty high resolution
representation of exactly what you're
looking at.
But outside of that center,
like if I look at you,
I can't see her eyes.
I can see her glasses,
but barely,
I can't even tell whether you're male or
female.
The person passed that.
I can't see it all.
Now you don't notice that.
You know,
you don't notice that you're that blind
because your,
your central vision is always popping
around illuminating that tiny space.
But you're Sudan blind.
It's just mind boggling.
And I'm sure some of you have seen the
invisible gorilla video,
you know,
wear a gorilla,
comes into the video and you don't
notice,
which is somewhat shocking because you
would think that you had noticed a
gorilla.
But what happens is that you actually
don't notice something unless it
interferes with what you're doing.
And because what are you going to do?
Notice everything.
You can't do that.
You can hardly notice anything.
So what you do is you pick something to
focus on.
It's usually something that you value
because why else would you focus on it?
So that means that your value system
determines the direction of your
perception.
Bloody well,
think about that for a minute.
That's a Buddhist idea,
right?
People,
people live in a kind of illusion and
sometimes that illusion causes suffering
and they can transform the way they look
at the world and that can release them
from their suffering.
But the idea that you do live in an
illusion,
well,
I don't know if it's exactly an
illusion,
but you certainly do live within a
framework of perception that's
determined by your values.
Now that is so weird,
you know,
because we never think of the world is
something that reveals itself through
our values,
but of course it of course it does
because you look at what you want,
you aim at what you want,
and once you've aimed the world lays
itself out for you and that,
and that's exactly how perception works.
That's why represented at this way.
You're always somewhere that's point a
and that somewhere in some place in some
time and you're always have some notion
about what you want to have have
happened next.
You know you're going to go to the next
class.
Maybe you've got a plan after this.
In this class you have a plan.
You're hoping to learn something,
I presume,
and maybe you have a goal with regards
to a grade and that's nested inside your
desire to get a degree and that's nested
inside your desire to be educated and to
have a career and,
and,
and have a successful life.
So attending to me at the moment,
the reason you're doing that is because
all of those values exist within you
simultaneously focusing your attention.
And so you're attending to me and not to
something else,
assuming that all of you with your
Computers Open Aren't surfing the web,
which you might be,
but assuming that you're focusing w
whatever you're focusing on is directed
by what you value.
And some of that can be unconscious.
In fact,
a lot of it is unconscious because you
know it's very difficult for you to get
control of what you pay attention to.
You know what that's like.
You're trying to study.
It's kind of a boring paper.
Christ your attention.
It's just like everywhere.
You know?
Maybe you'll vacuum under the band
instead of doing the paper,
reading the paper,
you know,
you can't get grip on that thing.
So your attention has an autonomy and
that's another psychoanalytic idea,
you know,
because you kind of think,
well,
you're in control.
It's like really ever try telling
yourself what to do.
Does the,
how does that work for you?
I'm going to go to the gym three times a
week,
right?
Sure you are.
I'm going to quit eating sugar for a
month.
It's like how long does that last?
It's like 50 minutes.
And you're eating like three chocolate
bars.
So you're,
this is,
and this is Freud central insight.
I would say you're an autonomous group
of spiritual agents,
let's say personalities and they don't
really get along very well.
And you,
the ego will say is by no means
necessarily in charge.
And that's a very strange thing to
realize,
but you can really realize that by
noticing how little control you have
over your attentional focus.
Okay,
so you've got your point a,
you're going to point b,
you're always doing that.
You inhabit a structure of value and it
changes what the point is and what the
point B is.
But the structure itself doesn't change.
And when you're looking at the world,
what you see is not objects.
You see tools and they make you happy.
Those are the things that facilitate
your movement forward and you see
obstacles and those are things that make
you unhappy.
When you encounter an obstacle,
one of the problems is as well,
you don't get to where you're going and
that's a problem.
But the other problem is if you
encounter an obstacle,
the frame might be wrong,
right?
Because you never know.
It might be just something that you
could detour around real easily,
might be a fatal flaw in your whole
plan.
And so obstacles have this dual nature,
they get in your way,
but they can also take your plan down
and so they can produce anxiety.
So my point is this,
there's a book called a visual,
an ecological approach to visual
perceptions.
Great book,
um,
by Gibson,
Jj Gibson,
if I remember correctly,
and this is,
although I thought of this a while back,
I realized eventually that it was a
variant of his theory.
And what he believed was that when
people looked at the world,
they saw a value first and inferred
objects second.
So for example,
for Gibson,
if you're standing by a cliff,
you don't see a cliff.
And then think about the fact that you
might fall and then feel frightened.
You see a falling off place.
And part of the seeing of that part of
the act of seeing is being afraid of
that because your eyes are connected
right to your emotional systems.
And part of what your eyes do is tell
you what the object is,
but your eyes do all sorts of other
things.
Like they prepare you for action,
they prepare you for gripping,
they prepare you for emotion.
And,
and none of that actually requires the,
the existence necessarily the existence
of your perception of the object.
So there aren't people who have blind
sight and if you show them,
so they think they can't see.
But if you flash them an angry face,
they'll show a skin conductance
response.
And that's because the visual pathways
to the Amygdala,
which does face Emoji,
facial emotional processing,
can still be active.
These are people who have usually had a
stroke,
so their eyes are okay,
but they've destroyed the visual cortex.
So,
so anyways,
it's perfectly plausible that at least
at one level of analysis,
when you look at something you see it's
utility first.
So you see a chair and you might say a
chair is an object,
but I wouldn't say that beanbags,
a chair and a stump is a chair and they
don't share much in common except that
you can sit on them.
And so you know the chairs,
the chairs basically conceptualized by
its functional utility.
And when you look at a chair,
what you perceive it's is it's
functional utility and the chair tells
you what to do.
It says,
sit on me.
And so that,
and there are people who have prefrontal
damage and they engage in something
called utilization behavior.
And if they're walking down a hallway
and there's this door open,
they have to walk through it.
They can't not do what the object tells
them to do.
That's called utilization behavior.
So that's how the world is laid out.
And I would say inside that domain,
you're in the predictable world.
You're in the world that you understand
that,
that you know and that if you hit an
obstacle or if you're outside,
that you're in the unknown.
You're in unknown territory.
In the mythological world and the world
for action,
you could conceptualize the world as a
stage for action.
And this is a shakespearian quote that
that sort of sums it up quite nicely.
All the world is a stage and all the men
and women,
merely players,
they have their exits and their
entrances and one man in his time plays
many parts.
And you might say,
well is that really true?
And the answer to that is,
well,
it depends on what you mean by true and,
and,
and that really is the answer because
there are different ways of defining
true.
So,
and it isn't self evident that there's
only one way of defining true that's
appropriate.
You know,
the definition of truth might be more
like a tool.
And you know,
we,
our tool using creatures and really what
we're trying to do with our conceptions
of truth is to work through the world
successfully.
So even science is subordinate should be
subordinate to our use of the world as a
tool.
Because if it isn't useful tool,
like what are we doing with it?
You know,
just generating technology that might
destroy the world,
that seems like a bad idea.
So,
so I think that,
that the world as tool is actually the
fundamental sort of truth.
And I think that that's a Darwinian
idea,
right?
That our notions about the world have
evolved through a Darwinian process and
that it's appropriate for us to regard
as what is most real.
Those things that reliably ensure are
the continuation of our life and the
probability of our propagation.
And if you're a true Darwinian,
I don't think there's a way out of that
argument.
And it isn't self evident by any stretch
of the imagination that seeing the world
as our as objects is the way that our
brain works.
In fact,
I don't think it's the way it works at
all.
And I think that that's why we're so
wired for stories,
right?
It's a mystery.
You know,
like you won't line up for two hours to
go see a lecturer,
but you'll line up for two hours,
maybe you'll even camp overnight if
you're mythological imagination has been
seized for God only knows what reason by
star wars.
And you know that's a source of
mythology.
It's the mythology of the modern person
and it fills a gap.
And that's why people do it.
So that to me speaks of Ma,
the manner in which our psyches are
constructed.
And that's a union idea.
That's the idea of the archetype,
essentially,
that to be human is to participate in a
certain pattern of being.
And that that pattern of being is acted
out socially.
It talked about individually,
but it's also part of your structure.
Even your perceptual structure as a,
as a living organism of your particular
type.
And it would be the case at least in
part that the hero myth,
which is go out where no one has gone
before,
face the terrors of the unknown,
gather something of value and return is
the central story of humankind.
It's not the only central story,
but it's,
it's up there in the top three and many
of the dramas that you engage yourself
in are variations of that story and you
watch it over and over and over because
you're trying to learn how to do that
because that's what you need to do live.
Okay,
here's the,
here's an idea.
What's common among people?
Well,
we're self conscious so we know of our
own existence and we knew of our own
limitations and so that means that we
have a certain innate terror and
fragility.
Our,
our,
our existence is a problem to us.
And in some sense what we're trying to
do when we search for meaning is to
search for a solution to that problem.
And that can be security,
but it can also be motive being,
you know,
and so for example,
being engaged in something worthwhile
seems to be a good medicine for being
fragile,
you know,
because you think,
well I'm doing this,
it seems worthwhile.
And the fact that there's a price to be
paid for it and that things could be
following me that aren't good,
I'm willing to put up with that because
what I'm engaged in seems to be of
appropriate of sufficient significance
to justify all that.
We all become self conscious and we're
all trying to do something about that,
figure out how to deal with it.
So there's a landscape that we inhabit,
I would say within which that takes
place.
So there's a human being,
self conscious,
d doom to tragedy and doomed to be aware
of that.
The human being has two elements and
that's the element that seeks the good.
And there's the other element that
seeks,
I would say
revenge and destruction.
And we have our reasons.
You know,
if something tragic happens to you and
it's tragic and unfair and it really
brings you low,
the probability that you're going to
become resentful and want revenge is
extraordinarily high and no wonder,
and you know,
the architectural representation of that
is evil itself.
And the architectural representation of
the good that you could do is,
is the hero.
And so those things inhabit us.
They're permanent elements of the
psyche.
And then what else is universal to us?
Well,
we live in a society you could say,
and that's deep.
That's deep.
It's not just human society.
Like we've lived in a society forever.
So you know,
lobsters live and dominance hierarchies
and they use their serotonin system at
least in part to keep track of their
dominant position.
And so you can use antidepressants on
lobsters when they get defeated and they
don't feel so bad from being defeated in
a fight.
And so you just think about that because
the anti depressants do the same thing
to us.
We're so bloody social that the circuits
that evolved 300 million years ago when
the lobsters in us had a shared ancestor
are still operating at the base of your
brain.
That's why status is so important to
people and reputation.
I mean that serotonin system governs
your emotional regulation,
how people respond to you and what they
think of you.
Man that matters.
That's why you're on facebook all the
time and checking your texts and,
and obsessing continually about your
online presence as soon assuming that
you're doing that and you know,
contacting people frantically and seeing
what the updates are.
It's like where,
where,
how are you held in the esteem of
others?
Very,
very important.
And that's because it determines your
emotional regulation.
It's really important.
So we exist in a society always,
and the society has two elements.
The tyrannical element of the society
that would be the tyrannical king,
roughly speaking,
a very common mythological theme.
You see that in the lion king too,
right?
Cause that scar.
Um,
and of course you see it in the real
world with almost continually.
And then the benevolent king who is the
source of all the good things about
culture,
you know,
and,
and you can see these things play out as
mythologies in,
in political terms.
So I would say for example,
the continual harping about the
oppressive nature of the Patriarchy is
part of a myth.
And the myth is that society is
oppressive.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
obviously,
you know,
because you have to be quite a bit like
you and you have to be quite a bit like
you even if you're not so that you can
get along.
Right?
Everybody sacrifices a tremendous amount
of their individuality to the common,
to the common motive being that's,
there's a tyrannical element to that.
But you know,
by the same token,
it's the basis of cooperation and I'm
the stability of society.
And the,
the final element is how it's often
represented,
matt,
in a masculine manner,
by the way,
society.
And I think that's because our primary
dorman structures,
given the creatures we are like
chimpanzees,
the primary structures of dominance are
masculine.
And then outside of what's known is the
unknown.
And we always have to contend with that.
And it's wonderful in that it's the
source of all new things and it's
terrible in that it's the place where
all the things that destabilize you come
from.
And so this is a good representation or
no,
not the only one.
So that's the feminine
nature.
That's the masculine order and that's
the individual who's destined to suffer
in the grasp of those two things.
MMM.
I'll finish this next time.
What have we got here?
Yep.
All right,
good enough.
We'll see you next time.
So today to begin with,
we're going to finish
the last lecture and then with any luck,
we're going to start the next one.
They're thematically linked anyways.
Well you know what?
All the lectures for the next,
well for the whole course,
hopefully we'll be thematically late to
some degree.
Uh,
given that normally they're about the
same topic,
but some are more tightly linked than
others.
So
I started telling you
last week about this idea of the voyage
to the underworld.
And I wanted to tell you a little bit
more about that.
You in particular conceptualize the
voyage to the underworld as a journey
into the unconscious.
And the unconscious for the
psychoanalyst is a place of fantasy and
dream and implicit presupposition and
habit.
And that's all correct.
You know,
we,
there is an unconscious and
it's perfectly reasonable to
conceptualize it that way,
that the big difference I think between
the psychoanalysts and the later more
empirical scientists is that the
psychoanalysts sort of envisioned your
psyche as a place of living partial
personalities instead of cognitive
computational systems.
You know,
that they took into account the fact
that you're alive and that the parts of
you are alive.
And you know,
there's,
there's a neuroscientist named Zack
[inaudible],
nick,
I don't know how to say his name.
Gaza Nigga.
That's wrong.
Is that cause I had to go,
yeah,
I think that's it.
Anyways,
he did some of the earliest experiments
on split brains.
And so sometimes if you have intractable
epilepsy,
which I wouldn't recommend by the way.
Um,
one of the surgical procedures for
mediating its negative effects is
something called a,
you cut the corpus callosum and it's
very large,
very large structure in the brain that
connects the two separate hemispheres.
And you know,
it's not obvious why we have two
separate hemispheres,
although I'll tell you a little bit
about why I think it is.
But anyways,
they do communicate and Uhh,
what Kazana Gha
demonstrated was that you could tell one
hemisphere something without the other
one knowing
that both hemispheres we're conscious
and that the consciousness was somewhat
independent.
It really strange.
It's very interest.
Makes very interesting readings,
reading,
you know,
because it suggests that fragments of
ourselves,
you can think of,
you have fragments of yourself within
you that are like low resolution
representations of you,
you know,
and the,
and the psychoanalysts would think of
those more as they're kind of like,
they're kind of like one I giants.
That might be a way of thinking about it
if you were thinking about it in a
fantastical way.
So there's the angry you and you know
you've all come in contact with the
angry you.
It's a rather rigid.
That's the first thing you might say
about it.
It's impulsive and short term.
It doesn't think much about the past
unless it's bad things about whoever
you're angry at,
in which case it thinks about them a
lot.
It's not too concerned with longterm
future consequences and mostly at wants
to be right.
And you know when angry you disappears
and normal you assuming such a thing
exists,
reappears,
you can be perfectly shocked about how
angry you behaved.
And in fact sometimes if angry you
really gets out of hand like it might in
a battle and a war,
it might do things that you just can't
imagine you would do.
And under those circumstances you can
reveal parts of yourself to yourself
that are so foreign and so horrifying
that it will leave you with post
traumatic stress disorder because it is
the case that
many,
but not all people who suffer from post
traumatic stress disorder,
especially if it's battlefield related,
get it because of something they did
rather than something they saw or
something that happened to them.
And that's really worth thinking about.
You know,
I mean there's a lot of weird potential
nested inside people and you know,
you don't see it under normal
circumstances because the circumstances
are normal.
And part of the reason that we liked the
circumstances to be normal is precisely
so that we don't see those parts of
people we don't want to see.
And that's really worth knowing.
It's really worth knowing because
that's why people are so identified with
their culture and why they need a
culture.
You know,
like the terror management theorists
types,
they kind of think of culture as a
mechanism that inhibits anxiety and they
think about it psychologically.
Like it's,
it's something inside your,
your head,
let's say.
Um,
and it gives meaning to events and stops
you from collapsing into chaos and
protects you from death anxiety.
But
that isn't,
that's not right.
It's sort of right.
But that isn't what your culture is.
Your culture is a set of value Laden
presuppositions that you orient yourself
in the world that match the set of Value
Laden presuppositions that everyone in
your culture has and acts out.
And so what that means is that when you
believe something and you're among your
own people,
you believe something implicitly.
It's the way you look at the world.
It's the way you act things out.
You Act about,
everyone expects you to act the belt.
They're happy about it,
in fact.
So there's a match between what you're
doing,
what you see and what you're doing and
what other people expect.
And it's that match that regulates your
emotions.
It's not the belief system,
it's the match.
And so part of the reason that people
are so tied to their cultural identity
is because their cultural identity
regulates their emotions.
And in a profound way,
like this is no joke.
You know?
I mean,
one of the things that stabilizes human
nervous systems is imagine that you have
a domain of competence.
There's many domains of competence.
Of course in some of those domains
you're completely incompetent,
but they met me not matter because you
don't go into that domain.
So you have some area of specialization
which you might think of as your
subtribe,
you know,
your university students.
And so some of you are lower status by
the rules of the university game and
some of you are higher status by the
rules of the university game by the
tribe.
And so the higher status people tend to
be the ones who,
um,
fit into the academic environment,
you know,
and,
and find it conducive to their mode of
being and all who also do well and their
serotonin levels rise.
And you know,
the neurochemicals that moderate mood
particularly are serotonergic.
It's Serotonin,
it's lots of other things.
It's an over simplification.
But that'll do for now.
As you become dominant in a hierarchy,
your serotonin levels rise.
And what that means is that happy things
make you happier and sad things make you
less sad.
It tunes your nervous system.
So if you're down at the bottom of the
hierarchy and you're failing,
it's like,
hey,
hardly anything makes you happy and
everything makes you nervous and it's no
wonder because it's just not very good
down there.
So the,
the,
the societal structure which,
which is an elaborated dominance
hierarchy,
regulates your emotions because of the
match between your expectations and
behaviors of the people within that
structure.
And then your position within the
hierarchy regulates the rate ratio.
Let's say I'm the intensity between
positive and negative emotion.
So you mass with people's status at your
peril and you disrupt their culture.
They don't like that and no wonder
because when it's disrupted,
they fall into chaos and chaos isn't
just anxiety.
My anxiety is bad enough,
but it's not just anxiety because when
you fall into chaos,
when things fall apart for you,
of course you're uncertain and anxious
because you don't know what the hell is
going on and you don't know where you
are and you don't know what to do.
That's anxiety provoking and maybe you
can't even understand your past properly
anymore.
That,
as I said,
that happens when people get betrayed,
and so you fall into this state where
nothing is certain.
The way you construe the world isn't
certain,
and even the way the world is is no
longer certain because you don't know
how to act or your actions aren't
working.
And so the world is presenting itself as
something that's chaotic.
It's not just psychological.
The chaos is a weird intermingling of
the chaotic world and the chaotic self.
I mean,
that's what happens when you get
unemployed.
It's like it's devastating.
It's devastating to people.
And if you could say,
well,
that's psychological.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
but they're unemployed.
That makes the world far more
incomprehensible and uncertain.
It's not just psychological,
it's psychological and that's bad,
but it's also real and that's even
worse.
And then those two things can spiral,
which they often do because you know,
if you don't set your expectations
properly for a job search and assume
that you're going to get 49 rejections
for every interview,
which you really need to know because if
you get 49 rejections,
it's not because you're useless.
It's because of the baseline for
rejection is 98% and that's okay because
the base rate for rejection for
everything is 98% no matter what you do.
But you need to know that so that you
don't feel that it's like something
wrong with you.
And of course you only have to get it
right once that,
and you have a job that's a lottery,
but you have to set yourself up.
You have to think,
okay,
well I'm going to look for a job,
I need to s how many resumes can I
tolerate sending out a day?
You know,
it has to be enough so you don't feel
like a useless moron and it can't be so
many that you're overwhelmed by the
burden.
So,
and I help people do this sort of thing
all the time.
So maybe you decide,
well you're going to send out 10 a day
and you're going to work two hours on it
and it's going to take six months.
And then you know you've got your
parameters set properly and you would
know what to expect in the world and
your emotions are regulated.
And so,
but the state of being unemployed,
it doesn't just produce psychological
consequences.
So the,
the distinction between the psyche in
the world in some sense is quite
arbitrary.
And the psychoanalyst,
I think it err too much on the side of
the subject.
They tend to think that too much of you
is inside of you and too little of you
is outside of you.
And part of the reason I believe that is
because of my clinical experience.
I love the psychoanalyst Matt.
They're brilliant,
they're brilliant,
they're deep.
They grapple with real problems.
Like with the problems.
When people have real problems and I
mean profound problems,
they're really profound moral problems.
They're problems of good and evil
really.
You know,
there are things going on in their
family that are so terrible that well
that there are,
there are some times fatal,
you know,
lie upon,
lie upon lie for decades and decades and
decades.
It's awful.
And that's not exactly inside them.
Okay.
It's out there in the world and lots of
the people that I see,
very famous critic of psychology,
I can't remember his name,
but I probably will
criticize the practice of psychology
quite effectively in the believe in the
early sixties the myth of mental illness
by Thomas Sas as zed,
a s zed.
It's classic.
You should read it if you're interested
in psychology,
read it like it's,
it's a classic.
And he basically said most people have
problems in living.
They don't have psychological problems.
And so I've experienced,
despite my love for the psychoanalysts,
very frequently what I'm doing as a
therapist is helping people have a life
that would work.
You know,
and you can parameterize that.
It's like,
what do you need?
How about some friends that can feel
kind of like that?
How about an intimate relationship with
someone that you can trust that maybe
has a future?
That'd be good.
How about a career that puts you in a
dominance hierarchy somewhere?
So at least you've got some possibility
of rising,
some possibility of stabilizing yourself
and our schedule and a routine because
no one can live without a routine.
You just forget that if you guys don't
have a routine,
I would recommend like you get one going
because you cannot be mentally healthy
without a routine.
You need to pick a time to get up
whatever time you want,
but pick one and stick to it because
otherwise you disregulate your circadian
rhythms and they regulate your mood and
eat something.
In the morning.
I had lots of clients who've had anxiety
disorders.
I had one client who was literally
starving,
very smart girl,
cheat.
There was very little that she liked.
She kind of tried to subsist on like
half a cup of rice a day.
She came to me and said,
I have no energy.
I come home.
All I want to do is watch the same movie
over and over.
What?
Like is that weird?
And I thought,
well,
it depends on how hard you work.
You know,
it's a little weird,
but whatever.
It's familiar,
you're looking for comfort.
So I did an analysis of her diet.
It's like three quarters of a cup of
rice.
It's like you're starving.
Eat something,
you know,
you'll feel better.
So she modified her diet and you're all,
our anxiety went away and she had some
energy.
It's like,
yeah,
you go out to eat.
So a schedule,
that's a good thing man.
Your brain will thank you for it.
It will stabilize your nervous system
when it's a bit of a plan.
That's a good thing.
You need a career.
You need something productive to do with
your time.
You need to regulate your use of drugs
and alcohol.
Most particularly alcohol.
Cause that does even a lot of people.
Um,
he knew your family,
like the family,
you have your parents and all that.
It'd be nice if you all got along,
you could work on that.
That's a good thing to work on.
And then you know,
you probably need children at some point
and that's life.
That's what life is.
And if you're missing,
you know,
you may have a good reason to not be
operating on one of those dimensions.
It's not mandatory.
But I can tell you that if you're not
operating reasonably well on four,
I think I mentioned six,
if you're not operating reasonably well
on at least three of them,
there's no way you're going to be
psychologically thriving.
And that's more pragmatic in some sense
than psychological,
right?
Human beings have a nature.
There's things we need.
And if we have them,
well that's good.
And if we don't have them,
well then we feel the lack.
So behaviorists,
behavioral psychologists concentrate a
lot more on that sort of thing.
You know,
it's practical.
It's like strategizing,
make a career plan,
figure out how to negotiate,
cause that's bloody important.
Figuring out how to say what you need,
figure out how to tell the truth to
people,
figure out how to listen to your partner
in particular.
Because if you listen to them,
they will actually tell you what they
want.
And sometimes you can give it to them
and maybe they'll return the favor.
And if you practice that for like 15
years,
well then maybe you're constantly giving
each other what you want.
Well Hooray.
That would be good.
And then there's two of you under most
circumstances and it's better to have
two brains than one because people think
differently because of their temperament
mostly.
And so the negotiation is where the
wisdom arises and it's part of the
transformation,
the psychological transformation that's
attendant on an intimate relationship
and one of the fundamental purposes of a
longterm intimate relationship.
Anyways,
when that falls apart,
chaos ensues.
And that's why chaos is represented.
So continually and myths and stories.
And I'm going to walk you through a bit
of that more today.
Um,
I talked about the story of Jonah.
Now here's something to think about.
The internal representations of language
meaning evolve partly from our pre
linguistic ancestor's knowledge of
social relations like modern monkeys and
apes.
Our ancestors lived in groups with
intricate networks of relationships that
were similar caneously competitive and
cooperative.
The demands of social life created
selective pressures for just the kind of
complex,
abstract,
conceptual and computational abilities
that are likely to have proceeded.
The earliest forms of linguistic
communication.
Although baboons have concepts and
acquire propositional information from
other animals,
vocalizations,
they cannot articulate this information.
They understand dominance,
relationships.
And matrilineal kinship,
but they have no words for them.
This suggests that the internal
representation of many concept relations
and actual action sequences does not
require language.
And that language did not evolve because
it was uniquely suited to representing
thought.
Well you,
you know,
you can think without language.
Well,
take the case of someone who's deaf and
mute,
they have no language,
well,
they can operate in society,
they learn how to represent other people
and they do that with image.
Now the postmodernists who I
despise would be a reasonable way of
putting it,
have this proposition that there's no
meaning outside language.
And it's a powerful argument by the way,
but it's,
it's seriously wrong.
MMM.
There is a meaning network outside of
language and it's what language is
grounded in.
And that's this pre verbal comprehension
of the world.
It's an embodied comprehension of the
world.
Animals have it,
lobsters have it.
You know,
this particular scientist,
seyfarth
talks about our shared history with,
you know,
higher primates.
That probably goes back 20 million
years,
something like that.
We split from the common ancestor with
chimps about 7 million years ago.
Um,
but you know,
lobsters have dominance hierarchies,
they hardly have a nervous system at
all,
which is partly why they're studied
quite extensively.
And so they have a social structure and
they understand it.
Like if one lobster Theora lobster to be
quite a shock to you,
if it happened and you were fighting
with another lobster and you lost,
you would remember that.
And the next time you saw that lobster,
you'd scuttle off somewhere else and
you'd know that.
And all the lobsters in an area,
no who's top lobster and who isn't.
And Pop lobster gets the best bloody
place to be and the best food.
So this dominance issue,
this cultural issue,
you know,
the fact that we live in a social
environment is far deeper than people
usually consider.
And it's also worth considering and that
this is what you might think of from an
evolutionary perspective.
You know,
you think of natural selection as
producing evolution,
right?
Well,
random mutation with natural selection.
But here's something to think about.
And Darwin knew this,
but Darwin was really smart and the
biologists who followed in his
footsteps,
even up to now,
I've only expanded out a fraction of
what he had to say.
You know,
he was very interested in sexual
selection.
Now one of the things about human beings
that's unique is that human females are
picky maters.
They're choosy.
Uh,
they're also sneaky because you can't
tell when they're ovulating and without
many other female animals,
you know,
so
they have hidden ovulation and they're
choosy and they tend to choose men who
are more successful in the dominance
hierarchy.
Well,
there,
there is a shock.
I mean,
if you have a choice,
why not?
If you pick someone who's at the bottom
of the competence hierarchy,
all that's probably not going to work
out very well for you.
And since women bear the burden of
reproduction,
okay,
it's perfectly reasonable for them to
search out someone who's going to be
helpful.
So productive,
fair,
generous.
And you know,
when you think of a dominance hierarchy,
you might think,
well,
it's the powerful guy,
the aggressive guy say that rises to the
top of the dominance hierarchy.
And that's not true.
It's not even true among chimps.
Like you can get a chimp tyrant.
But then what happens is other chimps
gang up on him and tear him to pieces
and they don't do it nicely.
They don't do it nicely.
And the chimps that tend to maintain
their dominance for long periods of time
have a pretty wide network of friends,
roughly speaking with whom they engage
in reciprocal interactions like
grooming.
And they actually pay a lot of positive
attention to the female chimps who have
their own hierarchy,
by the way,
and to the their offspring.
So they're like baby kissing
politicians.
And so the idea that it's raw power that
produces dominance is a,
it's just wrong.
It's,
it's wrong.
Now,
you know,
tyrants,
it's pretty damn up unstable business
being a tyrant.
There's lots of people who want to kill
you.
Plus,
you know,
you tend to rule over something
approximating hell.
So maybe that's the worst.
Better than being a subject in hell.
But it's not much better.
So anyways,
so this social social now,
so what this means,
think about this for a minute.
So imagine,
you know,
imagine what I'm telling you.
Bear some vague resemblance to the
truth.
I think there's quite a lot of evidence
for it from a,
from a biological perspective.
Um,
I mean this choosy mating thing occurs
with lots of species.
You know,
there's this bird called the bower bird.
You've got to look up bowerbirds man,
those things are,
you just can't even believe they exist.
And so the male bowerbird,
he makes this really complicated nest
that's close to the ground.
He weaves it.
It's really quite nice.
You couldn't make one.
So,
and then he sweeps the US the yard in
front of the nest and then he runs
around the forest or flies because he
has a bird finding pretty things.
So maybe he'll find a nice collection of
red leaves.
And so then he'll take the red leaves
one by one and fly back to his front
yard and make a little square.
You know,
he's a bird,
so it's not a great square,
but it makes a little patch of red.
And he takes a look at that and then he
goes off and find something blue.
And,
and he decorates,
it makes a little piece of abstract art
and the front of his nest and a lot of
male bowerbirds do this all at the same
time.
And so then the females come along,
they hop on something nearby and they
kind of look at it like this,
checking it out.
And if they're happy with it,
well then things proceed.
But if they're not,
they'd fly off to someone else's piece
of abstract art.
And if a of mail piece of art is
rejected by like three females in a row,
he gets irritated,
brushes it all off with his wing,
and then he makes another one.
It's like God,
well,
they obviously have a sentence of very
well developed sense of beauty.
It's so cool.
You know?
And I guess the idea is that who knows
what the hell,
the idea is the female birds,
like artistic males,
something like that.
But if you're thinking about it
biologically,
maybe it's an indication of
intelligence,
right?
It's a marker of intelligence,
you know?
And it's certainly the case that female
humans prefer creative meant so.
And the wonder,
of course we wouldn't be creative if
that wasn't the case.
So then imagine that there's two primary
forces of evolutionary selection
operating on us and they're not really
the natural world,
which is what people always think,
like the environment,
you know that the animals and the trees
and nature,
but it isn't nature that selected us.
It's two other things.
Well,
partly it's to other things.
So one is the dominance hierarchy,
the male dominance hierarchy is one is
the primary mechanisms of selection.
So it's like,
well women are faced with a hard choice,
which guy to go after,
right?
That's a hard choice.
Well,
so they do the same thing that people do
with the stock market.
They outsource the cognitive problem,
the computational problem to the male
dominance hierarchy.
Then they just let the mail cirque
themselves out however they're going to,
and then they peel from the top.
And so what that means is the dominant
male dominance hierarchy itself is a
selection mechanism because if you fail
at it,
then you don't leave any offspring.
And so what that means is,
at least in part,
is that we have adapted to be and better
at attaining status in dominance.
Hierarchies over God only knows how long
a period of time.
And that doesn't mean just power,
you know,
it might mean cognitive flexibility
because you could imagine dorman is
hierarchy a dominance hierarchy,
b dominance hierarchy.
See,
okay,
so if like if you're really successful,
you climb up dominance hierarchy a
right?
But you'd be in,
see now if you have land in though is
you just be a failure.
So then you could say the ideal human
being is someone who can climb to the
top of a dominance hierarchy no matter
what the dominance hierarchy is.
Right?
So we've evolved too.
We've evolved such that success across
the set of possible dominance
hierarchies is the target.
And I think that's why we have general
intelligence because general
intelligence is a general problem
solving mechanism and it's a single
factor.
Even like there is intelligence is a
single factor.
It's not divisible despite what people
like
Robert Sternberg and Howard Gardner
falsely claim.
So,
and then from the female perspective,
females are the next gatekeeper.
And that's why they're often mother
nature.
It took me a long time to figure this
out.
Why the hell is a nature feminine in
mythological representations?
He's a very,
very,
it's extraordinarily common mother
nature.
You don't think of father nature,
you think of Mother Nature.
It's like why?
Well,
nature brings forth new forms.
So that's feminine
and nature selects in fact,
that's the definition of nature from a
Darwinian perspective.
Nature is that which selects women
select their nature.
And that's partly why far more men than
you might think like far more are
terrified of women.
Because to be rejected as a romantic
partner by a woman is to be classified
as vaguely acceptable.
Lifeform Huh?
No value in propagating it though.
Right?
So it's a major,
major rejection.
And you know,
I've had dozens of clients and many,
many people write to me whose primary
problem is that they're so terrified of
women,
they can't even approach them.
Very,
very,
very common.
So,
all right,
I want to show you this little triangle
thing.
This is kind of cool.
okay.
So no,
no nonverbal.
Right.
Nonverbal.
So what happened?
Well,
there's mother triangle I would guess
and mother triangle has circle as a
child and triangle
is maybe a friend but not one that's
very welcome according to mother and uh,
child circle goes out to try to play
with triangle child and mother doesn't
like that.
So she goes out there and pecks the hell
out of it.
Out of him,
chase him away,
pushes child circle back into the home
and goes into the home.
And then child circle isn't very happy
about that.
It's running around causing trouble and
he manages to escape and then bad child
triangle shows up and they played
together and run around and run around
and run around and run around with
mother chasing them.
And then they will,
maybe they elope,
who knows?
And then mother triangle has a fit and
blows down the house.
Right.
So obvious,
reasonable.
Would you consider that a reasonable
story about what happened?
Perhaps you had other interpretations,
but I suspect they were vaguely along
that line.
Well,
but the point here,
and this is the point of this
experiment,
is how much information do you need from
which to derive a narrative?
And the answer is like none.
It just,
it's just immediate.
You can watch some triangles moving
around a box and instantly you
personalize it.
And that's because that's what you're
like.
And the reason you're like that is
because you're environment isn't nature.
Your environment is culture,
your environment is other people,
other people.
And that was even more true for
chimpanzees and so forth.
And especially animals had a limited
diet like,
like gorillas,
they pretty much only eat like leaves.
You know what?
Chimps spends like 12 hours a day
chewing.
And that's why they have a gut like
this.
It's like you can't eat leaves,
you know,
have you tried?
They have no nutrition.
So if you're going to eat leaves,
you have to eat a lot of them and then
it takes like three months to digest
them.
And so what we've done,
and this is pretty cool cause it's we're
so smart,
is that we've traded gut for brain.
And that's why we're so spelled.
And the way we managed that it appears
is that we learned how to use fire to
cook things.
And that meant that we had high quality
nutrition,
much higher.
It's easier to digest,
cooked things,
especially meat.
And so because we invented fire,
we didn't have to have so much in test
done and we could spend a little more
time on the brain.
So human beings really are fire users.
We invented fire or discovered it or
whatever.
Man Mastered it at least a couple of
million years ago,
a long time.
So that's all pretty cool as far as I'm
concerned.
So that's partly how you think
and that's naturally how you think.
You think a certain way.
And so we'll say that your fundamental
architecture is social cognitive.
You tend to view the world as if it's
personified.
And the reason for that is that the
world in which you emerged as a being
was primarily social.
And what you needed to know was who's
the big primate and who's the little
primate and who's related to who.
And you know,
among chimps,
if a big chimp is threatened by a small
chimp,
well you know what,
the big chimp can just tear the small
champ apart,
but the big chimp will back off if it
knows that the little chimp is
associated with some really big chimps.
And so the little chimp can bully the
big chimp because it's part of a
dominant family.
And that's because the nervous system of
the big chimp doesn't respond to the
little chimp like a little chimp.
It responds to the little chimp,
like it's a little champ with four great
monsters attached to it because it's
true.
So it's nervous system is actually
responding to the network around the
chimp.
And so that's exactly what you,
well,
it's not exactly what you're like
because you're not chimps,
but you know,
it's that kind of platform that
constitutes the evolutionary
underpinnings of your psyche.
So what does that mean?
Well,
it means this is like perfectly fine to
us,
right?
Can I automate things?
We can have rabbits are people,
no problem.
We'll go along with that.
You remember Roger Rabbit?
I presume most of you've watched that.
So this is the detective who's name I
don't remember.
He has to go to toontown cause there's
cartoons and there's people and you know
they share the same world and you can go
to toontown.
Although it's kind of annoying because
cartoon figures are kind of annoying.
Like there's slapstick types and so he's
a very happy to be there.
And this is what it looks like.
Okay.
Right.
Everything's animated,
meaning alive.
Anima means soul by the way.
So everything has a personality and you
know when you're reading books to kids,
the sun has a personality,
train has a personality,
jet has a personality.
It doesn't matter what it is.
It has a personality.
And that's because the child is learning
to understand the world using the
architecture,
social,
cognitive architecture.
And so,
and the thing that's really interesting
about that,
that's just blows me away.
You know,
evolution is conservative and so once
it's produced something,
it has to build on it.
It's like dos,
the operating system.
It's like really?
It's still there.
If I remember correctly,
under windows 10 you can't get rid of
the damn thing because it's part,
it's part of the structure now and it's
like the keyboards we use,
which were actually designed to slow
typers down because with mechanical type
writers,
if you type too fast,
the keys would jam.
So they divine device,
the keyboard to slow you down and we
still use it,
which is stupid.
You know you want the high frequency
letters close to your middle fingers.
That isn't what it's like at all.
But we can't change it because everyone
uses it.
So your body plan,
that thing has been around a long time
man.
If you look at mammals particularly,
but even lizards,
there's so much like us in their,
in their skeletal structure that is just
mind boggling.
You know?
And we're all variants of the same
symmetrical four legged mouth here,
structure.
And so you have to build to what you
have.
And if you have a social cognitive
architecture,
then you have to first understand the
world through the social cognitive
categories.
And what so bloody strange about that is
it actually seems to work.
We actually seem to develop a coherent
representation of being,
I would say of being that's not the same
as nature.
It's not the same as the world.
Because when we think of the world,
we think of the objective world.
And I'm not talking about the objective
world,
I'm talking about the world of human
experience.
And we see that through social cognitive
filter and it makes perfect sense to us
and it works.
That's so strange.
So anyways,
everything's got this animated nature
and we don't have a problem with that.
In fact,
we actually find it quite fun.
You know,
people go visit the Disney toontown and
participate in it 10 and have fun with
it.
And so that shows you as well how,
how natural it is for us to,
to view things this way.
You know,
cars have faces,
right?
Designers know that.
They know that people don't want a car
with three headlights because like who
wants to be associated with a three odd
monster?
No one.
It's like two eyes.
That's something you could be
comfortable with.
And so cars have faces and like a bmw is
the new one.
So they really look Cadillac,
you know,
and they have sexy curves.
They do,
they do.
There's been MRI studies of that.
So,
um,
if you showed men photographs of
attractive women looking directly at
them,
there's a little part of their brain
called the nucleus accumbens that lights
up because to have someone look directly
at you,
especially if they have like a smile,
is,
is interpreted as an invitation to
approach.
And women,
they have the same damn problem because
with women,
because if you go into drugstores say,
and you look at women's magazines,
they're all the same.
They've all evolved to the same
endpoint.
They all have an attractive woman on
them,
all of them.
And they're looking right out.
And so when women see that,
they actually see it as something to
with approach,
it's an ideal.
And now,
you know,
when people say that those beauty ideals
are oppressive to women and all ideals
are oppressive,
but the empirical research,
some of it done here suggests that
interacting with those images
helps the performance,
the psychological function of helping
the woman equate herself with the ideal.
And in most cases that actually produces
a po and elevation in mood.
And you know,
think about it,
you're really going to go to the
magazine store when you're just looking
for something to do and you're going to
buy something that makes you feel
depressed and oppressed.
It's like,
no,
you're not going to do that.
Magazines that do that to you,
they will die because no one will buy
them.
And there's a reason they all turned out
the same way.
It's like they're just responding to
demand.
So
yeah,
faces,
Oh yes.
With regards to the sexy curves.
So
woman who looks upon picture looking
right out,
a man will produce this activation in
the primary reward system.
Cocaine produces the same response and
Sodas,
sports cars,
especially curvy red sports cars.
And so that's why you often see an
attractive woman sitting on a curvy red
sports car in an ad because it's,
you know,
if there's an ad for beer on the side,
it's like,
hey,
everything's perfect.
So,
and you know,
those are all primary reward reward
representations.
And they produce attraction because part
of positive emotion,
the dopamine dopaminergic Lee mediated
element and positive emotion is an
approach emotion.
It's not a satiation satisfaction
emotion.
It's all good.
There's something good here.
I can move towards it.
And that,
that is what happiness is.
That's directly what happiness is.
It's not attaining something because
that just puts you in a whole new
problem.
You've got to figure out what to do
next.
All right,
so I suggested to you
that one of the problems that we have,
the problem I would say is not what the
world's made out of,
but how we should be in the,
because we're alive and how we should
be.
Well,
it's,
it's fairly straight forward.
Not so much pain would be good.
That'd be good.
Not Too much anxiety.
Hey,
we're on board for that.
Um,
little pleasure down then.
Some stability,
uh,
not dying.
That's a big one.
And then let's say from the Darwinian
perspective,
propagating.
And so that's what we're aimed at.
And the reason we're aimed at that is
you just think about this.
It's so amazing.
So every single one of your,
of the relatives you have in your
ancestry,
every single one of them
successfully produced a child who
successively successfully produced a
child all the way back to 3 billion
years ago.
It's bloody unbelievable.
Like the probability that you exist
while it's 100% because there you are,
but the probability of predicting that
you would exist,
you know,
if you tried to predict it,
it's like the chance that the chances
that you're here are so infinite
testable that it's just absolutely mind
boggling.
Think about that unbroken sequence of
success over literally over billions of
years.
God,
it's amazing.
And so you have to,
obviously you have to think that there's
a pretty strong proclivity for that to
happen.
I mean,
some of them are obviously was
necessity,
but not only that,
I mean it's necessary that impregnated
females have an infant.
It isn't necessary that they keep it
alive.
So you can't account for that continuity
merely from necessity.
You have to interject a least,
a small amount of consideration that the
care that's associated,
especially with taking care of infants
because they're,
you know,
there are a lot of work that's there to
tennis.
It's actually,
I think it's manifested in the
personality trait.
Agreeableness cause it looks to me like
agreeableness is one of the dimensions
where men and women very most
substantially agreeableness.
It looks to me like the manifestation of
the maternal instinct.
Now men can be agreeable to because of
course male human beings take care of
children.
You know if you're a grizzly bear female
you just chase the damn mail away cause
he'll kill your cubs.
That's not so helpful.
But they're not maternal at all.
Quite the contrary.
But you know human manner are pretty
damned maternal.
They're not as a maternal is women on
average,
although some women are less maternal
than some men because you know the
curves overlap but,
but on balance,
how are we in the world where all we're
already aware of our own vulnerability.
We're aware of our own shortcomings
let's say.
And that's,
I think that's partly from being a
social being cause people are always
signaling your shortcomings to you to
such a degree that you even signal your
shortcomings to yourself because while
you might as well fix them before
someone else points them out,
that's guilt and shame.
You know when Freud called that the
Superego,
the superego is kind of like the
internalized representation of the
judgmental father and culture I think is
represented as a father figure.
God the father let's say because it's
actually,
oh it's actually quite a bit like there
is an all seeing eye that's always
watching you.
It's a really,
really intelligent way of
conceptualizing it because the group
which is more or less eternal is
watching you all the time,
all the time and it's judging you all
the time.
And we know that if you put people in a
room and you put a big eye on the wall,
you know,
and then you give them an opportunity to
cheat on some little cheeky thing.
You know,
nothing too important.
If they're in the room with the big eye,
they're less likely to cheat if they're
in the room with no way at all.
So,
you know,
and what do you do?
You keep an eye on your kids and the
reason you do that is so they don't
misbehave and we keep an eye on each
other.
And so we have a representation of that.
And as far as I can tell,
we represented as a transcendent figure
of judgment.
And it's like,
yeah,
that's,
hey,
that's a pretty good metaphor.
So
one of the,
this is a major intellectual battle,
the major intellectual battle and it's
raging in universities.
It's basically a battle between
postmodernism and traditional and
tradition.
I think that's the right way of thinking
about it.
For the postmodernists,
human beings have no nature.
We're blank slates.
Everything that we are is enculturated,
so we're completely malleable and all
elements of our identity are malleable.
On the other side are the
traditionalists who are,
I would say grounded more in
biology on the one hand,
but also in,
in,
in the historical humanities tradition
that suggests that people have in
nature.
Um,
I explained some of that nature.
Most people want to have friends as part
of your nature.
You know,
most people want to find love part of
your nature and,
and you suffer without it.
So,
and you know,
you could say those are all social
constructs,
but
you can say,
you can say anything.
So you know,
and no to ever trust someone who has one
explanation for everything,
you know,
how much intelligence does that take?
You got one explanation,
you can just trot it out for every
phenomena.
This is an alternative.
Now,
here's what happened in park
nature back in the late 18 hundreds was
very interested in the dissolution of
traditional faith in,
in,
in the west.
We fell out of our myth.
That's a way of thinking about it.
We stopped believing in its fundamental
axioms.
You start believing that there was such
a thing as a transcendent deity.
For example,
it didn't mesh well with the emerging
scientific viewpoint.
And so in the late 18 hundreds,
Nietzsche announced the death of God.
MMM.
Which sounds fairly presumptuous,
but it wasn't something,
he was celebrating the full quote and I
haven't gotten it exactly right is God's
dead.
We've killed him and we'll never find
enough water to wash away the rivers of
blood.
So like that's a lot different than what
you see scrawled on bathroom walls and
Nietzsche hypothesized that in the 20th
century millions of people would die in
the conflicts over what values we're
going to reign as an alternative to that
tradition.
And he particularly brilliantly
pointed to communism.
He said that's where it's going to be in
Dostoyevsky did the same thing.
And so,
and since then there's this been this
battle.
He and the battle is kind of like this,
the battle is on the one hand between
social construction,
social constructionist utopians who
believe that human nature is infinitely
malleable and that with the proper
transformations in society,
you can bring apart about the perfect
state and the perfect human being.
And,
and traditionalist
and young I think is the classic example
of this who believed that there is a
human nature and it's deeply embedded
within us and that the cultures we set
up have to manifest themselves in
accordance with that nature.
Or they will fail.
Oh,
young believed in the existence of a
Meta narrative,
the hero myth,
roughly speaking.
And he explained it's connections to
various religious traditions in a
staggeringly brilliant manner.
Camille Paglia,
who I would recommend,
and I think I already told you that,
you know,
she,
she's already concluded after going
through a radical feminist period early
in her life,
that the proper way for society orient
itself is within a mythological
structure.
And that that's part of what the
humanities provides.
Um,
and the alternative is
rational arguments over what values are
going to dominate.
And it isn't obvious that rationality
can solve that problem.
I don't think it can.
That's hume's point.
David Hume said,
you can't derive an ought from an is,
right?
You cannot use science as a guide to
behavior.
So what do you use?
Instinct instinct manifested in
imagination and the evolution,
the evolved structure of your organic
cultures,
something like that.
Do they have a structure?
That's the question.
Okay,
so you ask yourself this question,
what is it that every being shares
regardless of place and time.
So any universally comprehensive
language that would be a Meta narrative,
a myth,
a hero myth.
Let's say a myth about what a human
being,
not only his life but should be like,
has to speak to us about those aspects
of experience that we all share.
Because otherwise we wouldn't understand
the damn story.
Now we go to how we go to stories that
we understand all the time,
like star wars,
and it really doesn't matter what
country,
you know,
everybody gets it more or less.
So obviously there's stories that we can
understand and mutually,
you know,
we understand love stories,
we understand stories of conflict,
we understand stories of betrayal,
we understand stories of anger.
And that's because we can feel jealousy.
We can feel love,
we can feel anger.
It's,
it's part of you.
It's right there.
We even know where the circuits are,
you know?
And then you're like other animals,
they feel it too.
So very similar emotions as far as we
can tell.
So
here's,
here's this is drive in large part from
young but not only,
um,
here's what we share.
Natural world,
social world and the fact of our
existence as an individual.
And that can be represented in different
ways.
It can be represented as you,
the known,
the and the unknown or it could be you
culture and nature,
all the same representations and the
cultural representation tends to be
male.
That's God the father let's say.
And they
representation,
the Feminine Representation tends to be
female.
This is the known culture apollonian
control that's associated with the son
consciousness,
the king,
the patriarch,
the plow because it pushes up the earth.
The Phallus obviously order and
authority and the crushing weight of
tradition,
the wise old man and the tyrant dogma,
the day sky,
the country mountain,
the island,
the heights,
the ancestral spirits,
the activity of the dead
captain hook,
he's a tyrant.
And that's why Peter Pan doesn't want to
grow up to become him.
grow up well because he thinks that
adults are all tyrants.
Why is captain hook a tyrant?
Because a crocodile ate his hand and the
crocodile has a clock in its stomach.
And the reason for that is that the
crocodile is time and time's already got
a piece of Captain Hook and he's not
very happy about it.
He's bitter and resentful and
tyrannical.
And when Peter Pan looks at adulthood,
that's what he sees.
And he thinks,
why should I sacrifice the potential of
childhood for the singularity of tight
tyranny?
And so we stay as immature his entire
life.
And he's king of the lost boys.
Jesus.
Great.
There's a porn star named Jeremy Christ.
Can't remember his name.
It's really an ugly guy.
He is.
He is not ugly guy.
He admits it and he,
he said something funny,
I was watching a documentary about him
and he said the funniest thing,
he said,
I'm the hero to people who think people
like me are heroes.
What a drag.
I mean,
he's just in this horrible situation.
He doesn't admire the people that admire
him.
But he gets admired by them all the
time.
Well,
it's sort of like Peter Pan.
It's like,
well he's king of the lost boys.
He doesn't get windy either.
Right?
She grows up,
she has a family.
He asked to contend himself with
Tinkerbell and you know what?
Tinkerbell doesn't exist.
Well that's what happens when you don't
grow up.
That's a representation of culture.
That's a nasty one.
A
nasty one.
Hell,
we'll kiss,
kiss a statue of Stella.
Who cares that he murdered 30 million
people culture.
Well,
you know in the university you hear a
lot about the patriarchy and how
oppressive it is.
It's like,
yeah,
right.
Definitely.
No kidding.
But you know,
it's kind of useful as well since it
provides the light and the heat,
the food and all of that,
which you know,
kind of counterbalances it to some
degree.
Culture has a positive element and a
negative element.
The individual has a positive element
and a negative element.
Nature has a positive element and a
negative element.
And if people tell you a one sided
story,
which is the ideological story,
they leave out bat,
they say all culture is terrible.
The human being is a despoiled and
nature is perfect.
It's like no nature kills you.
Culture keeps you alive,
and there's things about you that are
honorable and good,
as well as things about you that aren't.
And you need to know both of those.
And that's what the great stories tell
us.
All right.