Okay,
well I thought this time that I would
actually cover some of the biblical
stories so,
and hopefully a number of them,
as I said last time,
I'm going to go through this while as
fast as I am able to,
I want to do it as completed job as
possible and of course the probability
that I'll get through the entire Bible
is very low,
but we'll get through a lot of the major
stories in the beginning of it.
And that's a good start.
And then,
you know,
assuming that this all goes well then
maybe I'll try to do the same thing
again either in the fall or next year.
So I'm assuming I'm at,
everything is still working out properly
next year.
It's a long ways away.
Alright.
So,
um,
I guess we'll start.
So last week I talked to you about
aligned in the new testament that was
from John and it was a line that was
designed to parallel the opening of
genesis and it's a really important line
and I thought I would reemphasize it
because the Bible is a book that's been
written forward and backwards in time in
some sense,
like most books because if you write a
book,
of course when you get to the end,
if you're the writer,
you can adjust the beginning and so on.
So it has this odd,
it has this appearance of linearity,
but it really,
it isn't linear.
It's like your God in some sense,
standing outside of time.
That's your book and you can play with
time anywhere along it.
And the people who put the book together
or the books together,
uh,
took full advantage of that.
And,
and,
and that makes the story.
It gives the story odd parallels in,
in many,
many places in a very large number of
this isn't.
This is one of the major parallels,
at least from the perspective of the
Christian interpretation of the Bible,
which of course includes the New
Testament and so there's this strange
idea that Christ was the same factor or
force that God used at the beginning of
time to speak habitable order into
being,
and that's a very,
very strange idea.
You know it,
it,
it's not.
It's not something that can be just
easily dismissed as superstition.
Partly because it's so strange.
It's it,
it,
it doesn't.
It doesn't even fit the definition of
like a superstitious belief.
It's,
it's a dream like belief in some sense
and what I,
what I see many of the ideas in the
Bible as is,
is these dreamlike ideas that,
that underlie our,
our normative cognition and that
constitute the ground from which are
more articulate and articulated and,
and explicit ideas have emerged in this
one.
So complicated.
This idea is so complicated that it's
still mostly embedded in dreamlike form,
but it seems to have something to do
with the primacy of consciousness and
this is one of the biggest issues
regarding the structure of reality.
As far as I can tell,
because everyone from physicists to
neurobiologists debates this,
there's there's the the stumbling block
for a purely objective view of the world
seems to me to be consciousness and
consciousness has all sorts of strange
properties.
For example,
it isn't obvious what constitutes time
or at least duration in the absence of
consciousness and it isn't also easy to
understand what constitutes being in the
absence of consciousness because it
seems to be the case.
Well,
if a movie is running and there's no one
to watch it,
I know it sounds like the tree in the
forest idea,
but it's.
It's.
It's not that idea at all.
If if a movie is watching is running and
no one's watching it,
in what sense is can you say that
there's even a movie running because the
movie seems to be the experience of the
movie,
not the objective elements of the movie
and there's something about the world,
at least in so far as we're in it as
human beings,
that is dependent on conscious
experience of the world.
Now,
of course,
you can take consciousness out of the
world and say,
well,
if none of us were here,
if there was no such thing as
consciousness than the cosmos would
continue running the way it is running,
but of course it depends on what exactly
you mean by the cosmos when you make a
statement like that because there's
something about the subjective
experience of reality that gives it
reality,
or at least that's one way of looking at
it and since we're all pretty enamored
of our own consciousness as although
they're painful because they define our
being.
It's not unreasonable to give
consciousness a kind of metaphysical
primacy now and it's deeper than that,
you know,
on steeper idea than that.
Because there are physicists and they're
not trivial physicists like John Wheeler
who believes that in some sense,
consciousness plays a constitute of role
in transforming the chaotic potential of
being into the actuality of being.
And he actually thinks about it.
He's not alive anymore,
but he actually thought about it as,
as playing a constitutive role.
You know,
and then from the neuro biological
perspective or from the scientific
perspective,
it's like consciousness is not something
we understand that I don't think we
understand it at all with something we
can't get a handle on with our
fundamental materialist philosophy and I
don't know why that is.
It's quite frustrating if you're a
scientist,
but it isn't clear to me that we've made
any progress whatsoever in understanding
consciousness even though while we've
been trying to understand it for
hundreds of years and even those
psychologists,
neurobiologists and so forth have really
like put a lot of effort into
understanding consciousness from a
scientific perspective in the last 50
years.
So anyways,
what,
what it's,
it seems to me is the idea that,
that God used the word to,
to extract order out of habitable order,
out of chaos
at the beginning of time,
which is roughly the right way of
thinking about.
It seems to me deeply aligned with the
idea that what it is that we do as human
beings is his encounter.
Something like a formless and potential
chaos.
I mean,
we're not omniscient obviously,
and we can't just do whatever we want,
but we encounter a formless and chaotic
potential.
That's always what we're grappling with
and somehow we use our consciousness to
give that form and this is how people
act like if it.
If you look at how they regard
themselves,
it's how they act because you say things
to people like,
well,
you should live up to your potential
when you make a case that there's
something about a person that's more
than what is that yet could be if only
they participated in the process
properly and everyone knows what that
means and no one acts like a mystery has
been honored.
When you say that and you can see a
situation in your own life that's full
of potential.
You are often extremely excited when you
encounter something that's full of
potential because what you see is
something that could be you see a future
beckoning for you.
That could be if only you interacted
with it properly and it activates your
nervous system right in in a in a very
basic way and we even understand how
that happens.
To the degree that we understand how the
nervous system works because the systems
that mediate positive emotion,
which are governed roughly by Dopa,
by the neurochemical,
dopamine and which have their roots way
down in the ancient hypothalamus,
a very,
very archaic and fundamental part of the
brain that responds to potential,
which is the possibility of accruing
something new and valuable.
It responds to potential with active
movement forward and engagement.
And so we're engaged in the world as
potential and looks like consciousness
does that.
And so there's this idea that,
and this is the main idea that I think
is being put forth in genesis one.
It's something like,
and you see this in mythology,
like from,
from what I've been able to gather
there,
there's always three causal elements
that make up being at the bottom of,
of world mythology and one is the
formless potential that makes up being
once it's interacted with and that's
generally given a feminine nature.
And,
and I think that's because it's like the
source from which all things emerge and
rise.
It's something like that.
It's more complicated than that,
but it's something like that.
And then there's some kind of
interpretive structure that has to
grapple with that form potential and
that's I think that's the sort of thing
that was alluded to by a manual count
when when he was criticizing the notion
that all of our information comes from
census data,
which would be the pure empirical
perspective,
right?
Because when you encounter the world you
encounter with a cognitive structure
that already has shape and so it's,
it's already in you this structure and
without that a priority structure,
you wouldn't be able to take the
formulas potential and give it structure
and I think that's something that it's
akin in some way to the idea of God the
father and I'll try to develop that idea
more.
It's,
it's the.
It's the notion that there's something
in all of us that transcends all of us
that's deeply structural.
That's part of this ancient.
While I would say evolutionary and
cultural process that enables us to
grapple with the formulas,
potential and bring forth reality
roughly speaking,
and then there's the final element and
that element seems to be something like
consciousness itself.
The consciousness that actually inheres
in the individual,
so it's not only that you have the
structure,
it's the structure,
has the capacity for action in the world
and it's like it's,
it's you're this,
you're this spirit that gives the dead
structure life.
It's something like that and as far as I
can tell,
that trinitarian notion that
characterize this Christianity is
something like,
well,
formless potential which has never given
a the status of a deity in Christianity
and then the notion that there's an a
priori interpretive structure that's a
consequence of,
of our ancient existence as as beings.
It goes back as far in time as you can
go though the notion of a structure and
then the idea of a consciousness that
that is the is the tool of that
structure and that interacts with the
world and gives it and gives it reality.
And that's the word as far as I can
tell.
And so the notion is is that there is a
father and that's the structure and
there's a son that's transcendent that
characterize as consciousness itself and
that it's the sun,
the speaking of the sun.
That is the active principle that turns
chaos into order and God,
it's such a sophisticated ideas as far
as I'm concerned because,
well,
there's something about it that's at
least phenomenologically accurate
because you do have an interpretive
structure and you couldn't understand
anything without it.
Your very body is an interpretive
structure,
right?
It's been crafted over,
let's say 3 billion years of evolution.
Without that,
you wouldn't be able to perceive
anything and it's taken a lot of death
and struggle and tragedy to produce you
the thing that's capable of encountering
this immense chaos that surrounds us and
to transform it into habitable order and
then there's the idea too.
Of course,
it's deeply embedded in the first
chapters of genesis,
which is a staggering idea.
You know,
and and certainly not one that's likely
that human beings were made in the image
of God.
Both male and female were made in the
image of God.
And that's of course a very difficult
thing to understand,
partly because the god that's referred
to in the in those chapters has it kind
of polytheistic element.
Although it's an element that's moving
rapidly towards a unified monotheism.
But it's not also obvious to me why
people would come up with that concept
because I don't really think that when
we think about each other,
we immediately think God,
like you know,
the notion that every single human
being,
regardless of their peculiarities and
strangeness is and Sins and Crimes and
all of that has something divine in them
that needs to be regarded with respect
and that plays an integral role,
at least an analogy analogous role in
the creation of habitable order,
out of chaos.
That's a magnificent,
remarkable,
crazy idea.
And yet we developed it and I do firmly
believe that it sits at the base of our
legal system.
I think it is the cornerstone of our
That's the notion that everyone is equal
before God,
which is of course it completely.
That's such a strange idea.
It's very difficult to understand how
anybody could have ever come up with
that idea because the manifold
differences between people are so,
so obvious and so evident that you could
say the natural way of viewing someone
is or human beings is in this extremely
hierarchical manner where some people
are contemptible and and and easily
brushed off as as pointless and
pathological and and without value
whatsoever,
and all the power accrues to a certain
tiny,
no aristocratic minority at the top,
but if you look at the way that the idea
of the individual sovereignty developed,
it's clear that it unfolded over
thousands and perhaps 10 thousands of
years before it became something firmly
fixed in the imagination that each
individual had something of transcendent
value about them and man,
I tell Ya,
we dispense with that idea at our
serious peril and so if you're going to
take that idea seriously then which you
do because you acted out because
otherwise you wouldn't be law abiding
citizens,
right?
You Act that idea out.
It's,
it's,
it's firmly shared by everyone who,
who acts in a civilized manner.
The question is,
why in the world do you believe it?
Assuming that you believe what you act
out,
which I think is a really good way of
fundamentally defining beliefs,
so,
alright,
so that's the sort of ideas that there's
this god of tradition and structure.
That's God the father who uses the sun,
which is more of an active force,
uh,
and,
and primarily something that's verbal,
which I also think is extremely
interesting because it's associated not
with thought precisely but with speech.
And I think the reason for that is,
is that there's something to speech
that's more than mere thought.
And I think part of the reason for that
is that speeches of public utterance,
and at least in principle speech is
something that's shaped by the existence
of,
of everywhere of everyone else,
at least across time.
Because when you speak you,
your speeches is put forward in the
world as a causal element.
And it's also subject to criticism and,
and uh,
and cooperation and mutual shaping.
And so there's an idea here to that
speech is that that the cognitive
processes that bring habitable reality
out of out of uninhabitable chaos have
this collective and public element,
which,
which is part of the reason by the way,
that I'm an advocate of free speech,
let's say above all because I don't
think,
although it is the case,
for example,
in the Canadian bill of rights,
that every single right has equal value.
That's the theory.
It's an idiotic theory because it's
absolutely impossible for a large set of
rights to have absolutely equal
standards stances that cannot happen.
There's no way that that could never
work.
But that is the legal judgment.
But I think it's a huge mistake because
free speech has this while this divine
quality,
let's say,
that you can't escape from because it's
the thing that manufacturers everything
else.
You know,
it's so.
And I do think that the dream that you
could think of as encapsulated in the
stories in genesis is the dream by which
human beings dreamed up.
The idea that we would now consider
consciousness.
Because you know,
it took us a long time to figure out the
word consciousness.
It's not like it's bloody obvious it who
knows how many thousands of years or or
or who knows what struggles we had to
undertake to abstract out something like
consciousness and how we had to
represent that dramatically say or
symbolically or in a dreamlike fashion
before we could actually formulate the
term and and localize that to some
degree in people.
It's very sophisticated.
So,
so John makes the case that while
there's,
there's an emanation of God or an
element of God that transcendent
consciousness.
It's something like that that acts
directly and in,
in this sort of living way with the,
with the underlying potential of the
world.
And I think that that's
phenomenologically accurate.
And I do think that that's the way we
regard our lights.
Because you know,
when you think about it too,
we tend to think that what you encounter
when you're looking at the world is the
material world.
But that isn't how you act.
You do act as if you're in a place of
potential and also in a place of
potential that you can actually
transform,
which is also something extraordinarily
strange,
you know,
because we do treat each other as if
we're capable of bringing new forms into
the world in some permanent manner.
Right,
and we treat each other as if we have
free choice and free will and perhaps we
don't,
but it's certainly the case that
societies that are predicated on the
idea that we don't don't do very well
and societies that are predicated on the
idea that we do seem to do a lot better.
Plus people tend to get very annoyed at
you if you treat them like they're
automatons that lack free will.
There's something that people find very,
I would say constraining slave,
like about that even you know that,
that the demand that you don't have
actual autonomy and even worse that
you're not responsible for your choices.
It's an insult to someone to suggest to
them that they're not responsible for
their choices.
You know,
you,
you usually to do that to someone from a
legal perspective,
you have to argue something like
diminished capacity,
right?
While you're mentally ill or you don't
have the intellectual capacity or,
or,
or you were or you were adult by some
substance or you had a brain injury or
something and that's why you're not
responsible for your actions.
Otherwise,
part of the respect that you give to
another human being is the assumption
that they're responsible for their
actions and some of that can be,
well if you do something bad then you're
responsible for it.
But part of that too is that if you do
something good,
you're also responsible for that.
And that also seems necessary because,
I mean,
do you really,
I mean it's got to be more annoying
than,
than anything else that you could
imagine to strive virtuously let's say,
to produce something of extreme value
and then to be treated as if that was a
mere deterministic outcome and that
your,
your actual choices had nothing to do
with that.
I mean,
people find that sort of thing
extraordinarily punishing and so I'm
willing to,
you know,
I mean,
I know that there are debates about all
these things and debates about freewill
in debates about the nature of
consciousness,
but I'm trying to take a clear look at
how people act and how they want to be
treated and then to trace it back to
these old ideas to see if there's some,
if there's some metaphysical,
let's say metaphysical connection.
So,
all right,
so here's how the,
here's how the book opens.
In the beginning,
God created the heavens and the earth.
The earth was without form and void and
darkness was over the face of the deep
and the spirit of God was hovering over
the face of the waters.
Now this is a hard,
this is a hard,
uh,
what would you call narrative?
Section two to get a handle on,
because in order to understand it
properly,
you have to actually look behind it.
So there,
there are a lot of pieces of old stories
in the old testament that flesh out the
meaning of these lines.
And I can,
I can give you a quick overview of it,
one of the ideas that lurks underneath
these lines,
although you can't tell because it's an
English,
you have to look at the original
languages and of course I don't speak
the original languages,
so I've had to use secondary sources
too,
too bad for me,
but the,
the,
uh,
without form and void and the deep idea
you see that's associated with this
notion of endless deep potential.
So for example,
the words that are used to represent
without form and void or something like,
well one is toe,
I'm going to get this part wrong.
Tohu wa Bohu.
And another one is tail.
And it's important to know this because
those words are associated with an early
miss earlier Mesopotamian word which is
titled Matt and Tie that was a dragon
like creature who represented the salt
water and,
and time out had a husband named app
suit and time at aps who were sort of
locked together,
kind of a sexual embrace.
And it was that locking together of
timeout and APP sue.
And I would say that's potential and
order.
Something like that or chaos in order.
They were locked together and it was
that union of chaos and order that gave
rise in the old Mesopotamian myth,
which is the Enuma elish to the to the
to being to the old gods first and then
eventually as as creation progressed to
human beings themselves.
And so there's this idea lurking
underneath this,
these initial lines that God is akin to
that which confronts the unknown and
carves it into pieces and makes the
world out of its pieces.
And the thing that it confronts is
something like a while.
It's something like a predatory reptiles
or something like a dragon or something
like a serpent.
And I think part of the reason for that
and and this,
this is,
this is a very deep and ancient idea,
is that this is where it gets so
complicated to do.
The translation is partly.
That is how human beings created our
world.
Like we went out beyond the confines of
our safe spaces.
Let's say our space,
our safe spaces defined by,
by the tree or defined by the fire.
And we actively voyaged outward to the
places that we were afraid of and didn't
understand and and Kong and conquered
and encountered things out there like,
like add,
like literally animals like mammoths and
snakes and predators of all sorts.
And it was as a consequence of that
active,
brave engagement with the domain of what
we did not understand the terrifying
domain of what we did not understand
that the world in fact was generated.
And that idea lurks deeply inside the
opening lines of,
of Genesis.
And it's an.
It's a profound idea in my estimation.
And I think.
See,
I think also that the way our brains are
structured,
and this is something that I'm going to
try to develop more today,
is that the ancient circuits that our
ancestors used to deal with the space
beyond which they had already explored.
So that would be home territory.
That.
So that's that unknown territory that's,
that's characterized by promise because
there are new things out there,
but also by intense danger,
right?
Because we're prey animals,
especially billions of years ago when we
were very young,
we had to go out there and encounter
things that were terribly dangerous and
there was a kind of,
let's say,
paternal courage that went along with
that and it was that the spirit of
paternal courage that enabled the
conquering of the unknown and there's no
difference between the conquering of the
unknown and the creation of habits,
habitable order.
And the thing is is that as our
cognitive faculties have developed to
the point where we're,
we're,
we're capable of very high levels of
abstraction.
The underlying biological architecture
has remained the same.
And so I.
I don't think that it's too much to say
at all that the circuits that you,
that engage you,
for example,
when you're having an argument about
something fundamental with someone that
you love and so you're trying to
structure the world around you jointly
to create a habitable space that you can
both exist within your using the same
circuits,
the abstracted version.
You're using the same circuits that are
archaic ancestors would have used when
they went out into the unknown itself to
encounter beasts.
And,
and,
and predators and,
and geographical unknowns.
It's the same circuit,
it's just that we do it abstractly now
instead of concretely,
but of course it has to be the same
circuit because evolutionary
evolutionary is,
is a very conservative force.
And what else would it be?
And this is also why I think it's so
easy for us to demonize those people who
are our enemies because
our enemies confront us with what we
don't want to,
with what we don't want to see.
And they,
they ended because of that.
Our first response is to use snake
circuitry,
snake detection circuitry on them and
that accounts for our capacity almost
immediate capacity to demonize and,
and,
and there's a reason for that.
It's not a trivial thing.
First of all,
it's a very fast response and second of
all,
it's a response that has worked for a
very,
very long time.
And so,
you know,
one of the variance of the hero and I
would consider a variant of the hero,
like a fragment of the picture of God is
the heroic warrior who slays the enemy.
Right?
And of course,
that's not precisely a politically
correct representation of the hero in
modern times and well then no wonder,
but it's still something that you go
watch and movies all the time and
admire,
right?
It's,
it's like this one of the.
How many plots are their romance and
adventure.
That's about it.
And most of the adventure genre is while
there's some enemy that's lurking in
some form,
it could be human,
it could be alien,
and someone rises up to go and confront
it,
maintain order,
you know,
it's like there's no getting away from
that story.
And if you don't have that in your own
life,
then you play a video game where that's
happening.
Or You watch a movie where that's
Or You read a book where that's
happening and it captures you.
Even if your atheistic and you're only
religion is star wars,
you know,
and,
and it's still well really,
really right.
It really,
it still captures your imagination and
you act like someone who's possessed by
religious fervor.
When you line up for three days to be
the first one into the theater,
you know,
and all the while claiming that your
atheistic to the core,
it's like,
okay,
so this,
this without form and void is this
chaotic and certainly it's a hard thing
to.
It's a hard thing to get a grip on.
You know,
what exactly this means.
But I can give you another kind of
example of how you would experience the
formless chaos of potential in your own
lives and,
and even how the order that you
currently inhabit can dissolve into
that.
And you know,
in Dante's inferno,
when he outlined the levels of hail,
so Dante was trying to get to the bottom
of what constituted evil really in,
in,
in this representation.
So it's a work of psychology.
And he was thinking,
well there,
there are various ways to behave
reprehensible,
but there is a hierarchy of re
reprehensible behavior and there's
something absolutely the worst at the
bottom.
And Dante believed that it was be trail.
And I think that's right,
because you know,
one of the things that enables our long
term cooperation,
peaceful cooperation between people is
trust.
And I would also say that trust is the
fundamental natural resource.
So there's been some very good books
written on the economic utility of
trust,
for example,
in societies where the default economic
presupposition between trading partners
is trust tend to be rich even if they
don't have any natural resources.
And you can see that,
for example,
with what happened with Ebay,
which I think was a kind of miracle
because of what should have happened
with Ebay was that you sent me junk and
I sent you a check that bounced.
Right?
And that was the end of Ebay,
but.
Right,
right,
exactly.
But that isn't what happened.
You're like the default,
the default transaction on Ebay was so
honest that the brokers,
you could hire brokers to begin with.
I can't remember what they were called
exactly,
but you could pay someone a fee so that
they would guarantee the transaction.
So you know,
you wouldn't send me John Can,
I'd actually send you a payment and we
pay 10 percent for someone to guarantee
that the default trade was so honest
that those things vanished right away.
And so that meant that all this frozen
capital,
roughly speaking,
which were all the junk that people had
lying around,
that someone else might want instantly
became money and the only reason that
worked was because people trusted one
another.
And so trust is,
is unbelievably powerful.
Economic Force,
maybe the most powerful economic force
anyways.
If you have a relationship with someone,
it's predicated on trust.
And a part of the reason for that is
that trust is what enables us to look at
each other without running away
screaming.
And what I mean by that is that if I
trust you,
then I don't have to take into account
how complicated you are because you're
horribly complicated to know.
I think chimpanzee full of snakes.
That's what a human being is.
And as long as you'll do what you say
you'll do,
then I can take you at your word and
your word simplify as you and you can
take me at my word and my word simplify
as you,
and then we can act like we understand
each other even though we don't.
But then if that trust is betrayed,
then all the snakes come forth very,
very rapidly.
And so you,
all of you,
I suspect of being betrayed one way or
another.
And so what happens if you're in a
relationship with someone and you trust
them,
then you make certain assumptions about
the past and you make certain
assumptions about the present and you
make certain assumptions about the
future and everything stable.
And so you're standing on solid ground
and and the chaos.
It's like you're standing on thin ice.
The chaos is hidden.
The sharp beneath the waves isn't there.
You're,
you're safe.
You're in the lifeboat.
But then if the person betrays you,
like if you're in an intimate
relationship and the person has an
affair and you find out about it,
then then you think one moment you're
one place,
right?
You're aware,
everything is secure because you
predicated your perception of the world
on the axiom of trust and the next
second,
really the next second,
you're in a completely different place
and not only is that place different
right now,
the place you were years ago is
different and the place you're going to
be in the future years hanse is
different and so all of that certainty,
that strange certainty that you inhabit
can collapse into incredible complexity
and you say,
well,
if someone betrays you,
you think,
well,
okay,
who were you?
Because you aren't who I thought you
were and I thought I knew you,
but I didn't know you at all and I never
knew you.
And so all the things we did together,
those weren't the things that I thought
were happening.
Something else was happening and you're
you or someone else,
and that means I'm someone else because
I thought I knew what was going on and
clearly I don't.
I'm some sort of blind sucker or the or
the victim of a psychopath or someone
who is so naive that they can barely
live and I don't understand anything
about human beings and they don't
understand anything about myself and I
have no idea where I am now.
I thought it was at home,
but I'm not.
I'm in a house and it's full of
strangers and I don't know what I'm
going to do tomorrow or next week or
next year.
It's like all of that certainty that
habitable certainty collapses right back
into the potential from witchetty merged
and that's a terrifying thing.
That's a journey to the underworld from
a mythological perspective and that is
really something worth knowing because
you know,
journeys to the underworld are
extraordinarily common in mythological
stories and you know,
like the hobbit going out to find the
smaller the dragon and get the gold is a
journey into the underworld.
Journeys to the underworld happen all
the time and modern people don't
understand what the underworld is except
that we've all been there and we go
there all the time and we'd go there
every time.
The solidity and stability of the world
that we've erected,
at least partly through our speech is
shattered because while some sort of
snake appears,
that's another way of thinking about it
and it's a really good way of thinking
about it because you know,
no matter how carefully you construct a
little habitable area that's around you,
there's always something you didn't take
into account and there's always
something that can pop up its head and
do you in and make you aware of your
mortality and age you for that matter or
even kill you.
And that's the permanent.
That's the permanent situation of life.
Which is part of the reason why I think
the story of Adam and Eve,
for example,
is archetipal.
It's because we do inhabit walled
gardens,
right?
Because a walled garden is half
structure society and half nature.
That's what a walled garden is.
A walled garden is a place of,
of,
of paradise and warmth and,
and,
and love and,
and sustenance.
But it's also the place where something
can pop up at any moment and knock you
out of it.
And I think part of the reason that that
story exists at the beginning of this
collection of books is because it
explains the eternal situation of human
beings.
We're always in that situation.
We're in a walled garden or we bloody
well hope we are,
but there's always a snake and then it's
even worse because if there is a snake
where exactly the sort of creatures who
are going to do nothing but go and
interact with that state,
the second that we can manage it,
you know,
it,
it's,
it's definitely the case that if you
want a human being to muck around with
something,
the best thing to do is to tell them not
ever to do it,
have anything to do with it,
which is of course something,
you know,
if you have teenagers or even children
or,
or if you know anything about yourself
or your partner.
So these stories are trying to express
what you might describe as an unchanging
transcendent reality.
You know,
it's,
it's something like what's common across
all human experience across all the
time.
And that's what young essentially meant
by an archetype.
And you could say,
well,
you know,
we tend to think that what we see with
our senses is real.
And of course that's true,
but what we see with our senses is
what's real that works at the timeframe
that we exist in.
Right?
And so we see things that we can touch
and pick up.
We see tools essentially that are useful
for our moment to moment activities.
We don't see the structures of eternity,
especially not the abstract structures
of eternity.
We have to imagine those with our
imagination.
Well,
and that's partly what these stories are
doing.
They're saying,
well,
there's,
there's forms of stability that
transcend our capacity to observe,
which is hardly surprising.
We know that if we're scientists,
right?
Because we're always abstracting out
things that we can't immediately
observe,
but there are metaphysical or moral
realities or phenomena,
logical realities that have the same
nature that you can't see them in your
life by observing them with your senses.
But you can imagine them with your
imagination and sometimes the things
that you imagine with your imagination
are more real than the things that you
see numbers that are like that.
For example,
and there's endless examples of that,
and I would say,
well,
this is also a good way of thinking
about fiction because a good work of
fiction is more real than the stories
from which it was derived.
Otherwise it has no staying power,
right?
It's distilled reality even though in
some sense it never happened.
It's like,
well,
it depends on what you mean by happened.
You know,
it's,
it's a,
it's a pattern that repeats in many,
many places with variation.
You extract out the central pattern.
It's,
it's the pattern purely never existed in
any specific form,
but the fact that you've pulled a
pattern out from all those exemplars
means that you've extracted something
real and I think the reason that the,
the story of Adam and Eve,
which we'll talk about and quite a bit
of detail today has net has been immune
to being forgotten is because it says
things about the nature of the human
condition that are always true.
I can give you another brief example.
You know,
like people have a lot of guilt.
there's a line of social psychology that
claims that most people feel that
they're better than other people and
like I just don't buy that,
that isn't what I've seen in my life and
maybe it's,
I'm a bit biased because I'm a clinical
psychologist and I see more people who
are overtly suffering maybe than people
do in general.
Although I'm not so sure about that
because you don't have to scratch very
far beneath the surface of most people's
lives before you find something truly
tragic.
And I don't mean this sort of tragedy
that you whine about.
I mean,
you know,
your mother has Alzheimer's or,
or your,
your best friend committed suicide or
you have a close relative with cancer.
You have a sick child or you know,
there's something wrong with you because
almost everyone has at least one really
terrible thing wrong with them.
And if you don't,
hey,
you will.
So you know,
so know that,
that so,
so that,
that tragic sense of being there with
people all the time.
And it's also the case that the,
my,
in my experience,
like I rarely meet someone who says,
Hey,
you know,
I'm doing everything I possibly can.
I'm a hell of a guy and I can't see how
I could possibly improve.
You know,
you meet,
you meet someone like that.
You think they're narcissistic,
right?
Would endure,
right.
And,
but,
but most people don't feel that way.
They feel like they could do a hell of a
lot better than they are and they're
quite acutely aware of their faults and
they don't feel that are what they
should be.
And you see what happens in the story of
Adam and Eve as well as that.
When people become self conscious,
at least that's how it looks to me.
They get thrown out of paradise and then
they're in history.
And history is a place where there's
pain in childbirth and where you're
dominated by your mate and where you
have to toil like mad,
like no other animal because you're
aware of the future.
You have to work and sacrifice the joys
of the present for the future
constantly.
And you know you're going to die and you
have all that weight on you.
And to me,
again,
that's just how can anything be more
true than not.
That's just as far as I can tell.
That's just how it is for.
Unless you're naive beyond
comprehension,
there's something about your life that,
that,
that is echoed in,
in that representation and why it is
that.
I mean we're such strange creatures
because we don't seem to really fit into
being in some sense.
And that's also what's expressed in the
notion of the fall.
We,
the existentialist said,
well,
people feel like they have a debt that
they have to pay off to existence for
the,
for the crime of there,
for the crime of there being something
like that.
And maybe it's because we're acutely
aware that we have to offer something of
value to the people around us so that
they can tolerate us.
You know,
well we're,
we're going about our business.
But it seems deeper than that.
It's that human beings seem to exist in
a post cataclysmic world.
And that's exactly also what's
represented in genesis.
And it's very interesting because you
know,
there's,
in the Adam and Eve story,
there's two,
there's two catastrophes.
Essentially there's the catastrophe that
occurs when Adam and eve wake up,
which we'll talk about in detail and
become self conscious and know that
they're naked,
that and their eyes are open,
right?
So that's the terminology that's used.
And to have your eyes open means to have
an increment in consciousness.
Essentially [inaudible] eyes are
associated with consciousness for human
beings because we're intensely visual
animals.
And so the metaphor of having your eyes
opened means,
is the same as the metaphor of coming to
consciousness.
And as soon as Adam and eve come to
consciousness,
they realized they were naked.
And you know,
the classic interpretation of that is
that it has something to do with sexual
sin.
And I don't,
I don't believe that I,
I don't believe that that's what it
means.
All the other elements about that that
are irrelevant,
it's more of that to realize that you're
naked.
It's like you're,
you know,
if you dream that you're naked on a
stage in front of people,
that's not a sexual dreams man.
Unless you're some kind of strange
exhibitionist,
right?
It's,
it's you want to cover yourself up and
get the hell off that stage as fast as
possible and so to be naked in front of
a crowd is to have everyone to have the
judgment of the social world focused on
your self evident inadequacies and that
makes people self conscious and that
that's a real human state.
It's associated with neuroticism and in
the big five traits model,
but people don't like that at all.
They don't like having their fragility
and vulnerability exposed to the group.
It's one of the two major fears of
people because one is social humiliation
and the other is something like
mortality and death and like your.
Your typical agoraphobic for example,
gets to have both those fears at the
same time because she usually is.
She tends to believe she's going to have
a very spectacular and exhibition mystic
heart attack in a public place and make
a terrible fool of herself while she's
dying.
So then that's a good example of the two
archetipal fears that characterize,
characterize human beings.
So.
So to me,
and I said that I tried to approach
these stories as if I didn't know what
they were about because that seemed
right to me because there are mysteries
there.
Everything about them is mysterious and
why we have them is mysterious and what
the hell you're all doing here is
mysterious,
you know,
listening to this lecture and so and
reading young [inaudible] young Carl
young was very,
very helpful in this because he,
he faced these stories with a beginner's
mind and presumed there was something to
him that he didn't understand given that
they were at the very bloody bottom of
our civilization in which is
historically perfectly clear and that
they came out of the midst sub time and
he wasn't satisfied with the idea of the
Freudian idea that God was just the
father or the Marxist idea that religion
was the opiate of the masses.
It's like religion was the opiate of the
masses.
Then communism was the methamphetamine
of the masses.
I can tell you that.
So,
so you know,
you've been betrayed by someone and so
you fall into that underworld of,
of,
of doubt about everything.
And it's a serious place to be in that
underworld a because not only do you not
know where you came from or who you are
or where you're going,
that's bad enough.
So that's the underworld itself,
but there's a subdivision of the
underworld,
like the worst suburb is I think what
hell is essentially from a metaphysical
perspective because you know,
if someone really cuts you off at the
knees,
especially if they do it in a malevolent
way,
and if you're going to be betrayed and
you really want to be betrayed properly,
you want to be betrayed by someone who's
really out to hurt you.
You know,
they just weren't being stupid.
They were like,
after you for whatever reason.
And then that's also you plunged into
that underworld space.
And that's also when you start to nurse
feelings of resentment and agreement and
murder and homicide.
And even worse,
you know,
because if people are betrayed enough,
they start.
They start to obsess about the utility
of being itself and perhaps go to places
that no one would ever want to go with.
They were in their right mind and to and
to develop a nurse fantasies of the
ultimate revenge and that's a horrible
place to be and that's held as far as I
can tell and that's why hell is always
been a suburb of the underworld because
if,
if you get plunged into a situation that
you don't understand and things are not
good for you anymore,
it's one step from being completely
confused.
It's only one step from being completely
confused to being completely outraged
and resentful and then it's only one
step from there to really looking for
revenge and that can take you places
that well that that merely to imagine
properly can be traumatic.
And I've seen that happen with people
many times and I think that anybody who
uses their imagination on themselves can
see how that happens.
Because I don't imagine there's a single
person in the room that hasn't nursed
fairly intense fantasies of revenge at
least at one point in their life.
And usually you know for what appeared
to be good reasons.
It's no picnic to get betrayed.
That's for sure.
And it can shake your faith in being.
But if it shakes it so badly that you
turned against being itself,
that's certainly no solution,
that's for sure.
All it does is make everything that's
bad,
even worse.
So
okay,
now so and God said,
let there be light and there was light
and God saw that the light was good and
God separated the light from the
darkness.
And so that's,
that's another,
that's another fundamental separation,
right?
Light and darkness.
Those are,
those are in some sense the two
fundamental,
two of the fundamental elements of our
conscious being because of course when
it's light,
we're awake and conscious because we're
diurnal animals and when it's night,
well then we're asleep.
And so our,
our,
our existence is bounded by light and
darkness.
We're,
we're up and alert when it's light.
And that's partly because we're highly
visual animals,
right?
Unlike most animals,
because most animals you smell,
we use vision were very strange that
way.
And Vision is associated with
enlightenment and illumination and with
the breaking of the dawn and with the
coming of the new day and,
and all of that.
So and so for,
for light to be created is,
is,
is associated in some sense with the
emergence of conscious being and so
that's another echo of that notion and
there the,
the particular phrasing of the of the
story also is important because it's
that God sad,
right?
So that's the use of that word and
that's the active element of the
structure that gives rise to,
gives order to chaos.
It's something like that.
So it's this.
It's like the spirit of the structure
manifests itself and and produces the
fundamental divisions of experience.
That's what's being presented here.
And God separated the light from the
darkness.
He called the light day and the darkness
he called night and again again,
the fact that things are named is also
very important.
So you see this later without them
because God gives them the job of naming
all the animals and it's sort of like
the animals don't actually exist in some
sense till they're named.
And that's,
that's another indication of the authors
of the Bible's attempt to come to terms
with the fact that our cognitive
faculties and our ability to speak have
something to do with the way that we
cast chaotic potential into actuality,
right?
Because we can't.
We can't really get a grip on something
before we have a name for it,
which is why,
for example,
you all have names and everything that
you encounter has to have a name because
before it has a name,
it's just kind of part of the blurry
background and something like that.
And you could say it exists before it
has a name,
but.
And that's true.
But it's also true that it doesn't exist
before it has a name.
Because as soon as you give something,
a name,
it's nature changes and you've
transformed it into something that's not
so much mira potential anymore,
but it's at least on its way to being
actuality.
It's on its way to being a tool.
And so the,
the act of naming is repeated
continually in the first chapters of the
Bible.
And the reason for that is this
continued emphasis on the importance of
consciousness and conscious articulation
and speech and speech is really
something that does separate us in an
important way from animals,
you know,
like we haven't got very far teaching
animals how to speak the best we've
managed so far as some parrots,
right?
There's gray African parrot,
there was one of them that got up to
about a four year old level and that's
mind boggling because like how big is
the brain of a parrot?
It's like that big and that bloody thing
could talk.
And so that shows you how much we know
about brains,
but I know they're small and all that.
But,
and we tried teaching chimpanzees to
talk and they could kind of get
somewhere with sign language,
especially if you started when they were
young,
but they don't have the capacity for
language like we do and they were never
able to really pass it onto the,
to the next generation,
which is obviously a critical element of
really having that ability.
So human beings,
we,
we've,
we've used our linguistic capacity to
parse up the world in a new way and to
conceptualize it to the new way and you
know,
you can say that we're just like ants on
this little trivial planet out on the
edge of,
of one of 100 million galaxies and that
what's happening here has no cosmic
significance.
But that's an arbitrary,
that's an arbitrary a proposition,
you know,
I mean,
we're very complicated things and
whatever's going on on this planet has
to do with conscious reality and the
transformations of consciousness for all
we know might be the most important
things that happen everywhere.
There's no reason to consider
consciousness at trivial phenomena.
I mean,
it's taken three and a half billion
years for you to develop the brain that
you've developed and you and human
beings are amazing creatures.
I mean,
just a casual walk through youtube and
all those crazy kids that climb cranes
and do that.
What's that?
Yeah.
Park who are,
man,
that stuff's unbelievable.
You know?
I mean,
human beings are crazy,
crazy animals.
There's almost nothing we can't do.
And I'm very loath to assume that the
transformation of consciousness that are
described in the early,
in the early stories in,
in the biblical accounts are somehow
cosmically trivial.
It doesn't strike me that way and it's
certainly not self evident.
And even if they are cosmically trivial,
whatever that means,
the rocks don't care what you think.
Well,
who cares what the rocks think first?
They don't think so.
I don't see why that's exactly relevant,
but even if even if it's all the same to
the cosmos,
which is something that I doubt,
it's certainly not just all the same to
you,
you know,
because your consciousness has a quality
and it matters.
The heidegger,
for example,
who's,
who's a philosopher,
who,
who's writing sort of influenced me post
hoc because I recreated some of the
things that he had talked about in the
thirties before I knew much about it,
but one of the things that heidegger
said was that the fundamental element of
human being of human phenomenology was
care.
You said that that's the basic essence
of your being is that you care about
things you know and that that's either
negatively or positively,
right,
you to not care about something or to
hate.
It is still to be involved in care and
so even if the cosmos itself is,
is neutral with regards to our
existence,
we're not and we're the only things that
we know of that are conscious and so
while we might as well go with that and
there's no reason.
See,
I can't help but think that the constant
attempts by people to trivialize the
nature of their own consciousness has a.
has a dark side.
I'm a psychoanalyst and so I always
think that way.
It's like,
well,
first of all,
if you're,
if you as a being don't matter,
then you don't have to do anything.
It's a great justification for total
lack of responsibility and that,
that really twigged something for me
because you know,
people who are band,
let's say,
or vengeful or angry,
are always looking for a reason why they
don't have to be responsible for
anything.
Plus plus it's a lot easier.
And so the notion that consciousness is
trivial immediately allows you to wander
down that path.
And so I'm skeptical of those claims and
I also think that there's a deep hatred
of humanity that underlies those claims
as well.
And I read my youtube comments
sometimes,
you know,
and I've always been,
I've always been annoyed that,
you know,
because I've heard like sort of radical
clueless environmentalist say things
like planet would be better off without
people on it,
which is something that like,
you just cannot say that,
that if you say that and listen to
yourself,
you should like go to a monastery for
like three years and never say a word
and have a shower every 10 minutes until
you've learned your lesson properly.
You know,
you can't order a more genocidal phrase
the mat.
And of course you always do it in a
display of your care for the world.
It's like,
well,
if we just didn't have any people,
it's like,
well,
we'll just line them all up and shoot
them with machine guns.
No,
it's,
it's really sickening.
It's appalling.
It's.
And there's a hatred for humanity that's
at the bottom of it and I mean,
you can kind of understand why because
we're messy and we don't clean up after
ourselves and you know,
we're like raping the rain forests and
that sort of thing.
But I do have some sympathy for people
because,
you know,
we're,
we're hell on mother nature,
but she certainly returns the favor.
So.
And that's a good thing to remember,
you know,
a lot of what we're doing is just bloody
well trying to exist with a relative
minimum of pain and we're doing our best
to get,
you know,
to get as good at doing that as fast as
we can.
And that's not an easy thing.
There are lots of us and like life is
bloody complicated.
And the other thing that happens too is
again,
if you scratch beneath the surface of
people,
and this is something that's always,
you know,
to me,
it's been a kind of miracle is if you
talk to someone,
they're out doing their job and maybe
they're doing a good job at it.
Like some emergency room nurse,
you know,
God,
there's a job for you or maybe they work
in palliative care,
you know,
when you talk to them and you find out
they've got like four,
as I said before,
a serious problems in their family and
maybe their diabetic to boot and yet
they haul themselves out of bed in the
morning and go and take care of dying
people.
It's like good God.
People deserve a bit of respect for
struggling forward and not always trying
to make the planet a worst place when
they're beset on all sides constantly
by,
you know,
what unending series of tragedy you
think we could have a little bit of
sympathy for ourselves as a consequence
of that.
It's like we're not all like rapacious
greedy monsters who are bent on just
devouring everything in our path,
you know,
so a little bit more complicated than
that.
So.
Alright.
Anyway,
so,
so.
Well,
so let's go to the next part of this
here.
All right,
so God said,
let there be an expanse in the midst of
the waters and let it separate the
waters from the waters.
And God made the expanse and separated
the waters that were under the expanse
from the waters that were above the
expanse and it was so and God called the
expanse heaven and there was evening and
there was morning the second day.
Well to understand that because what,
how did,
that doesn't make any sense at all
really.
So I think I told you a little bit about
this before.
So the,
the,
the world that's being created in this
particular account is a phenomenological
world.
There's a disk of land because if you go
out in the field and look around,
you're on a disk of land.
So that's pretty obvious.
And then there's a dome on top of it is
more or less held up by the mountains
and rain comes.
So there's water above the dome because
where else would the rate come from?
And,
and underneath the ground there's fresh
water.
You can drill down and find that.
And then around that there's salt water.
And so that's the world.
And it's kind of an empirical world
because if you're a child and you just
go out and field and you look at the
world,
that's sort of what it would be like.
And so that's the world that's being
created.
And so one of the things that is worth
thinking about,
this is something Carl young was very
interested in,
is that these old descriptions are half
geographical and half empirical,
so sort of based on observation and half
psychological.
So one of the things young was
interested in,
for example,
was astrology,
but mostly for a psychological reason
because you know,
they're obviously there are stars up on
the dome.
And then when you look at the stars,
you can imagine the shapes of the stars
and that helps you orient yourself
because as soon as you can see shapes in
the stars,
then you can recognize the
constellations and you can orient
yourself at night.
But then the constellations become God,
say it in the gods,
turned into a drama.
And so and the drama comes from within.
It's the projection of imagination.
And so when young was analyzing
astrology,
he was a matt analyzing psychology.
Because he saw the astrological
narrative as the projection of the human
imagination onto the cosmos and so when
he was analyzing astrology,
who is analyzing psychology and that the
same thing as the case with these
stories is that the world they they
described is only,
it's not the natural world like a
scientist would describe it because
these people weren't scientists.
They didn't have the technology and the
tools.
It was,
it was the way they fruit for them it
was the world for us,
it's the way they saw the world.
And so we're looking at the way they saw
the world and a lot of that psychology
and we share that psychology to a large
degree with those people.
So in this is psychology,
but it's interesting to know what the
geographical substrate is so that you
can kind of understand the stories.
And I like this picture because that's,
it's great from a psychological
perspective.
So very famous picture and you know,
so basically what you have here is the
world as we know it.
And there's the dome with the Sun and
the moon on it and the stars.
And then if you look outside what you
know,
well then you're out into this cosmic
space,
right?
And that's,
those are like the wheels of,
of the planets and the music of the
spheres.
That's the ever present explorer who's
gone beyond the domain that he can
understand and is peering out into the
unknown as such.
And it's a psychological pictures.
It's like because you do know some
things and then outside of that there
are things you don't know and when
you're feeling brave,
you put a foot or two out where you
don't understand like because there's
frontier everywhere,
right?
And if you're,
if you're feeling heroic and you want to
do something for the world and you want
to expand what you understand,
you poke your head through what you know
when you take a look at the,
at the,
at whatever structure is out there,
you know,
he's pretty smart because of them is
still where it's safe.
And I would say that's a good,
that's a good thing because if you jump
right out there,
well then maybe you fall off the edge of
the earth.
And I wouldn't precisely recommend that.
Especially if you do it accidentally,
and to me this is a recreation of the,
of the Taoist Yin Yang symbol,
you know,
with the,
with the White Paisley here,
and that's what you know in the dark
paisley serpents really there,
and the right place to be is right on
the line between them because you're
sort of got one foot where you
understand that gives you security and
then you know,
but it's kind of dull because hey,
you know,
everything that's going on there and
that isn't what people are like.
They don't want just security.
Dostoevsky said that in notes from the
underground,
a great,
great book,
and he said,
I love this.
It was his,
an early critic critic,
criticism of the notion of a political
utopia.
He said,
look,
if you gave people everything they
wanted,
they had nothing deep but cake and
nothing to do,
but sit in warm pools and busy
themselves with the continuation of the
species.
That was his,
his lines that the first thing they
would do,
well maybe after the first week was like
goal kind of half insane and smash
everything up.
Just so that something that they didn't
expect,
what happened so that they'd have
something interesting to do and it's so
right.
Because you know,
the,
the utopia notion that if you just had
all the material stuff you wanted that
you'd,
you'd be,
well,
what would you be?
What would you do?
Would you just sit on the couch and
watch TV?
I mean,
you,
you'd,
you'd be,
I don't know why you'd be cutting
yourself just for entertainment in no
time flat,
you know?
And that's the sort of thing that people
do.
And so we're not adapted for security
and Utopia were adapted for a certain
amount of security because,
you know,
we are vulnerable,
but mostly we want to have one foot out
where we don't know what the hell is
going on because that's where your alert
and alive and tents and with it and,
and you know,
I think I believe this and I believe
that actually has something to do with
the hemispheric structure of your,
of your,
of the physiology of your brain is
because the right hemisphere looks
roughly adapted to what you don't know.
And the left hemisphere,
this is a very,
this is an over simplification,
but a useful one,
is adapted to the world that you do know
and the right place for you to be as
halfway between them.
Because that,
and you can tell that that's what's so
cool and this tells you that this is
actually reality that's manifesting
itself.
Do you know that sense of active
engagement you have in the world when
things are working well for you,
you know where you're.
Where are you should be at the right
time.
You're alert and on top of things and
engaged and you don't have much of a
sense of time and the sense of the
tragedy of life sort of recedes and
that's when you're.
That's when you've got one foot,
when it's where it's secure in one foot
out in the unknown and your brain
signals to you that you're in the right
place by making what you're doing
meaningful.
And that sense of meaning is actually a
neurophysiological signal,
but you've got forces of the cosmos
properly balanced in your being at that
moment.
And that's why it feels so good and it
will.
What else could it possibly be?
I mean,
you know,
our,
our brain is capable of looking beyond
our vision.
That's what it's for and that sense of
engagement.
There's no reason to assume that that's
anything but a real signal and you can
reduce it.
You could say,
well,
the problem with being where you know
only is that you don't know everything
and that's going to be a problem in the
future.
And the problem with being where you
know nothing is that's just too much
man.
Like you know,
you go into panic mode and because
anything can happen there and you can't
handle it,
so you got to mediate between those two
things.
You want to be secure enough so that
your physiology isn't revving out of
control and you want to be out there in
the unknown enough so that you keep
updating yourself constantly,
constantly,
and that's,
that's the place where information flow
is maximized and you know that because
that's where you are.
When you're having a really interesting
conversation with someone or you're
gripped by a book or you're really into
a movie or maybe something that you do
as a,
uh,
you know,
apart from your work or maybe even in
your work,
you're into it and that's because you
are in the right place at the right time
in your whole nervous system is
signaling that to you.
And I would say that's the sort of place
that you should be all the time.
If of course you can't be because no
one's perfect,
but it's,
that's,
that's the recreation of paradise on
earth.
It's something like it because you are
in the right place at the right time.
When that is happening,
subject to certain,
what would you say?
Restrictions that we can talk about
later.
Well that's what this guy is doing and,
and that's I would say akin to the
action that God is taking when he's
transforming the chaos of potential into
habitable big.
And it's the sort of thing that human
beings are supposed to act out and God
said,
let the waters under heaven be gathered
together into one place and let the dry
land appear.
And it was so god called the dry land
earth and the waters that were gathered
together,
he called Seas and God saw that it was
good.
Well,
that's an interesting thing too,
because you know,
there's this,
there's this play written by a German
named Gupta.
I can never say that properly.
It's Johan van g o e t h e,
and I can't say it,
but he wrote this play called Faust and
he wrote one part of it when he was
quite young and then files to when he
was quite old and he has a character in
there,
Mephistopheles and Mephistopheles the
devil.
And he actually has the devil explain
himself twice,
basically using the same words,
which,
which I really like.
It was very profound.
And basically girth is memphis awfully
says,
you know,
he's the adversary of the word.
That's a good way of putting it,
um,
because that's how it works out.
Mythologically,
he's the figure behind the snake in the
garden of Eden,
which is something we'll talk about
more,
but he has a.
He has a sophisticated philosophy.
He's not just some random maker.
He's got a.
he's got a deep philosophy and his
philosophy is quite straightforward and
it's compelling,
and people are gripped by it quite
often,
far more often than they think and his
philosophy is,
well,
look around at the world.
It's like an I then Karamazov in the
brothers Karamazov when he's trying to
disabuse his younger brother of being a
a,
a Christian monk.
Mephistopheles says,
well,
look at the world.
I mean,
all you look around the world,
it's nothing but a blood bath.
It's just suffering everywhere.
Everything eats everything and people
die terribly and they're cruel to one
another and the whole mess is nothing
but a constant hall of terrible carnage
in and ruin and,
and,
and rec.
He says it it be better if it was never
existed at all.
And that's a very interesting.
That's a very,
very interesting idea.
And I do believe,
and I've seen this in people many times,
that in the depths of despair,
especially when you've been betrayed,
for example,
and you wander into the wrong
subdivision of the underworld,
that's something that comes to mind if
you have a very sick child,
for example,
or maybe your whole family is suffering
as whole families do.
Sometimes an idea is going to come to
you.
It's like good God,
who put this message together and is it
really worth it?
Is it really worth this suffering?
Suicidal people,
you know,
they say no,
they say no enough of this.
You know,
and you have to be pushed along way.
Generally speaking before you'll
actually commit suicide.
You have to be in very,
very desperate straits.
But your answer under those conditions
is that being is such that it would be
better if it had never been.
And that's a very,
I think,
I think it's a very.
It's a terrible philosophy,
I believe because I think what happens
if you acted out is that you make the
very things that lead you to despair far
worse.
And I can't see that.
If it's reasonable to draw a logical
conclusion that suffering should justify
as your desire to make being in that the
answer to that can be to produce more
suffering.
It just doesn't make sense.
And my observation has been that people
who act out the Memphis too,
feely and philosophy inevitably make
suffering far worse and so and then that
raises the specter of well do they
weren't being just to cease or are they
just out for bloody revenge at every,
at any cost.
And my conclusion has always been that
is that the mask is well being shouldn't
exist because it's too terrible,
but the true motivation is I'm going to
make everyone suffer as much as I
possibly can before I say goodbye to
this place.
And if you read the writings of people
like the kids who showed up the
columbine high school,
they'll tell you exactly that.
That's precisely and exactly what they
concluded and then acted out.
So anyways.
But in this God says that it was good
and I've thought about that a lot is
like because the question is something
like,
well,
is it something better than nothing?
Because that's a really good question,
you know,
and I,
I thought about two things in
relationship to that and one is,
one is,
well maybe it depends on how it is that
you are right,
because it could be that there are ways
of being in the world that justify the
world and their ways of being in the
world that make the world unbearable.
And I believe that the narrative that
runs through the biblical stories is
precisely a dialogue between those two
types of being.
And the optimistic part of the story is
that being requires limitation and
suffering.
There's no escape from that.
But there are modes of being that allow
that to be perhaps even more than
tolerable.
Perhaps there are modes of being that
allow that to be good and it's a
straight and narrow road.
It's a very difficult road to tread.
So,
so I think,
well,
that that's possible.
You know,
I'm not an optimist by nature and,
but uh,
that's,
that's one of the things that I've
conceptualized and read about that I
actually find plausible because it's
certainly the case.
Everyone knows this,
that there are ways that you can act and
make things worse.
Everyone knows that,
and so if that's the case,
there has to be the opposite,
right?
There has to be ways that you could act
that make things better and obviously
you can act in ways that make things
really way worse and so the question is,
well,
are there ways that you can act and make
things really much better?
And I think that's the question is can
we have our cake and eat it too?
Can we have the being that requires
limitation and suffering and also
simultaneously transcend that by our
mode of being and I believe that the
biblical stories and perhaps not only
the biblical stories,
but the biblical stories,
are they human?
Imagine one of the human imagination is
best attempts to address and answer that
question.
That's what the entire story is about.
So the first of it is the catastrophe of
the collapse of self consciousness and
the entrance of humanity into history
and the rest of it is okay,
now we're in history.
Now we know that we're going to die.
We know about our mortality,
we're conscious of our own being is
their emotive acting in the world that
allows that to be justifiable or maybe
even more that allows that to be
triumphant and then I would also say
maybe it's worth finding out.
You know that that's the other thing
that's so interesting because you've got
this short time on earth and there's
lots of things that are very,
very difficult to contend with and and
you have the problem of tolerating
yourself even in all your insufficiency.
And one of the things that seems to me
to be the case is that if you adopt a
sufficiently profound motive being,
if you attempt to do that,
then the mere act of lifting up that
weight is enough to justify the fact
that you're insufficient and mortal and,
and,
and bound by tragedy.
And I believe that and I believe people
believe that because if you watch how
people act,
they look for people they admire and
they do admire people,
right?
It's a natural.
It's a natural phenomena.
You see it starting with children being
children admire and then they imitate
and we looked to people who seem to be
able to bear the burden being in a
heroic manner and there's something
inside of us that calls to that and that
makes us want to mimic that and to
follow it.
And I think that that's.
I think that that's the deepest and most
profound of instincts.
And I think it's right and even if
you're not so convinced on the positive
and you know,
because it's more difficult to be
convinced of the positive,
you can certainly be convinced on the
negative end because there are ways of
being that are so brutal and so
reprehensible that merely to read about
them is enough to traumatize you.
And I think that if you're a person who
hasn't lost their soul completely,
you can't help but encounter stories
like that and shudder away from them.
And you know,
Alexander Solzhenitsyn,
who,
who was the person who did most
unmasked,
the absolute horrors of communist
totalitarianism,
said that he believed that the Nuremberg
judgments were the most important event
of the 20th century.
And that was the judgment at the end of
World War II,
that there were certain actions that no
one was to undertake no matter what
their cultural background was because
they were,
let's say,
crimes against humanity that there was
such a thing as universal evil and you
can debate that,
you know,
and,
and people certainly have.
But the problem is,
is if you debate that,
then you have to say that there are
conditions under which the sorts of
things that happened,
say in the concentration camps,
which would be the gassing of children
after their torture and,
and they're,
they're forcible removal from their
parents and all the terrible things that
went along with that,
that that's just okay.
It's just an opinion.
It's just something that happened and
there are circumstances under which
that's justifiable if you,
if there's no transcendent,
good and evil underneath that argument,
it's only a matter of practicality.
And,
and,
and it seems to me that that's,
that's not the right conclusion to draw.
That's how it seems to me.
And that's what the units and concluded
when he looked at the Nuremberg trials.
So the notion that the notion that it
was good,
well even if you don't believe that and
you know,
because maybe it's not as good as it
could be,
I would say it's incumbent on you as
someone who participates in the process
of,
uh,
furthering creation to act as if it
couldn't be good at least.
And to further that with,
with all of your efforts,
partly because what the hell else do you
have to do that could possibly be better
than that,
that could possibly justify your
existence.
More than that.
And you know perfectly well if you,
if you,
if you have any sense at all,
if you think clearly about it at all,
is that that's what you want to see in
everyone else.
You know,
it's,
you're,
you're desperate and maybe you're
cynical and now and then someone appears
that acts at least momentarily,
like a light in the darkness and that
lifts your spirit up and gives you a
little bit of hope and maybe helps you
continue on.
It's well,
that's obviously a call to being.
It's,
it's a,
it's a statement from your own soul that
says,
well,
there's something about that.
That's how you should be,
and maybe then,
well,
we get a chance to,
to participate in what is good.
I've thought too,
you know,
well,
we'll leave that for a little later.
And God said,
let the earth sprout vegetation plants
yielding seed and fruit trees bearing
fruit in which is their seed,
each according to its kind on the earth.
And it was so and the earth brought
forth vegetation.
Plants yielding seed according to their
own kind and trees bearing fruit in
which is their seed,
each according to its kind.
And God saw that it was good.
There was evening and there was morning
the third day.
I like that.
That's,
you see,
it's interesting these old pictures say,
because if you look,
here you go,
you got this halo around God's had and
you've got the split again between night
and darkness and God's right on the
border between the two.
And that's the sun,
right?
That's what,
uh,
that's what a halo is.
A Halo is the sun or the moon.
Sometimes it's like a coin,
you know you have the Queen's head on
the coin and that's the queen on the
moon and it's and it's silver and it's a
symbol of value because of course the
queen is sovereign and the moon is the
sovereign of the night.
Sky and gold of course is the sudden and
gold is pure because it doesn't mix with
other metals and it shines like the sun,
so it partakes of the son and God
partakes of the sun because there's
something about whatever he represents
that's associated with consciousness and
illumination and enlightenment.
And it's that force of illumination.
Enlightenment that's right on the border
between these two sets of phenomena.
And that's.
That's kind of what that picture is
trying to present.
And so you know,
it's a metaphor.
That's one way of thinking about it,
but it does again allude to the
underlying idea that there's something
about consciousness that's integral to,
to being itself.
And God said,
let there be lights in the expanse of
the heavens to separate the date from
the night and let them be for signs and
for seasons.
And for days.
And for years,
I mean,
that's a,
that's a remarkable bit of a bit of a
writing there too,
because you just think about how bloody
long it took our caveman ancestors to
look at the night sky and start to
figure out that there were repeating
patterns across years that enabled them
to mark the seasons.
I mean,
I just can't imagine how they figured
that out.
It's that the degree of careful
observation that it took.
And I mean,
we know people figured that out a long
time ago because,
uh,
you know,
those great megalithic monuments,
like stonehenge seemed to be
astronomical observatories essentially.
And you'll see the same thing with the
pyramids.
I mean,
people were looking at the damn sky
trying to figure out,
looking at God,
you know,
because that's kind of what you're doing
when you're looking at the night sky
trying to figure out the regularity to
order in the universe.
And that's all compacted into this
little light,
you know,
and let them be for signs and for
seasons to be oriented by the stars.
Amazing.
And then let them be lights in the
expanse of Heavens to give light upon
the earth,
and it was so and God made the two great
lights,
the greater light to rule the day and
the lesser light to rule the night and
the stars and God set them in the
expanse of the heavens to give light on
the earth to rule over the day and over
the night.
And so there's an idea of sovereignty
there too,
right?
That,
that,
that there's an analogy between the
ruler and the and the heavenly bodies
that that light up the light up the
darkness essentially.
And that's a really interesting idea too
because it took us a long time to come
to terms with,
as I mentioned last week,
to come to terms with the idea of
sovereignty itself and to decide what
constituted valid power.
And it's not power.
It's not power.
It's authority and competence and not
power.
It's not dominance either.
It's more sophisticated than that
because the people that you want to rule
aren't people who have power because
power just means I can hurt you and you
can't hurt me back.
That's,
that's not that,
that's not what you need from a ruler,
even though devolves into that from time
to time.
What you want is the kind of wisdom that
illuminates the darkness and to
associate the sovereign with the,
with a heavenly kings of the light is a
perfectly reasonable thing to do from a
metaphoric perspective.
That's an ancient,
ancient idea,
you know,
and another example of how we're
grounded in a dream and God set them in
the expanse of heavens to give light on
the earth to rule over the day and the
night and to separate the light from the
darkness.
And God saw that it was good.
Now their emphasis on the fact that it
was better,
that there was something than nothing.
And you know,
maybe you could,
maybe you could consider that the
declaration of the cosmos is something
like,
well,
it's better that there's something than
nothing and well,
how do you know that?
And I guess the answer to that is that
there's something instead of nothing.
And I know that that's not proof,
but,
but it's still a remarkable fact that it
happens to be the case.
And no one does know why that is and so
maybe we should go along with it and see
what we can do with it,
you know,
and see how we could make it better
because we certainly could if we were,
if we were really committed to it and we
shook our resentment and our,
our anger and our hatred and I know
there's reason for all of that because
people do suffer terribly,
but you know,
God only knows what being could be like
if we all contributed,
it,
contributed to it to the best of our
ability.
God only knows what we could conquer and
what sort of magnificent cities we can
produce and what things we could we
could eradicate from,
from,
from the suffering of the world.
Thanks.
And there was,
you know,
there's this guy I read about this,
this is amazing and I don't remember his
name,
but he,
he found out about this worm that was
called the Guinea worm.
And Guinea worm is a really horrible
thing and you can look it up if you
want.
But I'll tell you a little bit about it
even though it's very distasteful.
So Guinea worm is a parasite that lives
in Africa to burrows under your skin and
it's quite long.
It's about that long and it's about that
wide and so it'll burrow underneath your
leg and then it's in there,
you know,
and maybe it posts this little head out
a whole,
which is one of its delightful
tendencies.
And then if you want to pull it out it
breaks,
right?
Because obviously otherwise you'd just
pull
it out and it would be dead and so it
doesn't like that.
So it just breaks off and many,
many people had this horrible disease,
you know,
and did it while you can,
you can't imagine what that would be
like because you're a part of the one
percent and you live in North America
and thank God for that.
But you know,
just a little.
Imagine you don't even want to think
about it,
let alone habit.
And he went to Africa and wipe the damn
thing out.
It's like crow.
Great.
You know,
it seems to me the planet,
it's a lot better off without any Guinea
worms on it.
Even though that's like Guinea worm
genocide talk.
I'm still,
you know,
pretty happy about it.
And so that was,
that was one guy who thought,
well,
we don't need these things and yeah,
well fair enough.
Yeah.
Well,
so good for him.
Like,
you know,
I mean he can die thinking that the
world's a better place than it was when
he first popped out and so,
so good for that.
That's,
I think that's a good.
That's a good aim,
you know,
I think is to think that when you're on
your deathbed and you can look back and
think,
well there's a little less suffering in
the world from here on out.
Then there would be if I had never
existed and that's a lot better than the
opposite because it's certainly
possible.
Say if your stolen to ensure that there
is a hell of a lot more suffering in the
world and there would have been if you
hadn't lived and we perfectly well know
that people can manage that and that
many,
many people try to do nothing but manage
precisely that.
So.
And it's hard for me not to think about
that as some sort of metaphysical evil
and I think it's the right way to look
at it.
And there was evening and there was
morning the fourth day.
So you have the sun here and then the
moon here as far as I can.
Yeah.
Actually I think this is the moon over
here.
Right?
But,
so yeah.
And that's part of the Sistine Chapel,
which is,
you know,
an absolutely remarkable.
No part of the reason too,
in the part of the reason I'm teaching
about these biblical stories is because,
you know,
I'm thinking because the humanities have
been decimated so badly.
And,
and,
and again,
I think that has mostly to do with
resentment and hatred more than anything
else,
but I don't really think that you can
get a grip on the humanities and what
they have to offer without knowing the
biblical stories because they're the,
they're the dream out of which the
humanities emerge.
And so unless you have that background
knowledge,
that dream,
then there's all sorts of things that
are utterly profound that don't open
themselves up to you.
And Dante's inferno would be one of
those Milton's paradise lost,
which is an absolutely amazing piece of
work.
I mean,
Milton wrote it because he wanted to
justify the ways of God to man,
you know,
what an ambition that is.
And I mean he was serious about that.
He took the problem seriously.
It's like it's the Memphis to feely and
problem is that,
well,
this is a rough business that we're
involved in and you know,
maybe maybe we should just give it up.
I think the world,
the whole world I think was deciding
that in the 19 eighties when we were
deciding whether we're going to engage
in the ultimate nuclear catastrophe,
you know,
and we were very,
very close to that a number of times and
I think it was a decision in some sense
on the part of humanity that we might as
well keep the whole awful game going
rather than just demolish it.
But,
um,
but you know,
Milton,
he wrote paradise lost too.
It's dream again.
It's a dream.
And trying to explain the nature of
being in the nature of evil and you
can't crack the damn thing without
knowing the underlying stories.
And that's really too bad because it's
utterly profound and the reason you need
profound things as far as I can tell you
need profound knowledge is because life
is actually a profound problem for
everyone.
I mean you can shelter back and live a
very conservative existence and look
like more power to you.
I understand why you would do that,
but it doesn't stop you from having to
face the ultimate questions of life
right there,
right there in everyone's face and at
least at some point in your life.
And it would be better if you could.
I think if you could confront them full
on and end to deal with them properly
and to be a beacon of strength as a
consequence of that.
It's and it's.
And I think that wisdom,
that's what the humanities are supposed
to teach.
His wisdom and wisdom is what enables
you to deal honorably with the tragedy
of life.
And I think you.
I can't see how you could think that
that was a bad idea because they're
going to be times when you're in an
emergency room and you know,
prone to panic and to and to cry and to
break down into and to collapse and to
be of no use to anyone around you and
that's not the right way to be.
It's the right way to be in a situation
like that is too strong and reliable and
I don't think you can do that without
being wise and you can't be wise without
putting yourself together without
knowing something about where you came
from and what you're like and that
that's history and the humanities.
And so this isn't optional.
It's,
it's more necessary.
The man does not live by bread alone and
that's exactly the issue here.
So you see these magnificent works,
you know,
I mean there's a,
there's,
it's not like Michelangelo thought of
this literally,
you know,
he was a genius for God's sake and he's
trying to get at something and he's
trying to get at the profundity of human
culture.
I suppose that's why you have this
patriarchal figure here and that the
cosmic role,
that consciousness and tradition plays
in being itself and it's ennobling and
you know what you think.
People religious or not people,
hundreds of millions of people come from
all over the world to Rome and go
through this little tiny chapel to look
at this.
There's something in it that everyone
needs to see.
You know,
it's not just beauty.
It's more than beauty.
It's,
it's that which feeds the soul and and
everyone feels that even if they can't
explain it so and God said,
let the waters swarm with swarms of
living creatures and let birds fly above
the earth,
across the expanse of the heavens.
So God created the great sea creatures
and every living creature that moves
with which the waters swarm according to
their kinds and every winged bird
according to its kind.
And God saw that it was good and God
blessed them.
Saying,
be fruitful and multiply and fill the
waters in the seas and let birds
multiply on the earth.
And there was evening and there was
morning the fifth day.
And God said,
let the earth bring forth living
creatures according to their kinds
livestock and creeping beasts,
creeping things and beasts of the earth
according to their kinds.
And it was so and God made the beast of
the earth according to their kinds and
the livestock according to their kinds
and everything that creeps on the ground
according to its kind kind,
right?
That's kin,
And to be kind is to treat others as if
they're your kid.
And so according to its kind and God saw
that it was good.
That's continually continually,
um,
re presented over and over.
God said that's the thing that calls
being into existence.
And God said it was good.
And that's the fundamental judgment
about the nature of reality.
And you know,
one of the things that happens in the,
in the translation,
in the movement,
let's say,
from the Old Testament to the New
Testament,
is God is obviously blessing creation in
the beginning of this story.
And then you have old testament God and
like don't mess around with him,
right?
Because he'll give you a good smiting if
you get out of line.
There is no doubt about that and he's
kind of an arbitrary character and you
know,
lots of modern people think,
well,
how could you believe in a God like
that?
And it's like when I read that,
I think,
well,
the Old Testament people that isn't how
they thought.
They thought you better look the hell
out because life is really difficult and
if you step out of line,
you're going to get flattened and God
doesn't care in some sense whether you
approve of him.
It's like,
what the hell does that have to do with
anything?
Obviously you don't approve.
It's like you better pay attention
though because otherwise you're going to
be in real trouble and that there's real
wisdom in that niche of thought that it
nature really admired the old testament
as a work of literature because he
thought that the representation of the
divine,
let's say as a representation of,
of the essential nature of being was
extraordinarily accurate and it's
arbitrary and often cruel.
Nature wasn't following a morality that
human beings could really understand as
moral,
but he thought that was very realistic
and I like that interpretation.
But what happens in the New Testament is
quite interesting because there's an
insistence all of a sudden in the new
testament that you're supposed to act
towards God as if he's nothing but good,
and that's such a strange thing because
you know,
you look at the world and you think are
really just good a well,
the cancer and the earthquakes is kind
of hard to fit into that picture and you
know,
the terrible things that happened to
children and all of that is very
difficult to square with the notion of a
good God obviously.
But then there's the under.
The underlying idea is that if you act
in that manner,
it makes it more likely to be true.
It's something like that.
And so it's that I would consider that
in some sense,
inactive,
both courage and faith.
It's like you're going to make the case
like God makes at the beginning of the
Bible.
That being is in fact good.
Now you can't see it because you get to
see all the things about it that aren't
so good.
That's not the point.
It's a metaphysical presupposition.
Something like that.
It's an.
It's a decision to act that way.
I'm going to act as if being as good and
to further that,
and then the implicit idea is,
well,
there isn't anything.
There isn't any way that you can make
things work out better than to do that,
and so there's a current courageous
element to it,
which I think has also expressed to some
degree in the idea of Christ's like
voluntary sacrifice of his own life.
His presupposition was something like,
I'm going to act as if God is good and
I'm going to play that out right to the
end and now that becomes something like
a divine pattern and I believe there's
wisdom in that because again,
most of the time that I've been
wrestling with this sort of thing,
I've always been looking at the
opposite.
I haven't been studying good.
I've been studying evil because evil is
easier to believe.
Especially after the 20th century.
It's like I think you have to be.
You have to be blind not to think about
the things that happened in the 20th
century as evil and and some of the
things that happened were so brutally.
It's just absolutely unimaginable and
well,
unless you imagine it and and it's,
it's,
it's right there.
It's part of the historical record and
then I think,
well,
if there's something that that's,
that's that terrible.
It indicates as clearly as anything can
that there's also something that's its
opposite and that's whatever it is
that's the farthest away possible from
that outcome.
Now that doesn't mean we can exactly say
what it is because it's easier to grip
in some sense what it means to torture
and break and hurt and not to be able to
conceptualize so clearly how you would
have to act if you are acting in the
exact opposite manner,
but at least it implies that it exists
and I see that pattern being laid out in
this dreamlike manner in the new
testament and it has something to do
with it.
Well,
it has something to do and this is for
sure with the,
with the voluntary acceptance of
mortality,
because of course that's the poisoned
apple,
right?
The fact that everybody looks forward
into the future to know that your finite
and so as everything that you love and
it's very difficult for that not to
poison your existence and while there's
no getting out of it as far as we can
tell,
but there might be something like
switching your attitude to it and you
could say,
well,
that's the price you pay for being and
they're heroic thing to do is to accept
that and not even to accept it
grudgingly to say,
all right,
I'm going to go along with that.
I'm going to accept that and I'm going
to act nonetheless as if being is good
and then I'm going to see how things
turn out.
It's something like that and God saw
that it was good and so it's an act of
courage,
right?
There's a,
there's a,
there's an act of courage that's
associated with that transformation of
attitude and even with regards to the
notion that the world is good.
It's a courageous attitude,
especially given that there's so much
evidence that makes that conclusion
difficult to continually draw,
but the alternative seems to me to be
far worse.
So there's God again with the sun behind
him because he's associated with the
solar consciousness and he's creating
all these strange,
wonderful creatures and,
and you know,
it's a.
and people say,
well,
you know,
the idea of God as a,
as an old man in the sky,
let's say that's primitive.
It's much more better to think about it
as a much more better Jesus anyways.
It's more sophisticated to think,
to think of the divine essence as a
disembodied spirit or something like
that.
But you know,
that's not.
So that's not so obvious either because
as I already pointed out,
there isn't anything that's more
complicated than a human being.
And,
and so the idea that the divine is
something that's at least as complicated
as a human beings strikes me as
something that's actually quite
reasonable.
And I know it's a metaphor,
although I don't know to what degree it
is a metaphor and it's also something
that's embodied.
And I really,
that's also a very interesting notion,
you know,
because it's become increasingly obvious
as we've tried to do such things as
produce artificial intelligence,
that it's very difficult to produce an
intelligence or perhaps a consciousness
that isn't the embodied in some manner.
It,
it can't be just,
it can't be just a spirit,
a spirit without form.
And I think that's part of the reason
too,
why Christianity put so much emphasis at
the end of time on the resurrection of
the body.
Because there,
there's,
there's a,
there's a drive in there too.
He noble to ignoble the idea of the
body,
not just the spirit,
the consciousness that floats abstractly
above the body,
but to say that knowing you can't do
that,
you can't just shed that part of you
that's heavy and materials,
so to speak,
and leave it behind as if it's of no
value.
You have to ennoble ennoble that as
well.
And that idea is also linked to the note
to the representation of God as as a
human being and as a wise human being
and as something that's embodied and so
for,
at least from the metaphorical
perspective,
I don't think it's reasonable just to to
brush your hands across it and say,
well that's,
that's primitive because I don't think
it is.
I don't think it's primitive at all.
And then God said,
let us make man in our image after our
likeness.
And it's our.
Because while this is,
this is part of the priestly story,
there's,
as I said,
a number of sources for the old
testament and in the priestly version,
if I remember correctly,
it's below him.
That may be wrong.
It doesn't matter,
but the precisely it doesn't matter
because the notion is is that the God
who's in the background of this story
has a kind of plurality of being right.
And it looks like the idea of monotheism
arose with great difficulty across time.
Because there are lots of powers.
And the idea that there's a power of
powers was something that it wasn't easy
for people to figure out,
you know,
and it because what's what's constant
across sources of power or some kind of
mega power,
but it's hard to figure out what that is
and that's what's being represented by,
by the movement,
as far as I can tell from polytheism to
monotheism.
It's,
it's the first,
the observation that there are powers
that determine the destiny of people,
at least in part that you're,
that you're subject to.
And then the idea that there's something
common across all those powers that you
can represent,
partly say with the idea of the Sun
rising in the morning and finding its
way out of the darkness at night and
that that's associated with
consciousness and sovereignty is very,
very see.
One of the things that bothers me about
simple minded atheism and I would say
the simple minded atheism is of the sort
that regards these stories as nothing
but simple superstitions is that it's
very,
very poorly informed because whatever
these stories are,
they are not merely simple
superstitions.
They weren't conjured up by some cabell
of priests to bamboozle the masses even
though they were used for that purposes
from time to time.
It's.
It's much,
much more complicated than that.
They have a very ancient lineage and
they're tied together with all sorts of
other stories and there's.
There's an emergent wisdom in them and
and I think the right way to view them
is as the birthplace of sophisticated
philosophical ideas and so you have to
wrestle with these stories.
You can't just,
you and I said already that I'm going to
be as rational as I possibly can in my
discussion of these stories and not
refer to anything metaphysical except
when that's absolutely necessary,
even though I don't want to eliminate
the possibility of a metaphysical
reality because I think that's
premature,
but,
but you have to take the story seriously
if you're going to,
if you're,
if you're going to approach the problem
properly,
you can't just casually dismiss them.
It's not appropriate.
And so,
so let us make man in our image.
That's a very interesting idea and like
I said,
it's not easy to understand how it was
that human beings came up with the idea
that US lowly creatures were so with the
Mesopotamians for example,
and the Greeks were like this to human
beings,
weren't God like they were the play
things of the gods,
right?
They were.
They were just the gods just tortured us
for their amusement,
you know,
love and hatred and anger and all those
powerful forces.
We were just.
We were just playing things to the gods.
There wasn't anything particularly
divine about us.
The notion that that in some sense we
partake of the divine is that's a
staggering idea and you don't want to
underestimate the difficulty that there
was an abstracting that or the utility
of that idea for our current mode of
being,
let them have dominion over the fish of
the sea and over the birds of the
heavens and over the livestock and all
the earth and over every creeping thing
that creeps on the earth.
So God created man in his own image,
in the image of God.
He created him,
male and female.
He created them.
That's interesting because there is more
than one creation story in genesis and
in this story,
males and females are basically created
at the same time.
Later Eve is extracted out of Adam and
we'll talk about that,
but not here.
It's the two sexes are generated
simultaneously and they both carry
within them the divine stamp,
which is very egalitarian,
very
appropriate,
and I think unbelievably advanced that
that's what it looks like to me and God
blessed them.
Well,
that's a good thing and God said to
them,
be fruitful and multiply and fill the
earth and subdue it and have dominion
over the fish of the sea and over the
birds of the heavens and over every
living thing that moves on the earth and
there's God creating Adam and eve and
they're looking pretty happy about the
whole thing.
And that's Michelangelo's famous Sistine
Chapel Representation.
And there's some cool things about this.
I mean,
you've got to wonder is this.
This is an aside and I don't know if
it's a credible aside,
but it's an interesting aside,
so that's,
that's a form of credible.
What the Hell is God doing?
In this thing,
no,
I mean,
what is this exactly?
And,
and so,
so there's,
there's been some interesting answers to
that and this is one of them.
So there was a group of scientists about
20 years ago that,
that were remarked on the precise,
the precise analogy between this
structure and the brain bisected down
the middle.
And of course Michael Angelo was one of
the first people who did detailed
dissections.
And so they felt that,
that Michelangelo had put God inside the
brain for some reason.
And uh,
that seems to me to be associated with
the notion that there's,
you know,
there's a,
there's an analogy or a metaphorical
identity between the notion of whatever
God is and the structures that give rise
to consciousness.
And uh,
I think we really underestimate the
degree to which consciousness is,
is both same,
miraculous and an not understood.
I mean,
you know,
you,
you have what appears to be an entirely
material substrate.
Yep.
Here you are aware and self aware and
able to generate the world merely in
some sense by looking at it.
It really is remarkable and that
consciousness is dependent on,
on something that wells up from deep
within that material substrate that we
don't understand at all.
It's,
it's really,
uh,
it's crazily remarkable thing.
You know,
when you hear,
you hear a lot about scientific
reductionism,
but I'll tell you something that's kind
of interesting and it's a tangent to,
you know,
the guy that discovered Dna,
I think it was Watson and Watson and
crick,
but I don't remember who wrote this
book,
but one of them
I don't remember which one,
he believed the DNA was so complicated
that it had to come from space.
He didn't believe it could have possibly
evolved on earth.
And so like a lot of these people who
are used as exemplars of scientific
reductionism aren't like that at all.
When you actually read what they had to
say,
right.
They,
they were very aware of the limits of
their own knowledge.
And I mean DNA is something really quite
spectacularly remarkable.
It's an eternal substance.
It's been around for a very long time.
And the idea that we understand it is a
very stupid idea.
And I would say that I would say that
the same thing applies to the brain.
Like we're,
we're,
we're scratching away at the surface of,
we don't understand at all.
And so it's quite interesting.
I think that,
and maybe Michelangelo had enough gall
to do that,
it's certainly possible.
I mean,
he had enough goal to do dissections
when the,
when the cost of that was death,
you know,
he had this rob corpses essentially to
go and do it.
So he was,
he wasn't,
I would say,
not particularly politically correct.
So.
So that's kind of interesting.
And there is another representation of
the same thing.
And that's a funny one.
I had to throw that in.
I don't know how many of you know this,
but there's,
there's,
there's this joke in the atheistic
atheist community.
I think it might've been started by
Richard Dawkins,
but that might be wrong,
that it was just as reasonable to
believe in the flying spaghetti monster
as it was to believe in God.
That's the flying spaghetti monster by
the way.
And,
and,
and so that's,
that's called touched by his noodly
appendage and anyways,
it's fun.
It's not very sophisticated,
but it is funny so and God blessed them
and God said to them,
be fruitful and multiply and fill the
earth and subdue it and have dominion
over the fish of the sea and over the
birds of the heavens and over every
living thing that moves on the earth.
God said,
behold,
I have given you every plant yielding
seed that is on the face of all the
earth and every tree with seed in its
fruit,
you shall have them for food and to
every beast of the earth and every bird
of the heavens and to everything that
creeps on the earth.
Everything that has the breath of life I
have given every green plant for food.
And it was so and God saw everything he
had made.
And behold,
it was very good and there was evening
and there was morning,
the sixth day.
Thus the heavens and the earth were
finished and all the host of them.
And on the seventh day,
God finished his work that he had done
and he rested on the seventh day from
all his work that he had done.
So God blessed the seventh day and made
it holy because on it,
God rested from all his work that he had
done in creation.
And I like that too.
You know,
one of the,
I did a lot of counseling work with
people who were coaching work I guess
with people who were fairly
spectacularly successful and they were
usually workaholics,
you know,
they're the sort of people that were
like,
they work 80 hours a week just nonstop.
That's just what they were like.
And one of the things we're always
trying to figure out was,
well,
how much should you work?
Because one answer is you just work til
you die,
right?
I mean you just exhaust yourself and
while that's not,
that's not a good idea.
And then you have to figure out why that
isn't a good idea.
It's got to be something like this is
that you don't want to do so much work
that the amount of work you do
interferes with the amount of work that
you could still do,
right?
Because if you work like mad for two
weeks and then you have to lie in a
hospital bed for a month,
that obviously isn't very productive,
so you have to figure out how much you
can work diligently and then how much
you have to recuperate so that you can
get back up and work again.
And you know,
that's.
People have basically settled on
something like this and given it the
divine imprimatur that that's one way of
thinking about it,
which is,
well,
you can toil away for six days and no
wonder because you have to work,
but you should rest at least one day out
of seven because otherwise while you
don't appreciate life,
that might be part of it.
And plus I think it's more a matter of
iterative interability,
you know,
because one of the things that defines
morality is the capacity to repeat
something,
right?
So if something is properly structured
in a moral manner,
then you can do it over and over and
over again without any degeneration.
And so that's kind of like a
relationship.
If your relationship is negotiated,
you can continue to negotiate it and
then you can have a relationship that
lasts for a long time.
You can do it today and next week and
next month.
The next year you could maintain it
across time,
and this I would say is the wisdom
that's been associate that's been
garnered over God only knows what period
of time to say,
well look,
I mean even God needed to take a break
and appreciate what was going on and
it's not such a bad thing for people to
follow that pattern and that's a good
thing for modern people to know because
we seem to be.
Even though you know we're very wealthy
by historical standards,
our capacity to relax isn't exactly what
it could be and I think that's really
hard on people.
Okay,
so I'm going to go over again the idea
of the attributes of God.
I talked about that a little bit last
week,
but I want to return to it because I
think it's worth.
It's worth dwelling on a little bit
because we're trying to figure out what
it is that people were trying to
formulate when they were formulating
these representations and we've sort of
come to the conclusion that there there,
there is an attempt to abstract out the
nature of power from specific aspects of
power and there is some attempt to
associate that with consciousness as
that which gives rise to being itself
and there's some attempt to associate
that consciousness with something that
has a cosmic quality,
whatever that might mean,
and and it's a statement that it has a
cosmic quality rather than rather than a
discovery.
It's a mere statement that there's.
That there's something about
consciousness that has world generating
significance and also the implication
that it's associated with human beings
as well.
It's a very.
It's a very interesting set of
propositions and I don't believe that
there simply refutable it.
It's a perfectly coherent argument even
though it's primarily made
metaphorically and so then once again,
I want to build up the,
the framework of associations around the
idea of God.
One of the things that Freud did when he
was interpreting dreams and it's quite
useful,
you know,
so if someone comes to me with a dream,
then I have them tell me the whole dream
and then I get them to repeat it line by
line and then whenever they say a line
and it there's an object in it or a
person or something like that.
I asked them what that makes them
remember or what that thing means to
them or what comes to mind.
And that's the associational technique.
And it's predicated on the idea that
your memory works by association and you
know that if you're daydreaming,
you know you go from one thing to
another,
like a conversation and that
you can take an idea that's at the
center of a web of associations.
And by tracking the associations you can
kind of zero in on what the idea might
meet.
And then you expanded that by trying to.
He called it to amplify the dream by
thinking about about narrative or
literary or mythological similarities
that that might be associated with the
narrative structure of the dream.
And I think often that can be
unbelievably useful,
you know,
and it's like the dream is an idea
that's trying to come to birth.
It's,
it's partly formulated.
And then if you discuss it and amplify
it,
it's like you can speed along its
transformation into a more articulated
idea.
And the dream is also something that
because your brain,
your mind is trying to work with one
foot in the unknown,
it's trying to formulate what's out
there in the unknown and to make it
concrete.
But it doesn't do that in one fell
swoop.
It doesn't just take potential and turn
it into two articulated ideas.
It has to dream up what's out there
first projects,
it's imagination out there to get a
handle on what it might be.
And then that's presented in the dream.
And if you analyze the dream you can
make it more articulate.
And so that's what we're going to do
with the attributes of God to,
to build up the representational
structure a little bit.
So.
So the hypothesis is that God is an
abstracted ideal,
formulated in large part to dissociate
the ideal from any particular
incarnation or man or ruler.
And the underlying idea there too is
that when the ruler becomes the ideal,
the state turns into the biblical Egypt
and the biblical Egypt is a tyranny.
And so there's a very,
very solid idea in the old testament
that I think took people.
God only knows how long to figure out
that if you transformed,
if you confuse the notion of sovereign
sovereignty with the current sovereign,
then your culture immediately
degenerated into totalitarian state and
turned to stone and that was deadly than
you were slaves.
And then the thing was going to collapse
as well.
Like no matter how big and grandiose,
as soon as the ruler became the concrete
incarnation of the ideal,
there was no distinction between the man
and the divine notion of the ideal.
Then the society was doomed.
And I think that that's a less.
I think that's why I think that's true.
It's just,
it's simple as that.
And I think we saw more than enough
evidence of that in the 20th century and
we're certainly seeing the same thing
repeating itself now,
when the ruler becomes the ideal of the
state,
turns into the biblical Egypt and the
biblical Egypt as the architectural
tyranny.
So what is God like?
Well,
from the Christian perspective,
there's three elements.
One is seems to have something to do
with tradition.
And so that's God the father.
And that's partly the embodiment I would
say,
of of the human being.
And that's an ancient,
ancient thing.
And it's also partly the embodiment of
the tradition of human beings,
which is also a very ancient thing.
And that's the structure.
As I said,
it's the structure that consciousness
emerges from that enables us to grapple
with the unknown as such.
And then there's,
there's the intermediary between that
and,
and Christ say that's the Holy Spirit,
that's that bird.
And that's the spirit in a more abstract
sense.
And I,
I would say that's probably as close as
Christianity ever got to the notion of
consciousness as such,
you know,
disembodied consciousness,
something like that.
And then there's the notion of the
suffering individual and,
and that's,
that's a very complicated idea and it's
something like in order for.
So there's this idea,
an old idea,
and I believe this was originally a
Jewish idea that something with the
attributes of God,
omniscience,
omnipresence and omnipotence lacks
something.
So it's like a Zen Koan.
It's a really interesting idea because
well,
what in the world can something like
that lack and the idea is limitation.
So something that's everything lacks
limitation and bounce that idea.
Like when I first encountered that just
blew me away.
I thought it was such a,
such a brilliant,
brilliant realization that there are
advantages to not being able to do
things because partly because it gives
you something to do.
I suppose that's,
that's a big part of it,
right?
Is If you,
if you had everything you wanted to have
at every moment at your fingertips,
well that,
that's there's,
there's nothing,
there's no story.
It's funny,
you know,
because that happened to superman,
the cartoon character by the 19
eighties,
he could juggle planets and you could
bounce like hydrogen bombs off them.
And be fine,
it's like everyone got bored because,
well,
what were you going to do to superman?
It's like you have a hydrogen bomb.
Adamant,
he just brushes it off and like combs
his hair and that's the end of that.
And the whole cartoon series basically
died because he didn't have any flaws.
There's no story without the limitation.
And I think that's an absolutely
remarkable idea.
And so part of the notion of Christ,
and this is something that I've puzzled
over for a long time and I learned a lot
of this from youngest,
that there's idea in Christianity that
there's consciousness as such,
which,
which in some senses eternal.
It stretches from the beginning of the
time to the end of time,
but it's this abstract notion,
but it lacks a certain kind of reality
because it's not instantiated somewhere
not.
It's not instantiated in a specific time
and place in history.
And so the idea of the sun,
the third part of the trinity or one of
the three parts of the trinity is the
notion that tradition and consciousness
as such also has to be embedded in
history in a particular time.
And place,
and so there's the archetypical
embededness and that would be the
incarnation and that's the perfect man,
right?
Who accepts his mortality and that acts
in a virtuous manner,
but it's an uh,
it's,
uh,
it's the archetypal story of every
individual as well.
And you know,
there's a very strong strain in
Christianity.
I would say this is more pronounced in
Orthodox Christianity,
that the,
that the purpose of that,
the proper path of life is to take the
tradition,
let's say,
and the spirit that's associated with
consciousness as such,
and to act it out in your life,
in your own personal life,
in a manner that's analogous to the
manner in which Christ acted out in his
life.
And what that means in part is the
acceptance of the tragic preconditions
of existence.
And so that's partly betrayal,
betrayal by friends and by family and by
the state.
And it's partly punishment for sins that
you did not commit to as well as the
ones you did commit.
And sometimes that's just a relief,
but you know,
the arbitrary nature of justice and also
the fact affinity dude.
And the notion is,
is that your duty,
let's say,
and the way to set things right in the
cosmos is to accept that as a necessary
precondition for being and to act
virtuously despite that.
And that's a very,
very powerful idea as far as I'm
concerned.
And I'm also,
you know,
the world's a weird place and I've seen
some very strange things in my life.
And one of the things that I've seen is
that,
you know,
I've dealt with some people who were
very,
let's say that they weren't on a good
path,
let's put it that way.
And one of the things that was really
interesting about being around people
like that,
it was almost like they were surrounded
by a gravitational field of sorts.
I'm speaking metaphorically,
obviously,
and their worldview is so warped and
twisted that if you came within contact
of them,
you all of a sudden started to play a
part in their drama.
And it was almost inevitable.
They would maneuver and manipulate and
interpret in a way that made you into
the villain in their story.
No matter what it was that you wanted to
do.
And unless you've encountered something
like that,
and many of you probably have you,
you don't know how powerful a pole that
is.
And so it's certainly possible that
someone can act in like,
like a,
like a gravitational object and ben
things around them to fit their
narrative.
They're unhappy and tragic narrative.
But I've seen the opposite too,
you know,
were people who were,
were aiming upward with the best of
their ability and because of that they
had a positive effect on the people
around them and,
and that,
that,
that and that ordered things around them
in profound ways.
And I think it's an open question.
The degree to which the cosmos would
order itself around you properly if you
got yourself together as much as you
could get yourself together.
And I,
I mean we know that things can go very,
very badly wrong if you,
if you do things very badly wrong,
there's no doubt about that.
But the converse is also true.
If you start to sort yourself out
properly and then you have a beneficial
effect on your family being,
first of all,
that's going to echo down the
generations.
But it also spreads out into the
community and we are networked together.
You know,
we're not,
we're not associated linearly,
we all affect each other.
And so it's an open question.
The degree to which acting out the
notion of,
of the notion that being is good and the
notion that you can accept its
limitations and that you should still
strive for virtue.
It's.
It's an open question.
How profound effect that would have on
the structure of reality if you really
chose to act it out.
And I've seen things as I said in my
life that indicate that I do believe
there's a metaphysical element to life
as well as the rational,
practical element.
And I think there are times when those
two things come together and I've seen
that happen and so I don't think we know
the limits of virtue.
I don't think we know what true virtue
could bring about if we,
if we aimed at it carefully and
practically.
And so the notion that there is
something divine about the individual
who accepts the conditions of existence
and still strives for the good.
I think that that's an idea that's very
much worth paying attention to and I
think the fact that people have
considered that idea for at least 2000
years quite seriously is also an
indication that there's,
there's at least something to be thought
about with in relationship to that.
So that's kind of the trinitarian idea.
Same idea there.
And do you see this is.
It's interesting too because you have.
Here you have God the father essentially
who's who's coming out of this strange.
You see this isn't the sky.
Exactly,
and you see this very often in these old
pictures.
It's not exactly the sky.
Whatever the heaven was that,
that,
that people believed in.
It's something that's.
It's like the sky opens and there's a
dimension beyond the sky.
It's something like that,
and I wanted to show you this too,
just to show you that this isn't only a
western conception know when it has
something to do with mystical experience
because there is a bar to satisfy.
It kind of looks like he has a hat,
but that's not a hat.
That's a whole bunch of bodhisattvas
going back to we turn it right and this
hole in the sky here is like a whole
into time and these things are recurring
across time.
It's the eternal recurrence of this,
of this redemptive archetype and the sky
opens up and you can see that thing
recurring and recurring and recurring.
Same ideas.
Basically.
That's the Blue Buddha whose a healing,
who is the healing entity sitting in a
Mandela,
which is like a representation of
paradise and it's the same idea.
It's like reality opens up and reveals
this image of perfection.
And so it's a.
well,
it's a universal conception and,
and while I think it's a representation
of the,
the,
the possibility of the metaphysical and
the physical coming together in some
sort of,
in some sort of communication.
It's something like that.
Anyways,
and I mean you have to remember that
there's absolutely no doubt that people
have metaphysical and religious
experiences.
That's an absolute fact.
You can induce them chemically.
You can reduce them electrochemically.
Lots of people who have epilepsy have a
epileptic pro dramas that are associated
with divine enlightenment.
So does the Esky for example,
he had,
he had epilepsy and that was really,
I think one of the things that made him
a great author because Dostoevsky would
have this feeling that he was going to
have an epileptic seizure and he said
that the feeling for him was that the
world was opening up and he was becoming
more and more and more enlightened and
he was just on the verge of grasping the
essence of existence.
And then he'd have an epileptic seizure
for the subjective feeling.
Was that that much knowledge was just
too much for him to bear.
Well,
you know,
you can say,
well that was a neurological abnormality
and fine,
you know,
but God,
he was Dostoevsky,
you know,
and so you can't just brush that off.
So
yeah.
Well,
so that's the trinitarian idea.
Fundamentally.
And this,
this notion here is the notion that,
well the crosses crosses a funny thing
because the cross marks the center,
you know,
and it's an x and the x is the center of
the world,
like the x that the cathedral is and
it's the center of the world is where
you are.
Because as a consciousness,
you're the center of the world.
That center of the world is a place of
betrayal and suffering and limitation.
That's that's exactly what it is,
and the question is,
well,
given that and given the fact that you
know it,
what the hell are you supposed to do
about it and what that represents?
I believe that's Goya.
What that representation implies is that
you're supposed to voluntarily accept
that and then move forward on
well in good faith and with courage.
That's the notion and that you're
supported.
You're supported by your tradition and
that's why you need your tradition too.
That's why you need to be embedded in
your tradition because without that,
without the support,
let's say of your father and I mean that
both practically and metaphysically,
without that behind you,
without the knowledge of you as both a
biological and a cultural creature,
without that depth of knowledge you
can't hate,
you don't have the courage to do it
because you don't know what you are,
what you could be,
and so without that,
because you're a historical creature,
you know what students ask me sometimes.
Why study history?
It's like,
well,
because history is about you.
That's why it's like history tells you
who you are.
You can't tell who you are because you
only live a little while.
How the hell can you figure out who you
are so you need all this collected
wisdom and all this dream like
information and all this mythology and
all this narrative to inform you about
what you are beyond what you see of
yourself and you know you're pummeled
down and people picked on you and
there's 50 things about you that are
horrible and you know you've got a self
esteem problem.
You're sort of hunched over and you've
got all these problems.
You know,
and so it's not easy to see.
Let's say the divinity that lurks behind
that and unless you're aware of the
heroic stories of the past and the
metaphysics of consciousness,
let's say.
I don't think that you can have the
courage to regard yourself as the sort
of creature that could stand up
underneath that intense existential
burden and move forward in encouraging
grace.
And of course that's part of the reason
that I'm talking about these biblical
stories.
And it's 9:30,
so we're going to have to stop.
Thank.
Okay.
So we're going to stop exactly at 10
tonight because that,
that's the deal with the theater people.
And so,
um,
besides I'll be out of anything
intelligent to say by that point,
certainly so.
Well,
at least we got through one story.
So that was good.
So
let's give everyone like to,
you know,
just a few seconds to settle down and
everyone who wants to leave can leave.
So thank you for all,
all for coming.
By the way,
I'm constantly amazed that,
that,
you know,
everybody comes and listens to this
because you know,
it's just,
well,
it's strange,
let's put it that way.
So,
so far it's been fun though,
so that's good.
Okay,
let's go.
I opened that works.
Hi Dr Peterson.
I was raised Catholic and any time there
was a bit of a,
an inherent contradiction,
let's call it,
in the document to the Bible,
it will be referred to as a mystery.
And there's one mystery I've always kind
of wondered about,
and it's very important to genesis,
how do you,
how do you deal with a perfect God or
the conception of a perfect God,
who by nature isn't capable of an
imperfect design,
are incapable of a perfect design?
So what I mean by that is many religions
present,
for example,
good and evil as separate deities that
preexisted simultaneously.
What's interesting though,
Christianity,
is that Lucifer,
the embodiment of evil in the Christian
religion is an outgrowth of God and is
sometimes the Milton for example,
presents him as a rebel against his
interpretation of God's tyranny.
Right?
Another example,
you know,
we,
we didn't touch on,
um,
even today,
but in paradise supposedly perfect
garden,
a perfect design is infiltrated again by
that evil outgrowth of a so called
perfect God.
So from a psychological perspective,
do you think there is a significance to
this presentation of perfection,
yet the contradictory flaws that are
sort of naturally part of that
perfection.
Hold on,
quote,
Kol.
So good.
That's a good simple question.
We're starting to see you.
He was Kinda Manichaean in his approach
and he,
he,
he tended towards thinking that evil in
some sense was a separate entity.
You know,
when I thought about that for a long
time because there's a potency about
evil that just can't be brushed away and
not.
I mean,
I mean this most practically,
as I've said,
I went in for people in my clinical
practice,
I've,
I've dealt with many people who are
touched by malevolence and there's no
other way of,
of,
of stating it properly and this happens
a lot to people who have posttraumatic
stress disorder,
like they encountered someone that
wanted to hurt them for the sake of
hurting them.
You know,
it wasn't some misunderstanding.
You can forget about that.
It wasn't that at all.
And so to,
to deny the reality of evil in some
sense I think is the ultimate naivety.
Even though it's a word that you won't
hear used,
for example,
very often in universities anymore.
But I just,
that just,
I just can't understand that at all.
But.
But I thought about that lot and so I'm
gonna kind of answer that question by
hitting it scatter shot.
The first thing is that there's an idea,
and this happens in Milton,
is that comes across in Milton,
that distance from God is hell right?
That,
that hell doesn't actually have any.
I know it's ambivalent in Milton,
but,
but the fundamental claim seems to be
that the farther you get from God,
the more it's hell.
And then there's another idea that
Milton,
Satan,
who's Lucifer,
the bringer of light,
right?
He's God's highest angel,
God most wrong.
And I kind of think about him as the
spirit of rationality,
of intelligence.
It's not because I'm not an admirer of
intelligence because hooray for
intelligence.
But one of the things that that Milton
seemed to cotton onto before the rise of
modern totalitarian states was that
intellect has the capacity to fall in
love with its own creations and to
elevate them to the highest place,
which is basically a totalitarian claim.
It's like what I know is everything that
needs to be known and if it was only
manifest in the world,
the world would become a utopia and I
also think that's.
We'll talk about this next week.
I also think that that's the core idea
behind the tower of Babel.
Remember the tower of Babel is raised by
human being so that the pinnacle will
hit heaven and so it's the idea that we
can build a structure that makes the
transcendent unnecessary.
And so okay,
so there's those two things.
Then there's,
there's an idea of freewill that's
associated with it too,
and it seems to me that in order for
there to be good there has to be evil.
And so I think the answer is something
like this,
is that in order for there to be being
there has to be limitation in order for
their good to be good.
There has to be the possibility of evil.
I think the right path is to exist such
that the possibility of evil remains
open,
but that you choose the good and I don't
think that evil per se is built into the
structure of the world.
I do think that that's human.
I think that evil is human and I think
it's understandable.
I did a lecture that's online about the
distinction between evil and tragedy and
tragedy seems to be built into the
structure of the world and perhaps you
can blame God for that.
I mean,
it doesn't seem to me that it's your
fault that the earthquakes for example,
but,
but it is not obvious to me either that
it's tragedy that takes the spirit out
of people.
I think that human beings are actually
equipped to deal with tragedy,
but we're not equipped to deal with
malevolence that destroys people.
And so I think that I think that
metaphysically speaking,
the world is structured so that people
have a choice between good and evil and
that.
So then the next question is why do we
have a choice and that that's where my
knowledge runs out.
I don't.
I don't like the alchemists,
for example,
speculated that the Orthodox Christians
also follow this line of reasoning is
that human beings in some sense are
furthering creation by our actions and
our choices and I think there's
something to that.
It's like it's like creation is
unfinished in some sense and that we're
participating in,
in moving it in whatever direction it is
that we want to move it,
and part of that is that we have
freewill and part of that is that we
have the choice between good and evil
and that's also was all associated with,
with the significance,
maybe the cosmic significance of our
lives and I blood that strikes me as
plausible and I think the weight of
responsibility that people feel
existentially as an indication of that.
So that's about the best I could do with
that.
So,
and it seems the way you're describing
it,
it's built into at least the text that
you presented because one of the other
things I had noticed was God
consistently describes creation is good,
right?
Creates light,
it's good,
he creates dark.
It's good after he creates things,
he announces that he creates man and
woman announces that they have dominion
over those things and can use them,
and it might be something lost in
translation,
but that is described as very good.
As soon as that dominion is brought into
existence,
you might speak to that notion of
furthering.
Well,
here's something interesting too,
and we'll develop this a lot,
is that you see when Adam and eve eat
the fruit and the snake gives him the
fruit,
the first thing that happens is their
eyes are opened.
To me.
That means that while they've woken up,
right,
they've,
there's been an increment in their
consciousness and the next thing that
happens is that they recognize that
they're naked.
Okay?
And to recognize that you're naked is to
recognize that you're vulnerable and
human beings are strange creatures
because most animals are like this and
they're protected,
but not us.
Like our most vulnerable parts are
displayed for Harman,
for everyone to observe,
right?
So we've got that sort of bipedal
selfconsciousness built into us,
but what's really interesting is that
when Adam and eve realized that they're
naked,
it's the same moment that they know the
difference between good and evil and
that God,
that just,
I just ground away on that for years.
Trust if they can.
What the hell is,
is what's going on here?
What's the relationship between
consciousness,
knowledge of nakedness and the knowledge
of good and evil.
And then I think,
I think I figured it out,
I think,
I think it was that you see when you
know that you're vulnerable and they
also develop knowledge of death,
right?
So there's deep knowledge of
vulnerability and they get embarrassed
about that.
They cover themselves up,
right?
So that's culture.
So it's a very profound shock for them
to recognize that they're naked.
It even makes Adam hide from God.
Then they developed the knowledge of
good and evil.
Well,
I think it's because you see human
beings have this peculiar capacity that
no other creature has,
which is,
I know how I can be hurt because I'm
aware of my own limitations.
Painfully aware and now because I know
how I can be heard,
I know how you can be hurt and I can
take advantage of that and that's I
think how evil enters the world.
That's what it looks like to me.
It's like I've got this expansion of
knowledge.
It says in genesis that that,
that,
that gives people another attribute of
divinity.
Knowing the difference between good and
evil as it has nothing to do with
animals and it has nothing to do with
Adam and eve prior to having their eyes
opened,
but that the cosmos switches when that
self consciousness manifests itself and
that's when the possibility of evil
enters the world.
It's something like that and that's also
echoed by the intimate relationship
between the snake in the garden of Eden
and Satan,
which is we go into because that's what.
That's a very strange associations like
the snake all also becomes the adversary
of bea and I think that's all jumped
very quickly into that,
but I think that's because you know,
there's the snake that bites you in the
jungle and then there's the snake that
lives in your enemy.
And then there's the snake that lives in
your family,
if you've,
if you've banished the enemy to the
Netherlands,
and then there's the snake that lives in
you.
If you remove yourself from your family
and that snake that's in you,
right?
That's,
that's a,
that's a psychological phenomena that's
equivalent to transcendent evil itself.
The thing that inhabits every single
person.
That's why there's that association
between the snake and Satan.
And that's why I think that people have
this.
It's associated with our knowledge of
vulnerability that gives us this
constant capacity for,
for evil being.
Imagine if you're a medieval torture,
you know what I mean?
People don't generally imagine that sort
of thing,
but,
but people were medieval torturers and
they were very good at what they did and
the only way that you can be a torturers
to know what would hurt you,
right?
And so you exploit your own
vulnerability,
exploit the knowledge of your own
vulnerability to bring pain into the
world.
And I don't think that you can lay that
precisely at God's feet.
Now people have been arguing about that
for a very long time.
But,
but my,
my question,
the question for me that arose from that
is,
all right,
fine,
like tragedy.
You can lay that at God's feet.
Well,
if we didn't bring additional evil into
the world,
could we tolerate the tragedy of being
without becoming corrupt?
And I think generally the answer to that
is yes,
because I've seen people react quite
heroically to the arbitrary burdens of
their life,
but malevolence man,
that,
that lays the low,
it lays the low and it seems to be to be
nothing but a destructive force.
And I do believe as well,
and I think you see this indicate
enabled story,
that the root of malevolence is the
desire for revenge against God for the
creation itself.
And I,
I mean I've read terrible things written
by terrible people trying to get to the
bottom of things.
And I mentioned the columbine killers
for example,
and it's clear.
All you have to do is go read what they
wrote.
What they were doing was taking revenge
against.
They knew that it wasn't unconscious,
that they'd been dwelling on this for
months plotting the revenge and it was
revenge against being itself for the
crime of being so.
Thank you.
Hi,
Dr.
you'd said when God saw that it was
good,
you read that as potentially well might
be better than nothing.
And the story in genesis,
it's bracketed by days,
which aren't necessarily literal days
yom,
the original word,
but it's also bracketed by and he saw it
was good,
you know,
at the end of the day.
So my question is,
is there something more profoundly
happening there between this profundity
of speaking into existence?
The way to start is to this observation,
the seeing that it's good and are we,
is God modeling consciousness is a
little more there for us to do,
to grapple with.
Okay,
so.
So go more for us to grapple with.
In what way?
In the sense that we have this amazing,
this insight of speaking things forth,
but you'd also commented on
consciousness as until something's
observed during until,
until it's seen.
So when God sees that that creation was
good,
is there.
There's kind of this bracketing between
the bringing forth through the sport
when you know,
through the word through Jesus.
Okay.
That's good.
I see what you mean.
Okay.
Well,
I think.
I think what that is is that I think,
okay,
so it's perfectly reasonable from an
architectural and psychological
perspective to consider the idea of the
word equivalent to the spoken truth
being Christ makes that claim in the New
Testament,
but he's the truth.
Right?
And embodied.
And so then you can logically,
you can derive from that the idea that
if things are spoken into being through
truth,
then they're good.
And so yeah,
I think that that association exists and
I think that that's.
Well,
I also think that that's in some sense
the deepest claim of faith.
I believe that because I think that I
think you have to make a decision in
your life as far as I can tell,
and I think kierkegaard knew this more
clearly than anyone else I've ever read
in is if being is good,
then an honest relationship with being
also has to be good and then if you have
an honest relationship with being,
then you're going to speak the truth and
then I think what you have to decide is
that speaking,
if you speak the truth,
then what happens is good regardless of
what happens and that that's that.
That's the rub of faith and I think
that's something that kierkegaard
wrestled with,
you know,
and that,
I mean,
I'm trying to think if I
can provide an example about,
about that.
It didn't need an easily and quickly.
Well,
I guess it's partly because it's partly
because you can live your life two ways.
You can,
you can,
you can use your language to manipulate.
You can use your language as a tool to
get what you want,
but the problem with that is that that
assumes that you know what you want and
that you're right and that's a problem
because there's lots of things you don't
know and if you get what you want,
you may find a that you didn't really
want it and be that you're not the
person that started the journey towards
that.
That happens a lot to people,
especially when they use their language
in a manipulative way,
and so the alternative seems to be,
and I think this is one of the lessons,
for example,
it's laid out in the movie Pinocchio,
which happens to be a kind of
archetypical favorite of mine.
Is that part of the act of faith,
let's say,
and then I wouldn't say Christian faith
necessarily.
I would say faith and being itself is is
the decision,
the decision that God is good.
The decision is there's no better way to
bring better being into being then to
speak the truth,
and I do think that's echoed.
I think that's a very wise observation.
I think that's echoed in that first
story,
first of all,
they active speech and second,
the observation that the consequence was
good.
So yeah,
thank you.
Good morning.
Citizens Peterson first have a bunch of
questions and the one that had them
answered immediately like you have a
post on quora in which you encourage all
children to incur skateboarding
injuries,
but also stated in this post you wrote
that,
do not try to rescue someone who does
not want to be rescued and be very
careful about rescuing someone who does.
And can you reconcile this with what you
stated about transcendent morality and
the heroic impulse that I guess men are
supposed to be
born with.
Okay.
So,
um,
well the skate,
the skateboarding question is I wrote,
I have a book coming out in 2018 called
12 rules for life,
an antidote to chaos.
And one of the chapters in there is from
that cora posting and it's called don't
bother their children when they're
skateboarding.
And it's sort of associated with what I
had said earlier about Parker for
example,
is that,
you know,
kids need to go out and push themselves
against danger because that's what life
is,
is pushing yourself against danger and,
and when you see kids doing things that
are dangerous but spectacular,
then you kind of have a moral obligation
to back the hell off and let them
experiment with their own mortality
because you can't keep them safe.
The best thing you can do is make them
able and courageous.
And,
and I would say that that's a more
difficult lesson generally speaking for
mothers to learn then for fathers to
learn.
And that was Freud's fundamental
observation,
but it's,
it's absolutely crucial.
And so I've seen do,
I mean,
you know,
you can obviously be a full on a
skateboard,
although the distinction between being a
fall and developing yourself as not as
clear as people might like to imagine.
And when kids are out there with no
helmet and doing dangerous things,
it's like there's a part of me that of
course is very worried about it.
But there's another part of me that
admires it very much because they're
practicing what they need to practice in
order to cope with the world.
Okay.
So there's that.
Now the other one was rescuing people.
Yeah.
Well,
I got this partly from Carl Rogers.
[inaudible] rogers was,
he's a clinician of very famous
clinician and and he,
he was,
he was a Christian missionary to begin
with,
but he didn't end up that way,
but he was very interested in the
utility of listening as a,
as a means of redemption.
Essentially.
Listening by the way,
is if you have someone that you know
that has a problem,
the best thing you can often do is
listen to them if they're actually
trying to communicate because people
configure themselves through speech and
most people can't think.
And I don't mean that in a mean way.
I mean the way they think is by talking
and they can't talk unless they have
someone to talk to.
And it's partly because they're bouncing
the idea off them and seeing if it makes
sense and seeing how the person
responds.
So listening is a great thing,
but Rogers was also interested in the,
in the preconditions for having a
redemptive relationship and that could
be a therapeutic relationship or an
intimate relationship and one of the
things he claimed was that unless the
person was aiming upward,
there was nothing you could do about it.
That and that seemed to be associated
with this idea of that initial choice,
say between good and evil.
So once someone comes to therapy,
they've already done something,
they've already said,
I have a problem,
conceivably I could fix it and I need to
do something about it.
And then so half the work is already
done by the time they show up because
they've already said,
well,
things aren't as good as they could be
and I could do something about it.
The question is,
can you do anything about someone who
isn't at that state?
And my observation,
and this is Roger's observation as well,
is that you can't.
I think you can serve by example,
but until the person has decided on
their own that they're wrong.
That's why they're suffering.
And if there's something wrong about
what they're doing and that they want to
fix it,
I don't,
I think that even trying to hammer
against that often makes it worse.
So,
and I know that soul Schnitzel,
when he was talking about the communist
ideologues,
the really hardcore communist ideologues
that were eaten up by the Gulag
archipelago system,
you know,
sort of devoured by their own.
He saw the same thing,
was that until they were willing to
admit that something was wrong with the
manner in which they had construed the
world,
that it had resulted in their own
device,
that there was actually no way of
communicating with them.
They're in kind of an authoritarian
bubble.
And so,
so I,
I don't think that.
So even if you orient yourself as an
archetypal hero,
there's no way you can get through that
barrier.
Well,
I think that that's part of the issue of
freewill.
I think that I do not think that people
can learn unless they admit that they're
wrong.
There was this,
there's this play the cocktail hour by
tsl.
Yet,
here's this woman in the play and she
comes up to a psychiatrist and she says,
just in the course of casual
conversation,
she says,
I really hope there's something wrong
with me,
and of course the psychiatrist is a bit
taken aback by that.
And he says,
well,
why in the world would you hope such a
thing?
And she says something like,
well,
like I'm suffering,
man.
Things are not good for me.
I'm having a dreadful time of it.
And as far as I can tell,
there's only two possibilities.
Either the world in its essence is
conspiring against me and I'm doomed
because what am I going to do about the
world?
Like it's just built into the structure
of reality or I'm doing something wrong.
So I'm really hoping that I'm doing
something wrong because if I am,
then maybe I could fix it and I'd
stopped suffering and it's.
It's something like that and see.
It's also,
I think that if your life isn't what it
could be and you're suffering,
then it seems to me that that should be
sufficient evidence that you don't know
enough,
and if that isn't sufficient evidence
that you don't know enough,
then I don't know how anyone else can
provide you without evidence and so I'm
going to leave it at that.
This is psychological rescue,
not like rescuing someone who's
drowning,
for example.
Yes,
you can rescue people when they're
drowning even if they don't want you.
Perfect.
I'll tell you something about that
though.
Something interesting about that and
that's relevant is that you know,
I don't know how many of you know how
you rescue someone who's drowning.
You do it like this,
right?
You come to them like this and you push
them away with your foot.
If there.
I'm telling you that's what you do if
you're a lifeguard because if they're
panicking and they grabbed you,
you both drowned and that's stupid
because then you both drowned and that's
a really good way.
That's a really good metaphor for trying
to help someone too.
It's like when people are in real
trouble,
you know,
some of it's,
they're confused and some of it is that
their life has collapsed around them and
there's some malevolence there and
there's some desire for vengeance and is
just like one dangerous mess and if
you're gonna wait in there unprepared,
the probability that they're going to
take you down compared to you elevating
them is very,
very high.
You know,
because you don't even know what your
damn psychological stability rests on.
You might be saying just because you're
lucky and surrounded by saying people.
That doesn't mean that you have the
psychological wherewithal to really post
someone up from the depths of the
underworld,
especially if they've also got one foot
inhale so you should bloody well be
careful about doing that kind of thing.
It's,
it's Hubris to attempt it.
And I would,
I would definitely caution people very
carefully about trying to rescue someone
who doesn't want to be rescued.
It's,
it's very dangerous activity and it can
easily be counter productive.
Okay.
So about,
since 2006,
I've been trying to figure out like,
extract the Meta the way you've put it,
of um,
social justice warriors,
and I think I found it actually,
um,
they seem to have this behavior where
they just,
they nebulize every standard we have.
So they take a standard,
you have that handful of criteria.
You say what something is,
is how it is,
like that's a podium,
but it has these criteria within that
place they take,
um,
they do something on nebulization where
they take something of what and they
dissolve the criteria such that there is
no way to say how it is.
So you see this now with gender where
someone will say their agenda,
but there's no way to get logically from
how they can be that gender,
like how you can be an attack
helicopter,
a male or a woman or something like
that.
Um,
but the thing that came from this,
and I figured this out when I found
about you when I learned about you,
is that nebulization appears to be the
exact opposite process of individuation.
Philosophic.
It's the philosophical version of
intuit,
individuation that rests on three
premises are three core axioms,
which is I exist,
which is an axiom that exist in like in
the objective that you exist here,
and then I am,
which is a reiteration of reincarnation
of I exist,
which is basically you have to say I'm
right about having existed or also just
falls apart.
And then you have asked which is the
question,
begged from that.
Well,
if you exist and you're right as what
you're talking about,
God being the metaphor of God in Genesis
being the,
uh,
a metaphor for the creation of
consciousness.
And it appears that individuation
actually fits that triad.
Because if you take ads,
for example,
at the,
as is a,
it's the predictive aspect.
When you try to take the subjective and
make it objective.
So you have an idea,
you test it in reality.
And time is the ultimate arbiter that
determines these things.
And it changes your understanding of
reality.
It gets,
it lets you know God,
it lets you know the objective.
And then from that point,
there's the subjective which is supposed
to be formed from objective reality,
but because you've changed that,
you know have to sacrifice your old self
the old way.
You saw Jordan Peterson of 10 years ago,
it was not who he is now.
So it gets sacrificed and at the same
time you can point back to that guy that
Jordan Peterson and say,
well,
that guy was wrong,
and that's the scapegoating of the sun.
So the subjective aspect,
the I am right as the son and the Holy
Spirit,
which is supposed to lead you to God is
the ass.
And they don't understand that
the relationship between that in the
first part,
the okay,
so can,
can you just clarify that the social
justice aspect and the nebulization
oh,
the social justice is the exact opposite
process of individuation.
That's all it is.
And it actually occurs it as if you're
at and you're thinking,
well,
what am I?
You either apply individuation.
You try to apply criteria.
You had to find out what you are in
reality or refuse that paradigm and say,
well look,
I am.
I'm always going to be right,
I'm completely self righteous and you
stop at that subjective aspect where
everything becomes subjective and you
ultimately become relativistic and
nihilistic.
So I'm asking have you considered that
the genesis tail and the,
the um,
the creation myth and God is actually
the,
is the process of individuation and the
trinity is actually those three core
premises.
The three axioms that come from that.
K,
I haven't considered that.
I mean I know that
[inaudible] draw drew a parallel between
the idea of the passion for,
for example,
and the development of human
individuality.
And so there's,
that idea was,
is lurking inside the union notion of
individuation because it has to do with
voluntary confrontation,
mortality and also with evil,
right?
As,
as two of the key elements of genuine
self realization.
I haven't considered the metaphorical
pathway that you just described.
So I can't comment on that.
I'd have to think about that.
But I could say that one of the things
that does disturb me about the
ideological battle that's going on right
now,
and,
and I think this is a very deep part of
it,
and this is the part that's a battle
against the logos in,
in,
in Dera,
does old terms,
right?
The fellow egocentric West needs to be
taken down to its essence,
is the refusal to engage in precise
language.
And I see that in part,
for example,
manifested in the refusal of the people
who are criticizing.
Do we ever engage in any debate?
They don't believe in debate and they
don't believe in the,
in the,
let's say,
the redemptive power of dialogue,
because mostly what they believe in his
power.
So there's a nebulization in that
manner.
There's this tendency to hide behind
what's vague and foglight instead of
making things sharp and clear and
crystal clean.
And I do think that that's.
Well,
that's part of the degeneration of a
civilization as far as I'm concerned.
So do you haven't considered that then
would you please?
I'll do my best.
Thank you.
Okay.
So one,
this is it.
One more question and then I'll make it
quick.
Okay,
thanks.
Hi,
Dr Peterson.
My question is,
I know you stated in the last lecture
that the importance for setting aims in
life and to kind of have goals,
goals to work towards.
Right?
So my question was,
where do you,
how do you do that if you don't know
where you want to go because that's kind
of where I got stuck on your future
authoring program because.
Okay,
that's a good question.
That's a really good question.
Um,
I think it's echoed to some degree in,
in the structure of the biblical stories
and in this manner.
So there's this notion in the Old
Testament that morality is following a
sequence of prohibitions.
There's a bunch of bad things you
shouldn't do and then basically you're
good enough and,
and,
and I think there's wisdom in that.
I think that's kind of where children
start,
right?
You,
you,
I mean,
I love children and all that,
but they're there.
They're crazy little creatures and they
need to be civilized.
And partly what you do is you,
you lay prohibitions on them and mostly
what you're trying to do is lay
prohibitions on them for the behaviors
that if they manifested,
would make their life miserable.
So I have another chapter in this book
that I'm writing called don't let your
children do anything that makes you
dislike them.
And the idea there is that your,
your job as a parent is to help your
children become sort of four year olds
that adults genuinely smile out when
they come into a room because that makes
the entire social environment both
truthful and welcoming.
And so your job is to make them
desirable.
Social beings and lot of that is
prohibition.
Okay?
There's this ethical transformation and
it happens to some degree in the,
in the tradition of the prophetic
tradition where there is a spirit that
seems in some sense to rise above the
law,
but there's a real transformation
between the old testament and the new
testament.
The Old Testament is prohibition and the
New Testament is,
well,
here's the good things you do once
you're more than merely prohibiting
yourself from,
from impulsive sin.
Let's say there's a positive good to be
accomplished while you might say,
well,
I don't know what the positive good is.
Fair enough,
man.
So,
so this is why this thing that I've said
to people,
it's become this crazy Internet meme,
but that's to clean up your room and
which is a lot better and more useful
than people think.
It's a lot harder to.
But the thing,
the first thing you do,
I think,
and I learned this in part from
Solzhenitsyn when he was trying to iron
out his soul when he was in the Gulag
because he was trying to figure out how
we got there,
how he contributed to how we got there.
You know,
not Stalin and Hitler even though they
were kind of to blame,
you know,
but it wasn't much he could do about
that.
I think what you have to do,
and this is part of humility,
is you have to look around you within
your sphere of influence,
like the direct sphere of influence and
fix the things that announced themselves
as in need of repair.
And those are often small things you
know and they can be like your room,
put it in order because the thing is it
isn't exactly so important that your
room is in order,
although it is.
What's important is that you learn how
to distinguish between chaos and order
and to be able to act in a manner that
produces order.
And in most households there's 100
things that could be done to just make
it less hideous and horrible.
And so practicing that is a real useful
form of meditation.
And it's also,
it's also,
I think it's a divine act because you're
taking chaos and you know,
if you pay attention even to a room,
it's so interesting.
And I learned because I've,
I've renovated many places now and tried
to make them beautiful.
And one of the things that I've really
learned is that even if you own a
structure,
unless you investigated all the nooks
and crannies and cleaned them up and put
your own imprint on them and made them
years,
they're not yours.
The mere fact of physical ownership
doesn't make them yours.
You have to establish a dynamic
relationship with the objects before
they're actually years and I think you
can.
You can do something as simple as just
sit on your bed and think,
okay,
there's probably like five things I
could do today so that tomorrow morning
is slightly better than this morning was
at least,
or at least I'm not falling behind and
those will usually be like having needed
toad in the morning.
Right.
It's like it's not going to be something
you want to do.
There'll be things you're trying to
avoid.
There are snakes essentially,
but if you ask yourself like you're
asking someone,
which I think is a form of prayer,
if you ask yourself,
instead of telling yourself,
you know,
what is it that I could do to set things
more right today that I would actually
do?
It's usually some small thing because
you're not disciplined,
you know?
Then you can go do it and then you put
the world together a little more when
you do that and that spreads out,
but you also put your.
You also construct yourself into
something that's better able to call
order forth from chaos,
and that makes you just incrementally
stronger and then the next day you can
maybe take on a slightly larger task and
like you get the benefit of compound
interest.
If you do that,
it's a tremendously powerful technique
and they think if you do that at some
point,
instead of just having to fix things up
that are not good,
you'll start to get a glimmer of the
positive things that you could do.
You know,
the positive things that you could do
that would actually constitute a vision
and that that's what I would recommend.
Thank you.
Good night.
Thanks.