Welcome to the fence planers.
I'm Danielle crittendon and I'm
Christina Hoff summers and we are
thrilled to have the father of all
mansplainers in our studio today.
I think he's actually more of a man
whisperer.
Yes,
a man whisperer.
I'm the mad genius behind the
intellectual dark web,
whatever.
Welcome to the FIMS planers Jordan
Peterson.
Thank you very much.
So delighted to have you and it's an
honor to have you honor.
It's an Ode to our listeners.
We're recording this in front of a live
audience at the American Enterprise
Institute in Washington DC where
Christina is a resident scholar and
there'll be video of the podcast as well
and we will let you know where to find
that when it's ready and we're also
grateful to Aei every week for the use
of its recording studio for the podcast
and now for an introduction though he
needs no introduction to the people
here,
but Jordan Peterson is a professor at
the University of Toronto and author of
many books and and poster of many
fantastic lecturers and his most recent
book has.
I can't keep track of how many languages
it's been translated into and the sales.
Just a phenomenally successful book
tour.
In fact,
my first question is really about your
tour.
You look pretty good for somebody who's
visited what,
100 cities in the past since January
23rd.
I don't know how you do it and mostly
flying.
What do you do for fun?
What do you ever get to relax in brief
moments and what do you do?
Go on twitter and
good.
Although I've been qualified that is
relaxing and I tried to forestall that
temptation as much as possible.
Well,
I have the automotive bit of time that I
spend with my wife.
She does travel with me and so,
you know,
we've had,
we,
we try to take some time to walk around
the cities that we're in,
um,
and see what we can.
It's,
we're usually not at any given place for
more than a day or two and they're
usually pretty packed up with,
well,
whatever is associated with the lecture.
And then with press that the publishers
usually arrange.
Well,
I heard you interviewed in Sweden in
Stockholm and you were,
you had a half an hour to visit the city
with your wife and you loved it,
but that,
you know,
it's true
breaks where you get them.
Well,
the thing is is that the,
the lecture tour is unbelievably
positive and a lot of this is,
is ridiculously positive,
you know,
like,
so if I'm going out on the streets now
or in cafes or you know,
airports,
I meet people all the time and they're
always polite and they're always happy
to see me and they always have some very
touching story to relate and then the
audiences themselves are very positively
predisposed to whatever it is that doing
together.
And so that makes it a lot easier to
stay motivated and,
and to continue right now.
I mean it's demanding because
everything's scheduled so tightly and,
and I do a different lecture every
night,
every,
every time I go,
I find that amazing because I get a lot
of lectures that I anguish over every
word.
And then I have another one and you go
up without notes.
Yeah.
Well,
I have a large collection of things that
I know what,
how to talk about and usually what I try
to do is to formulate a problem before
the lecture so I'm addressing a specific
problem and then I can track how I would
set up the argument and then I walked
through it,
but part of it's also an attempt to
formulate the argument on the fly,
you know,
to,
to make the question what would you say
to formulate it more precisely and to
make a more precise and engaging answer
and then I can use the audience to judge
whether or not that's,
that's happening.
And so it's also a real challenge to do
that.
So I enjoyed that and it's a excellent
intellectual workout and I've been
recording the lectures and I've been
using fair some of them to write the
first draft of the chapters for my next
book and for books after that.
And so,
you know,
I'm,
I'm able to maximize the,
what would you say that utility of doing
this at each event and my wife seems to
be particularly well suited to traveling
like that.
She actually enjoys it quite a bit and
is a very stable person and so that's
also helpful.
So,
uh,
and,
you know,
it's nice to have an extra brain along
because things are scheduled so tightly
that we don't ever have any room for
error.
Yes.
Well,
we're going to,
I can't,
I don't know how intellectually rigorous
we plan to be with you today because we
know that when ever you on one of these
platform,
you're talking about your ideas,
but on the fence planners,
we want to hear more,
a little bit more about Jordan Peterson,
the man desk desperately and definitely
want to hear about your wife Tammy,
and also you're so well known for your
views on men or how your ideas have been
taken up.
So enthusiastic or by young men,
but we want to talk to about women.
Yep.
That's good.
So,
but
one of the things you and I share is
that we both grew up in Canada.
I promise,
Christine,
I would not do my Canadian accent.
So while you were here,
but you grew up in rural Alberta.
I grew up in Toronto.
Um,
and you are what the country's most
famous guru now since Marshall Mcluhan,
m and a,
but it's the fact that you came from
Canada,
have any effect on your views,
do you think,
has it formed you in any way?
I mean,
what did,
what would it,
what would it be the same if you think
you'd grown in rural Texas?
How is Canada contributed to your
worldview?
She's always looking to the Canadian
Angle Canada.
So in Canada,
well I think is a particular part of
Canada I grew up in probably was
formative to some degree.
I mean the town I grew up in was only 50
years old and the particular part of the
world that I grew up in was really the
last settled part of the North American
prairie.
This was outside of Edmonton,
correct?
Both 400 miles north of Edmonton.
Oh,
400 years.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's right at the tip of the short,
short,
short.
So the prairie,
the prairie stretches up that far north.
It's stretches up farther north in
Alberta than it does anywhere else in
the North American continent.
And so we were at the tip of viable
farming essentially,
and so it was,
um,
it was a new place and it was a rather
raw place and it was,
it was a rather harsh place in many
ways,
especially because of the winter and it
was fundamentally a working class place,
although a prosperous working class
place,
right.
Because most of the industry there was
related to the oil and gas industry on.
Although it was cyclical when things
were good working class people could
make a very good living.
This was during the whole.
Yeah,
that's great.
I to be a kid in 400 miles outside a
small town.
But yeah,
I liked it when I was a kid.
I,
I wouldn't say it was as fun when I was
a teenager.
Um,
but I'm not convinced that,
you know,
the majority of people who are teenagers
necessarily have the most wonderful time
of it.
Um,
I think adults often look backwards at
the pass through rose colored glasses.
I think that's what the cartoonist
trudeau accused Reagan of doing
continually.
Gary,
Mr. No,
no,
definitely not.
Used for it in your book was teenage
wasteland?
Yeah,
what you call it,
but yeah,
but it's Canadianness does.
How does that form you or affected you,
if at all?
Maybe it didn't.
It's hard to say.
I mean I've lived in lots of different
parts of Canada now and and Canada does
quite different.
I lived in Alberta for a while and it
had this particular flavor of existence.
I mean mostly in fairview.
I was striving to leave [inaudible] and
to move ahead let's say,
or two moves,
I hesitate to say up,
but somewhere different somewhere more
urban,
but that's the case with many people.
I mean the small towns all across the
West in theU ,
s and Canada are dying.
They're down to nothing because
everyone's moved to the cities.
I lived in Montreal for a good while and
that was interesting because it was a
very,
very different culture.
It was a culture that was to some degree
stratified by language and by class.
None of that was true in Alberta because
it was so new that there is no class.
Right.
So that was quite
interesting.
You worked what I loved.
I pulled a passage because I think as
you say,
people are born in small places
everywhere and someone to leave and some
don't.
You said I wanted to be elsewhere.
I wasn't the only one.
Everyone who eventually left the
fairview I grew up knew they were
leaving by the age of 12 I knew and my
wife who grew up with me on the same
street knew.
What was that thing?
What would you call that?
What's the thing that makes you want to
leave and sets you off?
Because you point out there was no class
system.
Education was cheap in Canada compared
to them.
It wasn't ego,
it wasn't cost.
It was stopping people from a middle
class or you other
teacher.
And my wouldn't.
My mother was a librarian.
The Bush,
you're trained as a nurse.
So,
you know,
we had a comfortable,
I would say a suburban lifestyle
essentially,
you know,
um,
moderate,
middle class suburban lifestyle.
That's what fair have you looked like?
It looked like a suburb that was built
mostly in the ninth,
say between the 19 fifties in the 19
seventies.
So
the young Jordan and the then young
Tammy,
and you'll have to tell us that story,
how you met but wanted,
wanted more.
Well,
you know,
I think that's one thing that is
different to some degree about class.
Um,
my father and my mother had both left
the towns they were from and they were
forward future looking people and you
know,
most of my friends who quit school and
who didn't attend university,
they didn't have,
they didn't have that sense.
I would say that more developed sense of
a world outside of what they knew.
And the other thing is that my,
my father took us on long trips when I
was a kid.
He was a teacher and so he had summer
holidays and we drove all over western
Canada and down into theU ,
s long driving trips,
thousands of miles.
And you know,
that also gave us the sense that the
world was a bigger place.
But I knew way before I was 12.
I believe that I was off at least to
university.
And I think generally in your family,
if you're liable to go to university,
people don't even really talk about it.
It's just a given that that's what's
going to happen.
It's something that you take in with
every breath almost.
It's,
it's an and it's often an unspoken
expectation and maybe people make casual
reference like well when you go to
college,
but it's not like there's a question
about it.
Whereas if you're from a working class
background,
especially if your family hasn't pursued
postsecondary education that isn't in
the realm of unspoken or spoken
expectation.
And it wasn't like,
like lots of my friends,
including many of them who dropped out
before they hit high school,
they weren't by,
they were by no means the dumbest people
in the class.
Like they were plenty smart but they
weren't oriented towards the idea of
pursuing a career that involved
intellectual.
What intellectual engagement wasn't in
their worldview.
And you know,
when you hear people on the,
let's say more socialist end of the
distribution,
talk about barriers to education.
They are often talk about cost and
sometimes cost is a barrier.
And,
and,
and it's more the merrier.
Yeah.
And it's more of a barrier,
although there's still plenty of
community colleges and state colleges
where you can get educated for a
perfectly reasonable amount of money.
But for my friends,
it was never a reason that money was
never a reason.
They didn't pursue post secondary
education.
It was more like a truncated view of
time,
I would say,
you know,
there was more of an emphasis on the
here and now and there were jobs the
plenty.
I guess there also that.
Yeah.
And well paying jobs,
like it wasn't obvious that you were in
better shape economically to go to
university.
They have.
Yeah.
Well,
especially if you were doing something
like working on the oil rigs.
Right.
But um,
but you know,
that was rough,
cold,
harsh work and it wasn't,
it wasn't once you had an in you could
stay employed,
but it wasn't that easy to land an entry
level job either.
And so,
um,
yeah,
well it was wise for lots of work.
He caused people to work in those jobs
because they were unbelievably
lucrative.
So,
and they should have been because they
were very difficult and dangerous and
frigid cold and,
and,
and rough.
So,
you know,
it's not like the people didn't earn
your money.
Let's just tell us quickly how you met
your wife.
You were,
you met her when you were seven or
eight,
or in grade three and grade three?
Yeah.
And you,
did you fall in love with her in grade
three?
Grade three,
yeah.
And was it mutual?
She wouldn't,
she wouldn't admit it if it was.
There were lots of the boys in grade
three were in love with her.
She had a whole little crew of guys that
were perfectly willing to follow her
around and she was perfectly willing to
exploit that.
She very good at it.
Yeah.
She was very popular.
Little girl.
Wonderful.
That you met his children.
We were friends for a long time.
You know,
we used to play chess together and
croquet and she is a vicious croquet
player.
She would,
I don't know if you've ever played
croquet,
but if it's,
if your balls touch then you can stand
on Ireson wack it and then the other
person's ball will vanish off into the
stratosphere and she liked to knock it
all the way down the street and then
she'd laugh and so she,
she always had a good sense of,
of good vicious sense of humor is one of
the things I actually admired about my
wife when we're not,
when we've had our verbal disputes,
which you know,
have certainly happened.
She can string together a sequence of
insults that.
So hair racing that you have to laugh.
It's like,
did she have brothers?
She did.
She has a brother much older,
eight years older,
but he's quite a peaceful person and she
had two brothers can't seem to get along
with guys where they show love and
affection by
insults and jabs and jeers.
And if you and I had brother and I sort
of learned,
okay,
I can,
but if you don't have brothers,
girls like,
oh,
that's so rude.
That's so,
so she was.
Yeah.
Well,
she,
she has a naturally or maybe case she
came by it naturally in twists.
She lost her father is,
are quite sharp,
witted and,
and,
and um,
well he was a real town character.
He's still alive and he was a real
character in the tone,
real hyper extrovert.
Everybody knew him and he had a pretty
good width on them and she had some of
that while it still does have some of
that,
so she was a side from her humor and her
ability to whack balls and I just don't
want to go further on that description,
that many,
many things that tells us about you.
What else brought,
what else attract.
I mean you've known her pretty much your
whole life,
so some of the other qualities that not
just attracted you but enable you to
sustain.
I mean,
I think every young person in this room
will want to know,
and maybe there isn't one,
but what's the secret?
What's it like to be with someone that
long?
How do you sustain that?
We're fortunate.
Some of it's,
some of it's good fortune.
When I would say this is true,
I've watched people in their
relationships,
no personally for a long time,
but also as a professional because I've
done a lot of clinical counseling and I
mean there's some things that need to be
a given about the relationship.
I would say it doesn't hurt to find the
other person very attractive,
you know,
and that's a mysterious thing where
we're not exactly sure what it is that
produces,
let's say chemistry between people.
Although chemistry is definitely part of
what produces it.
There's subtle things that attract
people to one another that are way below
the level of consciousness.
So for example,
women don't like the older men who have
rh blood factors.
Who if they had children with would be
likely to produce a stillborn infant.
Well that's definitely a category on
match.com.
Well,
it's so strange though,
because you
know,
that's a good question.
And you know,
you know,
by older apparently,
and so there's all wearing Cologne
then it would depend on what type of
Cologne
smell is very
strange sense and it's very deeply tied
to very profound emotions including
memory.
And so you find people attractive for
reasons that you can't always determine.
And so,
so that,
that was part of it.
I mean I've always found her very
attractive and that continues and I
liked her combativeness,
you know,
like I think that there's,
you want someone I think in a
relationship that you can spar with and
it's partly because you have hard
problems to solve and if the person
you're with isn't willing to put forward
their opinion,
then you only have half the cognitive
power that you would otherwise have now.
And hopefully you find someone who's
interestingly different from you,
like not so different that you can't
communicate and you have to be careful
of that.
But interestingly different.
And then hopefully they have the ability
and the will to express their opinion.
And then all,
then it's,
you know,
then then your interests stays
heightened and there has to be that
tension in a relationship.
You know,
people think,
well I want to get along perfectly with
my partner.
It's like,
no,
you probably don't.
You just get bored and then you go
looking for trouble.
And so you want a little bit of trouble
in the relationship and the little bit
of mystery and a little bit of combat of
medicine and the ability to exchange
opinions forthrightly and,
and I trust her,
which is a huge element.
I mean,
when,
when we finally did decide to get
together permanently,
we're both in our later twenties and,
you know,
one of the things that I had learned by
that point and insisted to her about was
that we had to tell each other the truth
and she took to that wholeheartedly,
you know,
and um,
for better and for worse because truths
can be harsh.
Does that include like does this outfit?
Yeah.
Well,
the truthful answer to that is I don't
answer questions that are likely to get
me in trouble.
So my,
I have a son who will answer honestly,
and it's infuriating,
but then I realized if you want the
truth,
talk to Tamworth.
Well that's the thing,
you know,
it's,
it's useful to know the truth is
empowering truth tellers are
charismatic.
And actually both my sons are like
brutally honest,
which is disconcerting.
Yeah.
But it's,
I can see that it has made them very
formidable.
And,
and because of that,
people trust them and friendships and
just,
it gives them the.
And you've written a lot about this.
Well,
you know,
if,
if I tell my wife that she looks good in
an outfit,
she knows that I mean it.
Yeah.
And so there's some utility.
No.
And then if you're silent and say I
don't answer her questions that she goes
and she goes,
well sometimes sometimes,
you know,
she'll say,
do you like this and all Keller that I
don't.
And,
and you know,
and that really
make her happy in the moment.
Right.
But,
but if I do say I like it,
she knows that I mean in,
and you know,
I actually liked her sense of style a
lot.
So it turns out that 90 percent of the
time it's pretty easy for me to say,
look,
I think you look great and mean it.
And uh,
you know,
she's a fairly harsh standard bearer to
like,
she's,
she's insisted that I stay in whatever
reasonable physical shape I happened to
be in,
you know,
that was,
that was something that she's very
demanding of and I would say that it's
the same my side and we've been good at
negotiating,
which is,
you know,
what do you want from a partner?
Fundamentally,
what,
what do you want need,
I mean,
the first thing is that I'll hopefully
you,
like I said,
you're blessed with the fact that you
find each other attractive and I think
it's very difficult for the relationship
to begin or proceed or sustain itself
without that.
But having that,
then what do you want?
While you want someone that you can
trust,
you want someone that you can build a
view of the future with and you want
someone that you can negotiate with.
And that's very hard to negotiate with
people because they have to tell you
what they think.
They have to know what they want or
figure it out.
They have to tell you what they want.
They have to be satisfied when they get
what they want,
which is also a very difficult thing to
manage and you have to continually
update that because your life goes
through different stages and well in
your attraction wanes as we all know it
are
agent live not fatally necessarily for
yourself but but no,
but you will go.
I mean you will not be 25 forever so.
So that that has to be renegotiated.
Yeah,
well when you have to work at that too,
you know,
and that's something that people also
don't understand because they tend to
think that,
well,
the that all romantic interaction should
be spontaneous.
It's like,
well,
if that's your theory,
then you might as well just give up
right now if you're going to get married
because that like the only reason you
can think that is because you don't have
enough responsibility to make romantic
entanglement virtually impossible.
And what happens when you're married,
especially when you have little kids,
is that,
and you both have a job,
let's say,
is you're so busy that the probability
that you're going to find time for
spontaneous mutual interaction is
decreased to zero.
And so if that's what you're hoping for,
then you're never gonna have it.
And so what you have to do is you have
to make time for each other and you know
if you're dating,
when you're establishing a relationship
while you put some effort into it,
do you know you,
you decide that you're going to go out
for dinner and you dress up to some
degree and you know you try to present
yourself to each other in some halfways
mutually acceptable manner and you hope
that there's going to be a positive
consequence of that,
that you're going to find each other
attractive.
But then as people somehow think that
once they're married,
that the same amount of effort isn't
necessary.
And that's wrong.
I would say more effort is necessary on
the same front end.
And you have to think it through.
It's like,
you know,
if you don't want to be bitter about the
intimate element of your relationship,
how much time do you have to spend
together each week,
and my,
my rule of thumb sort of derived from
clinical observations is that you need
to spend 90 minutes a week with your
partner talking and that means you're
telling each other about your life and
staying in touch,
you know,
so that you each know what the other is
up to and you're discussing what needs
to be done,
keep the household running smoothly and
you're laying out some mutually
acceptable vision of how the next week
or the next months are going to go
together.
Right?
So that,
that keeps your narratives locked
together.
Like a,
like the strands in a rope.
You need that for 90 minutes or you
drift apart and you need to spend
intimate time together at least once a
week and probably more like twice.
And that has to be negotiated.
And if you don't negotiate it and if you
don't make it a priority,
then it won't happen in all likelihood.
And then,
well,
well then you don't have it.
And that's a catastrophe because there's
not that many things in life that are
intrinsically,
what would you say,
engaging and meaningful and pleasurable
and also bonding all of that.
And if you let that go,
then well part of you dies and part of
the relationship dies and while then
there's always the possibility of
becoming attracted by alternative
entanglement,
which,
which you would do if you had any spirit
left.
Right?
I mean that's the thing is if,
well,
if you're not,
if you're.
If your relationship at home is entirely
unsatisfying sexually,
what are you supposed to do with that?
Nothing is supposed to just bear it in
one way.
The answer is yes because it's your
marriage,
but another way as well,
that's all the fight you've got in you.
You're going to just let the erotic
element of your life die and accept
everything that goes along with that
because you're not willing to cause a
bit of trouble to ensure that it's
maintained and you know,
and we're not very good at thinking
these things through consciously.
I mean,
people are bad at negotiating period as
far as I can tell,
but they're particularly bad at
negotiating things that are deeply
private.
How much do you want your partner to
know about you anyways?
It takes a lot of trust to have a real
conversation about what you need and
want.
Now you have it in the press.
People read that you are a.
You have a following of young men and I
went to hear your lecture and Washington
DC and there were a lot of women there
and your book,
first of all,
men don't buy books that often compared
to women,
so I'm presuming you have a lot of
female readers and I found it,
Danielle and I found it completely
readable and it wasn't uncommon for men.
It was more like a delusional desire on
the part of the radical leftists that
the only people that could possibly be
attracted to me or angry men.
Exactly.
It'd be better if they were angry young
white men,
you know,
because then that fits the narrative.
Particularly,
there's a way you have a diverse
audience and diverse following,
including many women and they're also
not particularly angry.
I mean,
I've talked to 200 using the anger.
That's the point of your book is stop
being angry.
Stop being resentful.
Right.
Of resentment is that.
That's absolutely crippling.
Resentment.
Just zenman deceit,
arrogance.
That's part of.
I'm writing another book and one of the
rules is don't allow yourself to
resentful receiptful,
deceitful and arrogant fingers together.
Yeah,
but it could be rad if you just.
Well,
that's supposed to be a good thing.
Yeah.
There's been 250,000 people,
as I said,
come to the lectures and there hasn't
been a single negative incident.
Not One.
This is what I find fascinating is that
I found you early on.
I said I'd had no idea you were just
that.
It was like butch cassidy and the
Sundance kid.
Like who is that guy?
Who is that guy?
Like you were pretty good and we were
covering a lot of the same topics later
on.
Yeah.
Wow.
And then,
you know,
I found out who you were.
What is astonishing to me is that
there's this amazing,
it just split between the positivity of
your audience,
the diversity of your audience,
the,
the intellectual content of your message
and then you get with a snarky
journalist with an agenda.
And I'm not mentioning names,
but
no,
this,
this young woman from a Gq and it was
just me on,
so it was just like lady.
Gotcha,
Gotcha.
For we don't want to blame the BBC saint
and then I.
and she seemed,
you know,
like as often she seemed intelligent and
capable of insight up to a point,
but it's almost as if something had
seized her mind and show you something,
had something new.
But I think people,
it can be a poly says that a whole
generation,
some of our most talented young women
are incapable of thought because of
this.
I thought maybe you can just an openness
to she couldn't and you were saying
completely like interesting,
fascinating,
original things even to me who've
studied these topics and.
Wow.
No,
it was quite the day.
So I went to Baltimore.
You survived it very well,
but it just made me think a lot that day
because I went there and I had to go out
of my way to do it.
Not that I'm complaining,
but there's a reason for saying that,
you know,
so I got there in Baltimore.
Yeah.
Well I was talking in Baltimore,
so.
Okay.
So,
so,
um,
the aquarium and I showed up to the,
to the hotel room where this was all
occurring and you know,
what you expect generally speaking,
even from journalists who aren't,
you know,
who are more of the attack dog variety
or who may be,
aren't positively predisposed to you
ideologically or personally,
you expect a certain modicum of
professional politeness.
Right.
Because while you don't have to be there
and you came and you and you accepted an
invitation and,
and all of that.
And so even with the channel for
journalists,
Kathy Newman,
she was quite polite and,
and forthcoming in the,
in the green room before the interview,
you know,
so she would have had at least that
professional persona,
which is,
it's not nothing right there.
There's something to be said for,
for going through the motions
professionally in an inappropriate
manner,
but when I walked into the hotel room in
Baltimore,
it was obvious that this interviewer had
already made up her mind about me 100
percent and that she was absolutely,
you know,
negatively predisposed to me with a
personal animus.
Animus is exactly the right word.
There was about a half an hour
photography session because it was Gq
and so I was in that atmosphere.
The photographers were fine.
I was in that atmosphere for about 45
minutes before we started to talk and
part of the reason that I'm so I'm not
as calm during that interview is are
usually I'm,
I'm a little bit harsher and the reason
for that is that,
you know,
it just started off instantly combative
and,
and what I,
what I should have done,
you see,
it's very,
very difficult to be awake enough to do
these things properly and they interview
progressed fine.
Although by the end of it,
I thought that I had maybe done enough
interviews for awhile because I didn't
think I had regulated my temper as well.
During that interview as I might've,
I wish.
Well so bad.
So you were getting it and then she
brought up a question about anger and I
just saw you kind of adjust and then
after that it was smooth sailing.
Well that's good because it was touch
and go,
you know,
and I thought,
boy,
you know,
maybe you're running out of patients.
Maybe you know,
maybe it's time to dial back on the
interviews because you know,
I've had many interviews like that and
they're very.
I find them like it takes me like three
days to recover from an interview.
You start thinking yourself like what I
should've said,
I should've said that,
and I dragged myself mad.
No,
but you did very well.
But it's so interesting that what it
told me was how parochial she was and
she lives in her own little world,
isn't it?
More a little bit about the ideology of
our time and Gosh,
you encountered this everywhere and I
used to write about this wisely.
I would.
I would encounter it.
I mean,
I think part of the issue is that you
will acknowledge that there are
differences between the sexes.
That seems to be,
I know that's a hell of a heresy.
Heresy because when I was reading your
book,
um,
there's nothing about it that is anti
female.
In fact,
you,
you do a lot of examination of the Adam
and Eve story and you have this
wonderful passage about like Adam being
the originally agreed,
okay.
The man who throws the woman under the
sea,
a return fault do you made her
really funny.
So,
so,
so there's nothing in you
this and the rules such as they are,
you know,
they seem very common sensical.
They could apply to anyone.
Um,
so is that a fair
surmise of why you get so attacked a
that just the very fact that you're
willing to speak about the sexes as
being not unequal but different but
equal?
Yeah.
Well,
you know what,
I would say that that's part of it
because there's a threat there.
So one of the things that happened when
I was in Scandinavia,
I just wrote a column about this
actually,
um,
was interesting being in Scandinavia,
especially in Sweden because they've
pushed the equality of opportunity
doctrine farther than any other country
in the world today.
It almost started there like in the UN
and the original charter.
The Swedes were there and they,
they've never given us.
No,
no.
And so,
and the week that I was there was the
same week that two articles were
published on gender differences,
um,
in,
in temperament and an interest in the
biggest sex differences that we know of
that aren't morphological are in
interest.
So women are more interested in people
by and large and men are more interested
in things by and large.
And the difference is actually large.
It's one standard deviation.
And so that means if you're a man,
you would have to be more interested in
people than 85 percent of men to be as
interested as 50 percent of women.
And if you're a woman,
you'd have to be more interested in
things than 85 percent of women to be as
interested as the 50th percentile male.
So the difference is actually quite
substantial and it's certainly large
enough to drive occupational choice
differences and it explains a lot of
configuration of people in the
workplace.
Absolutely.
Well,
and you know,
we're approach approaching parody in
terms of workplace overall workplace
distribution of women,
but there's massive differences in
occupational choice.
Like it's very interesting,
for example,
to go to the website of the US labor
department and look at male and female
dominated industries.
And you know,
there's the top 10 male dominated
industries have basically zero women in
the brick layers being one of the
people.
There are people three zones according
to Camille Paglia that you find is a lot
of men in the people freeze up.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And the women are in.
You ask a group of women and men,
would you rather spend the next three
weeks taking apart a machine and putting
it together or helping a group of people
work out their problems and the pool of
people who want to do them,
she,
it's just far more men than women.
There's more men in women dominated
industries than there are women and men
dominated industries at the extreme.
So that's like nursing.
Nursing is way more male nurses,
brick layers.
I've studied these male nurses and they
already,
you know,
gender activists are upset because they
earn more than women.
And a professor of nursing at University
of Pennsylvania tried to find out why
and she found out they immediately find
out what's the best paying field
subfield.
So they go into like nurse
anesthesiology,
it pays a lot more than men are there
and disproportionate number and they're
willing to work in insane hours.
They're far more willing to move to a
higher same thing.
Feral phone with,
with gender differences is that men are
more willing to move million or more.
They're more willing to,
to,
uh,
work outside.
They're more willing to take on
dangerous tasks.
They're more likely to work in scalable
industries,
so we'd like you can't scale personal
care.
It's really very.
It's very,
very difficult.
They're much less likely to work part
time if they have small businesses,
they're much more likely to work full
time in the small business rather than
this than part time.
And I mean women have their reasons to
want to work part time and feral also
pointed out that if you work 10 percent
longer hours,
you make 40 percent more money.
Your non linear nonlinear return on
overtime had something that's really
useful to know,
you know,
in terms of your career to an employer.
They have some also marks you out,
you know,
like if you have 10 employees and
they're all doing a reasonable job,
let's say,
but one of them is working an extra half
an hour a day or 45 minutes a day and
you can observe that everyday.
Then that gives them an edge with
regards to potential promotion and so.
And the return on those edges is
nonlinear.
And so anyways,
so I went to Scandinavia and it was the
same week that two studies were released
showing what had already been
established beyond a shadow of a doubt
that the personality differences between
men and women and the differences in
interest as well actually get bigger as
your society gets richer and as it gets
more egalitarian and,
and not just a little bit either.
That's the other thing that's so
interesting is you might think,
well the effect is it's the opposite of
what the social constructionists would
predict.
First of all.
So that's the first thing to point out
is it's not only that their hypothesis
wasn't supported,
it was decidedly refuted and,
and none of them have come to terms with
that.
And,
and,
and it's not a small effect.
The,
the,
the difference between personality
between men and women in Scandinavia is
a lot larger than it is in non
egalitarianism,
rural but true in the United States.
And the richer the democratic,
your household demographic,
your household,
the more likely the woman is to take
time out and be at home with,
right?
Because you can afford to do it.
And she can afford to major in od,
you know,
low paying fields,
like a feminist dance therapy.
The other thing you see too is that one
of the things that's also interesting I
think is that,
you know,
there's this idea that made that
marriage is a patriarchal institution,
you know,
that's primarily put there for the,
for the utility of the,
of the mail and think,
well,
like I think that's complete bloody
rubbish.
And I don't think there's any evidence
to support it at all.
But I think the best counter evidence is
that,
well if that's the case,
then rich people shouldn't be getting
married because they don't have to
oppress themselves.
But the truth of the matter is is that
the higher your demographic position,
the more likely you are to be married.
So marriage is falling apart among the
more likely the wife is staying home and
not.
I mean she has all sorts of pursuits but
wasn't.
She's not.
Well,
there's an old saying,
anyone,
any woman who marries for money earns
it.
But now let me just.
Okay.
This is where you might get in a little
trouble because in your book you call
men order and women chaos,
and you say order.
The known appears symbolically
associated with masculinity and chaos.
The Eternal Feminine is also the
crushing force of sexual selection.
Yeah.
What's up with that chaotic chaos?
Men and women net
or order and chaos.
It's masculinity and femininity
symbolically and so what's happened
fundamentally is that we're.
Our brains are wired for social
cognition,
so we're not natural.
Scientists were natural sociologists.
That might be a better,
even though I shutter to think that that
might be true,
especially given the sales associate as
well.
That's it triggering or maybe or or
maybe we're more,
we're more naturally a people who
observed through the lens of fiction and
that what we see as the world as
characterized and w the world.
Obviously it's made out of men and women
and children and those seem to be our
fundamental cognitive categories.
Masculinity,
femininity and,
and,
and then the category of children and
those categories have expanded to take
on connotations outside of,
of pure person perception.
And so,
you know,
it's for this reason that if you go to a
movie and that maybe it's a Disney
animated movie,
and I like to talk about those because
they draw on a very deep symbolic,
well,
it's perfectly reasonable to see a witch
that lives in the swamp because those go
together like it makes sense.
You know,
the which doesn't live in a gleaming
chrome,
high rise,
you know,
she lives in the swamp.
Is that.
So maybe
you could just fly up.
Well that's it.
That's where the high rise would be
better for.
The brain could take off,
you can take off better.
But there are categories of,
of symbolic association that are natural
to the way we think and the fundamental
elements of those categories seem to be
gendered.
And so this is partly why make reference
to Taoism,
for example.
So for the Daoists,
the world is made out of chaos and order
and chaos is the domain that you don't
understand and that emerges
unpredictably,
but also the domain from which new forms
emerge,
right?
Because it's from novelty that the new
way emerges.
And I think the fundamental association
between femininity is chaos is the
association between what's unexpected
and novel and what's new because new
forms emerge from chaos and it's not.
The chaos is,
is bad in order to good that that's both
have their pathologies.
Yes.
And,
and,
and what you're looking for,
and this is,
this is the book concentrates on above
all,
is that you're looking constantly to
find the balance between those two.
So for example,
formerly speaking,
the domain of order is that place that
you are,
when what you're doing is producing the
results that you want,
who have produced.
So imagine,
imagine,
think about the preconditions for not
being anxious.
Okay?
So the preconditions are that you're
constantly making predictions about
what's going to happen next.
And those predictions are tied tightly
to your behavioral output.
So you act in a certain way and you
presume that a certain thing is going to
happen.
And if your actions produce the results
that you desire,
then you assume that you know where you
are and you know what you're doing and
that your plan is intact and that the
environment is secure.
And that keeps her anxiety under
control,
that order,
and then you know,
maybe you're at a party and you don't
know anybody and you tell a joke and
everybody looks at you like what you
said was not only not funny but also
downright offensive and then all of a
sudden you've moved from the domain of
order into the domain of chaos because
you thought you were somewhere and you
thought you were someone and you thought
you were with people that were of a
certain type and you got all that wrong.
And so it causes suggesting it is going
to be the woman who says,
I find that really offended.
I'm not suggesting that,
but it probably is nevermind.
But women are also more sensitive to
negative emotion.
Right?
So there is some slightly higher
probability that that might be the case.
But then I think women are also
associated,
at least in men's imaginations with
nature,
which is part of the chaotic domain say
as opposed to culture because they're
sexually selective.
So you gotta think what?
What is nature?
When we have that as a cognitive
category,
right?
We think of the natural world,
we think of nature versus culture.
It's a fundamental opposition.
What is nature?
Well,
nature is trees and landscapes and
animals and all of that up,
but that isn't what nature fundamentally
is.
Nature fundamentally is that which
selects from a genetic perspective,
that's nature.
That's the fundamental definition of
nature,
and it is the case that human females
are sexually selective and it's.
It's a major component of human
behavior,
so the.
The evolutionary theory,
roughly speaking is that the reason we
diverged from chimpanzees 8 million
years ago,
7 million years ago,
is at least in part because of the
differences between sexual selectively
between female humans and female
chimpanzees.
Female chimpanzees are more likely to
have offspring from dominant males,
but it's not because of their sexual
selectivities.
So female chimpanzee has periods of
fertility that are marked by physical,
by observable physiological changes,
not the case with human females.
Human female ovulation is is concealed,
so that's a very profound biological
difference between human females and
chimpanzees and the chimpanzee.
Females will meet with any male,
but the dominant males chased the
subordinate males away,
but human females are sexually selective
and so and and it's not trivial facts.
So you have twice as many female
ancestors as male ancestors.
You think,
well,
how can that be?
Well,
imagine that on average,
every single human female has had one
child throughout the entire course of
history,
which is approximately correct by the
way.
Then imagine that half of the men had
zero and the other half had to.
Okay,
and that's roughly the case.
So half of males historically speaking,
have been reproductive disasters and the
reason for that is because of female
sexual collectivity.
So it is actually the case that female
humans are nature.
It's not only that they're,
that they're associated with nature
symbolically as far as production is
concerned.
They are the force of nature that does
the selection and so their nature in the
most fundamental way and there is a
chaotic element of that,
at least in relationship to men and also
in relationship to women.
Because a lot of the female on female
competition is competition.
That's chaotic for the right to be
sexually selective,
right,
not only with regards to men which
drives a lot of politics,
but also in relationship to each other
because part of what human females do
his jockey for position in the female
dominance hierarchy for the top
position,
which is the woman who gets to be most
sexually selective and so that drives
female female competition and it's a
different dynamic.
There's similarities between female
female competition and male male
competition,
but there are also differences and
they're pronounced.
So men for example,
while men are more likely to compete,
compete for socioeconomic status,
and that's partly because that drives
female mate choice.
So the correlation for men between
socioeconomic status and sexual success
is about point six.
And for women it's zero zero.
In fact,
it's actually slightly negative.
So when that's a huge difference between
men and women,
the anthropologists,
Sarah Hrdy,
h r,
d,
y,
and,
and she's like my favorite feminist
theorist,
although is she would say I'm a theorist
who happens to be a feminist,
but she studied primate behavior and she
watched.
She lifted the women very the the
females.
And we very carefully and looked at it,
a chimpanzees and gazelles and found
that,
um,
the female initially like male
primatologists would look and say,
oh,
the females,
the males are dominant in the females
are so cooperative.
She looked more carefully and so the
females weren't exactly cooperative,
like they would pass around their
infants,
their baby,
you know,
whatever they were and would find it.
And so the male primatologist who say,
oh,
they are,
they're so kind and caring.
She found out that when it was not your,
it was not hers.
They would take a little tufts of hair,
it would come out or they do something
to the eyes and the baby would be
injured and she saw all this violence.
But it was true in the status
differentiation.
So it's much more likely that it'll
happen when a higher status female is
taken care of.
Lower status infant.
Exactly.
And she said the great tragedy,
but it will not tragedy.
She had the reality of our species.
And in fact,
the subtitle for the book is that the
woman who never evolved,
we didn't evolve for niceness and
cooperative.
There's an immense competition and we
can,
according to her,
we are,
it's indelibly marked in our nature to
compete for the dominant males and no
doubt about that and so,
and that seems to cross culturally as
well.
That doesn't fly in a little bit in the
morning.
Gilda tarian societies.
So instead of being exaggerated,
it does flattened to some degree,
right?
So you could imagine that there's a
biological component and the cultural
component both in in,
in that case,
if you modify the cultural component and
that seems to decrease the overall.
So like,
let me be more clear about this.
Women are less prone to mate up across
an upstate is hierarchies in Scandinavia
than they are in less egalitarian
countries,
but there are still prone to do it.
So worldwide.
For example,
women,
young women find men who are about four
years older than them,
maximally attractive and they tend to
mate across an upstairs hierarchies.
And so one of the consequences of that,
for example,
is that as women have entered the
workforce,
they've actually driven in equality
because rich women will only marry rich
men.
Men is riches,
them or Richard.
Whereas rich man will marry women who
are poor than them,
but women won't,
and so what that means is it's another
factor that's pooling wealth in the
hands of fewer and fewer people
assortative mating now,
and you just find someone with your
background.
You'd whereas a doctor might have once
married his secretary now marries
another doctor.
Yep.
Can I ask then stepping a little bit
back from primates as well,
how does this selection work in the era
of swiping right and left?
How?
What is your reaction to the way young
people date today?
Oh,
that's a good.
I was really hoping we'd get into that.
I was really into the monkey,
so I didn't want to interrupt.
You know what?
I should close off the Scandinavian
discussion just by pointing out,
and this is something that the
scandinavians are already going to have
to wrestle with,
is that if you institute effective
policies to promote equality
opportunity,
which the Scandinavians have done,
you're going to produce some equality,
so like a 50 slash 50 distribution of
men and women in the workplace,
but you're also going to exacerbate
certain kinds of inequality and you
can't get out of that.
So you cannot have equality of
opportunity and equality of outcome
together.
They don't work together and equality of
outcome.
Essentially quality of outcome doctrine
which is often described with the code
word equity,
is that at every level of every
occupation,
the people have to be represented by the
same number that they're represented in
the population.
So if it's not 50 slash 50 men and women
at each in each occupation I need and in
each strata at each occupation,
then that sort of prime fsc evidence for
discrimination and for systemic
discrimination.
It's like,
nope,
sorry.
You have to factor in choice and choice
actually turns out to be a very
important determinant.
And as the society gets flatter and
flatter,
choice becomes a more important and more
and more important determinant.
And so you.
So what that essentially means is that
the most radical end of the left wing
political agenda is logically
impossible.
Apart from the fact that it's impossible
for a variety of other reasons.
And they should look at the data.
I mean it,
it's just a cliche now have in,
in a group of activists and they'll say,
oh,
well we need to,
in order for women to achieve equality,
we need government funded daycare and we
need.
They have it in Sweden.
Sweden has fewer women in managerial
levels.
The American women are ahead.
In fact now they have a,
they have quotas over there,
so they need more female ceos and
females on boards made any difference
between bringing in memory American
women because we're so much further
ahead.
So it's called the no difference in the
distribution of men and women.
Lower in the.
It's called the Nordic paradox and say,
you guys are so wonky.
I want to get back.
Okay.
Yes.
We all want to get back to get back to
these monkeys.
Well,
I was thinking just
thinking this morning about.
I was talking to a variety of political
types and we were talking about this
morning in DC.
It hard to believe,
hard to believe.
No,
I'm not.
I'm not telling you a bunch of
Republicans here and I'd been talking to
Democrats as well,
but it was mostly Republicans here and
we were talking about abortion and I
made a case that that's really not a
very productive discussion because
you're talking about a problem way too
late in the sequence of problems.
So by the time the discussion starts to
be about abortion,
there's 50 problems that have already
emerged that no one has addressed and
some of those problems are.
The fundamental problem is how human
being should regulate their sexual
behavior and that's a big problem.
And you think,
well there's an interesting thing that's
happening because you know the people on
the right would say,
well that's easy.
It's like don't sleep around and get
married and have sex with your marital
partner and that'll solve the problem.
So there's strictures on sexual behavior
and those would be the traditional ones
and what you see on the left is that
there's this weird paradoxical demand,
let's say
that people should be allowed to express
their sexuality in any manner that they
choose whenever they want,
but that sex is so dangerous that it has
to be carefully regulated at every
single stage of the interaction.
And so you know that many state
legislatures have now followed the
example of university campuses and put
in affirmative consent legislation so
that every move you make towards
physical intimacy has to be preceded by
the instantiation of a verbal contract.
Essentially.
It's like,
what?
Can I take your hand?
Yes.
You actually,
from what I understand,
you actually have to say yes,
like nodding is not sufficient.
And so and so each stage has to be,
has to be proceeded by affirmative
consent and
you know,
which,
which.
Well,
I won't,
I won't say anything about.
Yeah,
I will.
It's desert.
It's absurd to assume that that's how
human intimate relationships are
supposed to proceed.
And then you have complicated laws
emerging that are part of that that,
for example,
this is the case in California as I
understand it,
is that you cannot give affirmative
consent if you're intoxicated.
Okay.
So you think about that.
It's like what?
What does that mean?
It means that like a lot of sex is.
This unit has been illegal for a long
time.
Including marital.
Marital?
Yes.
Next to me on my honeymoon.
Okay.
Well that is Marie thinking.
It seems.
It seems to me,
it seems to mean.
No,
I'm.
It seems to me,
to me the California legislation that if
you have sex with your wife or husband
and either of you is intoxicated,
then you're either one of you or both is
guilty of rape.
That's what it looks like to me.
Actually.
I was in a debate a few years ago at the
University of Virginia Law School
and I turned to my debate partner and
said,
so if what you're saying is right,
um,
two people can rate one another,
right?
She said yes.
And I thought,
Oh shit.
I mean,
how can that be?
Well,
that's the question.
okay,
so then I would say,
well it's interesting because I think
that a lot of this confusion has emerged
fundamentally as a consequence of the
birth control pill,
so you know,
because you gotta think situationally
before you think ideologically or
psychologically,
it's like,
it seems to me that the 20th century
will be remembered for the hydrogen
bomb,
the transistor and the birth control and
those are unbelievably radical
technological innovations and maybe the
most common.
Yeah,
but on my fair lady,
just dependent on the transistor
so that,
that's the big technological innovation
that spawned all that.
And of the three I would say that the
birth control pill is probably the
bigger hydrogen bomb.
So because it,
it changed the fundamental biological
nature of women and men and because it
gave women for the first time in
biological history the,
the option of choosing their
reproductive status.
And that's,
that's,
that's abs.
Well,
yes and no.
Like,
yes,
we like it,
but it's not something that's come
without a tremendous.
Well it's come with
a fellow.
Can you,
have you been reading align with?
No,
no I haven't.
You'll find them interesting because
he's.
He writes about that I'm not,
I'm not making a case for the abolition
of the birth control pill by any stretch
of the imagination,
but I'm pointing at its complexity and
so because one of the questions is,
well,
once you can regulate your reproductive
function,
what attitude should you have toward
sex?
And one answer might be the more of it
under the more varied circumstances,
the better because why not?
And I would say that was actually part
of the attitude that emerged in the
aftermath of the birth control pill in
the 19 sixties.
Right.
And it was,
it was a reasonable response in some
sense because it's such a cataclysmic
change that you don't know what it
implies.
Well,
what's the consequence of that?
first of all,
people aren't reliable enough to use
birth control in an entirely reliable
manner.
So even though it can work at near 100
percent efficiency,
you have to take it extraordinarily
regularly and in a discipline manner for
that to work.
And so
there was still the problem of unwanted
pregnancy,
let's say.
And then there was the problem of the
proliferation of sexual epidemics and
that culminated in aids,
which could have easily wiped all of us
out but didn't.
But there was other sexual epidemics
that could have had the same effect.
But we've,
we've been fortunate enough to escape
them.
And then,
and then more recently there's been this
weird inversion,
especially on the radical left
that points to the reemergence of
something like a set of sexual taboos,
you know,
like I think the idea that sex is casual
and that it's a form of entertainment is
I think it's an absolutely preposterous
idea.
I think that
it's,
it's psychologically shallow beyond
belief to hold that as a core
proposition because it forces you to,
first of all,
if,
if it's repetitive sex with multiple
partners at it,
it forces you to treat people as if
they're interchangeable.
And I don't see how that's good for you
psychologically or for the people that
you're using interchangeably.
It,
it implies that you can divorce
sexuality from play,
from the desire for a relationship,
from emotional fragility,
from love,
from family,
from responsibility,
all of those things that are part and
parcel of every one and I don't think
you can and I don't think people's
experience indicates that you can and
especially on the emotional front.
And I think that's partly what's driving
and there's also a residual sense that
there's something about sex that's
fundamentally dangerous and maybe it's
dangerous emotionally and personally and
maybe it's dangerous socially and
psychologically,
which most certainly is because it's a
powerful force.
And the way the left is reacting to that
is by insisting that all forms of sexual
behavior are valid and,
and,
and that it's reasonable to manifest all
of them,
but that it's simultaneously so
dangerous that absolutely every aspect
of it has to be state regulated and in
an increasingly draconian form.
And so I think what needs to happen is
that the left and the right have to get
together and have like a real discussion
about what constitutes valid sexual
morality.
And that's the conversation you have to
have.
Way before you worry about solving like
the abortion debate,
which is very divisive and very and very
intractable.
Well,
one of the things we talked about
actually just last week on the podcast
is this cover story in the Atlantic
about the sexual recession amongst young
people that despite the advent of the
birth control pill,
abortion is going down.
Um,
uh,
it's,
that there's a,
there's lexus,
there's less thing is going down,
fewer things.
And what have you looked into that you
worry about that?
Well,
if you raise the cost of something,
you decrease its prevalence.
You know?
And,
and I think that it's,
it seems to be,
you know,
your wrists now to look up.
I kinda think that it's also a
reflection of the same thing that
Bloomberg reported on just a few days
ago.
They said that across businesses,
men are thinking,
I'm not spending any time with a single
woman that isn't,
you know,
associated with me in some formal
manner.
Like my wife.
I'm not going to do it.
I'm not going to mentor young women.
I'm not going to be in a room alone
because I could face career annihilation
and instantly they're frightened of
young women.
Now,
Kate Julian said that's part of it,
but we can overexaggerate the part.
I mean,
anxiety and depression is going up
amongst both young men and young women.
A suicide is going up,
um,
that,
that there's,
it's,
it's not just a,
you know,
most people I think are not.
We're talking about an elite demographic
who is into the consent and political
correctness and workplace [inaudible]
this is across the board and it's
global.
Um,
it's,
it's happening even in Sweden.
It's really happening in Japan and
Japan.
Exactly.
So
that speaks to,
and especially in Japan,
they just have people,
especially young men have given up on
intimacy and that having sex is
actually,
I mean,
that had too much trouble.
Sex robots.
Right?
Well,
right,
right.
Well,
my last question.
and there's pornography.
There's basically zero risk when you
allow for pornography that,
that,
that the men and women will sort of
separate that from their actual.
Exactly.
Maybe we were seeing a whole,
I guess,
collapse of intimacy,
let alone sex and,
and,
and I don't think that's just explained
by the political nature.
Um,
so I'd be interested in your thoughts.
Yeah.
Well,
I don't know that I don't know the
literature on the decline in sexual
activity well enough to know if it's
valid or reliable,
but I mean,
I think that,
you know,
in a stable society you take lots of
things for granted.
You take,
you take the fact that men and women are
going to be sexually attracted to one
another for granted and even though it's
more fragile than it appears,
you know,
and it's suppressed more easily than you
might think.
Um,
and you take the idea that men and women
are going to move together towards the
establishment of longterm intimate
relationships for granted.
But that's partly because you don't
understand what invisible preconditions
exists to make that self evident,
you know?
And when those invisible preconditions
are disrupted by rapid technological or
sociological change,
then things shift underneath you when
you don't know why.
A lot of it is traced to the advent of
the smartphone,
especially in the generation z that,
that kate was explaining this to us that
you could see it was broadband internet
and the smartphone that led to this
increasing fall off of relationship.
Well,
maybe the abstract is more interesting
than right proximal.
See that?
I just want to.
I want to know the truth.
Have you ever been with somebody you
loved?
If I'm fascinated in all that,
but you really wanted to get back to
your smartphone.
Has that ever happened?
Yeah.
Well,
it happens all the time.
Happens to me.
Happens during our podcast.
Tell you to put your phone.
I'm,
I'm researching.
Very addictive,
very addictive.
You know,
I read the other day that
like they are kind of going together.
The preferred method
method of interpersonal communication
between young people now is testing
rather than face to face communication.
Right.
And the swiping that apes.
Well that's,
that's,
that's a very interesting topic to the,
the like the tinder phenomenon.
That's right.
Because that that's also a major
technological revolution because what
it's done,
I would say for the first time is reduce
the cost of rejection,
two males to zero because it hides it
you the only people you ever hear from
people who haven't rejected
you,
although,
although they.
True.
But,
but there was one man who had to make
300.
He key actually tallied it.
You had to make 300 requests,
a swiping right or whatever.
So I think he had the sense of,
sure,
sure.
But it's massively attenuated because
you're not being humiliated.
Not at all.
It's really,
it's really at arm's length and you
know,
you can swipe very,
very rapidly and so you can get all that
rejection over within a very short
period of time.
It's like losing a video gamers or will
last because it's not.
I mean,
not nearly as bad.
Yeah.
So,
and I don't know what tinder also
reduces the.
One of the other things that things that
you want to think about with regards to
sex,
and I think this is probably
particularly true for women,
is that to what degree is it in women's
interests to allow the cost of sex to
fall to zero,
because with pornography certainly does
that and it just seems to me that that's
not a very good longterm strategy for
relationships between men and women
because whatever sex is worth,
the cost of zero is the wrong price and
so that's,
you know.
All right.
You heard it from Bunny ranch and pay
quite a bit for it.
Well true,
true.
That's true.
But
do you know,
I've heard from a number of women what
written read blog reports on their
frustration with their attempts to be
relatively sexually selective.
Like let's say they decide that they're
not going to sleep with their new
partner on the first date.
You know,
they're frustrated by the fact that to
the degree that they're being cautious
in their sexual behavior,
which I think is actually an admirable
idea that they're instantly out
competed.
Especially if their partners are
somewhat impulsive by women who will say
yes at the drop of a hat and so,
well,
again,
I don't think you know,
it depends on what the goal is.
That's the thing is that there's the
short terms there,
short term sexual gratification,
but the literature indicates that
married couples for example,
or couples in a permanent long term,
monogamous relationship are more
sexually satisfied than single people
and maybe the single people have to be
parsed out into those who are sexually
successful and those who aren't,
but I suspect that wouldn't make that
much difference,
but whatever.
There's the utility of relatively
immediate sexual gratification for
whatever that's worth and the
adventurousness that goes along with
that.
Let's say the hunt and the excitement of
having a new partner and all of that and
maybe even the danger that's associated
with that because people like to have a
little bit of danger in their life.
But what's the goal?
It's like what do people want?
And I mean there.
There's a great book called a billion
wicked thoughts that was written by
Google engineers and so it contains
great psychology because Google
engineers don't care about political
correctness and they just write down
what they find.
They don't even notice that it's
politically incorrect.
Hence James Demore for example,
and what they found was that women use
pornography just as much as men,
but the pornography that women use is
verbal.
It's not in logistic.
And the pornographic novels essentially
follow the same extraordinarily standard
plot line to the degree that publishing
houses like Harlequin,
which was going to say it's the,
it's the bodice rippers the veteran.
Right?
So in the Harlequin series,
you have the ones that were published
like in the 19 seventies that are pretty
tame.
There's a small bit,
they're pretty hot actually.
Well,
there's a variety.
They range from.
They range from red team to essentially
to hardcore pornography,
but the,
but the plots are quite similar in the
plot is,
um,
you know,
young,
relatively innocent woman finds
powerful,
interesting,
dangerous male tames him and then they
live happily ever after.
And it's the beauty and the beast plot,
which is a fundamental,
which is to search for women on pornhub.
We discovered we did an episode on porn
was for women.
It was getting
rape.
Wasn't that like there's no lesbianism
or at least that was your port.
Yeah,
that was me.
Oh,
okay.
I don't like porn is going to the
William Sonoma store.
I know it is.
It is female.
All those
losses
or Bill Maher,
one said that men and women should never
tell one another their fantasies because
when are outraged by what we say and
we're totally bored by what they say.
And I thought like women have kind of
these scenarios and you know,
I don't know Unicorns,
I don't know what they're doing.
Storylines,
storylines,
and it's just like A.
I don't want to say this to you,
but it is a lot of just close ups of
female body parts.
Yeah.
Well men are much more visually oriented
sexually,
but now they're being shamed.
I mean now that it's called the male
gaze,
and so there's all of this sick.
Oh my God,
the sports illustrated is exploiting the
female figure.
Yeah,
been men like it and I'm worried that
now sort of the way in the past,
um,
sexual sub,
you know,
gays were shamed.
We're now reversing it in shaming like
heterosexual.
Yes,
that's definitely,
that's definitely.
Remember we had the young woman who
complained about being whistled at and I
said,
don't worry,
it stops.
Yeah.
Do we have a little bit of time for a
couple more topics with you because one
of the things that are just coming out
of this younger generation and you have
a chapter of in your
book,
which I wanted to finish what the line
that we were pursuing to do this.
Well with sexual behavior.
The question is what's the end game?
And then this is what people have to ask
themselves is like,
one of the corollaries to the female
pornographic romance is actually the
establishment of a longterm
relationship.
And the question is,
you know,
it's so funny because I got pilloried in
the New York Times,
um,
for,
for talking about enforced monogamy was
quite interesting because that gets
brought up like in every scene was so
ridiculous.
I to that woman for two days.
I know it is just like a little side
comment and then that became like the
center showcase,
like like enforced monogamy,
you mean forced marriage or.
No,
I mean that was an anthropological term
which she knew perfectly well because
she's a very smart person and all it
means is that there's a pronounced
proclivity in human societies around the
world to enforce monogamous
relationships at multiple levels of the
sociological hierarchy.
You do it culturally do it.
You do have an expectation.
You do it legally enforced monogamy.
So my son was just married and if he
came to me next year and he said,
you know,
Hey dad,
guess what?
I've managed to have four affairs in the
last year with hot women and my wife
hasn't found out about any of them.
I'm not going to pat them on the back
and say,
good job,
kid,
you know,
I'm going to say,
what the hell is up with you?
You know,
you violated the vow that you took your
putting your whole future risk.
You're betraying yourself and your wife
and well,
that's enforced monogamy.
You know,
the,
uh,
the idea is that the social norm is the
establishment of a long term monogamous
relationship and that there are
structures put in place to support that,
but also to punish deviation from it and
you say,
well,
you know,
maybe,
maybe not so much on the punishment in,
but you can,
it depends.
It's like what do you want,
what,
what is it that you want,
you want a longterm stable relationship
or not,
and if that's the goal,
then your behavior should be devoted to
whatever it is that facilitates that
goal.
And I don't see that.
I certainly don't see that casual and
impulsive sex fits that bill now,
not in the least.
And all of the evidence with regards to
living together shows that that's
actually detrimental to the
establishment of a longterm
relationship.
So first of all,
common law marriage,
people who are in a common law marriage
are much more likely to be be divorced.
So that's the first thing.
The second thing is people who live
together before they get married are
much more likely to be divorced after
they get married.
So the idea that while you can try
someone on for size and see how it works
and then you're going to see if you're
compatible,
it's like that's one story.
Another story is how about you and I
lived together for a little while and
you know,
if you're,
you're not so bad,
but maybe I can find someone better and
if I do,
you know,
in the next year and a half or so
because we're not hooked together in any
formal way,
I can just trade you in.
It's okay,
you can do the same to me,
but I don't really see that as the sort
of complimentary mutual interaction that
leads to the formulation of longterm
trust.
And I think it's a better story for
interpreting what constitutes living
together then.
Well,
you know,
we're going to try each other out
because that's what mature people would
do it.
So our rental.
Yeah.
Well that's right,
the rental car.
Yeah.
Well that's,
that's it.
And,
and,
but what more,
most importantly,
the data indicate that it doesn't work
is that you're more likely to get
divorced.
Not less likely because maybe the right
attitude is,
well,
you're probably about as flawed as me
and you know,
we're lucky that we found each other and
so let's see if we can make a commitment
because we're engaging in something
that's very risky,
you know,
an intimate relationship and we're going
to commit to each other and see if we
can build something of value across time
and there's a definite risk in that,
but there is a compliment to your
partner.
It's like,
well,
I think you're worth making a sacrifice
for and what's the sacrifice?
While it's everyone else.
It's a big sacrifice and there's.
If you don't see that as a compliment,
then I don't think you're thinking
because not only is it a compliment,
it's sort of like the ultimate
compliment and maybe you don't get to
have a marriage that works without that
compliment.
Maybe it's so difficult to establish a
longterm relationship that's functional
that you have to make a walloping
sacrifice very early on in the
relationship.
In order for that to even be a
possibility.
Maybe not because what the hell do we
know about what binds people together,
but,
but it's not that easy to stay with
someone for a long period of time,
you know,
it's,
it's a real,
it's a real commitment.
It takes a tremendous amount of effort.
So actually you're bringing us back to
the beginning and your time with Tammy
and I'm.
One of the things about.
I think I'm going to guess this is a bit
of an overlooked part in your chapter in
your book,
but I just was like one of my favorites.
It was your book on modern parenting.
Oh yes.
And that was good.
I thought I would get most trouble for.
I know,
but it reminds me don't read that far
into the book.
Well,
it,
my mother,
when I had my first child gave me a 19
fifties copy of Dr Spock and he was
considered so controversial and yet he
was just like the most sensible person
made new children very,
very well.
Was a pediatrician and you,
your rule for parenting is do not let
your children do anything that makes you
dislike them and you kind of in that one
chapter and it's not even one of your
longest chapters,
just did this wonderful sweeping
overview of modern parenting and the
problems and in some ways that we're
producing maybe some of these kids who
are prolonging adulthood,
prolonging the markers of adulthood,
um,
that,
that you feel that parents,
uh,
you said you see today's parents is
terrified by their children,
not least because they've denied credit
for their role as benevolent,
unnecessary agents of discipline,
order and conventionality.
And then you told some hilarious stories
about when your wife ran a daycare
center out of your house and you would,
you would get into tests of wills with
some of the two year olds,
but
sun is ordinary.
It here,
he got married.
Congratulations.
He still doesn't want to do anything he
doesn't want to do.
He's very charming and very emotionally
stable.
So it's like he's easy to get along
with,
but trying to get him to do something he
doesn't want to do.
It's like he had my wife defeated when
he was nine months old and she's tough
like seriously she,
she's no pushover,
but he would just sit there with his
mouth closed and glare adders like I'm
not eating out and I can take more than
you can.
Dish out.
Was really something to see,
you know,
to see that kind of force of will and
someone that small.
Talk a little bit about that and just
the modern roles between men and women
were less.
You know,
you don't really.
You're not really supposed to
distinguish between fathers and mothers
even though that seems to inevitably
happen in most.
Well,
it happens in large part because the
children differentiate between them.
Like parents are under the delusion that
most of what you do with your children
is driven by what you want to do with
your children.
When in fact it's driven to a massive
degree by what your children want you to
do with them.
And so there were studies done 30 years
ago on feminist parents who decided that
they were going to raise their children
in non-gender differentiated matters.
And when they were studied,
they found that the parents who had that
explicit philosophy,
we're just as gender differentiated with
their children as the parents who didn't
have the philosophy.
And the reason for that is that if
you're a parent that has any sense at
all,
you don't respond to your children as a
rigid idea log.
You respond to them as whatever it is
the child man manifests it,
him,
him or herself as like,
you know,
with any individualized relationship,
you take your cue from the person and
you might think,
well a child has no intrinsic nature,
but you know,
if you think that you either don't have
children or you've never seen a child or
you're so blinded by your radiology that
you don't have a child.
You just have a blank projection screen
onto which you project your
presuppositions and then heaven help
your child.
You know.
So,
so a lot of the gender differentiation
is actually driven by the children's
demands.
And that's all for the good.
That chapter,
I thought I would get into tremendous
trouble for writing that chapter because
it's contentious,
right on the surface.
Just to the rule,
because the rule first implies that
children can be dislikable and then I
would say again,
you know,
like have you met children,
every child where their children you
didn't like obviously,
and so lots of children or dislikable,
but it's taboo to admit that because
they're all sweetness and light and
innocence ever since Rousseau,
but you know,
was so put all five of his children in
an orphanage where they all died.
So maybe we won't,
so we won't talk too much about Rousseau
and um,
and then the next taboo is while that
parents can dislike their children,
right?
But if you're a clinician and you don't
think that parents can dislike their
children,
then well then,
well then you're not a clinician because
one of the things you constantly see is
that path all within families is an
incredibly common common source of
psychological destabilization.
Right?
And it's terrible tension between
parents and their children in between
siblings.
What I suggest in the book,
which I think is radical by today's
standards,
is that your fundamental job as a parent
is to ensure that by the time your child
is four years old,
that they are maximally desirable to
other children and to adults because
what happens is that after the age of
four,
you aren't the primary agent of
socialization.
The social world becomes the primary
agent of socialization and if your child
is the sort of child that's invited to
play by other children because your
child is capable of for stolen
gratification and taking turns and
playing someone else's game when,
when it's necessary and abiding by the
rules and not having a temper tantrum
when they lose and not getting to,
you know,
high on their horse when they win,
than many children will invite them.
Sorry,
I,
I don't know what you mean.
Just say it.
What do you want me to do?
No,
I,
I know we,
we have,
we have our limited time and so I just
wanted to.
I was actually saying
anymore,
so this is great.
I was selfish of me because I really
wanted to hear you talk.
I know I just want to let him take this.
I'll take 15 seconds to wrap that up and
then stop.
Well,
so look,
you get married when you have your
children and you're flawed and your
partner slaughtered and hopefully you're
flawed in different ways and so you put
the two of you together and you make one
approximately normal person and then
hopefully and then your child has to
interact with that dyad.
That is a reasonable representative of
social norms and if they disagree or if
your child disappoints you with their
behavior,
the probability that they will
disappoint other people is very high and
so you have an ethical obligation to
ensure that your child is behaving in a
manner that makes them optimally
desirable to their playmates and also to
other adults because then the kids
invite them to play and they get to be
socialized,
right?
They get,
they have friends for God's sake.
It's like,
what do you want for your kids?
How about some friends?
Wouldn't that be nice and maybe what
you'd like is that they regulate their
behavior well enough so that when you
take them places,
restaurants to see your friends,
to see your relatives,
they behave in a manner that's
sufficiently civilized,
so their intrinsic charm winds over the
adults and everywhere they go,
people are smiling and welcoming instead
of wishing with fake smiles that the
Damn Brat would leave along with their
foolish parents,
which is not a good.
That's not a good environment to have
your child constantly exposed to no
friends because they're too selfish and
immature and irritated era irritating to
adults so that they're barely tolerated
under the mask of false smiles.
It's like you have an ethical obligation
to regulate your child's behavior so
that they're optimally acceptable
socially and that is not how people look
at children in the modern world.
They think,
well,
you raising their self esteem or you're
enhancing their creativity or you don't
want to put constraints on their
behavior because you're going to
interfere with the flowering of their
intrinsic self and you know,
it's all roost,
soliah nonsense and there's no evidence
to support it.
Yeah.
Father,
yeah,
he was such a corrupt
and he had these babies with this poor
scullery maid and left them all in a
actually a place where they would just
languish and die.
Yeah,
right.
Five of them Russo.
Yeah.
No,
I know.
Yeah,
exactly.
Oh man,
that is intrinsically good.
Yeah.
One example,
I just remember
a few weeks ago I was reading about you
in somehow I got onto somebody's twitter
feed whom I will not mention because,
oh my God.
But anyway,
a difficult person and she was attacking
you and had a,
a selection from your book a bit where
you would called two-year-olds little
monsters.
And so suddenly all of these distraught
twitter followers of this feminist were
saying,
ah,
called them.
Yeah.
Little monsters and everybody.
And then occasionally there'd be a
apparent who would take a two year olds
kind of are monsters,
you know,
and then there'd be kind of art and they
had taken this out of context and shown
it like something to deplore and,
but,
and it was so amusing to me.
This little.
Yeah.
Hopefully they'll soon be cursed with
some.
My son was,
I won't say which one was two years old,
had he was a good boy,
but he had an insane meltdown in a
supermarket.
I was with my mother.
We both pretended we didn't know
to be the parent and we heard people
say,
oh my God,
look at that child and watching a two
year old have a Tantrum is I didn't want
to be associated with
boy who used to be like when my wife was
taken care of more kids than ours.
There was a little boy who who,
who had learned to throw a pretty decent
town and and he would do that and it
didn't work in our house because we'd
just leave him,
have his tantrum and going into a
different room and then he'd kind of
wake up out of it.
There wouldn't be anybody around.
And so that
like if you put all that work to a
dramatic difference
play and you have zero audience,
it's not.
You're not going to sustain it anyways.
He could actually turn,
hold his breath until he turned blue.
So you should try that.
Go home and see if you can do that in
front of the mirror man.
Like it's hard.
It's very,
very good.
Will you do.
It was impressive.
It was.
And,
and you know,
two year olds are very impressive.
They're there.
They have unbelievable outbursts of rage
and disinhibited emotion.
And your job is,
you know,
they're,
they're driven by these underlying
motivational systems that are
unbelievably powerful and as part of
what makes them delightful because when
they're happy,
they're insanely happy.
And when they're playful,
they're incredibly playful.
And so the positive end of the MS is way
exaggerated compared to,
you know,
or rather drab adult and,
and so it makes two year olds
extraordinarily interesting.
But the same is true on the negative
emotion side.
They're completely dysregulated and it's
really hard on them.
Like to have a two year old who isn't in
control of their emotions means that you
have a child who's developing central
personality,
you know,
their,
their ego,
for lack of a better word,
is constantly being swamped by these
powerful underlying emotional systems.
You know what it's like if you are
enraged for any period of time or if
you're engulfed by grief,
like it's exhausting.
It's,
it's demeaning and it's exhausting and
it's the same with a little candidates
like it's a real defeat for the
developing integrated individual to be
subjugated by those catastrophic,
really powerful emergency motions and
part of your job as a parent is to
scaffold the part of the child that can
regulate and inhibit those powerful
underlying system.
So with my son for example,
when he used to misbehave,
I would count say you're going to go sit
on the steps.
He'd say,
oh no,
I'm not.
I would say,
Whoa,
yes you are.
And then usually I'd have to chase the
morale because he wouldn't go sit on the
steps and so I put them on the steps.
Say you're going to sit there until
you've got yourself under control.
And so he'd say no,
I not say yes you are.
And then he tried to get up and I just
told him,
see,
you're going to sit there.
I'm going to hold you until you sit
there.
No,
I'm not.
It's like I could out wait a two year
old,
so I usually won those battles and then
he'd sit there and say,
look kid,
this is the deal.
I'd say two things like you want to have
a bad day or you want to have a good
day,
you think about that because if you want
to have a good day,
have a bad day,
we could have a bad days.
You sit here and as soon as you get
control of yourself and you're ready to
be civilized,
then you can come back and we can have a
good day.
So we'd sit there
just,
it was unbelievable to watch.
Just the developed with rage,
you know,
just trying to get himself under
control,
you know?
And so I'd come back 30 seconds later
and I'd say,
you know,
but got yourself,
got your act together.
Yeah,
no,
now I wait.
And usually it took them two or three
minutes and he'd calm down and then he'd
come back out and he'd say,
I'm ready to have a good day.
And he meant it,
you know?
And I can tell he meant it too because
whatever resentment,
I was harboring towards him for his
misbehavior and you have to watch that
when you're an adult would vanish
because he'd come and he'd,
he was done.
He was ready to just,
you know,
to proceed on a civilized basis.
And it was really interesting to watch
that because it took them every time he
sat on the steps,
it took them a shorter and shorter
period of time to attain mastery.
Right.
Until,
you know,
it got to the point where he could only
have to sit for 15 seconds or so when he
would bring himself under control.
And that was a victory.
Like if you imagine the neurological
systems developed that are responsible
for personality integration,
it was a victory for those systems
because they were attaining the ability
to regulate the lower order,
spontaneous emotions and you know,
and,
and he,
he turned into an individual who's
capable of a tremendous level of self
control and you know,
and he had large daymond's defined with.
Yes,
absolutely.
And,
and,
and while it turned out well for my
daughter too,
because she ended
up being very ill and he ended up being
extraordinarily levelheaded and reliable
and thank God for that.
Could you,
could you come to my house and do that
for my little multiport izzy?
Because I can't,
I can't,
I can't train her.
She's nice.
The next book,
the dog.
I would love to know how to train your
dog.
You like cats?
That's the one role I have checked.
Like petting the cat.
I wrote about dogs for two pages to
begin with,
just to satisfy the dog.
It didn't satisfy satisfied.
You can't satisfy them.
All right,
well we can't thank you enough for
coming here.
Um,
I know the Aei audience is just so
delighted to have had the chance to hear
you
talk.
Have once we met in DC,
but I've seen you passed electronics.
Yes.
Oh,
you've swiped past.
Oh yeah.
Well there was that.
We're not going into that.
Okay.
Thank you everybody.
Thank you.
Thank you Jordan.
Thanks.