Hi everybody.
I'm in a little air BNB in Manhattan a
few days before this event that I'm
going to talk to you about.
Um,
I'm here to talk to Jonathan Heit today,
so that should be good.
Anyways,
I wanted to tell you about an event
that's coming up on November 11th call,
the stifling of free speech on
university campuses and it's going to be
held at the Canada Christian College,
which is at 50 Jervais drive in Toronto.
And it'll start at 1:00 PM.
I'm all put all that information.
In the description of the video,
we're going to talk about the state of
free discussion on campuses.
And uh,
this event has actually mushrooms into
something that was far beyond its
original borders,
let's say,
because of,
because it was scheduled for August 22nd
and had been canceled by Ryerson
University.
And I'll tell you why that is as I go
through this video.
So first of all,
I'm going to tell you who's going to be
there.
So this is actually organized by Ms
Serena Singh,
who's a former social worker and a newly
hatched political and social
commentator.
You can find out more about her and her
views and her work at a channel called
recovery social worker on Youtube.
Serena has served as a social worker in
the child welfare system,
which is a really rough place to work
for many,
many years and has been disturbed deeply
about the rising tide of political
correctness in social work in particular
because social work is a discipline
that's been almost entirely corrupted by
in my estimation,
by political correctness.
And so because of her concerns,
she decided to speak out and also to
organize this event.
So that's been very challenging as this
is the first thing of this sort that
she's done.
So the panelists include doctor
[inaudible] and doctor or an [inaudible]
and myself.
And I'll tell you,
most of you know about,
uh,
Gad sad I s I presume some of you know
about doctor Aminay as well.
Give you a little background information
about them.
So Dr Sad is a professor at Concordia
University in Montreal and host of the
Youtube Channel,
the sad truth.
And he's the author of a couple of
books.
They're consuming instinct and the
evolutionary basis of consumption.
And he's also served as the editor of
evolutionary psychology and the business
sciences.
Doctor [inaudible].
Doctor [inaudible] is at clinical
psychologist,
a media consultant and a lecturer at
Ryerson University in Toronto.
He's host of the podcast,
the real reality.
I actually served on his Phd Defense
Committee a number of years ago,
but a while back he invited me to talk
to his class at Ryerson University.
Uh,
that talk was recorded and was released
as an incendiary discussion at Ryerson
University.
It's garnered about 400,000 views on
youtube and I'll put a link to that in
the discussion as well.
And so those are the three people that
are going to be speaking at the panel as
well as me.
The panel discussion was originally for
our August 22nd but was canceled by
Univer Ryerson University.
So the irony of that was not lost on us
because what that meant was that there
was a panel on the suppression of free
speech at university campuses that was
actually canceled by a university.
So,
but that's only,
you know,
that's just an example of all the odd
things that have been happening
everywhere recently.
I would say,
uh,
administrators,
their quote prioritize safety unquote
over free speech in light of recent
events and they were referring to the
Charlottesville meeting and the tragedy
that occurred there.
I guess they had their reasons to be
concerned.
The BBC covered the cancellation,
uh,
and quoted the administrators who were
responsible for the cancellation as
follows.
There is often attention at universities
resulting from our commitment to be a
place for free speech and our commitment
to be a place that is civil,
safe and welcoming.
In light of recent events,
Ryerson University is prioritizing
campus safety said university
spokesperson,
Michael Forbes and an email Mr. Forbes
said a part time instructor had rented a
room on campus to host the event.
But after conducting a standard safety
review,
the university decided that quote
Ryerson is not equipped to provide the
necessary level of public safety for the
event to go forward.
Well,
you can make of that what you will.
I think that Ryerson who had agreed to
host the talk could have decided that
long before one or two days before the
event.
But in any case it was canceled.
We would have got about two or 300
people at the event if it would've gone
forward in Ryerson.
And there was some organized opposition
to the event,
which basically claimed that it was
being run by Nazis.
It neonazis a,
that was actually what they posted on
their facebook site,
although they took that down after it
became publicized at,
that was the sort of symbolism that they
were using to object to the event.
And then in the aftermath of their
successful campaign to have Ryerson shut
it down,
which involve multiple phone calls to
the administrators and so forth.
They scheduled a post cancellation rally
where about a hundred or so might've
been up to 200 people,
came out at Ryerson and uh,
had a celebration party,
well waving around banners that
prominently displayed the hammer and
sickle.
So that gives you some idea of who is
behind this.
And then later the same people shut down
a comedy event,
uh,
which was entitled something
approximating a free speech comedy
event.
And that was rescheduled as well for
November 4th,
which I think is two days ago.
I think it's the sixth today.
Yeah.
And they disrupted that as well.
So we expect some level of disruption at
the November 11th event and are
organizing security to minimize the
probability that it will be either
disrupted or shut down.
But you never know what's going to
happen.
We've sold about 950 tickets so far.
Um,
the other thing that happened recently,
and I think this is a good indication of
the kind of opposition that we're going
to be facing as that my neighborhood was
postered with uh,
a number of posters claiming that I was
a risk to the,
to the neighborhood.
Uh,
I think they were entitled a community
safety warning describing me as a well
as a reprehensible person.
And funnily enough,
the photograph they used with of meat,
which was actually one where I appear
quite angry,
was taken from a free speech rally where
the same sort of people showed up in
opposition and they took the microphone
and shut down the PA system and blasted
white noise.
So in order to make myself heard,
I had to speak very loudly and that's
the picture they took to indicate what a
public safety menace I am.
So anyways,
that's the sort of people that are
opposing this.
So I'm encouraging you to buy tickets or
you can get them at Brown paper tickets.
I'll put the link in the video
description.
Uh,
I would also say though,
if you're planning to come and your an
advocate for the sort of thing that I've
been doing and doctor [inaudible] and
doctor sad and Serena as well.
I really would like to emphasize the
necessary necessity for calm and,
and detachment.
And there's going to be,
if the protesters are there,
I suspect there'll be quite provocative.
I wouldn't put it past them to plant
provocateurs in,
in the crowd to cause trouble.
And the last thing I want on any of us
on the panel want is for anybody to be
hurt or for anything stupid to happen.
Um,
you know,
disruptions are one thing and we
certainly don't want them,
but we don't want anyone hurt.
And I would like to implore all of you
who are coming to support us,
who were,
who were just interested in this issue
to maintain your cool regardless of
level of provocation.
It's unbelievably important because in
the social media climate that we have
right now,
the misbehavior of any single individual
has ramifications that can echo far past
what would normally be the case.
And so it's of extreme importance for
everyone who's in favor of let's say
free speech and in favor of supporting
the endeavors that,
that a number of people are,
are uh,
engaged in to sure that free speech
remains a priority in our society and on
campuses that no one behaves badly.
Uh,
again,
regardless of provocation,
keep your damn cool,
okay.
Because it's really important.
It's crucially important.
We have good security as far as I can
tell,
done our best to vet them and all of
that.
But um,
this is,
this just isn't the time or place for
anything untoward to happen.
So anyways,
we'd like to invite you to come.
You can get tickets.
As I said at Brown paper tickets,
I'll post that.
There's still,
the venue is somewhat expandable.
So although we've sold approximately a
thousand tickets,
which is of course it's about five times
as many people as we would have
originally talked to.
That's pretty funny too because you
know,
this is another reason to maintain calm
is just because the protesters show up
and even if they caused trouble,
that doesn't mean that they're obtaining
any more than a local trivial victory.
Um,
the medium term and long term
consequences of them shutting us down at
Ryerson is that we're going to talk to
five times as many people at the Canada
Christian College.
The reason we picked the Canada
Christian college just because,
well,
first of all it was a large venue,
but more importantly,
um,
we believe that there they,
the people who run the college would
have enough courage to withstand
pressure from activist types who mount
phone call,
uh,
campaigns to have this shutdown and that
they wouldn't shut it down no matter
what.
And that's definitely proved to be the
case.
So thank you very much to the people at
the Canada Christian College for having
the courage to host this.
To begin with.
And also the courage not to shut it
down.
So I'm also going to link in the
description of this video,
a number of the news stories that were
published in Canada and to some degree
internationally about the original
shutdown.
So anyways,
I'd like to invite you to come.
It should be an interesting event.
A Gad and Orrin are good speakers there.
Well-Informed.
Serena has a variety of very interesting
questions.
Ready for the panel discussion.
I think it could be an excellent event
and hopefully it will go smoothly.
And even if it doesn't,
hopefully people will have enough sense
to maintain their cool and react
intelligently and not respond to
provocation because that's the best way
forward in this particular situation.
So,
uh,
thanks very much.