Today we're going to talk about pretty
much ends the section on traits
and we're going to talk today about the
practical utility of traits.
Essentially.
It's always nice if you're doing
psychological research to have a hard
target.
No,
it's it.
It turns out to be relatively uncommon
amongst psychological researchers to
actually try to predict something.
I mean if you use a regression equation,
which is what most of the stats that
you'd use if you were doing psychology
research or based on the purpose of the
experiment or the research
hypothetically is the derivation of a
regression equation that might enable
you to predict something useful in the
future.
But in in psychology,
a lot of that is devolved into sort of
descriptive work.
Showing that two groups differ on some
trait or some feature,
but the actual utility of knowing that
is not.
It's not self evident.
It's partly why I got interested in
prediction in performance prediction
because
you can measure performance and it
actually matters.
So that would be performance creatively
say or academically or if you're working
in an industrial area,
so just say as a factory worker or in a
job that can be reduced to essentially
an algorithm.
So if you're in a job that can be
reduced to an algorithm,
once you learn it,
you know how to do it.
So those are simpler jobs.
Um,
and then performance in complex jobs as
well.
Performance as an entrepreneur,
those are all
in some sense real world phenomena.
Although of course you still have a
measurement problem,
right?
So if you're trying to measure,
for example,
how successful middle managers are in a
corporation,
it's not that easy to specify because
you know,
if you're measuring the performance of
salesman,
you can see how much they sold and then
you have a performance measure that's
basically defacto.
But if you're trying to measure their
performance of managers say,
and we'll say in an institution like the
University of Toronto or even in a
profit making institution,
their connection with outside
marketplace is not.
It's not immediately obvious.
So then you might ask,
well,
how in the world could you assess their
performance?
And the way it's generally done is when
you can have them rate themselves that
has all these problems,
but you know it's not without validity,
completely without validity.
You could have their managers rate them.
I'm that assume that their managers know
what they're doing and that they're
accurate.
Judges have their actual quality of
performance.
You can have their peers rate them,
and you can have the people that are
working for them,
rate them,
and it turns out that if you do that on
a fairly regular basis,
say once every quarter or once every six
months or something like that,
and you use a standardized questionnaire
that you can,
that you can so that you can do
quantitative analysis,
that you can get pretty reliable
indicators of performance.
Now the problem of course is is just
because your manager or the people that
are working for you think you're doing a
good job.
Does that mean that the job you're doing
is adding anything to the actual
productivity of the company?
And the answer to that is you don't
know.
So I think to some degree that's why
large companies tend to be somewhat
unstable is once they get large enough,
there's a lot of inside to them.
It's not attached to the market in any
way.
And so people can be working very hard,
but,
and,
and therefore productive from the
perspective of actual,
you know,
labor input,
but whether or not that actually is
producing a profit or producing the kind
of consequence that you'd want it to
produce so that the company can keep
going,
that's a completely different problem.
So even when you're trying to predict
performance,
which is a fairly,
as I said,
a fairly real world phenomena,
you still have the problem of how it is
that you measure performance.
So for example,
you guys are being graded all at the
time and you might ask yourself,
well,
what are the,
what's the utility of those grades?
What do they accurately represent?
While you know they're going to be used
in situations where you're trying to
enter higher education and the CRA and
the selection criteria are actually
grades,
you know,
so if you want to go onto graduate
school or to law school or to medicine
or any of the professional schools,
then whether or not you get good grades
actually matters,
but then the relationship between grades
and say achievement outside of those
specific places where grades are
necessary.
You might argue that that's less clear.
One thing we do know about the grades at
the University of Toronto is that their,
their correlation with trait creativity
is zero and so you know,
you might hope that one of the things
that you'd be assessed for while you're
in university would,
would be,
would have something to do with
creativity,
right?
You're supposed to think originally and
creatively and so on.
But our research so far when we've
analyzed what's predicting grades at the
uft,
it's all ICU and conscientiousness.
So an introverts do slightly better but
not a tremendous amount.
That's probably because they're not out
partying all the time.
That would be my suspicion,
but openness apart from ICU has no
relationship whatsoever and I think
that's actually partly because it's not
that easy.
First of all,
you're not going to get graded for being
creative on a multiple choice task,
right?
Because the last thing you want to be on
a multiple choice test is creative,
right?
So and then with regards to an essay,
well the problem with writing a creative
essay is in some sense you force the
greater to come up with a scheme of
grading that's sort of unique to you,
right?
Because if you've done something
original and new and so it's not that
easy for the person who's grading it.
You're forcing them to step outside of
their comfortable rubric and of course
that's a demand.
And when your Ta's or grading for
example,
and they have 100 papers to grade the
probability that on average they're
going to appreciate a clear easy to read
an essay that does exactly what it was
supposed to do is quite high rather than
something that's original and creative
and that actually requires thought to
understand.
Now,
you know,
I don't know if that's actually the
problem,
although I suspect that it could well
be,
but I do know that grades are not a good
marker of creativity,
so neither,
you know,
creative achievement per se.
So that's actually creative products
that you've produced in your life.
Neither that nor trade,
openness nor measures of creative
thinking are associated with grades.
So I would say that the data sort of
indicates that grades might be a good
marker of managerial administrative
ability,
but they're unlikely to be a good marker
of creative and entrepreneurial ability.
So anyways,
in any institution,
you know,
there's always a tension between the
specific demands of the institution
which are kind of orderly and set and
then the requirement for creativity,
which is very difficult thing for an
institution to deal with because
institutions try to make thing things
algorithmic so they can be predictable.
So I think that tension,
that tension is always there wherever
you go in your life.
And that's also probably by why openness
and conscientiousness are actually not
correlated,
right?
Because their,
their,
their responses to two really different
forms of environments.
So.
Okay.
So predicting performance is difficult,
although it's useful because performance
exists and,
but assessing performance is also
extremely difficult.
So that's why in some ways that's why
you could regard market solutions to
complex problems is almost inevitable.
Imagine that.
So how do you know if a company is run
well?
Well,
the answer to that is people buy its
products and they buy them for enough so
the company can keep running.
Then you might ask,
well,
is there anything that you could measure
outside of that and answer that is a
possibly not because it's so difficult,
you know,
because I remember I read once that you
know,
under the Communists,
uh,
there was uh,
there were central committees that had
to do pricing.
And so this committee,
if I remember correctly,
had to make something on the order of
100,000 pricing decisions a day.
So you can imagine,
you just try to think for a minute about
how you would calculate what a nail is
worth.
Now remembered it.
You don't get any price data from the
market because the market would say,
well a nail is worth whatever someone
will pay for it.
While say you don't have a market,
well,
how in the hell do you figure out what
it nails worth?
The answer to that is he can't because
the nail is only worth something in
relationship to every other thing that's
worth something.
So you could imagine trying to commute
compute the comparative cost of one
thing against all other things and then
having to do that against all other
things.
Well,
that's why
hypothetically,
that's why markets actually work
efficiently is because you could think
of the market as a gigantic
supercomputer made up of the brains of
every single person who's making
purchasing decisions and you just don't
even bother solving the problem.
You just throw things out there and some
of them succeed in the sort of Darwinian
way and some of them fail and that's
that.
And you might say,
well,
the market,
you know there's.
There's problems with the way that the
market values things and the proper
response to that is yes,
no doubt,
but what are you going to do that might
constitute a better alternative?
And then I'll tell you,
if you start wrestling with that
problem,
it gets extraordinarily difficult.
It's just,
it's so technically complex that I don't
actually think it's manageable.
I think you can't do anything probably,
but make it worse.
Anyways.
So I'm going to talk to you a little bit
about the difference between pursuing a
career in psychology and pursuing
scientific truth.
I want to tell you about that because
one of the things I've learned from
trying to predict performance is that a
whole lot of things that psychologists
talk about research psychologists don't
exist really at all.
And I'm not saying that because I'm
cynical about psychology because
I think that any.
Yeah,
human venture has to produce a
tremendous amount of waste and nonsense
in order to produce any incremental
knowledge whatsoever.
You know,
so like if you're thinking that every
piece of research is going to produce
new knowledge,
genuine knowledge,
then you're naive because there's lots
of reasons why psychologists do research
and some of it is well because they have
to.
And some of it is because they have to
train undergraduates and so
undergraduates basically have to do bad
research because well you only have four
months to do it and you're really going
to discover something new and for months
it's like,
no.
And then master's students are kind of
in the same situation is they're kind of
getting up and running and so they have
to do some experiments and they have to
be doable in the time that's allowed and
they don't know what they're doing and
they don't know the statistics.
So of course they have to do bad
research and then.
But they're,
they're being trained at least in how to
do it.
And like,
like most,
most human enterprises aren't very
efficient.
So for example,
what do you guys think is,
what do you think's the average per
percent of profit that a typical say
North American Corporation makes over
like a 50 year period?
If you averaged it,
what's a good rate of return?
Ten percent.
Anybody?
Twenty five.
Anybody else?
Three.
Okay.
So three is the most accurate guests so
far.
Now it's a little higher than that.
But not much,
and you can kind of tell that because
if business produced a higher rate of
return than say three to seven percent,
no one would put their money in the
bank.
They all put their money in the stock
market,
right?
Because how much do you get right now?
If you put your money in the bank?
Nothing,
right?
One percent maybe if you're really
lucky.
So obviously business has to produce
more of return than that or everybody
would put their money in the bank,
but it's not a tremendous amount more.
And so what that means is that for your
typical corporation,
97 percent of what it does is,
is merely to keep itself running.
Only three percent.
Five percent is profit.
So why you,
why would you expect anything different
in scientific research?
It's like 95 percent of it's probably
rubbish,
but five percent is a lot.
When you think that there's tens of
thousands of research papers being
produced,
you know,
on a monthly basis.
So how fast do you want things to move
forward?
To me in some sense,
I think they're moving forward fast
enough,
right?
I mean,
it's already hard to keep up with things
like phones or anything electronic
because they change so frequently that
you know you have to continually force
yourself to readapt so it's not even
obvious how fast you want new knowledge
to be generated.
So the reason I'm telling you all this
is because I'm going to tell you a bunch
of things that I think psychologists do
wrong,
but I'm not telling you that because I
think psychologists do things
particularly wrong.
It's that almost everything that people
do is mostly just to keep things going
and then there's this little frog
fraction of the enterprise that might be
profit or it's equivalent in scientific
endeavor,
which would be the generation of new
knowledge.
And so you don't want to be.
You don't want to be cynical about that.
You need to know something about base
rates,
you know,
when these sorts of things help you to.
If you do something like apply to
graduate school.
So I'll,
I'll just talk to you very briefly about
that.
If you're going to apply to any place
that had that where you have a low
probability of getting in law school,
graduate school,
medical school,
business,
school,
some of what predicts whether or not you
get in as you grades,
letters of reference,
and your scores on the,
you know,
on the,
on the standardized tests.
Those are important.
Grades are the most important and then
performance on the standardized tests.
But once you hit threshold,
so maybe you're like an a minus student
and you do 70,
fifth percentile or above on the typical
standardized exam,
gre,
Ramcat,
cat or whatever it is.
Then what determines whether or not you
get in our random factors so when you
need to know that because all the time
when you're trying to progress in your
life,
some of whether or not you progress is
going to be dependent on you.
Your intelligence and your diligence and
and perhaps your creativity and your
emotional stability and other things
that we've talked about.
But some of it is just the variation in
the marketplace and it's random.
And so then the question is,
well,
how do you beat randomness in the
marketplace?
An answer to that is by playing many
different lotteries because it's all a
lottery.
So if you want to go to clinical
graduate school,
then you apply to 30 of them,
not two or three or 4:30 and there's
about that many in Canada that are
accredited now and there are schools in
the us that you can apply to and that's
hard.
Then it costs,
I think 50 to $75 a an application.
But that's trivial.
Like that's nothing,
that's an investment.
You don't worry about that.
You borrow for that if you have to.
And then you might say,
well I don't want to go to,
you know,
some little ratty town somewhere in
northern Ontario say.
Or there's ratty little towns
everywhere.
And the answer to that is,
well,
you can always say no when they accept
you,
right?
So maybe you'll get lucky and you'll get
to go to somewhere you want to go or you
think you want to go and find,
go there.
But maybe you won't get so lucky,
but someone will offer you a place at a
smaller institution.
Well then you have to think,
are you sure that there's not more
opportunity at that smaller institution
then you can make use of.
And the answer to that is yeah,
there is.
So for example,
where are you going to get a research
degree is nowhere near as important as
whether or not you go.
So the difference between no degree and
a degree is way bigger than the
difference between where you got your
degree.
So if you're going,
this is the same with applying for jobs.
Like one of the things you might realize
is that the return on a CV is probably
two percent if that.
So you can figure 25 applications for
one interview and then maybe one out of
three interviews or one out of four
interviews is going to get you a job.
So.
And you need to know that because
otherwise when you're applying for jobs,
you're going to get old disappointed
because you're going to think,
well Jesus,
I've sent out like 30 job applications.
I haven't got one response.
You know,
there must be something wrong with the
job environment or there must be
something wrong with me.
It's like,
well no,
there might be something wrong with you
and there might be something wrong with
the job environment,
but you need to keep baselines in mind.
It's a low probability event and so then
what you have to do when you're applying
for a job is like apply for two hours a
day and assume you're going to do that
for six months and don't burn yourself
out and don't get depressed or oppressed
by the fact that it's extremely
difficult because it is extremely
difficult.
So it isn't.
It isn't a commentary on you or it.
It's not a commentary on society.
It's just that it's a low base rate
phenomena.
Lots of jobs that are posted aren't
really.
They don't even exist.
The companies are just trying to keep a
turnover of hot resumes.
Some of them are.
They've already picked a candidate,
lots of places,
but they have to advertise by law,
you know,
so there's a whole bunch of reasons why
you're not going to get called back.
It's not the right day when they pick up
your resume,
they've been flooded with resumes.
There's all sorts of reasons.
So anyways,
baselines matter.
So back to psychologist.
What is psychologists do?
Well,
they do two things.
Hopefully they have to do both of these
to be successful.
They have to pursue scientific truth and
they have to pursue careers.
Now the problem is is that pursuing a
career in pursuing scientific truth are
not the same thing and so primarily
people focus on pursuing their career
and secondarily on scientific truth and
maybe it has to be that way,
that way it's possible that it has to be
that way,
but that's not so good.
It's better to pursue scientific truth
and then do what you can for your career
along the way because otherwise you end
up chasing things that don't exist for
your whole life and polluting the
scientific literature with nonsense and
that can have pretty bad personal and
also social consequences because you can
end up discovering things that don't
exist and then policy makers will make
educational policy say on the basis of
those recommendations and then that's
not good and that happens a lot.
So here's how you pursue scientific
truth.
Well,
the first thing,
and I'm not saying this is the only way
of defining reality,
you know,
we've talked about the phenomenologists
for example,
and the phenomenologists talk about
reality as lived,
right?
So it's reality that encompasses your
entire experience,
emotions,
motivations,
dreams,
all the things that are subjective plus
the objective world that isn't how it
works in science.
There's a rule in science and one of
them is if you're phenomena can't be
defined well enough to measure it,
then it doesn't exist scientifically.
And so that's the first rule.
You have to come up with a measurement
tool for your concept.
So,
and I'll tell you why that's important a
little bit later.
Then you have to take your measurement
and you have to see if it measures what
it's supposed to measure.
And that's a very tricky thing because
you have to figure out,
well what is it supposed to measure?
So let's say you come up with a measure
of anxiety,
okay,
well a,
what's the measure?
And B,
what's it supposed to predict?
Exactly.
A heart rate increase.
Say,
well,
no.
Sometimes people's heart rate decrease
when they get anxiety and sometimes
people's heart rate increases because
they're excited.
So skin conductance increase.
Well,
same problem.
Their skin conductance tends to rise
generally whenever you're putting any
sort of motivated state,
well self report,
well that's not so bad except maybe
people aren't that good at
distinguishing between guilt and shame
and disgust and anxiety and emotional
pain and frustration and disappointment
assuming that those things are actually
different.
So
it's a complicated problem to design a
measure and then to determine whether it
measures anything and also to determine
whether or not it measures what it's
supposed to measure.
And you do that.
The rules are quite straightforward.
One is that you should be able to
measure the phenomena of variety of
using a variety of different methods,
so then you get into the problem of what
constitutes different,
but you can think about it,
the analogy of your senses.
You have five senses and if all five of
them telling you that something there,
something is there,
the probability that it's there is quite
high and that's why we all managed to
live right?
Once you get five different reporting
systems telling you the same thing,
the probability that it's not there or
that you're wrong starts to become
vanishingly small.
So you sort of have to do that with your
measure.
So maybe it'd be a physiological measure
and a conceptual measure in a self
report measure and an observational
measure and a behavioral measure.
If you can get all of that and it
converges,
you know,
all the measures correlate,
then you might think,
well there's something actually there
and then you know,
you might also want to target something
in the real world to predict and that's
criterion related validity.
So you have to see if your measurement
is reliable,
measures the same thing more than once
in a role,
whether it can be the phenomena can be
detected in a variety of different ways
and whether that actually predicts
something that might be useful.
So I really liked the last one and I
think that's when where psychologists
like there's a lot of complaints about
psychology as a field right now,
especially in social psychology.
There's been a lot of scandal in the
general scientific literature including
medical literature.
You know,
people have been,
there was a guy a while back,
unfortunately I can't remember his name,
he had a Greek last name.
He published a paper showing
mathematically that on average the
reports that were submitted say in
medical journals had to be wrong.
They were too improbable.
He figured it out statistically,
you know.
And then there's been a recent attempt
to replicate some of the most
fundamental findings in psychology and
you know,
there's been some success at that,
but there's been plenty of failure too.
So one of the things I think that is
useful if you're thinking about a
research career is to pick a hard
target,
see if you can make progress on that
because that's one of the things that
puts constraints on your theorizing,
you know,
like what I try to do when I'm,
when I'm working out a concept I liked
to find out,
you could probably figure that out from
this course.
I like to see if there's like a solid
theoretical basis.
So the philosophy is solid and I like to
see if there's a brain model that'd be
kind of helpful.
I'd like it if it was derived from
animal experimentation rather than human
because I think that's more valid.
I'd like to see if there's a
pharmacological level of analysis,
if that supports it,
that'd be really good.
Some behaviors would be nice.
And then if there's self report data,
well all that's all to the good.
And if you get something that you could
measure across all five of those levels,
I think I mentioned five,
then you kind of think,
oh man,
there's probably something there.
Anxiety is a good example of that
because you can measure anxiety with
quest self report questionnaires,
you can get behavioral observations,
you can measure psychophysiology.
There's really good animal experimental
models.
Plus there's a pharmacology because we
know for example,
that you can give people benzodiazepines
or alcohol or barbiturates and that
dampens the response and there are the
reverse of those.
Actually there are drugs you can take
that make you more anxious that work on
the same basic systems.
So you might think a lot of that's been
Jeffrey Gray's work or the stuff he
summarized.
You can kind of think there's something
there and then there's the animal
behavior and so forth.
That also is indicative of anxiety.
That's your triangulation is getting
pretty complete by the time you have
five separate sources of information all
pointing to the same direction.
So,
and you know,
you really gotta be skeptical if you're
a scientist because the probability that
you're discovering something is very,
very low.
And so it's easy to,
especially with the statistics because
you know,
you tend to think of statistics as a
sort of little machine.
You'd dump in numbers at the top and you
crank it and outcomes knowledge at the
bottom,
and it's like,
that's just not true at all.
Statistics.
Is it an exploratory technique
fundamentally,
and you're making decisions all the time
about what constitutes a valid data.
So you know there's an outlier problem,
right?
So if you graph your data one dimension
across another,
you'll see people who are way the hell
out on the measurements for one reason
or another,
but,
and then you don't know whether you
should include them in the analysis,
which is deadly if it's a regression
analysis because it's really sensitive
to outliers or whether you should toss
them out,
but then there's the problem if you
tossed them out,
then maybe that makes it easier for you
to prove your hypothesis.
You know,
and you want to do that because you want
results because then you can publish
them.
So like it's a really tricky business.
It's an,
it's an ethical business all the way
because you have to make these decisions
that depend on your judgment.
And then you've got to ask yourself,
well,
when is your judgment valid?
And as far as I can tell,
the only answer to that is when you
actually know what you're aiming at.
And so for example,
if you're going to go into science as a
career,
you kind of have to decide is it a
in which case the scientific element of
it is subordinate or are you trying to
find something out?
And building a career as a consequence
of that.
And it's,
it's really good to walk through that
consciously because you know,
when you think about the value
hierarchies we've talked about before is
your value hierarchy determines the
decisions that you make and if you're
conflicted about whether it's career
promotion or truth.
While career promotion is gonna win out
because it's,
it's,
it's expedient,
there's a lot of pressure pushing on
youtube,
like get results to get good results,
to get publishable results and to get
lots of them.
And so that's a lot of pressure pushing
you to produce data that's better than
it.
That looks better than it is.
And I think these are all micro
judgments to say the problem of handling
outliers as well.
Their rules,
like if somebody is three standard
deviations below the mean and the
particular measure,
well then you can throw them out because
they're an outlier,
but well what if there two point seven,
five standard deviations from the meat,
it's like and there's only one of them
so they stick way out there or even two
standard deviations.
It's like how do you know when to get
rid of them and the answer is you have
to use your judgment so that you're
modeling the data in the best way
possible and one of the ways that I sort
of protect myself against that and my
students is I tell them to use their
statistics destructively,
which means okay,
you got a result,
see if he can make it go away,
fiddle with the data till it goes away,
see how hard that was or can you get the
same result using three different
approaches,
three different statistical approaches,
you know,
different cutoffs and so forth.
Can you,
if,
if you play with it multiple ways,
does your result only come out once?
If that's the case,
well maybe it's not there.
If you can make it go away,
maybe it's not there and you know,
that's hard on the students because I
had one student in particular,
he must've done eight studies,
lot of them were replications.
He'd get a result and then we tried to
replicate it and it wouldn't replicate.
And so,
you know,
he did that for like four years.
He never got anything that would
replicate and he could've published
because I couldn't let him publish
before we replicated.
But well,
the problem with that is then you set up
these red herrings that people chase,
you know,
he'd chase it and other people would
chase it and that can happen forever.
So
here's how you pursue a career.
This is the sort of the opposite to
pursuing scientific truth and one is
invent a scale or a construct or rename
a scale that already exists,
refused to validate it,
so you don't actually test it against
anything where it's a critical test and
then correlate it with some other
phenomena that maybe doesn't exist.
So I can tell you a couple of examples
of that.
Um,
one of the most recently,
and I think most scandalously was a
concept called grit.
So a woman whose name I can't remember
at the moment,
um,
Duckworth,
I think that's her name,
I hope that's her name.
Anyways,
she,
she did some research at the,
uh,
west point,
which is the place where the Americans
train their soldiers and she was trying
to figure out what predicted their,
their achievement and what she found was
that there were questions in a
questionnaire that she called Grit that
predicted performance and this,
this was big news man,
like she got a macarthur genius grant
for this work,
which is very rare thing to get.
And it was like headlines all over the
place,
grant and now if you look at the federal
government's publications on improving
education in the US,
it's like,
well,
we have to teach our children grit.
But if you look at her paper,
you find out that grit,
which is derived from a questionnaire
and we already know the questionnaire
rules,
right?
What's the questionnaire rule?
If it's a questionnaire,
then it measures one or more of the big
five traits either well or badly.
That's the rule.
While her grit questionnaire correlated
with conscientiousness,
like at about point seven five,
and she said,
well,
that only accounts for 50 percent of the
variance point seven,
five squared,
but as we know,
hopefully point seven five is an
insanely high correlation.
It's like if you give someone a
questionnaire once and then you give
them the questionnaire again and you
correlate their two scores,
unless it's a deadly good,
the test,
retest reliability is only going to be
about point seven five,
and so what that meant was grit measures
conscientiousness and conscientiousness
predicts performance.
Of course we already know that
conscientiousness predicts performance,
so that's not at best.
That would be an incremental addition to
a literature that's already well
established,
but hey,
who cares about that name?
It Grit
and then you know you.
Your career progresses rapidly,
especially if you're talking to people
who are clueless,
but you wore the whole structure of the
say the educational establishment
because now they're all shorting out and
you asked about teaching students grit.
It's like,
first of all,
it doesn't exist because it's
conscientiousness.
Second conscientiousness has a pretty
vicious biological basis.
Third,
to the degree that it's malleable,
we don't know how to teach it.
No one.
I've never seen a study ever that showed
that it increased people's
conscientiousness.
How do you do that?
I mean your parents tried to do that to
you for like 18 years.
Did it work?
You know,
work harder,
you know,
be more diligent,
pay more attention,
don't waste so much time.
It's like,
well,
they probably spent,
I don't know,
half an hour a day on you trying to
teach you that maybe it's like 150 hours
a year.
It's about 2100 hours over the course of
your life.
Assuming that they were that diligent.
So that's 2100 hours made you as
conscientious as you are now.
Another 20 hours of training is really
gonna make a difference.
It's like highly improbable.
So then I remember another study this
was done by shelley Taylor and Taylor
was the proponent of positive illusions.
How many of you have heard about
positive illusions?
Okay,
so what's a positive illusion?
Do you remember?
Perception?
Well,
she would've called it less than
grandiose.
The theory fundamentally is that people
buttress their self concepts with these
sort of mild deceptions about how
wonderful they are and she thinks that.
So for example,
she's,
she draws on data showing that if you
ask,
well let's try this,
how many of you think you are above
average drivers?
Really,
let's do this because I'd like to
replicate the experiment.
How many of you think that,
okay,
one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
How many of you think your average
drivers?
Okay,
one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10,
11,
12.
How many of you think you're below
average drivers?
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
seven.
Is that your voter?
Hers.
Okay.
So it looks.
So Taylor's hypothesis was that if you
ask often undergraduates in particular
if they think they're better than
average drivers,
I think maybe this isn't self report
rather than,
you know,
in an audience like this that most of
them say they're above average.
Now you guys failed that.
So that was a non replication as far as
I'm concerned because the mo about two
thirds of you said you were either
average or below average.
So,
but anyways,
hypothetically,
that evidence for this pervasive sort of
self aggrandizement in mild ways is
quite high and people who are like that
are happier.
Well
their wellbeing is better,
whatever wellbeing is.
So anyway,
she published this paper and there was
in the Journal of personality and social
psychology and she took all these.
So you might say,
well what's the positive illusion?
And the answer to that is,
well,
who knows,
try defining it.
Well how much,
when does it become a lie?
Well,
if it's too big,
well exactly how big.
Exactly.
When is it an illusion and when is it a
positive illusion?
When does that turn into like a
deception in windows?
That turned into a lot.
It's like that's really hard to.
It's not hard to specify.
It's bloody impossible to specify.
And then exactly.
What do you mean by wellbeing?
Okay.
So what she did in this one paper was
she took a bunch of measures that were
hypothetically aligned in some way with
positive illusions,
um,
and then she factor analyze them.
Okay.
And she took out the first factor and
she said,
well,
that's a positive illusion factor.
Got that.
Okay.
Then she took a bunch of outcome
measures which were like quantify
psychiatric scales that purported to
measure wellbeing and mental health,
and she factor analyze that and took out
the first factor.
And then she showed that the first
factor from the predictors correlated
with the first factor from the outcome
measures of course,
whether it was an outcome measure
predictor was,
you know,
just happened to be which call them,
you put them in.
But even worse,
if you take questionnaires and you
factor analyze them,
the first factor is usually
extroversion.
So basically what she did was factor
analyze one group of questionnaires and
go on extroversion,
which he called positive illusions.
And then she factor analyzed another set
of questionnaires and took out the first
factor and she called that psychological
wellbeing.
And then she showed the positive
illusion predicted wellbeing.
Except what she really showed was that
extroversion predicted extroversion,
which is to show nothing at all,
right,
but right,
but you got like,
you really got to watch this because you
got to assume that most of the
psychological studies that you're
reading are wrong in some important way,
and unfortunately you can only figure
that out if you read the actual results,
which is actually very difficult.
You can't read the results in 10
minutes.
Like you know,
it took somebody a whole year to do it.
You have to think through it and it's
hard and you know like that,
that paper,
for example,
criticizing how to critique that is not
obvious.
You have to know that if you take
questionnaires that measure emotion,
roughly speaking or something akin to
personality and you factor analyze them,
that's the first factor.
You're likely to pull out his
extraversion.
If you didn't know that,
then you wouldn't know what sort of
games were being played with the data.
So that happens all the time.
So here's some things.
Oh yes.
So then what do you do once you've got
your little phenomena,
you publish it and then you get some
other people who are interested in it.
So that's your little primate dominance
hierarchy and you don't want too many
people in that because then it's hard to
climb to the top but you don't want too
few because if it's just you and some
other jerk,
then you know
who cares about you.
So it has to be,
it has to be of moderate size,
right?
And then you use a bunch of jargon so
that you can separate yourself from the
criticisms of other people and then you
compete with each other to climb up the
hierarchy and it's a fairly small
hierarchy.
So you have a pretty good chance of
being like at least you know,
vice president or something like that.
Use your statistics selectively and then
enjoy the fruits of your success.
It's like it's a crummy way to go about
it and it's dangerous.
It's dangerous because public policy
people get jump all over this sort of
stuff and then bad things happen.
So.
And they will tell you some stories
about that.
So I told you already that psychologists
are having a hard time with replication.
It's like,
yeah,
everybody has a hard time with
replication,
but there's other problems to a.
because the damn journals won't publish
replications.
So if you're going to publish something.
So we've done studies like seven studies
in a row,
say trying to replicate based on a
finding that's hypothetically well
established in psychology.
So we're using it as a measure and be
damned if we can get it to work.
So we have like seven studies where it
doesn't work.
So you think you could publish seven
study saying you know what,
this thing that everybody thinks works,
it doesn't work.
You can't,
you can't publish non replications.
So that's a big problem.
You know,
the journals won't take them.
And so not only that,
the journals will rarely publish
replications themselves,
even if they're successful because they
don't contribute anything new to
knowledge,
you know?
And so you can work yourself half to
death and do a really good study,
you know,
and you find out,
oh this,
that didn't work.
And so maybe it took you two years,
like you're basically screwed because
what are you going to do with that?
Put it in a drawer somewhere and you
know,
maybe you're a bit wiser but it doesn't
advance your career.
So that's a big problem.
So part of the problem with sciences
that we forced scientists to only
discover things,
you know,
and that's,
they don't get rewarded otherwise.
And so it's a big problem and it's not
certainly not just psychologists that
have.
So okay,
here's some things I think don't exist.
So if you're going to predict anything
in the real world,
here's some things not to use.
I don't think self esteem exists is
wrote really one scale.
The Roman taffer automated self esteem
scale,
that's pretty good.
But the standard one is the Rosenberg
and I can't remember how many items it
has.
15 or something.
Not enough items to be,
to be reliable.
I think there were,
yeah,
25,000 published papers on self esteem
figure 10 grand to paper,
which is a true,
you know,
comparatively conservative estimation.
So you can do the math 25,000 times
10,000.
So that's the total amount of research
funding that's gone into looking at self
esteem.
It's like,
well what self esteem,
it's a word actually,
it's two words,
right?
But you know,
and,
and it's sort of something you think you
might have or not have,
but,
but that's a figure of speech that's not
an empirical phenomena.
And so most of your artists,
most of extroversion,
most of extroversion is just
neuroticism.
As it turns out,
it's like if you have a lot of negative
emotion,
you don't feel that good about yourself.
Well isn't that a surprise?
You have a lot of negative emotion,
you know,
and if you want to fix it up a little
bit,
then you can also subtract positive
emotion from that because if you have a
lot of negative emotion and you don't
have a lot of positive emotion,
so that's neuroticism minus
extroversion,
then your self esteem is even lower,
you know?
And then maybe over time
conscientiousness starts to make a bit
of a difference,
right?
Because if you're conscientious and you
work hard,
you can start to see that that's paying
off and calf rod has done some work that
seems to sort of indicate that.
But you know,
the first thing that happened is
everybody went on a self esteem bander
even though the measures were pretty
appalling and even though you could
model it with the big five,
and then one of the things that happened
as a consequence of that was that the
whole California school system started
to teach students self esteem.
It's like a,
what makes you think you should have
high self esteem?
Like maybe you're a miserable little
worm.
God only knows,
right?
It's not the case that you should have a
good opinion of yourself in every bloody
situation.
You know what?
If you're a bully who pounds people out
in the schoolyard,
bullies by the way do have higher self
esteem than normal.
So there because it's not like they're
feeling bad about themselves when they
pound you,
they're feeling bad about you and the
best work.
You know,
the low self esteem equals bully
hypothesis.
Lots of people believe that,
but if you read Dan always,
who's the world's leading authority on
bullying and who's actually done
something about it,
what he says is that bullies have
inappropriately high self esteem,
which is why they think they're in a
perfectly good position to pound you out
if you happen to be on the playground.
So it's not like they're suffering from
an,
you know,
neurotic weakness of self image.
It's quite the contrary.
So anyways,
in the California school system,
they tried to teach kids self esteem and
you know,
there's no evidence that you can do that
first because neuroticism is actually
quite hard to shift.
So.
And if we knew how to treat it well,
hooray,
everybody would be thrilled about that.
But it's not easy.
And second,
there are people like,
uh,
what's her name,
Jean,
when she used to be a student of Roy
ministers who claims that all that self
esteem training has just made younger
people like you guys more.
What do you call that?
Narcissistic.
Yeah.
Because the self esteem becomes
disconnected from the actual
accomplishment because you might hope,
well,
you'd sort of feel good.
How good should you feel about yourself?
Well,
you know,
you might say,
well,
you should grant yourself the right to
exist like you do.
Everyone else,
you know that sort of like a basic human
right as a human being,
you're valuable and then maybe you
should sort of think you're about as
valuable as other people roughly think
you are.
That seems about right,
right?
So the right amount of self esteem would
be your perception of your value within
the context of a group.
It's got to be something like that,
you know,
so there shouldn't be a concordance
because like maybe you need to improve.
Could well be,
you know,
and are you going to improve if you're
feeling really good about yourself?
Well the answer to that is what we don't
know.
How much misery about yourself do you
have to have before you're motivated to
improve yourself?
Not.
Well,
that doesn't seem right,
but we also don't know whether it's
shame or guilt or anxiety or pain or you
know,
these negative emotions that motivate
you.
Now it's clear that if you have enough
negative emotion that can paralyze you,
but that's like depression and and,
and you know,
psychiatrically high levels of anxiety
that's not like low self esteem,
so that's a problem.
I don't believe that working memory and
executive function are distinguishable
from ICU,
especially.
Gee,
our research,
we've done a lot of it.
I've added factor,
analyzed a battery of 10 dorsolateral
prefrontal tests done given to 3000
people.
It's a big,
very big sample.
We haven't published this for a variety
of reasons,
but one factor comes out and you know,
and Carol's rule for Iq,
as you take cognitive tests,
a bunch of them,
you fact around analyze them,
you pull out the first factor.
That's fluid intelligence.
It's like,
well that's basically what we found.
And so if you look at the correlation
between each of the single tests and the
first factor,
it's only about point three or point
four,
but that's also what you find in Iq
tests.
You know,
each individual test only correlates
with the aggregate at about point three.
But if you aggregate enough of them,
you get fluid intelligence and it's just
a solid as a rock.
So I'm emotional intelligence.
Not only does that probably not exist
because it's agreeableness,
it,
you know,
how you always hear,
you need emotional intelligence to,
to thrive in the workplace.
It's like turns out that's exactly
backwards.
Disagreeable people do better as
managers in the workplace.
So it's actually,
if you lack emotional intelligence,
you're more likely to be an effective
manager.
So an emotional intelligence is a great
indicator of sort of pathology and
psychology because it was invented by a
journalist,
you know,
you can't just have some word invented
by a journalist and then go make a whole
bloody,
you know,
enterprise out of it.
You got to find out if it,
if it's really there and there's not a
lot of evidence that it is.
And what does it mean anyways?
Emotional intelligence.
What does that mean?
I can infer what you're feeling.
Well,
is that Iq like our smart people better
at that or like,
am I mirroring you in some way or do I
care for you?
Like maybe I can figure out exactly what
you're feeling and I just don't give a
damn,
you know,
is that still emotional intelligence?
While I don't know.
Right.
How would you separate that from
sympathy or empathy and what and what if
you're over sympathetic to someone is
that emotional intelligence?
Like maybe you'll feel way too sorry for
your children.
So it's like you're all empathetic and
all that,
but you're not doing them any good or
sometimes you would be,
but sometimes you should say,
you know,
quit whining,
go the hell outside because that's the
right response sometimes.
So these things are not straightforward
at all.
And of course emotional intelligence is
generally measured with questionnaires
and we know the rule for questionnaires.
What's the rule for questionnaires?
That's right,
exactly.
It's measuring one or more of the big
five either well or badly.
Okay.
So and,
and as far as I can tell,
that doesn't mean that personality as a
five dimensional structure.
I'm not making that argument because who
the hell knows?
I don't think it does likely,
although it's very difficult to say,
but what the big five theorists have
really demonstrated as far as I'm
concerned,
is that if you factor headlights,
questionnaires,
what you get looks a lot like a five
factor structure and you can do that
cross culturally and so I think we sort
of nailed the question of how our
questionnaire is structured so you can't
just invent some new thing in term.
It's something and then pretend it
something new without testing it against
and I would test it against Iq because
that bloody thing.
We know for example,
Iq eats up most of the variance in
disgust.
Sensitivity scales.
You would think,
well,
why?
Why would I qb related to disgust
sensitivity.
It's inversely related.
By the way,
the smarter you are,
the less sensitive you are to discuss.
Now I don't know if that's because maybe
your cortical inhibition of underlying
like limbic limbic motivational systems
is better.
Who the hell knows?
We don't know why,
but we do know that it's a major
predictor.
Orderliness also predicts,
but the thing about Iq is that it
predicts things that you'd never expect,
so you should validate your scale
against Iq and against the big five and
not some trivial little 10 item measure
of the big five either because then if
you use two questions per trade,
you're going to have a lousy measure of
the big five and if you're stupid
questionnaire predicts over and above
that,
all that means is that you didn't test
it against you.
No,
you didn't set it up for a good
challenge.
You set it up for a week challenge.
So grant,
that's very annoying.
Yes,
that's very annoying because it's
clearly.
I think it was correlated.
I think I told you this was correlated
with conscientiousness of point seven,
five.
I don't believe that optimism and
pessimism exist.
I don't believe that promotion and
prevention exist.
Empathy.
We tried measuring empathy.
It's like we use.
You can measure empathy like mad if you
use one measure,
but he was three.
Then all of a sudden your empathy
measures don't correlate,
so that really sucks.
So the way out of that is just to use
one measure,
right?
Well obviously not if you're three
empathy measures don't correlate while
you got a problem.
It's like you have three rulers and you
measure something and you get different
numbers from each.
It's like really?
That's probably you're either measuring
like bubblegum,
well it stretching or there's something
wrong with your rulers.
So I don't think psychopathy exists.
I think it's low agreeableness and low
conscientiousness because that would
make you a Predator that's low
agreeableness and a parasite because
that's low conscientiousness.
So that kind of sums up psychopaths in
terms of personality disorders.
There was a bunch of them and you know
over the last 20 years people have been
the psychometricians in particular.
I'd be trying to cram those things into
the big five structure and they're
reaching,
they're experiencing a tremendous amount
of resistance from the established
psychiatric community and no wonder but
the but it still lift big five does seem
to be able to provide a pretty good
model of what constitutes personality
pathology.
And that's kind of surprising because
you may remember I told you when,
when the personality measures were first
originated,
they threw out all the evaluative words
like evil or bad or,
or good for that matter,
and you know,
you could imagine that that would
attenuate the relationship between
personality and psychopathology because
you tend to use more anti,
more judgmental words when you're
describing psychopathology,
like antisocial for example,
which isn't in a personality
questionnaire,
but which if it was,
would likely load primarily on low on
agreeableness,
low
positive illusions told you about that
already practical intelligence.
It's like,
no,
that does not exist and there's no
evidence that it exists.
So Sternberg who has said that part of
the reason he was interested in
practical intelligence was because he
didn't do very well on his gres.
So,
um,
you know,
he's got this idea that,
well there's a difference between book
smarts and that sort of nerdy people and
like,
you know,
street smarts,
which is like,
I don't know,
the punk who makes it out in the real
world,
something like that.
And Street smarts is like practical
intelligence with.
The problem is is that he never really
puts his practical intelligence
measures,
which really don't exist up against Iq
in a fair head to head fight and he's
being just slaughtered for this in the
scientific press,
especially by Linda.
God Fredson who wrote that paper that I
had you guys read on,
you know,
the complexity of everyday life.
God's since she's a smart cookie,
that woman,
and she's brave too,
you know,
because she follows the data where it
goes and she's a very,
very clear thinker.
She really gave Sternberg couple of good
wax and he certainly deserved it.
Multiple intelligences.
You've heard about that.
I've imagined.
What are they?
Sensory Motor.
Kinesthetic,
emotional.
I don't remember.
What's that?
Interpersonal.
Yeah.
Those aren't intelligences.
First of all,
a who knows if they exist and be.
We had a perfectly good word for them,
which was talent.
It's like you can't just take a word,
you know,
like that's been studied for 100 years,
like intelligence,
which has a very,
very specific,
a specific definition,
more specific than anything social
scientists measure.
Right?
So if you believe in social science at
all,
you have to take Iq into account.
He just swipes the word says,
oh,
well everybody wins.
You know?
It's like,
yeah,
people have talents,
fair enough,
you know,
and they're not trivial.
But to call them intelligences.
And then he also says,
when people harass him about his
concepts,
he says,
well,
I don't really believe in measurement.
It's like,
okay,
that's fine.
Except if you're like,
if you're not going to believe in
measurement,
then what are you doing?
It's not science.
It might be,
I don't know what it is.
Maybe it's educational philosophy or
something like that,
but it's not science.
And so it's 20 years later with his
multiple intelligence theories and
there's be no published measures of
them.
And whenever people have tried to
measure them and set them up head to
head against say intelligence plus
personality intelligence and personality
just eats them up.
And so,
you know,
multiple intelligence theory had a big
effect on educational theory.
You know,
it's like,
well,
every child should have the opportunity
to develop their own particular form of
intelligence.
It's like,
yeah,
well that's great except you can't
measure it.
We don't know if it exists and even if
it does,
we don't know how to develop it and you
haven't shown that you can develop it
and you haven't shown that you're not
doing harm by,
you know,
pretending that these things exist and
act as if that's actual knowledge.
So
things that might exist.
Well,
I told you about these already while
there's lots,
you know,
I talked to you a lot about the big
five,
you know,
but personality isn't that great.
A predictor of individual behavior
because people are very variable in
their behavior from situation to
situation.
So the best you ever get out of a
personality measures about point three
or maybe about point four,
that was discovered in 1968.
There was a big hubbub about that made
by Walter Michelle who said,
well,
personality scales,
they give you a point to point three.
That's like nine percent of the variance
at best.
So what about the other 90 percent and
why are we chasing such a trivial amount
and that killed personality research,
Stone Dad,
four til 1992.
So for 20,
that's 24 years I believe because
everybody went,
oh yeah,
these are trivial effects,
but then no one ever looked to see what
the effects were in all the rest of
psychology because it turned out that
point two,
point three is about on the upper end of
the effects that you get in most forms
of psychology and so that even if it
isn't that great,
it's as good or better than whatever one
else is doing.
And so then there are also economic
analysis which we'll show you later done
in the 19 nineties that showed that
because human variability in
productivity is so great,
especially on the Prieto distribution,
that you don't need very accurate
predictors for them to be extremely
useful economically.
Because the question might be,
you know,
like,
so you're paying your employee $50,000 a
year and you can,
you could potentially pick an employee,
an employee that was one standard
deviation above the mean higher than
average on conscientiousness.
So with some bad measure,
you know,
so over 10 employees you get an average
of one standard deviation higher,
something like that.
The real question is,
well,
what's the economic return on that?
And the answer is well,
because people are so variable in their
performance when some people do like
their crazily productive and others are
like,
they actually detract from the function
of the organization that they figure
about 40 percent of managers,
ab negative net value to the companies
they work for.
So it's like the productivity line
doesn't end.
It's zero.
It's like if you're a particularly bad
manager,
you can be sucking money out of the
enterprise like Matt.
Well it turns out that even small
predictors have huge economic value.
So even though they're not that good,
the amount that they are good is better
than interviews for example,
by quite a substantial margin.
And so if you're gonna hire people and
you want better people,
then you can use personality tests and
that that actually works.
So what,
what's real well,
cultural factors are real.
The,
the effects of your peer networks,
that's real.
The degree to which like one thing you
guys should think about as you progress
through life is that,
you know,
there's a variety of things that make
you successful.
Intelligence is one,
intelligence is another.
Those are pretty rough.
The breadth of your social network,
that's a big deal too.
That's something to think about.
You know,
people talk about,
I hate this word schmoozing,
it's a horrible word and I wouldn't
recommend that anybody ever does that
because that's sort of making
connections for the sake of having them.
But you know,
as you get older you'll find that of
course the people that you know get
older too and they get centralized and
more and more in positions with more and
more influence.
And so what that means is that one of
the things that makes you valuable as
you get older is how well connected you
are in a sort of broad social network.
Because a lot of what happens if someone
comes to you and says,
well,
here I've got a problem.
I mean one potential response to that as
well,
all solve it,
and another potential response is,
well,
I don't know how to solve that,
but I know this guy or this woman,
and they do know how to solve it,
so you know that that's an extremely
useful.
That's an extremely useful additional
attribute and we haven't measured that.
We don't.
We have measured that much.
I think it's one of the things that give
older people in edge on younger people.
Younger people are smarter in terms of
fluid intelligence.
They're not as conscientious though when
their social networks are nowhere near
as well developed.
I put that slide together about a year
ago.
It's kind of an interesting one.
I think you can see just from the facial
expressions,
were these people sort of map pay while
Jim Carey,
you could hardly get extroverted than
him.
It's like he's on cocaine all the time.
Mr Rogers,
he's agreeable.
You wouldn't know the next guy.
His name was able to go to a played.
He played a very introverted policemen
on an old sitcom.
What do and while he's neurotic is can
be a castle high in openness.
Jimmy Stewart,
very high in emotional stability house.
What's houses primary characteristic?
Disagreeable.
He's really disagreeable.
He's very,
very intelligent,
right?
But he's super disagreeable.
So.
But that's what makes him interesting.
Robert mentioned was the same then.
I'm Clint Eastwood,
disagreeable,
introverted and emotionally stable.
Right?
So
it's quite interesting to see how varied
the facial expressions are.
So you guys of course remember this will
just take a look at it briefly,
so to,
to clue you in.
So the big predictor seemed to be
industriousness,
emotional stability,
agreeableness.
If you're working with people and
disagreeableness if you're working with
things and plasticity,
openness gives you creative achievement
plus entrepreneurial ability and
extroversion is pretty good.
We just published a paper using the
creative achievement questionnaire,
which I'll show you a bit later and what
we found was that openness was a very
good predictor of,
of creative achievement,
but so is extroversion.
So I think that's probably because if
you're going to be an artist or a
creative type,
you better be a bit of a marketer,
you know,
because it's one thing to sit in your
garret and paint things,
but what'll happen is you'll starve to
death and then you know,
100 years later someone will sell one of
your paintings for $25,000,000,
which is not very helpful for you,
but if you're extroverted,
you're going to get out there a bit and
be enthusiastic about what you're
producing and maybe that gives you an
opportunity to market it.
We also know that openness and
extroversion together make up
plasticity,
right?
And plasticity actually seems to be a
better predictor of creative achievement
than openness per se.
So which is
there's several,
several hundred people in this
particular sample.
So
you guys know about this already.
Extroversion is associated with
happiness,
optimism,
enthusiasm,
gregariousness,
and assertiveness,
neuroticism,
it.
It correlates negatively with longterm
life outcome.
A bet.
It's not that powerful,
but it's,
it's,
it's there.
A height.
People high in neuroticism have a hard
time with stress so they can get.
I think what happens with neuroticism is
you pass a certain point of
vulnerability,
you know,
if you're too high in neuroticism and
then some life event comes along that's
just too much and sucker punches you and
then that further destabilizes your
nervous system and you're,
you're kind of out of the game at that
point.
So if you're high in negative emotion,
you know you want to.
I would say the first thing I would say
is make sure you eat breakfast.
Sounds like a weird suggestion,
but I know from my clinical practice
that if I can get my,
my clients who are high in negative
emotion to eat a decent breakfast,
that helps stabilize their nervous
system throughout the day.
You really got to watch yourself if
you're high in negative emotion because
your stress tolerance isn't that great.
So you might also want to not take like
really,
really stressful jobs because they grind
you down over time.
So that's something to think about.
So agreeableness,
compliance,
empathy,
materiality,
kinship.
Now on the negative side,
if it gets extreme,
it's criminality,
but disagreeable people are tough
minded.
They're hard to push around,
you know,
and they can be a little bit on the
catalyst side and you know,
you think,
well,
is that a useful attribute?
Oh,
I know this one guy who is dismissed,
disagreeable as you can possibly
imagine,
you know,
like,
and he,
I was watching him work at a large
corporation.
He was firing people because the
corporation was shrinking,
like mad.
It was like was,
it,
was having a real rough time.
So they had to downsize and I asked him
how he handled the emotional stress of
having to fire people and he said,
well,
he,
that he enjoyed it and I thought,
wow,
that's not something that I've heard
very often.
He said,
yeah,
I mean most of the people that are fire
or they've been useless and they've been
like a existing on other people's Labor
for like 10 years.
No one's ever called them on it.
So it doesn't bother me a bit.
I just think of all the people who
they've been interfering with and,
and I think,
well,
good,
you deserve to be gone and you don't
have to be a tough son of a bitch to do
that,
you know,
you think about that,
you think about that because,
and I do a fair bit of management
consulting.
So let's say you're a manager and you've
got 10 employees and one of them is hard
to get along with and not productive.
And so because they're hard to get along
with,
they make everyone else's life more
miserable than it has to be and because
they're not productive,
then everybody else has to do their
work.
So then you might say,
well,
you know,
what are you going to do about that
person?
And I don't know,
maybe they have a sick parent.
You know that too because people are
complicated.
So what do you think you think,
wow,
this person's in place in their life.
And uh,
so what do you do about that?
Well,
you think maybe if you're compassionate,
you think,
well,
you know,
they've,
they've got a difficult situation at
home.
They've got a sick parent,
this isn't a really good time to fire
them,
La Blah Blah,
but then you think,
what about those other nine people you
know going to work for them that's not
near as good as it could be and like
they're working hard but they're not
benefiting from it and plus the fact
that this person gets away with it is
demotivating and unfair.
So then you've got to ask yourself,
well,
exactly who are you being empathic with?
And this is a hard question.
Like it's seriously,
this is a very difficult question when
you're in an organization and you're
trying to build something that goes into
a particular direction.
It's like,
well what's your threshold?
Like my experience,
and I wouldn't say I'm very good at this
because I'm kind of tender hearted,
much to my chagrin so,
but my experience doing management
consulting with people is that if they
have someone who is a problem and
they've been a problem for say a
substantial amount of time,
everybody's happier when that person
leaves,
often the person themself.
Not always obviously,
but sometimes people are miserable and
hard to get along with.
An unproductive because they hate their
bloody job and someone should just kick
them out of it so they can go on and
find something,
you know,
that they might be half decent tap.
So.
And people tend to be quite resilient.
So even if they do end up out of a job,
it isn't exactly clear that six months
later that's worse for them.
So anyway,
so that's,
that's,
I think disagreeable people are better
at that.
So if there's a rule,
a disagreeable person will say,
you buy,
abide by the rule,
I don't care about your damn feelings.
It's like,
well that's Kinda harsh.
Maybe
conscientiousness.
That's a big predictor.
Openness that's associated with
creativity.
Intelligence.
Here's some combinations.
If you're disagreeable and neurotic,
you tend to have a personality disorder.
So those are the two big personality
markers of personality disorders.
If you're extroverted and disagreeable,
think about that.
You know,
people like this,
they're really social in there.
Really.
You know,
they're,
they're not that empathic,
they're selfish,
they're narcissists.
If you're extroverted and disagreeable,
you have a proclivity towards narcissism
and you might think,
well that's an awful thing and maybe it
is,
but
actors,
I mean how,
how narcissistic do you have to be to be
an actor?
Oh,
that's a hard question,
right?
Because you obviously have to have some
self confidence that goes beyond the
norm.
So
anyway,
so
this is a summary of what we knew about
emotion and motivation in relationship
to the abortion,
so we know that extroversion is
associated with incentive reward,
hope,
curiosity,
play enthusiasm.
That seems to be associated with
dopaminergic function and with the part
of the hypothalamus that governance
exploratory behavior.
So it's an approach circuit and so it
seems that people who are extroverted
have a lower threshold for having that
circuit activated.
Maybe it's something like that or,
or maybe they're there unless they're
stimulated,
they don't have enough positive emotion.
It's not that easy to tell.
Extroverts harvest attention from the
social group.
So you think about these as ways of
adapting to the world.
Like the social group is full of
resources and if you're assertive and
you're popular,
than you can benefit from the accrual of
social resources.
That puts you up the dominance
hierarchy.
So it's a good strategy for moving.
It's one good strategy for moving ahead.
Um,
neuroticism,
pain,
frustration,
disappointment,
fear,
anxiety.
Those two seem to be associated with
Gaba circuits because those are the
circuits that value and barbiturates and
benzodiazepines effect.
And it's also the case that as you move
up the dominance hierarchy and your
serotonin levels rise,
your negative emotion gets more
well-regulated.
Whereas if you fall down on the
dominance hierarchy,
then your negative emotions get less
regulated.
Probably your positive emotions too
agreeable.
This empathy,
sympathy compliance care system,
that's the care system that Jaak
Panksepp described.
So if you're interested in that,
you could read a bit more about that.
That's maternal circuitry essentially
now runs on oxytocin.
So agreeable people can always tell when
I have an agreeable person in my
clinical practice because what happens
when they come in is that they instantly
start to talk about relationships and
also their layout,
their biography,
and like a conscientious person.
We'll talk about the things they have to
do and the things they've done over
their life and an open person will say,
well,
here's the things I'm really interested
in,
you know,
but an agreeable personal say,
well,
from 19 seven,
1982 to 1987,
I went out with this person and then I
had a relationship with this person.
And so they naturally seem to configure
their biographies in terms of dyadic
intimate relationships.
So whereas the disagreeable people,
you know,
well they're,
they're,
they're not so good at that kind of
thing.
And if you talk to engineers,
for example,
and I've talked a lot about silicon
valley,
it's there,
they're pretty oriented towards things
and their interpersonal skills can be
well interesting to say the least,
but you know,
they invent lots of interesting things.
So like Hooray,
go,
go engineers.
We've talked about conscientiousness and
it seems to be associated with disgust
and guilt and shame and the,
if you think about it as an adaptive
strategy,
orderliness means stay on contaminated
and sparkly,
clean.
You know,
it's like an efficiency strategy.
Everything in its place.
And so that way you don't have to expend
as much energy to get the results of
your labor.
You know what it's like if you're trying
to work in your office and it's a
complete bloody disaster,
right?
You expand the whole bunch of energy
just coping with the fact that you're
surrounded by chaos before you even get
down to what it is that you're supposed
to work at.
Industriousness,
while industrious people seem to
implement their goals and maybe they
have some social utility to I would
suspect,
right?
Because if you're an industrious person
and you get a reputation for that,
then people are gonna want you around
because like you'll do the work.
And one thing I will tell you that that
might also be useful as you progress
through life is that if you get into an
organization and you are diligent and
you know and you really commit to what
you're doing,
you might think
you might be cynical about whether or
not that's going to be noticed.
But I'll tell you,
if you're not conscientious,
you'll never figure out why you don't
advance.
What'll happen is that a bunch of doors
that could open to you just won't
because if you're a conscientious,
so like I find this with my students.
Some of them I can say because I have
more opportunities than I know what to
do with usually.
And so if I have students I can say,
well,
you know,
here you could do this,
and then if they come back three weeks
later and they say,
well,
here's four reasons why I couldn't do
it,
and they're all good reasons,
you know,
but it's not done.
And then someone else comes back and
it's four weeks later and they say,
here it is.
Then the next time I have an opportunity
to end the person who did it gets it.
And so what happens is that in almost
all organizations,
there's a certain percentage of people
who are conscientious and intelligent
and are doing almost all the work and
they're always looking around for other
people who are like that.
Like they don't go out of their way to
advertise it.
But if,
if you're like that and you come to
their attention,
they'll open doors for you.
And you won't even know it,
and so it'll be like your progress
upwards and there's no reason that you
leave a necessarily knowing why.
Whereas if you're not doing it,
people won't come out and whack you on
the head and say,
well,
you should improve in these six ways and
you know,
pay a lot of attention to you.
They just won't allow you to have any
opportunities and then you won't even
know it.
So that's not good unless you want to
know,
unless you're not that ambitious,
which you know is not necessarily a bad
thing.
Open people will open.
People are good at manipulating
abstractions.
And so what they seem to do is to model
the world abstractly and to figure out
what strategies will work.
And then maybe they can implement them
if they're conscientious and if they
can't implement them well maybe they can
offer them to other people you know.
So you have good ideas that has some
value.
And so I was thinking that
we don't exactly know how to integrate
the trait theory into the narrative
theories.
You know,
there,
because almost all of the clinical
theories of psychology are narrative
theories and they all seem to have to do
with this kind of story that you act
out,
but I've been thinking that maybe this
is one of the ways that you could
conceptualize it anyway,
so the little frames of reference that
you find yourself in that,
that govern your perceptions and that
help you determine your actions are
maybe motivated by constellations of
fundamental motivational systems.
So you know,
we,
we talked a little bit about
hypothalamic function and the really
basic motivational and emotional states.
Well,
it seems like they sort of clumped
together in the traits.
So we know extroversion is where the
positive emotions clump.
A negative neuroticism is where the
negative emotions clump,
play seems to go along with extroversion
and then abstract creativity and
exploration seems to go along with
openness and so on.
And so there's these like maybe the
traits or something like amalgam stable
amalgams of emotions and motivation,
something like that.
And then they're,
those stable amalgams produce the
frameworks within which you operate.
So here's an example.
So
if you're extroverted,
you're goal is going to be,
well there's a group I'm going to
integrate myself into it and I'm going
to make my presence known and enjoyable
because we know for example,
that like parties and so that's an
adaptive strategy because they have the
social hierarchy out there and that
that's a place where rewards can be
obtained and so are fundamental tilt is
towards exploitation of the social
surround.
It's probably a bit of a trade because
extroverts,
you know,
there it can be very amusing to be with
and they're always trying to entertain
people so it's not like it's a one way
street.
Whereas you know,
someone who's more,
more conscientious is going to be well
you know,
this place is in bad order and it needs
to be repaired and we should do
something to straighten that up.
And so that's like a generalized rubric
that they're using to apply to the world
in every different situation.
And so that's.
So it sort of like base level
motivations and emotions.
The first order aggregation,
which gives you maybe the five
dimensions and then those actor as the
underlying,
what the underlying primarily biological
systems that tilt your perceptions in
your actions toward certain niches in
the environment.
So the agreeable person is going to go
for relationships.
The disagreeable person is going to be
selfish somewhat or self oriented
anyways,
and competitive.
These are all ways that you can go
through the world.
If you're high in negative emotion,
then you're going to be quite concerned
with making sure that things are secure
and safe.
You can see that those are all valid.
A priory theories about how you might
adapt to the different niches that the
world provides.
So,
so then I would say that it's something
like that.
These hierarchies of values are built up
around the fundamental trait
orientations.
It's something like that.
So,
you know,
for an extrovert,
something down here might be,
tell a joke,
you know,
plan a party,
um,
go to a bar,
you know,
those are all made up of obviously
implementable,
implementable behaviors,
but they're fairly,
they're fractured and elements of what
constitutes extroversion.
What is it?
Well,
that's probably pretty good.
Yeah.
Okay,
so we'll stop there and then I'll see
you on Thursday and that's it.
You guys know the final is cumulative,
I presume so it'll only be covering the
material that was from the last test and
it'll be the same format as the other
tests.
So you're familiar with them,
you know what's coming.
Okay.
See you on Thursday.