Yeah.
So yeah,
my name's Christine van Gyn.
I'm currently the Ontario director of
the Canadian Taxpayers Federation.
Uh,
we work on issues of lower taxes,
government waste and accountability.
And oddly enough,
this is the third time in six months
that I've done a speech or talk publicly
about the issue of free speech and
specifically free speech on campus.
Um,
I think that this is a defining topic
and mood of of 2017 and oddly support
for free speech is increasingly falling
along partisan or ideological lines.
Now CTF,
we at the Canadian Taxpayers Federation,
we deal exclusively with fiscal and
economic issues and you would think that
that subject,
government debt,
generational debt and balanced budgets,
you know what,
you would think that that's non
controversial but not so on university
campuses.
Our student group,
a generation screwed,
has been kicked off of campuses,
had room space denied and we were even
told by one university student union
that we may need to change our name
generation screwed because screwed is
oppressive.
So while we may not have encountered the
kind of blow back that some of,
uh,
some of the speakers today will have
received from universities,
um,
it just goes to show you how little it
takes to trigger a university
administrators and students on campuses
and just how restrictive and ham fisted,
uh,
they,
they can work at how they can act when
restricting speeds.
So,
uh,
with that,
I will introduce our speakers.
Uh,
our first panelist is God sad.
He's the professor of marketing at
Concordia University,
Montreal Canada.
He's the holder of the Concordia
University Research Chair in
evolutionary behavioral science and the
Darwinian con con consumption,
sorry.
He,
uh,
is also quilt.
No wait,
quite well known for his popular Youtube
Channel.
The sad truth.
A channel that has garnered over 4
million views.
Yeah.
Okay.
So everyone,
please welcome God sad.
Okay.
Our second panelist is they're not
sitting in the right order,
but I'll enter.
This is the order in which they will
present a,
it's a,
it's John carpay on the far end.
He's the president of the Justice Center
for Constitutional Freedoms and
organization that he founded to defend
the constitutional freedoms of Canadians
through litigation and education.
He has a BA in political science at
Laval University in Quebec City and a
law degree from the University of
Calgary.
So please welcome John Carpet.
And our third panelist is Jordan
Peterson's.
He did in the middle.
He's a psychology professor at the
University of Toronto and a clinical
psychologist with two main areas of
study,
the psychology of belief,
including religion,
mythology and political ideology,
and the assessment and improvement of
personality,
including the prediction of creativity,
academic and industrial performance.
So everyone,
please welcome John and Peter
and we're going to begin with remarks
from Mr Sod.
Thank you very much.
All right,
so apparently a food restaurant or here
in Ottawa caused me some food poisoning.
So even the restauranters are trying to
stifle my famous speech because I almost
didn't make it to the session.
Uh,
so what are some strategies for stifling
opposing opinions?
If you live in a dictatorship,
then of course you just killed the
intellectuals.
Those who oppose you,
you get rid of them.
If you are unable to implement such a
strategy,
then you perhaps have some hate speech
laws or some campus speech codes and of
course what flows from that is the
third.
A way to stifle people is to create an
environment that is sufficiently ominous
that people engage in self censorship.
This picture right here is worth a
thousand words.
It basically says we condemn freedom of
speech that hurts other people's
feelings.
What I'm going to do for the rest of
today's lecture is simply read to you
first person accounts of emails that I
received.
I received these in there enumerable.
How many I received were for either
students,
professors,
parents are writing to me to document
the stuff that they are facing on
campuses.
And the best way to actually show you
this is to just read a bunch of them.
So bear with me as I actually go through
about seven or eight of these.
The clock by the way,
is not working.
So I don't know how much time we have,
but I'll assume we're okay.
So here is a student testimony example
one I'm a 47 year old white male who
because of an injury made a choice to
return to school.
Sadly,
it looks like my path through university
is going to be interrupted and the first
year to maintain full time status,
I'm forced to take another social
justice black lives matter.
Of course,
the challenge is students are not
allowed to challenge or question the
course content because that's considered
disrespectful and may disrupt someone's
safe space.
I believe I am a respectful students
with good attendance and who's the marks
average in the mid eighties that said,
after a few weeks of the one side is
syllabus,
I'm considering dropping out of the
program and leaving school entirely.
This left,
this academic world is a little too much
for me.
Testimony to today,
we had a panel discussion on the Quebec
city shooting with two historians and
two sociologists where I was told with
solid moral,
righteous stone that there is no such
thing as good and bad immigrants.
My heart was racing and my teeth were
clenched,
sorry,
and grinding to this.
Finally,
the spite my heart beating out of my
chest.
I asked a question,
how do you,
the panel interpret Charlie Hebdo,
the Danish cartoon,
Isis Salman Rushdie and the bataclan
shootings.
The denial of individual responsibility
and complete disregard for any value
based interpretation was off the table.
I think I screwed myself because I'm
pretty sure my professor is,
let's say,
quite suspicious of me now because this
person aired his opinion.
He knows that he's in trouble.
I just feel really alone,
but the thought of restoring strength,
tolerance and diversity of factory
university really keeps me going today.
Just really proved to me that I'm up
against and how alone I am.
What can I do?
I'm reaching out to you in the hopes
that the godfather that's yours truly
would be able to help direct my future
research projects.
Since most professors and required
courses I have to take seem to be run by
Social Justice Warriors Feigning
Intellectual Ism.
The reason I'm contacting you is because
as an honors cognitive student,
part of my requirements is to complete
12 credits worth of individual research.
However,
because of purely political reasons,
I'm apparently a violent,
misogynist,
racist trump supporter.
I have not only lost my job at a
prestigious behavioral neuroscience
laboratory.
I had the identity at why,
why,
but my name has been removed from the
publication on research I personally
conducted and the lead researcher told
me that he would never work with me
again.
This is not North Korea,
this is Canada.
This is US help.
I'm a fourth year student and a five
year teaching program.
I'll be heading to why,
why,
and next year for my one year of
Teacher's college,
only recently have I realized the
radical left wing messages embedded in
virtually all of my classes and I know
that it will only get worse at the
school in question.
What can I do about this?
How do I stand up for the truth without
risking my career as an elementary
school teacher?
Thank you.
Let's move on to some faculty.
Those were all students.
I very much appreciate your courage to
fight the cancer that is taking over
American academia.
People like me feel cheated and their
attempt to pursue a tenure track career.
It only takes a glimpse to the job
offerings that the modern language
association publishes each year to
understand what is expected from recent
graduates like me.
It is political activism and I refuse to
mix that with my academic interests.
I will save you my long stories of
dealing and suffering career wise from
politically correct nonsense from the
directions of feminism,
gender,
ideology,
trans extremism and Islamophobia.
I am trying to keep a lid on things for
now as my wife is very,
as a very promising academic but hasn't
security position yet.
I know that if I started voicing my
thoughts and arguments on social media,
she'll be completely shut out of the
academy.
If she does secure a tenure track spot,
I'm off to the races and you and others
would see that I'm an ally to take
notice of.
Seriously.
I'm more than happy to transition out of
philosophy at this point,
which has become a virtue signaling
competition.
As a fellow professor who has been
frustrated by the discourse within
academia on issues such as political
correctness,
moral relativism,
and social justice.
I'd like to thank you for speaking up
the way you have,
uh,
been from within academia.
Why my training and research as further
removed from social issues than yours?
I have nevertheless been frustrated by
the conformism and group think I see and
hear around me.
I see.
Otherwise very reasonable and capable
people abandoning reason and counting to
the narrative of the regressive left on
many social issues.
These are all things which I would like
to get involved in once the tenure
decision is behind me,
about one year to go.
As upsetting as it is,
one fierce expressing unpopular social
ideas prior to tenure and the meantime,
please keep fighting the good fight for
freedom of speech and against start
policing and orthodoxy.
Almost done.
I won't read this whole one,
but basically this person writes to me
and thanking me for my conversation with
Sam Harris,
agreeing with some of the issues that I
raised regarding some issues dealing
with Islam.
But then look at the bottom.
He says if you decide to mention this
information in your videos,
I would ask that you do so without
mentioning my name.
I do not have tenure yet.
This is from uh,
uh,
this is the last testimony and then I'll
wrap up.
This is from a parent of a high school
student.
I recently received an email from my
son's school district that they are
going to be screening a film called,
I'm not racist,
am I as an in school field trip at the
end of January for high school students.
I did some preliminary research on this
and I'm absolutely appalled at the
content of the movie based on the
descriptions,
the trailer and additional materials
surrounding it.
It appears to be a feature length film
pushing the agendas of white privilege,
institutional racism and white people
are the problem.
It's scares me beyond belief that they
are attempting to force these ideas on
developing minds and now of course the
usual request that they be anonymous for
reference.
My son is a junior at xxx.
I have included the original email as
well as the pdf of the communication
that was sent out.
If it is something you feel you should,
you should,
should be shared with others.
I only ask that you keep identifiable
information from my son or myself out
for our safety.
This is not North Korea for his safety.
I'm sure you understand.
So to conclude,
freedom of speech is everything and I
should know I come from the Middle East.
I escaped that which you don't want to
have replicate here in Canada.
So no more language police,
no more thought police,
no more echo chambers that sean
intellectual diversity,
no more identity politics,
no more culture of offense and the ethos
of perpetual victimhood.
No micro
aggressions,
no trigger warnings,
no safe spaces and no cultural
appropriation.
Science reason and logic.
Trump,
trump ideology and feelings.
Thank you very much.
[inaudible]
is it okay to uh,
to move this away please?
Thank you very much.
Good morning.
My thanks to the Manning Center man
unconference for inviting me to speak
with you this morning.
And it's a,
it's a great honor to be on the same
panel with Dr. Jordan Peterson and Dr
Saad free speech in Canada is not dead,
but at Canadian universities it is
certainly is on life support.
Uh,
each year of the Justice Center releases
the Campus Freedom Index,
uh,
most recently with the new website
www.campusfreedomindex.ca where you can
very easily and quickly look up your own
university and see what letter grade a,
b,
c,
d,
F has been assigned to your university
or to your student union.
Uh,
based on its policies,
based on his practices.
We're trying to follow Dr. Michael
Walkers.
Great Dictum if it matters,
measure it.
So annual campus freedom index measures
with a objective criteria,
the state of free speech at over 60
Canadian universities.
The situation on the whole,
it's,
it's very bad.
There are far more f's handed out.
Then there are a letter grades and the
Justice Center has been involved with
uh,
over 12 court actions against
universities and student unions in four
provinces.
Fortunately,
we have had some successes a number of
years ago.
The University of Calgary took it upon
itself to sensor a small pro life group
on campus and threatened the students
with a trespassing charges and even with
non academic misconduct charges with
penalties ranging up to expulsion if
they continue to express their prolife
us on campus.
The students continued with her
expression and they were indeed found
guilty of non academic misconduct for
having done soul.
Now the penalty was not expulsion,
it was a warning,
but we took the university to court and
in 2014 in the case of Wilson versus the
University of Calgary,
we got a court ruling setting aside the,
uh,
university of Calgary's decision to find
the students guilty of non academic
misconduct.
So that case
is now a precedent that can be used by
students across Canada.
We also recently,
uh,
this past summer sued the Brandon
University student union,
which had banned a campus prolife club,
which of course is significant because
if you don't have the official club
status,
you cannot participate in clubs day or
book a table or you,
you cannot on par with the other clubs,
rent out a room or holding events,
uh,
invite a speaker,
hosted debate,
et Cetera.
So we sued the student union at Brandon
University and before the action got
very far,
they did settle and the re-instate of
the club.
So another positive result.
But University is a very clever,
so we've got the University of Alberta,
which is obviously aware of the
precedent against the University of
Calgary.
So rather than censor speech directly
itself with the university does,
is it lets the mob sensor the expression
that is unpopular.
So in 2015,
the prolife group put up a,
a peaceful stationary display and there
was a huge mob of people came with
sheets and towels and banners and
megaphones and swarmed it and rendered
it completely impossible to carry on any
kind of civil conversation or dialogue
or debate.
Now,
in spite of the fact that the University
of Alberta's code of student behavior
expressly prohibits interrupting,
obstructing,
or interfering with university related
activities and events in spite of very
clear provisions in the code of student
behavior.
When this disruption and obstruction
took place,
campus security stood by and watched and
did nothing to enforce it.
The,
on the university's own code of conduct,
the following year,
2016,
the students went back,
uh,
filled out a form to have another
display in the university says,
yes,
you can,
you can put up a display on campus
provided that you pay us a security fee
of $17,500.
Now of course,
if you're,
if it's the,
uh,
campus gay pride March,
or if,
if it's a feminist or socialist or
aboriginal or environmentalist
expression,
there's no security fee is required for
that.
But if your opinion is unpopular or
controversial,
you're not allowed to express it on
campus unless you pay a security fee of
$17,500.
So we're suing the University of Alberta
and the court in Edmonton is going to
hear our case coming up in June and it's
going to be hugely,
uh,
for,
for better or for worse.
You know,
you can't predict ahead of time if
you'll win or lose,
but this is going to have a huge impact
on the rule of law because the message
that the University of Alberta is
sending to its own students sim to the
whole world is that if you disagree with
somebody else's opinion,
you should shut them down and silence
them.
And that's the message,
you know,
and it's,
it's tempting,
uh,
you know,
for,
for people who disagree with or perhaps
despise or detest the prolife viewpoint,
it's tempting to,
you know,
kind of chuck hole cause you know,
this is being shutdown,
but it should be obvious to any thinking
person.
If this is the condone trend that's
going to crack in all directions and
it's not going to be too long before
you're going to see all kinds of views
and eventually even left wing views,
they're going to get shut down by mobs.
If this is not a font immediately and
urgently what to do about the situation.
I've got five recommendations.
Firstly,
exercise your free expression.
Rights.
Freedom is like a muscle.
If you don't exercise your muscles,
they atrophy and weather and become weak
and useless.
Conversely,
if you exercise your muscles,
they stay strong and get even stronger.
So exercise your free expression rights.
Do not be intimidated by the name
calling.
We've all heard it.
Racist,
sexist,
homophobic,
transphobic,
Islamophobic,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
If you self censor,
you are giving ground to the enemies of
freedom and
yeah,
to make a commitment to the idea that
it's better to die standing them to live
on your knees.
Okay,
second point,
come to the defense of others whose
freedoms are threatened makes a huge
difference,
especially if it's somebody that you
disagree with.
Uh,
the Justice Center takes,
uh,
we,
we have taken a position on it.
We're not pro choice,
we're not pro life,
but we're pro free speech.
So we take no position on abortion.
As it turns out,
most of our clients on university
campuses are pro life groups.
We're also acting for the men's Issues
Awareness Society,
uh,
which is suing the student's Union at a,
at Ryerson University.
I'm,
I'm sad to say that in most of these
cases,
when a pro life group is getting
censored by the university or by the
student union,
in most cases,
they get no help from the campus.
Christian clubs get no help from the
campus,
Jewish campus,
Muslim campus,
conservative clubs,
and they're there all alone.
You can make a huge difference if you
see somebody else being silenced or
treated unfairly when you speak up.
It's especially powerful if you say,
I don't agree with their viewpoint at
all,
but they have a right to speak their
opinions in a peaceful fashion on
campus.
And what you're doing with your
censorship is wrong,
and that's very powerful.
So we need to do more of that is speak
up for others who are being persecuted.
Thirdly,
sign our petition.
No taxpayer funding for universities.
That sensor,
it's high time that universities were
stopped from perpetrating a fraud on
taxpayers,
which they do by going to the general
public and to the politicians and
saying,
we believe in academic inquiry.
We believe in freedom of speech.
We believe in frank,
honest debate as a tool for reaching
truth.
And they get $13 billion per year from
taxpayers,
most of it from provincial governments.
And then they take the 13 billion and
turnaround and they don't even honor
their own mission and mandate.
And that can be stopped by legislation.
Provincially.
Provinces simply have to amend the
legislation and say,
universities are not getting money
unless he uphold free expression on
campus.
So please sign the petition.
There's copies that are,
um,
justice center booth and there's also
copies in the,
in the back of the room.
Fourth Point,
uh,
support the groups that are defending
the free society.
Uh,
don't assume that the organizations out
there that have their booths up,
that,
uh,
there's a,
there's a few billionaires that are all
giving these groups $100,000 a year.
Uh,
I know with the Justice Center,
and I think it's true for a lot of the
groups out there,
the majority of the money that we get,
it comes in the form of the $200 or $500
$100 donations.
That's 60% of our budget.
So don't,
don't leave it to some imaginary wealthy
person,
but step up to the plates and support
the groups if you're not already doing
so that are defending the free society.
Last but not least,
when you yourself are in a situation
where your fundamental freedoms are
being violated and whether it's your
freedom of expression,
your freedom of conscience and religion,
your freedom of association,
stand your ground,
do not be intimidated.
This is really where the war is fought.
Freedom is lost when people cave in and
capitulate on fundamental points of
principle when they shouldn't.
And I,
I said earlier,
it's a,
it's a great honor to be on the same
panel with Dr. Jordan Peterson.
If more Canadians showed the courage and
fortitude that he is demonstrating on a
daily basis in the face of adversity,
we'd be a lot better country.
Thank you.
[inaudible].
So,
um,
I want to recommend a book first to
everyone here.
It's called explaining postmodernism and
it's by a gentleman named Steven Hicks.
And you need to understand postmodernism
because that's what you're up against
and you're up against it far more than
you know or think.
And it's a much more well developed and
uh,
pervasive,
pernicious,
nihilistic,
intellectually attractive doctrine then
has yet come to public realization had
absolutely dominates the humanities and
increasingly the social sciences in the
universities.
And what's happening,
you see,
someone once said,
who unfortunately I can't remember,
it might've been Friedrich Nietzsche
said that everybody is the unconscious
exponent of a dead philosopher.
And,
uh,
fortunately the postmodern philosophers,
most of them are dead.
So that's a good thing.
But that doesn't mean that their words
aren't continually being spoken by
people who,
who are following in their wake,
let's say.
And it's not like any given person is
absolutely possessed and say by the
spirit of postmodernism,
because often they're not educated
enough to know all the details about
what it is that has them in their grip.
But if you get 20 of them together and
they're all 5% influenced by the
postmodernist ethos,
you basically have the spirit of the mob
that's a mouthpiece for that particular
philosophical doctrine.
And if you understand the doctrine,
then you understand why things are
progressing the way that they are
progressing.
And so I'm going to tell you a little
bit about the doctrine,
um,
because it's not optional to understand
this.
It's absolutely crucial to understand
this,
huh?
You can't underestimate the power of
ideas and,
and also the power of words of course,
because ideas are expressed in words,
but you see the postmodernists
completely reject the structure of
Western civilization.
And I mean completely.
So I can give you an example in one
term,
Jacques Derrida whose head trickster for
the postmodernist movement regarded
Western culture,
let's call it the patriarchy as fellow
go centric.
Okay.
So fallow comes from Phallus,
p,
h a,
l,
o.
And so that's the insistence that what
you see in Western culture is the
consequence of a male dominated,
oppressive,
um,
self serving society.
And we might say,
well,
you know,
societies do tend to be self serving and
people in power do tend to act in their
best interests,
but a tendency is not an absolute.
And that's one of the things that needs
to be considered continually.
There are no shortage of flaws in the
manner in which we've structured our
society.
And compared to any hypothetical utopia,
it's an absolutely dismal wreck.
But compared to the rest of the world
and the plight of other societies
throughout the history of mankind,
we're doing pretty damn well and we
should be happy to be living in the
society that we're living in.
Yeah.
So the first
thing that you might want to note about
postmodernism is that it doesn't have a
shred of gratitude.
And there's something pathologically
wrong with a person who does have,
it,
doesn't have any gratitude,
especially when they live in what so far
is the best of all possible worlds.
And so if you're not great for your
driven by resentment and resentment,
is the boat the worst emotion that you
can possibly experience apart from
arrogancy,
resentment,
arrogance,
and deceit.
There's an evil triad for you,
and if you're bitter about everything
that's happening around you,
despite the fact that you're bathed in
wealth,
then there's something absolutely wrong
with you.
You know,
the black community in the United States
is the 18th wealthiest community,
18th wealthiest nation on the planet.
Now,
that doesn't mean there isn't such a
thing as relative poverty in relative
poverty.
It's an important,
it's an important political economic
issue,
and it's very,
very difficult to deal with.
But absolute wealth matters too.
And the western societies have been
absolutely remarkable in their ability
to generate and distribute wealth.
As you can tell by just looking around
and taking a,
you know,
a brief bit of consideration for the
absolute miracle that even a building
like this represents.
So you have to educate yourself about
postmodernism.
Okay?
So here's what the postmodernists
belief.
They don't believe in the individual.
That's the logos park.
Western culture is fell logo centric
logo is logos.
That's partly the Christian word,
but it's also partly the root word of
logic,
okay?
They don't believe in logic.
They believe that logic is part of the
process by which the patriarchal
institutions of the West continue to
dominate and to justify their dominance.
They don't believe in dialogue.
The root word of dialogue is logos.
Again,
they don't believe that people of
goodwill can come to consensus through
the x through the exchange of ideas.
They believe that that notion is part of
the philosophical substructure and
practices of the dominant culture.
So the reason they don't let people who
they don't agree with speak on campuses
because they don't agree with letting
people speak.
You see?
It's not part of the ethos.
Okay,
so what else do they believe and not
believe?
They believe that you,
since you don't have an individual
identity,
your fundamental identity is group
fostered.
And that means that you're basically an
exemplar of your race,
hanse white privilege,
or you're an exemplar of your gender or
your sex or your ethnicity,
or your an exemplar of however you can
be classified so that you,
you are placed in the position of victim
against the oppressor.
Because that's the game and it's,
it's,
it's a post Marxist sleight of hand,
right?
The old Marxist notion was that the
world was a battleground between the
burrs,
waze and the proletariat.
And that a failed to have any
philosophical or ethical standing.
That argument after the working class
actually saw its standard of living
massively elevated as a consequence of
of Western corporate democracy,
a Western free enterprise democracy and
also b.
And and also as a consequence of the
revelations of everything terrible that
it happened in every bloody country that
ever dared to make equity.
And,
and the Marxist communist dogma part of
their fundamental structure,
right.
And nothing but murderousness and
oppression.
And so by the 1970s it was evident that
that game was up the postmark,
the postmodernist Marxist just barely
basically pulled a sleight of hand and
said,
okay,
if it's not the poor against the rich,
it's the oppressed against the
oppressor.
We'll just read,
divide the subpopulations in ways that
make our,
our bloody philosophy continuing its in
its,
in its movement forward.
And that's where we're at now.
And so for the postmodernists,
the world is a hobbsy in battleground of
identity groups.
They do not communicate with one another
because they can't.
All there is is a struggle for power.
And if you're in the Predator group,
which means you're an oppressor,
then you better look out because you're
not exactly welcome.
Ah,
not exactly welcome and neither are your
ideas.
So that's what you're up against.
I would say it's time for conservatives
to stop apologizing for being
conservatives.
You know,
and
you don't apologize to these people.
That's a big mistake.
Apology there.
They read apology as a,
as a,
as an admission of guilt.
You don't apologize and you don't back
down.
You young people that are out there who
are university students,
you need to take over the student
unions,
you need to take them back because
they're absolute snake pits and they
haven't been since the [inaudible].
No.
And with regards with regards to the
universities,
I thought at one point that the best
thing to do would be to cut their
funding by 25% let them fight amongst
themselves for the remnants because it
would force the universities to decide
exactly what's important and what isn't.
So I would say the humanities and much
of the social sciences have has turned
into a postmodern Neil Marxists
playground for radicals.
The scholarship is terrible.
80% of humanities papers aren't cited
once,
once.
And so what that means is that they
write papers for each other and they
sell them to libraries.
And that's how the publishers make their
money and no one reads them.
But the publishers can print them
because the libraries have to buy them
and they're buying them with your tax
money.
And so all of you who are sitting here
are funding and our postmodern radical
neo Marxist agenda that has its roots in
the university and your tax money is
going towards that.
And if you want proof of that,
you just go online and look at the
websites,
especially of of disciplines like
women's studies,
which is pathological,
right?
To the core.
But it's not just women's studies,
it's all the ethnic studies group,
it's anthropology,
it's sociology,
it's social work.
And most of all it's education and
noisy,
for example,
in Ontario is perhaps apart from the
Ontario Human Rights Commission,
the most dangerous institution in
Canada.
It should be defunded.
It's as simple as that.
They don't do the research they purport
to do.
They're not interested in,
in,
at all in education.
They're interested in the indoctrination
of people as young as they can fund a as
young as they can get their hands on,
so to speak.
Now we need to figure out,
our society needs to figure out how to
stop shunting public tax money to
radical left wing activists.
If we were doing that for radical right
wing activists there,
it'd be an absolute storm.
But it's happened incrementally since
the 1960s and it needs to stop.
So that's,
that's partly what the Conservatives,
not only conservatives,
but also liberals,
true liberals in the English sands are
up against.
I mean,
what's happened as also as a consequence
of this postmodern,
neo Marxist intellectual invasion,
is that the center keeps moving.
It's moved way to the right now.
So if you're a classic liberal,
you've become a conservative.
And so for all of you who are interested
in pursuing the conservative agenda,
there's a lot of classic liberals that
you could be talking to.
And then finally,
with regards to talking to young people,
you finally have something to sell to
them.
You know,
it's not easy to sell conservatism to
young people because they want to change
things.
And that's not what conservatives want
to do.
They want to maintain things.
Well now you've got something to sell to
young people.
You can sell them freedom of speech and
you can tell sell them responsibility.
The left is selling them,
right?
You can sell them responsibility.
And I can tell you because I received
many letters of the sort that,
that God was talking about,
young people are absolutely starving for
someone to provide them with a sense of
responsibility and say,
look,
here's something worth living for,
man.
[inaudible]
you know,
you can find meaning in life with
freedom,
but freedom.
Freedom is a chaotic sort of meaning,
right?
And,
and freedom isn't the sort of thing that
makes people happy.
It's the sort of thing that makes people
troublesome.
Troubled because,
um,
freedom expands your,
you're a series of choices and that
makes you nervous and uncertain.
So,
but responsibility is another.
Not to say that that's a bad thing.
It's a good thing,
but it,
it,
it requires that you,
that you shoulder the responsibility of
the freedom.
But responsibility per se is what gives
your life meaning genuine meaning in the
face of suffering.
And you and young people are really,
they're starving for that.
I've been teaching young people for 30
years and mostly what I've been teaching
them about his responsibility,
it's like your errors to a great
tradition.
It's not perfect obviously,
but comparatively,
you know,
there's nothing else like it that's ever
been produced and it's,
it,
it represents a tiny minority of,
of,
of the human politics,
most of which are,
are,
are run by murderous,
antisocial,
psychopathic,
um,
uh,
thugs and that,
that's seriously.
And so what kind of alternative is that?
We've got this beacon of freedom and
wealth in the West that works,
although it doesn't work perfectly.
And one of the,
one of the responsibilities of young
people is to find out what's at the core
of that.
The great,
great core of that,
that the paramount,
the paramount importance of the
individual and the divinity of speech.
Man,
that's some to sell.
It's what our whole culture is
predicated on.
All right,
well I should start there.
So thank you very much for the
invitation.
So
thank you very much to all of our
speakers.
Really insightful comments.
Um,
I'm just going to lead a better 20
minute discussion,
15 minute discussion.
Um,
and my first question is the direction
in which we're going.
So,
um,
there was a pool that was published by
the Economist and uh,
I think tuition is ago that showed the,
the support among young people for
different sets of rights in different
countries across the world.
And they found that support for the
expansion of rights that are considered
rights for historically marginalized
groups.
So the right for women's equality,
um,
right to same sex marriage,
Rachel abortion,
things like that.
Even in countries where those rights are
not in trying in law has incredible
amounts of support among young people.
The only exception is the right to free
speech,
particularly the right to speech that
may be perceived as offensive to
minority groups in that category.
Countries like Britain,
Germany and Canada,
the support among young people for that,
right?
It's under 50% so right now we have,
um,
we see,
we see censorship,
self censorship and real state
censorship by people who actually hold
the,
the leavers of power in government and
in institutions.
But when these people who right now have
less than 50% support for the right to
free speech are 15 years from now,
the ones holding those leavers and
power,
where do you see this going?
Well,
the,
the short term future is very bleak,
but I,
I always say you just got to keep on
fighting for what is right and
exercising courage and we can't see what
the medium term or long term future is.
Uh,
you know,
the history is,
is,
is quite unpredictable,
but the short term trends are terrible.
Uh,
I think another thing for people in the
audience who are parents is you don't
get your kids out of the public
education system.
And,
uh,
do homeschooling or private school make
that a priority.
You know,
even if you can't afford it,
figure out a way because this
indoctrination into these postmodernist
or neo Marxist type ideas,
it just permeates the whole,
uh,
curriculum.
Whether it's math,
science,
social studies,
what have you.
So that's something practical.
Uh,
certainly the,
the students that are now 18,
19,
20,
it's obvious that in high school they've
never been taught that if there's an
idea that you disagree with,
while you had come up with reasons why
that's wrong and you try to use facts
and logic to engage in discussion,
that's a,
you know,
it,
they've got these mobs as,
you know,
what I feel very offended by by what you
said,
I feel that way and therefore you
shouldn't be allowed to say it.
What were they getting that from?
I mean,
that's coming out of the K to 12
education system.
Yeah.
Great.
One of the things that I tried to do is
to convince both colleagues and students
and anybody who's willing to listen to
participate,
participate in the trench warfare.
I'm ideas.
Many people feel as though they don't
have the necessary platform,
unnecessary testicular
fortitude to actually battle.
But then they see gentlemen like Jordan
Peterson,
if I may include myself and a few others
who are on the front lines and then they
feel very invigorated.
So the,
I think the ship can be turned around as
long as people feel sufficiently
empowered that they actually have a
voice.
You could wait in simply on your
facebook page.
You could weigh in at the bar when
speaking to someone,
everybody has a voice and everybody
should feel sufficiently invigorated and
the possibility of lending their voice
to the debate.
And if we can do that,
then I don't think we need to be
pessimistic.
If we can't convince people to do that,
then I think it will be an infinite
abyss of darkness.
So you know,
one way of conceptualizing yourself is
that your one speck of dust among 7
billion.
And when you conceptualize yourself that
way,
you might think,
well,
what difference does it make?
What I say or do?
And that it's actually quite convenient
for you.
Because if it doesn't matter what you
say or do,
then you don't have any responsibility.
And you can do whatever you want,
the price you pay for that.
It's a bit of nihilism.
But if you don't have to shoulder any
responsibility,
that's a small price to pay another.
That's the underground motivation for
nihilism.
But the other way of looking at it,
and this is actually the accurate way of
looking at it,
is that you're in a network,
you're a node in a network,
and so you can do a little bit of
arithmetic very rapidly and just
figuring out how powerful you are.
You know a thousand people,
you're going to know more than that over
the course of your life,
but let's say a thousand for the sake of
argument.
For now they know a thousand people.
That means that you're one person away
from a million people and two persons
away from a billion people and you're
the center of that network.
And now the way networks work is that
information propagates in a network
manner.
So don't underestimate the power of your
speech.
Now,
you know,
western culture is fell logo centric.
Let's say it.
Okay?
So we'll say,
yeah,
that's just fine.
That's exactly what it is.
It's predicated on the idea of the
logos,
that the logos is the sacred element of
Western culture.
And what does that mean?
It means that your capacity for speech
is divine.
It's the thing that generates order from
chaos and then sometimes turns
pathological order into chaos when it
has to.
Don't underestimate the power of truth.
There's nothing more powerful.
Now in order to speak what you might
regard as the truth,
you have to let go of the outcome.
You have to think,
all right,
I'm going to say what I think stupid as
I am biased,
as I am ignorant as I am,
I'm going to state what I think as
clearly as I can and I'm going to live
with the consequences no matter what
they are.
Now the reason you think that that's an
element of faith,
the idea is that nothing brings a better
world into being then misstated truth.
Now you might have to pay a price for
that,
but that's fine.
You're going to pay a price for every
bloody thing you do and everything you
don't do.
You don't get to choose to not pay a
price.
You get to choose which poison you're
going to take.
That's it.
So if you're going to stand up for
something,
stand up for your truth,
it'll,
it'll shape you because people will
respond and object and tell you why you
a fool and a biased moron,
why you're ignorant.
And then if you listen to them,
you'll be just that much less like that.
The next time you say something and if
you do that for five years,
you'll be so damn tough and articulate
and able to communicate and withstand
pressure that you won't even recognize
yourself.
And then you'll be a force to contend
with and you don't get to wait until,
because I get letters like Gad,
Saad gets all the time too from to
members in particular and they say,
well,
you know,
when I get tenure slight,
then they think,
well,
when I'm an associate professor,
and then they think,
well,
when I'm a full professor,
it's like if you're a professor already,
you're like the most protected person in
the history of the planet.
You know,
and,
and you,
you,
you need,
well,
okay,
but what,
one of the things that that indicates is
that it's almost impossible to provide
people with enough protection.
So that they feel safe to speak.
Okay,
so we'll address that directly.
It is not safe to speak and it never
will be,
but the,
the thing you got to keep in mind is
that it's even less safe not to speak,
right?
It's a balance of risks.
It's like you want to,
you want to pay the price for being who
you are and stating your mode of being
in the world.
Or do you want to pay the price for
being a bloody surf one that's enslaved
him or herself?
Well,
that's a major price man.
That thing unfolds over decades and
you'll just be miserable worm at the end
of about 20 years of that,
right?
No self respect,
no power,
no ability to voice your opinions,
nothing left but resentment because
everyone's against you because of course
you've never stood up for yourself.
It's like say what you think carefully.
Pay attention to your words,
the prices.
It's a price you want to pay.
If you are willing to believe that truth
is the cornerstone of society.
And in the most real sense,
if you're,
if you,
if you're willing to take that leap,
then tell the truth and see what happens
and nothing better could possibly happen
to you.
There'll be ups and downs and there'll
be pushback and there'll be controversy
in all of that.
But it doesn't matter.
The truth is what makes the world the
truth is what redeems the world from
Hell.
And that's the truth.
And we saw plenty of hell for the last
hundred years,
you know,
and we haven't learned a bloody thing
from it.
It's like wake up,
tell the truth,
or at least don't lie.
If that's a start and you go,
you gotta understand that's a risk.
But I will,
one more brief thing to say about that.
Um,
so,
you know,
I said what I had to say back in
September and I'm sure that I could have
done it better.
And many people have told me how I
could've done it better,
although it didn't mean they would
actually do it.
Yeah.
But,
but,
and you know,
my job was at risk,
serious risk for about two months and
these stabilized my family been very
brains about this.
So like thumbs up to their mandate
just stood by him.
But the OP,
here's the optimist
stick news is the university has left me
alone completely.
I shook hands with the dean two weeks
ago.
We're on friendly terms.
They don't want this to go any farther
than it has already.
The students were tremendously
welcoming.
When I came back to teach in January,
I haven't had a single negative incident
at the university and I've received
thousands of letters from people all
over the world,
all of which have been in support.
I've received two negative letters.
That's it to the people.
People have it in Kuwait,
longing to have the sort of thing that
we're talking about articulated.
And so don't be thinking you're alone.
It's just that people can't talk,
they're afraid to talk or they don't
know what to say.
And,
and those are real problems.
So if you're reasonably articulate,
like start talking and sharpen yourself
up.
I mean the enemy is,
is a cloud.
Their cloud is nat.
They're only courageous in groups.
They're only courageous.
And moms,
if you stand your ground and don't
apologize and articulate things
properly,
they'll disperse around you.
Like they're not even there.
So most of it's illusion.
So don't be be afraid,
but be afraid of the right thing.
And the right thing you should be afraid
of is not saying what you say.
Cause that's the same as not being.
And here you are suffering away.
You might as well be at the same time,
at least then there's something to you.
So,
so
one of the other things I wanted to ask
your opinion about is what rule do
provocateurs play in the debate over
free speech?
So,
uh,
the example of the day is,
is obviously Milo Yiannopoulos.
Um,
are these champions of free speech or do
they undermine public support for the
right or are they simply self interested
people who are hijacking a right in
order to promote themselves and their
own interests?
Um,
and obviously is this a new phenomenon
or is this something that is,
is,
is age.
They're all of those.
Marlowe is a classic example.
He's an amazing person.
I mean,
he's,
he's a contradiction.
He's a walking contradiction.
You can't pin that guy down,
right?
Like,
what is he half Jewish,
half English gay,
uh,
Catholic,
provocateur Catholic.
Who's,
who's,
who's really,
yeah.
Who loves black guys and who,
who,
who is it?
Who Appeals to American Republicans?
It's like,
what are you going to say about
something?
Somebody like that.
It's like he's a,
he's a,
he's a trickster figure.
Archetypically speaking,
you know,
and he's,
he's a provocateur and a comedian.
And the funny thing about Comedians,
they're like gestures in the king's
court.
The gesture was the only person who
could tell the truth because he was
beneath contempt.
And that's the role that comedians and
provocateurs play.
They're poking,
they're poking and laughing and making
fun and you know,
Milo Christ,
even dresses like,
what do you call those?
A Harlequin,
you know,
he's a trickster and trickster figures,
emergent times of crisis.
And they point out what no one wants to
see and they say things that no one will
say.
You can say all the terrible things
about him.
He is a provocateur,
he's an EGOMANIAC,
he's a,
I don't think he's narcissistic,
but because he has the real capacity for
self reflection,
but,
and he's brave as can be.
I mean,
and,
and he's unstoppable on his feet.
He just amazes me.
I've never seen anyone ever,
I don't think,
and I've met some pretty damn smart
people.
I've never seen anyone who can take on
an onslaught of criticism and reverse
it.
Like he county.
It's bloody amazing.
But he is all those things you
described,
but you know the times call forth us the
speakers and we've called Forth Milo.
Yeah,
well then that tells you what our times
are.
Milo's been on my show and he's supposed
to come against him.
He's at,
he's exactly the things that Jordan said
at times.
He,
he has an ability to depart from truth.
You're speaking to shy.
So for example,
when he says things like,
there is no such thing as lesbians.
I appreciate his provocateur nature.
But then it'd be nice to stay closer to
the truth.
But to the extent that he is getting a
lot of young people engaged probably
more than Jordan and I could,
you know,
in our lifetimes a lot of people are
associating to him and so as a central
message is truly important.
So even if once in a while he makes a
departure from truth,
our grant him that because his greater,
uh,
his own death is quite important.
So I certainly support them.
Oh,
just add that a is the so called extreme
speech that pushes the envelope and that
ends up in the long run being
fundamentally transformative.
W The top question ask always is,
you know,
is it true or to what extent is a true
or why is it not true?
Truth is always the thing too to think
about.
We should never be concerned with
whether something is quote extreme or
not.
Cause that changes from year to year,
from decade to decade.
I mean you think,
you know,
in 1969 it would have been extreme to
advocate for gay marriage.
That would have been an extreme position
with less than 1% support.
And today in many quarters is considered
extreme to say that gay marriage is a
bad thing.
So extremism changes from,
from year to year,
decade to decade,
month to month.
And it should never be a criteria for
your speed is an extreme or nuts.
That's not the right question.
The question,
is it true or false?
Is it right or wrong?
Those are the questions to ask.
Okay.
Um,
really quickly,
one final question.
Um,
part of the debate that we have,
uh,
when we talk about free speech is in
universities.
Is is a university of public institution
or is it an institution of higher
learning?
No one would dispute that the manning
center is free to invite disinvite or
not invite anyone that they want to come
to this conference to learn and to
train.
But because universities are recipients
of large amounts of tax dollars,
are they more of a public institution
that is required to provide a bigger
forum for speech free speech?
And where do you draw that line?
When organizations that receive large
amounts of charitable tax benefits are
freer to disinvite or not invite or not
host,
you don't have to give a platform to
someone who speaks,
who disagree with,
but when do you,
when you're the recipient of public
monies.
Okay.
Well,
I think in the current context with,
with the universities and receiving $13
billion a year from taxpayers in that
particular context,
I think that they don't have the right
to behave as say,
a private institution like Trinity
Western University,
uh,
which gets no government funding.
That's very different.
If Trinity Western University,
uh,
said we're going to ban the expression
of,
of um,
atheism or Islam on campus and see
what's private institution as long as
they're up front about that,
that when you go there,
you know that,
uh,
pro Islamic or pro atheist speech is
outlawed and you still choose to go to
that university.
But ironically,
uh,
what I've heard from people,
currently and in the past that are
attending trinity is they do have
Muslims and atheists and gay people
there.
And it is a healthy,
vigorous intellectual climate.
But in response to the question,
if,
if you're a private institution,
you can invite or not invite,
you can do whatever you want.
Uh,
but for the university is because
they're holding themselves out as
supposedly in favor of academic inquiry
and free expression.
They should be required to honor that
commitment that they've made to,
to taxpayers.