Yeah,
my neighbors,
astronomers,
it's got a picture of like
Jimmy Hoffa,
see his head still attached with nobody.
I mean the things they could do with
photography or so when
there is a little bit there is an
article,
but no more pictures,
pictures,
great grandmother
for two minutes after class.
Anything that makes a difference to
shape and a bunch of those,
but there's lots of.
I guess this is
great.
Okay,
so today we're going to
want to
pass the picture.
You can.
We'll take a look at
this picture here.
This is very interesting.
I think there's a number of pictures
like this from around this time period
in European art.
This is about the best complete
representation that I've seen.
Alright,
so I'll pass this around.
Anyways,
the picture is divided into two halves.
On the right side.
This is the tree of life.
The tree of knowledge of good and evil,
sort of combined into one image,
which is not all that infrequent.
On the right side of the images,
Eve Adam sitting in the background here,
eve is handing out fruit from the tree,
taking it from a serpent's
mouth,
by the way,
that's the certainty of chaos.
Taking the apple from the serpents mouth
and handing into humanity over here and
in the background is this figure that
clearly represents death.
And also you'll note in the tree,
one of the apples is replaced by a
sculptor.
Alright,
then on the right hand or the left hand
side of the image,
there's a figure that represents the
church given maternal forum here seen as
a counterpart to eve and,
uh,
there's a picture of Christ crucified up
in the branches of the tree.
And that,
that symbolizes the notion that the old
Christian notion that Christ was the
second fruit of this tree.
So the first fruit was the,
was the fruit that bestowed on people
knowledge of good and evil that had as
its negative consequence consciousness
of death.
And the second fruit was the figure of
the hero here who's construed in most
myths as the answer to the question that
was posed by the original event.
So you say Christian store story makes a
loop,
basically it posits that there's a
problem,
which is the fact of mortality or the
fact of knowledge of mortality depending
on how you look at it and that there's
also an answer to that problem,
which is whatever pattern of being as
represented by this figure.
So the thing that the finger
representing the church is handing out
our hosts and the hosts and the Catholic
mass or theoretically considered to be
equivalent to Christ's body.
And that's a wrap.
That's a reference to really archaic.
Um,
what would you say?
Archaic Sacrificial Symbology,
incredibly archaic nature based on the
notion that if you ingest something that
you can become like it,
which is the idea that sort of stands
behind the mass.
So,
um,
anyways,
you can take a look at this painting one
that sorted like it,
although it's not quite as good an image
in this particular book on page 121
expressing the same sort of idea.
So I'll just pass that around.
You can take a look at it,
think about it because it makes a nice
background for the talk Landis class
off,
which is today.
So
I'm gonna read you some things today
from the last part,
the Spanish girl,
because while I spent a long time
constructing them,
I think they're more
because I have to cover a tremendous
amount of material today.
I don't want to miss the two essential
lines of the argument.
So,
um,
this whole course has been aimed at
trying to understand motivations behind
acts of cruelty that have no apparent
justification.
So one of the things that we've been
trying to understand is what forces
motivate individuals to,
to protect their social territory in
general.
And the idea is,
well,
will you shut the door please?
Thanks.
So I mean the initial hypothesis
basically is predicated on the idea that
people have an innate response to the
abnormal.
He is terrifying at first encountered,
particularly if that encounter is
voluntary.
And the reason we construct
organizations of social order is to keep
that novelty at bay,
which is to say that we would rather
live where there's order.
Then we're,
there's chaos because chaos has an
intrinsically overwhelming how effective
valence.
So we have one level of motivation to
protect our territory that stems purely
from,
uh,
our psychobiology.
Everything stems from our psychobiology
I suppose,
when it's most clear there,
then there's a second level of phenomena
that have to be accounted for him.
And I've told you some stories more
recently that Gold Hagen had gathered
together when he was talking about the
Nazi death camps near the end of the
war,
making the point that the Nazis did not
assuming that they were motivated as you
might assume,
by the desire to take over the world to
dominate the world,
which would be motivated by the desire
to spread their particular pattern of
beliefs everywhere.
So there was no chaos anymore anywhere.
You would expect that when they put
people like the Jews are the Gypsies
into the concentration camps,
that they would have tried to extract
from them as much productive labor as
possible in order to further this
particular man.
But it seems to be the case at least
frequently,
that the Labor that was extracted from
the victims in the concentration camps
was had no productive value whatsoever,
certainly wasn't useful in furthering
the cause of the war.
It may have even happened it evidently
at that point,
because of course the Germans lost
tremendous amount of their intellectual
capacity when when the lucky Jewish
intellectuals managed to escape their
clutches,
Gold Haggett points out in social units
and details,
this sort of thing quite frequently to
that much labor,
so to speak,
was only implemented for the purpose of
cruelty and humiliation.
So Gold Hagen tells a story about a
typical work operation which involved
moving a large rock from one place to
another wellbeing beat and then moving
it back,
which is a parody of work not work
itself.
And obviously only instituted to
humiliate and,
and torture people who are already
bought as victimized as you could
possibly imagine.
Uh,
you know,
you need another level of motivation
now,
that level of explanation to account for
that sort of phenomena,
which is gratuitous,
cruelty or even cruelty as a,
as a sort of aesthetic,
as a way of life,
as something worth pursuing in and of
itself,
and I don't think you can understand,
you don't understand what human beings
are like.
You certainly don't understand
motivation for acts of social conflict
until you get both parts of the story
sort of firmly embedded in your mind.
So you could say,
well,
it's more purely the case that the fear
of unknown territory and motivates our
desire to associate it with a group
group is composed of people whose
actions we can predict.
Furthermore,
while we're in that group,
we can predict our own actions,
so pretty.
That pretty much keeps the novelty of
the environment,
so to speak at bay,
but also the novelty that's,
that's,
that's in other people and ourselves
and you needed then you,
but then you have to account for this
other level of phenomenon.
The way I attempted to do that was
by discussing mythologies of the dawn of
consciousness.
Two of them in particular,
the Buddhist,
the mythology of the
initial stages of the enlightenment of
the Buddha and also the myth,
the methods containing the story of
genesis which describes how Adam and eve
ate the fruit of the tree,
of the knowledge of good and evil,
and then immediately became aware not
only of their own mortality but of
everything that that sort of signified,
which was
partly the fact that they were going to
die.
Partly the fact that now it was
necessary for them to make moral
choices.
They have that capacity part of it.
They were going to have to work in that.
That's something that we haven't
concentrated on that much.
They have to work to sustain their
existence.
You only.
You only have to work when you can
envision negative possibilities that
your instincts would not have normally
construed of themselves.
Mean animals don't work.
They just live.
We work because we can imagine a
plethora of negative possibilities that
do not exist in the present and we're
always attempting to ensure that they
don't exist in the future as well,
which is just a hypothetical place in a
sense,
but we're the fact that we work means
that were dissociated in a sense from
what we'd like to do because we
certainly normally juxtapose work with
what we would like to do and the two
aren't in the same category.
Work is what you do,
so you get to do what you would like to
do,
at least under normal circumstances,
so part of the fall,
part of the consequences of the fall or
the rise into selfconsciousness,
depending on how you look at it,
was the necessity of endless work.
So knowledge of death,
endless work had basically about some
stuff.
Of course,
it's also the case that went out to
become self conscious.
He puts on his fig leaf.
He adopts the trappings of culture.
He also immediately hides from God and
while those ideas are all tangled
together in the Genesis Meth,
I mean Adam Heights from God because
he's ashamed and the reason he's ashamed
just because he's clearly recognizes his
own vulnerability
and
that vulnerability,
the recognition that
that vulnerability makes it impossible
for him to to exceed to God or to see
God,
at least in the mythological story,
and I think what that trying to
represent this in part of the fact that
it's knowledge of our own vulnerability
that makes us doubt our,
our.
What would you say are
our fitness in the sight of God?
It's hard to talk about this without
lapsing into mythological terms.
It's knowledge of Berlin vulnerability
that leads to our own shame.
I guess that's the simplest way to put
it and that makes us hide from the
possibilities in ourselves that have
been our most potent.
Yeah,
so are.
Then I told me a little bit of a split,
a story that sort of went like this.
I mean that there's a feedback loop in a
sense that's generated as a consequence
of the dawning of self consciousness and
one is that one is the generation of
shame.
The other is the moving away from
destiny that's most appropriate.
That leads to a weakening of character,
weakening of character,
makes the world seem much more terrible
than it is because
wow,
as you lose sight of the process that
can allow you to adapt to things the way
they are.
It is the case that things that you can
no longer handle take on a more and more
aggressive and hostile and vicious face.
So I guess the simplest way to look at
that is to think that in the world is
such a complex place,
so unpredictable at its essence.
It's so charged with danger everywhere
that in order to adapt to it properly,
it's necessary to utilize all of your
resources.
Your own knowledge of your own
limitations is enough to stop you from
bleeding.
That those resources have any value.
The more you move away from those
resources,
partly because they take work partly
because you don't believe in them
anymore that week or you get and the
more terrible the world.
Paris Hilton basically represented that
part in his description of Satan's
generation of hail,
around tying in another complex aspect
of the argument,
which was the inability to admit to
error.
It's hard.
It's hard
in brief,
to demonstrate how old those ideas are
are pain without.
I guess the basic notion is that it's
knowledge of our own essential
vulnerability that makes us lack belief
in our capacity to face the consequences
of our own errors or even to admit that
those errors are there.
Without that capacity,
it's impossible for us to further the
development of our personalities because
it's only after admission of air that
further exploration can take place and
it's out of the consequences of
exploration.
That personality is generated and the
terrors of the world
transformed into something either
positive or at least irrelevant.
Okay,
so what we're hoping to do today to some
degree in a very brief period of time,
is to describe how that process,
how all the negatives that are
associated with with the processes that
we've described might be overcome to
some degree can to start that by reading
something.
I guess the argument basically hinges on
this point,
so does the fact that there are negative
things necessarily corrupt.
You can see.
Nietzsche said,
and I
quoting his David last week,
he said that everyone who
only he who suffers from an actuality
has motivation to lie himself out of it,
and of course that that statement was
his attempt to account for human
behavior in general making the case.
Then we all have reason to suffer from
actual on the m,
therefore are all motivated to lie
ourselves out of it.
Freud took an extreme position like that
saying that our fear of reality,
which was essentially knowledge of our
own mortality,
was sufficient to have generated all of
the religious and the artistic
structures that we've erected,
which Freud basically regarded as
neurotic delusions against the anxiety
about death as a powerful argument type
thing.
I guess the problem I have with that
particular perspective is that it's
extraordinarily,
it's extraordinarily pessimistic because
it basically predicated on the idea that
unvarnished reality,
so to speak,
is of necessity,
so terrible that it's impossible to face
it,
so then some,
some false,
some sort of has to be erected between
you and your actual experience in order
to make that experience tolerable.
Now I can understand the rationale
behind that argument.
It's brings up again in these social
psychological studies that we'd be.
That idea springs up again.
You know that a certain amount of
dilution is necessary for mental health.
Well,
I guess really what I want to do is
explore the other day and they look at
the opposite perspective,
which is that,
well,
no,
that's not right.
It's insufficient grasp of reality that
makes it two terrible.
The mayor and the story I want to tell
you today is the story about,
um,
how about the exploration of that
particular hypothesis.
And the first thing I did,
I thought I might be useful because one
of the things we've been trying to do in
this class so far is to draw
distinctions between things you know,
so that we can figure out distinctions
between various negative things and
distinctions between various positive
and to look at how the mythological
imagination categorizes the world so
that we can understand it more
rationally.
What are the things that I think is very
useful to draw a distinction between
when we're talking,
when we're trying to answer the
question,
is the world so terrible that cannot be
actually proceed properly,
is to attempt to draw a distinction
between evil and tragedy.
And I'm going to.
Because it's certainly the case.
Look,
it's certainly the case as we all know
that in the course of our life we're
going to encounter the same sort of
phenomenon of the Buddha encountered
when he went outside of his outside of
his castle walls.
And there's no possibility in anyone's
existence for them to escape sickness
for old age or death.
I mean those,
those things are absolutely certain and
certainly tended with negative effect,
at least in terms of their apprehension,
so the question is under those,
given that those are the background
conditions of existence,
is it possible?
Nonetheless,
that existence can be positive enough so
that it can be apprehended accurately
instead of hidden from.
And I think one of the things that you
have to understand before you can answer
a question like that is the nature of
the distinction between evil and tragedy
and in order to address that
distinction,
I turned first to an argument that was
put forth by Ivan in the brothers
Karamazov,
which is regarded as far as I can tell,
is one of the most potent
pro atheistic arguments that's ever been
sat down in literature.
I've been in low shower,
two of the brothers Karamozov handle.
Osha is a,
is a spiritual person.
He wants to be a monk and his brother
Ivan is also,
I suppose the same sort of spirituality
from the genetic perspective.
They are brothers after all,
but he's also extraordinarily
intellectual and his intellectual
ability has completely destroyed his
ability to manifest the sort of faith
that that characterizes Losha and so
they're sitting down one time,
I believe they're both drunk.
I don't remember all those characters.
The SDS novelists are always drunk
and they have a very lengthy discussion
about about
well,
about the central meaning of the world,
I guess,
and I haven't makes it very,
very powerful case and it's the case
that it's sort of the worst case
scenario.
He says,
look,
this is how the world is constituted by
all approaches I can can see above if
it's constituted in this way.
It's necessary to adopt the attitude of
girth is Mephistopheles,
which is basically that the conditions
of existence are so unbearable that
existence,
that show itself has no justification.
It should cease to be
now under most conditions.
We don't draw that sort of conclusion,
but there are times,
especially when when our world's become
much less secure than they normally are
aware,
that sort of thing springs naturally the
mind and you know,
as long as things are going according to
plan,
we don't think like that,
but when the unexpected rises up and
manifests itself in some extraordinarily
destructive way,
that's the first sort of notion that
comes,
comes into our minds.
So I'm going to outline that argument.
This is from Jeffrey Burton,
Russell,
a for volume series on the devil in the
water world.
He presents Ivan's argument for atheism.
Ivan's examples of evil are all taken
from the data newspapers of 1876.
They're unforgettable.
There's a noble man who orders his
hounds to tear a peasant boy to pieces
in front of his mother,
a man who whips his struggling horse on
generalized parents who lock their tiny
daughter all night in a freezing privy
while she knocks on the walls,
pleading for mercy at Turk who
entertains a baby with a shiny pistol
before blowing his brains out.
Okay.
I haven't noticed that such horrors
occur daily and can be multiplied
without an he states I took the case of
children to make my case clearer
and so of course what he's doing is he's
presenting a situation where the
innocent are tormented because that's
that's an archetypal situation.
Fundamentally,
it's because in our typical situation is
where the most extreme situations that
characterize any particular case on
brought into the story.
So if you want to tell a very good
story,
what you do is you make the extreme case
and that's what I was doing because how
can you justify the suffering of
innocence of the other tiers with which
the earth is soaked?
I will say nothing.
We're also states the relation of evil
to God has in the century of Auschwitz
and Hiroshima once again became a center
of Philosophical and theological
discussion.
The problem of evil.
It can be stated simply,
God is omnipotent.
God is perfectly good.
Such a God would not permit evil to
exist,
but we observed that evil exists.
Therefore,
God does not exist.
You know,
I think it's absolutely necessary to
realize that this,
this,
this line of reasoning does not have to
be formulated in a pure,
purely theological manner.
I mean whether or not you consider the
conditions of existence generally as God
or as due to God,
has no relationship really necessarily
on the attitude you bring to bear on the
conditions of existence,
whether you're an atheistic or religious
explicitly.
The same problem presents itself to you,
which is that things that are terrible
by any,
uh,
any manner in which terrible can be
lead,
define,
constantly occur without apparent reason
and also without,
with,
without our ability to control them
under such circumstances which evidently
exists.
Is it possible to pause it in any
tangible manner that life is worth
living
on?
That doesn't have to be a religious
argument or expressed in religious
terms.
Although at its core,
it's a religious.
The only religious argument really.
So the only question
variations on the theme or nearly
infinite.
The problem is not only abstract and so
of course he is also personalized.
Immediate believers tend to forget that
God takes away everything that one cares
about possessions,
comfort,
success,
professional craft knowledge,
friends,
family and life.
What kind of God is this?
Any decent religion must face this
question squarely and no answer is
credible.
That cannot be given in the face of
dying children.
Okay,
so that's the.
That's the argument there is setup for
the worst case scenario
is this typical of Dostoyevsky's novels.
I mean that's.
That's what makes him a great novelist
fundamentally is five great novels all
address problems that are basically
impossible.
The relationship of good evil and crime
and punishment.
Yeah,
the relationship of divinity and
individuality and the idiot,
the relationship of personal behavior to
social catastrophe in the devils
and the relationship between fathers and
sons.
That's part of it.
In the brothers Karamazov where this
argument is also discussed,
what do you say to a dying child?
You say,
look,
you can do it.
You're strong enough to do it.
Hold her hand and fight the Safra and
you can't control with the love that you
can't.
It seems to me that we use the horrors
of the world to justify our own evil.
We make the presumption that human
vulnerability is a sufficient cause of
human cruelty.
We blamed God and God's creation for
twisting and perverting our souls and
claim all the time to be innocent
victims of circumstance.
I don't have much experience as a
clinical psychologist to my patients,
however stayed in my mind.
The first was a woman about 35 years
old.
She looked 50.
She reminded me of a medieval peasant,
least my conception of the medieval
peasant.
She was dirty clothes,
hair,
teeth,
dirty with the kind of filth that takes
months or even years to develop.
She was unbearably shy.
She approached anyone who she thought
was superior in status to her,
which was basically everyone hunched
over with is shaded by both hands as if
she could not tolerate the light
emanating from her target.
She been in behavioral treatment as an
outpatient before and was a site known
to the permanent staff at the clinic.
Others have tried to help her overcome
her unfortunate manner of self
presentation,
which of course many people on the
street shy away from her,
made them regard her as crazy and
unpredictable.
She could learn to stand or sit up
temporarily with her eyes on garden,
but she reverted to her old habits as
soon as she left the clinic.
She might've been intellectually
impaired consequences of a biological
fault.
It's difficult to tell because their
environment was so appalling.
It may have caused or ignorance.
I thought perhaps that she had an Iq of
about 80 or 85.
She was illiterate as well to live with
her mother whose character I knew
nothing about and with an elderly
desperately ill and bedridden at her
boyfriend was a violent schizophrenia,
alcoholic,
at least as far as I can determine who
ms dot traded her psychologically and
physically and was always modeling her
simple mind with tirades about the devil
in the worship of sate.
She had nothing going for her.
No beauty,
no intelligence.
It will loving family.
Those skills,
no employer,
nothing.
She didn't come to therapy to resolve
her problems.
However,
10 burden her solar to describe her
mistreatment and victimization at the
hands of others.
She came because she wanted to make
friends with someone who was permanently
hospitalized.
The clinic where I was interning was
associated with the largest psychiatric
hospital.
All of the patients that still remained
after the shift to community care and
the sixties were so incapacitated that
they could not survive on the streets
on.
You've seen street people and Aaron cat
incapacitated enough as a general rule,
so imagine how fascinated people who
weren't allowed to go back on the
streets where the basement of that
hospital,
there was a coke room down in the
basement of the hospital.
The hospital was connected by tunnels
all over the place.
I think product because it was so cold
there.
It looked like a scene from Dante's
inferno in that coke room.
I mean there were people in there that
were so damaged.
It was just beyond beyond your capacity
to imagine.
Anyway,
she'd done some volunteer work up some
limited type in that hospital and
decided that she could maybe take
someone for a walk and make friends with
them.
I think she got the idea because she had
a dog when she walked regularly and when
she liked to take care of all she wanted
from me was helping,
arranging this,
help finding someone she could take
outside,
help finding someone in the hospital,
bureaucracy who would allow this to
happen.
I don't think I was very successful in
80,
but she didn't really seem to mind
said that one piece of evidence that
runs contrary to a theory is sufficient
to prove that theory.
Just prove that theory.
Of course people don't think this way
and perhaps should not general theories
to useful to give up easily.
It's too difficult to regenerate and
evidence again should be consistent and
believable before it's accepted,
but the existence of this woman made me
think
she was destined for a
psychopathological and from the
viewpoint of biological environmental
determinism has faded.
This faded as surely as anyone I'd ever
met and maybe she beat her dogs
sometimes and was rude to her sick.
Maybe I didn't see her when she was
vindictive or unpleasant.
Even when our simple wishes were
thwarted.
Don't want to say that she was the same
because I didn't know her well enough to
tell,
but the fact was that in her misery and
simplicity,
she remained essentially without self
pity and still able to see outside of
herself.
I hesitate to say that I learned more
from her than she did it for me because
that sounds literary have tried,
but she didn't learn anything from me.
Why wasn't she a criminal,
cruel,
unbalanced,
and miserable.
She had every reason to be,
and yet she wasn't.
It seemed to me that in her simple way
she'd made the proper choices.
She remained bloody but unbowed,
and she seemed to me rightly or wrongly,
to be a symbol of suffering.
Humanity solely affected,
yet capable of courage and love
such I created all the theory,
will powers and spirits both of them who
stood and fail and fail,
not free.
What proof could they have given sincere
of true legions,
constant faith or love.
We're only what they needs must do.
Appeared on what they would.
What praise could they receive a
pleasure.
I from such obedience paid when will and
reason,
reason also his choice useless to me,
of freedom.
Both despoiled made passive,
both had served necessity,
not me.
They therefore as to right along so
we're created or can justly accused
there,
maker or they're making or their fate
has it.
Predestination overruled.
There will dispose by absolute decree or
high for knowledge.
They themselves decreed their own
report,
not I,
if I,
for new for knowledge,
had no influence on their fault which
had no last group certain on Granola,
so with our so without least impulse or
shadow of faith for by me,
immutably foreseeing a trespass authors
to themselves in all both what they
judge and what they choose for.
So I formed them free,
free.
They must remain until they enthralled
themselves.
High else must change their nature and
revoked the high decree,
unchangeable eternal which ordained
their freedom.
They themselves are doing their fault.
That's God's discussion of the
relationship between choice and evil in
milk.
Have a patient I wished you described
was the schizophrenia can falling
inpatient ward had a different hospital.
He was about 29,
a few years older than me.
I've been in and out of confinement for
seven years.
When I met him,
he was of course on anti psychotic
medication,
participated in occupational therapy
activities on the ward,
taking coasters and pencil holders and
so on,
but he couldn't maintain his attention
for any length of time.
It wasn't even much good at craft.
My supervisor asked me to administer an
intelligence test to him.
Standard wastes are more for the sake of
my experience.
Then for any possible diagnostic good at
my deal.
I gave him a dozen or so red and white
blocks for the block design test.
He's supposed to arrange the blocks so
they matched the pattern printed on the
cars that came with the test,
pick them up and started to rearrange
them on the desk in front of them are
like timed them stupidly with a
stopwatch.
Task was impossible for him,
even at the simplest of stages to
constantly look distracted and
frustrated.
I asked what's wrong?
He said,
battle between good and evil.
That's going on in my head.
I start the testing.
At that point.
I didn't know exactly what to make of.
His comment was obviously celebrate the
testing seemed to make it worse.
What was he experiencing?
Wasn't lying,
that's for sure.
The face of such a statement,
it seemed ridiculous to continue.
Spent some time with him that summer.
I never met anybody who was so blatantly
or we talked on the ward and
occasionally I would take him for a walk
through the hospital grounds outside.
He was the third side of first
generation Middle Eastern immigrants.
His first born brother was a lawyer.
The other physician,
his parents were obviously ambitious for
their children,
hardworking and discipline.
Being a graduate student at Mcgill,
working towards a master's degree in
immunology.
I don't remember exactly.
His brothers had said daunting example,
and he felt pressured to succeed,
has experimented work at,
not turned out as he had expected.
However,
any apparently came to believe that he
might not graduate,
not at least when you hope to,
so he faked his experimental results in
wrote up his thesis.
Anyways,
he told me that the 90 finished reading,
he woke up and saw the devil standing at
the foot of his bed and this event
trigger the onset of his mental illness
from which he had never recovered.
Of course,
it might be said that the apparition
merely accompanied the expression of
some stress induced pathological
neurological development whose
appearance was biologically
predetermined and that the devil was a
personification of his culture.
His conception of moral evil manifesting
itself in fantasy as a consequence of
his distress.
Such description would remain accurate
implausible,
but the fact remains that as a person he
saw the devil and the division
accompanied or was the event that
destroyed him.
He was afraid to tell me much of his
fantasy.
You very well developed fantasy world
and it was only after I'd paid careful
attention to him that he opened up.
He wasn't bragging.
We're trying to impress me.
He didn't want to tell me this.
It was terrified about what he thought.
He was terrified as a consequence of the
fantasies that impressed themselves upon
him.
He told me that he couldn't leave the
hospital because someone wanted to shoot
him.
I said,
typical paranoid delusion.
Why did someone wanted to kill him?
Well,
he's hospitalized during the Cold War on
its height,
perhaps still during the time when the
threat of purposeful nuclear
annihilation seem more plausible than it
does now.
Many of the people I knew used this
threat,
the existence of this threat to justify
to themselves their failure to
participate fully in life life which
they thought of Romantically as do and
therefore it's pointless,
but there was some real terror in this
pose and the thought of countless
missiles pointed here and there around
the world,
sap,
the energy and faith of everyone
hypocritical or not,
my schizophrenia patient believed that
he was in fact the incarnation of the
world in our lady force.
He was arrested upon his release from
the hospital to make his way south who's
in Canada to a nuclear missile silo and
American territory,
and to make the fateful decision that
would launch the Third World War,
the people outside the hospital,
and that is why they were waiting to
shoot him.
They didn't want to tell me this story
because he thought that I might want to
kill him to
my friends in graduate school.
I thought it was quite comical.
Denied contact a patient like this one,
peculiar interest in human and humans,
ideas regarding the collective
unconscious.
We're well known to them that seemed
absurdly fitting that I would end up
talking to someone with deletions of
this type,
but I didn't know what to do with his
ideas.
Of course they were crazy,
my patient,
but it still seemed to me that they were
true from a metaphorical viewpoint.
Historian totality.
Length is individual choice between good
and evil,
with a cumulative horror than facing the
world.
Historic implied that because he had
given into temptation at a critical
juncture,
he was in fact responsible for the
horror of the potential of nuclear war.
How could this be?
Seemed insane to me to even consider
that the active one,
powerless individual can be linked in
some manner.
That time of history as a whole,
no longer so sure.
I've read much about evil,
perpetration and growth,
and I no longer convinced that each of
us are so innocent or harmless.
It is of course a logical to presume
that one person,
one speck of dust among the 4 billion
modes is there any sense responsible for
the horrible course of human events,
but that course itself is not logical
far from it,
and it seems likely that it depends on
processes that we do not understand.
Jeffrey Burton,
Russell argues in his work on the
history of the concept of the devil,
that the classic distinction drawn
between Natural Evil and moral evil is
untenable.
It'll currencies such as plagues and
earthquakes belong in the same category.
Companies dance as concentration camps
on wards the existence of natural evil,
for which God is theoretically
responsible,
has been used as evidence for the most
potent arguments for the nonexistence of
God.
Say you put the nonexistence of any
meaning such as I outlined previously.
That was the states.
Perhaps the entire cosmos is not worth a
single innocent child suffering.
How can the universe be constructed so
that pain is permitted?
How can a good God allow for the
existence of a suffering world?
It seems reasonable to me to draw a
distinction between tragedy and tragedy,
has an ennobling aspect,
at least influential has been constantly
explored it to that and great literature
and mythology.
Tragedy exists where the heroic
encounters limitation,
evil by contrast is anything but no more
participation in Alex whose sole purpose
is expansion of medicine,
pain and suffering destroys character,
forthright encounter with tragedy might
increase it.
This is the meaning of the symbol of the
crucifixion.
It's Christ full participation in freely
chosen acceptance of his fate which he
shares with everyone that enables him to
manifest his full identity with God and
it's that identity which enables him to
bear that fate and which strips over
evil.
And conversely it is our voluntary
demeaning of our own characters which
makes the necessary tragic conditions of
existence of pure evil.
Where did these conditions exist?
Why are we sending to unbearable
limitation to paying disease and death
and cruelty at the hands of nature and
society?
It seems to me that it is because of
game cannot be played without rules.
God and man are in a sense twins,
so there's a mid rush and this means the
God made man because he lacked
limitation.
We could have everything we wanted
merely for wishing it.
If every tool performed every job,
if everyone was omniscient and immortal
and everything would be the same,
same old powerful thing,
God and creation wouldn't exist.
It is the differences between things
which is a function of their specific
limitations that allows them to exist at
all should they be.
It seems to me that we answered this
question implicitly,
but profoundly.
When we lose someone loved and grieve,
grieve presupposes.
Having love presupposes the judgment
that this person specific,
bounded and vulnerable existence was
valuable,
was something that should have been.
Let's do it.
Question lingers,
why you shouldn't.
Things even loved things exist at all if
they're necessarily limitations caused
such suffering.
I dreamed I was walking out of a deep
valley along the paved two lane highway
highway was located in northern Alberta
where I grew up and came out of the
valley for miles around and then the
sleep flat prairie asked the man
hitchhiking could see another in the
distance.
As I approached him,
I could see that he was in the first
stages of old age,
but he looked terribly strong.
Someone passed them in a car driving the
opposite direction and a female voice
yelled out,
look,
he has a knife.
He was carrying what looked like a
wooden handle kitchen knife,
well worn and discolored,
and it had a blade at least two and a
half feet long.
Cross the shoulder strap,
the large leather sheath.
He was walking along the edge of the
highway,
muttering to himself,
had swinging the leg jerky and chaotic
fashion.
He looked like the landlord lived next
door to me when I was a graduate student
living in a poor district in Montreal.
My landlord was a powerful aging x
biker,
former president of the local hell's
angels chapter by his own account.
He spent some time in prison as a
younger man.
He's settled down somewhat typically as
he became more mature and had brought
his drinking under control for a time.
His wife committed suicide.
However,
when I lived there and he went back to
him as well,
your ways,
he often went on binge drinking sprees
and spent all the money he earned in the
electronic shop.
You ran out of a small apartment.
He would drink 40 or even $50 in a
single day and would return home in the
evening.
Blind drunk,
howling,
knows little dawn,
laughing,
kissing between his teeth,
incoherent,
good natured still,
but able to become violent at the
slightest provocation,
took me once to his favorite haunts and
slightly better condition on his 1200 cc
Honda,
which had the acceleration of a jet
plane for short distances.
We perched precariously on the back of
his bike,
clinging to him,
wearing his wife's,
which settled my head ridiculously as it
was at least five sizes too small drunk.
He was almost in a singly destructive
and ended up in fights constantly,
unavoidably because he wouldn't take
slights from people whose paths crossed,
who were insufficiently cautious in that
conversation with him.
I heard by this figure he seemed upset
that no one would stop and pick them up
as if he were unaware of the dangers
posed.
As I went by.
His gaze fell on me and he started after
me,
not from anger or for desire,
for companionship,
I think,
but he was too unpredictable for me.
He wasn't fast.
However,
I stayed ahead of him on the road.
Scene shifted and I wielding figure
nine.
We're now on opposite sides of a huge
tree.
Perhaps 100 years,
100 yards in diameter on a spiral
staircase,
wander around,
wound around the tree,
out of the depths below,
into the heights above the staircase was
made out of old,
worn dark wood.
Reminded me of the church pews in the
church I attended with my mother as a
child where I was married.
His figure was looking for me.
He's a long way back and I hit myself
from this view
as I send them the staircase.
I remember wanting to continue in my
original journey out of the valley.
One of the flats around the plane with
the walking would be easy,
but the only way to stay away from the
knife was to continue up the staircase
up the axis Mundi.
That's awareness of death.
The grim reaper,
terrible face of God compels us
inexorably upward towards the
consciousness,
sufficiently heightened to bear the
thought.
The point of our limitations is not
suffering.
It's existence.
Excel point of evil by contrast is
conscious destruction,
manifest desire for increase of pain,
anxiety and suffering.
We've been granted the capacity to
voluntarily bear the terrible weight of
our mortality,
returned from that capacity and degrade
ourselves because we're afraid of
responsibility.
That's the necessarily tragic
preconditions of existence are
intolerable.
Perhaps we could reserve answer to the
question of God's nature is
responsibility for the presence of the
evil and creation.
Until we have solved the problem of our
own,
perhaps we could tolerate the horrors of
the world if we left our characters in
intact and develop them to the fullest,
we took full advantage of every gift
we've been granted.
Perhaps the world would not look
horrible that it seems to me that it's
not the earthquake,
a flood or the cancer that makes life
intolerable,
horrible.
As those events appear who seemed
capable of withstanding natural
disaster,
even if responding to that disaster in
an honorable and decent manner,
it is instead the pointless suffering
that we inflict upon each other that
makes life appear corrupt beyond
acceptability,
and that undermines our ability to
manifest,
save faith in our central nature that
makes us work even more diligently for
the destruction of everything that lives
and breathes.
It said,
be therefore perfect as your father in
heaven is perfect.
How seems stymied has always by as
pilots are running query.
What is truth?
Well,
even if we don't know precisely what the
truth is,
we can certainly tell each of us what it
isn't.
It isn't greed and the desire above all
else for constant material game,
it doesn't denial.
I've experienced,
we know full well to be real and the
infliction of pain for the purpose of
pain,
it appears possible to stop doing those
things which we know beyond doubt,
to be wrong and to become self
disciplined and honest and maybe
therefore to become able to perceive the
nature of the positive group
maturity seems painfully simple,
so simple that it's a miracle of sorts
that can ever be forgotten.
Love God with all thy mind and all I and
all that heart sort of truth above all
and treat your fellow man as if you were
yourself.
Not with a pity that undermines his self
respect and not with a justice that
elevates yourself above you,
but as it corrupted divinity,
a light to the center,
it's more difficult to rule oneself in
the city.
And this isn't a metaphor.
This is truth as literal as it can be
made.
It is precisely for this reason that
we're always trying to rule.
The city is a perversion of pride.
To see praying in public and uh,
clean up the dust under our feet and
staff seems too mundane to treat those
we actually faced with respect and
dignity when we can be active against in
the street.
Maybe it's more important to strengthen
our characters that to repair the world.
So much of that reputation seemed self.
Channing is selfishness and intellectual
pride masquerading as well.
Creating a world polluted with good
works
don't work
who couldn't believe that it is the
little choices that we make everyday
between good and evil,
but turn the world to waste and hope to
despair,
but it is the case we see are immense
capacity for evil,
constantly realize before us and great
things and then small,
I can never seem to realize our infinite
capacity for good can argue with the
soldiers.
And when he states one man who stops
lying can bring tyranny.
Christ said,
the Kingdom of Heaven is spread out,
spread out upon the earth,
but men do not see it.
What if this were in fact the case?
What if it was nothing but our self
deceit,
cowardice,
hatred and fear of polluted our
experience?
And turn the world into hell hypothesis
at least at least as good as any other
admirable and capable of generating.
Why can't we make the experiment?
Find out if it is true.
I want to read you something else.
Now.
This is.
This is another.
This is a description of the dream that
I collected from my nephew.
I'll read you the story about it because
it's related to
the experiment that I was just
describing,
right
hypothesis that I was trying to generate
in that chapter was that,
hmm,
look,
if you're treating someone in
psychotherapy for an anxiety disorder,
which basically means treating them
because they're too afraid to continue
living their life in the way that it has
to be lived even for it to continue it.
It appears beyond reasonable doubt.
Now that
attempting to convince the person of the
unreality of their fear or of the
unreality of the category of things to
be afraid of is not useful.
Don't people do not respond to that?
You can't talk someone out of their
neurotic beliefs.
All you can do is help them learn to
confront those things that terrify them
and then perhaps what they learned is
that they can confront those things,
terrify them.
They don't learn that the thing itself
is any less terrifying,
but they seem to learn that their own
conception of themselves with so
pathologically limited this,
that it was that conception that was in
fact leading to their to their
discomfort because the neurotic person
who runs from everything that he or she
is afraid of is possibly to themselves.
Whatever it is that they are in essence
is something so trivial that it can
stand up to negative emotion and prevail
and in therapy what you do is structure
the situation so that the person can
learn as a consequence of their own
experience,
not a consequence of the therapists
words.
Then if they're brave enough to look at
what they can tolerate,
looking at the devil in fact get better.
And the thing that's so interesting
about that,
and it's mysterious even from the
standard psychoanalytic viewpoint,
is that when you do so when you do that
to someone,
their ability to withstand fear
generalizes,
which means that if you teach them to
withstand fear in one situation,
then they're better at doing it in other
situations and their fear,
even if it's symbolic underneath,
doesn't multiply everywhere.
That you haven't exposed them.
So they may also get more confident,
for example,
in their interpersonal relationships and
that.
So that's a very common contaminant of
exposure therapy for agoraphobic women,
for example.
Then they start standing up to their
husbands because of course prior to
that,
their husbands were categorized in the
category of all those things that are
too terrible to face and what the
therapist is teaching the client.
Even if the therapist doesn't know it
explicitly,
is that you are the sort of creature who
is capable of standing off to the
category of all things that are too
terrible to face.
And all you have to do is give it a shot
for awhile.
Which is basically.
Which is to say basically that you have
to manifest some behavioral faith in
yourself and you can discover that all
by yourself and that's as far as I can
tell and I've looked at different
personality theories and different
theories of psychotherapy and me.
They tend to boil down to the same thing
in some way.
That same thing is that,
well,
first of all,
you need a coherent theory about what
things are about and second of all,
that exposure to the things that
frightened you,
cures you.
There's a now chemical dictum that
according to you and was the primary all
chemical dictum in steer clear linear
inventory.
I hope that's pronounced right,
but my Latin isn't any good.
The translation for that is it is found
incest pools and that was the El Kevin.
That was the alchemists general theory
about where the philosopher's stone list
to be found and the philosopher's stone
was a material substance in theory that
possess the power to grantee turtle
life,
but also to bring about eternal health
and you and.
Well,
in other words,
it was a thing that would.
Granted,
they're all the wishes and the chemical
notion when you can find this thing
where no one will look and what that
also means from the personal perspective
is where you will look well,
that's a strange notion,
but it's a bit more comprehensible if
you start to think about it from the
psychological perspective rather than
from the empirical perspective because
you could say,
well,
even though the places that we won't
look differ from person to person,
from the perspective of a natural
category,
it might be reasonable to pause it.
That that place where one will not look
is similar in some sense across
individuals,
which is only to say that all of us have
those particular things that we're
afraid of facing and the particular is
different,
but the fact that those things exist is
standard across people.
King Arthur is night sitting around
table because they're all equal.
They set off to look for the holy grail,
which is a symbol of salvation
symbolically container of the nourishing
blood of Christ,
which is another reference to
sacrificial symbolism,
keeper of redemption.
Each night leaves on his quest
individually.
Each night enters the forest to begin to
search at the point it looks darkest to
him.
When I was about halfway through reading
this manuscript,
I went to visit my sister in law and her
family.
She had a son,
my nephew who's about five years old.
It's very verbal and intelligent.
He was deeply immersed in a pretend
world and like to dress up as a night
with a plastic helmet and sword
Martech.
He was happy during the day to all
appearances,
but didn't sleep well at night,
had been having nightmares for some
time.
He regularly screened for his mom in the
middle of his rest and appeared quite
agitated by what was going on in his
nightmares.
This was a daily occurrence,
essentially enough so that the household
was being disrupted
or house.
One morning after woken up,
what he dreamed about,
he told me in the presence of his family
that dwarf like beat creatures who came
up to his knees,
have been jumping,
jumping up at him and biting him.
Interesting was just looking through
some
mythological imagery on the weekend and
I found out that that while there is
some archeological notions and don't
know how valid they are,
that there was a point in European
history where worship of the mother
goddess was very widespread and the
cultures that performed this worship
word then overrun by patriarchal
cultures later and patriarchal religions
replaced these early matriarchal
religions.
I don't know the
similar theories to that like bio
conference theory that human race was
once matriarchal and then was later
patriarchal have been discredited in the
past and I'm not so sure that this isn't
just a projection of mythological
structure onto history,
which happens very often,
but it doesn't matter.
There are,
there are doesn't matter to this
discussion,
although it matters.
Many of these.
There are very many ancient images of
goddess figures.
We've looked at some of them and I found
out this week and that many of them are
figures of their fingers off the
combination of a woman's body without
burden.
Sometimes the figure has wings,
sometimes it has a beat had.
It's quite interesting.
I guess this would be an example of
synchronicity because I've been thinking
about this.
I just saw the movie crumb.
Have any.
Have you seen that David Lynch,
you should all see that by the way,
because it's first of all,
it's very interesting study of of an
extraordinarily pathological family,
three brothers,
one who molests women,
his bum in the streets of San Francisco
who also sits on beds of nails and it
has a very ascetic attitude.
Another man,
50 years old,
never left home,
never slept with any women depressed
since he was 20.
Multiple suicidal finding,
kills himself a year after the movies
made and this other brother named crumb
who's a famous underground cartoonist
who produces a lot of the images while
he perceives himself in relation to a
ship to women in general as a small,
thin outcast,
sort of figured who tends to clean the
back of very large,
powerful looking women who by the way
often have bird heads,
which I found very interesting.
Anyways,
these figures that popped up in my
nephew,
his dreams,
these dwarf like beat creatures.
Where were these sorts of,
are this archaic sort of image
representing the source of all things
and while you say,
well,
why would it beeped goddess be a good
representation for the source of all
things?
Well,
it has something to do with the notion.
There's a whole bunch of notions
compiled all together that one is the
wild birds.
They fly.
So there's spiritual creatures because
they're associated with the air and the
sky and so they have a masculine aspect
like the whole,
like it goes to,
for example,
in a masculine aspect.
And the goddess of course is more a more
down to earth bakers.
So these figures represent the union of
opposites,
just like the dragon of chaos,
which is a serpent with wings anyway.
So that's what pops up in this
particular dream.
So anyways,
he told me in the presence of his
family,
the door,
like creatures
who came up to his knees had been
jumping up at him and biting him.
Each preacher was covered with hair and
Greece that had a cross shaved and the
hair on the top of his head.
The dream also featured a dragon who
breathed fire after the dragon exhaled,
the fire turned into these dwarves who
multiplied endlessly with each breath.
Oh,
that was a great image too.
He told the dream in a very serious
voice to his parents and to my wife and
I,
and we were shocked by it.
Same Ingredient,
horror.
It was really interesting to watch him
because
he,
while I,
like I said,
he was always reading around this little
night outfit anyway,
so he's in this world.
Whatever it was composed of is very
imaginative,
but then as soon as we asked them about
the dream,
I mean he just launched into it without
a pause where you could almost.
It was almost as if you could see the
imagery running in his head and he just
told the story with no with no
hesitation whatsoever.
And well,
the other thing,
I guess that was what made so
interesting to watch him was,
was that his attention moved from
outside world in and we're,
all of us were obviously inside because
he wasn't focusing on anything when he
was telling the story.
He's just letting the imagery run.
Anyways,
the dream occurred at a transition point
in his life.
He was leaving his mother to go to
kindergarten and was joining the social
world.
The Dragon,
of course,
served as a source of fear itself for
the unknown.
In general,
there are a burroughs,
while the doors were individual things
to be afraid of.
So you see the mythological imagery with
dragon of chaos,
the grease fires standing in the back of
everything and it produces these things
that have this Artek,
matriarchal nature,
which is the unknown as it actually
manifests itself and experience,
and so there's this eternal source and
as it breathes fire,
particular things that frightened,
frightened him would pop up.
And the thing that I thought so
interesting is there is hydro mythology
and a two because hydro of course is
multi headed dragon.
He kind of had me like seven more grow
all basically all that's a pretty
accurate representation of the way life
progress is under some conditions
because every time you solve a problem,
some other problem pops up somewhere
else.
Or sometimes when you solve a problem,
the solution that you use to solve the
problem generates a whole bunch of new
problems and the hydro mythology is
basically just a representation of the
idea that no matter how much time he's
running around putting out fires,
new fires keep popping up all over and
that's.
That will always be the case.
It's also a representation of the fact
that a political utopia that's conceived
of as a permanent state is impossible
because when you generate a solution,
the solution to these problems and
there's no way you can stop that partly
because the solution does far more
things than you would like it to do.
Which is why,
for example,
drugs have so called side effects.
I mean you have a problem,
you applied to drug to it.
The drug produces all sorts of other
problems.
I mean hopefully that are smaller than
the original problem,
but sometimes knows maybe there are
bigger and it still remains to be seen,
for example,
where their television has solved more
progress in his creative mind.
Yes is the reverse,
but whatever the point is,
things do all sorts of things.
Other than what you think they'll do,
like
anyways,
I asked him why he could do about this
dragon.
He said immediately I would take my dad
and we'd go after the dragon jumped on
his head and I poke out at size with my
sword.
Then I go down its throat where the fire
came out.
I cut the box out that the fire came
from and make a shield from it without
really.
I mean not really blew me away.
I couldn't believe that he could.
I mean the idea of going,
first of all,
he blinded the dragon,
which I thought was very interesting,
but then he went down his throat.
I mean not steps showed you that video.
Right?
And they go inside the whale.
I mean that's exactly,
exactly.
Do you have a dream?
But then there was a twist of brilliance
in this dream because he said that the
thing to do was to take the box that the
fire came from,
which was the source of the unknown
itself and transform it into something
that he could actually use against the
unknown.
That idea is so brilliant that it's.
It's a.
it's a miracle of sorts that it can be
reproduced in the dream of a five year
old because what it says is that what
what is necessarily used to go to where
fear itself resides without knowing
itself resides to identify with that
thing and to use it as a defense against
the unknown itself,
which is exactly what we do all the time
when we adapt to the fact that there
isn't a milling,
which is to say that when something I've
known occurs,
which means when some new information
pops up because the two things are
precisely equivalent.
It's as a consequence of exploring that
new information that you generate,
new things that you can use to further
the process of adaptation.
So you say,
well,
the unknown is the source of all the
problems.
We know that,
but it's also the source of all the
answers to the problems and it is the
case that while we use nature against
nature,
so to speak,
to to quote an ancient source that I can
remember.
That's the process of constructing
culture,
is we use the material world to defend
ourselves against the material world.
And hopefully the balance remains on our
side.
He had reproved preproduced,
an archaic hero myth in perfect form.
I thought the use of making a shield
from the firebox or thought the idea of
maintenance shield from the firebox was
brilliant.
This gave him the strength of the dragon
to use against the dragging
his nightmares ended at that point and
did not return even though he had been
suffering from them almost every night
for a number of months.
I asked his mother about his treatments
more than a year later and she reported
no further disturbance.
Of course,
many of you are going to find that hard
to believe that that's true.
That's actually what had occurred or you
saying the thing is he was having this
problem,
obviously,
whatever it was,
it was plaguing him in his nightmares,
whatever those composed of whatever
those were composed of.
He was running around like a night
trying to act out the solution or you
didn't quite have it.
He was using his behavior in ritualistic
forum to address a problem about
adaptation which he couldn't manage,
but as soon as he made the dream
explicit and then came up with a
solution,
problem disappeared.
The little boy guided by his
imagination,
adopted identification with the hero
faced his worst nightmare.
If we're to survive individually and
socially,
each of us must do the same
trick.
Wiliness inventor in film will be found.
This is the prime alchemical victim.
What do you need most is always to be
found where you least wish to look.
It's not a mythological statement.
It's the only recognition of the fact
that in order to adapt to ongoing
experiences necessary to make use of
every experience that you've had and
it's only those experiences that you
haven't made use of,
that you determined are too terrifying
to contemplate,
and then as a logical consequences,
it's necessarily the case that all of
those things that you're allowed to
state classified as too terrible to
contemplate,
do in fact contain all that information
that you need to survive because it is
their locked.
It's the.
It's their lack of use.
That has actually resulted in you
constructing a personality that's too
trivial to to withstand the full weight
of your experience.
You know,
if something's bugging you,
you know,
it's like let's say you have,
you have a situation with your parents
that's never been resolved.
It's like bugging you for who knows some
people that things like that funding for
like decades without ever facing the
reason it's bugging us because that's a
little chunk of the unknown that your
limbic system has detected so to speak,
and it's always popping it up saying,
look,
look.
Here's some information you're not
paying attention to.
Well,
I don't want to pay attention to it
because it makes me anxious.
Well,
he asked.
It makes them anxious.
That's how.
That's the form that new information
always takes,
right?
That's how it interests into your
consciousness to begin with as something
that makes you anxious.
Of course you have any number of reasons
to move away from it since it makes you
anxious,
but the problem is if you keep doing
that,
then you don't make use of all the.
All the novel experience on the question
is,
well,
why would you move away from it instead
of facing it?
Well,
the answer to that is obviously because
you don't think that you're capable of
facing it,
which is to say that you've defined
yourself in opposition to this thing
which is intolerable,
and the definition that you use is that
I am too insignificant or weak or
whatever,
inconsequential consequential or unable
to face this aspect of my experience,
which I know by my own rules actually
exists.
No
anomalous information brings terror and
possibility,
revolution and transformation,
rejection of an unbearable facts stifles
adaptation and strangles life.
There was a good man who owned the
vineyard.
He leased it to tenant farmers so that
they might work at.
Then he might collect the produce from
them.
He sends his servant so the tenants
might be having the proper use of the
vineyard bases to serve and beat him all
week.
Telling him serving.
Went back and told his master.
The master said perhaps they didn't
recognize him.
He sends another servant.
Tenants beat this one as well.
Then no one has said his son and said
perhaps they will show respect to my son
because of the tenants knew that it was
he who was heir to the vineyard.
They seized him and killed him,
but him who has ears hear Christ said,
show me the stone which the builders
have rejected that.
We'll use the cornerstone.
Thank
you.
Great.
That particular story,
as one of the sources for the notion of
the philosopher's stone says,
show me the stone which the builders
have rejected that.
What is the cornerstone?
Oh,
it's a complicated story.
Was he in the Jewish temple?
The quarter stone was the stone that had
the perfect dimensions with all of
stones are based on that.
Right?
Right.
Jesus as the savior,
Messiah,
and he is the one that.
Well,
that's.
I would say that's a yes.
That's part of the symbolic structure
that surrounds the idea.
The story in a sense has more.
It has a more
straightforward interpretation in a way.
I mean all of it.
The moral of that story means is two
things.
One is then whatever it is you reject is
the thing that you need.
That's the first thing.
It doesn't matter what it is,
it's just the fact is that you have to
make use of all the things that present
themselves to you whether or not you
find the map actively tolerable.
Now we already know that you determined
what,
what's an effective tolerable as a
consequence of the value structure that
you were raped,
right?
You're always analyzing phenomena in
reference to the goals that you perceive
as valid,
so whether something is actively
tolerable,
no,
it depends to an immense degree on your
interpretation of what's important and
it's maybe the case that certain things
to you appear intolerable because you're
unwilling to give up a value structure
that's really pathological.
If you gave up the value structure,
the thing we looked unbearable wouldn't
be unbearable at all.
It might be positive so you can switch
the valence and things very rapidly by
just transforming the thing that you
believe it.
Well,
we already know that certain forms of
anomalous information have the capacity
to completely overthrow the philosophies
that you use to evaluate events.
What about the first part of that story
or the other story there?
That seems a little bizarre.
I don't quite see that they are one.
Well,
why is that idea of the story is saying,
well,
these two events are precisely the same
is that if you define yourself as that
creature,
which is unable to accommodate two or
assimilate negative events,
you've Ah,
you've abandoned your identification
with the hero.
That's what that means.
What did the individual characters
symbolizing the story about the
vineyard?
They symbolize?
Well,
that's what I was trying to get at with
them with that.
Well,
the owner of the vineyard symbolizes
God.
Okay.
Now the story is trying to represent is
the idea that sacrifice of identity with
the hero,
which is equivalent to this death
internally is equivalent to rejection of
the novelist information.
That's what it means because it's.
This is the thing that I've been trying
to lay out describing the relationship
between the process that's represented
by Satan's Milton Satan.
There's no difference between saying
this thing is to to intolerable to face
and saying,
I am too little deface it.
Those are exactly the same thing.
So removing yourself away from
information that you regard as to
threatened to tolerate is identical to a
destruction of identification with the
hero.
So why the two services?
First,
we're wondering what are the.
What?
What's that from?
Yeah,
I,
I don't know.
I don't know actually what route.
Maybe.
What's
that?
Well,
yeah.
Yeah.
I guess what I guess what those figures
represent his approximations to the hero
that which,
which would fit perfectly well and into
the,
into the interpretation that they were
prophets.
I mean,
you know what they like to hear hero
even less,
right?
Right.
They weren't too thrilled with people
who approximated the hero precisely.
And so that will.
That's exactly the case.
I mean it's a rare.
It's referenced to the fact that people
tend to devour people in groups tend to
devour those individuals upon which the
group actually depends.
And what this story is pointing out,
I guess,
is that that would even be the case if
they figured that constituted the
archetypical individual upon whom the
group depends appeared how people would
still be motivated to do precisely the
same thing.
So.
Okay,
well then the next thing which I really
don't have time to go into in much
detail,
so you have to read this,
but this will give you some,
some intimation of at least what was
going on and know.
Look,
I've been,
while it's been my position
fundamentally,
that people have paid an insufficient
amount of attention to use writings.
Well,
they're confusing,
that's for sure.
I give some reasons why that might be
the case in the manuscript.
Most of his students were women.
Most of them were outside of the
academic tradition.
He discussed religious imagery to a
large degree in psychology tends to shy
away from any religious imagery because
it's very young scientists and it's just
dissociated itself from philosophy.
It's dominated by materialistic way more
materialists in psychology than there
are in physics for example.
There's all sorts of reasons.
It's certainly the case with youngs
early writings,
but it's even more dramatically the case
with his later writings and all his
later writings deal with alchemy and
nobody's been able to figure out what
the hell he was talking about.
Why spend all this time trying to
decipher these l chemical writings,
but what was the trying?
What was young was trying to
outline was the symbolic representations
of the internal process that occurs when
people do precisely what my nephew in
this dream said that he should do,
which is to say
what are the consequences of.
You can put it all sorts of different
ways.
What are the consequences of admission
of error or what are the consequences of
identification with Harold?
Or what are the consequences of the
adoption of a stance of religious
humility?
Because all those things piled together
and actually constitute the same
phenomena.
And what you said was,
well,
it's possible for people to undergo
revolutions in their cognitive
structures.
We know that from Thomas Kuhn much later
by the way,
so this is not only true for empirical
structures,
but also for moral structures so we know
that's the case and people have updated
their views of the world over and over
and what.
What you was trying to point out was
that this could actually happen within
an individual and not only that it could
happen,
but that it had happened many times in
the past and there was symbolic
representations of all the stages of
this particular process and most of them
are going to be pretty familiar to you
already because I'd be trying to make
reference to them all the time in the
diagrams that I've been using you and
basically stated that there were 45
sequences of events
frequently intermingled in terms of the
narrative structure that characterized
the alchemy,
some more the alchemist trying to do
while they were people who possessed by
an intimation of the insufficiency of
the churches.
Rick,
a representation of reality followed
their notion that there was still valued
to be apprehended in the interpretation
and discovery of matter.
The alchemists were the first scientists
in a service knowing from the empirical
perspective because they didn't have an
experimental method method methodology,
but from the standpoint of interest
because they were the first people who
were willing to pause it.
That in this huge domain that had
essentially been outlawed as heretical
by the church,
something of interest still might be
there to be found.
He said,
well look,
you know,
the Church says,
as a consequence of these historical
events,
humanity is being redeemed.
The alchemists,
you might say,
looked around and said,
well,
if this redemption taking place,
things are still in pretty sad shape,
so maybe there's something more going on
here.
Then we might that might meet the eye.
All they become interested in.
So you want you almost trying to do is
to explain why it was that we developed
science,
especially why developed in Europe.
So what,
what were the historical precedence to
the explosion of science in the last 500
years following the reasonably logical
hypothesis that something of that
magnitude was likely prepared by us at
least several centuries of previous
thought rather than just like coming out
of nowhere all of a sudden and only in
one culture so.
Well,
the first thing that preceded the
development of science was the notion
that the pursuit of
knowledge about material might in fact
be valuable.
So that's the hypothesis,
test the hypothesis,
the abundant life science is that if you
investigated the transformations of the
material world,
you might find some information of
value.
You said,
well,
this first popped up in the form of what
might be regarded as a kind of cultural
dream,
and the dream was the dream of the
philosopher stone,
which was that there was a material
substance that if you only possessed it
with grandpa and of your wishes,
and you can say,
well,
what is it that motivates science?
This is why you thought that science was
still embedded in the mythological
format.
I said,
that's what motivates us at the border.
We're convinced that if we can just find
out enough about the way things are made
that we won't have to get old anymore
and we won't have to get sick anymore
and there'll be enough for everyone and
all that seems like a perfectly
reasonable hypothesis as far as I can
tell me
anyways.
He tried out.
Now,
the other thing that you pointed out,
however,
and this is I suppose where the argument
gets very,
very complicated,
is that
what the outcome is set out to
investigate was not matter as we can see
that because they didn't know what
matter was as we can see that they
didn't even have way of representing it.
Blacking entirely an empirical
methodology for what they were actually
out to explorer was the unknown part of
which was mattered in the material
world.
As from the from the medieval
perspective and young basically made the
point that what the outcome was did was
posited that the notions of the church,
which is the group identity basically
we're not complained,
were insufficient.
Which is to say that you
positive that the alchemist was someone
who was willing to admit to him,
to himself that the manner in which the
world had been interpreted was not
complaint.
Which is to say that there was still
something left.
So you could say,
well,
he.
He regarded himself as something that
was still ignorant and also the church
community,
which was essentially totalitarian was
too military infrastructure is could be
imagined,
was nonetheless incomplete,
and you said,
well,
it was merely the process of that
preset,
which is I don't know everything.
Maybe there's still something left to
explore necessarily produced and our
identity of the alchemist with the hero,
even though they didn't know what I
mean,
that because what they were doing was
acting out the role of the hero and you
can say,
well,
whenever you do that,
certain things happen and those things
are expressed to no chemical symbolism
and what happens when you drop the role
of the hero,
but were you already know that it's like
there's a mission that unknown
information exists.
The information comes in.
It blows the structure of your previous
worldview.
He descended into a a situation that's
characterized by emotional chaos as a
consequence of processes that occur in
that state of chaos.
There's a reconstruction of a new world
view,
but how is that represented?
Now can be the first stage is we're
represented either by the prime of
material or the descent of the king.
Now you guys should know enough about
symbolism to start to understand what
this means.
He said,
well,
what happens to you when you first admit
that something that meant everything to
you might not be complete?
He said,
well,
that can be represented as two ways,
depending in two ways,
depending on what stage of the process
you need to be represented by the depth
of the cake or by your identity with
what was called in Alchemy,
the primary material,
which is basically chaos,
the dragon of chaos,
and you can say,
well,
those two things are the same.
Why pause?
Because of the descent of the king,
the descendant of King and beyond your
world,
or the death of the king or the
distillation of became.
Remember the alchemists.
They were trying to explain things like
why matter would dissolve saying salt
water and mercury.
So it's a weird mixture of empirical
speculation and metaphysical theorizing.
You remember the alchemist didn't have
any scientific techniques,
so all they could do when they were
manipulating material,
the material world,
which was demonic like church
association,
was used,
their fantasies and what were their
fantasies full of last mythologies,
Christian mythology.
That was their worldview fundamentally.
So of course that's all they saw.
Everything.
It's all they knew.
That's the dragon of chaos,
the prime of material,
the source of all things.
Well,
in the medieval view,
the primary material was not just
something material.
It was much more akin to these
mythological notions of the dragon that
we've discussed because the outcome is
set well.
Whatever the world comes from is a weird
intermingling of all those things that
will eventually become society,
the individual soul and matter,
which is I think an unbelievably
sophisticated perspective because,
well,
that's something you'll have to think
about on your own,
but it is the case that whatever the
source of all things is is that thing
which in time turns into the subject and
an object plus society at large.
Now we tend to think of that something,
that thing as something purely material,
but that's because we make the
presupposition that whatever we are a
subject is something that's reducing to
whatever is through the material and I
would say,
well that might be true,
but if it is the case that whatever we
are is reducible to something material,
by the time we figured you figured out
how that relationship exists,
the way we interpret matter will be
completely different from the way we
interpreted now and that's.
That's one.
That's one thing that really argues
against a simple minded material.
Reductionism is the presupposition that
you understand the phenomena to which
you're reducing everything,
which you know clearly.
Anyways,
all these stages,
there are descriptions of this process.
The key,
the death of the king produces
immersement and chaos that was also
described as the Nigredo,
which is an interesting stage.
It's often represented in an alchemical
symbolism,
has a.
An old man who was black who was very
close to death,
sitting in a pit like breathing out of
the Raven.
It's symbol.
It's symbolic of anxiety and depression.
Fundamentally more than that.
Also emotional chaos and all you one was
trying to point out in this analysis,
so our committee,
what is the.
If you lose a moral philosophy,
your emotions become dysregulated and
you're swamped with anxiety and
depression.
The outcome is regarded that as a state
in this process of transformation.
Not as a final statement necessarily,
but it's the kind of thing that needs
she's describing when he talks about
standing at the edge of the cliff and
looking off into the abyss.
Well,
that's the UBS.
The chaos is represented by on the
dragon also by the queen of chaos.
That's.
That was my representation anyways.
I said,
well,
the notion here was the
thing that was to be dissolved in the
salt solvent.
The king and chaos can be represented as
a Kenyan,
a queen,
the queen sorting,
making reference to the sort of
matriarchal symbolism that we've talked
about the past and that was the union of
those two things that would produce a
new structure and that's an idea that's
very much like the old Egyptian idea of,
well,
cirrus going into the underworld or or
the idea of the Egyptians have that the
Egyptian Pharaoh was simultaneously the
old dead Pharaoh and the new federal,
which is to say that
if you have a particular philosophical
viewpoint,
which is the manner in which you would
describe an aspect of value to your
environment and it dissolves all things
that you had classified are no longer
classifiable and you're swamped as a
consequence.
Swamp with anxiety and depression,
which are two of emotional phenomena
that that whole classification system
wasn't directed to inhabit.
To begin with.
When that system blows itself apart,
those emotions come back up.
And and how do you construct a new
system?
Well,
you use the anomalous information that's
blowing your old system apart,
plus everything that you had known
before to erect something new.
And the outcome is symbolized by the
Union of the king border and the Queen
of chaos,
sexual union,
something that notion that makes
illusion to incest symbolism and their
offspring.
The divine son was the new state of
order on the outcome associated that
with
with the philosopher's stone.
Everything,
either a permanent state of order or a
permanent state of redemption or the
process that gives rise to that when she
was the aspect that we're more
interested in.
I'm sorry.
That's too much to bring that discussion
to make,
to do justice to you,
his ideas,
but they can't really be summarized
rapidly.
Okay.
I just ask you one thing that's always
interested me is there it is.
The Union of opposites
essentially given the context,
the context of the theory of this class,
I take the union of opposites to me,
sort of a creative type of stable
hierarchy of goals.
Yes,
but those goals are essentially a
separate things in competition.
I mean if they're not,
if they're not organized or
effects often,
why?
Why did it?
You characterize it as a union of
opposites because the fact that they're
in competition doesn't necessarily mean
that there isn't a structure where you
have exactly one opposed to another.
What did he mean?
Did he get that out of you got that out
of symbolism I guess,
but at the same time,
why isn't it represented more in terms
of sort of chaotic competition for other
than that?
In terms of the.
That's a good question.
What I think it's mostly because he
viewed the competition of.
It's more from the perspective of the
mythological structures that we've
discussed where things are held in
opposite the positive aspect of the,
of the creative unknown at the negative
aspect,
the positive aspect of the known and the
negative and there's clearly a structure
of opposites there and if you what if
you take the biological perspective that
what young is referring to is the
integration of different effects driven
philosophies in a sense.
Then the notion that they're in
opposition breaks down to some degree.
There's still a certain amount of.
Would you say was that Kurt,
to to guess that they were represented
that way simply because that's an easy
way to,
to review conflicting things is in terms
of a simple up opposition.
I mean if you're gonna spend more than
that too though because like let's say
that
let's say that
the two things you want in a given
situation,
conflict with one another,
so that means you value one thing and
you value.
Now you're in love with someone they
don't like your job.
Alright?
So those are two affectively driven
philosophies in a sense,
structures of value that are brought
into conflict as a consequence of a new
situation.
In those situations,
those forces would war and opposition
and that's part of the reason why this
has always represented as opposing
forces mean you don't have a conflict
until you have a conflict of duty.
You have a conflict of duty.
When one thing you think is important
and valuable and morally appropriate
conflicts very powerfully with another
thing that you think is valuable and
morally inappropriate.
Then you're caught in the war,
torn apart by these two.
Flow down.
One of the things you and was trying to
point out was that your a structure
evaluation,
the fact that you love this person,
the fact that you valued this job are
structures that have developed as a
consequence of an incredibly lengthy
historical process and even the notion
of love,
although it might be rooted in certain
biological predispositions,
is a cultural construct that's developed
over thousands and thousands of years.
That's,
that's fed in part for example by the
notions of,
uh,
what's the medieval notion?
Central many medieval notion of
gallantry chivalry,
right?
I mean love is the construction and
part.
Why do you.
Why are you so attracted to your job in
that particular circumstance?
Well,
it's very complicated job as being
described values as a consequence of all
sorts of processes.
It's your way of holding anxiety and
depression at bay had they.
It's part of the way that you described
determinant meaning to the world.
It's part of a larger social structure.
When you put those forces in opposition
in a given circumstance or when they can
flip in a given circumstance,
you're torn apart as a consequence of
their conflict that makes you the pawn
of the gods,
so to speak.
What you was trying to describe in his l
chemical sequences is the process by
which all these conflicting hierarchies
of value could be brought into one
internally.
Coherent story.
My story he was trying to represent,
he said,
well,
by the end of the chemical period,
the more psychologically sophisticated
alchemists were drawing an analogy
between whatever the hell the
philosopher's stone was in Christ,
which is very peculiar thing.
So as they had more or less left the
church in order to pursue this process
to begin with,
and what does that mean?
Well,
the philosopher's stone was the thing
that represented that thing that's of
ultimate value and in Christian
mythology that's also love Christ
represent.
So it's not very surprising that they
would end up falling into the same
category,
so to speak,
because it was the existence of that
category that gave rise to both those
concrete examples.
Anyways.
Well,
the question is,
what the hell does this represent what
we're trying to get at painful even dot
last lecture?
Well,
we know already that this process might
be regarded as the continual process by
which particular answers to the
philosophical question,
what is the good or generates like,
here's one philosophical Schema,
new information,
what was it?
The part it's replaced by another one
that's theoretically more complete.
New information comes in and blows it
apart and so on and so forth.
Always never ending says,
well,
how do you get out of 12?
We sent over months ago.
Look,
you pop out of identification with any
of the states which is adolescent
identification with an ideology anyways
under all circumstances,
and you start to identify with the
process which is the process of
voluntary encountered with the unknown
descent into this chaotic state and
reconstruction says,
well,
the only have two modes of protection
against a known one is identification
with a particular system of beliefs.
The other is identification with the
process by which chaos itself can be
transformed in order.
Do you have a saying,
well,
this constant,
and this is represented various in
various ways and mythology sometimes as
the philosopher's stone sometime as the
figure of a given prophet like Moses,
sometimes it's price,
sometimes it's Buddha,
what is supposed to represent his
identification with the process of
adaptation and not the outcome.
You said
what's your youngest concerned with is
the hierarchical structuring of value
systems.
That's what do you mean by the Union of
opposites?
Well,
but you said was,
look,
there's only one answer to the problem
of what's more important than what else,
which is to say there's only one answer
in a sense to the problem of how value
should be hierarchically organized,
and his answer was essentially the thing
that's at the pyramid of the hierarchy
of values should be the process by which
the whole hierarchy is constructed and
that means everything should be
subordinate to it.
So when you read,
for example,
in the new testament notions that say
it's more difficult for a rich man to.
It's easier for a rich man to go through
the eye of a needle than to enter into
the Kingdom of heaven.
What the story means is if you think
that security,
which means how do I deal with death,
how do I deal with the Old Lady,
how do I deal with sickness,
can be found.
If you think that money,
material possessions for that matter can
provide you with the kind of security
that you want,
which is security in the face of all
those terrible things.
You're wrong because it won't work,
and furthermore,
if you put the desire for money,
which is security basically,
above all else,
you'll sacrifice necessarily sacrifice
identification with the only process
that could in the final analysis offer
for you,
the kind of protection that you're
needing.
So it's not going to work.
Well.
First of all,
this is.
There's an assumption here that order is
a good thing.
That's,
you know,
that's what you're.
Well,
there's an assumption here,
right?
That's,
that's the problem with these states is
that is the assumption orders.
Good chaos isn't.
That's wrong,
right?
I see.
Okay.
So then you get to that point and what
an unresolved issue I have.
Is that okay?
If you placed yourself with the ultimate
goal of the identification with the
process,
well,
I don't see how,
if you,
um,
you know,
actively moved towards the unknown,
look into that which we are all capable
of.
So I see I am capable of evil,
I am capable of killing someone.
I am capable of,
you know,
all these things.
Well,
what,
how does that fit into that?
How does that fit into that framework?
So
well,
tell me more to expand your notion of
what it is that you are and also perhaps
bring up the capabilities that you would
be unwilling to use or even unwilling to
admit to at times in situations where
they might be appropriate.
Like it isn't until,
for example,
it may be that in order to survive
optimally,
whatever that means,
that you might have to have access to a
whole realm of aggressive impulses.
The existence of which you're not even
willing to admit.
So we say,
well,
if you can actually come to grips with
the fact that your behavioral capacities
are much broader on the negative side
than you might have on the negative side
as you define it,
then you might have never been willing
to admit and you can also start to
understand that you may have
capabilities that you have not even
begun to explore,
and it's certainly the case that all,
although aggression can be used in all
sorts of ways that appear clearly
negative,
that there's any number of situations
where the capacity to maintain your
ground or even to move forward in the
face of tremendous opposition is
absolutely necessary to you.
So that would be.
That would be one part of the excel.
It's also the case that until you're
capable,
have at least conceiving conceptually of
how significant the errors that you're
making might be.
You haven't got a hope in hell of doing
anything about them.
You can't even see that they're there.
He say,
well,
I'm not the sort of person that would
ever do anything like that,
which is of course just patently,
patently ridiculous.
Once you see that you are capable of
killing someone or are capable of,
you know,
aggressive behavior,
it almost makes you not the hero not to
act upon those.
Aggressiveness stinks.
I mean,
there may be some certain cases where,
yeah,
that's actually our right.
You know,
if you're four years,
six years old and you go to the
playground and the nine year old pounds,
you flat,
you can't go home thinking while I did
the right thing,
I was nonviolent because the reason you
were nonviolent just because you got
pounded,
clap.
Now it's different situation entirely.
If you go out somewhere and you have the
capability of truly aggressive response
and you're provoking and you don't
manifest it well,
then that's a different circumstance,
but the mere lack of ability to respond
in a negative way,
it's no indication whatsoever of any
morality.
That's why I need you to send no
standing.
Morality is cowardice.
It wasn't because he thought all
morality equals cowardice.
It's because much of much of what passes
for what much of what people define to
themselves as their own morality is just
their own cowardice.
That's part of the reason why I figures
like the gangster are so popular in
American mythology because they act out
what everyone would actually like to do,
so to speak,
but is too moral,
which isn't the case at all too cowardly
to do.
Now there's positive and well,
how can you simultaneously say that I'm
the person who denies,
um,
error,
the are the person who denies this
within them as evil and yet killing is
evil.
Um,
how can you say those two things?
Well,
I didn't say the ladder.
What killing isn't,
but that's what I'm trying to get at.
Like are we trying to say here that
killing is evil?
Look
there only one way to answer that
question I guess.
And that is one of the things that are.
One of the things that's constantly
referred to in hero mythologies is the
fact that
you shouldn't break a traditional rule.
Okay?
So that answers that question,
right?
It's wrong.
But then there's a problem with that in
the traditional rules as listed are not
a sufficient and complete guide to
adaptations.
So then the question is,
well,
under what circumstances is it
reasonable to break a rule?
Well that's a different issue.
And so in the broad sense you can say,
well,
you know,
do you want to be good?
Well then you follow the Ten
Commandments.
I mean there are there rules upon which
most civilized societies are structured,
fine,
but there are situations in which the
rules conflict,
for example,
or whether where perhaps they're not
necessarily applicable well under those
circumstances than what can guide your
morality.
Well,
that's the question that we're trying to
answer here because we also need to know
if this is the theory,
so to speak.
What's the practical implication?
Because that's one thing that you need
to know.
I mean that's the only reason that any
of these stories have any relevance to
begin with.
Well,
it's your attitude towards the novelist.
Information in large part determines
your morality.
So let's say,
let's see if we can figure out what that
means.
First of all,
I would say,
look,
it's the case that
no,
you might ask yourself the question,
what does life have?
Any beans?
Well,
that's the question that people often
ask themselves and I would say,
well,
what is that you mean by that?
Well,
what does meaning mean?
for me it means implication for action.
I mean that's what we mean when we say
meaning,
are we meeting emotional significance?
And then I would say,
well,
so we're going to look at this
structure.
Emotional significance.
Well,
what does anomalous information for
Dusek well,
anxiety,
especially if it's involuntary
hope,
interest.
Oh,
isn't that interesting means that has
some significance for my behavior or the
way that I interpret things that I'd
never considered before.
Speed.
I'm going to read the last three days.
That'll pretty much do this.
Do a same interest is meaning,
meaning is the manifestation of the
divine,
which is the individual adaptive path.
Pursued of interest necessarily exposes
the individual tomorrow when social
limitations,
I'm produces a symbolic death of
personality which sort of simultaneously
as the precondition to renewal an
antidote to the necessity of real death.
When circumstances inevitably change.
What does that mean?
Well,
if you watch your experience,
there are going to be phenomena that
appear to you as if they're meaningful.
I would say they attract your interest.
You can watch yourself.
Your interest will be attracted by the
not even on your own accord,
so to speak,
just by the fact that those phenomena
for reasons that you might not
understand,
produce an orienting response or in your
heightened your interest.
Well,
I would say that that's evidence of the
manifestation of the unknown,
so to speak,
from within the perspective of your
particular philosophical framework says
if you follow those things that appear
to you as meaningful,
which is what you want to do anyways,
because it is the case that that is the
sort of thing that people want to do
virtually.
By definition.
What will happen is you'll end up
participating in the process that you
described,
which is to say that if you hold onto
your interest and don't let it go
despite all the social pressure that
you'll find not to do it because you're
supposed to be doing the thing that
everyone else says is useful and the
fact that it's going to expose to you
all sorts of things that you didn't
understand to begin with.
Well,
what if I find it immensely interesting
to cut to it?
Well,
no,
this is absolutely,
absolutely.
We will definitely discuss that.
I mean,
that's.
Look,
there's two poles obviously say you know
what's like Joseph Campbell?
He says,
follow your bliss,
right?
Well,
in the first thing that pops into the
head of the good paranoid is exactly
what Daniel popped up.
It's like,
what if my interest is serial killing?
Because if you read,
if you read accounts of serial killers,
for example,
what you find very rapidly is that
they're very interested in what they
were doing and so if you are very
interested,
they couldn't start doing and they got
their interest expanded as they
continued to pursue the territory.
So you say,
well obviously interesting in of itself
is known as sufficient guide because you
can interest can manifest itself within
the confines of the personality that so
pathological than in,
in and of itself is a sign post for
pathology.
When I say,
well,
that's why we concentrated so much on
this.
So if you feel your head up with
garbage,
what did labels is interesting,
it's no longer going to be healthy and
so there's two poles to the sort of
moral process that we've been
describing.
One is do what you're interested in.
Make sure you do what you're interested
in.
The second thing is don't lie to
yourself because if you lie to yourself,
you're going to work the mechanism that
produces interest as a phenomena because
we already know,
look,
we already know that.
What occurs to you as anomalous,
what pops up in your phenomenological
field as meaningful?
It's going to be dependent very much on
the philosophical theory that you bring
to bear on the event is write your
goals,
the ends you have in mind and so on and
so forth,
determined the significance of
phenomena.
The only way you can ensure that those
structures are healthy is if their
existence accounts for all of the
experience that you've actually had in
the past,
which is to say that you've constantly
modified and updated your worldview to
account for all of the experience that
you've had.
But if you don't do that,
you're living within a philosophy that's
twisted off cedric precisely to the
degree that you've twisted it off
center.
The more that it's twisted,
the more that whole structure is going
to produce intimations of meaning where
they shouldn't be,
and then if you follow those well,
they'll lead you places that perhaps you
would have never really wanted to go or
maybe deeply,
unconsciously,
perhaps leading you exactly where you
want it to go.
It depends on how you look at it.
So there's two poles.
One is when it comes right down to it,
the only thing that you have to rely on
is the phenomena,
meaning you know what it occurs and when
it doesn't mean if you're immersed in
something you really love,
what are they?
One of the phenomena that might be that
the self consciousness vanishes.
That's one thing you can see what
performers who are really great,
they're really immersed in what they're
doing is that they're very attractive
because they've mastered that domain so
well that they pay absolutely no
attention to themselves as phenomenon
while they're doing whatever it is
they've been doing.
Another thing is if you're immersed in
that,
then your notion of time tends to
disappear so you can be working very
hard on whatever it is that you're
interested in book.
I say,
well,
where did it all the time?
Nope,
and I would say,
well,
that's another indication that that's
that phenomenon is producing an added
note to self consciousness because a big
aspect of self consciousness is tick,
tick,
tick of the consciousness of time.
What pops you out of that?
Meaning?
Where does meaning manifest itself?
It manifests itself on the border
between order and chaos and the reason
it does that is because that's where all
the adaptive processes are taking place.
That's where you have to be operating in
in order to ensure that the phenomena
that you use to interpret the world with
the structures you use to interpret the
world are constantly being updated and
also those of your society are
constantly being updated because after
all I discover something and then I tell
it to you and that's how.
So that means that the individual
process of creative
exploration updates the social world as
well.
So
it's not a simple matter of,
well,
the other thing Campbell's statement for
example,
is follow your bliss.
Well,
this strikes me as quite quite one sided
in the sense as well,
and I guess that's the problem with new
age philosophy.
I mean,
that's why I like his works on alchemy.
I said,
look,
you look where you don't want to look.
Now,
if someone tells you that it strikes me
that maybe you could believe it seems
realistic to me,
rather than a message that says,
well,
if you do,
if you do in some simplistic sense,
whatever makes you happy,
that's perfectly fine,
so young,
escaping through his analysis of this
chemical process that if you pay
attention to what you find meaningful,
it will take you to the place where you
would least likely to want to go first
because of because of the necessity of
this process emerging.
Okay.
The abandonment of meaning ensures the
induction of the demonic mode of
adaptation because the individual hates
point is pain and frustration and we'll
work towards destruction of its source.
This work constitutes his revenge
against existence,
which is pride is rendered unbearable.
Rebirth is reestablishment of interest
after adoption of culturally determined
competence is rebirth,
makes the individualist practically
adapted as anyone in history has
motivated is he has courage to be the
rebirth of interest moves man to the
border between the known culture and the
unknown nature and thereby expands is
adaptive competence his in the world in
this manner,
the domain of history is expanded.
This capability for extension is the
manifestation of God within the
individual in the modern world.
Socialization should allow the
individual to devote the power of
history to the act of exploration.
Interest manifested in the absence of
self deceit,
places each of us on the border of the
unknown and removes the tragedy from
temporality.
The pursuit of subjective of interest in
there inevitably brings each individual
into contact with his own fears,
such contact mediocre in the social
sphere when expression of individuality
conflicts with normative behavior or in
this sphere of the absolutely unknown.
When pursuit of individual interest
takes man beyond the cultural Canada and
places him against the forces that
govern mortality and limitation per se.
The heroic motive being is predicated
upon the assumption that something
divine exists within the individual that
is capable of manifesting itself when
called upon when necessary.
This is individual possibility arises to
meet the challenge presented by life
without faith in the heroic challenge
must be avoided from the practical
viewpoint,
this means the abandonment of
subjectivity and the search for
security.
This choice eliminates the possibility
for personal development and increases
the likelihood of fanatic identification
with history or adoption about outright
distractedness.
Selfconsciousness means in knowledge of
individual vulnerability.
The process by which this knowledge
comes to be can destroy faith and
individual work.
What this means in concrete terms is
that in the course of development and
the individual may come to sacrifice his
own experience because it's pursuit
creates social conflict or exposes
individual inadequacy.
However,
it is only through such conflict that
change takes place and weakness must be
recognized before it can be transformed
into strength.
This means that the sacrifice of
individuality eliminates any possibility
that individual strength can be
discovered or developed,
and then history itself can progress.
Individuals whose life is without
meaning hate themselves for their
weakness and hate life or making them
weak.
His hatred manifests itself and
identification with destructive power
and it's mythological historical and
biological manifestations and in desire
for the absolute extinction of
existence.
Such identification leads,
Manda poison,
whatever he touches degenerate,
unnecessary misery in the face of
inevitable suffering to turn this
fellows against themselves,
to intermingle earth with hail merely to
attain vengeance upon God garden,
his creation,
the human purpose,
if such a thing can be considered,
is to pursue meaning to extend the
domain of light and consciousness in
spite of limitation.
Meaningful event exists on the boundary
between security and novelty.
The pursuit of meaning exposes the
individual to the unknown in gradual
fashion,
allowing him to develop strength and
adaptive ability in proportion to the
seriousness of his pursuit is during
contact with an unknown that human power
grows individually and then historically
meaning is the subjective experience
associated with that contact and
sufficient proportion,
the great religious misstate that
continued pursuit of meaning adopted
voluntarily and without self deception
will lead the individual to discover his
identity with God and to the bead,
thereby capable of withstanding the
tragedy of life.
Abandoned of such meaning reduces man
who is more than weaknesses.
It makes them hate life and work towards
it's elimination.
It could be said that meeting is the
most profound manifestation of instinct,
so that's why I think Adam hid from God
in the garden of Eden.
Man is a creature attracted by the
unknown and adapted for its conquest.
The subjective sense of meeting is the
instinct governing rate of contact with
the unknown.
Too much exposure turns changed to chaos
and too little promote stagnation and
degeneration.
The appropriate balance produces a
powerful individual confidence in the
ability to withstand life,
ever more able to deal with nature and
society and ever closer to the heroic
ideal.
Each individual constitutional unique
finds meaning in different pursuits.
If he has the courage to maintain his
difference,
manifestation of individual diversity
transformed into knowledge that can be
transferred socially changes the face of
history itself and moves each generation
of men farther into the unknown.
Social and biological conditions defined
the boundaries of individual existence.
The unfailing pursuit of interest
provides the subject of means by which
these conditions can be met and their
boundaries.
Transcendent meaning is the instinct
that makes life possible.
When it is abandoned,
individuality loses its redemptive
power.
The great lie is that meaning does not
exist or that it is not important.
When meaning is denied hatred for life
and the for destruction inevitably
rules.
If you bring forth what is within you,
what you bring forth will save you.
If you do not bring forth what is within
you,
what you do not bring forth will destroy
the wisdom of the group can serve as a
forest that mediates between the
dependency of childhood and the
responsibility of the adult.
This makes history of the power that
serves the individual society predicated
upon belief in the divinity of the
individual,
allows individual interests to flourish
and to serve as the forest that opposes
the tyranny of culture and the terror of
nature.
The denial of meaning by contrast
ensures absolute identification with the
group or interest psychic degeneration.
If such identification fails,
the denial of meaning makes the
individual desperate.
When the validity of identification is
challenged and the great maternal sea of
chaos threatens his weakness,
makes them hate life as well and to work
for it's devastation in him and as well
as those around the lie,
as the Central Act in this drama of
corruption.
These are the secrets sayings which the
living Jesus Spoken,
which did a most Judas Thomas wrote
down.
This is from the Nag Hammadi Library,
and he said,
whoever finds the interpretation of
these sayings will not experience death.
Christ said,
let him who seeks continue seeking until
he finds,
when he becomes troubled,
he will be astonished and he will rule
over the all Jesus said,
if those who lead you say to you,
see the kingdom is in the sky than the
birds of the sky will precede you.
If they say to you it is in the sea and
the fish will proceed you rather the
kingdom is inside of you and it is
outside of you.
When you come to know yourselves,
then you will become known and you will
realize that is in you,
that it is you who are the sons of the
living father,
but if you will not know yourselves,
you dwell in poverty and it is you who
are that poverty.
Christ said,
the old man,
olden days will not hesitate to ask a
small child seven days old about the
place of life and he will live for many
who are first will become lost and they
will become one in the same.
Christ said,
recognize what is in your site and that
which is hidden from you will be
complaining to you for there is nothing
hidden which will not become manifest
his disciples and said to him,
do you want us to fast?
How shall we pray?
Shall we give arms?
What Diet shall we observe?
Christ said,
do not tell lines and do not do what you
hate.
For all things are playing in this side
of heaven for nothing hidden will not
become manifest and nothing covered will
remain without being uncovered.
That's it.
Thanks.