Yeah,
did you see the news?
Professor Jordan Peterson of the
University of Toronto,
the professor who's been fighting so
valiantly for free speech and academic
freedom and against political
correctness.
He has had his scholarly funding cut off
his grant application to continue as
academic research.
It was rejected for the first time in
his career 10 times.
He's applied 10 times as being granted.
He's a successful professor,
beloved by his students,
huge popular following,
lots of published research.
He'd normally be treated like an
academic star,
but as soon as he was attacked by the
forces of political correctness and he
refused to submit to them.
Well,
just by coincidence,
he was cut off by an anonymous
government committee.
I'm sorry,
I'm not buying it.
Just to be clear,
this research money isn't his salary,
it's the budget he needs to do his
research to hire graduate students and
other out of pocket expenses to pursue
his scholarships.
That's what's being rejected.
They've cut off his studies,
which just happens to include studying
the psychology of political correctness.
So I said to professor Peterson,
I said,
we can raise some money ourselves.
We don't need to depend on the
government and they're anonymous
bureaucrats.
I know for a fact that hundreds of
thousands of people,
millions actually have watched his
videos,
read about them in the news,
support them.
What if everyone chipped in a little bit
for his research ourselves.
What if we set up a
website@wwwdotsupportpetersonresearch.com
and he said,
sure,
let's give it a try.
I don't know why my research application
west rejected the reviews are anonymous
and all the reasons are not yet in,
but it's the first time my funding
request is being rejected in 20 years of
applications and I think it's important
research.
It's basic science and more rarely it
has immediate demonstrated public
applicability,
which is hypothetically one of the
social sciences and humanities research
councils,
mandates.
I requested funding to continue research
into the fundamentals of personality
psychology by not published a paper in
2007.
Dr Colin de Young was the primary
author,
the differentiated the standard big five
personality model into 10 aspects.
That's extroversion,
neuroticism,
agreeableness,
conscientiousness and openness.
How we differentiate each of them into
to some some traits we call them aspects
and that's become very widely used among
scientists as has the work we've done on
creativity.
We need to understand everything we can
about personality as it's an important
predictor of human behavior and I want
to do the fundamental research property.
We've also been assessing the
relationship between personality and
political belief,
liberal,
conservative and now politically correct
and it's the first time the latter has
been investigated scientifically.
Those beliefs are having a huge impact
on our culture and we believe it's
important to understand.
Finally,
we've been producing online
interventions such as the self authoring
suite.
You could see that@selfauthoring.com and
that's helped thousands of students get
better grades and stay in school.
We've raised the grade point average of
students 25 percent drop the dropout
rate by about 20 percent and that's been
especially useful for men and also for
non Western ethic minority students and
we want to continue the basic research
upon which such programs depend.
I should know too that none of this
salary,
none of this research money goes to me,
none of it.
It doesn't supplement my salary,
doesn't pay any of my personal expenses.
It's pretty much all spent on the celery
and tuition of my three graduate
students and I have three excellent
graduate students and helps me support a
postpartum postdoctoral student.
The remainder pays research subjects
with a bit leftover for travel.
We're supposed to present the results of
our research at scientific conferences.
We spend a little bit on computer
equipment.
It's bare bones funding.
Am I live is very efficient in spending,
so the rejection of my grant application
primarily hurts my students as well as
bringing the research effectively to a
halt,
so I'd like to try to crowd fund it.
I think that would be interesting for
people who support my work,
who've watched my videos or listening to
my podcasts are for anyone interested in
the research that I'm doing.
I guess I could invite you to join us
and be part of it.
Doing so.
It would also help me learn whether that
sort of funding for scientists as
possible because I've already been
contacted by others whose research was
curtailed for what appeared to be
political reasons,
so if it can be done for me,
perhaps it can be done on a more
permanent basis for others.
It'd be interesting to investigate that
and see if it's possible.
My application was for a five year
grant,
but it's less daunting if we do it one
year at a time.
Anyways.
You can see anyone interested,
conceived by a full proposal and a
shorter summary of it beneath this video
and now also app support Peterson
research.
Don't come back to you.
Israel.
Thanks Professor
Peterson.
I'll chip in the first $100.
It's the least I can do in the name of
free speech and academic freedom.
Now,
if that's too much for you,
well please consider $10.
If you can do more than $100,
please do.
Anyone who contributes $100 will get
access to an exclusive thank you video
from Professor Peterson for just $100.
Donors and anyone who contributes $250
will be invited to a reception where he
and his students will discuss his
progress and if you contribute the
thousand dollars,
you'll get all of the above as well as a
bound copy of the finished research
personally autographed by him.
So let's do this.
Go to support Peterson research.com.
We'll send all of the net proceeds
directly to professor Peterson
specifically for this research project.
Let's show the university and the
government panel that rejected this
project.
The Canadians believe in Professor
Peterson and his research and we're not
willing to let him or his work be
silenced.
Let's show Canada and the world that our
universities are still free.
Go to support Peterson research.com and
let's help a great professor and scholar
complete his work.
Thank you.