I called the course personality and its
transformations.
And I think you could think about that
as a restatement of the idea of being
and becoming.
And that's what you are.
You're for whatever that means.
You're an entity that both is and is
transforming.
And there's a rule that goes along with
that,
by the way,
which has don't sacrifice who you could
be for who you are,
which means if you have to choose to
transform in a positive direction or
maintain your current position,
then it's better to transform in a
positive direction.
So you might even think of that as the
core of your being.
And that's a Ph,
Eddie and idea.
It's a union idea as well.
Who are you?
You're the thing that transforms who you
are now.
You're also who you are.
But on top of that,
you're the thing that transforms who you
are.
And I,
I do think that that's,
and that's not an arbitrary statement,
you know,
um,
one of the things that modern
universities do dreadfully now is
convinced their students that value
structures are relative and that,
and that's a,
that's a big mistake.
It's,
there's a lot of things wrong with that
idea and one of the things that's wrong
with that ideas,
that doesn't include what I just
mentioned,
which is that's a good moral rule is you
are the thing that is and you're the
thing that becomes,
and you should put the thing that
becomes at a higher place than the thing
that is.
That means you also have to allow
yourself to shake off those things about
you,
that you might be pathologically
attached to habits and people for that
matter,
ways of thinking,
all of those things.
You have to allow yourself to shake
those off and that's more like a
burning,
that's why the Phoenix is,
that's why the Phoenix is the symbol
that it is,
right?
It's old and it deteriorates.
It bursts into flame and then it's
reborn.
It's like,
well,
do you want to be reborn?
It's like,
that's not the question.
The question is do you want to burst
into flame and answer to that generally
is no,
but that's the wrong answer.
The right answer is you let all that
nonsense burned away and you know,
and you might say,
well,
I don't know what I should leave behind.
An answer to that is that's a lie.
You know,
some of the things that you should leave
behind you,
all you have to do is ask yourself,
you'll come up with a list instantly
have a hundred stupid things that you're
doing that you know you could stop
doing.
Some of them maybe you don't know you
could stop doing.
It's like,
well fine,
leave those alone for now.
But there's a bunch of things you
perfectly know well that you could stop
doing that would improve your life.
And so do that to see what happens.
That's a good,
that's a good idea.
All right,
so its personality and its
transformations because partly I wanted
to talk to about,
talk to you about what you are as a
human being and also as an individual,
but also what you could become.
And that's actually a crucial question
in the domains of clinical psychology in
particular because a lot of what you're
doing with people as a clinician is
trying to figure who they could become.
That's right.
You come,
you're,
you have a problem.
Your life isn't what it could be.
It's like fine,
let's see what it could be like if we
changed it,
we'll figure out how to change it.
That's gotta be a negotiated dialogue,
right?
Cause they're like,
I don't know what the hell you should do
with your life.
I can help you figure it out.
Maybe we can talk about it,
but you are the person who has to decide
if the things that you're aiming for,
you know,
get you out of bed in the morning.
Cause that's really the,
that's at least one of the crucial
issues.
So you've got to specify the goal.
Then you got to specify that
transformation processes and start
practicing them.
And you have to understand that you're
going to be bad at it,
but it doesn't matter because bad's
fine.
Persistent is what you need to be.
If you persist with tiny improvements,
if you persist,
you win.
So,
okay,
so in a broader,
in a broader context,
you can think about this as a more
fundamental ontological question.
So one,
one question is how you should act in
the world.
The other question is,
well,
what is the world?
And that's complicated problem.
This is a scientific answer to that
question and now is that the world is a
collection of objective phenomena and
that's a very powerful perspective.
Um,
and we have a good method for
determining what the world is like as a
collection of objective phenomena.
And that's made us very technologically
powerful and so more power to us and all
that,
but leaves a question on answered.
And the question is,
well,
the world isn't just a place of
objective phenomena because it's not a
panoply of inert matter.
It has living conscious creatures in it.
And that's a different,
they're a different order of being.
And the fundamental issue for conscious,
active creatures is not what is the
world from an objective perspective,
but how it is that you should conduct
yourself in the world.
And that's a,
and there's a very,
there's a kind of unbridgeable gap
between those two domains of inquiry.
And I think the reason for that is that
there's a,
the scientific method removes value from
it's description.
So that's actually what it does.
And so once you're left with value free
descriptions,
it's very difficult to extract out a
value proposition from them cause
you've,
that's the scientific method removes the
value propositions.
You're supposed to be left with only
that which is objective,
right?
And value propositions are in the domain
of the subjective.
So I think the idea that you can derive
what you should be or do from a
collection of facts is flawed.
A,
because the collecting the facts
themselves gets rid of the value
structure.
But B,
there's an infinite number of facts.
And so which,
how are you going to pick which ones
should guide you?
You can't,
you can't,
you,
you have to do something else that the
facts do not tell you what to do with
the fact you need something else to help
you figure that out.
Well,
it's come to me over the years that
that's what essentially that's what the
narrative cognitive framework does.
It's the framework that we use to
specify how we should act in the world
and so you could divide the world into
the world as it is and the world as
perhaps it should be.
That gives you some direction and you
need that and we know this technically
right?
You need direction.
The reason for that is its direction
that produces the primary that produces
primary positive emotion.
And so if you need positive emotion to
move through life,
which you do cause you can't even move
without positive emotion.
And also positive emotion is a good
ball,
work against terror and pain.
If you need those things,
then you need direction.
You need a goal,
you need a value structure.
So that doesn't seem particularly
disputable to me.
You could still say,
well what value structure?
It's like,
okay,
fine.
That's a good question.
But I was,
you know,
I've thought a lot about that too.
So if we're going to adopt a value
structure,
there's a couple of rules that go along
with it.
And this is why the bloody
postmodernists so wrong as far as I can
tell is a,
it can't just be my value structure
because I'm stuck with you and we're
both stuck with all these other people.
And so if I'm going to lay out a value
structure,
which is a way of interpreting the
world,
let's say,
and there's an infinite number of
potential ways of interpreting the
world.
It's like the,
I find no problem except that I have to
interpret the world in a way that I can
use.
Well,
I'm dealing with you and the world.
Two of us are dealing with everyone else
and well,
all of you are dealing with everyone
else.
And so that,
that's the Piagetian game proposition.
If you want to be a popular kid on the
playground,
you better play games that other people
want to play.
That's a brilliant,
brilliant,
brilliant observation.
And I told you that Piaget was trying
to,
uh,
heal the rift between science and
religion.
And that's one of the things that he did
that he thought help do that as a
question is well,
where the moral judgments come from.
Well,
they partly come emerge as a consequence
of consensus and it's a bounded domain.
If we're gonna,
if we're gonna occupy the same space for
any length of time,
and those are two critical propositions,
thus same space and a long time,
then we have to figure out how to play
an iterative game that doesn't spiral
downward.
Hopefully that might even improve that.
We both don't object to because
otherwise it's not gonna work.
Right?
You'll walk away and play another game
or the game will will disintegrate
catastrophically.
So there's massive social constraint on
what constitutes an appropriate frame of
reference.
So,
so much for the relativist argument.
And then there's another issue that's
equally relevant and it's associated
with the idea of objective reality to
some degree.
But it's not exactly,
it's not,
that's not exactly correct because it's
not exactly objective reality.
Let's say that you and I decided to
occupy the same place for some
substantial amount of time and we
figured out how to solve the problem of
being together.
But you and I still have to figure out
how to solve the problem of being
together in a manner that doesn't make
the world object too much.
And it isn't just other people,
although that's a huge part of the
world.
You want them to not object.
You may not even want them to support
you,
that would even be better.
But you also have to deal with the,
you know,
the,
the tendency of matter to object
because,
so your mode of being in the world,
your interpretive framework as a
description of how you should act is
actually the laying out of a strategy
that will produce the ends that it
predicts,
which are the things that you want.
So this is the pragmatist perspective.
This was worked out by William James and
his people back in the late 18 hundreds
in New England.
The only genuine brand of American
philosophy and what the pragmatists said
is,
how do you decide if something's true?
The answer is,
well,
how the hell can you,
you don't know anything.
Well,
that's true.
But that isn't helpful because there
you're stuck with the problem of how to
be in the world.
Well,
so what you do is you lay out a motive
interpretation that has an end point and
then you run the mode of interpretation
embodied,
right?
Cause he acted it out.
And if it doesn't produce the outcome,
then it's not,
let's say,
true.
The claims within it aren't,
they're not true by the definition of
the game itself.
So you might say,
well,
you're a kid on a playground.
You want to play a game.
One of the implicit demands is that the
game is fun.
If it's not fun,
it's not worth playing.
So you play it for a while and then you
see,
well,
was that fun?
If the answer is yes,
then you keep playing the game.
You say,
well that game is,
it's good enough,
it's accurate enough,
it's true enough.
And so you lay out interpretations in
the world and they're subject to massive
constraints.
Other people have to go along with them
and cooperate with you because if they
don't,
then look the hell out.
Like it's a major,
serious,
nontrivial constraint.
And then the other thing is,
will social proof isn't good enough.
It also has to work in the world outside
of the social world.
You know?
So if you have an illness and you have
some hypothesis about how to construe
it,
you might say,
well,
is my understanding of the illness?
Correct?
Well,
it implies that I take these actions.
how do you know if it's correct while
you take the actions and if the illness
gets worse,
then by the definitions that are
implicit in the framework of reference
that you're using,
you've made an error.
And so there's no relativism in that.
You could still say,
well,
there's a lot of potential solutions to
any potential set of problems.
It's like,
yeah,
there's lots of different ways to play
chess on the,
on a single board,
right?
But that doesn't mean that any old
solution is as good as any other
solution.
It doesn't mean that at all.
So,
okay,
so then we're looking at things two
ways.
We're trying to figure out,
well,
how does the world present itself?
And then how is it that you should act
in it?
And so
while there's other,
there's other constraints on the
mechanisms of interpretation that you
place in the world.
So we could say,
well,
you're constrained in your
interpretations by the constraints that
other people place on you.
But there's internal constraints as
well.
We talked about those mostly from a
biological perspective because you could
also re regard yourself in some sense as
a loose internal society and that sort
of a psychoanalytic dictum,
right?
You're,
you're a collection of subpersonalities.
Or You could say you're a collection of
sub routines.
I don't care how you,
how you formulated,
but you're a unity,
but you're a,
you're a universe unity.
That brings together a plurality of
subcomponents.
And part of the constraints on how it is
that you lay out your interpretation of
the world is that you have to satisfy
those internal subsystems,
right?
So you're the ego,
but it's more like you're the captain of
a ship full of people who were rowing.
You got to keep the people rowing.
You're,
you're not,
you're not tyrant,
you're not omnipotent tyrant of your own
destiny.
You're constrained by the nature of your
own being.
And so you have to provide yourself with
food and you have to provide yourself
with shelter and you have to provide
yourself with water and all of these
things.
And those are demands that are laid on
you by the nature of your internal
processes.
And of course,
how they lay themselves out as demands
and what the appropriate solutions to
that is to those problems are,
is,
is debatable infinitely,
but you can see the constraints stack
up.
You have to satisfy your internal
constraints.
So they have to be brought into a unity
that seems to happen at least in part by
between the ages of two and something
like between the ages of birth and four
years old,
maybe even two years old.
You bring yourself together into
something that's sort of functioning as
a unity.
Then you have to turn that unity into a
unity that can function in the social
world and with increasing breadth and
that unity in the social world has to be
a unity that can function inside the
natural world.
It's something like that.
So it's you're stacking up these games
into a hierarchy of increasing
complexity.
And one of the questions that emerges
from that is,
well,
what should be at the top of the
hierarchy?
If it's a hierarchical structure,
it has to be a hierarchical structure
because some things have to be worth
doing more than others or you can't act,
which is another thing I really don't
like about the postmodernist ethos
because it claims that value structures
are there to eliminate,
to exclude in Oh press and never once
notices that.
Well Yeah,
fair enough.
But value structures are also there so
that you know which way to walk because
you can't figure out which way to walk
without saying that that direction is
preferable to that direction.
She stuck with the damn things and they
do exclude obviously category structures
exclude.
The question is if you're going to have
a value structure,
how is it that it should be can
constituted when we're already described
some of the constraints,
like if your value structure is
perfectly functioning,
except that you don't get enough to eat,
that turns out to actually to be a fatal
problem.
Right.
And it might be,
you can run into all sorts of fatal
problems.
You're too lonesome.
While it means you're,
let's say that your value structures too
narcissistic,
there's lots of reasons to be lonesome,
but that might be one of them.
Or you're too timid or something like
that.
Like you're going to be informed by your
own internal biological mechanisms when
the value structure that you're laying
out in the world is insufficient to keep
itself propagating across time.
And some of that's just you and some of
that's other people and some of that's
the natural world constraints Galore.
And so in the phase of all those
constraints,
it's absolutely unreasonable to say any
old solution goes.
It's try it,
generate a random solution,
run it as a simulation in the world and
see and see how many slings and arrows
come your way.
There'll be plenty.
And you might say,
well,
I don't care about slings and arrows.
It's like,
yeah,
no,
that's a claim you don't get to make.
So,
okay,
so you know,
you're,
you're being informed internally as to
the nature of your value structure.
You have to specify where you are.
You have to specify where you're going.
You have to integrate all your
underlying biological mechanisms into
that,
into that Schema.
It's something I think that's actually
kind of weak about the piaget and ideas.
Hey,
because piaget,
I,
I'm a great fan of Piaget,
but piaget tended to think that the
child came into the world with nothing
but a set of reflexes that's as
technical claim and that the bootstrap
off those reflexes and I think that's,
it underestimates the degree to which
the child comes into the world as an
already prepared unit.
And I mean he just thought of those
things.
It's so self evident that you don't need
to talk about them,
but that's actually not true.
You do need to talk about them.
We know for example,
that if you provide children with food
and shelter and an adequate food and
shelter,
but you don't interact with them
socially,
almost all of them die in the first
year.
Right?
It's not optional touch.
He's not optional for children.
Attention is not optional for children.
Play is not optional for children.
So it isn't just like,
well the child comes into the world with
a set of reflexes and can adapt to any
old environments like know the
environment has to be structured in a
certain way or the child will die.
And it's very interesting when it comes
to things like play and touch because
you wouldn't think of those as
fundamental necessities,
right?
But it turns out that they are,
if you deprive a child badly enough of
play and touch in the first three years
of their life,
even if they survive,
what comes out at the end of that is
often something that's like barely
recognizable as a functional human being
and cannot be repaired after that point.
And that that experiment was done with
Romanian orphans back in back in the
nineties so,
and it was,
it was an ugly situation to say the
least.
Okay,
so now you take these underlying
biological systems and maybe they
aggregate themselves into something that
vaguely looks like your temperament,
your,
your five temperamental dimensions.
So maybe if you're an extrovert,
you're dominated by the dopaminergic
system just like you are as if you're
high in openness.
And if you're,
if you're,
if you're high in neuroticism,
it's mostly that you're dominated by
anxiety systems and systems that mediate
emotional pain.
And if you're agreeable,
you're dominated by the function of the
underlying maternal slash care
affiliation systems.
But so you could say,
well,
you've got these loose,
you've got a multitude of fundamental
biological predispositions that manifest
themselves as implicit stories,
something like that.
And they organize themselves into the
primary temperaments and the primary
temperaments are,
are,
are biasing factors that determine in
part the nature of the interpretive
structure that you're going to lay out
in the world.
It's not entirely determined by your
temperament.
We know that personality is only
predicting,
you know,
something like let's say 10% of the
variance in most complex social outcomes
and,
and the other elements are well
temperamental as you might be.
You still have to get along with other
people in the world.
So you know,
you come in with these internal biases,
but they have still have to be modified
extensively by your social and your
natural surround.
Okay.
And then you develop your routines from
the bottom up as piaget pointed out in
sometimes from the top down because now
and then you can think yourself into a
radical transformation.
But mostly what you're doing is building
the micro units of your interpretive
scheme is and your behaviors and
aggregating them into higher order
structures that you can then tag with
higher order abstractions.
And we talked about that.
You can't tell a three year old to clean
up his room.
And the reason for that is he,
those are empty boxes as far as the
kid's concerned clean he's doing,
he might,
he might have room,
he might have that clean,
he doesn't have,
he might have pickup the teddy bear and
put it in that space,
right?
So that's one of these little micro
routines.
And maybe you say you put 20 of those
micro routines together and now you can
say clean up your room.
And basically what you're saying is
here's,
implement the 10 micro routines that
you've learned.
And so a well functioning personality
has all the micro routines in place.
That's actually something that you help
people with if you're a behavioral
therapist.
Because one of the things you assume if
you're a behavioral therapist is that
sometimes the reason people aren't doing
things is because they don't know how.
You know,
sometimes maybe the person is depressed
but potentially high functioning,
they got all the damn micro routines,
they're well socialized,
they're just dormant.
You got to get them awake again and
implementing them.
But sometimes you get someone in your,
in your practice say who's just been
neglected.
Like you cannot believe,
right?
The parents never paid any attention to
them or maybe just punish them every
time they did something good.
That's really fun.
And then,
you know,
they didn't make friends and so they're
really,
really
vague and,
and,
and poorly articulated.
And so then what you do is you work at
the bottom of the micro routines and get
them to practice building up all these
little attributes that they didn't build
up.
And you know,
one of the things you can think about in
terms of character development is so now
maybe understand something about your
own personality.
You might say,
well what could you do to improve your
personality?
And answer is develop some of the micro
routines on the other side of the
personality distribution.
So if you're disagreeable as hell,
maybe you could start learning how to do
nice things for people.
And that actually works by the way.
So if you take disagreeable people who
are depressed and you get them doing
nice things for other people,
their depression tends to lift.
But then by the same token,
if you're agreeable,
then you should practice doing some
things for yourself and being more tough
minded in your negotiations.
And so you can sort of place yourself on
the,
on the personality trait distribution,
you know,
you're extrovert.
It's like,
okay man,
learn to spend some time with yourself.
Right?
You're low in openness.
Well try reading a book that's outside
of your,
you know,
your,
your sphere of interest now in that if
you're conscientious,
well you should probably learn how to
relax.
Okay.
Usually and so forth.
So you can,
I think partly what you're doing as
you're developing your personality is
not moving the mean much,
the average where you know where you're
located,
but you're extending the standard
deviation so that you're a bigger bag of
tricks than you were before.
And I think you can practice that
consciously.
It's like you're hyper orderly.
It's well get a dog,
you know,
dogs,
they're messy,
horrible things,
you know,
it's just what you need if you're hyper
orderly because they're gonna leave hair
everywhere and force you to live with
it.
And so,
okay,
so and so this is sort of you,
right?
This is your personality.
It's this connect collection of routine
sub routines that you've turned into a
hierarchy.
And then there's something at the top of
it.
And that's,
that's a big question.
Like what the hell should be at the top
of the hierarchy?
Because that's the ultimate question of
unity and the,
and the,
the clinicians would say,
well,
it's the self actualized person,
or it's the self or something like that.
You know,
that's,
that's the eye,
that's the implicit and perhaps explicit
ideal that you're aiming for.
And you might say,
well is does such thing existed?
I would say,
well do you admire people?
Cause that's your answer,
right?
Do you despise people while you like
some people and you don't like others?
You respect some people you don't
respect others while you're acting out
the notion that there's at least an
implicit ideal,
you do the same thing when you go to
movies,
you know you,
you know who the hero is,
you know who the bad guy is,
you're acting out the proposition that
there's some sort of value hierarchy and
there's some sort of manifestation of it
that's coherent across time.
So you appear to believe that and you
know you are driven at least to some
degree by your own inner ideals.
And so you tend to answer the question,
is that real with an affirmative?
And if you don't,
there's catastrophic consequences.
Nicha and the existentialists were very
good at detailing.
That's like you let your value hierarchy
disintegrate.
Well then what?
Well part of it is nihilistic chaos.
Who that's not so much fun.
And then there's the alignment of
nihilistic chaos with the intrinsic
desire that someone will come along and
tell you what to do.
Right?
So what happens is if you let this
devolve,
you end up with nihilistic exit with
nihilistic chaos or the demand for,
for the tyrant to come forward.
And we've had that happen lots of times
and doesn't seem to have gotten that
will.
So,
all right,
well,
so what happens when you,
you lay out these little routines in the
world at different levels of analysis.
Well,
this is how your emotions function
broadly speaking.
You know,
you're aiming at something and that this
is an oversimplification,
which is why I want to show you this,
right?
When I show you this,
assume that it's made out of that,
right?
It's just a schematic oversimplification
because even if,
let's say that I'm trying to do
something as simple as walking towards
the door,
I mean that the action of walking
towards the door is predicated on the
existence of all the sub routines that
enabled to propel my body across time
and space.
And like there's that t.
Dot.
It took a lot of internal organization
to get that right.
It's a traumatized now.
And so you can treat it like it's
invisible.
But implicit in any one of these
structures is this entire structure.
And you actually see this in therapy
very frequently too.
So I was talking to a client the other
day,
it was so interesting.
This person said something,
he had been talking to his mother and
he's,
he just made a casual comment.
He said he was talking to his mother who
is in a state of grief for,
for good reasons that were independent
of,
of this particular person who said,
and I hate her.
And I thought,
oh,
that's interesting.
Like where did that come from?
And so I made a comment on that.
That's a Freudian slip,
right?
Because there was,
the conversation was flowing and then
this little emotion tagged utterance
came forward.
And whenever an emotion tagged utterance
of that sort comes forward,
you know,
it's associated with a whole rat's nest
of underlying pain and anxiety and,
and,
and what would you call it?
Disappointment and frustration that
hasn't been properly rectified.
So it's like a marker.
And yet you know this,
when you're talking to people,
they say something and you think,
oh wow.
Too much information.
That's one way of thinking about,
it's like,
just what are you up to?
And then if you have any sense,
you just forget that that even happened
and you continue.
But that's,
that's like the snout of a dragon peak
peeking out from a cave.
And you might say,
well,
it's just a snout man.
But it's not because dragon snouts tend
to be attached to the whole Damn Dragon.
And so this is also something to know
about relationships because when you're
in a relationship with someone,
they'll do that now and then they'll,
you know,
outer something and you think,
ah Ha.
I was like,
there's a bump in the road where we're
going to look underneath that at our
peril.
But if you do go down there and you look
at it,
then,
uh,
then the whole thing comes,
you can start to disentangle the,
the way above of,
of memories and experiences that are all
tangled together as a consequence of
their emotional identity.
Because I could say,
well,
everything that makes you anxious or
everything that makes you upset is the
same as every other thing that's ever
made you upset.
And so,
and then there's an even different sub
set of that,
which is all those things that have made
you upset that you've never dealt with.
They're all laying down there at the
bottom of your nasty little soul waiting
to pop themselves up in some,
in some random moderates,
right?
And so then you go in there at your
peril because if you're the person who
pokes around in that,
then you're going to get blasted with
all of that stuff.
It's going to come out like almost
uncontrollably then.
Then you can sort it out.
And so what you find is if you ask a
person a question like that and then you
let them free associate,
which is just talk about it,
they'll,
they'll do a wandering around like that
maze that I told you about.
They'll do a wandering around of that
entire territory.
And sometimes just having them wander
around in it can help them straighten it
out.
But you might find out that something
happened to them years ago that left
them with a terrible sense of guilt or
dismay or frustration.
And then when,
when they interact with their parents in
a certain way,
the parent knows exactly how to tap that
and then that all comes up and that's
what produces that,
that little,
that little utterance.
And so that's the material of the world
manifesting itself.
That's what matters manifesting itself.
And it almost always manifests itself as
an object.
Something that objects,
we're having a conversation,
it's going quite well.
No problem.
There's a bump in it.
There's an emotional disjunct right now.
We're no longer in the same place at the
same time.
We're no longer playing the same game.
So then I might say,
okay,
well let's open that up and see what's
behind it.
While in the question is what's behind
the game you're playing an answer to
that is all the world that you're
ignoring always.
So when,
so when imagine that,
think about it this way.
You're trying to do well in a class and
you get a bad grade.
Okay,
so you're in this little frame.
You want to get a good grade that isn't
happening.
He got a bad grade.
Okay,
what is it that's manifesting itself as
the bad grade?
While you could say,
well,
it's a c minus on a piece of paper.
It's like,
well,
that's,
you know,
really know that that's the objective
manifestation.
You got a piece of paper with a c minus
the value free proposition is that
you've been delivered a piece of paper
with a curve on it and a little,
you know,
negative side.
Well,
you think,
well,
that's what that is.
Well,
you know,
it's as dopey as thinking,
well,
here you got your failing grade.
You go into the lab and you like weigh
it on a scale.
Then you burn it and see what it was
made of.
It's like,
well,
why did I get so upset about that?
It's just paper.
It's like,
no,
that's not just paper.
It's an entity that exists in a web of
connections.
The fact that it signified by paper is
almost completely irrelevant.
What is it?
The answer is you don't know.
And that's why when you pick it up,
you get this paralyzed,
sinking feeling because your limbic
system is a lot smarter than your
perceptual systems.
And your perceptual systems say,
well,
that's a piece of paper,
and your limbic system says,
Nah,
for sure dragon.
Right?
Right.
And so then you're sweating and then
maybe you put it away and you go play
video games because you know better the
hypothetical dragon,
then the real dragon.
And so instead you pull out the piece of
paper maybe and you think,
okay,
why did I get this c minus?
Well,
that's a hell of a question,
isn't it?
It's like,
maybe you're stupid.
Well,
that could be,
or at least stupid compared to who you
think you are.
Like that's,
that's the real horror that's lurking
there rights.
Like,
oh,
I thought it was kind of smart.
That's a,
that's a proposition of the highest
order.
I thought I was kind of smart.
It's like,
yeah,
well what about this c minus?
It's like,
well,
that God damn professor,
right?
That's the first thing.
I've been attacked by a predator.
That's the first response.
Right?
So it's,
it's a nonsensical message.
It's just delivered by someone evil and
predatory.
Well that's,
you know,
possible.
But I wouldn't go there.
I wouldn't go there first necessarily.
So,
but then while then say you don't go
there.
Okay,
well,
so what is this exactly?
Do you not know what you thought you
knew or are you not who you think you
are?
Do you not work hard enough?
Are Your values not organized properly?
Do you misuse your time?
Are you in the wrong field?
Is the way you're construing Your Life
Completely Inappropriate?
Are you acting out what your parents
wanted you to do it and you're pissed
off about it.
So you're only running at 40% to spite
them despite the fact that they're
paying $25,000 a year for your
education.
Cause that's a fun game.
Yeah,
I'll go do what you want me to do,
but I'll fail at.
But not completely because then that
would wouldn't cost you very much.
I'll just fail a little bit so that you
have to spend all that money forcing me
to do what I don't want to do,
but you'll never get to escape from it.
And then every time we interact,
I'll stab you in various ways that you
don't quite understand,
just to show you how irritated I am that
I happen to be acting out the destiny
that you've put forward for me.
So maybe that's part of the Dragon,
right?
And then that pulls in the whole parent
thing and you know it's,
these are bottomless pits.
Often when you,
when you're in the world and something
objects to you,
something that matters,
objects to you then in the entire
unrealized world is in that thing that
objects,
it's all tangled up inside it.
That's why it's the great dragon of
chaos.
It's everything that's outside of your
conceptual structure.
And what is that?
It's everything that lurks outside of
your,
of your walled city.
And it's manifested itself like the
snake in the garden.
And the easiest thing to do is say,
I'm not having anything to do with that.
But the problem with that is,
well,
you get your c minus and you don't do
anything about it.
Maybe you're a little bitter and more
resentful in your study.
Habits get a little worse.
So the next time you get like a d plus
and then you collect a bunch of f's and
then you stopped going to school,
then you stop showering,
right?
Then you end up jumping off the bridge.
And so that's uh,
that's,
that's how the dragon eats you when you
don't pay attention to it.
And so it's no bloody wonder that people
avoid,
you know,
it's really no wonder that they avoid
because error messages contain within
them the implicit world.
Now the upside of that is while they
contain within them the implicit world
and the world isn't all negative,
and so maybe you get your c minus and
that's actually the best gift you ever
got because somebody finally took you
and went whack,
you know,
clue in.
And so you take that apart and you
think,
oh,
I don't know how to write.
I don't know how to think.
I've never read anything in my life.
My study habits are a Bismal,
you know,
like maybe I'm working at 2% efficiency,
which,
which is probably,
I would suspect that,
you know,
some of you aren't doing that,
but I bet you that I bet there's 30 30
to 50% of the people in the room are
working at 2% efficiency.
It's like you got it.
That's,
so to find that out is so optimistic.
I mean,
if you're barely hanging in there,
but you're only working out 2% you might
imagine what you could have as a life if
you work at at like 50% so,
so the,
the c minus can be the best gift you
ever had.
And that's the gold that the dragon
hordes,
right?
That's exactly what that means.
And so,
well,
so you're moving from point a to point
b.
In your little circumscribed world,
you've made everything invisible.
And as long as that works,
then your theory is good enough.
It's accurate enough.
It's true enough,
you're in your little paradise.
But if something comes up and objects,
well that's where your character is
tested fundamentally.
That's the character test.
It's like,
what do you do with messages of error?
And that's a tricky issue.
Okay,
so here's a solution to that.
Here's what not to do.
I am a bad person.
I got to see mice.
I'm a bad person.
I might as well just go jump off the
bridge.
It's like,
no,
that's not good.
Because what that means is that every
time,
every time you try to learn something,
you're going to make a mistake because
what you know,
so you're gonna make mistakes.
And if the rule is every time you make a
mistake,
you're going to go jump off the bridge,
then that's not a useful problem solving
strategy.
And so when you make a mistake,
you don't get to beat yourself to death
with a club.
It's a bad strategy.
And you'll have your internal tyrant in
there who's perfectly happy about doing
that.
That's the,
you know,
overactive superego that Freud talked
about.
Maybe it came to you via a parent who
was too authoritarian or a grandparent
or,
or maybe it's just you cause you're
disagreeable in neurotic and so you'll
take yours or had hyper conscientious,
you'll take yourself apart.
Well starting the,
so you've got a problem,
something has objected to you,
then the question is,
well,
what does that mean?
Well,
maybe you're not looking at the world,
right?
Maybe your goals are wrong,
maybe you're not acting properly.
So,
okay,
so the question that arises when an
obstacle emerges is,
which part of this structure needs
attention?
And the first answer can't be all of it,
which is why when you're arguing with
someone in an intimate relationship and
you're angry at them and you want to
win,
which is a big mistake,
you want to,
when you say,
well you're,
this is what you're like,
here's another 10 examples of how you've
done that in the past.
And I can new rate more of them if you'd
like.
And so it doesn't,
that's actually what you like.
And I tried fixing it didn't work.
And so it looks like you're going to be
like that up into the future and you're
basically saying to them,
well,
you're a bad person and the only thing
they can do is either collapse or punch
you and punching you is actually better
than collapsing.
But you don't.
You know what I mean?
It's such a counterproductive way of
arguing.
You don't leave the person any out.
And so maybe while they're civilized so
it doesn't get physical,
well maybe that's good and maybe it
isn't,
but then they end up either really not
happy with you in a way that they will
manifest the first possible opportunity
they get.
Or they have to go off in the corner and
cringe.
It's like,
great,
you won.
It's now your partners either hates you
or is cringing.
It's great.
That's a real good victory band cry rack
up about a hundred victories like that,
and you'll be in divorce court and
spending $250,000 while being miserable
about it.
Yeah.
So anyway,
so something objects to you and you
think,
okay,
well I need to,
I need to take myself apart,
right,
because there's a piece that's broken
somewhere and then you might think,
well,
let's,
let's assume it's a little pace to begin
with.
That's the right mechanism.
It's like,
okay,
you got a c minus
that doesn't prove that you're stupid
and now it implies that you might be
stupid,
but it doesn't.
Right.
Really it does.
And that's why you don't want to look at
it.
Maybe it applies that you're lazier,
implies that you're ignorant or like it
implies all sorts of terrible.
Might imply that you're a bad person
even,
but you don't want to leap to that.
And that's sort of the proclamation of
innocence before guilt.
Assume that you're the least amount of
reprehensible and ignorant possible.
And so then you look at the micro
routines,
it's okay,
well I got a c minus in this course,
maybe I should study for that course,
15 minutes more a day for the next three
months.
And then you ask yourself,
do you think you could do that?
No,
I'm too useless.
Okay,
how about 15 minutes every second day?
You think you could do that?
You put it in your schedule like 15
minutes every second day in the morning
and that's while you think,
well,
what's wrong with me?
Well,
I'm not very good at managing my study
schedule.
That's not quite down here at the
behavioral level,
but it's pretty close because what you,
you can take an action,
you can open up your schedule and you
can say,
Oh mark,
15 minutes away aside,
then you can practice doing that.
It's pretty low level in the hierarchy
means while you're still not a horrible
person,
you just got to polish up your work
ethic and so what you want to do is you
want to,
it's like,
it's like the L.
Dot.
Adage.
You got to stand up for yourself,
but you don't want to make unnecessary
enemies.
Hots are really good thing to know.
It's like shut the hell up most of the
time,
but now and then you don't shut up
because it's time to say something you
don't.
You don't want to make unnecessary
enemies though.
Well,
you don't want to take yourself apart
any more than is absolutely necessary.
Start little and you do that with people
around you to like if you have a child,
you know and the child does something
that isn't right,
then you think,
okay,
minimal necessary intervention.
What can we do to decrease the
probability that that's going to occur
in the future?
So,
and that's it.
So that's a good thing to know with
children.
And it's also a good thing to know with
your partners.
You have having an argument with them.
It's like,
okay,
what the hell do you want?
What's the minimum thing you can request
from them that would satisfy you and the
evil part of your soul is going to be,
I want them cringing in the corner.
It's like,
yeah,
get that.
Get that stuff under control,
man.
See if you can figure out what the
person could offer you that would be
minimal that you would accept.
And then tell them that.
It's like,
here's the words I would like you to say
in the apology.
I would like you to formulate,
assuming that you think you did
something wrong when you have to argue
about that because maybe you didn't.
But if you did,
I want to specify precisely and narrowly
and I want to give you an escape route.
And you know you might only be able to
do it badly because you're still mad.
So you apologize.
Halfheartedly.
It's like you get a pat on the head for
that good.
Next time it'll be 51% not
halfheartedly.
Right?
So it's careful training,
it's careful training of yourself and
other people with,
with the goal in mind,
but also with the least amount of
harshness possible.
And then the other thing to do as well,
and this is also true for you,
and this is something I learned from
studying the behaviorist is like watch
the people around you like a hawk.
Whenever they do something that you
think is good,
you tell them,
that's wisdom,
man.
You'll get so far with that.
You cannot bloody well believe it
because most people,
you know,
they're afraid of any number of things.
But one of the things they're really
afraid of is that now and then they'll
creep out of their cynical shell and try
to do something good.
You know,
it's like there,
it's like they're popping out this thing
that's unbelievably vulnerable.
Then try to do something good and creep
right back into their persona and
they'll look around,
see if anyone noticed and sometimes
they'll get punished for it.
And then,
well then they won't do it again.
So don't do that.
But then now and then you think,
hey,
I saw you do this.
It was actually,
that was actually pretty good.
And they think,
Oh wow,
somebody noticed,
you know,
was like wow.
And then they'll think,
yeah,
I could,
maybe I could do that again.
And if you want to live with someone for
a long period of time,
I would say every time they do something
that you would like them to do more of.
Number one,
notice number two,
tell them right.
Because I know you don't want to because
you really want to dominate them and you
don't want them thriving because then
they'd be,
they'd be competition to you and you
wouldn't be able to go complain to your
mother about what a miserable partner
you have.
And you know how delightful that is.
So you'd have to forego all that
pleasure if you actually helped your
person developed.
So you've got to get over all that.
It's really annoying.
So you know,
you've got this person,
peg does.
Yeah,
you're stuck with them.
And you know,
maybe it's the best you can do,
but you've got one eye open and then
every time they do something good you
don't want to notice.
Because if that elevated them a little
bit,
you wouldn't be able to feel so
resentful and miserable and keep your
eye open for the next possible affair.
And that is what people are like.
That is what people are like.
And that's what you're like too.
That's what people are like.
So you've got to decide if that's what
you want or you want to help the person
that you're with grow,
you know that's dangerous because they
might know shine you well good.
Then you'll have someone to compare
yourself to.
That'd be a good deal.
It's really rough with kids,
you know,
because parents will stop their children
from succeeding beyond them.
They get jealous and then they'll put
them down and then they have kids that
do not like them and they'll pay for it.
So one of the things that I've figured
out over the last years is this is a
good proposition.
So you know,
it's pretty self evident that life is,
has got its rat's nest of miseries and
that's for sure.
Maybe you could even make a categorical
statement that life is mostly a rat's
nest of misery.
You know?
And you could make a pretty powerful
argument for that.
But then there's a counter question,
which is,
well,
what if you tried not to make it any
more miserable than it had to be?
Right?
Then what?
Then what would it be like?
And my suspicions are,
is that a lot of that misery,
I would suspect that most of that misery
would go away because it's the
unnecessary misery that really brings
you down.
You know?
It's like,
well,
someone has cancer.
It's like,
that sucks.
But it's not like,
it's not like you can say,
if only we had done this differently
than that wouldn't have happened.
But when someone's out,
like torturing you in a malevolent way,
or maybe you're doing the same,
you can always ask yourself,
was it really,
is this really necessary?
Is this just like a useless add on to
the miseries of life?
That's what disheartens people.
And so even in your own life,
if,
if you,
if you aren't suffering from selfimposed
misery and you're only suffering from an
escapable misery,
maybe you could handle that and you know
who you could,
you could survive.
You could bear it.
And even maybe without becoming
irredeemably corrupt.
And so the goal would be,
well,
yeah,
life is a rat's nest of miseries.
And maybe it has no ultimate meaning.
We could say that if we're feeling
particularly pessimistic,
but it still leaves one question open,
which is,
if you didn't do everything you could to
make it worse,
how good could you make it be?
And the least answer is,
well,
it,
it could be tragedy,
but maybe not hell.
And I think that's right.
I really believe that that's,
that's the most pessimistic proper
statement.
The worst case outcome in the worst of
all possible worlds is that your life
could be tragic,
but not hell.
And that's blood better than hell,
right?
It's,
it's,
and you think I could give you an
example of the difference.
You're at your mother's death bed.
Well,
that's tragedy.
Here's another scenario.
You're out of your mother's death bed
and all you,
you and all your idiot siblings are
arguing.
Well that's the difference between
tragedy and hell and you might be able
to tolerate the first circumstance and
maybe it would even bring you closer
together with your family members.
The second one,
no one can bear that you walk away from
a situation like that,
sick of yourself and sick of everything
else too.
And you know,
it's often the case that tragic
circumstances bring out the dragons
because the stress is high and all those
things that people haven't dealt with,
they don't have the energy to repress
and,
and all the bitterness comes pouring
forward.
It's like seriously man,
it is.
So that's actually a good,
it's a rough lesson,
but it's a good hallmark for figuring
out whether or not you're,
you've got yourself adjusted properly
and in relationship to your siblings.
It's like if you are all gathered around
the bed,
if someone close who was dying,
could you manage it?
If the answer is no,
it's like,
well,
put your life together because it's
going to happen and you should be the
person who's there that can do it and do
it properly.
And then maybe you'd find that it isn't
the sort of thing that will undermine
your faith in life itself.
And I've seen,
I've seen both of those situations,
you know,
ugly,
ugly situations,
murderously ugly situations.
And then they're opposite where people
have had terrible things happen and to
happen to them as a family and you know,
they pulled together and
they rebuild their damn ship and they
sail away.
And so that seems to me to be a lot
better.
Okay.
That makes you noah when the flood
comes.
Right?
Well,
okay,
so the same thing.
Yes.
The question emerges,
well,
who are you?
Well,
you could say
you're this plan.
Yeah.
That's what people usually,
that's how people usually identify.
Maybe they have no plan at all and
they're just in chaos.
Right?
That's like being in the belly of the
beast.
They're nihilistic and chaos.
They have no plan.
They're just chaos itself.
And that's a very dreadful situation for
people to be in.
Or maybe they conjured together a plan.
That's their identity.
It's kind of fragile and they're holding
onto that with,
with everything they've got,
it's their little sticker would that
they're floating in the ocean clinging
to,
you know,
and so they're identifying really hard
with that plan.
That's what happens when you're an idiot
log is that you're identifying really
hard with that plan.
The problem is something comes up to
confront it.
Well,
how do you act?
you can't let go with a plan cause you
drown.
Okay?
Then you cling to it rigidly.
Well,
that's no good because then you can't
learn anything.
Then if that's you,
you're a totalitarian,
you're not going to learn anything.
You're going to end up in something
that's close enough to hell so that you
won't know the difference and you might
drag everyone along with you.
And that's happened plenty of times,
right?
It's the whole story of the 20th
century.
It happened over and over and over,
and it happens in people's states.
It's to happens in their business
organizations.
It happens in their cities.
It happens in their provinces,
it happens in their states,
and it happens in their psyches all at
the same time.
You can't blame the manifestation of
that sort of thing on any of those one
levels.
It happens when a society goes down that
way,
it goes down everywhere at the same
time.
It's not the totalitarians at the top
and all the happy people striving to be
free at the bottom.
It's not that at all.
It's totalitarianism at every single
level of the hierarchy,
including the psychological.
And so you don't want to be the thing.
You don't want to be in chaos,
that's for sure.
But you don't want to be the thing that
clings so desperately to the raft that
you can't let go when someone comes to
rescue you.
Right?
You don't want to be that.
So then you think,
well,
exactly what are you?
You're not the chaos.
You're not the plan.
Maybe you're the thing that confronts
the obstacle.
Okay.
And I would say that's the categorical
lesson of
okay.
Of psychology in so far as it has to do
with personal transformation,
because that's what you always teach
people in psychotherapy.
I don't care what sort of
psychotherapist you are,
you're always teaching them the same
thing.
You're the thing that you're not,
you're not the plan.
You're the thing that can confront the
obstacle to the plant.
And then when you know even further that
the obstacle is not only an obstacle but
opportunity itself,
well then your whole view,
the world can change because you might
think,
well,
I've got this plan.
Something came up to object to it.
It's like it's possible that the thing
that's objecting has something to teach
you that will take you to the place
where you develop an even better plat
and it's a nice framework to use.
It's like,
are you so sure that this is a problem?
Is that the only way that you can look
at it?
Or is it an opportunity?
I mean,
I'm not trying to be,
you know,
naively optimistic.
There are some things that's pretty hard
to extract gold from some dragons and
maybe the death of a family member is a
good example of that.
But in even in a situation like that,
I can tell you that it's an opportunity
for,
it's an opportunity for maturation,
that's for sure.
And the thing is,
you might say,
well,
it's pretty miserable to go to be
digging for gold when someone's falling
into the grave.
Well,
if they really love you,
first of all,
that's what they'll want you to do.
And second,
you're going to make their death a lot
more palatable experience for them.
If you're someone who can be in the room
and be helpful instead of being,
you know,
quivering in the corner and feeling that
the entire world is collapsing in on
you,
I mean,
that's another,
you want to be the useful person at the
funeral.
How's that for a goal?
That's a good goal,
man.
You know that you've got yourself
together in a situation like that
because you're going to be at them and
maybe you want to be the person on whose
shoulder people cry.
That'd be a good goal.
And it's Kinda,
you know,
I don't like being naively optimistic.
So when I tell you to get your life
together,
I'm not going to say roses and sunshine.
It's like that's,
that's,
that's Pablum for fools.
But it really is something to be the
reliable person at a funeral.
Right.
And you can aim it that you can do that.
You gotta be tough to do that because it
also means that you can sustain a major
loss without collapsing and that you've
got to be a monster to do that.
Right.
Because you might think,
and I've had clients like this,
well,
I love my child.
I love my mother so much that I couldn't
survive if anything happened to them.
It's like you have some serious thinking
to do about that.
It's like you really want to curse
someone with that kind of love.
Do you,
I couldn't live without you.
It's like my God,
get away from me.
Really.
It's terrible.
That's the depaul mother,
right?
That's like,
I'll forgive you no matter what you do.
It's like really no matter what I do a,
you are not my friend.
That's for sure.
Not at all.
It's a horrible thing to do to someone
that's,
that's the witch in Hansel and Gretel
story,
all gingerbread and outside to the last
kid inside.
You feed them candy and make them fat
and eat them.
Right.
That's Hansel and Gretel.
That's the oedipal mother.
That's one of Freud's major discoveries
if gets a major discovery.
It's like the devouring force of love.
You want the person to be able to stand
on their own and the price you pay for
that is that you stand on your own.
It's like good to have you around.
Glad you're here.
But if,
if,
if tragedies when and if and when
tragedy strikes either
of us,
I hope that one of us is standing when
it blows past and,
and that there's a harshness about that.
It's unbelievably cruel cause you know,
you say,
well if my mother died I could live
well,
what kind of monster are you exactly.
You need the death of your mother
doesn't do you in.
Well,
it turns out that being a monster is the
right thing.
So,
and that's a rough thing to learn,
but it's necessary to learn,
you know,
cause it also makes you,
at some point,
for example,
as you get older,
by the time you were in your mid
twenties something like that,
you should start having a relationship
with your parents.
That's approximately one of peers.
And you can tell if you have that.
So here's a little trick you can use.
So you have parents,
obviously they have friends,
you probably care what your parents
think.
I would imagine,
do you care what their friends think of
you?
And answer to that is,
well,
not nearly as much.
And so then I would say,
well why do you care what your parents
think of you?
Then there are the same people.
Do you know what I mean?
It's just luck of the draw that your
parents or someone else's kids,
friends,
they don't think the same way about them
that you do.
That's where you see that you have a
projection,
right?
If by the time you're 30 if what your
parents think of you matters more than
what,
say a random set of their friends.
Think of you,
then you've still got your parents
confused with with God.
That's one way of looking at it.
You've still got them confused with an
archetype and you're still a child and
you might think,
well,
it's pretty damn rude not to think about
what your parents think of you anymore,
not to care.
It's like,
yeah,
it's kind of rude,
but maybe you'll be useful for them when
they get old and that's a much better
form of caring.
It's like you're going to be independent
enough and strong enough and and
detached enough so that when the top,
when the,
when the power dynamic shifts,
which it will,
that you'll be the person that can carry
things forward while you can't do a
better thing for them than that,
right?
That's the best of all possible outcomes
for your parents.
Well,
you can think about the world this way.
You can think about it as you're orderly
little plan that's a place and you can
think about it as the place that things
that disrupt your plan comes from.
That's another place.
This is a bigger place than this because
there's an endless number of things that
can disrupt your plan and only a tiny
number of them that can,
you know,
that will help you work it out.
So part of the question then too is like
are you the friend of your plan or are
you the friend of the thing that
disrupts your plan?
And I would say you should work to
become the friend of the thing that
disrupts your plan because there's a lot
of that.
And then if you become the friend of the
thing that disrupts your plan,
then you be,
you start to develop strengths in
proportion to the,
to the disruptive force.
And that's really what you want.
You want to be able to implement your
plan obviously,
but you want to be able to take on the
consequences of error and learn from it
then.
Then you win
constantly because even if something
goes sideways,
you think there's something to be
derived from this.
That's wisdom fundamentally so and so.
Those are the eternal domains,
right?
There's the domain of order that's a
snake by the way,
and that's a domain of chaos and that's
the world.
And maybe you're in the order and maybe
you're in the chaos,
but those can flip on you and maybe you
shouldn't be in either of those places.
Maybe you should be right in the middle
and that's where you should be.
As far as I can tell,
and I think this is,
this is another escape from postmodern
nihilism,
let's say that's actually a real place.
It's not metaphysical or maybe it is,
but it's metaphysical.
If metaphysics is more real than
physics,
and you can tell when you're at that
place because that's a maximally
meaningful place and you drift in and
out of it all the time in your life,
and when things are really bad for you,
you're not there hardly at all,
right?
Because everything's overwhelming.
Your or things have become sterile.
But if you watch your life even over a
week or two,
you'll see that now and then you're
there.
Thank you.
Stand up straighter,
right?
Cause you're in the right place at the
right time and you think,
Aha,
I've got the forces of chaos and order
properly balanced.
It's unstable and it'll fall apart on
you.
But you know,
you can practice bringing things
together continually and then you can
end up so that you're there more often
than not.
And then that's,
that's a metta place.
It's not a place,
it's a metta place and it's a place that
you can be in all places and,
and it's not an illusion of any sort.
It's the deepest reality.
Your nervous system is always orienting
yourself.
Your is always orienting you to that
place always.
And,
and that's because it's a real place.
That's another way of thinking about it.
Well that's the normal world
with,
that's the garden with the snake in it.
And that's chaos.
That's the chaos that arises when your
plans collapse.
Right?
That's the world and the underworld.
And so the underworld is always there
and it's lurking beneath everything.
It's like the figure of the shark and
the jaws poster right there.
You are swinging at the top and there's
that terrible thing underneath that can
come up and pull you down.
That's the world.
So you need to be able to operate here
and you need to be able to operate here.
And when you operate here,
well that's when you rescue your father
from the belly of the whale.
That's when you go down.
You see when you're down in chaos and
you don't know what the hell is going
on.
You have to rediscover the values that
Orient.
People have oriented people forever.
That's what you have to discover.
So for example,
when I'm dealing with people who have
posttraumatic stress disorder and
they've usually encountered someone
malevolent,
they have to relearn the description of
good and evil because if they don't,
they'd have no framework.
They're lost.
They think,
well,
there's a malevolence afoot in the
world,
and I'm a naive,
I'm a naive,
I'm a prey animal,
a naive prey animal for the malevolence
of the world.
It's like,
well,
good luck functioning under that set of
assumptions,
man.
You just do not recover from that.
You stay at home in your borough.
That's what you do.
Well,
you have to,
you go down into that,
you think,
okay,
well malevolence is afoot.
I better be the sort of person that can
understand it and deal with it.
And that's another reason why you have
to transform yourself into a monster.
That's the young Ian Incorporation of
the shadow.
It's no bloody joke because the only
thing that a monster won't mess with is
another monster.
And you might say,
well,
I don't want to transfer myself into a
monster.
It's like you don't have a choice.
You can either be a pathetic monster or
you can be a monster with some power.
Those are your options.
There's no non monster alternative,
weak or strong.
And I don't mean strong like dominating
tyrant strength.
That isn't what I mean at all.
I mean strength like functioning at a
funeral strength and that's a kind of
monstrosity.
And when you're down in chaos,
that's what you have to rediscover.
Well that's partly what that means.
You're lucky if you come back out.
You remember I told you the story of
Jonah at the beginning of the course.
So like he had something to do and was
refusing to do it,
and so God pulled him down to the depths
of being and threatened him with death,
but worse,
not just death.
Hell really?
Well,
he decided it was better to come popping
up back into the light and go do what he
was supposed to do.
Well,
there's a reason that that like that's
the oldest story of mankind.
Do you as far back as you go into the
archives of history,
you find this story right?
And it's because,
well,
it's because not only is it because it's
true,
it's because it's true and everyone
knows it's true.
Even though they don't know that.
They know that this is the story too.
It's the same thing.
There's always a city.
It's always enclosed,
right?
There's always people who inhabit it.
There's always someone who's willing to
notice that the dragon hasn't gone away,
is skulls are still around.
There's someone who's willing to come
out of the fortress and,
and take that on.
Right.
And to prefer perform the job of
rescuing.
That's an eternal story.
Are you the city?
Are You the Dragon?
Are you the thing that
okay,
engages voluntarily in combat with what
lies outside your range of safety?
Cause that's what that image represents.
It's that is the monster amalgam,
symbolic amalgam of all that which lies
outside your realm of safety.
You want to be safe.
Forget that,
right?
That is,
that's not,
that's not in the cards.
You're not going to be safe while then
you have to be medisafe.
And that's way better because then
you're not safe.
But you know how to cope with danger
while fine,
that solves the problem.
And maybe it's even a better solution
because if you're safe then you just
have to stay in your burrow.
But if you can confront danger,
then you could go wherever you want and
you can have an adventure.
And maybe that's what you need to do is
to go out and have an adventure.
So you don't even want safety.
Cause how exciting is that?
Not Dostoyevsky said very clearly would
say we made you perfectly safe.
All that you had to do was eat cakes and
worry yourself with the continuation of
the species.
What would you do?
You'd smash it all down as soon as you
possibly could,
just so you had something interesting
and challenging to do.
So you don't want safety.
You want to be able to cope with danger.
That's a whole different thing.
And I'm like,
this isn't,
again,
metaphysical that did clinical data on
this as clear.
When you treat someone for an anxiety
disorder,
like agora phobia,
you do not get rid of their anxiety.
You make them braver.
That's way better.
There's no going back.
Like once you're agoraphobic,
you're heart's not doing the,
you know,
it's,
it's missing beats now in that,
and it's like death.
Like the crocodile,
it's got the clock and it's in his
stomach.
It death is after you.
There's no,
there's no going back to naive it.
You don't get to be safe ever again.
Well,
so what happens?
You get to be stronger.
Well,
Hey,
it turns out that's a better bargain
anyways.
Okay.
Lynn Isbell,
an evolutionary arms race between early
snakes and mammals triggered the
development of improved vision and large
brain in primates.
A radical new theory suggests the idea
proposed by Lynne Isbell,
an anthropologist at the University of
California suggest that snakes and
primates share along an intimate
history.
One that forced both groups to evolve
new strategies as each attempted to gain
the upper hand.
Now it's Hercules',
right?
Well,
that's infinity.
That symbol,
and this is the snake.
You cut off one head and seven more
grow.
It's like the,
it's an infinite snake.
You're never going to run out of snakes.
Those are the things that object to your
plants.
Well,
you can't get rid of the snake,
so what do you do?
You learn how to handle them,
right?
That's it.
That's,
that's the answer is you learn how to
become a handler of snakes,
both physical and metaphysical.
See,
you see the little halo around it.
I think that Saint George might be Saint
Michael,
but I think it's St George.
Why has he got a halo?
Well,
that's the sun,
or what does that mean?
It's gold to gold is pure.
It's the pure gold sun.
It's associated with consciousness.
It's the pure gold sun of consciousness
that can confront the terrible thing
that paralyzes.
Yeah,
and that's the same thing.
That's death,
right?
The clock in the stomach of the
crocodile,
it's already got a taste of captain
hook.
Captain Hook's no St George.
That's why Peter Pan doesn't want to
grow up.
I'd always sees is Captain Hook.
I don't want to be Captain Hook.
He doesn't see this.
So he stays at home and plays video
games with the rest of the lost boys.
Look,
I've got nothing against video games,
by the way.
I mean everything in moderation,
right?
And I mean they demand skill.
Well,
so what's this?
Do you know?
There you are and you go down into chaos
and then you come back up.
And so you might say,
well,
am I this or am I the chaos or am I the
new new solution?
And answer is you're not this or you
shouldn't be because that's your old
dead self,
right?
That's the thing that needs to burn
away.
You're not chaos itself,
but you're also not the new regenerated
order.
You're the thing that can make the
journey and more than that,
you're the thing that decides to make
the journey voluntarily and then more
than that,
you're the thing that decides to make
the journey voluntarily for as long as
it takes.
And that's where you derive your
strength.
It's like there's no getting rid of
chaos.
It's eternal.
There's no getting rid of order.
Those are both traps.
You mediate between them and that's
where your strength lies and that's not
only strength for you,
it's strength for you,
it's strength for the people around you.
It's strength for the community as
strength for everything.
It's the thing that makes everything
order itself properly and thrive.
You have to ask yourself,
and this is the thing you ask yourself,
this is the existential question.
Do you want things to be ordered
properly and thrive?
Because if the answer to that is yes,
you have to give up your hatred of
being,
you have to give up your resentment,
you have to give up your margin demond
your victimization and all of that
because to the degree that you carry
that forward,
it will corrupt you and you will not
want the best cause to be.
If two want the best,
you have to be without rage,
hatred and Rand Corp and,
and resentment because in,
Oh,
if I resent you for your enigma
adequacies or even for your,
for your accomplishments,
I'm not going to have a conversation
with you where I'm aiming for the best.
I'm going to have all sorts of
motivations.
I'm going to take you down somehow.
You know,
especially if you're successful.
That's the Cain and Abel Story.
It's like,
I bet I want to be who you are,
but I can't be.
So I'll just cut you off at the knees
and that'll do just fine and then I can
get my revenge on you and I can get my
revenge on being.
And you know,
the fact that it helps turn everything
into hell.
Well,
maybe that's just an additional benefit
that's right.
Represented all sorts of different ways.
The masculine and the Feminine Moon.
And that's horace in gold,
right?
Horus is all speech and eyes,
and that's,
oh,
cyrus,
that God of tradition and Isis,
the queen of the underworld.
And you see the same thing here,
suffering individual that transcends it
by accepting it nested inside of society
and the patriarchal structure nested
inside the natural world and the
feminine.
It's the same idea there.
That's Buddha emerging from the lotus
flower.
The lotus flower,
its roots go down into the merch at the,
at the bottom of the,
of the,
of the pond.
So it emerges out of the darkness and
manifest itself.
And then it climbs upwards towards the
light.
And then the lotus floats on the surface
of the water in bloom's open.
And inside that the Buddha sits golden
buddha sits in the light.
It's,
it's the flowering of being.
And that's,
that's a Mandela from the union
perspective.
It's the Mendell opens up and it reveals
this motive.
Perfect big.
Uh,
it's what the Buddha means.
And he found enlightenment underneath
the tree because that's the human
environment there is to find
enlightenment underneath the tree.
He's got the sun on his head too,
and he's gold for the same reason.
Gold is pure.
You see the same thing in Hinduism,
so that's the Yoni Feminine Symbol case.
You were wondering masculine symbol.
That's the union of the two,
right?
That's the union of chaos and order with
the snake lurking in the background and
it's golden because it's the union of
those two things that produces the power
of the snake.
That's something that you might think
about.
You could think about those as two
halves of the DNA molecule.
They,
that is what they are.
Although I can't tell you how I know
that,
but it's the same idea.
It's the same idea here.
So this,
what happens here is that you see,
this is a very remarkable pictures.
So this is eve.
Eve is handing out skulls to mankind,
right?
It's self consciousness and the
discovery of death.
This is Mary as the church on this side,
and she's handing out these things that
are the hosts.
It's,
those are pieces of Christ's body and
see,
so he's put up there on this tree,
the same as the skull as an antidote.
The antidote is something that you
incorporate and the thing you
incorporate is the voluntary acceptance
of suffering as the cure for death.
That's what that picture means.
People worked on that bloody picture for
a long,
long,
long time.
And you know,
we see the picture,
but we don't know what it means.
But that's what it means.
It means the same thing that this means.
He's the same thing that this means.
See,
there's,
there's pride rock.
This is the Scandinavian world tree.
There's pride rock right there.
There's the territory outside.
See,
it's a serpent.
It's a snake.
That's the territory outside.
That's outside of the light and that's
all in a tree.
That's how can you not read that as a
history of the evolution of mankind and
it's exactly what it is.
That's our eternal home.
Well,
we better stop before that girl comes
in.
Well,
it's very nice having you all in the
class.
And I appreciated the warm welcome I go
out,
especially in January,
because it was a rough time in January.
And so I'm glad this all worked out so
well,
and it was a pleasure teaching you.
So good luck to you all.
I mean,
it be what you can be,
God,
he let the world dissolve around you.
Otherwise that's not a good thing.
You got something that everyone needs,
man,
including yourself.
It's like,
let it out.
That's where everything you want is,
and it's this,
it's the case for every single one of
you.
So,
you know,
hoist up your God damn privilege and go
out there and do something in the world
to,
yeah.
[inaudible].