Tell her where everyone.
Hello everyone.
Where do we go?
Good to see all of you.
So
first question,
well,
I guess I could catch you up on what's
been happening first in case you were
vaguely interested,
most of you probably know or some of you
know anyways,
about what happened at Wilfrid laurier
university this week or two weeks ago,
a teaching assistant named Lindsay
Shepherd was interrogated,
I would say,
by the typical suspects,
the kind of postmodern,
Neo Marxist that I've been talking
about,
holder into an inquisition and,
um,
proceeded to rape her over the coals for
having the goal to show a video that
featured me about a year ago on our
Canadian TV show called the agenda.
Um,
they accused her of violating the
criminal code essentially,
and the Canadian human rights code,
um,
under the provisions of Bill
[inaudible],
which was the bill I warned about last
year and accused her of transphobia and
making an unsafe environment.
And then they accused me of being
Hitler,
which was really quite interesting
because I've never been accused about
being Hitler.
So I modified my kermit puppet here.
Um,
which,
see,
you can probably see that I guess,
and I've done a response video which I'm
going to launch pretty soon.
So this is a Hitler,
the frog and the spokes frog by the way.
And He,
uh,
well this is what we've come to.
So.
All right,
let's answer some questions.
I'm going to start with Pigeonhole,
which,
uh,
is the site that allows people to vote
on questions.
And so the top voted question is,
how do you identify,
how do you justify a rejection of
identity arianism when a pillar of the
neo marxists strategy is to
demographically replaced the indigenous
people of Europe?
London,
it's less than half ethnically English.
Um,
okay.
So let's take that question apart.
First of all,
it isn't self evident to me that it is
specifically a neo Marxist strategy to
demographically replaced the indigenous
peoples of Europe.
And um,
I don't think that's the strategy
anyways,
even if that's the outcome because you
have to distinguish strategy and
outcome.
Um,
the strategy and principle is to bring
in immigrants to balance out the
declining birthrate.
Now I'm not saying I agree with that,
I'm just saying that that's what the
strategy is a and then the next part of
the question is predicated on the
assumption that identity Arianism is
necessarily the answer to the problem of
the problem that's being identified,
which is characterized as excess
immigration.
First of all,
we'd have to figure out exactly what
identitarianism means because it isn't
clear if it means radical,
right wing ethnic nationalism.
I don't think that that's going to be
particularly constructive if it means
having a sensible discussion about what
the appropriate limits might be on
immigration,
uh,
and to think about that over the long
run and also to have a serious
discussion about
the degree to which say Islam and the
West,
the values of Islam and the West are
actually commensurate.
Then that has to be obviously has to be
done.
But I'm so I'm afraid that to answer
that question,
I'd have to know more about exactly how
these terms were being were being
defined.
Especially with regards to
identitarianism because it's a vague
word.
And so that's all I can do with that.
I lose my ability to think straight or
intelligently in confrontational or
unfriendly social situations.
Any suggestions for adoptation or
improvement?
Well,
a couple.
I suppose.
One is that when you get nervous in this
kind of situation that you're
describing,
what often happens to people is they
start paying attention to themselves.
They get self conscious so you know,
let's say I got self conscious all of a
sudden during this q and a.
What would happen is that I'd start
paying attention to the questions and
the screen and what I'm doing and I'd
start paying attention to how I was
feeling and to the nervousness and then
I'd start to get aware that I was not
responding properly and that would make
me more nervous and then I would get
more aware of that and that can just
shut me down entirely.
And that's happened to me now and then
in a lecture and sometimes almost
happened when I was talking to Sam
Harris the first time.
I'm all right.
I paused for a long time and then became
aware of the pause and then anyways,
what you have to do in a situation like
that is it's not so much that you have
to stop attending to yourself because if
you start thinking,
I should stop attending to myself,
then you'll just think about yourself
more.
What you have to do instead is pay more
attention to the situation and to the
people that you're talking to.
So you have to increase the degree to
which you're at attending outwardly and
that'll stop you from attending
inwardly.
Um,
that's a very effective technique.
You can practice that.
Generally speaking,
every time you get nervous,
start paying more attention and that'll,
that'll,
that'll help you out a lot.
Um,
the,
a really good suggestion for social
anxiety in general is that if you see
most people,
but not everyone,
but most people have enough implicit
social skill because they were
reasonably socialized when they were
children so that they do know how to act
in social situations,
but they get anxious and then that
interferes with them implementing what
they know.
Just like if you're a pianist and you
get anxious and self conscious while
you're playing,
you'll forget what you know because
while you've activated a different part
of your brain,
if you can remember to pay attention and
you can direct your attention outward
and you attend hard enough,
then what will happen and try to put the
other person at ease and try to ask them
questions.
Then that'll kick in the automatic
because you're paying attention to what
the person is doing into their facial
expressions and all of that.
That will clue in the automatic and
implicit
knowledge that you have and make things
much more smooth and,
and uh,
and anxiety free.
So attention really attention really
plays a huge role in regulating anxiety.
I would.
Lauren asks,
I would love to hear you do a lecture
series on raising children properly.
Is that something you would consider?
Well,
in my new book,
I've written a chapter on that called
don't let your children do anything that
makes you dislike them.
And I've laid out a bunch of,
uh,
I've laid out a philosophy of care and
discipline that's predicated partly on a
French philosophical legal notion,
which is do not multiply rules beyond
necessity.
It's sort of like a legal equivalent to
[inaudible] razor and an English common
law principle is which is used minimal
necessary force.
And I think the Union of those two,
which is don't have too many rules,
but make sure that you properly enforced
the ones that you do have is a good
start for how you might consider your
attitude with regards to raising
children.
The other thing you have to figure out
is exactly what's your aim.
And you know,
one of the aims that people have had
most recently pushed by clueless
psychologists,
I would say,
is that you want children to have high
self esteem and a,
that's actually a large part trait
neuroticism anyways,
but it can be modified to some degree.
Jerome Kagan has done some very
interesting work on that.
But,
um,
the best thing to do,
the,
I think,
the best thing to orient yourself
towards with regards to children is that
you're trying to make your child your
children or help your children to be
delightful in the eyes of others.
And so that means they have to be
reasonably well socialized.
And that really takes place between the
ages of two and four because what you
want for your children is that when they
go out into public,
when they're away from you or even with
you for that matter,
what you want for your children is for
other people to genuinely like them.
Because if they behave reasonably and
they attend properly to adults and they
know how to play with other children,
then wherever they go,
they're going to be,
um,
unless they encounter someone truly
malevolent,
they're going to be welcomed with smiles
and open arms.
And that's not going to be fake because
almost every human being actually likes
children if they're reasonably behaved.
And so your job is to make your children
highly socially desirable because that
opens up the world to them.
So they're,
that's not a lecture series,
but it's a little lecture looking at
myself,
honestly,
John says,
I'm deeply envious and resentful of
others happiness.
How do I turn this around?
Well,
John,
I would say you've started to turn it on
around already because you have at least
come to the conclusion that you're
deeply envious and resentful of others
happiness.
So you do have the damn problem
diagnosed.
So one of the things you might do is
figure out what you would like instead.
Like how would you like to feel about
the world,
you know,
because you're implying that being
deeply envious and resentful isn't for
the best.
So let's assume that you would rather be
pleased about other people's successes
and not envious.
Well,
you know,
the first thing you might think is,
well maybe you have to do some writing
or at least some thinking.
It's like maybe the alternative would be
happy,
be happy about other's success and
happiness.
Well maybe you should start by thinking
about why you might be happy about their
happiness.
It's not like happiness is a zero sum
game,
you know,
it's not like,
it's not an,
I believe me,
I'm taking your question seriously and I
think that what you're saying
characterize is plenty of people and I
think that you're being deeply honest,
noticing it,
happiness isn't a zero sum game,
you know,
lots of people can be happy at the same
time.
And do you really want to live in a
world where other people are less happy
in what possible manner without be
useful and good for you in the medium to
longterm?
It might make you feel,
you know,
grudgingly,
uh,
satisfied,
you know,
in a dark way temporarily,
but it's not a very good long term
strategy.
So I would say you got to think it
through,
you know,
what,
how is it that you would like to view
the world?
How do you think that would be best for
you?
I mean as if you were taking care of
yourself,
like you,
like you're someone who deserves to be
taken care of.
Think about how you'd like to have the
world,
how he'd like to view the world.
And one of the ways you can do that too
is to think about some people that you
admire and try to figure out how they
look at the world or even ask them,
you know,
because maybe then you can find out what
it is about your thought patterns that
are driving you down this dark road.
So
why are you now Francoise St Onge asks,
why are you hiding the amount you
receive from Patriot?
And I found it very motivating to see
the amount skyrocket and tell cloud to
be part of this as if you were an
artist.
I now feel more like I'm buying a
product and I find it less appealing.
Yeah.
Well it's one of those things where I'm
kind of damned if I do and damned if I
don't,
you know,
and I don't know what's correct.
I guess I probably got tired of the sort
of more left leaning,
let's say radical left leaning press
people jumping up and down on me every
chance they got because people were
donating money for,
for services that I particularly rent,
you know,
that I render essentially for free.
Um,
you know,
I,
there must have been 10 articles in the
last week following the Lindsay shepherd
a incident pointing out that I'm somehow
being manipulative and,
and,
uh,
evil in a capitalist sort of way for
daring to
allow people to donate money to help
support what I'm doing and it gets kind
of tiring.
And so I don't know,
I just.
And I guess I also thought that maybe
there's a part of it,
it's like,
well,
I wouldn't exactly call it bragging,
but because it's not,
but
ah,
that's about good enough.
I mean,
it was an appeal to privacy I suppose in
part two.
I don't know if it's the right thing.
I could do a poll on twitter and find
out.
I guess I did that first of other things
this week.
So anyways,
that's,
that's the answer to that user in.
Okay.
Says I love you man.
Keep it up.
Well,
that's a pretty good question and uh,
I'm trying to keep it up.
I'm actually feeling quite a bit better.
I was actually happy today and it's been
so rare for the last while that I could
hardly even recognize what it felt like
so,
but I'm definitely feeling better.
I'm getting some energy in the morning
and so I'm,
I'm really happy about that.
So thanks.
Anyways,
I appreciate it.
Thoughts on the radical left and they're
superficial view,
belief and value on the environment.
How has this influenced by their own raw
emotions?
Inviting,
questionable,
immoral,
and dangerous actions despite good
intentions?
Well,
I don't really buy the whole good
intentions thing.
I mean,
I think that it's really hard to have
good intentions.
Like John,
the question are just answered.
Uh,
you know,
John said,
looking at myself honestly,
I'm deeply envious and resentful of
others happiness.
Well,
if you listen to the Lindsay shepherd
recording at Wilfrid laurier university
and you listen to the professors and the
administrators,
I think that it's,
uh,
it's,
it's absurd to start with the
presupposition that they have good
intentions.
I don't think they have good intentions
at all.
So,
um,
but you know,
we could give the devil his due and say
that there are people on the left end of
the spectrum,
like,
like there are all parts of the spectrum
who are,
are trying to do good things,
but having good intentions and figuring
out how to do well in the world are our
good intentions are only the beginning
and people are always influenced by raw
emotions and fuzzy thinking and it's
hard to think critically and it's hard
to plan strategically and it's hard to,
to intervene in the world in a way that
doesn't cause trouble,
which is partly why I recommend to
people that they start local.
You know,
you can't even trust your own good
intentions to some degree because you
have to test out what you do when you
have good intentions and see if it
actually produces the result that's
intended.
But I wouldn't make the case to begin
with that,
especially on the radical end of the
left.
I think it's unbelievably motivated by
resentment.
So
how does one save a marriage when it
seems that there is no longer attraction
both physically and intellectually?
There are kids involved,
which is the main reason for wanting to
save the marriage.
Huh?
Well,
alright.
I know a couple of things about that.
I mean the first thing I would say is
that if you haven't had any intimate
interaction with one another for quite a
long period of time,
that can put both people into a stagnant
state where desire starts to slip away.
What what sex therapists recommend under
such conditions is to,
well essentially start in some ways,
start dating again so you could ask your
partner to go out to a movie or
something like that and you know,
maybe when you come home you could,
you could neck for a little while,
like teenagers.
That's probably a word no one uses
anymore,
but kinda pull back and you got to
agree.
Say not to engage in full sexual
activity for a while,
but to tease each other and to play a
bit.
Even if you're not attracted,
you have to act.
Acted out for awhile and hopefully you
can get the motor running again.
The other thing I would say is that you
guys might want to sit down and make a
joint plan.
It's like what a marriage is like a
story that two people are acting out
simultaneously and you have to have
shared goals and because you're both
rowing the same boat,
let's say if you don't have a
destination in mind,
then,
well,
maybe you're rowing in circles or maybe
you're just standing still.
So I would say work hard to put some
romance back in the relationship,
you know,
you could say to each other,
look,
let's try this for six months and just
see how it goes.
We'll have two dates a week for the
first month.
We won't have any sex,
but we'll play around and then,
you know,
we'll see how that goes and,
and,
but we'll try it out for the,
for,
for the whole,
for the whole six months.
There are reasons to save a marriage.
I mean,
it's hard on kids.
Divorce is really hard on kids and it's
hard on the adults involved too.
Um,
so I would say
you have to negotiate an agreement and
you,
you know,
you could try the future authoring
program,
both of you,
what,
what I would recommend for example,
is that you each do the future authoring
program separately.
So that's that self authoring dotcom
because then you both have a life plan
and then you could sit down and read
each other's future authoring plans and
see if you have some things in common
and then see if you can figure out how
to support each other with regards to
each of you obtaining what you want.
So Paul Maloney asks,
you edited out a disagreement with
Camille Paglia.
What was it?
No,
no,
that's not the case.
There was a piece edited out,
but it wasn't because there was a
disagreement,
it was because there was some glitch in
the video or something like that.
Generally speaking,
and you know,
I can't say this with absolute
certainty,
but I do.
And so does my crew do everything we
possibly can to leave the videos alone
except for getting rid of things that
would be of no interest to anyone that
are mistakes.
So there was no disagreement.
Are you interested in coming to
Australia?
Yes.
I've been invited a couple of times but
it hasn't worked out yet.
But um,
my book will be published in Australia I
think sometime in January as well.
And uh,
I imagined that all becoming there at
some point in order to talk about my
book and so on.
Tray says,
how can a person go through the future
authoring process of imagining a future
for yourself as though you or someone
you care about when you barely don't
care about yourself or even hate
yourself?
Yeah,
well I would say that
go through the exercise anyways and act
as like try to extend to yourself some
courtesy.
You know,
sometimes you have to act something out
before you can start to believe it.
And so I would say sit down and pretend
that you're your friend,
you know,
trade the probability that there's
something so wrong with you that you
don't deserve any regard whatsoever is
zero,
you know,
so,
and I would say if,
if you just can't get it together,
you know,
maybe you were depressed and maybe you
need to go talk to someone because you
don't have to be depressed.
You talked to a physician,
you know,
there are treatments for depression if
you happen to be depressed and if you
actually hate yourself,
then it's a possibility that that's
what's going on.
I don't know how old you are,
but you know,
there are effective treatments for that
sort of thing.
You might want to find out if there's
actually something wrong physically or,
or psychophysiological.
He,
you know,
because you don't have to trudge through
life absolutely miserable.
Their antidepressants,
for example,
work really well for some people.
Not for everyone but for some people.
So.
Okay.
Were the Nazis left wing?
Um,
that's a good question.
It depends.
See the problem with any question that
says is a,
B is a equivalent to be,
is that it depends on how you define a
and B.
Right?
And I'm not trying to weasel out of the
question.
I'm,
I'm very,
very serious about that.
The Nazis regarded themselves as
national socialists,
you know,
so they,
they,
they weren't free market capitalists,
let's say.
So they certainly weren't right wingers
in the way that free market capitalists
are right wingers,
even though they're probably more
centrist,
um,
they differed from the international
socialists,
which were the Marxists because they
were much more concerned with national
identity and racial identity.
And to the degree that you regard
nationalism and racial identity as
primarily right wing views than the
Nazis would have been right wing.
So let's say that they,
maybe they pulled from the worst of both
extreme,
something like that.
But I do think it's reasonable to note
that there extreme nationalism and
ethnocentrism and racial identity
probably has more in common with the
radical right than it does with the
radical left,
which tends to be utopian universal.
So I'm one of the things I thought would
be an interesting research project would
be to take like 100 Nazi policies and to
turn them into a questionnaire and asked
people either how much they agree with
them after I figured out whether they
were left to right wing to begin with or
whether they thought the policies were
representative of the left or the right
because that could be studied
empirically and I don't think anyone's
done it.
But that would be a very interesting,
uh,
that would be a very interesting
research project is left for Helgason
probably Matt,
Matt massacred that name,
says who has a higher Iq at really
gifted mathematician or a really gifted
painter.
Very difficult to say.
Um,
but I would say that gifted math,
because if they're both gifted,
they both have high Iq.
So you can be certain that it's very
difficult to do anything that's truly
gifted,
say above the average,
above the norm without being,
without having a very high Iq.
And in a creative realm.
I mean,
you hear about these idiot savant who
have like one area of extreme expertise,
but generally in those cases it's not so
much that they have one area of extreme
expertise,
it's that they have one area of above
average expertise that really contrast
with the rest of their impairments,
but they rarely if ever make it into
the,
you know,
the very short list of true geniuses.
Mathematicians are kind of an odd bunch
though because you.
They peek really,
really early.
Like if you're going to be a
mathematician and truly gifted,
then you're going to show signs of that
when you're like 17 to 20,
something like that.
Whereas painters can,
can be creative through their entire
lifespan.
I would say probably on average,
I would guess this is a guest that if
you took 100 really gifted
mathematicians in 100 really gifted
painters,
that the mathematicians would have far
higher nonverbal Iq,
but the painter's might have higher
verbal Iq.
So that also complicates things.
See with Iq also,
you know there's.
There's this factor called the g factor,
which is the central element of
intelligence and it seems to be
associated with such things as head size
and brain size relative to body and
neural conduction speed and simple
reaction time,
like really basic physiological markers,
um,
and it's a pretty tight single factors
say as opposed to the personality
dimension d domain where there's five
quite clear factors,
but I think it was earl hunts research
indicated that as people get smarter and
smarter,
the variability between the subsets of
their intelligence starts to increase.
So it's sort of like there's a lot of
ways to be really smart,
but there's only one way to be not very
smart.
So that's another little tidbit of
information with regards to ICU.
So
hello doctor,
I am a 23 year old male with paranoid
schizophrenia.
However,
I feel like controlling 95 percent of
it.
Okay.
So let's say I think you mean that
you're controlling 95 percent of it.
I decided to seek a partner,
but I am afraid how to reveal it.
Any advice on how to approach it?
Oh God.
Steven,
that's a really hard question.
Well,
look,
you're not under any obligation when you
first meet someone to drown them in
information about your identity.
So I would say
the devil's in the details.
Fundamentally,
if you have a relationship with someone
and it's progressing and you're being
honest,
my suspicions are that it will come up
with its own accord.
You know,
that you'll be able to tell in this
situation when the right way to
introduce it is,
um,
you know,
if,
if you're asking me this because you've
been in a relationship for a long time
and you haven't revealed it,
then I don't know what to tell you about
that because,
and because I wouldn't give someone
general advice about that,
you know,
if,
uh,
sorry
if I,
we speaking to a client and I had some
real
detailed information about their current
situation,
I would sit down and help them
strategize about that.
Ask about the person you're telling.
Figure out how long you've gone out with
them,
figure out a way that it might be
revealed that you would be comfortable
with.
I suspect probably what you should do is
find someone you trust to talk about it
if you're already in a relationship and
if you're not,
then assume that if going into the
relationship,
your basic goal is honesty,
that you'll handle it appropriately when
the situation comes up.
So
how would you address accusations that
you are creating another ideological
group identity which is equal in its
capacity for destruction to post Modern
Neo Marxism?
Well,
uh,
I would address it the way I've been
addressing it for the whole last year,
which is that I'm not trying to produce
a group identity of any sort.
I'm trying to get people to act locally
in the confines of their own environment
and to sort things out that are under
their direct control.
So it's,
it's an elaboration of one of the ideas
I suppose that's in the New Testament,
which is that you should take the log
out of your own eye before you worry
about the dust speck in your neighbor's
eye,
which I think is a really good general
maxim.
And so there's nothing about that that's
associated with group identity.
Now people have tried to,
um,
what would you call it,
attribute to me some identity with the
right or the alt right,
or even the far right more recently,
even Hitler,
which is what came up in at Wilfrid
laurier.
But I think the reason for that is
twofold.
One is,
look,
if you're imagine that there is a
radical left that's not very difficult
to imagine,
and then imagine that everyone to the
right of the radical left is our all in
opposition to the radical left.
So then you have a group and the group
is all those in opposition to the
radical left and that'll include people
on the radical right.
And so then when you look at that entire
group,
so let's say a thousand people or 1500
people come in here,
a talk that I give on free speech that
happened on November 11th.
First of all,
there's 1500 people in a room,
like 15 of them are going to be
completely out of their mind,
probably more like 30,
but at least 15.
And that's just base rate.
And so to demonstrate that the group was
somehow pathological,
you'd have to show that the base rate of
pathology was higher in the group than
it would be in a randomly selected
group.
And I've seen no evidence of that.
But also even if there are a number of
people say on the far right in that
group that doesn't indicate at all that
that's characteristic of the group.
But it's very hard to distinguish that
because what tends to happen is that a
group is defined by the most egregious
behavior of,
of its most extreme members.
So anyways,
the other way that I did address the
accusation is that,
and I have done this as well,
and I think it's what really protected
me this whole year,
is that I have all these youtube videos
online,
you know,
600 hours of them.
And the message is pretty stable.
The more the newer manifestation is,
you know,
a fairly focused critique of the
university,
which I think is entirely justified.
But everything around that is focused on
the individual and the role of the
individual and the responsibility of the
individual.
And so I don't believe that that is an
ideological group identity,
so that's how I would address it.
So.
All right,
let's see what else we've got here.
What is the evolutionary reason for
having consciousness?
I think that was toby who asked that
God only knows
that's been a problem that people have
been hammering on for a long time.
I mean,
that's the so called Zombie problem that
David Chalmers is as described,
which is something like,
how do you know that other people aren't
exactly like you except acting in a
completely determined manner and devoid
of consciousness.
This,
um,
I don't know what the evolutionary
reason is for consciousness.
I mean,
I can speculate like what consciousness
seems to be,
at least in part,
is a,
a mechanism of repair.
So a lot of the things that you do are
unconscious.
You know,
like when you're driving,
if you're an expert driver,
you're,
you're using your eyes to watch the road
and your eyes are moving your hands and
your arms,
but you're not really thinking about
what you're doing.
You're not attending to it consciously
because you've built circuitry already,
specialized circuitry that handles all
those tasks.
Now what happens when you're driving?
Let's say that you make a mistake.
Well then what happens?
You consciously attend to the mistake
and you attempt to revise the part of
the automatic structure that produced
the error.
So let's imagine this.
Imagine you're playing the piano and
you're playing a very complicated a
sequence and you stumble over part of it
so you're zooming along and you stumble
over part of it and then you attend to
that.
You'd go back and you slow down and you
move your fingers slowly and you try to
reprogram those little automatic units
that have handled that part of that.
You repair them and,
and reprogram them and you get faster
and faster out of it as they automatize
and then you go.
So consciousness seems to be something
that watches what you do,
automatically checks for errors and then
repairs it.
And so that's its function.
Now you might ask why a repair mechanism
like that would have to be associated
with awareness announced that is,
uh,
not only do I not know,
I don't think anyone knows if I was
speculating and which I've done,
I think consciousness actually plays an
integral role in being itself because
I'm not convinced that there would be
any being of any recognizable sort
without a conscious observer.
So I think consciousness is actually
like a center point of the cosmos in
some sense,
and I think it's because of ideas like
that,
that the,
the grand archetypal idea of the soul
has emerged and I think it's correct.
So,
but how to precisely integrate that with
evolutionary theory.
Um,
apart from the description that already
provided,
I just don't,
I just don't know.
So
let's see,
what else have we got here?
Would you consider a more official
consultancy role with Andrew Scheer's
Conservative Party?
Um,
it's very difficult to say what I would
consider.
It isn't obvious to me that Andrew
Scheer would particularly like to have
me as no official consultant time,
kind of what might you describe a
controversial?
Yes,
that's the word right now.
And so,
you know,
it's funny though,
because I was making this new video
today,
which I alluded to earlier,
using good old.
What's this character here?
Uh,
Hitler though Hitler the spokes frog.
And uh,
I,
I went back and looked at my comments on
bill [inaudible] last year,
which,
which were the comments that originally
got me in hot water and had me accused
of all the things I've been accused of
Transphobia,
bigotry,
racism.
Um,
what else?
Oh,
you fascism being on the far right.
Then finally,
and to top it all off,
Hitler himself.
And one of the things that I realized
was that,
that I was really calm during that
video.
You couldn't have really.
I couldn't have offered a more mild
mannered criticism of bill [inaudible].
And it's pretty funny because,
you know,
I'm this scandal that engulfed Wilford
laurier this week is the worst scandal
that I remember involving university in,
in,
in my memory,
going back to the 19 seventies.
And what happened at Laurie was exactly
what I predicted would happen except it
was actually worse because they did
accuse Lindsay of breaking the law
spill,
see 16 specifically,
and have contravening the Ontario Human
Rights Code,
which I,
you know,
for all I know she might've done.
So we're,
we're at this situation where a Ta
showing a video of someone discussing
pronouns in candidate can now be termed
a hate crime and illegal provincially
and federally.
And like all the usual suspects have
come out of their
caves,
let's say,
uh,
like Brenda Cossman,
the lawyer I debated last year and said,
well,
it's a real stretch to assume that what
Lindsay Shepherd did was,
was sufficiently reprehensible to
actually constitute a violation of the
Ontario Human Rights Commission.
A guidelines,
policies hits a stretch.
So I guess we're supposed to feel good
about that.
But,
um,
I'm probably a little bit too hot right
now to serve in any official consultant
role,
uh,
that doesn't mean that I wouldn't be
happy to speak to,
you know,
political figures who might be
interested in speaking with me because,
you know,
I generally speak to people who asked me
to speak to them.
So
as reprehensible as that might be,
recently moved up and was promoted and
not liking it because I have to adjust
massively.
Is there a difference between liking
your job and the lack of discipline to
perform a change?
Are there,
are they connected?
Yeah,
well,
they're definitely connected.
It's a tough one.
Um,
the first thing I would say is that if
it was a real radical change,
you know,
it takes people,
unless they're very young,
it takes people about a year to adjust
to a really radical change,
like to move to a new city,
to,
to adjust to being married.
That can take longer than a year to
adjust to having a new baby to,
to getting over a relatively serious
loss,
like a death in the family a year,
you know.
And so the first thing you might ask
yourself is,
are there things that are good about the
promotion?
The second is,
do you have the capacity to do the job
or to learn how to do it?
You could talk to someone about that.
And then the third thing is have you
given yourself enough time to adjust
because one of the things I often
recommend to people when they've made a
radical change like going leaving home
and going to university,
is don't pay any attention to how you
feel for a year because everything is so
much up in the air that you can't really
trust your own judgment.
So you have to give yourself time to
adapt and you can't expect that that's
going to happen overnight.
It,
it's certainly not.
And to put that expectation on yourself
increases the probability that you're
going to feel bad about it.
So,
um,
let's see.
Atomic Carlos says,
my Iq is north of one slash 30.
Yet I questioned my own intelligence all
the time.
I feel big cognitive dissonance between
what people expect of me and what I
considered myself capable to do.
Well,
you know,
Carlos would,
I would recommend there is that if,
if you haven't done it,
just go do the personality test and
understand myself.com because what
you're describing sounds very much like
high levels of negative emotionality or
neuroticism and you might want to find
out if that's the case because if you're
much higher than average in neuroticism,
then you're going to be questioning
yourself all the time and you might want
to figure out if that's actually a trait
and if it is a trait,
well then that gives you an explanation
of it.
And then you might also note that your
levels of negative emotion are not well
matched to your likely skill.
Now that doesn't necessarily help you
learn to cope with it,
but sometimes identifying the reason
it's useful and there's another
possibility too,
is that your mood is dysregulated and
that you're depressed.
So that's another thing to consider.
Um,
if you,
if you do find that you have high levels
of neuroticism but you're not depressed,
then one of the things you might do is
write down all the reasons,
like really think them out.
You know,
I mean,
really get serious about this,
write down all the reasons why you might
give yourself more credit for
intelligence than you have,
and part of that could be like a really
deep reconsideration of successes you've
had in the past with complex
intellectual issues because imagine that
you are serving as your own defense
attorney against a very critical part of
your mind.
Um,
that can help a lot.
That can help.
Marlene hibbs says,
my little girl loves you.
Uh,
well that's,
that's good.
I guess you can say hi to her for me.
I hope that she has a great little life.
So give her a pat on the head and tell
him that cognizant of the modern art
scene.
So
it isn't easy to figure out how to,
how to answer that question.
So,
um,
I haven't been thinking also about art
for quite a long time because I've been
so engaged in all this political and
philosophical materials.
So,
but music,
as far as music goes,
I really liked the last recordings of
Johnny cash.
Who else springs to mind?
I like a very large variety of a lot of
different genres of music as well,
so
I'll have to leave it at that.
I think
Richard Boyle says,
hi,
Dr Peterson,
how does the score of 91 for compassion
and one for politeness equals a score of
35 for agreeableness?
Yeah,
well it's because 91 in one aren't
ordinary numbers.
Their percentiles and you can't just
average percentiles.
It doesn't work that way.
What it says is that,
let's see,
I don't know if I can generate it,
just a description on the fly because
I'm not,
I wouldn't say I'm particularly
mathematically gifted,
although I know that the answer I just
gave you is correct.
Let's see.
There's one in,
there's a one in 10 chance that a person
would be that compassionate and a one in
100 percent chance that a person would
be that,
that,
that uh,
nope,
I can't generate it on the fly,
but that's the answer.
So if you want to point to the proper
literature,
you'd look up,
I'm,
uh,
how to transform percentiles into CSI
scores.
They were called CSI scores.
Then you can,
if you,
oh,
that's how it works.
You convert the percentiles in disease,
scores,
you some disease scores,
and then you reconvert them into
percentiles,
and so if you take the z score for not
for compassion 91 and the z score for
politeness one,
add them,
divide them into and reconvert them to a
percentile,
you'll get 35.
I know it's weird,
but that's,
that's how it,
that's how it is.
That's how it's done.
So
let's see.
The opioid crisis.
This is army hat or hateful.
The opioid crisis in my community in the
midwest of America greatly bothers me.
I've been thinking about becoming a
police officer.
The culture has been very favorable
towards cops lately.
Maybe maybe majoring in law in Grad
school instead.
Advice,
please.
Thanks.
Well,
if you're,
if you're going to be a police officer,
you should be very emotionally stable,
so low in neuroticism and very high in
conscientiousness.
If you're going to be a lawyer,
you better be very bright.
First,
you need to be extremely bright verbally
in particular.
You need to be extremely conscientious.
You need to be emotionally stable and
you need to be fairly disagreeable.
That's,
that's what characterizes lawyers.
If you're high in openness and
creativity,
let's say.
I would say neither nor law is a good
occupation for you.
So I wouldn't worry about the culture
not being too favorable towards cops.
That's,
I don't think it's really any worse than
it was.
It's probably not as bad as it was in
the sixties and I don't that it will
necessarily continue.
I don't think you should let that stop
you because you know,
the police have their own brotherhood
and you'd find your community within
that.
Um,
you what I would say you should think
more about what you want then how other
people view the occupation.
I know that's irrelevant,
but you should think about what you
want.
And I think if see if you can figure out
if the life of a policeman would
actually interest you or the life of a
lawyer.
Like lots of people go into law and
don't like it.
You have to be argumentative.
You have to really be literate because
there's so much reading and writing.
You have to be able to write,
you have to be able to lay out clear
arguments,
you have to be really orderly and detail
oriented because there's so many things
to keep track of.
Um,
so you've got to make sure you got the
right temperament for that so you could
try the big five personality scale at
understand myself.
I'm,
like I said,
the good lawyers are high in
conscientiousness,
low in neuroticism,
pretty disagreeable,
and then extroversion helps to some
degree because it makes you better in
the court and it also makes you better
at generating sales leads,
which you know,
growing your business,
which is super important if you're a
lawyer,
like lots of people are competent
lawyers,
but only a small set of competent
lawyers are also good at generating new
business.
And that makes you extremely valuable.
So if you've got a salesmen aspect to
you as well as those other traits,
which makes you a pretty rare person,
then you know you could be a bang up
lawyer.
So
link with a light saber,
says,
hey man,
as a Canadian,
I just wanted to say thanks candidate
short on heroes these days and I'm glad
to see you filled that role.
Thanks again bud.
Hey,
well thanks a lot man.
I don't really think of myself as a
hero.
I think of myself as someone who's on a
relatively small raft perched on a
relatively large wave paddling like a
mad dog and trying not to be submerged
so and so far.
Well,
I haven't drawn yet,
so hooray for that.
So,
hey guys,
I'm going to read you a little bit of my
book if you don't mind,
somewhere near the end of this.
Uh,
let's see.
I'll probably go for about two hours.
So we got about another hour,
so I figured I'd read something to you
for about 15 minutes and if you're
interested in that,
why don't you just say so in the
comments section,
that would be good.
Then I could see what people think of
that idea.
Um,
let's see here.
Sorry,
it's taken me just a little while to
good.
Someone says,
well,
I'll,
uh,
go for that.
Let's see.
Hi Jordan.
What are feelings and why do we have
them?
Well,
here's a way of thinking about it.
So look,
let's say you were walking down a
pathway.
I actually saw this happen one day,
so I'll you this story.
So I was walking along the cliffs near,
I think it was San Diego La,
I don't remember.
I think probably,
I think it was,
I think it was San Diego.
Anyways,
I was walking along there with some
friends and a and a brother of a friend
of mine who was quite a tall guy.
He's about six foot five,
something like that.
And he was walking along the path on the
edge of the cliff,
kind of sandy and with with scrub pine
around overlooking the Pacific Ocean.
And it was march I think,
so it was warm but not too warm.
We were walking along and all of a
sudden,
his little girl who I think was like
four or five,
she was walking in front of him and in
front of me and I guess we were going
round a little bit of a corner and all
of a sudden she jumped right up on his
shoulders,
which I'd never seen a child do that.
It was like watching,
you know,
if you,
if a cat sleep and you and you and you
go out and it'll jump up and puff out
its hair and can jump straight up.
Well that's what this kid did and there
was a rattlesnake at the side of the,
of the path.
Now it was cold,
which was probably good,
but you know,
there's a guy named,
uh
Oh,
I can't read.
He wrote a great book on fear.
It'll come to me.
It's a book that I should have on my
booklist actually.
And he showed that there are circuits in
your brain there reflects circuit.
So this had been demonstrated to some
degree much earlier that map.
So imagine that a snake is a pattern.
And then imagine that there's a pattern
on your retina that constitutes the
snake,
and then imagine that that can be
transformed into another pattern which
is a muscular output pattern.
And that muscular output pattern is to
jump you in the air,
so your eyes make your,
your make your muscles move in a
particular way that happens before you
see the snake and before you're afraid.
And the reason for that is that so it's,
there are not many neural connections
between snake detection and leaping in
the air.
And that's because if you waited to feel
fear and waited to see the snake,
that would take between a quarter and
half a second,
something like that,
and the snake would have already bitten
you.
So unless you had those really short
neuropathways that have been conserved
in the evolutionary process since like
the beginning of time,
anything super fast and simple would be
able to kill you.
So now,
so let's say that you do encounter
something unexpected.
Well first you have these bodily
reflexes that are really fast.
And then the next thing that happens,
generally speaking,
is that you feel an emotion.
Like maybe you're frozen,
so if you hear a real girl behind you,
you'll freeze and then you'll feel fear
and that'll keep you frozen.
And so the fear is,
uh,
an indication of that physiological
state.
And then only after that will you start
to think and strategize.
And so you need reactions at multiple
levels of temporal resolution in order
to keep you safe in the world.
And the fast reactions are muscular and
reflexive.
And then the next ones generally
speaking,
are something like emotions and they're
low resolution,
but quick,
you know,
like if you're afraid it means there's
something that may be dangerous.
It's vague and it's not until you
explore it,
that you know exactly what the danger
is.
But the fear is a good enough initial
category.
So you could think about feelings as
instinctual categories,
things to love,
things to eat,
things to run away from,
things to run towards their low
resolution categories.
And that's how animals categories the
world.
They use emotion and motivation to
categorize the world.
So we have to keep ourselves properly
oriented in the world and to react
quickly and so that we can stay alive.
So.
Okay,
let's see here.
What else have we got?
Recently?
I took a job working at a camp with at
risk boys were.
Well there I will live at work as a
counselor and a house with the kids.
Any advice for working with young people
with behavioral issues?
Uh,
yeah.
It depends on what the behavioral issues
are.
So I don't know what our risk means,
but uh,
so I can't be too specific,
but what I can tell you is that almost
nothing beats listening,
you know,
like take a kid for a walk,
let them talk,
like listen to them,
ask them questions,
you know,
because most disturbed people and maybe
even most people don't actually have
anyone they can talk to and they need to
talk first of all to find out that
someone actually cares enough to listen.
So it's sort of like a validation of the
fact that they exist and second so that
they can sort out their own thoughts.
So as a beginning counselor,
the best thing you can do is listen,
you don't want to give advice really,
you know,
because what you want,
you can ask questions that might lead
someone in an advisable direction.
But the problem with giving advice is
that people are much more likely to
remember something and to implement it
if they've thought it up in their own
words.
I think that actually produces a kind of
neurological transformation.
The idea has to be engendered from
within.
It's one of the prime dicta of,
of psychoanalytic theory,
for example.
And I think it's a really good one.
So yeah.
With,
with regards to.
So Brendan Crystal says trippy snakes
and retinas.
Yeah.
Like it's really specific.
So this woman named um,
no,
I probably can't remember her name.
Me It either.
She,
she wrote a book about trees and
serpents.
Uh,
she's a ucla professor.
Um,
the fruit,
the tree and the serpent,
I think it's called.
She showed quite clearly that not only
do our retinas say directly detects
snakes,
but they do a better job in the bottom
half of the retina and that we're really
good at detecting the camouflage
patterns that are characteristic of
snakes.
Snakes have these like patterns which
are very,
very rare and we have specialized
circuitry for detecting those.
And there is recent research conducted
that showed that children six months old
who had never been exposed to anything
even resembling a snake,
had an automatic response to snakes.
And so it actually seems to be innate,
not just,
uh,
not just easily learned.
So that's really quite interesting.
So.
Okay,
let's go back to the pigeon hole thing
here.
How do you clean your room when your
spouse doesn't share that goal?
Huh?
Well,
that's another one of those questions.
It's really hard to answer because I
don't have the details,
you know,
how do you clean your room?
What goals does your spouse have?
That's the first thing.
I mean,
is there some commonality?
it might be maybe you're exposed as much
more disorderly than you or less
conscientious or irritated at you for
all sorts of reasons.
You know,
the first thing you could do is
try to lead by example and see how that
works,
but you may have to argue and fight it
out,
you know,
um,
break it down into sub tasks and,
and see if you can distribute the tasks
and negotiate.
You have to negotiate.
And without further information,
I can't say much more than that,
you know,
you can say why you're doing it,
what you think the goal we're and goal
was and that you'd like some help and
maybe there's something you could offer
in return.
Um,
if you can't negotiate at all with your
spouse,
then you have a much broader problem
than how do you clean your room when you
were supposed doesn't share that goal
because the real problem would be how do
you learn to negotiate with your spouse?
I could talk about that a little bit.
I mean,
the first thing that you have to do,
if you want to negotiate with someone is
be able to say no.
The second thing is to have something to
offer.
The third thing is to find out what they
want and to know what you want.
You know,
because often people,
especially with people that love them,
they say,
well,
if you really knew,
if you really love me,
then you'd know what I want.
It's like,
no,
that's just wrong.
The person that you are in love with or
that living with isn't any smarter than
you.
And so you pretty much always have to
tell people straight out what you want
and then you have to let them be really
stupid about giving it to you for quite
a while.
You know?
So sometimes I've recommended to my
clients that they take their wife or
husband out on a date and of course
they're all skeptical about that and
cynical about it.
And uh,
then they go on a date and they have a
terrible time and they come back and
say,
oh,
I told you that was a stupid idea.
And I tell them,
that's it then a,
you're not gonna do anything romantic
with your spouse for the next 40 years.
That's your plan.
That's the plan is that it's like you
might have to go out to a movie after
you haven't been good to each other for
like five years.
You might have to go out to movie 10
times movie and dinner,
say before it starts to become fun
again.
It's like it's hard to do that sort of
thing,
right?
You don't.
People think those things are easy and
they're not.
So anyways,
you have to.
You have to learn to negotiate with your
spouse.
And that's a very difficult thing to do.
So I'm figuring out what you want is a
good way to start.
So.
Oh,
okay.
What advice would you give the parent of
an only child?
Well,
I'll make sure that the child,
your child has lots of time for free
play with other kids.
And by free play,
I mean play with no electronic gadgets,
not sitting in front of the TV.
The kids have to be able to learn how to
amuse themselves and to especially to
engage in pretend play,
say if they're between three and
probably 11 damn near that time with
other kids is extremely important and
kids don't get enough time for free
play.
So that's what I would say is get them
around other kids as much as you can and
not under situations where the parents
are going to just sit them in front of
the TV or something like that to amuse
them so they don't make too much noise.
It's not like there's anything wrong
with seeing them and letting them watch
a movie,
but there's nothing wrong with the
movie.
But there is something wrong with not
giving the kids enough time to engage in
spontaneous play.
It's a catastrophe.
So how has the GRANDPA and going?
I think it's going pretty well.
It's quite a lot of fun to have a little
baby around again.
I mean I think like most man,
I'm somewhat nonplussed,
let's say by infants.
Um,
it's easier for me to deal with kids
after they were about,
once they get mobile la,
once I can sort of throw them around a
bit more than I know what to do with
them once I can play with them,
but it's really fun to watch my daughter
be a mother.
She's really good at it and it's good to
have another young thing in the family
and you know,
because babies are very,
they're kind of like fire you,
you can't help but watch them and
it's great.
It's great and she seems healthy and um,
she's cute as can be.
Of course babies are sneaky that way,
but it's working.
So yeah,
I think it's really going well.
So
I constantly cannot verbalize my
thoughts written and focal regardless of
topic and my level of knowledge.
Tips for verbalizing thoughts to get
them into writing and therefore speech.
Well,
what I would say lauren is do this like
read something,
put a decide,
try to summarize it in writing and talk
while you're doing it.
And then write down what you say and
don't edit while you're doing that.
See,
one of the problems that people have
when they're trying to write,
as they try to write a good sentence,
they,
they not only tried to write a sentence,
but they try to write a good sentence
and you can't do that.
You have to write a sentence that's hard
enough and then you have to edit it.
So allow yourself to write badly.
I'm dead serious about this,
like write a bad,
bad,
bad first draft and then edit it if you
get rid of 70 percent of it.
So what?
That's exactly what should happen.
So like if you want to write a thousand
word essay,
you should start by writing a really bad
2000 word essay and then you should get
rid of the worst 50 percent.
You can do that iteratively.
I have a document online.
It's,
it's.
If you go to my website,
I'm under courses,
there's psychology for 30 is the course.
I should make this more public,
but under a cycle psychology for 30.
There's a template for writing and if
you went looked at that template,
it tells you it answers your question.
I,
I produced this little guidebook for,
for writing that will help and if you
write enough,
you'll learn to speak.
The other thing I would say too is that
it might be anxiety that's do you might
think about joining a club like
toastmasters or maybe if you're a
university student to public speaking,
uh,
something where you'd get in front of
people and then when you're in front of
people,
don't talk to the group,
talked to the individuals within the
group and let yourself be bad at it.
You'll get better as you practice.
What is your plan if Youtube deletes
your account?
Alright.
Cause as much trouble as I possibly
could.
And um,
I don't think they will.
I do have it.
I do have most of my videos on Vimeo,
I think I haven't had,
I did try to do that.
I set up an automated service to
duplicate them.
I've never checked to see if it worked,
which is probably stupid,
but I've been so overwhelmed with,
with this,
with,
with this surreal position that I found
myself in that I haven't been able to be
sufficiently diligent.
So,
um,
how to be less afraid of death.
I have a better suggestion.
You should be more afraid of not living
properly.
I don't know if you can be less afraid
of death.
Exactly.
But I think that here's a hypothesis,
and this is a socratic hypothesis.
I write about this in my book too,
by the way.
Um,
maybe if you live your life thoroughly,
thoroughly,
right?
You take use of the advantage is make
use of the advantages that are put in
front of you.
Make use of your talents.
Say Yes to things.
Tell the truth like stand and get out
it.
I'm assuming that you can do that,
you know,
because some people are very ill and,
and hurt.
But assuming you can do that,
I think the only way to combat fear of
death is to live fully.
And I think that that might actually
work.
I kind of wonder,
I've talked about this with my father
too.
He was getting pretty old.
You know,
I've asked him if,
for example,
if he could be transformed back into an
18 year old,
knowing what he knows now,
would he do it?
And he was ambivalent about that,
you know,
he didn't say no,
but he didn't say yes.
And we talked about this idea that if
you lived your life fully,
you know,
maybe that would be good enough because,
I loved having kids,
but I don't feel that I would have kids
again,
you know,
because in some sense I've already done
that.
And so maybe there's a set number of
adventures that you have to go on in
your life.
Let's say you have to be married,
you have to have kids,
you have to have a career,
you have to have friends,
you have to have something useful to do
with your time outside of work.
Those are all things that are covered in
the future authoring program.
By the way,
maybe if you do all those,
it's like,
that's good enough.
You've had your life.
And,
and that's enough.
I mean,
I don't know,
10 years ago I thought,
you know,
if I could extend my life radically,
then I would.
And I'm not so sure about that.
Now that I'm,
I'm 55,
you know,
I'm getting older.
I kind of have a suspicion that you
might come to an end,
you know,
that's what it looks like.
I mean,
I don't want that to be sued,
but
maybe you exhaust yourself in your life,
you know,
maybe you can so that there's nothing
left of view really.
It's a good goal anyways.
So.
Okay,
let's find out.
Let's go back to this other
Dr Peterson.
I have an interview for medicine coming
up very soon.
It's structured in the I format and it's
intensely competitive.
Any tips on how to stand out from the
rest?
Well,
the only thing I can say is that
two things.
One is really pay attention to the
interviewers,
right?
Super attention,
like don't glare at them like you're
aggressively paranoid,
but like make sure you're focused on
them.
And then the other thing I would say is
say what you really think,
like tell the truth.
It'll make you,
first of all,
if you tell the truth and it doesn't
work,
then you know,
maybe that's not the school for you.
That's something to really think about.
Um,
and if it doesn't work anywhere and you
tell the truth,
maybe medicine isn't for you,
and I know that might be a terrible
shock,
but let's assume that you are genuinely
properly motivated to study medicine.
Then tell them what you think.
You know so many people when they go
into an interview,
try and they do this when they write
essays too,
is try to tell the interviewers what you
think they want to hear it,
but you can bloody well be sure that
virtually everybody who's being
interviewed is going to do that.
And I don't think that's very advisable
because if you don't manifest yourself
the way you are,
then there's no way that the path that's
proper for you can reveal itself.
I know that sounds sort of mystical,
but I don't know how to put it any
better.
The best way to stand out in an
interview always assuming you're
competent and that you've done the
preparation,
you know and that you're not living a
lie is to actually say what you think.
And hopefully what will happen is that
there will be other people on the panel
that's,
that are looking at you,
who are of the same type and that would
characterize a good position for you,
a good place to be.
If there are people like that and
they'll know what you're doing and that
will that,
then they'll think you know that person,
you know they're there,
they'd be good.
There are straightforward,
they're honest,
they're,
they're tough.
They're,
they can say what they think.
And if there aren't people like that on
the panel,
then I would say you probably don't want
to go there anyways.
So that's what I would.
That's what I would do.
Be True to yourself,
you know,
but that also assumes that you've done
your homework and that you're prepared
and all of that.
Because if you're useless jackass and
you're yourself,
obviously that is going to work.
So good luck.
Good luck with your interview.
But I always think that like you,
the other thing too is don't treat the
interviewers as enemies.
You know,
if that's hard because if you're kind of
petrified about the potential outcome
and you feel intense judgment,
then you're likely to go in there and
kind of afraid and nervous and and and
maybe even resentful.
It's like
you've already done enough so that
you're going to get interviewed.
So in some sense the interviewers are
hoping that you'll be great already.
You know,
there might be the odd cynic in there
who's trying to figure out a reason to
give you an x and and check you off the
list,
but most of the people sitting there,
if they have a clue,
are going to be looking for good
candidates and they're going to assume
that you're.
You've hit threshold and so it's not
like they're not on your side.
And so that's a good thing to keep in
mind too.
You're not going in there to,
to face a panel of enemies,
you're going in there to face a panel of
the sort of people that you're likely to
be in 10 years.
So that's another thing that's really
useful to keep in mind with interviews
in general.
I would say so.
Okay.
Many of my friends seeing the wonders of
diversity,
I try to tell them diversity isn't a
moral good,
but I ended up looking like some
terrible racist.
Why isn't diversity a moral good?
Well,
diversity is a moral good,
but you can't.
Diversity by race doesn't produce
diversity.
That's,
that's called racism.
That idea or diversity of gender doesn't
produce diversity unless that's how you
define diversity.
Look,
let's say that you get diversity partly
as a consequence of personality,
which is a good way of looking at it.
There is more diversity within groups of
people then between,
so like men and women differ to some
degree in their personalities,
but there's far more difference between
men within the male group and women
within the male group than there is
between the average or typical male and
female.
So it's a stupid wait.
Let's assume that what you want the
organization is pursuing your complex
goal and you want a variety of skills
that would be suited to that goal.
Then you want there to be enough
diversity of ability within the group so
that the goal can be achieved in a
efficient and,
and uh,
and inexpensive manner,
right?
Because what do you want?
Inefficient and expensive,
obviously not.
So there's a presumption that you get
diversity by using identity politics
categories,
but there's absolutely no evidence for
that whatsoever.
So that's why diversity defined by race
or ethnicity or gender is not only not a
moral good,
it's actually a moral evil because it
dispenses with the whole idea of the
individual dispenses,
with the idea of competence.
It just replaces it with the assumption
that if you randomly select from the
population,
because that's how you would get real
equity,
you randomly select from the population
that that gives you the best qualified
group of people.
Well that's just that.
You wouldn't do that to select the
plumber.
It's the stupidest possible way of
selecting for anything randomly,
you know,
there's no difference between selecting
randomly and selecting accidentally.
So it's moral diversity defined properly
is a moral good.
Diversity based on identity politics.
Categories is a positive evil,
you know,
true to our.
Our prime minister's great example of
that,
so back,
I think it was in 2015,
he announced that half of his cabinet
was going to be women because it was
2015 or some like muddle headed virtue
signaling,
signaling excuse for not thinking.
I think only 20 percent or 25 percent of
the elected mps were female.
So the proper balance on average would
it be 25 percent female,
75 percent male.
What he should've done was figured out
who,
what qualities would make for a
competent cabinet minister because it's
actually quite important to have
competent cabinet ministers and then
selected from among his people for
nothing other than competence,
but he could virtue signal and then he
set up the most important board,
let's say,
of the entire comp country on a random
basis.
Jesus,
how pathetic.
He should've been pilloried by Canadians
for that.
But we're so clued out and also in this
situation that you described is like if
I say,
well,
50 percent of Trudeau's cabinet
shouldn't have been women.
It's like,
oh,
you're a misogynist.
It's like,
no,
only 25 percent of the elected officials
were women.
Now you might say,
well,
it would be better if 50 percent of the
were elected.
It's like maybe it would be better,
but it didn't happen,
so you can't.
You can't fix it at the top end.
It was appalling.
So it's a hard argument to make because
you need to know that there's more
difference within groups then between
them in order to be able to come up with
a credible argument,
you know,
and then so yeah.
Yeah.
How does one distinguish a statement
coming from oneself rather than from
ideology?
Hey,
I got a good hint about that.
If you're saying something that almost
anyone else could say,
then it's likely to be either cliched or
ideological.
Where as if you're speaking from
yourself,
then in some sense you're the only
person who could be saying that,
and so what that means in some senses
that you've taken ideas,
philosophical,
even in theological,
and you've made them personal so that
you're speaking from a position that
only you can speak from,
and then then you have something
original to offer in Solzhenitsyn's
Gulag archipelago.
He talked about the like radical
communists who were thrown into the
Gulag and they used to play comrade with
them.
It was a game.
And what they would do is bait them into
making continual propagandistic
communists statements.
It was an attempt to try to educate them
out of their possession,
but it's a good.
See if you can predict what someone is
going to say on the basis of their set
of beliefs,
then they're not speaking.
The ideology is speaking.
And if the ideology is speaking,
you don't even have to listen to them.
You could just read about the ideology
and make up your own mind now.
So that's,
that's sort of the,
um,
what would you call it?
That's the objective view of this.
The subject of view is that statements
come from yourself that come from
yourself.
I think first of all,
frightened you to some degree because
you actually open yourself up to the
world by saying something genuine,
but they also make you stronger.
They make you feel stronger put because
I think you're confronting your
vulnerability properly,
you know,
because if I tell you something that I
really don't believe and you criticize,
it's like who cares?
Because I don't really believe,
believe it anyways,
so maybe I have an ideology that's like
a mask or a persona,
which is generally the case personas,
a youngin concept that means mask and
it's often the thing that people confuse
with their real identity.
Well,
if I have a persona and someone
criticizes it,
it's like,
well,
you haven't got to the real meat,
but if I say something that I really
believe deeply believe and then it gets
criticized like I've really put myself
on the line,
and so people don't do that.
It's kind of frightening,
but it's.
It's still the way to genuine strength
because you need.
And also not just strength but also
value.
You need to manifest yourself in the
world because you're a unique thing and
people bite need what's unique about
you?
Everybody else might really need that.
I believe that you don't because each
person has something that's unique to
them to bring into being and if they
hide that they hide their light under a
Bushel,
that everyone is poorer for it and you
do that in part as social units and says
by turning in,
you're turning over your God given sole
to human dogma.
It's a very bad idea.
Very bad idea.
So okay,
let's see what else we've got here.
What time is it?
Two 21.
Someone said,
daddy read for us.
Yeah,
no problem man.
I'm going to do it.
David Maxwell.
I scored the zero percentile for
conscientiousness and the 84th for
neuroticism.
How do I improve these scores?
Well,
okay,
so the first thing David you might want
to think about is like if all of your
scores were low,
then there's some possibility that
you're being too hard on yourself.
And what I would recommend Danny's,
get a couple of friends to fill out the
questionnaire for,
for you to describe you and then see if,
first of all,
if there's any agreement,
see if they've,
they are easier on you than you are
yourself.
So,
but let's assume that you are rather low
in conscientiousness.
The next question would be,
well,
how young are you?
Because younger people tend to be
lowered conscientiousness.
So if you're like 16,
well that's low,
but it's not catastrophic.
If you're 40 and you're not depressed
and zero is,
you know,
that's low
anyways.
If you are that low in
conscientiousness,
one of the things I would recommend is
a,
make a plan and be learn how to use a
schedule a calendar and do it badly to
begin with,
like electronic calendar,
like Google calendar.
That's the best thing I know of to
improve conscientious,
make a plan so that you've got something
to aim at and um,
use a scheduler and maybe you have to,
you know,
talk to someone to help keep you on
track.
Now the other question would be do you
have other personality traits that are
really high,
like openness,
because if you're really high in
openness,
then it might be that you're more
inclined towards being motivated by
spontaneous interest and in the artistic
direction and if you're really high in
extroversion,
then you could be motivated by being
around people.
So it also may be that in order to be
conscientious about something,
you have to pick a domain that you're
suited to like socializing or artistic
endeavor and try to work on being
conscientious in those domains.
So that's it.
So
James Montgomery says,
how can you be confident and courageous
if your father was emotionally absent
and narcissistic?
I'm 21 and very creative.
My mother is a people pleaser who isn't
confident in herself and uses me as
emotional support.
Help.
Well,
look,
you're confident about some things.
You said you were very creative.
So you're confident enough to say that.
And you know
I don't see the problem with questions
like this.
I'm not criticizing your question by the
way,
is that you're linking your lack of
confidence and courage to the absence of
your father and his narcissism and also
associating it with your mother being a
people pleaser.
So,
and you know,
there may be something to that.
It could be James,
that you could,
could stand to talk to somebody you know
for awhile on a regular basis and see if
they can help you sort this out.
You obviously seem to think that this is
a problem with you moving forward in
your life.
If you don't want to talk to someone
about it,
then I would say the other thing,
you need a plan.
I knew that.
I always refer to that,
but it's the case.
You need a plan and then you need to
break the plan down into this,
into small steps that are somewhat
challenging that you have a high
probability of nonetheless obtaining.
And then I would say by observing
yourself move forward properly that your
confidence will increase.
You're only 21,
you know,
so you're not that old.
But,
um,
that's the best I can do without having
more information about the specifics of
your situation.
Can't increase your Iq in any
significant way.
Eat healthy,
do the right thing.
Best potential.
Well,
one of the things you could do if not to
increase it,
is at least to maintain it,
is that because your Iq tends to decline
as you age.
It's quite depressing.
You read the relevant literature,
uh,
your crystallized Iq,
which is an indication of your
accumulated knowledge doesn't decline
in.
Sometimes it even increases,
you know,
unless you get dementia or something
like that.
But your fluid Iq,
which is more like the program or of the
brain declines a lot.
The best way to deal with that is to
exercise both aerobic and weight lifting
can really stave off cognitive decline.
And that's because your brain is a very
car.
It's very demanding.
It has a very demanding set of
cardiovascular requirements.
And so if your cardiovascular system is
in good shape,
then your brain is healthier.
And since,
at least in principle,
your Iq depends on your brain than
having a healthy brain is really a good
idea.
So
Jerry Newton says,
I often don't do very well,
don't very well and doubt my ability to
stand up for myself and discussions and
aggressive situations.
Hi.
Do I know when I've incorporated my
shadow?
I guess I would say,
Jerry,
that practice makes perfect.
You know,
one thing you could do is start keeping
track of situations like that.
You know,
where you you walk away thinking that
you should have said something and so
then I would say write down the
situation and then think through and
write down what you think you should
have done and that because that's going
to help you be sharper on the draw and
more ready when and then so.
So write down the situation,
write down what you think you should
have done.
Then sit and imagine the situation as
vividly as you can,
right?
Get the pictures in your head and
imagine yourself doing that and,
and try to get the psychophysiological
response is up as well so that you make
it as realistic as possible and that
will actually help you practice.
So Edna Foa,
who,
who's a very good clinical psychologist,
has demonstrated quite clearly that when
treating post traumatic stress disorder,
for example,
if you get people to sit and imagined
being back in this stressful situation,
they have to do that voluntarily and
after at least 18 months after the
trauma had that she did
psychophysiological recording of heart
rate and skin conductance and that kind
of thing.
She showed that the people who showed
the highest levels of stress reactivity
to the reimagining were the ones who got
better,
fastest,
and stayed better longest.
So you have a situation that you know
you haven't mastered,
define the situation repeatedly.
Define your proper action repeatedly.
Practice implementing that in your
imagination,
and then start,
do that in your real life.
And that'll,
that'll,
uh,
see if you write down what you should've
said.
You'll find out what you really want and
what you really think.
And that's,
that'll be your shadow talking it,
dude.
That's the best way to think about it.
Is that the part of your brain that
wishes it would have done something
different is the shadow associated with
the aggression.
Who's integration would strengthen your
character?
That's,
that's a very good way of,
of thinking about it.
So
Matt says,
Oh,
this is an.
Okay.
Oh,
Matt says I need to ask you something.
Can you please release your new book as
an audiobook as well in your own voice?
Yes,
I'm doing that.
I'm starting to record it on Monday.
Um,
I'm kind of surprised that people want
me to record it in my own voice,
which is kind of scratchy at the moment,
but I'm looking forward to it.
I've been practicing reading it with my
wife,
puts her to sleep at night.
Hopefully that's not because of the
book.
She does get quite tired at night.
So I'm.
Let's see here.
Would you ever consider having a
dialogue with legitimate Muslim scholar?
Yes,
absolutely.
And I know a number of them and I'm
hoping that I'll get to that.
Uh,
it's a big thing to take on,
you know,
and I'm trying to deal with this
biblical lecture series and with,
well all the other things that I'm
involved in,
including starting to lay the groundwork
for this online university,
which is which,
and I've started looking for an office
where a team could work on that and
we've sketched out some of the ideas.
We're gonna use competitive writing
exercises to help teach people to write,
which I think would really be fun.
So one idea is,
um,
so imagine,
remember this is just the outline of
idea.
Imagine we present you with a paragraph
that someone else wrote and then you
have the opportunity to do a better job
of writing it and then people get the
opportunity to vote on who's is better.
You could see that the paragraphs could
compete and that you could get a
academic points based on the quality of
your writing.
Um,
anyways,
uh,
that's all to say,
especially also with this book coming
out is that I'm going to be very
occupied and I want to start a dialogue
with legitimate Muslim scholars because
I would also like to learn more about
Islam.
So hopefully that'll happen in the,
uh,
in the relatively near future.
So
Jake says,
I've been incredibly inspired by you.
Love what you do and would like to
enlightened people in a similar manner,
be careful what you wish for it is,
is appropriate to aim to have as much as
an impact as you or more so.
Um,
I think it's the idea formulated wrong
in some sense.
I think,
I mean,
it's good to have people that you
admire,
let's say who can serve as models and
I'm not claiming that I'm necessarily in
that category,
but it's good to have people like that.
But what you want to figure out to do,
to do,
to do is how to manifest the ideal
within the confines of your own life,
right?
Because you're a particular sort of
person and so the way that you're going
to live your life best,
it's very unlikely that it would be
associated in any important way with the
way that I've chosen to live my life
unless we have very similar
temperaments,
which is possible,
but you know,
relatively unlikely
because the odds against that are,
you know,
extraordinarily high.
The odds of any two people having the
same temperament are very,
are very high.
So what you can do is aim to,
to Orient yourself towards high good
that you can conceive up to discipline
yourself to tell the truth and all of
that.
And then what I would say is that as
your life unfolds,
you'll have the amount of influence that
you should have.
Whatever that happens to be.
You know,
some people live pretty local lives.
Like my life for example,
is much more public than my wife's life.
But that doesn't mean that her
contribution is somehow lesser.
I mean,
she's been unbelievably good with our
kids.
My daughter was very ill and my wife was
extraordinarily good with her and was a
great mother and has been a tremendous
help to me as a very honest person and a
wise person and you know,
that all has an impact.
It's just not as obvious because while
the kids really love her and now she's
got grandkids and God only knows what
the consequences of that is going to be
across successive generations and you
know,
she isn't interested in public life.
I'm a journalist too vast to interviewer
like quite recently about what the last
year has been.
Liking her preferences to not do that
and that's fine.
Like she has her own destiny and her own
way of being in the world and there's
nothing to say that it's lesser in any
sense of the word at all.
So should artists wastes their time in
art school?
No.
You shouldn't waste your time ever.
I think your question is,
is it necessarily a waste of time to go
to art school?
And I would say it depends very much on
the art school and are on what you do
while you're there.
Um,
if you go to art school and you really
work at it like mad and you devote
yourself to it and you're in the library
and you're studying the great masters
and you're crafting your technique and
you're at a school where that's actually
possible,
then you can educate and going to art
school can give you an identity that
allows you to investigate that
possibility free from undue social
pressure for some period of time,
which is really the case with an arts
degree or something like that as well.
So if you can take advantage of it,
if you're disciplined enough and if you
can find a school that isn't completely
appallingly postmodern and and social
justice oriented instead of oriented
towards art and I don't think it has to
be a waste of time,
but I think there's a high probability
that it will.
So
serious.
Respectful question.
Why did you have a problem with Lindsay
Shepherd being criticized for being non
critical but you criticized faith Goldie
for being non critical?
Well,
the fundamental issue.
I really listened carefully to faith's
interview,
the interview that was conducted I think
with the daily stormer.
I really listened to it and I sat down
and listened to it with my son whose
judgment I respect a lot and
the thing that differentiates the two is
that faith is a journalist and my sense
was that
in this situation that she found
herself,
it was incumbent on her as a journalist
to ask at least one or two probing
questions given the nature of the people
that know nature and the fact that she
knew the nature of the people that she
was talking to and I don't feel that she
did it and you know,
I was obviously not alone in my
assessment of that.
So her employer who was very favorably
predisposed towards her also let her go
as a consequence of that.
And so I know that and I've been accused
of being hypocritical as a consequence.
And I should also say that the decision
to restructure the panel wasn't mine
alone.
It was actually while it was divided up
amongst the panel members essentially.
But
that's what we decided.
That's what we decided and you know,
faith herself had offered to bow out of
the panel because she knew that her
presence would be controversial in a way
that might not be productive.
So whereas Lindsey was just a student,
you know,
and,
and she was doing what she was supposed
to do.
Now I'm not trying to denigrate faith as
a journalist in it.
Some general sense,
but
you know,
Charlottesville was very touchy and,
and it was,
and it required an unbelievably deft
hand to go into that sort of rats nest
and come out unscathed and you know,
maybe we should think Kudos for her to
her for having the courage to even
attempt it.
But there's a difference between,
it's not that easy to distinguish
between brave and foolhardy and you know
what they say?
Well
anyways,
like I said,
we thought about it a lot.
I listened to it a lot.
We made the decision we made.
I'm not trying to say that,
you know,
it was right in some omniscient sense,
but I don't think that the situation
that Lindsay shepherd found herself in
is sufficiently comparable to that of
faith to make the question,
to make the comparison fundamentally
valid.
So Ethan,
beyond,
she says,
I'm a liberal.
Hi.
Hey Ethan.
Um,
you know,
I've considered myself a liberal for a
very long time.
So a welcome.
Do you think I publicly disassociate
yourself enough with my neo Nazi
followers that,
that use your work as justification for
violence and propaganda.
Well,
you know,
what kind of question is that?
First of all,
you're,
you're making the unwarranted assumption
that I definitely have neo Nazi
followers,
you know,
and that they use my work as a
justification and that they're engaged
in violence and propaganda.
It's like how about a specific example
or,
or how about 10 specific examples?
You know,
I already pointed out that,
imagine that.
So 30 million people have watched my
videos,
so let's add 500,000 of them are youtube
subscribers.
So let's say I have 500,000 followers
just for the sake of argument.
Okay.
Like a thousand of them are going to be
completely out of their minds because
that's one in 500.
So what does that proof,
you know,
you'd have to demonstrate that there's a
higher rate than average of pathology
among the people who claim in some
manner to be my followers.
You know,
you have to do that because as I said,
everyone who's to the right of the
radical left is a group and in that
group that was going to be people on the
far right.
That doesn't mean everyone in the group
of non radical leftists is a radical
right winger,
obviously.
So anyways,
you know,
I don't.
I think that that's a loaded question.
I think it's loaded in a bunch of ways.
Do you think you publicly dissociate
yourself enough?
Well,
that's a loaded question because the
implication is that I don't publicly
dissociate myself enough.
Then the next implication is that I have
more neo Nazi followers than a random
person with 500,000 followers would
have.
And then the next like loaded bit is
that they use my work as justification.
I'd like to see that happen because I
can't see it,
how it can possibly be used as
justification and that they use it as a
justification for both propaganda and
violence.
It's like really?
Come on.
Yeah,
you know,
maybe it's possible.
And if this is the case,
I apologize.
It's possible that you wrote that
question because you were favorably
disposed towards me and you know,
wanted to give me an opportunity to
address that question and you know,
I can't tell but,
but it is definitely the kind of
question that,
that sort of journalists who have been
coming after me have been,
you know,
it's like,
have you stopped beating your wife yet?
It's like,
how are you going to answer a question
like that?
You losing their way.
So.
Okay.
Well I think what I'm going to do,
I'm starting to run out of energy here,
so I'm going to read some of this.
Okay.
All right.
What the hell addressed the Jewish
question?
That's a hell of a thing to ask.
So that's Jack Linter,
you know,
I mean really that's a hell of a thing
to ask,
but I will say something about it,
you know,
and I've thought about this a lot.
So there is evidence that Ashkenazi
Jews,
so those are the Jews of European
heritage,
have iqs that are about 15 points higher
than the population average.
So that's a lot 15 points.
It's about the average difference
between the typical high school student
and the typical state college student.
It's a lot.
And one of the things that means is,
so imagine there's two distributions and
that they overlap and that the Jewish
one is,
uh,
is the mean is 1:15.
So the whole distribution is shifted to
the right.
What that means is if you go up into the
Higher Iq strata,
1:30,
1:45 way the hell up there,
that Jewish people are overwhelmingly
overrepresented at the high end of the
ICU distribution.
Now the price they paid for that is some
increased propensity for neurological
diseases that seems to be associated in
some sense with that heightened Iq.
Now,
you know,
the science on this isn't settled but,
but it,
it's reasonably solid.
It all given the standards of such
things.
Okay,
so Jews are going to be over represented
at the high end of cognitively complex
disciplines.
So then I would say,
and that's the case,
like they're way over represented among
outstanding scientists and among Nobel
Prize winners and and so forth.
And so you know,
people look and they think,
well why are there a disproportionate
number of Jewish people in positions of
authority?
And they say,
well,
it must be a conspiracy.
You know,
it must be systemic in some sense.
It's like,
no,
it can be simply accounted for by that
relatively large ICU differential.
Now the next criticism would be,
well,
don't the Jews tend to lean left?
Well first you might say,
well,
you know,
given what happened in Nazi Germany to
the degree that that was right wing as
we discussed earlier,
that's the nationalism and
ethnocentrism.
It's hardly surprising that they might,
you know,
in this historical period of time tend
to move towards the left.
But more than that,
Iq is associated with trait,
openness and trade.
Openness is a strong predictor predictor
of political liberalism.
So,
and it's the strongest predictor of
political liberalism.
So,
you know,
it's very difficult.
So that's what I have to say about that.
It's like.
And the other thing I would say is,
you know,
the fact that there's a population of
sub population of people who are much
smarter than average,
not on average,
right?
On average,
I've got to get that straight on average
is actually of great benefit to the rest
of us because why do you want fewer
geniuses?
Fewer people with Iq of 145 or 160.
That's and you know,
and it's no conspiracy that puts people
who are smarter,
higher up in competence hierarchies
because I accused the best predictor of
movement up in a complex con competence
hierarchy.
So there,
I've addressed the Jewish question.
It's like it's a confusion between
ethnicity and and ICU as far as I'm
concerned.
So I'll probably get like painted six
different shades of black for that
answer.
But it's,
I've thought about a long time.
It's the best that I can manage.
So.
Okay,
I'm going to read this.
Oh,
what huckleberry says,
should I start with past author three?
If I am 40,
I feel that I have so many unsolved
issues from my past that prevents me
from accomplishing my potential from
accomplishing my potential.
Mostly fear.
Yes.
They,
the way that you wrote that indicates
very clearly that you should do the past
authoring first because you already know
that you have unpleasant incidences or
incidents in your past that are
impairing your function.
So.
Alright,
so I'm gonna read.
I'm gonna.
Read this.
Hopefully you can see that there's an
illustration there.
Um,
I'm going to hold it up so that I can
see it.
There's a lag.
So I don't know if it's in focus.
So give me about 10 seconds.
Okay.
So this is chapter four rule for.
So the book has 12 rules in the book is
called 12 rules for life
and it's published by penguin random
house and it'll be out January 23rd.
And so this is a book,
this is chapter rule six.
Um,
there's 12 rules,
pence,
the title,
and they were taken from a subset of 42
rules that I wrote for a quora article
called what are the most important
things that everyone should know,
something like that.
A very popular cora
article.
Now,
the illustration was done by Ethan van
skiver,
who's a comic book artist and a good
one.
So you can look up his work if you want.
It's v a n,
s,
C I v e r Ethan.
This chapter is about the motivation
behind the actions of people like to
call them by and killers.
And the illustration is of a very,
very criminally oriented individual
called named Carl Pans Ram.
You could look him up,
p a n Zed r a,
m who was a very resentful,
vicious,
violent,
destructive and intelligent person
because those things can all go
together.
So rule six is called set your house in
perfect order before you criticize the
world.
And the chapters all have little sub
chapter.
So the title of this chapter is a
religious problem.
It does not seem reasonable to describe
the young man who shot 20 children and
six staff members at Sandy Hook
Elementary School in Newton,
Connecticut in 2012 as a religious
person.
This is equally true for the Colorado
theater gunman and the columbine high
school killers,
but these murderous individuals had a
problem with reality that existed at a
religious depth.
As one of the members of the columbine
duo wrote,
the human race isn't worth fighting for
only worth killing.
Give the earth back to the animals.
They deserve it infinitely more than we
do.
Nothing means anything anymore.
People who viewed people who think such
things,
view being itself is inequitable and
harsh to the point of corruption and
human being in particular as
contemptible.
They appoint themselves supreme
adjudicators of reality and find it
wanting.
They're the ultimate critics.
The deeply cynical writer continues.
If you recall your history,
the Nazis came up with a quote,
final solution and quote to the Jewish
problem,
kill them all.
Well,
in case you haven't figured it out,
I say kill mankind.
No one should survive.
For such individuals,
the world of experiences insufficient
and evil,
so to hell with everything.
What is happening when someone comes to
thinking in this manner,
a great German play,
foust a tragedy written by your hand.
Wolfgang von Gurta addresses that issue.
The plays main character,
a scholar named Heinrich Faust trades
his immortal soul to the devil
Mephistopheles.
In return,
he receives whatever he desires while
still alive on earth and this play,
Mephistopheles is the eternal adversary
of being.
He has a central defining credo.
I am the spirit who negates and rightly
so for all that comes to be,
deserves to perish wretchedly.
We're better.
Nothing would begin.
Does everything that you term sin,
destruction and evil represent.
That's my proper element.
Dirt.
The considered this hateful sentiment,
so important,
so key to the central element of
vengeful human destructiveness that he
add.
Mephistopheles repeated a second time
phrase somewhat differently in part two
of the play written many years later,
people think often in the memphis to and
manner,
although they sell them,
act upon their thoughts as brutally as
the mass murderers of school,
college and theater.
Whenever we experienced injustice real
or imagined,
whenever we encountered tragedy or fall
prey to the machinations of others,
whenever we experienced the horror and
pain of our own apparently arbitrary
limitations,
the temptation to question being and
then to curse it rises Fowley from the
darkness.
Why must innocent people suffer so
terribly?
What kind of bloody horrible places this
anyways?
Life is in truth,
very hard.
Everyone is destined for pain and slated
for destruction.
Sometimes suffering is clearly the
result of personal faults such as
willful blindness,
poor decision making or malevolence.
In such cases when it appears to be self
inflicted,
it may even seem just people get what
they deserve.
You might contend that's cold comfort.
However,
even when true sometimes if those are
suffering,
change their behavior,
then their lives would unfold less
tragically,
but human control is limited.
Susceptibility to despair,
disease,
aging and death is universal.
In the final analysis,
we do not appear to be the architects of
our own fragility.
Whose fault is it?
Then?
People who are very will ill or worse,
who have a sick child,
will inevitably find themselves asking
this question whether they are religious
believers are not.
The same is true of someone who finds
his shirt sleeve caught in the gears of
a giant bureaucracy who is suffering
through a tax audit or fighting and
interminable lawsuit or divorce,
and it's not only the obviously
suffering who are tormented by the need
to blame someone or something for the
intolerable state of their being
at the very height of his fame,
influence and creative power.
For example,
the towering Leo.
Tolstoy began to question the value of
human existence.
He reasoned in this way.
My position was terrible.
I knew that I could find nothing in the
way of rational knowledge,
denial of life,
and in faith I could find nothing except
it did not have reason and this was even
more impossible than it denial of life.
According to rational knowledge.
It followed that life is evil.
People know it.
They do not have to live yet.
They have lived and they do live.
Just as I myself have lived,
even though I had known for a long time
that life is meaningless and evil
tracy might told story,
could only identify for means of
escaping from such thoughts.
One was retreating into child like
ignorance of the problem.
Another was pursuing mindless pleasure.
The third was continuing to drag out a
life that is evil and meaningless.
Knowing beforehand that nothing can come
of it.
He identified that particular form of
escape with weakness.
The people in this category know that
death is better than life,
but they do not have the strength to act
rationally and quickly put it into the
delusion by killing themselves.
Only.
The fourth and final mode of escape
involved open quote,
strength and energy.
It consists of destroying life.
Once one has realized that life is evil
and meaningless,
close quote,
tall story relentlessly followed his
thoughts,
only unusually strong and logically
consistent.
People act in this manner.
Having realized all the stupidity of the
joke that is being played on us and
seeing that the blessings of the dead
are greater than those of the living and
that it is better not to exist.
They act and put it into this stupid
joke.
They use any means of doing it.
A rope around the neck,
water,
a knife in the heart.
A train
toy story wasn't pessimistic enough.
The stupidity of the joke being played
in us does not merely motivate suicide.
Good motivates murder.
Mass murder often followed by suicide.
Now it's a far more effective
existential protest by June of 2016.
Unbelievable as it may seem,
there had been 1000.
Mass killings defined is far more people
shot into a single incident excluding
the shooter in the US and 1,260 days.
That's one such event on five of every
six days for more than three years.
Everyone says,
we don't understand.
How can we still pretend that tall story
understood more than a century ago.
The ancient authors of the Biblical
story of Cain and Abel understood as
well.
More than 20 centuries ago,
they described murder as the first act
of post identic history and not just
murder,
but fratricidal murder and murder.
Not only if someone innocent,
but if someone ideal and good and
murdered unconsciously despite the
creator of the universe.
Today's killers tell us the same thing
in their own words,
who would dare say that this is not the
worm at the core of the apple,
but we will not listen because the truth
cuts too close to the bone even for a
minute,
as profound as that of the celebrated
Russian author,
there was no way out.
How can the rest of us manage when
amount of tolstoy stature admits defeat
for years,
he hit his guns from himself and would
not walk with a rope in his hand in case
he hanged himself.
How can a person who is awake avoid
outrage at the world?
The next sub chapters called vengeance
or transformation well,
and the rest of the trap chapter
attempts to answer the questions that I
posed in that beginning and hopefully
I've managed it at least in some small
way anyways.
Now it's a bit from one chapter of this
book,
12 rules for life,
an antidote to chaos.
It comes out January 23rd.
It's available for preorder.
For those of you who might be interested
on Amazon.com and Amazon.ca,
and it's quite heavily discounted at the
moment.
I think it's 50 percent off on the
Canadian site,
35 percent off on the American site.
Um,
maybe I'll put a link in the
description.
Um,
I hope that the book is helpful.
I,
I put a lot of work into it and I think
it's advanced my thinking quite a bit
and,
and I think it's readable.
I've a lot of people have looked at it
now and I've had good editors and so on
and I think that I tried to make it as
accessible as possible.
I mean it deals with ideas that are
pretty sophisticated,
but um,
I'm hoping I got the balance between
complexity and sophistication and ease
of access.
Right.
Tight.
I certainly hope so.
And I hope it's kind of poetic,
you know,
because I tried to make each sentence
scan properly and have a rhythm and all
of that.
Anyways,
um,
my wife has made thanksgiving,
it's not Canadian thanksgiving,
American thanksgiving,
but we celebrate both of them because my
son is American and we lived in the
states for quite a few years.
So I'm going to go and see my grandkids
and my son and my daughter and all the
other people that are around me.
Thank God.
And um,
thanks for listening guys and for being
interested in.
I hope you get your acts together and
fix up the world a
till next time.
Bye.