Neat.
You talking about the European state of
mind at the end of the 19th century.
So Nisha says,
well we're in this terrible situation,
right?
God is dead.
We've killed them.
What does that mean?
While we've taken our evolved
metaphysics,
which structures are moral viewpoint and
undermined by rational criticism,
a peculiar move,
Toma softly cause it was never
established on rational grounds.
Anyways,
we've undermined it rationally and
replaced it with well nothing,
nothing.
What's the consequences that,
well he outlines that here of what is
great.
One must either be silent or speak with
greatness and you can think about this
as a prophecy on the events of World War
One and World War II and the Gulag
archipelago and the 60 million people
dead in the Soviet Union and the whole
unfolding of 20th century history and
the great ideological battles that
characterize that unfolding.
So this is something nature sees coming
and knows was why he says of what is
great.
One must either be silent or speak with
greatness,
with greatness.
So that means cynically I'm with
innocence.
What I related to the history of the
next two centuries.
I describe what is coming,
what can no longer come differently?
The advent of nihilism,
right?
The belief and nothing.
Our whole European culture is moving for
some time now with a tortured tension
that's growing from decade to decade,
I was towards a catastrophe restlessly
violently headlong like a river that
wants to reach the end that no longer
reflects.
It's afraid to reflect.
He that speaks here has conversely done
nothing so far,
but to reflect as a philosopher and
solitary by instinct who is found his
advantage and standing aside outside.
Why is the advent of nihilism become
necessary?
Because the values we've had hitherto
thus draw their final consequence
because nihilism represents the ultimate
logical conclusion of our great values
and ideals.
Because we must experience nihilism
before we can find out what value these
values really had.
We require at some sometime new values.
Nihilism stands at the door when it
comes this uncanny,
first of all,
guests nihilism,
right?
Your beliefs or undermined once.
What's the consequence of that?
Well,
one consequences.
The belief has undermined the other
consequences.
More metaphysical,
which is fooled once you no longer have
the belief.
But maybe it's even worse than that
because human beings can generalize,
fooled once you never have any,
you no longer have any belief in
beliefs,
which mean you say something like this,
I don't care what you think.
It doesn't matter what you think.
The world is such a terrible place that
no interpretation whatsoever can
possibly suffice.
That's nihilism.
No meaning system whatsoever can
possibly suffice.
Well,
what's the flaw or the flyers?
of course,
no system of coherent belief can suffice
because most of the world's
transcendent,
you can't encapsulate everything that is
in your sphere of belief.
And what you might say then is that if
you ever believe that what you believe
is what should support you,
the facts,
you know,
say,
or the interpretation you place in the
world,
then your faith is badly misplaced.
You don't believe in what you believe.
You believe in something that's deeper
than that.
And so then you see what's wrong with
Tolstoy,
right?
And tolstoy story.
And tolstoy says,
uh,
accounting for his collapse in the
stability of Christian belief.
He said,
this all happened,
this collapse of my belief when I was
not yet 50 years old,
I should have been considered a
completely happy man.
I had a good loving and beloved wife
find children and the largest state
growing and expanding without any effort
on my part.
I was respected by friends and
acquaintances,
praised by strangers and could claim a
certain renown.
I was not physically nor mentally
unhealthy.
On the contrary,
I enjoyed a physical and mental vigor.
I had rarely encountered among others my
age.
I could keep up with a peasant's working
in the fields and work eight and 10
hours at a stretch without suffering any
after effects from the stream and in
such a state of affairs.
I came to a point where I could not live
and even though I fear death,
I had to employ ruses against myself to
keep from committing suicide.
It was as though I had lived a little
wondered a little until I came to a
precipice and I clearly saw that there
was nothing ahead except room and there
was no stopping or turning back.
No closing my eyes so that I would not
see that there was nothing ahead except
the deception of life and of happiness
and of the reality of suffering and
death of complete annihilation.
I grew sick of life.
Some irresistible force was leading me
to somehow get rid of it.
This thought was such a temptation that
I had to use counting against myself in
order to not to go through with it.
And there I was,
a fortunate man carrying a rope from my
room where I was alone every night as I
addressed so that I would not hang
myself from the beam between the closets
and I quit going hunting with a gun so
that I would not be too easily tempted
to rid myself of life.
I myself did not know what I wanted.
It was afraid of life.
I struggled to get rid of it,
yet I hope for something from it.
My position was terrible.
I knew that I could find nothing in the
way of rational knowledge except denial
of life and in faith I could find
nothing except the denial of reason.
And for me this was even more impossible
than a denial of life.
I myself according to rational knowledge
at followed that life is evil and people
know it.
I describe my spiritual condition of
myself in this way.
Okay.
My life has some kind of stupid and evil
practical joke that someone is playing
on me in spite of the fact that I did
not acknowledge the existence of any
someone who might've created me.
The notion that someone brought me into
the world as a stupid and evil joke seem
to be the most natural way to describe
my condition.
Yeah.
I could not be deceived.
All is vanity.
Happy is he was never been born.
Death is better than life.
We must rid ourselves of life.
Having realized all the stupidity of the
joke that is being played on us and
seeing that the blessings of the dead
are greater than those are the living
and that it's better not to exist.
The strong act and put an end to this
stupid joke and they use any means of
doing it.
A rope around the neck,
water,
a knife in the heart or a train.
Now,
the interesting thing about this,
I think is first of all,
a Russian wrote it and second of all,
it was written in the late 19 hundreds
and even more particularly is that you
note that when the strong act using a
rope around the neck,
water,
a knife in the heart and a train,
well tolstoy is talking about suicide,
but there's no necessary reason to
presume that this should only be
violence and gender against the self,
right?
If life is a stupid and evil joke,
then what's stopping you from
benevolently putting an end to the
suffering of others,
right?
Benevolently in theory at least.
Well,
you know,
that's one perspective,
right?
But then there's always the perspective
of the lady who went to see the
psychiatrist in ts Elliot's poem,
which is,
well,
if when your eyes are open,
life appears as nothing but suffering
and pain to you.
It could be that that is how life is.
But it can also be that there's
something wrong with the way that you're
looking at the world.
And in some ways that's a much more
humble perspective,
right?
Because the alternative the as well,
I know what's going on and I just look
out there and there's the world and I'm
pretty much got it.
Like I know what it means and what it
means is pointless suffering and pain
and that's my model and I don't see any
reason to question it,
but then the alternative is,
well,
wait a second.
There's always the possibility that I
don't know absolutely everything and
this final and horrible judgment that
I'm placing on the conditions of
existence could conceivably be misplaced
given the sort of presumptuousness of
the claim.
Right.
I'm in a position to render final
judgment on the moral value of existence
as such.
It seems to me
reasonable to presume that that's not
the kind of statement that you should
easily make.
Can I remember when George Bush launched
his most recent war?
The initial terminology,
I think this was for the Afghanistan
battle was operation infinite justice,
but he retracted that phrase after a
number of religious leaders objected to.
It's kind of presumptuousness,
which I thought was quite reasonable
because infinite justice is something
that most people should probably not
hope for,
right?
Because you never know precisely what
infinite justice means because it might
just mean that every bloodied mistake
you've ever made,
you're going to pay for.
And I suppose that would be just as
applicable to George W.
Bush as it would to anybody else.
And then Milton again describes the
development of this adversarial spirit.
He says,
first pride,
pride,
and worse ambition threw me down.
That's Satan's lament when he's in hell.
And Milton's description of hell is
extremely interesting.
He said,
the reason that hell is characterized by
its structure is not so much because of
its nature.
Precisely.
It's because of its distance from the
good.
So the farther you are away say from
what constitutes the good,
the more suffering is the more suffering
is endemic to that state.
So it's,
it's the distance away from something
that constitutes the suffering.
And then Melton says,
it's very interesting to do an analysis
of Satan's character and the notion of
hell per say,
because how in the world can you
reconcile the idea of a good God with
the notion of this continual suffering?
And so Milton says,
well,
Satan can step out of hell in one
moment.
All he has to do is meant that he was
wrong.
And that's the one thing that he will
not do under any circumstances
whatsoever.
So then we put one more twist on the
story and we say something like this.
Okay,
we already know that part of the reason
that people have belief systems is so
that they can structure their
interactions with the world.
It's a toolbox.
Say we're playing a game,
we share the rules,
that's fine.
We can cooperate with one another.
It could be other than it is,
but it's the way it is and it works for
us.
That's fine.
There's nothing absolute about it except
that a structure like that's necessary.
Now whenever there's a threat to that
shared view of the world,
well then we're afraid and for good
reason.
And,
and it's not surprising under those
circumstances that we fight to defend
what we've made ours.
But then you say,
let's say you adopt this perspective,
right?
And it's this vengeful desire to wreak
havoc that extends beyond other
individuals and beyond society.
Even to the structure of experience as
such.
And then you think,
well,
what's the best mask for that?
And how do these two processes sort of
interact?
And you think,
well,
the most efficient way to do terrible
things is to mask them with the highest
order morality.
And that's precisely what the
totalitarian does.
So that way he gets to have his cake and
eat it too.
He's perfectly well protected from
apprehension of the world because his
belief system is complaint plus these
underground motivations,
which is this constant desire for
revenge,
can find their expression within the
totalitarian structure and remain
invisible even to himself.
So he can say to himself,
well,
the reason I threw all those farmers out
of their house in 1920 I'm stalled.
Their soup and their food and their
grandmothers blankets and everything
they'd work to own was because I was
building the socialist paradise.
Right.
And it was a good thing for me to go
into that house and not a bad thing.
And as long as he believes that or acts
as if he believes that,
then he can look in the mirror without
screaming.
And there's no recognition whatsoever of
precisely the sort of game that he's
involved in.
So he has it both ways,
right?
He can do everything terrible that he
always dreams of doing and consider
himself not only good but good,
even at a higher level then the people
that he was actually afflicting.
And of course,
that's just standard description of what
happened in the Soviet Union.
He just says,
I love this definition of morality is
the most cynical thing niche ever said.
I think
the idiosyncrasy of decadence with the
ulterior motive of revenging oneself
against life successfully,
I attach value to this definition said,
well,
why are you an idiot log?
Well,
it's a good way to simplify the world,
right?
It's a procrustean bed.
You just chop off everything that
doesn't fit,
then you don't have to think,
right?
So that's good because thinking is
difficult and it's trouble.
Someone,
it takes courage and so forth to
transform chaos into order is no trivial
matter.
And if it's all ordered for you,
well then there's really nothing left
for you to do.
But then need,
she goes even below that,
he says,
yeah,
well there's more to the story than
that,
isn't there?
It's like once he got this little
procrustean bed all arranged for your
enemies,
then you can,
you can allow your most base vengeful
instincts,
full flow by just continually chopping
people.
So they fit
and you do it all the while by well
saying,
wow,
it's obviously the best thing that could
possibly be done.
Okay.
And so then you look
at Stellan say,
because not everybody who's adopted a
vantage full tack on existence,
it's sort of like the archetype of
vengefulness or adversarial spirit.
But he had to get now and then the
people like stolen,
who are good counter example say to the
people like Gandhi and so stones,
very instructive.
And so we could start by looking at what
he did in the Ukraine.
So at the end of 1929 the Kremlin decree
that millions of peasants from
individually owned farms would be forced
into agricultural collectives or cold
causes seen in the eyes of the politburo
as pliant providers of Soviet
agricultural needs in defiance of the
facts.
So they did the Ologists,
hammered out inappropriate Marxist
terminology to explain what was going on
throughout grain producing areas.
It was sad.
Okay.
Resistance to this scientific scheme was
being by so called rich peasants are
cool acts with his customer of
brutality.
Therefore stellan decreed the
liquidation of the cooler acts as a
class we'll stand in like this idea of
like group guilt.
That was a major theme for Stalin that
man I really didn't have to ever pay
attention to you as an individual.
I could just decide if you were a doctor
engineer or a Kulak or a German or
whatever ethnic racial or educational
division happened to characterize my
particular target at the time and it
didn't matter if you were guilty as an
individual.
That whole notion never even obtained.
It was class guilt.
It mattered and if you were in one of
those classes as well,
we are better without you and of course
the nature of the class just changed
constantly,
but it was perfectly logical thing to
think if you believed in like historical
determinism.
If your parents were rich version law,
what was the probability that you are
going to be a useful part of the
workers' collective bs?
You're just to get rid of you ahead of
time so you didn't cause too much
trouble.
So then you think about these kulaks
rich peasants.
Well who are these people like when we
get down to the individual level.
So you go on village village was full of
surfs like not 40 years before.
So these are people just struggling out
of the feudal society,
right?
And you got some people in there who've
managed to be successful enough as
farmers,
which is no easy thing to like have a
house and maybe hire one person and you
know,
maybe have a little extra food in a
larder and a few kind of material
possessions.
So these are successful people.
And so you could say,
well they're the ones that actually knew
how to farm to one theory.
Or You could say the reason they had all
this stuff was cause they stoled it from
all the other people,
right?
And then you think,
okay,
so I marched into town.
I'm a Soviet revolutionary and I say,
hey guys,
you know those rich people,
they stoled everything they have from
you.
And then you think,
okay,
which of you guys is going to listen to
that?
Well,
it's not going to be the sort of
struggling people just underneath them
who are really trying to get ahead,
right?
Because that's where they're hoping to
get.
It's going to be.
They're resentful and revengeful few who
think,
well,
the world is fundamentally unfair and
it's obvious that those sons of bitches
got what they want by stealing it from
me.
And here it turns out that if I just go
down the street and steal it back,
well not only,
not only am I allowed to do that,
but according to this new and emergent
ideology,
man,
that's the best thing I could possibly
do.
So then multiply that story by several
million participants and you have like
the first five years of the Soviet
Empire.
And so what do we have there?
The result was a catastrophic onslaught
on millions of peasant households at
first party activists and local
officials read bullies,
right?
Brutalized hesitance,
forcing them to surrender their
homesteads and their possessions,
deportations,
arrests,
and killing soon followed as terror,
generalized the violence mounted to full
scale rebellion in various places with
regular troops engaged for months.
For example,
suppressing peasant uprisings resistance
took various forms,
usually reflecting the hopeless
desperate anguish of a population in the
Ukraine.
There were even women's rebellions,
spontaneous uprisings of peasant women
who attack the local Coco's is Tibet
demand.
The return of confiscated farm products
with a colossal impact on the Soviet
economy.
Peasants slaughtered their animals by
the millions rather than see them seized
for two years.
The fighting raged as the dreadful
process of deep cooler conization
continued Stella in order to further
assault on the recalcitrant peasantry
what conquest calls the terror famine of
1932 Moscow rights conquest.
It's from a book called the harvest of
sorrow.
Knowingly decreed grain poker
procurements from Ukraine and elsewhere
exceeding by far with the local
population could produce right,
which meant that everyone who lived
there was forced in ordered to deliver
more grain than they had ever grown.
Communists Brigades roam the
countryside,
forcing agriculturalist to discourage
the little they had been able to produce
under conditions of severe dislocation.
Grain sat unused in state reserves while
the local population starved.
This is from wisdom park riffle.
Biblical writings
before they reasoned unsoundly saying to
themselves short and Sora for all is our
life and there is no remedy when a man
comes to his end and no one has been
known to return from Haiti's because we
were born by mere chance and hereafter
we shall be as though we had never been
because the breath in our nostrils is
smoke and reason a spark kindled by the
beating of our hearts.
When it is extinguished,
the body will turn to ashes and the
spirit will dissolve like empty air.
Our Name will be forgotten in time and
no one will remember our works.
Our life will pass away like the traces
of a cloud and be scattered like mist
that is chased by the rays of the sun
and overcome by its heat for our
allotted time is the passing of the
shadow.
And there no return from our death
because it is sealed up and no one turns
back.
So a piece of writing thousands of years
old.
And so Nisha says at the end of the 19
hundreds well,
rationality undermines our faith and
religion,
but you have a piece of writing from
more than 2000 years ago that says,
look,
what is it about being alive?
It's short and there's nothing to it,
right?
Our thoughts are biologically produced
and when we die,
there's nothing left.
Well,
that's a very modern thought.
Yep.
It was expressed thousands of years ago.
So you know,
I think merely from observing that,
that the crisis of faith that
characterizes modern society is a
reflection of the permanent crisis of
faith that characterizes human beings.
What's happening with the totalitarian,
while the totalitarian is afraid of the
unknown for good,
for good reason.
I mean,
and he's very interested in sustaining
his own belief structure.
And the combination of those two things,
it can start off trivially is that the
more convinced that you have to maintain
the stability of your current belief
structure,
the more afraid you are of going to have
anything that's unknown and the more
afraid you are of anything that's
unknown,
the less likely you are to go out and
explore it.
And then the less likely you already go
out and explore it,
the weaker you get cause you start
gathering information and then the week
or you get the more necessary it is that
you have to have this frame of reference
in,
it has to remain intact and this sort of
thing starts to cycle and cycle.
So you undermine your own sense of your
own autonomy and ability and you make
yourself more and more a rigid tool of
the propagandistic system and you're
more and more adopt the stance of enmity
towards anything you don't understand.
And that's a spiral that goes rapidly
downhill right rapidly into a state.
It's characterized by complete internal
chaos.
And I think that's a good definition of
what is meant in metaphysical language
by hell.
Hell is a bottomless pit.
Why?
Well,
I don't care how bad things are for you
or around you.
There's always some bloody thing you
could do to make it worse,
right?
There's always some suffering.
You can extend others.
There's always some bit of stubbornness
or rejection that you can pull off
that'll make your already terrible
situation worse,
right?
So there's no bottom,
and that seems to me to be right.
If he,
if you do just a cursory historical
analysis,
no matter what terrible account you can
come across with regards to say,
concentration,
camp brutality in some other book,
there's some worst story,
right?
Limited only by the absolute,
the absolute ends of the most brutal
form of imagination.
All a consequence,
I think of this process,
right?
And you can't really say what causes it
because on the one hand there's
cowardice and lack of faith,
right?
Anything I don't understand powered his
pride in lack of faith,
anything I don't understand doesn't
exist.
Plus I'm not the person to confront it
anyways,
right?
That's the lack of faith.
Each of those things feeds into the
other and it's very difficult to say
where it starts.
Ooh.
The thing that's kind of interesting
about the self referential processes is
that
they don't have to start dramatically.
Like the loop can start very,
very small and it picks up speed very,
very rapidly.
So you imagine you're speaking into a
tape recorder and the speakers on you
get too close to the speaker with the
microphone and you get some feedback.
And if you bring the microphone a little
closer,
the feedback develops more and more
intensely.
It can blow up.
The whole system doesn't have to start
dramatically to move forward very,
very rapidly.
And what that means,
at least in principle,
is that even small mistakes anywhere
along this circle can start the
development of precisely this kind of
spiral.
And so you'll say,
well,
people do,
people need to be abused to become
totalitarian.
Well,
and the answer to that is no,
because everyone's been abused
sufficiently by Samo currencies in their
life to justify taking negative tack on
the nature of experience.
They say,
well,
how cowardly do you have to be in order
to run away from things?
And you think,
well,
not that cowardly because under most
circumstances your life is characterized
by sins of omission,
right?
It's,
there are things you left on done and
like how just exactly how rigid do you
want your belief systems to be?
And you say,
well,
I like them to be stable because without
that stability,
then I'm terrified.
And then you can say,
well,
fair enough,
but that's all a sign of a kind of
existential weakness.
And then if social circumstances come
around and give your life a good tweak,
say like they did with the Germans prior
to World War II,
you just never know what side you're
going to end up on.
And so all these little tiny mistakes,
you know,
mistakes that I think are marked by your
own conscious are precisely that leads
you down this terrible path.
And if you think,
well,
no,
that can't be right.
Well then you have to remember that in
these processes,
say of d Kula causation and that immense
wave of desks that characterize the
Soviet Union.
And the Nazi Germany,
most people were involved and if they
weren't involved,
indirect acts of commission,
they were absolutely involved in direct
acts of omission,
right?
They knew,
but they didn't say anything.
Well,
classically sins of commission or
regarded as much more evil say than sins
of omission.
But I actually think that's backwards.
The sins of omission are worse because
every time you walk away and what do you
do when you walk away from a Nazi?
What are you walking away from?
Well,
we know what you're walking away from,
right?
If you're walking away from
a domain that's likely to expand into
something that's completely
undifferentiatable from hell and it's no
wonder you'd walk away from that,
but the fact that you walk away from it
makes it much more likely that it's
going to happen.
Okay,
so then I think to end this,
something like this,
okay,
we look for economic reasons to explain
great,
terrible acts,
right?
We look for social reasons,
we look for political reasons,
but we have niches,
observation,
which is something like this.
I don't care whether or not your life's
been characterized by suffering and
deprivation.
The mere fact of suffering and
deprivation does not allow you to draw a
particular conclusion.
You can't say that there's a causal path
between economic deprivation say,
and the rise of a totalitarian state
because any events susceptible to
multiple interpretations.
Well,
how do these states come about?
I think,
well,
we look for political and economic and
social reasons because that's the
easiest place to look,
right?
If you ratchet up the level of
description to social forces that are
beyond your control,
then you never have to worry about what
it is that you're doing or not doing
this actually causing this sort of
thing.
But I think if you look at the
historical record,
especially if you look at it from a
mythological perspective,
the stories basically clear and it,
it goes something like this.
Every time you make a mistake that you
know is a mistake and you don't fix it,
the world moves more towards that.
And it might be trivial maybe,
but it might not be.
So you look at Adolf Eichmann,
for example,
who is the little bureaucrat who planned
the final solution and you find out he's
just your little ratty guy,
right?
You see him in a bar.
You don't even notice him.
He's a negligible nobody.
But he's the guy who planned the final
solution.
He was a normal person.
I mean,
maybe even slightly less than normal,
right?
He was no monster.
He wasn't the sort of person you'd
remark on if you saw him.
Precisely the opposite.
Invisible,
quiet,
unassuming,
presuming.
No doubt that at least until he was
arrested that he was just doing what he
was told.
And that was just fine.