Yeah,
so today I'm going to tell you the best
three stories that I know.
I think these stories are absolutely
phenomenally potent and the reason for
that is that I think they illustrate in
an extraordinarily powerful way
the nature of the processes that lead to
the establishment of Western democratic
ideals received whose work I rely on
substantially substantially to make the
following argument has taken Western
academic culture to task in a manner
that hasn't fully been revealed yet.
He said that like all human cultures,
the West is parochial and narrow in its
viewpoint,
and although over the last 300 years,
there's been a substantial amount of
cross cultural intermingling and a
potential broadening of philosophical
and religious horizon broadening has not
been sufficiently complete.
If we build on the viewpoint that I've
been developing with you over the last
few courses and make the presupposition
that religious modes of thinking are
more phenomenological than they are
rational,
which means that they deal more with
what you experience say.
Then with the objective world,
if we look at archaic religious stories
through that Lens,
then they can start to open up and so
given that I want to open up three
religious stories to you today too,
in depth and one only in passing because
we'll return to it later.
I'll start with a Judaeo Christian myth
of genesis.
When I say myth,
I don't mean untruth.
I mean a form of knowledge that's
narrative instructor and predicated on
presumptions that aren't empirical.
A myth describes processes of
transformation.
A myth describes the process whereby
elements of experience come into being
and transform.
The fundamental structural
elements of genesis are the word of God
and chaos
and Hebrew,
words for chaos and waste our tail for
chaos and Tau who for waste and Tom in
particular,
Tohu who as well are very interesting
words because you can track their
derivation historically and sometimes if
you can track the derivation of words
historically,
you can get some sense of the culture
mill you out of which the word sprang,
and we know what time at means because
we have written records of a story that
involves a character named ty Matt and
time out as a dragon who lives at the
bottom of the ocean.
In the oldest creation myth we have,
which is the Enuma Elish,
the Sumerian creation myth,
Sumeria,
Babylon acadia rightly regarded as the
birthplace of modern western
civilization.
In Genesis two,
processes unite to produce being
the first of those processes are states
is chaos represented by tail Marto,
who?
The second of those processes is logos
and logos is another word that has an
extraordinarily broad range of meaning.
It's generally transcribed in the
Christian tradition has the word,
and it's identified with Christ,
which is a very peculiar identification
because it's the word of God that
creates order out of chaos,
and of course the word of God in Genesis
is a phenomena that predates the birth
of Christ infinitely from a classical
religious perspective,
so the fact that the two beings are
identified as a great peculiarity and
also of great interest,
the fundamental story of genesis as
something like this
and it's perhaps the most brilliant
contribution of Judeo Christian thought
to world history,
it's,
it's total impact is virtually
incalculable.
The idea is this,
that chaos can be conceptualized as
something that has an essentially
feminine aspect as a matrix and a matrix
is a structure from which other
structures emerge and the story in
genesis makes the hypothesis that logos,
which is the word of God,
a phenomena associated with speech and
communication and logic,
logos,
logic,
rationality,
courage,
exploration,
all combined into a single entity or a
trait logos.
The combination of logos and chaos is
what brings order into being.
That's what the story in genesis means.
It's not an empirical description of the
origin of objects.
It's a phenomenological description of
the origin of experience,
the idea being that without the piercing
glance of whatever consciousness is,
whatever the background of experience
is,
the Matrix,
chaos cannot be conceptualized as real.
It takes the interplay between the
feminine principle chaos and the
masculine principle logos in order to
produce being
now that's of substantial importance
when you give some consideration to the
fact that immediately in genesis,
after the establishment of livable
order,
the data Yahuah identifies as the
individual human being with logos right
made in God's image.
That's the essential characteristic of
the human being and what that means is
that the logo is that operates in human
beings,
which is this capacity to make order out
of chaos is identical to the principal.
That gives rise to the cosmos from a
mythological perspective,
so it partakes of the daddy in a very
direct sense.
In so far as being itself is dependent
on its operation.
Now,
it's still possible to claim given that
perspective that a story with that sort
of structure is superstitious and then
it doesn't bear any relationship.
To what actually constitutes reality,
but you have to understand that that
story,
old as it is,
is predicated on older stories and it's
on the ground that those older stories
established that our entire concept of
natural rights rests.
So if you believe that natural rights
have an existence that's more than
merely arbitrary,
the reason you believe that is because
they're predicate,
those rights are predicated on the ideas
that are expressed in these myths.
Okay,
so now we're going to go back in time to
Sumeria and I'm going to show you how
this Sumerian creation myth lays itself
out.
And not only that,
I'm going to describe to you the direct
political implications of the enumerated
list,
the Sumerian creation myth,
because the political implications of
that myth are well understood because
the political structure of Sumeria was
directly associated with the structure
of the myth because the Sumerian emperor
was regarded as the earthly
representative of the highest God in the
Mesopotamian Pantheon,
whose name was Marta.
So in so far as you were emperor,
the reason that you were emperor,
and this is what gave your sovereignty
legitimacy,
right?
Because sovereignty has to have
legitimacy,
otherwise there's constant revolutions.
What gave sovereignty legitimacy in
Mesopotamia was the identification of
the emperor with Marta and that has,
that has certain implications for the
emperor,
which we'll discuss in some detail.
The story starts like this,
you've got this dragon,
Talia,
Matt,
and tie them out is a great primordial
beast who lives at the bottom of the
ocean and the ocean is water and water
is associated with the primal element in
archaic thinking,
and I you.
There's reasons for that already.
If you viewed the transformation of
deserts as a consequence of rain can
understand why water would be considered
the element that gives life,
right?
That the element that that brings life
fourth,
and we know from an evolutionary
perspective that that's accurate and we
know that we're 90 percent water and so
to consider water.
The primal element is no trivial
conclusion.
No,
no less than presuming that the sun is
the ultimate source of life,
the ultimate God,
because the sun is the ultimate source
of life as far as we're concerned on
earth,
right?
Because it's the source of all our
energy.
These aren't stupid concepts.
All right,
so timeout is this horrible creature
that lurks at the bottom of the primal
element right now.
She has a husband app suit.
Now,
the massive Batavia and creation myth
doesn't say much about Appsu.
We only know that he's the male consort
of the dragon of chaos,
and we know from reading other sources
of mythology that the male consort of
the dragon of chaos generally represents
either logos or culture.
So we're gonna make the presupposition
in this particular case that the husband
of chaos is order or culture.
Okay?
And then the Mesopotamians don't say
much about that.
That that doesn't.
The development of the idea of apps who
are order or culture doesn't.
It doesn't take new force until the
ancient Egyptians.
We'll talk about them today too.
Okay,
so timeout naps who are locked into a
kind of sexual embrace according to the
Mesopotamian creation,
death.
And what does that mean?
It kind of means two things.
It means that they're not really
distinguishable because they're locked
into this embrace and it also means that
they're up to something creative because
the act of sexual congress in mythology
is most usefully,
is most frequently utilized as
representation of something creative or
as representation of the probability of
some new form coming to be right.
All right,
so cop suit and tie them out are locked
into this embrace in a state that other
creation myths describe as egg,
like the pre cosmo Gonek egg,
there are intermingling gives rise to
the initial state of being according to
the Sumerians and the initial state of
being.
According to the Sumerians is
characterized by the dominion of the
elder gods.
These gods feeding none to bright make a
tremendous amount of racket doing things
well.
What does that mean exactly?
Well,
it means something like this.
They make a lot of racket and they cause
a lot of trouble.
They make a lot of wind and all of their
racket and trouble and wind and
activity.
Rouses tire.
Matt,
what does that mean?
Well,
it means if you do things,
you get in trouble.
It means even if you're trying to solve
problems,
you get into trouble because the
solution to a problem,
Chin tends to generate a whole bunch of
new problems,
right?
It's like the Hydra,
so what it means is that it's more or
less fainted that any form of activity
whatsoever
is likely to produce the threat of
catastrophe,
and of course we're absolutely keenly
aware of that in the modern world
because were possessed by this sense
that all of our frenetic activity,
all of our frenetic motivated activity
is producing alterations in the world
order such that nature itself is going
to be destroyed and eliminate us,
and of course we're absolutely keenly
aware of that in the modern world
because were possessed by this sense
that all of our frenetic activity,
all of our frenetic motivated activity
is producing alterations in the world
order such that nature itself is going
to be destroyed and eliminate us.
Right?
That's classic Sumerian fear and
nothing's changed in the last 5,000
years.
The Sumerians presumed that once the
elder gods were constructed and started
moving around on the planet,
that their activity,
they're mindless activity.
Because remember,
these aren't well integrated
motivational forces.
They're more like primordial beasts
right there on the integrated activity
risks,
plunging everything back in chaos.
Well Tire Max,
the representative of chaos,
this generative chaos,
but so what?
At the Sumerian say,
well,
the elder gods caused a lot of racket.
They move around the planet and they
upset time at and she decides that
enough is enough and she's going to wipe
them out.
So she's sitting at the bottom of the
ocean,
fuming away as the elder gods go about
their business,
and then they take one step too many and
they kill Appsu.
Who's her husband.
Now the Sumerian creation myth doesn't
say much about this,
but we know that aps who is the male
consort of chaos,
that makes it harder.
So what happens is the elder gods
destroy order itself.
They destroyed culture itself,
and as soon as you've destroyed culture,
all hell breaks loose.
And that's exactly what happens in the
Sumerian creation myths.
So tye Maddie merges just going to wipe
everything out and the world will revert
back to its primordial non-existent
state.
Now the elder gods get wind of this,
and of course they're just terrified
because they know that this thing that
gave rise to them,
whatever it is,
the matrix of being can easily wipe them
out at a moment's notice,
and so despite the fact that they're
transpersonal and immortal and
characterized by a certain amount of
power in the face of absolute chaos,
they're insufficient.
Now this occurrence is extending over a
protracted period of time,
and as elder gods are threatened,
they're also breeding and mating and
producing new forms,
and they produce a great,
great grand son whose name is Marta.
Now,
mark has a lot of very interesting
attributes.
The attributes are described in the
Enuma elish in the following manner.
So this is what [inaudible] father sees
when his wife Damn Kina gives birth to
Marduk.
So when he who's murdered,
his father saw his son,
he rejoiced.
He beamed.
His heart was filled with joy.
He distinguished him and conferred upon
him double equality with the gods.
Okay,
so that's the first indication that
whatever Martik represents is something
that's elevated beyond the normal status
of a primordial daddy.
So that he was highly exalted and
surpassed them in everything artfully
arranged beyond comprehension,
where his members not fit for human
understanding,
hard to look upon for where his eyes
forward,
his ears,
when his lips move,
fire blazed forth.
Each of his four years grew large and
likewise his eyes to see everything he
was exalted among God's surpassing was
his form.
His members were gigantic.
He was surpassing in height.
Mary Youtube,
one of his names,
son of the son,
God the son,
God of the Gods.
Okay.
Complex bit of poetry.
It says a bunch of things.
It says,
well,
whatever Martech is is the offspring of
the gods.
Whatever Marta is,
is characterized by high heightened
awareness,
right?
Because he has four years and four eyes
and they're large.
Whatever Martech is characterized by as
the status that surpasses that of his
father's.
Whatever he's characterized by is
associated with the power of speech.
Real power,
because when he speaks fire spurts.
Fourth Marta is also huge,
but more importantly,
he's associated in this particular poem
with a Sun.
Why is that?
Well,
the sun dominates consciousness,
right?
Because we're conscious during the day,
most of our brain is visual Cortex,
so we're visual creatures,
so when the sunrises is when the day
begins,
so Martin is also associated with
whatever dandy dominates the day,
and that's the daddy of consciousness
and there's more to the story of the
Sun,
right?
Because the sun is also something that
rises and sets repeatedly,
and that means that the dandy that
dominates consciousness is characterized
by a cyclical nature.
That's a son.
Myth,
sunrises in the morning renewed as a
consequence of fighting a terrible
battle in the night with the enemies of
everything that's associated with
consciousness.
A Classic Solar Myth,
so absolutely entire Matt give rise to
the world of the gods,
the activity of the world of Gods
reawakens timeout.
She decides to destroy everything,
but at that moment the gods give birth
to mark.
Now,
that's a typical motif which is that the
is born at the time of maximal crisis,
and the reason for that is in part it's
simple.
Look,
if your culture is dealing well with the
forces of the unknown so that everything
is static,
static but productive,
so the problems themselves don't arise.
There's no reason for the hero,
right?
There's no reason to confront the
unknown.
It's only when crisis beckons that the
birth of the hero is necessary.
Marta constitutes the birth of the hero
and they say,
look,
you know,
we're in real trouble unless someone
goes out there and confronts tire Matt
Straight on,
she's going to wipe everything out.
Um,
it's a dangerous and terrifying job,
but somebody has to do it.
And Mark says,
oh,
well that's no problem,
but I got a few rules here and this is
the first rule I'm in charge from here
on forward.
What does that mean exactly?
Well,
these archaic stories,
our policy in our policy mic in Northrup
fries terminology,
and what that means is that they can be
misread validly had multiple levels of
analysis simultaneously.
And so one thing it means is that if you
take the two year old child who's
essentially under the dominion of
assorted primordial Gods and Goddesses,
right?
Aggression,
fear,
panic,
and according to Freud,
a certain degree of sexual aggression,
the child moves from domination,
from motivated state to domination for
motivated state,
and it isn't until the age of three and
four when under the pressure applied by
the social world and as a consequence of
the maturation of the prefrontal Cortex,
which matures throughout childhood and
adolescence and doesn't reach its final
form until perhaps into the early
twenties.
All of those fundamental motivational us
to start taking on a structured
relationship to one another,
which is to say that once your,
as your personality becomes integrated,
a single motive force forward has to
bring all of these underlying
motivational systems into some sort of
harmonious arrangement.
Okay,
so let's,
let's see what the Sumerians are doing
here.
Okay.
First of all,
they're,
they're doing psychology.
They're trying to figure out,
given the dominion of the elder gods,
the indisputable dominion of the elder
gods instincts.
Who should rule,
right?
What should be in charge,
how do you construct the hierarchy of
values and then more complex.
Lee,
when you integrate a state,
which is what?
The mesopotamians dead,
right?
The first great civilization,
what does that mean?
The first time hundreds of tribes were
hammered into some sort of stable
hierarchical order.
How do you represent that order?
So Marta gets his act together.
The gods all meet in a huge chamber.
They elect him king.
Then they prepare them for battle.
When the gods,
the father's beheld the power of his
word,
they were glad and then homage saying
Martin is king.
They bestowed upon them a sceptre,
a throne,
and a royal robe that gave him an
irresistible weapons.
Fighting the enemy saying Golan cutoff
the life of Tire Matt may the winds
carry her blood out of the way.
Places after the gods,
his father's had determined the destiny
of Martech.
They set them on the road the way to
success and attainment.
So then he goes to the heart of
darkness,
so to speak,
and confronts tire.
Matt
accuses her of treachery and challenges
are to battle.
When ty Imad heard this,
she became like one in a frenzy and lost
her reason.
She cried out loud and furiously to the
very roots or two legs,
shook back and forth.
She recited an incantation repeatedly
casting her spell.
As for the gods of battle,
they sharpen their weapons,
Tiamat and Marduk the wisest of the gods
advanced against one another.
They pressed onto single combat and
approached for battle.
Okay,
well,
things don't go out so well with
timeout.
From this point forward,
the first thing that Martech does,
it encapsulate her and then net,
and I think that's a really interesting
metaphor because that's essentially what
human beings do when they encounter the
unknown,
right?
They encapsulated in an explanatory
network,
so it's a way of binding up the the
anomaly or the unknown and giving it a
substantive form.
Then he cuts her into pieces and then he
makes the world out of her pieces.
In fact,
one of Martin's names is he who makes
ingenious things as a consequence of the
combat with tire mapped.
Oh,
that's very,
very interesting because what it means
is that the Samaritans are presenting in
metaphorical forum.
The notion that when the chips are down,
the survival of being depends on the
capacity of whatever Martech represents
the solar God to encounter the Matrix of
being,
to cut it into pieces and to make the
world.
If you think about it in those terms,
it's a very,
very straightforward story,
right?
It's basically the story of human
beings.
Fundamentally the story of human beings
because we in the words of a famous
evolutionary psychologist whose name
completely escapes me.
We occupied the cognitive niche,
right?
Our motive being his creativity and the
in the face of the unknown and when
chaos threatens the established motive
being.
It's necessary for us to put our
creativity into action and to carve out
new territory or territory as a
consequence of encounter with the
unknown.
Why?
Well,
because we can take the world apart with
our hands and put it together in new
ways and then we can scold what we've
done verbally and we can transmit it to
another person and then they can do the
same thing and we're all doing this all
the time and we're all telling each
other how we're doing it.
And that's how the embodiment of logos
in the human being,
which is precisely equivalent to the
Sumerian notion of Martech.
That's precisely how it is that we're
constantly capable of redeeming the
world.
And that's why you make resolutions at
New Year's because the new you is
supposed to be born at the new year.
Okay.
So what are the Mesopotamians do it the
new year,
they take their king and they bring them
outside the city.
Now you have to understand that outside
the city is chaos,
right?
Because these are city states.
When you go outside the dominion of the
human,
you're in chaos.
And then the priest makes the Emperor
Neil and takes all his marks,
have status off him.
So He's reduced to his assets,
fundamentally bereft of his social
persona.
And then he slaps him with a glove and
humiliates him and the king is reform
forest to recount his since right?
Everything he did in the last year,
that wasn't up to standard so to speak.
And you can see how that'd be pretty
useful thing to have somebody who's in
power do on a regular basis.
Right?
Because it reminds them that they're in
fact subject to a transpersonal
structure who's nature isn't precisely
evident,
but is nonetheless there,
which is the case act like Marduk or all
hell will break loose and demolish your
kingdom,
which is,
of course it's true now as it was then.
So the emperor gets humiliated.
He asked to recount his sins,
then he's locked up.
Then he reenacts the battle with Tire
Matt,
and when he emerges victorious,
he's locked up with a ritual prostitute,
a higher duel,
and they mate.
Why?
Well,
the higher duel,
the ritual prostitute represents tire
Matt.
Now,
why the hell would that be?
Because timeouts a dragon,
right?
A horrible man eating dragon that lives
at the bottom of the ocean,
which is to say that in any encounter
with the unknown,
as difficult,
traumatic and violent as that might be,
there's also the possibility for
something creative to emerge as a
consequence,
right?
Because it's out of the unknown that we
mind new information.
So in so far as the Mesopotamian emperor
acted out the role of Marta than he was
a good emperor.
Then he deserved his sovereignty and
literally as well as figuratively in so
far as he did play that role,
then the society was going through
remain not only stable,
but constantly updated because he's
engaged in this constant creative
contact with the unknown,
aided and abetted by his attempts to
remember his own inadequacies and
weaknesses and to do something about
them.
Okay.
So that's a pretty interesting story.
And it gets even more interesting when
you start to understand the Judeo
Christian creation myth is assimilated
to the Sumerian creation myth by the
union of the notions of chaos and tire
matt.
So the logo's in Judeo Christian
thinking,
the word of God that produces order out
of chaos is also essentially equivalent,
at least metaphorically speaking,
to whatever Martech represents in the
Sumerian creation myth.
And we know that our relationship with
the Enuma elish is obscured by time,
but our relationship with the stories
that lay out the fundamental
substructure of Western culture is not
so ameliorated.
Even though we may not believe them
explicitly anymore,
they still sit at the basis of our
society.