So the first question is,
how would you define self deception and
how is that different from say,
cognitive dissonance?
Okay,
we'll,
we'll start with the first one.
How would you define self deception?
Well,
in most accounts of self deception,
most accounts of self deception have
been basically formulated by logicians
and the logicians make a presumption.
And the presumption is essentially that
people think in,
um,
in fully articulated statements,
propositions you might say.
And as soon as you accept that you've
run into the paradoxes of self
deception.
So for example,
it doesn't necessarily seem possible to
believe proposition a and proposition b
at the same time.
So those would be stateable pro
propositions if they conflict with one
another.
But that begs a number of questions.
And one is first,
whether or not people think in
propositions in fully articulated
propositions,
which they do,
but it's not the only way they think.
And then also what does it mean for two
things to con conflict?
So I'm going to start with the second
answering the second question first.
So often when I've read badly written
essays,
often undergraduate essays,
one of the things that occurs very
frequently is that the writer will make
a statement on page one or paragraph one
and then two paragraphs later write a
statement that directly contradicts the
first statement.
And because their thinking is confused
because they're young and because they
don't know how to write and aren't
particularly careful,
they don't notice that the two
propositions actually are illogical
conflict.
And one of the things that indicates is
that people actually don't know this
when things are in logical conflict
because there's no marker for that.
The only time people notice that their,
uh,
their presuppositions about the world or
in conflict is when they try to act out
two contradictory notions at the same
time and find out that acting one out
interferes with acting another route.
And sometimes that happens because
they're in conflict with themselves.
But even more often it happens because
they become,
they enter into conflict with someone
else.
So you might say that you don't even
notice you're propositional conflicts
until you act them out in the world
stops you.
Okay.
So,
um,
so you can,
you can,
you can maintain contradictory
cognitions endlessly without ever
noticing how disorganized you are
because the world doesn't slap you in
the face for your foolishness unless you
try to act those things out.
So the idea that self deception is
impossible because people can't hold two
contradictory propositions
simultaneously.
That's completely ridiculous.
People do that all the time.
Um,
so then that's the answer to the second
question and the answer to the first
question is,
um,
the way that people generally deceive
themselves is that they act out a series
of propositions.
So say a series of beliefs about the
world or even one belief about the
world.
And then they run into evidence that
that inactive belief is not having the
results desired.
So let's say you tell a joke at a party
and no one laughs.
And your proposition was that the joke
was funny and obviously the world
indicated to you that
something about that proposition was
faulty.
Now the problem is in part that the
world doesn't tell you which part of
that proposition is wrong.
It just tells you that the frame of
reference that you were using when you
were telling the joke had something
wrong,
had something about it that was
sufficiently erroneous so that you
didn't get the result that was intended.
But that's subject to all sorts of
potential interpretations.
And so that's,
that's a situation where a classic
situation where the,
yeah,
the data,
which is the outcome of your joke is
insufficiently.
Yeah.
Informative to precisely indicate to you
where that your mistake was made.
So it's subject to all sorts of
potential interpretations.
And one interpretation could be all of
these people at this party are too
stupid to understand my humor.
And that's a perfectly reasonable
proposition.
Although it's unlikely to be true.
Now,
generally what people do when they
deceived themselves is that they,
they lay forth a belief in the world and
the results aren't what they intended.
And that produces a negative emotional
state.
And the negative emotional state
indicates an error.
But then there's a whole process of
exploration that has to occur to
precisely specify the error and to
precisely specify how the information
about the error could be used to revamp
the whole propositional sequence.
And that takes a tremendous amount of
work,
like ridiculous amount of work because
let's say people don't laugh at your
jokes.
While why is that?
Well maybe you're hanging around with
the wrong sort of people,
or maybe your jokes just aren't that
funny,
or maybe you're kind of a jerk or maybe
you don't know anything about social
interaction.
And all of those possibilities emerge
when your joke falls flat.
And in order for you to fully
investigate the consequences of that,
you have to do a tremendous amount of
cognitive work.
And so generally what happens is that
people just don't do the work.
And then what they do is they,
they,
they have as a representation of their
failure.
What you might describe as what you
might describe as an it counter with
chaos and the encounter is negative
emotion,
emergency preparation,
and then complete indeterminacy as to
the proposition of nature of the
information.
Now,
if you do that enough times,
so you lay out your beliefs and they
fail and you get a negative emotional
response personally,
but you fail to engage in the difficult
process of exploration to specify
exactly what went wrong.
What will happen is that you'll collect
around yourself and absolute morass of
chaotic and indeterminant experienced.
And that's the place that you will end
up living.
And that's what self deception really
looks like.
It doesn't look like you believe a and b
at the same time and you know,
you,
you don't notice.
It's way more complicated than that.
And I would say that's akin to cognitive
dissonance,
but the explanation that I just provided
as far more thorough then the typical
explanation of cognitive dissonance.
So,
so that's an answer to Mike's Question.
How would you define self deception and
how was that different from cognitive
dissonance?
So one of the things you guys might want
to do is take more than one question,
don't wait,
type of few.
And then I can select from,
there's people in the room with me here.
So,
which wouldn't be the case under normal
circumstances,
but we're just testing this.
So any other questions?
Do you think some people seek out drama?
Eg,
they make things difficult for
themselves because they confuse it with
meaning?
Yes.
People do that all the time.
Um,
is it because they confuse it with
meaning?
Yes.
Partly.
Um,
that's,
that's a really complicated question
that you're asking
the problem with.
Okay.
So,
so imagine that you gave people at
shorts and the choice could be that they
could suffer stupidly or they could live
a meaningful life.
And so you might say,
well,
obviously they're going to pick to live
living a meaningful life,
but it's not so obvious because one of
the prices that you pay for living a
meaningful life is that you have to
adopt responsibility.
And the responsibility that's attendant
on living a meaningful life might is,
is theoretically without limit.
So,
for example,
what w the ways that's been
conceptualized in classic Christianity
is that in order to lead a meaningful
life,
you have to take the world's sins onto
yourself.
And that means that you have to see
inside yourself all of the negative
potentiality.
So they're characterized that,
that that being human is characterized
by,
and then you have to take for addressing
those.
And so when Carl Jung talked about this,
for example,
you know,
one of the points he made was that if
you do a thorough announced
investigation into your own faults,
then you end up scouring,
what's the word?
It's not scouring precisely harrowing
hell,
literally as close to literally as you
might imagine.
And of course that's a very,
very,
very unpleasant experience.
And so then you might say,
well,
people are going to perfectly well and
logically want to avoid that.
And then they do that using all sorts of
subterfuge because they don't want to
admit to themselves that they're not
taking any responsibility.
So they'll often generates false crises
in their own life and amplified problems
beyond necessity so that they can
convince themselves that when they're
effortfully struggling through all that
mess,
that they're actually taking
responsibility for their lives,
but they're not.
And so that's one of the reasons that
people might seek out drama and make
things difficult for themselves.
And it's partly because they confuse it
with meaning,
but you know there's multiple levels of,
of horrible self deception and confusion
and avoidance that go along with that.
What role do you think diagnosis should
play in clinical practice?
Oh,
that's easy.
You needed to to get reimbursed by
insurance providers and that's about it.
I shouldn't say that because that's just
beating fast style.
There's a bunch of,
there's a variety of functions,
diagnosis place.
Part of part of engaging in the process
of diagnosis is utilizing classification
and you need to utilize stable
classifications for a number of reasons.
One of them is that
you can't understand anything about what
you're dealing with without classifying
it.
And even if you classify it incorrectly,
that might be better than not
classifying it all.
Because once it's classified
incorrectly,
you might at least be able to notice
specifically what's incorrect about the
classification and then rectify it,
which is to say that a bad theory might
be better than no theory at all.
But diagnosis also helps you identify
potential pathways forward.
So for example,
if you diagnose someone as agoraphobic,
then you have access to the large wealth
of treatment protocols that have already
been developed for ag or phobia.
And that's for useful.
It helps you rule out other things and
that that can be extremely important
because sometimes someone will come to
see you in a clinical practice and
they're just overwhelmed by what's
happening to them.
And what that means is that they're in
chaos,
they're suffering,
and they have no idea why.
And then you could say,
well yeah,
what's happening to you is horrible,
but it's precisely this kind of
horrible,
and here's what this kind of horrible
it's like,
and here's what you can do about it.
And here is a bunch of other people who
are also suffering from it and they've
recovered.
So with this kind of horrible,
there's all these other things that you
won't have to worry about.
And that's really,
um,
that can be really helpful for people
because it narrows the universe of their
problems from all potential problems to,
um,
potentially manageable set of finite
promos.
So,
so the,
so those are some of the,
some of the reasons for diagnosis and
some of the reasons why diagnosis is
useful.
So
how do you differentiate between having
an actually bad life and having
depression make your life bad?
Well,
that's a good,
that's a good question as well.
I think you could do that in a
multidimensional way,
technically speaking.
So,
and so,
one of the ways I conceptualize that is
that you imagine people's human life
actually has a fairly stable and
identifiable number of characteristics.
And so some of those are,
um,
you need to engage in trade with other
people in that,
in modern culture that would generally
be formalized as having a career.
You need to have friends,
you need to have an intimate
relationship.
You need to be embedded within a family.
You have to conjure up something of high
quality.
That's productive to do with your life
outside of work.
You have to attend to your physical and
mental health and you have to regulate
your use of mind altering substances
like drugs and alcohol.
There's other dimensions,
but those are pretty decent as an
initial.
Uh,
those serve the purpose quite nicely as
an additional Schema.
So when you're talking to someone in,
say in a clinical intake,
the first thing you want to find out is,
is the person functional on any or all
of those dimensions?
And the fewer dimensions on which
they're actually functional,
the more they just have a bad life and
aren't depressed.
So if you have no friends and you,
you have no educational history and you
certainly don't have an educational
history,
say that's commensurate with your
ability or maybe you have no abilities,
you have a patchy work history,
your family is an absolute nightmare.
You,
you,
all you do with your time is consumed
drugs and alcohol,
um,
and you have one or more serious
physical or mental health problems you
have,
your life is,
has fallen apart and now you're going to
be suffering because of that.
But to call that depression is not
useful,
particularly depression.
Technically speaking,
could spiral you into a place where
those things are more likely.
But I would generally,
I think it's better to conceptualize
depression as the mismatch between
function and emotion.
So if I did that,
approximately six dimensional analysis
with someone and I concluded that,
hey,
well look,
this person has friends,
um,
they may not be seeing them right now
because they were in a bad state,
but they have friends and the friends
are good for them.
They have an intimate relationship
that's functional.
They have,
they're embedded within a family that
isn't to pathological.
They have a job that in principle serves
the function of a job,
but maybe that they could even be or had
been interested in,
et cetera.
Um,
it's back.
They're feeling terrible and they're
having a difficult time getting out of
bed.
I would say,
well,
that increases the probability that they
should be accurately conceptualized as
depressed.
And then of course in,
in a real situation,
the clinical presentation is generally
some mixture of those sorts of things,
but it's very useful to distinguish one
from another.
Have I read Ayn rand and if I have,
what are my thoughts on her philosophy?
Objectivism of objectivism.
MMM,
Ayn rand is an idea log and she's an
interesting in the alarm because she's,
she,
her ediology runs contrary to the most
prevalent modern ideology,
which is the one that underlies
political correctness.
And so it's fun to read Ayn rand,
especially if you're hyper irritated by
political correctness because she
provides almost the perfect antidote to
that.
But,
and you know,
I have some sympathy for her because she
wrote in a anticommunist vein and she
had her reasons because your family was
chased out of what became the Soviet
Union by the Communists.
And if I remember correctly,
you had their property stolen and all
the terrible things that went along with
that.
But
she writes hero stories of a certain
type.
And the hero story is the individual
against the collective,
roughly speaking.
And
that's a perfectly reasonable hero's
story and it's a useful one.
But to think of that as the only valid
hero story in the constellation of
possible hero stories is a mistake
because you can also write a perfectly
good story where the collective is
relatively beneficial and it's the
collective and the hero against say,
the dire forces of nature.
And that's also a perfectly appropriate
story.
So you might say that there are
circumstances under which the attitude
that Ayn rand puts forth is accurate and
salutary.
But to think of that as covering the
entire universe of potential proper
narratives is a big mistake.
And usually Ayn rand's acolytes do
precisely that.
So,
okay.
Ariel says,
do you think all presupposition stem
from religion?
No.
What I think is that the deepest
presuppositions are identical to
religion.
That actually when we,
when we talk about what constitutes
religion,
what we are saying at the same is that
we're dealing with the most fundamental
presuppositions that people make.
And the thing that I find interesting
about that is that presuppositions are
necessary.
And the reason for that is that because
you have,
you're a finite cognitive agent,
you have extraordinarily limited
understanding in order to deal with the
world at all,
you have to act as if certain parts of
it are both understood and stable,
like unchanging.
And those elements that you treat as
stable and unchanging are at the deepest
level.
Are you religious presuppositions,
whether you think of them as religious
or not is irrelevant if you don't think
of them as religious or nor that their
religious.
All that means is that you don't know
anything about your presuppositions and
that you don't know anything about
religion.
And I learned that partly from reading
Carl Young because one of the things you
posited was that the highest value that
exists in a person's hierarchy of values
is de facto equivalent to their god.
Now,
you know,
that isn't often how people
conceptualize the idea of God or the
idea of value,
but it doesn't really matter.
His point was that psychologically a
person's higher highest value serve
precisely the same function that a day
at east serves in,
in a more explicitly religious society.
So in my experience too is being that,
that if you're ever having a
conversation with someone that is really
digging towards the bottom of things,
you,
the language that has to be used as
immediately religious,
because religious language is the only
language that's kate capable of
encapsulating the phenomena that exists
at the deepest levels of analysis.
And so if that language has never become
necessary for you,
all that means is that you've never been
into sort of crisis that would
necessitate it to you or that you don't
have the language at hand,
which is not good.
Ioannis says some researchers see shame
as something that is very destructive.
The consensus seems to be that it is an
emotion that is always destructive.
Do you agree with this?
No,
that's absolutely ridiculous.
And only modern psychologists and
probably social psychologists would be
foolish enough to even dare deposits
said something.
So absolutely observed psychopathy and
shamelessness are the same thing.
So shame is shame.
No emotion is always destructive.
Any emotion taken to an extreme can be
disruptive.
Just like any value taken to an extreme,
you know,
made into one thing can be destructive.
So,
um,
joy can be destructive.
I mean,
people who are manic are in some sense
possessed by a radical excess of
positive emotion and they,
they get incredibly impulsive.
And so,
and it's terribly destructive.
I mean,
there's almost no form of insanity
that's more destructive than mania.
People will go out and spend all their
money,
all their family's money and well,
it engage in all sorts of hyper
optimistic interactions with the world.
It would result in their complete rude.
So you know,
people think of happiness as an
untrammeled positive.
Well,
if you think of happiness as positive
emotion,
which is partly true because it's also
the absence of negative emotion,
if you think of happiness is only a
good,
then you'll have no idea about the
pathologies of positive emotion and
their manifold and shame.
It's like if you do something stupid and
destructive to yourself or to yourself
and the broader social community,
you should feel shame and you should pay
attention to it and you should learn
from it.
And if you're not capable of doing that,
that then people should stay the hell
away from you because you're shameless.
And of course for most of western
history,
and I don't know enough about other
forms of history to also make the same
comment to call someone.
Shameless was,
it was,
it was a tremendous insult.
It meant that they didn't have enough
sense to be appalled by the room
pathology.
And there's,
that's,
that's just not a good thing at all.
What makes a successful researcher?
Um,
curiosity,
intelligence,
diligence,
you know,
those might be the personality
attributes.
And then,
you know,
being embedded in,
uh,
in the kind of social network that
supports research endeavors is also
extraordinarily necessary.
So I guess you would add to that the
capability for,
um,
extended collaborations.
Um,
the ability to write is also
tremendously important.
I mean,
the place that I see most graduate
students fail,
it's,
it's very rare that a graduate student
is incapable of formulating a research
hypothesis and they can always discuss
with other people what those hypotheses
might be and also infer that next
logical step merely by being conversant
with the relevant literature.
They can also run experiments.
They can generally also analyze them,
although that starts to become a
differentiator.
But what kills graduate students is that
they,
they can't write.
And writing is really difficult.
So you have to be able to write and you
have to either enjoy it,
which means there's something wrong with
you or you have to be compelled to do
it.
And if,
if,
if you can't,
then you're going to run into trouble.
Oh,
let's see.
Christopher,
how do you feel psychotherapy and
psychiatry should work together and
curing psychological disorders?
Hmm.
Well,
I presume that by psychiatry,
what you're zeroing in on there probably
is the use of psychiatric drugs because
otherwise there's not much distinction
between psychiatry and psychotherapy.
Um,
look,
if you have a serious problem,
you should be very wary of letting your
a priority convictions interfere with
your health.
So,
you know,
you hear very frequently that people are
all too easily
made all too easily seek help in the
form of pills.
And I just think that's wrong.
I don't see any evidence for that at
all.
In my experience,
no one comes to
a clinician saying,
please give me a pill for my mental
illness.
So it will go away.
First of all,
people don't want to think even for a
moment that they actually have a mental
illness.
Second,
they certainly don't want to be modified
by a pill.
And you know,
they generally feel that that's an
abdication of responsibility and that
they're terrified of the side effects.
And that even if they do try it,
they want to get off it as fast as
possible.
And that it's a,
it's shameful that they have to be rely
on some sort of medication to begin
with.
And so like a lot of what you're doing,
if you're dealing with someone who's
truly depressed is helping them come to
terms with the fact that a trial of an
antidepressant might be a useful thing
for them.
And that can take months,
that can take years.
So mean you don't want to leave any
stone unturned in your search for health
and psych,
psych,
Psych,
psychiatric medications can be very
useful and sometimes they're absolutely
necessary.
So,
for example,
your,
if you have someone who is flirting with
psychosis or who is already entered a
psychotic state.
I think the general consensus in the
literature,
and I think it's appropriate,
is that if you don't facilitate their
use of anti psychotic medication,
what you're doing borders on
malpractice.
So now cake.
So having said all that,
the probability that a medication alone
will be sufficient to address the
problem is low,
partly because medications for
psychiatric disorders are much better
conceptualized as complex tools.
Then as curator of agents,
you have to learn to use them,
you'll have to learn what did,
you have to figure out what the drug
should be.
You have to figure out what the dose
You have to figure out what time of day
you're going to take it.
Um,
and all of those are very complicated
decisions and a fair bit of experience
to optimize.
And then you also have to learn how you
use those medications while you're
simile tineas Lee modifying whatever
needs to be modified in your attitudes
or your life in order to progress
forward property.
So the optimal balance between the two
is don't say no to drugs to,
to rapidly because you know,
you just might have the sort of problem
that's best addressed with a psychiatric
medication and that could save you and
your family not only suffering but even
death because you know,
the probability of suicide was serious.
Depression is quite high and you know,
trying to help someone who's committed
suicide because they're depressed is
extraordinarily difficult.
So one of the things you really want to
do is stave that off.
But the drugs,
the medications have to be used as tools
in a sophisticated way within a
therapeutic alliance because otherwise
the probability that their work is just
extremely low,
they're just too complicated and they
have too many negative side effects.
Like even with antidepressants,
even when they work,
they generally interfere with people's
sexual function.
So,
and that can be good if the person who's
depressed is also suffering from
something like premature ejaculation
because antidepressants are good for
fixing that,
but they produce an orgasmic out,
which can be a real catastrophe that
that's more likely with women and slow
sexual response and in end inhibited
sexual desire.
And you know,
all of that can be extraordinarily
problematic.
And that's just one of a host of side
effects that are,
that psychiatric medications are likely
to generate.
So there,
yeah,
they're,
they're like chainsaws,
you know,
there,
there are tools and they're useful but
they're kind of rough and you know,
if you use them in property they can do
more damage than good.
How do you,
how should you decide between being hard
on yourself and giving yourself a break?
That's a good,
that's a very good question.
So,
um,
one of the populations that I've had
some experience with as being,
I've worked with a lot of lawyers and
these are usually very successful,
hard driving,
ambitious people who are that way for a
variety of reasons often because they're
hyper conscientious as well as being
competitive.
But they're almost always at least hyper
conscientious and they have other
personality attributes.
And you know,
one question that a person like that
addresses is,
well,
how hard should I work and what am I
just being useless?
And the general answer to that isn't,
well,
you should seek some appropriate work
life balance because that's just a
bloody cliche.
If you're in high,
highly competitive job,
you're being chased by your peers and
your clients and the marketplace to work
flat out as fast as you can all the
time.
And so then the question that you have
to face as well,
why?
Under what conditions should you not do
that?
And I've found Piaget's thinking very
useful in formulating an answer to that.
And the fundamental answer is you
shouldn't work so hard that you failed.
You shouldn't work so hard that you
can't continue to work that hard.
So if you're working 80 hours a week and
say you don't take a day off,
you will eventually hurt yourself in a
manner that will make it impossible for
you to continue working 80 hours a week.
So that's obviously counterproductive.
So let's assume that your goal is in
spit is to maximize your productivity.
And then you might say,
well that means that you have to take
care of yourself because otherwise
you're going to burn out,
you're going to get depressed,
you're going to get anxious,
you're going to get exhausted,
which for which there is no diagnostic
category and that's going to interfere
with your career.
So what you have to learn is how can you
maximize your productivity?
And often that means learning actually
how much work you can do and how much
leisure you need and how much you need
to involve yourself in activities that
are outside of work.
And one of the things that happens to
women,
particularly when they hit their
thirties and I'll speak primarily about
the lawyers that I've worked with
because I've looked worked with lots of
female lawyers who will be made partners
in large firms.
So they've been very successful,
is that they hit 30 or so,
they're through their apprentice ship
and they start to get very disillusioned
with their job.
And part of the reason for that is,
is that they make partner and then they
find out that the partners that they're
associated with have all the foibles
that are associated with normal people.
And so there's a bit of a decline in
idealism,
but they also find out that there
actually is a lot more to life than
working like a mad dog for 80 hours a
week,
purely on legal issues,
which might not even be that interesting
in and of themselves.
So then they have to figure out,
well how much time should be taken off.
And most of the lawyers that I've worked
with have ended up working,
working fewer hours but billing more
hours.
So in fact they got to have their cake
and eat it too.
They take a day off a week or two days
off a week.
They generally can't work shorter hours
cause that isn't how a profession like
that works.
But they can plan to take time off in
the future and do that quite regularly.
So maybe it's a two week vacation every
three months or every four months,
something like that.
Or a week,
every four months.
And what they almost inevitably find is
that the boost they get from the
vacation
increases their ability to concentrate
at work and makes them more valuable as
a practicing partner.
And so you can think about it as the
attempt to reach an equilibrium state.
The question,
how much should you work is really the
question,
how much can you work productively so
that you can have the longest possible
productive
and sustainable career?
And that means that you have to set up
your career in such a way that it
doesn't eat so much of your life that
you come to resent and hate it because
otherwise you'll bail out or you'll act
in a counterproductive matter all you're
hurting yourself or so forth.
So I would say for young people,
the way that you figured that out is
that you pick something difficult to do
when you work yourself half to death
doing it so that you can figure out
where your actual limits are,
like your limits of psychological and
physiological endurance.
And once you've exceeded your limits to
pull back to the point where that
becomes sustainable.
And then that way you're being hard on
yourself to test yourself out,
but you're also allowing yourself the
opportunity to pursue what you're
pursuing in the best of possible health
and with the highest probability of
continuing in a high quality manner into
the future.
Um,
what are my views on euthanasia?
Okay.
Is the fact that so many are against it
a symptom of individuals and societal
aversion to death?
Or is it of the more practical issues
like consent,
morality?
Oh,
well I mean euthanasia.
So complete nightmare.
I mean,
you know the slippery slope from,
it's okay if someone who's terminally
ill wants to die too.
Let's empty out the hospitals of all the
people in it who are no longer being
socially productive is like that's a,
that's a road that society's traveled
down one tiny little step at a time.
And so when you open up the specter of
euthanasia,
you're also opening up endless cans of
snakes,
the existence of which many of which you
have no idea even exist.
Now
I kind of think of euthanasia like
torture.
So you can imagine this situation.
Imagine the following situation.
And it's unrealistic because no real
situation is this clearly bounded,
but we'll use it for the sake of
argument.
Imagine that you know for certain that
someone in your custody as planted an
extremely high and explosive device and
extremely high capacity in a football
stadium and they are going to detonate
it unless you find out where it is.
Well,
you might say,
well,
what interrogation techniques might be
ethically available to you in order to
conduct that investigation?
And I would say,
I know this is
a flawed philosophical argument,
but I'm just using it as,
as a,
as a as an example,
high levels of threat isn't
interrogation technique.
You should be willing to undergo
prosecution for your actions.
You can't expect to get a free ride even
if,
because the use of torture say in a
situation like that is so absurdly
socially dangerous that even if you
could make a case that it was ethically
justifiable in that particular
circumstance,
you should pretty much be willing to
give up the rest of your life as a
consequence of having participated in
that.
And I kind of think the same thing about
euthanasia.
It's like,
you know what it needs,
you said once the nobody who's truly
lived hasn't experienced the necessity
of killing,
you know,
to put this in simple terms,
I have my dog put down in February
because he,
he was done and allowing him to expire.
It naturally seem to
involve nothing but a lot of unnecessary
suffering.
So you can certainly imagine a situation
where euthanasia seems like an
the ethical option,
but that doesn't mean that it shouldn't
be absolutely surrounded by high
thickets of illegality.
Okay.
I mean,
sometimes I think to do the right thing,
you're required to break the law and be
punished for it.
Now
part from that,
I've also learned that commenting
generally on questions like that is,
this is almost always a mistake because
the devil's always in the details.
So,
all right.
Is there a way to find your true passion
or is that just a cliche was definitely
a cliche and it,
and it,
you know,
it's the sort of thing that actually
annoys me quite a lot about new age
thinkers.
I would more or less put Joseph Campbell
in that category.
Um,
I think you can find what compels you
and what might enable you to live in a
high quality manner despite the
suffering that's associated with life.
I think you can discover that.
And I think part of the way you discover
that is by watching yourself and
learning when it is that you are
meaningfully engaged.
You have to notice that it's something
that happens to you in some rather than
something that you do.
You have to notice when you're
meaningfully engaged and then you have
to work to expand the amount of time
that you spend in that state.
But I would also say that there are
moral requirements that go along with
that too because you might say,
well what if you happen to be the sort
of person,
for example who finds torturing small
animals meaningfully engaging?
Um,
it seems like that's a,
that's the sort of meaningful engagement
that you probably don't want to expand.
So I would say that if you're going to
set up your life so that you maximize
your meaningful engagement,
you have to,
there's a number of other things that
you have to do.
At the same time.
And one of those is that you have to get
very clear about
who you are and what you're doing.
And so although this would be grounds
for a much longer discussion,
I think that one of the things that you
have to do if you're going to attempt to
maximize,
make meaningful engagement is that you
also have to do such things as
uh,
endeavor to stop deceiving yourself and
other people in every way you possibly
can.
And part of the reason for that is that
if you engage in deception of any sort,
you pathologize the structure,
the structure of your being.
But you could say you pathologize the
structure of your nervous system and
then you can't trust it's reports.
So if you're nervous,
if you're going to rely on your nervous
system's reports of meaningful
engagement to guide your future
activities,
you better do everything you can to make
sure that you're not filling that
nervous system with the kind of garbage
that's going to make it malfunction and
give again,
give you false reports.
So I think that moving towards
meaningful engagement has to be
associated with making truth,
your highest value because otherwise you
can't trust yourself as your own guide.
I mean,
the Catholics have struggled with this
for a long time from a theological
perspective because the Catholic
position,
roughly speaking,
is that human beings are so steeped in
sin that they can't trust their own
instincts in relationship to good and
evil and have to use the church and the
priesthood as an intermediary.
And you know,
you can obviously have an argument about
that.
And of course Protestants have
historically done that,
but you've got to give the Catholics
there do.
It's like people aren't pure,
are by nature and and only traveled in
their vision by us.
It'll sociological impediments.
There are also corrupt beyond belief
individually and half to use society as
a source of value.
So if you're going to personalize your
life in some sense,
you better act in a manner that makes
you a reliable guide.
So
what time is two 30 well,
I think maybe we'll call that a day
because I'm starting to get tired and
I'll start giving answers that not only
rambled,
but never actually come back to the
question.
So let's call that a day and,
uh,
we'll take a look and see how it worked.