So we're going to discuss some very
rough things today.
Maybe you're somewhat accustomed to that
already,
but this is particularly brutal.
I think,
um,
I'm going to tell it,
talk to you about a body of research
that's been produced over about the last
10 years and I think it,
it's perhaps it's,
it's a body of research that might
outline some of the most important
things that psychologists have ever
discovered.
It's really changed my view,
for example,
on what happened in Nazi Germany,
which we're going to talk about a lot
today.
And you know,
we've already talked a fair bit about
the temperamental determinance of
political belief.
Right?
And I've made a case for you that people
who are liberal or leaning to the left
tend to be high in trait,
openness and low in trait
conscientiousness,
especially orderliness and people on the
right tend to be low in openness and
high in conscientiousness,
especially orderliness and the effect is
not trivial.
If you look at just voting behavior,
then you get the typical sort of effect
sizes that are characteristic of
personality research.
Point two,
two,
point four,
something like that,
correlations.
But if you start to analyze people's
political beliefs in detail,
so so you get your measurement up to the
point where it's nice and reliable and
valid,
then temperament,
a accounts for substantial,
a substantially higher proportion of the
variance.
And so a lot of what people seem to do
is one thing you could think of is that
they,
they politicize their temperament by
constructing post-hoc arguments about
the way the world is.
But it's deeper than that you see,
because we already know that you have to
use filtering mechanisms in order to
Orient Yourself in the world,
right?
Because the world is just too
complicated for you to Orient Yourself
without using filtering mechanisms.
And the question is,
well,
what are the filtering mechanisms?
And to large degree,
they're temperamental proclivities
because they set up your value
structure,
for example.
And that sets up your perceptual frame.
And so what that means is that you
screen the world at the level of the
facts that display themselves to you.
Because you know,
you could say,
well,
you're a dispassionate observer of the
universe of facts and that you extract
out the conclusions that are reasonable
person would extract out from that body
of facts,
but unfortunately that's not the case
because your perceptions are biased by
your temperament and they have to be
because,
well,
because you have to screen things and so
you screened things in accordance with
your temperament,
you know,
you're oriented toward certain things in
the world.
Certain values for example,
and that's a perfectly.
That's perfectly reasonable because you
can't do everything at once anyways,
so there's no reason for you not to be
directional.
The question is what are the pathologies
associated with directionality?
Now conscientiousness is a very
interesting.
I'm a trait relationship to that because
there are obvious benefits to being
conscientious,
right?
I mean it's the best long term predictor
of job performance for example,
and all outlined some other data that
might be more associated with
industriousness than orderliness,
but there's utility orderliness as well,
and we'll cover that in detail today.
The question is,
no,
the issue is that you never get a
benefit without a price and so you can
see that with agreeableness.
If you're agreeable high in
agreeableness than you're compassionate
and polite and you're empathic and you
can work well in teams,
but the price you pay for that is that
you don't negotiate very well on your
own behalf and that you can be easily
taken advantage of,
and then if you're very low in
agreeableness,
well then you're more competitive and
more out to win,
I would say,
but the price you pay for that is that
if you become too disagreeable,
then you're likely to be sufficiently
antisocial,
let's say,
so that you might end up in prison so
you don't get a cost without a benefit.
You don't get a benefit without a cost.
So then the question might be,
well,
what's up with conscientiousness?
Because it seems all things considered
that it would be a good thing to be
conscientious.
Now I can think of some exceptions to
that.
So conscientious people are dutiful,
industrious,
orderly,
that sort of thing,
and they tend to sacrifice the present
for the future and that's a good thing.
So you,
you save up,
let's say you save up wealth,
you save up labor and effort for the
future,
you know,
don't live for today,
don't be impulsive,
work hard and all that.
That will accrue.
Use success over the long run.
The downside of that is
the long run has to be stable in order
for that to be a reasonable strategy and
so conscientiousness is not a good
strategy,
at least under some conditions in
situations that are radically unstable
because in situations that are radically
unstable,
you might as well get what you can now
or that's one way of looking at it.
Anyways.
The other thing about being
conscientious,
if you store up wealth,
say as a consequence of hard work,
then that can make you targets for
people who would like to come and take
your wealth.
And so it's also one of the things that
happened to many people in the 20th
century,
most recently in in Venezuela,
is that let's say you're conscientious
and you save money.
Well,
what happens in that period of
hyperinflation while your money is wiped
out,
and so you know,
this happened to Germany,
say the 19 twenties and you got to
understand what hyperinflation does to a
society because
what hyperinflation does is destroy the
people who worked hardest to construct
the society because they're the people
who've been prudent and careful and
sacrificed and so forth.
And then when a period of high inflation
comes along,
poof,
everything they have disappears.
Not happened in Germany during the 19
twenties.
Now there was a bunch of reasons for
that.
But so Germany was very unstable in the
19 twenties,
right?
Because of the war had just ended.
They had been subjected to the
Versailles Treaty,
which was a very punitive treaty aimed
against Germany.
It's not like the allies had lacked
reasons to impose a punitive treaty,
but nonetheless they did.
Germany lost a lot of territory,
including their industrial,
including their industrial areas.
Germany was flooded by men who were
brutalized in the trenches in world war
one.
You could hardly imagine how terrible
trench warfare is and you can't imagine
what you'd be like after a month of that
day of that,
let alone a couple of years of that,
and then Germany under a period of
hyperinflation at the same time in the
Soviet Union,
the the Communist Revolution had had
been successful and so there was
tremendous political upheaval in Germany
during the 19 twenties as well.
I want to just set the stage for that
and so,
but the hyperinflation wiped out older
people that were
prudent and saved and left them with a
terrible sense that the entire system
had betrayed them,
which is of course exactly what had
happened.
So.
All right,
so anyways,
conscientiousness is a bit of a mystery.
Know we've looked at plasticity right
already.
That's a combination of extraversion and
openness.
I just want to walk you through again
where conscientiousness is located in
the big five space.
So plasticity is a combination of
extraversion and openness and then
stability is a combination of
conscientiousness,
emotional stability and agreeableness
and conscientiousness is made out of
industriousness and orderliness.
Now here's,
here's some markers for for
conscientiousness.
So here's what you're like.
If you're ordering or if you're
industrious,
you carry out your plans,
you don't waste time,
you don't find it difficult to get down
to work.
You don't mess things up,
you finish what you start,
you put your mind on the task at hand,
you get things done quickly,
you know what you're doing,
you don't postpone decisions and you're
not easily distracted.
That's what an industrious person is
like.
We don't know anything about industrious
people.
We cannot figure out why they're
industrious.
If you read the neuropsychological
literature,
you might assume that people who have
highly functioning prefrontal cortex is,
might be more conscientious because
people associate the prefrontal cortex
with such things as the capacity to
plan.
The problem with that is that we've,
for example,
tested now thousands of people using
tests of dorsolateral prefrontal
cognitive ability which are basically
cognitive tests and as you know from
being in this class,
if you take a battery of cognitive tests
and you subject them to a factor
analysis,
you can extract out a first factor and
that's fluid intelligence and the
correlation between fluid intelligence
and conscientiousness is zero.
Right?
So,
so that's,
that's very,
very strange because you would tend to
think that people who were smarter might
be better at planning and maybe they
are,
but they're not necessarily better at
implementing and that we don't
understand the difference between
planning and implementation.
We don't know what that is.
You've got to think about it this way
too though.
Just because you're better at planning
wouldn't necessarily imply that you're
better at implementing because actually
one of the prerequisites for thinking
abstractly is that can detach your plans
from your action,
right?
Because otherwise you just automatically
act out everything you planned,
but that is what people do.
They separate out their thinking so that
they can work in an abstract space
that's divorced from their action and so
they can lay out multiple plans without
necessarily acting them out,
but then that introduces the additional
complication of having to implement and
industrious people seem to be good at
implementation,
but we don't know why.
We've done all sorts of laboratory
studies trying to see if we could get
some sort of laboratory task that
industrious people would do better in
the lab.
The non industrious people,
God,
you'd think that would be a snap snap.
We.
We probably tested 50 things and have
never got anything.
Differences in language use is as close
as we've got.
You can extract out estimates of
people's conscientiousness or they're
industrious does from the way they use
language,
but that's not a lot different than
using self report.
Personality scales.
It's different but it's not a lot
different.
So we've done things,
for example,
like imagine we present people with a
row of h's n's,
m's and use row after row of letters.
Small type.
You say go through and circle all the
use.
Well,
obviously you would think that that
would be a task that would require
diligence and industriousness.
You could time how long it took people
to do it.
You could see how accurate they were.
Correlation with conscientiousness,
nothing,
zero.
It's an ICU task as it turns out,
and so the best we've been able to do so
far maybe with industriousness is,
and this is so vague,
it's embarrassing,
is that we think that may be
industrious.
People find inactivity aversive,
so it did because they're not motivated
by enthusiasm,
right?
For the task that would be an extrovert
and they're not motivated by intrinsic
interest in the task.
That would be someone who is open and
they're not motivated by the desire to
decrease anxiety or emotional pain
because that would be someone who's high
in neuroticism.
Right,
and they're not motivated by the desire
to foster affiliative relationships or
to compete because that looks like it
loads on it,
on agreeable.
This is something else.
It does a good job of predicting
military prowess.
For example,
we tested a number of people who worked
in the US military in a number of
different places.
Conscientiousness was a deadly predictor
of of,
of ranking in military performance in
schools like the US Naval Academy for
example,
and also on on military basis themselves
and that kind of makes sense.
I mean the military is a conservative
place.
You'd expect people who are
conscientious and dutiful to do better
in a place like that,
but so they're good at.
They're good at implementation,
they're good at following orders,
they're good at doing their duty.
Now we're starting to understand a
little bit about the value concerns that
conscientious people would have to,
and so let's go through orderliness so
you can decide whether you're orderly or
disorderly.
Leave your belongings around that you're
Obviously if you do that like order
well,
that's a.
that's a no brainer.
Keep things tidy.
Follow a schedule,
is bothered,
is bothered by messy people,
wants everything to be just right,
is bothered by disorder,
likes routine,
sees that rules are observed and wants
every detail taken care of.
You can imagine all sorts of occupations
where that would be useful.
Accounting,
for example,
or there are people who go around and
check,
you know,
natural gas fittings and that sort of
thing by a checklist and you know,
you want someone like that every in any
position where careful attention to
detail is absolutely vital.
The question is,
as we said before,
what,
what's the potential downside?
So with industriousness we don't know
anything about it.
Here's the problem with
conscientiousness.
Okay.
Broadly speaking,
there's no theoretical bottle.
Nobody has any idea why people are
conscientious except for the few things
that I've told you,
there's no neuropsychological model
because the prediction would be
something like people who are higher in
prefrontal cortical ability because
that's associated with planning would be
more conscientious.
That's not true.
There's no psychological model.
That's partly because conscientiousness,
as a trait was extracted out of the
linguistic pools that we described by
factor analytic processes.
Nobody predicted that that would emerge
as a fundamental trait.
It just came out of this statistics,
so there was no.
There's no model surrounding it really,
and there's no pharmacological model.
We don't know how to make people more
conscientious with the possible
exception of drugs like Ritalin,
amphetamines,
you know,
that that seemed to be able to make
people focus in more and so maybe
there's an association to some degree
between conscientiousness and the
ability to pay attention,
but when we've used attentional tasks in
the lab,
first of all,
they load on fluid intelligence and
second they don't correlate with
conscientiousness.
There was another dead end,
very,
very difficult to for.
It's a real mystery to me because we
don't have that many good predictors of
life outcome Iq.
That's a good one.
Conscientiousness.
Well,
what's conscientiousness?
we don't know.
We don't know anything about it.
W W with the exception of the things I
told you and I'm going to describe some
of the other things that we found out
more recently.
So.
Okay.
So what else is useful about
conscientiousness?
Well,
it's strongly related to life
satisfaction and happiness.
Actually,
if you look at the big five,
if you look at the traits that are most
correlated within the big five,
conscientiousness and neuroticism are
negatively correlated.
Make sure I got that right.
The more conscientious you are,
the less likely you are to suffer from
anxiety and emotional pain and I think
the reason for that,
but I don't know,
but I think the reason for that is that
by being conscientious,
you stabilize your environment,
right?
Because everything becomes more
predictable,
more scheduled,
more routine.
You're more likely to be successful,
so if things aren't going wrong around
you all the time,
then you're going to be less anxious and
less emotional pain.
So I don't think that there's a direct
relationship between being more
conscientious and less neurotic,
but I think there's one that's mediated
by the environment and this is very
interesting you see,
because you'll hear all sorts of social
psychologists tell you and that
conservatives are more likely to be high
in negative emotion.
They're more threat sensitive,
say the liberals,
but the weird thing about that is is
that the conservatives are not higher in
neuroticism.
The liberals actually,
the contrary happens to be true.
The liberals have slightly more neurotic
than the Conservatives and so of
conservatives are threat sensitive
because that's supposed to be the
theory.
Then why the hell don't they show up as
being higher in trait neuroticism and
you could say,
well,
they're so effective at their
conservatism that they've reduced their
neuroticism by organizing their
environment and to some degree that's
true,
but Jesus,
if your theory predicts one thing and
the opposite happens to be true,
you can't just post hoc say,
well,
there's some other reasons we didn't pay
any attention to to account for that,
like it's really bothered me because it
does seem to be the case that the
political landscape is shaped to some
degree by some sort of negative emotion
that's broadcast at the people who were
on the other side of the political
spectrum,
but the evidence that it's anxiety
related seems to be very,
very thin.
So the question is,
well,
what else might there be so well?
Conscientiousness is related to
depression and guilt.
There's a researcher named Faye Art who
looked to show use a med analysis to
show that conscientiousness was
associated with specific emotions and
overall negative emotion,
but was most strongly associated with
guilt.
It was most.
It was negatively related to guilt
experience,
but positively related to guilt
proneness and so maybe guilt is the
emotion that you feel when you don't do
your duty.
Something like that,
and that's partly why we were thinking
as well.
It's part of,
it's not exactly why we were thinking
that conscientiousness is motivated by
our inability to tolerate inactivity,
but it's.
It's a finding that's along the same
sort of theoretical lays out the same
sort of theoretical territory,
so you must know people.
Maybe the maybe the person is your
mother or perhaps it's your father.
They come over to your place or you go
over there and they're just working all
the time.
They can't sit down and relax.
They just work all the time and they say
it.
They'll tell you if you ask them all,
I can't stand sitting around.
I have to be doing something and you can
imagine to how that might have been
selected for across the evolutionary
time span.
I mean if you're living in a situation
where resources are somewhat limited,
like we pretty much all do,
you're going to want.
You're going to demand of the people
around you that they at least pull their
fair share of the weight.
Right,
and so you could imagine that the people
who were likely to feel a negative
emotion of some sort for not chipping in
and doing their share or more than their
share,
which would be a neat way of indicating
their value to the community.
We're more likely to be well less likely
to be less likely to be selected as
mates and also perhaps more likely to be
severely punished from time to time.
Now you might say,
well,
how do people get away with not
conscientious then?
Well,
the answer to that would be there are
other things that you can offer the
community that are a value that aren't
associated with to fullness,
and I think comedians are a good example
of that.
I don't believe that comedians are
particularly conscientious because it's
not the kind of lifestyle you would pick
if you were a conscientious person or
people who grow out on the road and play
music,
for example.
Because that's such an erratic lifestyle
and so unlikely to be stable across any
reasonable amount of time,
so maybe you could be valuable to the
community by being a music.
An extrovert would do that or or by,
by helping ensure success,
security and safety,
and maybe someone high in neuroticism
would do that or maybe you would be
useful because you're really good at
developing affiliative relationships.
That would be someone who is agreeable
or you're creative,
but the conscientious person
demonstrates their value by working hard
and being beautiful and contributing to
the broader community and and following
rules and all that sort of thing,
and there may be other things they do as
well.
So now here's the downside to being
conscientious.
If you're working in a big company,
say and there's mass layoffs and you
happen to be effected independently of
your work history,
the probability that you'll become
depressed is quite a lot higher.
If you're conscientious and some of you
may be conscientious people and you know
that if you fail at something or even if
you think you might be failing at
something,
you're going to tear yourself apart.
You're going to find it,
you're going to blame yourself for it
because conscientious people,
especially orderly people are also
judgmental,
right?
And so which is something the liberals
always accused the conservatives of
doing is being judgmental and laying
down their value structure on
everything.
But if you're conscientious,
you're going to tend to assume that if
things aren't going well for you that
it's your fault and that's you can
understand why that might be a useful
supposition when it is the case that
there's something you could have done
that would have stabilized you were or
improved your chances,
and you can often think of something
even if it's trivial,
but it's not so good when you happen to
be caught up in waves of mass movement,
for example,
when you're laid off by a big company,
that where the relationship between that
happening and your own work ethic is
very,
very tenuous.
Nonetheless,
you'll still pull yourself apart.
So.
Alright,
so let's take a look at orderliness
because we don't have much to say about
industriousness because we don't know
anything about industriousness,
but we're starting to understand a lot
about orderliness and it's extremely
interesting.
So we we'd only managed to parse out
orderliness,
roughly speaking,
only managed to parse out
conscientiousness into orderliness and
industriousness over about the last 10
years.
I mean,
people have had placed orderliness under
conscientiousness before that,
but psychometrically,
it's become with the big five aspect
scale,
it's become more straightforward to
measure and so here's what we know about
orderliness so far.
It predicts conservatism along with low
openness,
low openness is a better predictor of
conservatism and high openness of
liberalism than conscientiousness is,
but conscientiousness is a pretty good
predictor and that's almost all
orderliness.
It's also associated with disgust
sensitivity.
Now that's a very cool thing.
So Jonathan Heit has done a lot of work
on disgust sensitivity and so as a guy
named Paul Rosen and I knew their
research from really almost,
I guess it's almost 30 years ago now,
and I thought they were really onto
something back in the nineties.
I really thought that investigating
discussed would be useful because no one
had ever really talked about it,
hadn't conceptualized it as a separate
emotion system,
and we found that that disgust
sensitivity is associated with
orderliness,
with a preference for order and
tradition and not with egalitarianism.
It's also associated orderliness with
harsh judgments of moral transgression
and,
and this is the kicker here.
I think it's associated with the
function of something that psychologists
have started to describe as the
behavioral immune system and so we're
going to talk about the behavioral
immune system and then we're going to
talk more speculatively.
I would say about the role that the
behavioral immune system might play in
political choice and also in political
pathology.
And I find this overwhelmingly shocking,
this body of data because it's opened up
a view for me of why people are
prejudice that I had no idea existed and
it's.
It's make.
It actually makes prejudice a more
terrifying thing.
I was terrified about prejudice before I
do any of this stuff I'm going to tell
you about today,
but this makes it more terrifying
because it.
It locks it so deeply into people you
can't believe it,
and the worst than that,
if you understand why it's locked so
deeply into people,
you also understand why it emerged as a
necessity and that's the terrifying
thing now.
So we're stuck with that now and no one
really knows what to do about it.
And so what?
We'll walk through this and you can tell
me what you think.
So what's the behavioral immune system?
All right?
According to the parasite,
stress hypothesis,
levels of parasitic infection within a
region may drive variability at both
individual and societal levels.
Okay,
so they're talking about individual
variability in political attitudes,
in personality traits,
both among individuals and both in the
social world.
And so we'll outline that in some great
detail.
The avoidance of death or disability
through avoidance of infection is a
major evolutionary driving force,
for example,
until times that are recent,
in evolutionary terms,
almost 50 percent of children failed to
survive to reproductive age with the
majority of deaths being due to
infectious diseases.
Now we're less cognizant of that as
modern people because of the invention
of antibiotics,
which we're currently in the process of
destroying as rapidly as we possibly
cat,
right?
Because they're given widescale to
animals and to people too far too great
a degree and all over the world.
We're generating new infectious diseases
that are resistant to antibiotics,
all known antibiotics and we don't have
any new antibiotics in the pipeline,
so although we've had a 60,
70 year hiatus where infectious diseases
were well controlled,
they're back on the march again and for
example,
there are multiple strains that have
emerged of antibiotic resistant
tuberculosis that can't be treated by
any known combination of antibiotics and
they will.
Those are actually 10.
This is a terrible thing.
They tend to be bred in hospitals and my
guess is if we did the epidemiology
properly,
that hospitals kill more people than
they save and the reason they do that is
because they bring people together who
have diseases and they breed infectious
disease of all sorts.
That's antibiotic resistant.
It's absolutely insane.
And here's another thing we do that's
completely crazy.
So
if you bring cattle to a feed lot,
they're fed,
this is particularly the case in in the
US,
but it's also the case in Ontario.
They're fattened up on corn and the
reason they're fattened up on corn,
because corn is heavily subsidized as a
crop,
so it's damn near free.
That's why there's corn syrup in
everything,
right?
Because it's a very low cost,
very low cost source of calories,
and you might say,
well hooray.
You know,
a low cost source of calories.
Isn't that wonderful?
Because that means that people don't
have any who don't have any money,
get to eat and right,
fair enough.
But the subsidy is made corn so cheap
that you can.
You can feed it to cows to fatten them
up because they get quite fat fast.
They gave a lot of weight fast with
corn.
The problem is cows can digest corn so
it makes them sick or they digest it
very badly.
It makes them sick.
They're not designed for it.
They're designed to eat grass,
not corn,
and so in order to stop the cows from
dying,
when you feed them corn,
you pump them full of antibiotics and
that's one of the things that's breeding
antibiotic resistance,
so it's not very smart,
but that's what we're doing and no one
really notices and that's a very bad
idea,
so you can be sure.
One of the things that you can be
virtually certain of is that whatever
you're worried about happening terribly
in the future,
it will be something else that you're
not worrying about that will actually
cause the problem,
and this could certainly be one of those
things.
Local parasite types and host defense
systems will typically typically be
involved in a coal evolutionary arms
race,
and so at any given time,
a host's immunological defenses will be
specialized to be most effective against
local parasite species.
To the extent that a host defense system
is specialized locally,
contact with out groups will be
associated with an increased risk of
exposure to infectious diseases against
which there is no a priori immunity.
Okay.
I'm going to read that again because you
should think about it to the extent that
a host defense system is specialized
locally contact with out groups will be
associated with an increased risk of
exposure to infectious diseases against
which there is no a priori immunity.
Black Plague Europe came in on ships,
right?
The Europeans started to spread out.
They came back with the ships.
The rats came off the ships,
poof.
Third of the European population died.
The relevant infection,
avoiding behaviors such as avoidance of
strangers and high conscientiousness in,
for example,
food preparation are assumed to arise
from the operation of a behavioral
immune system.
The behavioral immune system comprises
adaptive psychological response
mechanisms that are sensitive to cues
that might predict the presence of
infectious pathogens and which respond
with appropriate cognitive processing
and affective reactions.
Such a system.
This is the next thing that you want to
pay attention to.
Such a system is likely to be
oversensitive.
The cost of a false positive,
avoiding non existent infection is small
relative to the possible cost catching
an avoidable infection.
Okay,
so you're walking through the grass and
your snake detectors go off.
They're full or the perifoveal of your
eyes,
the periphery,
periphery,
especially for the detection of things
that might threaten you,
and so you could say,
well,
your snake,
you have snake detection systems in the
periphery of your vision that are
hypersensitive because if you see a
stick and you think snake and you jump
up in the air,
the cost is you jumped up in the air,
so who cares that you miss identified
the snake,
but if there's a snake there and you
don't see it and it bites you,
then you're dead.
So the logic is why not set the systems
that protect you to be hypersensitive?
Because the cost of the hypersensitivity
is low compared to the cost of
hyposensitivity,
right?
In social terms,
an important component of the parasite
stress hypothesis is that high levels of
infection may lead to ethnocentrism,
xenophobia,
distrust of different others and
conformity because such behaviors will
reduce the likelihood of exposure to
unfamiliar of infections to which
immunity has not been developed.
Why is there strict sexual morality?
Because promiscuity is a prime vector
for disease transmission.
That's one of the reasons
conservatism,
as the social immune system,
disgust is considered to be one of the
basic human emotions defined by a strong
revulsion and desire to withdraw from an
eliciting stimulus or event.
Physically.
Disgust is accompanied by a distinct
facial expression,
involve involving constriction of the
oral and the nasal cavity,
so that's the disgust face which closes
up your nose and your mouth so that
things can get in.
Evolutionary models of discussed
proposed that this emotion evolved to
help us avoid contaminated or harmful
foods or other potential sources of
disease such as sexual contact.
You know there's lots of psychoanalytic
theories about sexual shame and sexual
disgust,
but it's much more straightforward as
far as I'm concerned,
to view it as a biological battle.
There's approach systems and sexual
arousal systems that are involved in
moving you forward towards a sexual
partner,
but there's disgust systems that guard
you against it and those two things are
mutually regulatory and so you're
basically stuck in the middle.
It's half move forward and half be
repelled and that's partly also the
balance of those two things has helped
is what helps you select a sexual
partner and people generally are quite
selective about their sexual partners.
So and we said,
well,
why are you selective about your sexual
partners?
Well,
there's the obvious practical reasons,
but then there's the reasons that are
more tightly associated with biological
protection and so even though we don't
like to think that way,
in addition to its role indirectly
helping to expel harmful foods from the
body,
disgust also forms an important
component of the behavioral immune
system,
the suite of psychological mechanisms
that aid in the detection and avoidance
of potential contaminants before they
can make contact with the body.
Although disgust may have its origins in
the protection against physical
contamination,
a number of studies have implicated
disgust responses in moral decision
making.
There's been experiments that are
specifically associated with the
elicitation of disgust and the
observation of the corresponding
behaviors in the lab.
So here,
here's an example.
So imagine I gave you a sterilized
beaker and I said,
well,
expel some saliva into it.
Now wait 10 seconds and drink it,
will you?
Well,
people know you see you made a disgust
face,
right?
While the question is why?
Right?
You know it's sterile.
It was in your mouth,
seconds before.
Why all of a sudden have have you
switched from it being part of your body
to not being part of your body and also
being part of your body that wasn't
ingested.
It was part of you to being something
that there's no damn way you're going to
have anything to do with so
well,
so that's a good example.
That's a good example of the of the,
of the disgust mechanism and in
operation.
Distinguishing between self and nonself
is a very,
very difficult thing and there's
multiple mechanisms that do it and it's.
It's definitely necessary.
Although disgust may have its origins in
protection against physical
contamination,
a number of studies have implicated
disgust response,
disgust responses in moral decision
making.
I mean,
you know that you can see the activity
of the behavioral immune system in such
simple things as avoiding sources of
contamination on a sidewalk,
right?
If you see something that's disgusting,
say rotting food or something like that
on a sidewalk,
the probability that you're going to
step in,
it is very low.
You're going to see it and you're going
to make a face and you're going to go
around it,
and the reason for that is because you
don't want that attached to you in any
way and the reason for that is while
it's disgusting,
it's contaminating and the association
there is that.
It's a place where you could conceivably
pick up a disease.
Now you see pathologies of this system
arise,
generally obsessive compulsive disorder,
so chronic hand washing,
for example,
is this is classified as an anxiety
disorder,
but there is an anxiety component to it,
but I don't believe that that's an
accurate classification.
I think that obsessive compulsive
disorder is actually a disorder of
disgust because all of the behaviors,
including hyper grooming people
sometimes have trichotillomania.
They'll pull out the hairs on their
body.
The grooming behaviors and that sort of
thing seemed to be more associated with
the operation of the disgust system and
almost everything about obsessive
compulsive disorder has a disgust basis.
And so one of the things that people who
are,
who have OCD obsess about is that I've
got a client once who was this poor
woman by the time her ocd was done with
her,
she built the equivalent of an airlock
on her house,
like not technically proficient or
anything like that.
And her husband and her children had to
go through an elaborate decontamination
process before they were allowed to step
foot in the house.
And one of the things she was very
concerned about was that she would go
out to a supermarket and touch a piece
of fruit and,
and become contaminated and then come
home and touch her children and then
they would become contaminated.
And so while she ended up in the
hospital and she was divorced and I had
just did it in her life,
you know,
and so then people who have obsessive
compulsive disorder,
you know,
they'll,
they'll wash their hands until the soap
is gone,
like a whole bar of soap.
Right.
And you can often tell who they are
because their hands are shiny from
Washington much and they'll shower,
it can't get out of the shower.
They'll shower until the hot water is
completely gone and their self cleaning
mechanism so to speak,
have gone seriously astray and the way
you treat them as by exposing them to
things that are disgusting and
contaminating.
I had a client with OCD once.
He was quite the character and I.
One of the things I had him do was we
would look for things on the Internet,
pictures of things that really disgusted
him.
It's not that much fun by the way,
treating someone who has ocd because I'm
rather disgust sensitive.
And so that was also rather hard on me.
So anyways,
we would look for things on the Internet
that,
that he really didn't like.
And then I'd print them out and have him
put them on his fridge,
which he did not like at all.
And he would,
he would,
he had a bunch of other problems and we
got along quite well.
But for a long time I treated him for
about three years.
He would phone me like three or four
times a day because he had obsessive
compulsive disorder and just swear at me
like mad,
you know,
just swear it,
it,
get these messages.
He'd,
he,
he phoned me and he just so mad at me
because I'd have to put these things on
his fridge,
you know,
and so he'd curse and swear and yell at
me and then two minutes later he would
phone and apologize and say he was
really sorry.
It helped.
I would continue to see them and god,
that just went.
Just went on forever.
But I felt sorry for the poor guy.
You know?
He eventually ended up getting a puppy.
A.
Yeah.
I see you agreeable people.
Oh,
Papi.
God.
Unbelievable.
A.
Yeah.
Anyways,
that was good for him because he had to
go around and clean up after the PA,
PA,
but that had poor puppy.
It was quite dominant and it,
the things that happened to that poor
guy,
so the puppy would dominate him,
so he'd take it outside to take it for a
walk and he wasn't a very skilled person
in many,
many ways.
He had a very large number of severe
impediments and so he really liked this
puppy.
He didn't have any or anything like that
and he was supported by his aged mother,
God,
it was just a catastrophe and he'd go
outside and try to walk the puppy and
the puppy would just sit down,
right,
because it was doing dominant stuff and
he didn't know how to overcome it and
then these crazy people from across the
way who styled themselves as animal
rights activists started to harass me
and they phoned up his mother and told
them that if they,
if,
if she didn't take the dog away from
that retard,
they were going to come over and do
terrible things to him and then he got
harassed on the street and then he went
to a park with his dog and they came up
to him and pushed him on the card and
swiped his dog and ran off to the,
to the SPCA and dumped it there.
He had to move away from his apartment
and God,
it was just,
it was just an absolute catastrophe.
They had plenty of sympathy for that
damn dog.
But no sympathy whatsoever for the guy,
you know,
it was really,
it was really something.
Anyways,
that story ended happily weirdly enough.
He got,
he got a job with a woman who used to be
a psychiatric nurse who was training
dogs and she gave him a little job
setting up the dog training thing and
then he got to learn to train his dog.
He lost like he was a thin guy to begin
with.
He lost like 30 pounds trying to learn
how to take care of this puppy.
It was just,
I thought he was going to die,
but there is no way he was going to give
up that dog.
And so anyways,
ocd,
it's square.
Quite the bloody catastrophe.
So.
And it's a good thing for someone who
has ocd to have a dog,
right?
Because dogs are messy and so there's
all sorts of things that are messy about
them.
But you have to kind of live with the
mess.
Like you have to live with the mess.
If you're going to have a child or if
you're going to have a partner of any
sort,
you know you can't let the orderliness
part of you get the upper hand so
terribly that it's impossible for you to
live.
That's what happens to girls who have
anorexia.
By the way.
You know how you get.
There's this idea with regards to
anorexia that it's often high achieving
girls who have it well,
it's hyper conscientious girls.
They get so disgust sensitive.
They can't stand their own bodies and so
for example,
then they start being able to look at
their bodies properly and so what they
do,
instead of looking at their whole body,
they lose the ability to do that.
They only can see parts of their body
and then they can't tell the difference
between a part that's healthy and well
shaped and a fat part and so anything
that's that's that's what would you call
of dubious.
Anything that's hard to measure becomes
impossible to see.
So either an anorexic client at one
point,
she wasn't a very big woman maybe about
this big and thin.
Yes,
obviously,
and so I was trying to work with her on
her body perception disorder and one of
the things I did was,
so I had her come and sit beside me,
so I was sitting like this and so is
she.
And I said,
well you look at our two thighs,
which one is bigger than mine,
was like 40 percent bigger.
And she said,
well I can't tell they look the same to
me.
And so I said,
okay,
this is what we're going to do.
I let her do it.
I said,
you take a pencil and all sit on a piece
of paper and you just trace my thigh.
Okay.
And then you can put that piece of paper
underneath your thigh and trace it and
then you can look at the difference.
Well,
so I had her do that and she looked at
the two pieces of paper and she couldn't
believe it.
She could not believe that that was
actually the case because her perception
had become so disordered that it was
impossible for her to see the real shape
of her body.
And we would go outside and I would ask
her,
is that person fan,
is that person fap and with other people
she could tell,
but with her own body,
not a chance.
She couldn't see it properly at all.
And so there was a real obsession with
purity among women who have anorexia and
all,
they'd like to starve themselves right
down to the bone because the bone is
sort of pure and white and there's no
excess tissue on it.
And so anorexia also looks like a
disease of disgust.
So it's very,
very difficult to.
She,
she thought in very black and white
terms,
one of the things I had her do at one
point was said she hasn't music.
She said,
I either really liked a song or I don't
like it at all.
And I said,
okay,
well you've got a music collection,
why don't you go through like 20 of
those songs and rate them on a scale
from one to 10.
And she couldn't do it.
It was either yes or no orderly,
right?
The boundaries around the categories
were absolutely segregated.
And her apartment tended to be decorated
in black and white and she was hyper
clean,
you know,
so everything in the apartment was
extraordinarily orderly,
well put away.
She couldn't stand to see anything
disgusting on the counters and that sort
of thing.
So very,
very difficult disorder to treat
anorexia very,
very difficult.
So,
and you know,
you can see how it can go wrong because
food,
when you're eating your disgust systems
are on alert,
you know,
like you,
you want the thing you want to eat and
you absolutely don't want the thing you
don't want to eat and your mouth is very
sensitive to that sort of thing to the
texture and all of that.
And your sense of smell is very
sensitive to that sort of thing because
you know you don't want to eat anything
that's contaminated or poisonous.
So it's another situation like sex where
the reward system is driving you forward
for,
to,
to engage in a conservatory behavior.
But the disgust system is right there,
Ma modulating and moderating it.
And there's a tension between those two
things.
That's already always at work with the
anorexic types.
The discuss sense the disgust system
gets the upper hand,
so she was also extraordinarily
judgemental and perfectionistic,
but that goes along with it because
orderly people are judgemental and
perfectionistic and so if you're.
You're a perfectionist.
Often what that means is you have very
high levels of orderliness and very high
levels of neuroticism and those two
things chase each other around like mad
because you can't stand the idea that
you would make a mistake and you get
anxious about it as well.
So then you get stuck in this
perfectionistic mindset and you can't
get out of it.
So
inducing disgust responses,
whether via fall order,
a disgusting work environment or
recalling a disgusting experience led
individuals to assign harsher
punishments to others who had committed
a moral transgression.
So you you describe a moral
transgression,
maybe breaking a law.
You exposed the people in the experiment
to some disgusting stimulus and then you
have the.
You asked them about the probability
that the person was guilty and then also
how long they should be imprisoned or
how much they should be fined.
And if you get the people disgusted,
then the probability,
especially if they're orderly,
then the probability of assigning a
harsh punishment goes upward.
So,
so if you're ever in court,
don't discuss the judge,
right?
That's part of the deal.
Harsher moral consump judgments can even
be induced following the consumption of
a bitter drink because bitter,
bitter substances are often poisoned or
poisonous substances are often bitter
and that induces a disgust response as
well.
Although you can overcome that,
coffee is bitter,
all of our bitter so you can,
you can retrain your system to accept
those things as food,
but it's not particularly easy.
In addition,
the same disgust related facial
expressions or observed in response to
unpleasant tastes,
disgusting photographs and receiving
unfair treatment in an economic game.
Concerns about cleanliness and
interesting.
So some of you may know.
I was at mcmaster university a couple of
weeks ago and there were a bunch of
protesters there and I went up to meet
the protesters because I kind of wanted
to see what would happen.
There were a bunch of them around the
back of the room now offered to shake
their hands and mostly what I got was
discussed faces,
you know,
and that's not good.
That's not good.
So here's something to know too.
Here's the bed,
here's a good predictor of whether or
not you're going to get divorced.
You go into the therapist office and you
talk,
the two of you talk and you roll your
eyes.
That'll predict if you roy,
if you're rolling your eyes at your
partner,
you're going to divorce them.
Why?
It's a disgust response,
right?
It's something like I'm lifting you up
with my eyes and throwing you into the
garbage.
It's something like that,
but I rolling is a great predictor of
the probability of divorce.
So.
So it's something to keep in mind with
regards to your relationships.
Like if you're starting to develop some
contempt or some disgust,
you bloody well better get on that right
away because that's a bad road to go
down and so well so.
Well.
So then you have to do whatever you have
to do not to go down that road.
Yeah.
So see,
one of the things I think that's
happening on the political landscape and
like we know for example,
that the more authoritarian political
correct types are high in agreeableness
and high in orderliness,
so that's a very interesting combination
and I think what's happening is that
they're very rapidly dividing the world
into contemptible Predator.
Like a snake often elicit a disgust
response rate.
A Predator will elicit a disgust
response like a crocodile or an
alligator,
a snake or something like that,
and so it's the.
It's the Predator response that's being
evoked to the people who are on the
other side of the political spectrum,
roughly speaking,
and so they're categorized as like
contemptible Predator or something like
that,
and the people that are being protected
or like innocent victims.
It's,
it's.
That's how it appears and that's a very,
very dangerous thing to have happen.
As I'll show you.
Concerns about cleanliness and feelings
of disgust have likewise been related to
political attitudes.
Situational reminders of the importance
of physical cleanliness,
such as asking participants to wipe
their hands with antiseptic wipes tend
to increase.
Self reported political conservatism
such as fine finding is consistent with
the notion that purity tends to be
valued more highly by conservatives than
by liberals.
Individuals who report being disgusted
more easily also tend to hold more
conservative political views on topics
including abortion,
gay marriage tax cuts,
and affirmative action.
In addition to the effects that have
emerged when using self reported disgust
sensitivity,
more conservative political views have
also been associated with stronger
physiological reactivity to disgusting
images.
There's a lawyer,
Martha Nussbaum,
who is also a political philosopher who
says that we should eliminate the effect
of disgust on our political theorizing,
that disgust shouldn't be something
that's considered as a valid means of
information from which you might drive
derive political conclusions.
So if I find your behavior disgusting or
if you find my behavior disgusting
according to Nussbaum,
that should be independent.
You should try to make that rationally
independent of your political views.
I'd like to believe that,
but there's a problem and this is the
problem that we're going to go through.
You can't muck about with these
underlying systems.
You can't just say ignore the reports of
your disgust system because it isn't.
It isn't like your emotions are insane
and irrational and you have the
rationality on top of that that's
guiding you properly.
That isn't how it works.
All of these underlying biological
systems guide you and to the degree that
you're the degree to which you're guided
properly is a consequence of the balance
of the action of these underlying
biological systems,
but the balance is very complex.
We maintained you need a disgust system
because if you didn't,
you'd eat something that would kill you
and then you would die or you'd do
something stupid and you'd end up like
you get caught and it would be dirty and
you wouldn't clean it and then you would
die.
So the idea that you can somehow just
rationalize the output of the disgust
system and decontaminate your political
viewpoints as a consequence seems to be
to be an.
It seems to me to be very,
very naive.
Not that there's no danger to it because
there's plenty of danger to it.
In addition to large literature has
converged on the notion that there are
two core dimensions of conservative
political ideology,
resistance to change,
and tolerance of inequality.
Resistance to change reflects the extent
to which people wish to maintain the
status quo.
While tolerance of inequality reflects
the acceptance of an unequal
distribution of resources and
opportunities within society.
Joest has done a lot of that work.
Jostes supervisor as Banerji and
Missouri and Banerji is unknown Marxist,
and so this is another place where
political ideology contaminates as far
as I'm concerned,
scientific inquiry,
because jostes work on on on,
let's say resistance to change is
predicated on the idea that the
conservative in the conservative
inclination to support the maintenance
of already existing structures is
precisely equivalent to supporting an
unjust system,
and that's not a reasonable thing to do.
If you're looking at these sorts of
things from a scientific perspective,
you don't get to make judgments like
that,
but they're built into the
questionnaires,
so resistance to change reflects the
extent to which people wish to maintain
the status quo.
While tolerance of inequality reflects
the acceptance of an unequal
distribution of resources and
opportunities within society,
these two dimensions appear roughly
aligned with social and economic
conservatism as expressed in the
constructs of right wing
authoritarianism and social dominance
orientation respectively.
There is no left wing authoritarian
psychological scales.
We're trying to derive one right now,
but the reason for that is that after
World War Two,
the social science community was
responding to what had happened in Nazi
Germany and perfectly appropriately and
they examined right wing
authoritarianism as a consequence,
but they never examined left wing
authoritarianism because the prevailing,
what would you call it,
political landscape of the time
proscribed made the idea that there
could be left wing authoritarianism
sufficiently incorrect politically so
that it was never analyzed from the
perspective of social science.
Even though the evidence for left wing
authoritarianism say by the end of the
19 forties,
was absolutely overwhelming.
Right?
By the 19 thirties,
people were reporting on what had
happened in the Soviet Union.
You know the forest,
the forest decolonization,
for example,
of the agricultural industry in the
Soviet Union and the consequence death
consequent deaths of several million
people in the Ukraine.
It was all extraordinarily well
documented.
These core facets of conservatism are
also closely related to the two higher
order value dimensions described in
moral foundations theory,
which reflect preferences for order and
tradition on the one hand and
preferences for egalitarianism on the
other.
Importantly,
the motivational basis of these two
dimensions appears to vary independently
from one another with an individual's
overall political attitudes on the left
right spectrum emerging from their
relative balance.
These motives are also strongly rooted
rooted in basic personality
characteristics such that preferences
for order and tradition are associated
with higher levels of orderliness.
Now,
you might think that's obvious,
right?
While obviously orderliness is
associated with preference for order,
that's not the issue.
The issue is whether or not you can
measure it right?
That's the issue,
so these things seem self evident,
but it's taken a very long time to build
up the instruments that allow them to be
measured in such a way that you can also
start to look at the correlates and the
underlying psychophysiology so it's by
no means obvious
higher levels of orderliness and aspect
of conscientiousness and politeness and
aspect of agreeableness as well as lower
levels of openness and intellect.
In contrast,
preferences for egalitarianism are
uniquely associated with compassion and
aspect of agreeableness,
so and that's exactly what we found when
we were looking at political
correctness,
which is primarily predicted not by
openness or by conscientiousness,
but by agreeableness.
Political conservatism can therefore be
thought of as a social immune system
reflecting the extension of pathogen
avoidance mechanisms to the integrity of
the social system.
Borders boundaries,
right?
That's the orderly person.
We'll keep borders between concepts.
We'll keep borders between people.
We'll keep borders between towns.
We'll keep borders between political
ideas and religions and states.
Why?
Because we don't want that terrible
things flooding in from everywhere.
Now the liberal will say,
wait a minute.
All the things flooding in from
everywhere aren't terrible.
They have great utility and that's true,
but the problem is they're both true.
They're both true at the same time
because well and will document that as
we move forward.
So then the question is,
well,
how do you know when things should be
more open and when things should be more
closed and the answer to that is,
well,
you better have a chat with everyone and
find out what they think because it's a
balance of probabilities.
There's no way of determining at a
priority.
It's a balance of probabilities and so
you have to have a discussion to
determine how wide the gates should be
open and how narrow they should be
closed,
and that's also going to depend on the
circumstances and the situation so
there's no way of the faith.
This is the thing that's so terrible
about this.
There's no way of determining a priority
who's positioning is correct.
Just as the behavioral.
Yes,
in particular,
the social immune system would help to
maintain order by suppressing any
actions or individuals that deviate from
a group's accepted social traditions.
It has been reported,
for example,
that regions with higher levels of
disease prevalence tend to be associated
with higher levels of social conformity
and autocratic rule.
Individuals who feel more vulnerable to
disease likely likewise report higher
levels of ethnocentrism,
xenophobia,
such basic concerns about pathogen
avoidance may thus contribute to the
desire for order and tradition among
conservatives along with the harsh moral
judgements associated with violations of
the social order.
How do you purify something?
How about with fire?
That's something to keep in mind as we
move towards the more political
expressions of this and the thing about
something that's disgusting is you don't
isolate it exactly.
You destroy it,
right?
It's the thing you do with rats and
insects,
for example,
is destroy them right,
and you do that with poison.
You do it with fire,
you do it by cleaning things up and you
do that because while the rats will eat
all your crops and the insects carry
disease and all of that so it or the
infest your food,
which I don't know what proportion of
today's food production is eaten by rats
and insects,
but it's a huge proportion still
according to the parasite stress
hypothesis,
authoritarian governments are more
likely to emerge in regions
characterized by a high prevalence of
disease causing pathogens.
Now,
who the hell would have ever guessed
that,
hey,
this is where you see the real utility
of a genuine social because it's by no
means self evident.
This hypothesis and this paper that I'm
going to discuss with you right now just
blew me away when I read it.
I thought it should have been front page
news across the world,
but he didn't really track that much
attention.
Recent cross national evidence is
consistent with this hypothesis,
but there are inferential limitations
associated with that evidence.
We report to studies that address some
of the limitations and provide further
tests of the hypothesis.
Study one revealed that parasite
prevalence strongly predicted cross
national differences on measures
assessing individual's authoritarian
personalities,
so that's very interesting.
So the more parasitic and transmissible
diseases in a particular locale,
the higher the probability that people
when measured at the individual level
held authoritarian attitudes because you
might say,
well,
there's parasite prevalence that
produces a repressive government,
but it doesn't really affect people at
the level of personality and that's not
what was found in the studies.
It was reversed.
The parasite prevalence slash infectious
diseases made people more authoritarian
and that was what was driving the more
authoritarian government.
So here's something cool.
Who knows about this?
Right?
So how do you fight authoritarian
governments across the world?
You get rid of infectious disease.
That could be it,
that could be the key.
So in there,
and again not that is by no means is
self evident.
Hypothesis study one that revealed that
parasite prevalence strongly predicted
cross national differences on measures
assessing individual's authoritarian
personalities and this effect
statistically mediated the relationship
between parasite prevalence and
authoritarian governance parasites,
personality,
authoritarian state.
That's the causal pathway.
This mediation result is inconsistent
with alternative explanations for
previous findings to address further
limitations associated with cross
national comparison study to tested the
parasite stress hypothesis on a sample
of traditional small scale societies,
results revealed that parasite
prevalence predicted measures of
authoritarian governance and did so even
when statistically controlling for other
threats to human welfare.
What additional threat famine also
uniquely predicted authoritarianism.
Together these results further
substantiate the parasite stress
hypothesis of authoritarianism and
suggested societal differences in
authoritarian governance result in part
from cultural differences in
individual's authoritarian
personalities.
Here's the effect sizes,
so look,
they're mind boggling.
So first that's authoritarian
governments one,
pathogen prevalence,
the correlation is point four,
two
point four,
two,
right?
There's malnutrition,
there's warfare,
it's actually negatively correlated with
warfare.
Famine point two,
six.
So if you square that,
that's about eight percent of the
variance.
That's about 16 percent of the variance.
So those are walloping effect sizes,
right?
That effect size is about.
So that 16 percent,
the typical effect size for a
personality,
variables about point two to point
three.
So let's say point two five.
So that's about seven percent of the
variance,
that 16 to 17 percent of the variance.
You almost never see a correlation of
that size.
So it's,
it's an absolutely remarkable piece of
work and it has all sorts of terrifying
implications.
So the question is,
now why would you have such a powerful
immune system?
Behavioral Immune System,
disgust system.
Okay.
So let's look at some little known facts
about the history of North America.
I don't know how many of you guys know
this,
but it's worth knowing.
Okay.
So what was the pre Colombian population
of the Americas?
The answer is we don't really have any
idea.
The estimates vary from 10 million to
$100 million with an emerging consensus
of 50 million.
Well,
it's halfway.
Okay.
We don't know.
We could be out by one order of
magnitude,
but a fair number of people.
So what happened to all the native
Americans?
Well,
that's easy.
They all died.
Why?
Because when the Spaniards came,
see there was no diseases in the new
world except for maybe syphilis.
There's some evidence that syphilis was
trends mended back to Europe as a
consequence of contact with North
America,
north and South America,
but there are almost no diseases in,
in,
in the Americas,
and that's partly because there were no
big cities and also because even where
there weren't compared to Europe and
also because where there were big cities
in Europe,
people live close with animals and there
was lots of movement of disease
pathogens back and forth between the
animals and the human beings.
And so lots of Europeans died as a
consequence of that.
Huge numbers of them,
especially from diseases say like
smallpox or or measles or,
and.
But the Europeans built up a whopping
immunity to all these diseases including
influenza.
And then they came to the Americas with
their diseases and bang,
it killed all of the native Americans if
figured 90 percent of them.
So here's some of the statistics.
What are the diseases that wiped them
out?
Influenza,
bluebonnet plagues,
smallpox.
Measles.
Chicken pox was deadly to the native
Americans.
So from 1492 to 1650,
there was a death toll of 90 percent.
So you know,
when the puritans landed in the US at
Plymouth Rock,
that was a long time after the Spaniards
had landed in,
in,
in the more southern areas,
the Indians,
the native Americans there,
they were desperate to see them because
they didn't have enough people to take
off their crops.
They didn't have enough people left.
Imagine nine out of 10 people died.
That's everyone right that you're done
at that point.
So there were 20 to 25 to 30 million
people in Mexico before the arrival of
Cortez.
Fifty years later there were 3 million.
So,
and the aboriginal population in Canada
estimates this is accepted by the
Canadian government.
No one really knows and the estimates do
vary substantially.
There might have been 500,000 people in
Canada in 1450,
and that decreased by 80 percent after
contact with the Europeans.
There's the population collapse in
Mexico.
Sixteenth Century population collapse in
So the 15,
45 and 15,
76 appeared to have been hemorrhagic
fevers caused by an indigenous viral
agent and aggravated by unusual climatic
conditions.
The Mexican population did not recover,
recover to pre Hispanic levels until the
20th century.
Absolutely catastrophic consequences.
So then you look at that and you think,
well,
is it really all that surprising that
people have evolved extraordinarily
powerful immune systems,
disgust responses,
and behavioral immune systems.
I mean,
this is no joke.
It's absolutely catastrophic.
So now I want to talk to you a little
bit about Hitler.
So when I was sorting some of this stuff
out,
trying to look at this disgust
sensitivity literature and then
understanding finally that it was
associated with orderliness,
orderliness is associated with
conservatism.
I was also reading a book by Adolf
Hitler,
which was called Hitler's table talk.
It's a very interesting book and Hitler
had secretaries at his dinner tables
from 1939 to 1942 and they basically
took shorthand notes of what he said
spontaneously,
and so there's a book that you can buy
called Hitler's table talk that,
that,
that is nothing but a presentation of
his spontaneous utterances across that
time period.
Now,
Hitler was a very strange person.
He was very high in openness,
surprisingly enough,
but also extremely high in orderliness.
At least that's what you can infer from
reading the historical data,
so he bathed four times a day,
for example.
He was also a great admirer of
willpower,
so which is something that's also
associated with conscientiousness and
orderliness.
He was very proud of his ability to
stand like this for eight hours in the
back of a car and his ability to
withstand,
you know,
what would you call them?
Trying circumstances by willpower alone.
One of the most famous film
documentaries that was made in the Nazi
era was called triumph of the will,
right?
Triumph of willpower.
That was by Leni Riefenstahl.
I'm not saying that quite right.
You can look at that on youtube.
It's a very interesting film.
Horrifying film,
but a very interesting one.
Well,
if you're wondering about orderliness
and mean,
take a look at that man.
So that's Nuremberg,
right?
That was the biggest rally grounds ever
made in human history.
Nuremberg and Hitler was unbelievably
good at spectacle.
Look at how absolutely perfectly ordered
daddy's.
God only knows how many people.
They're several hundred thousand because
they could all fit on the parade ground
at the same time.
All in absolutely perfect formation.
Orderliness gone out of control.
It's interesting because people think
about Nazi-ism Nazi as a method descends
into barbarity,
right?
But what it looks like is a disease of
civilization.
That's a whole different thing because
conscientiousness predicts,
be predict success in complex industrial
societies,
and this is actually conscientiousness
gone out of control on the orderly end
of things and why?
Why?
Well,
the twenties,
the World War One,
that was plenty chaotic and there was a
huge famine after World War One right in
Spanish.
Influenza killed more people than the
war did and he'd actually mutated in the
trenches because if people are packed
close together than viruses or other
pathogens can be very deadly because you
don't have to live very long to give it
to her.
If people are dispersed,
then the virus or the bacteria can't
afford to kill you as fast because then
it dies too.
And so if you pack people together,
then you can breed unbelievably variant
forms of pathogens,
infectious pathogens.
And that's what happened in World War
One.
Packed all the men together in
unsanitary conditions,
poof.
Up came,
Spanish,
influenza went all around the world
after World War One and killed more
people than the war.
So after the war,
after World War One,
of course,
Germany descended into utter chaos.
And so what happens when you descend
into chaos?
And the answer is there's a
corresponding call for order.
And that was answered by the that was
answered by Hitler and the National
Socialists.
And Hitler was very good at listening to
the German population and what they were
demanding in a period of chaos was
order.
And so that was exactly what he decided
to provide spectacles of order,
which is exactly what you'd expect from
someone who is really high in openness
and high in orderliness.
Spectacles of order.
And Hitler was also extremely interested
in art,
but he categorized art into like proper
hygienic art and improper chaotic art.
And he often would have art exhibits at
the same time have the approved art that
he approved of.
So those were in the official museums,
let's say,
and then there would be a corresponding
exhibit of degenerate art and that that
was art that was associated with
movements like expression isn't,
for example,
which has garish colors and it's very
emotionally expressive.
Hitler sort of preferred Kinda
eroticized Greco Roman representations
of heroic people.
You know,
that was the Nazi aesthetic ascent
essentially.
So there are some more examples of
order,
right?
Look at that.
Everything,
everything.
Geometric,
everything regular.
The borders completely well defined.
Everything here is squares.
Everyone's lined up perfectly.
Everything is uniform,
right?
Look at there's pathways between the
rows of people.
This is again at Nuremberg,
perfect order along with his plans for
the world capital Germania,
Elbert spear,
that was the Nazi architect,
made the plans for the world's largest
stadium,
which was to be located on the Nuremberg
rally.
Grounds derived from the pen,
authentic stadium of Athens.
It would have offered 400,000 seats.
It was good to get the shape of a horse
shoe planned dimensions,
800 meters wide,
450 meters high,
100 meters with a building area of
350,000 square meters.
The laying of the foundation stone was
on ninth of July,
1937.
It was to be finished for the party
congress of 1945 in 38.
The construction began with the
excavation.
It was stopped in 39,
but during the whole war,
the casting pitt had to be kept dry for
mentoring groundwater after the war,
the northern half of the pit filled up
with water and is today called silver
silver lake.
The southern half was used to deposit
the debris of the destroyed downtown
Nuremberg.
That's Nuremberg at night.
So what Hitler did because he was very
good at using fire and as display as
well.
So those,
that curtain there.
So you see there's the Nuremberg
buildings that we saw in the last
photograph that those are the search
lights from the from the Nazi air force.
So they had the parade all the way
around the grounds there and pointed
straight up.
So that night time rallies were
illuminated by a cube of light,
very effective.
What?
Display?
Artistic display of orderliness.
Now here's where things get seriously
ugly.
So this is a.
This is a pamphlet from I think 19.
Yeah,
1944.
And the pamphlet is called a Jew as
world parasite.
So this is something I found on the net.
I'll share it with you.
Very rare,
original,
late 19,
44,
anti Jewish Third Reich pamphlet.
This very scare six by eight and three
quarters.
20 page soft cover booklet by MRI for an
Erik Schwartzberg was published 1944 in
Frankfurt.
It was published at a time when a great
percentage of the European Jews had
already been deported to concentration
camps in the east perhaps to justify
what had happened to the Jews since the
Nazi seizure of power.
The authors compared the Jews with
parasites,
the most unpleasant forms of life on
earth,
and that it is only natural,
unjustified against them to free
humanity of them for the sake of
survival of mankind.
This is from the pamphlet the people of
the world will recognize the Jew as
world parasite.
And there will be a time when there will
be one united front of all people
against the Jewish world parasite,
the pamphlet ends and humanity will be
freed from the most severe illness from
which he suffered from thousands of
years.
Here's what happened in Nazi Germany.
So when,
when,
when Hitler came to power,
he was very interested in public health
campaigns and so he said he formulated a
number of policies including formulating
these vans that went around screening
people for tuberculosis at the same time
be announced,
announced a policy to beautify and
purify Germany.
And so he encouraged the factory owners
to clean up the factories to get rid of
the rats and the insects and to plant
flowers and so forth in front.
Right?
So it was cleanliness and beauty.
They used Zyklon b as the agent for,
for disinfecting the factories as icon
be cycle.
And B was the gas that was used in the
gas chambers.
So Hitler started out by getting rid of
the rats and the parasites and the
insects in Germany,
along with this public health campaign.
And then he moved into the insane
asylums and started a euthanasia
campaign,
and then he moved outside into the
broader political sphere and started to
target the people that he didn't
consider pure as parasites,
capitalizing on the behavioral immune
system and people's intrinsic sense of
disgust.
And so I'm going to show you some of the
propaganda that did that so that you
know how this sort of thing works.
Okay.
So this is from Richard Koenigsberg,
who wrote a book called Hitler's
ideology embodied metaphor fantasy in
history.
So we've already.
We've already sort of discussed the
idea.
This is sort of an archetypal idea,
grounded in biology.
You know that you're,
you're running in some on this
underlying biological platform of deeply
rooted hypothalamic systems and
[inaudible] systems and so forth that,
that and that you're a collection of
those underlying systems organized at
some higher order level while those
underlying systems manifest themselves
in fantasy.
So for example,
if you're hungry,
you're going to get a fantasy about
going to get something to eat and if
you're lonely,
you're going to get a fantasy about
someone that you'd like to be with.
And so forth,
because the fantasy is part of the
manner in which these underlying
biological motivation systems think,
okay,
so what do you think?
How do you think and talk if you're
possessed by disgust.
Okay.
The state did.
This is.
This is from Hitler,
Hitler's utterances.
The state did not possess the power to
master the disease.
The menacing decay of the Reich was
manifest.
The masses feel that the mere fact of
the Jews existence is as bad as the
plague.
Politicians tinkering around on the
German national body,
so most of the forms of our general
disease,
but blindly ignored the virus at the
time of the unification,
the inner decay was already in full
swing and the general situation was
deteriorating from year to year.
The Nation did not grow inwardly
healthier,
but obviously languished more and more.
It's all disease metaphor.
The symptoms of decay of the prewar
period can be reduced to racial causes.
Anyone who wants to cure this era,
which is inwardly sick and rotten,
must first of all summoned up the
courage to make clear the causes of the
disease.
They think that they must demonstrate
that they are ready for appeasement,
so as to stay the deadly cancerous ulcer
through a potter policy of moderation.
The Jew must take care of that.
The plague does not die.
If this battle should not come,
Germany would decay and it best would
sync to ruin like a rotting corpse.
You can see in the right today an
example of mortal decay that is not the
speech of someone who's possessed by
anxiety.
That's the speech of someone who's
possessed by disgust.
They are not the same thing.
The first of May can only be the
liberation of the nation spirit from the
infection of internationalism,
the restoration to health of people's
against the infection of materialism
against the Jewish pestilence.
We must hold a loft,
a flaming ideal,
another purification metaphor.
The restoration to health of our people
must start from the restoration to
health of the body politics.
So that was Hitler's essential metaphor.
The the nation was a body,
right?
It was a pure body,
it was a pure area in body,
and it was being assaulted by parasites
that were subjecting it to disease and
decay.
That's the fundamental metaphor at the
bottom of his political message.
I gave the order to burn burned down to
the raw flesh.
Jesus,
the ulcers have this poisoning of the
wealth.
Yeah,
pretty rough man.
This is the battle against a veritable
world sickness which threatens to infect
the people's a plague which devastates
peoples and international pestilence.
The international carry of the Bacillus
must be fought.
It is if within this community,
one state is infected,
that infection is decisive for all in
European Europe,
no common life of the nations is
possible when amongst their number.
There are some who are suffering from a
poisonous infection and who openly
preserved profess their desire to infect
others with the same disease.
We shall have a very real interest in
seeing to it that the bolshevist plague
does not spread over Europe.
National Socialism has made our people
and therefore the right immune from a
Bolshevik infection.
I'll read you one more,
although obviously you get the point.
Table seven is called the national body
is being consumed.
The Jew is and remains the typical
parasite,
a sponger who likes to know like a
noxious bacillus,
keeps spreading as soon as a favorable
medium invites him.
Alright,
now I want to show you a brief film
and you can.
You can look here at at the,
what would you call it?
Artistic and propaganda stick
transformation of the idea of order into
a politicized message.
And the thing that's so interesting
about Hitler's particular brand of
fascism,
it wasn't precisely and it see it wasn't
precisely a movement that was predicated
on ideas like communism.
Communism is predicated on ideas,
but the Nazis went out.
It was something that wasn't really in
the realm of idea.
It was more in the realm of embodied,
discussed and the image,
and so it was also very much more
difficult to fight against.
From the ideational perspective.
You know,
it wasn't a well developed intellectual
movement.
It was an embodied movement and Hitler
was extraordinarily good at using the
metaphors and the images and then his
incredible capacity for for propaganda
stick display to fire people up at a
level of analysis that they weren't
really even aware of,
so let's take a look at this film
campaign then gave us the opportunity to
really get to know the Jewish people.
Nearly 4 million Jews live here in
Poland,
but they won't be found among the rural
population,
nor have they suffered from the chaos of
war as has the native pole.
They set it out in differently in the
gloomy streets and the Polish ghetto
within an hour after the German
occupation.
They were back in business,
German and his head to look at the
Polish ghetto 25 years ago.
This time,
our eyes are sharpened by our experience
in the last few decades.
Yeah,
I'm lucky.
In 1914,
we no longer see just the most grotesque
and chemical of these questionable
ghetto figures.
This time we recognize that there's a
plague here,
a plague that threatens the health of
the Aryan peoples.
Once said,
the Jew is the demon behind the
corruption of mankind.
These pictures prove it.
Jewish home life reveals remarkable lack
of creative ability to civilize
in plain language.
Jewish dwellings are filthy and
neglected
bidding on it all.
Poor after decades of business,
they've hoarded enough to acquire a
decent comfortable home,
but they live for generations in the
same dirty and bug or written dwellings.
No,
I'm troubled by their surroundings.
They go right on with their prayers
depending on the vehicle.
And the rubbing motion is part of the
ritual for reading Jewish scripture.
Yeah.
How part of Jewish so-called community
life even takes place in the street.
The connection with trade,
you know,
you see what's going on in that.
Okay.
So what's the juxtaposition of those two
films?
You see?
The juxtaposition of order versus chaos.
And so part of the order versus chaos
archetype obviously is,
is rooted in the dichotomy between
disgust and purity.
It's not the only,
not the only access of our opposition
between order and chaos.
And then so this is all invocation of
archetipal chaos and it starts with the
use of the disease imagery.
And then also the use of music composed
in a minor key and threatening and low,
right?
So that's all juxtaposed together and
then they switched to trade again with
this undertone of threat and there's a
hand to hand exchange of goods and it
seems to me that they're,
they're using the image to continue the
metaphor that in this situation trade is
associated with contamination rather
than productivity.
Right?
And so you and you can see obviously a
dichotomy with regards to trade because
when you're taking goods from someone
else,
the question is,
are the goods of high quality and useful
or,
and are they useful?
Are they something that is going to
introduce a foreign element or,
or an unexpected element into your
house.
And so this film is obviously taking the
ambivalence that's associated with trade
and placing it into the chaos order
archetype and then associating it with
disgust.
So it's very,
very sneaky and it's not done.
It's done by inference rather than
directly,
which I think is much more powerful way
of doing this sort of thing.
And one of the things that's interesting
too is that you know,
you can imagine that if you're,
if you're seeing people who are poor and
downtrodden at that might evoke two
possible sets of responses.
When might be a compassionate response,
that would be the desire to help,
right?
And the other would be the desire to
distance yourself.
Of course,
you feel the same thing.
For example,
if you're walking down bloor and you
find somebody who's completely wreck
street person lying there in their
sleeping bag in a doorway,
it's like,
well,
what's your response going to be?
Is it compassionate or is it.
Is it fear?
Is it disgust?
Well,
it's going to depend on your mood and
all sorts of other things.
It's gonna depend on the particulars of
the situation.
It's going to depend on your
temperament,
but you can see that those two things,
they're both automatically vocable
responses and it isn't self evident
which one is going to come to the fore.
Nor is it always self evident which one
should come to the fore.
Because part of the reason that you're
ambivalent about a situation like that
is because you have no idea what would
happen even if you did choose to
interact and so you can't just simply,
what would you say?
There's no simple way of solving a
problem like that and so that's why
there's a war of competing emotions when
you're in a,
when you're in a situation like that,
but you could imagine as well you could
have taken the same images and put them
to different music and used a different
overlay and it could have been a call to
compassion,
but that's not what it is here.
It's a call to contempt and
extermination
because that's also another danger of I
suppose insisting upon the fact that a
given population is
cool,
victimized.
I suppose that might be way of one way
of thinking about because there's two
different sets of categorical responses
to people who are at the bottom of the
dominance hierarchy and one of them is
compassion,
but the other one is more like this.
It's not necessarily something that you
want to carelessly evoke.
One might want to regard these haggling.
Children as a sign of great poverty,
watch them awhile.
It becomes clear that they're proud to
act as their grownups.
Do.
You use young people,
don't have the idealism that ours do
with them.
The egoism of the individual is not in
the service of higher common goals.
Instead,
Jewish morality.
In kras contradiction of the Aryan
concept of ethics proclaims the
unrestrained egoism of every Jew to be
divine.
Law
is religion makes cheating and usury a
duty.
In the fifth book of Moses,
for example,
it has stated that a non Jew vow may
loan to upon usury,
but not my brother.
The Lord may bless thee in all ID lanes
for the Jews.
Then doing business is something holy.
This is totally incomprehensible.
Did Non Jews Aryan man attaches a sense
of worth to every activity he wants to
create something worthwhile.
Clothing,
houses or machines.
Yeah,
so there's a contrast there.
They actually use a contrast there
between industrious and non industrious
too,
which is quite interesting.
Works of art
or anything else of value to everyone.
He's ruled by the feeling of being
responsible for his achievements,
right?
For the Jew.
One thing of value money,
oh,
he gets it,
makes no difference.
The first trade goods,
generally worthless trash of all sorts.
That's how the little Jews start out.
So they reached the point where they can
sell from a tray and before long they've
assembled a complete line of goods,
not long after the owner,
regular stand,
the most ambitious,
soon own a small shop,
and then a bigger shop
wouldn't be the most cunning.
That is the most unscrupulous eventually
have warehouses in banks and move it to
the most splendid mentions in the city
is provided that they don't get in each
other's way as in the narrow ghettos of
the east.
That's why they try to escape to witch
lands with rich people.
Right
need.
So when the next part of the film,
there's another something else that's
done implicitly.
So you'll see a globe and then their
spread of of migration and the
underlying metaphor there is again,
the spread of disease
peoples because they need the.
Whereas with which to do business
creative,
Aryan people's find the value has been
reduced by the Jew to the mere
merchandise he buys and sells.
That produces nothing.
Yeah,
he leaves to the workers and farmers of
the host nation.
It's funny there.
There's an echo of Marxist ideology in
there too.
That's very interesting because what
they're there to get the insistence is
that the Labor that goes into basic
production qualifies as Labor,
but the labor that goes into mercantile
activity doesn't qualify as Labor at
all.
It's not like the Nazis were pro
capitalist by any stretch of the
imagination.
So there's this strange distinction
drawn between like it's almost like
physical production.
That seems to be something that's
valued.
It's the use of your musculature say,
but then as soon as it's elevated up
into trade,
which is obviously a value added
process,
I mean that.
That's almost self evident,
but it's put forward here as something
that's only.
That's only a parasitical that's right.
That and that's commonality with Marxism
of the time.
The Jews are people without farmers or
workers or race of parasites
in the dark.
Wherever the body of a nation shows a
wound,
they anchor themselves and feed on the
decaying organism.
They make business out of the sickness
of the nations,
therefore endeavor to deepen and prolong
all conditions of sickness.
That's how it is.
In Poland and was in Germany,
the Jews had been this way throughout
their entire history.
Their faces bear the age old features of
the perpetual sponger eternal Jew who in
the course of time on worldwide
wonderings has always been the same.
There's no difference between these Jews
in Poland and those in Palestine,
though the two are geographically
separated.
Palestine is the spiritual center of
international jewelry.
No,
the Jews are numerically insignificant.
They're
here at the Wailing Wall.
They gather and more in the fall of
Jerusalem.
Homelessness though is a matter of and
in keeping with their entire history
4,000 years ago,
their Hebrew ancestors were already
wondering out of the land of two rivers,
they wandered along the sea to Egypt
where they ran a lucrative grain
business for awhile when the country
farmer is and other Egyptians rose
against the foreign use,
yours and speculators,
they wondered once more and plundered
their way to the promised land.
They settled there mercilessly.
Looting the culturally superior rightful
inhabitants.
Yeah,
and bigger windows here in the course of
centuries from the oriental far eastern
racial mixture with negroid admixture,
the ultimate mom realized Jews developed
foreign from us Europeans born of
totally different racial elements.
They differ from us in body and above
all in Seoul.
We probably would never have been
bothered by them had they stayed in
their oriental home
about the cosmopolitan empire of
Alexander the great reaching from the
Near East across half the Mediterranean
and especially the boundless world
empire of the Romans,
brought about the evolution of the trade
and migratory traits of the Jews who
soon spread across the open
Mediterranean area.
While some of them settled in the large
urban traffic and trade centers of the
Mediterranean,
it could be up on youtube.
I'm doing
others wandered relentlessly on across
Spain,
France,
southern Germany and England and
everywhere they made themselves
unwelcome in Spain and France.
The people rose openly against them in
the 13th and 14th centuries and they
wandered on mainly to Germany.
Follow the path of the Aryan culture,
creative Germans colonizing the east.
They finally found the gigantic new
untapped reservoir in the Polish and
Russian sections of eastern Europe.
So well let's let's tie that together.
We talked about the use of archetypes,
archetypes in stories.
We talked about the the relationship
between archetypal symbolism and the
biological underpinnings of the human
psyche,
and then you can see that manifesting
itself in this sort of propaganda in the
political positions that come out of it.
Did he tap into the archetype?
Archetypal dimension?
That's chaos versus order.
You can.
You can place one against the other
however you want from a propaganda
perspective because you could make a
film decrying excessive order that
that's not a difficult thing to do,
but that isn't what happened here.
Order is associated with the sun and
with what's good and with honest labor
and with purity and with and chaos is
associated with decay and disgust and
and impurity and also with trade,
which is extremely interesting and the
trade dynamic.
You could see that in the second part of
the film there,
there was a.
There was the implication that it was
involvement in trade that was associated
with this pathological spread.
Right,
and so trade ins,
that's another reflection of the
ambivalence towards the transgression of
borders.
Is trade a good thing or is it a bad
thing?
Well,
that's always a political issue.
It's a huge political issue right now,
right?
You're going to have internationalist
trade.
You're going to close the borders.
You can have internationalist trade and
open editor.
You're going to close the borders and so
the degree to which the border should be
open or closed.
I think generally speaking is the prime
political question and of course we're
going through an absolute convulsion of
that sort of argumentation.
Again,
right now.
Part of the reason I wanted to show you
this,
I mean there's a variety of reasons.
I wanted to show you
how the,
how the archetype and the underlying
biology are are tightly associated,
but I also wanted to show you how those
associations can be hijacked essentially
and used for propagandistic and
political purposes because you need to
know that because these sorts of things
have a very powerful.
They have the capacity for a very
powerful emotional appeal and the only
possible way of resisting that I would
say,
and and avoiding the temptation of
allowing extraordinarily complex issues
to be catastrophic.
We reduced to there too.
Two principals that are far too simple
to do them justice is to become at least
aware to some degree of what the
mechanisms for the production of such
propaganda are and why they have such
potency than you have at least some
ghost of a chance of reducing your own.
What would you call it?
Proclivity.
We could even call it a temperamental
proclivity to the kind of propaganda
stick information that happens to suit
your temperament best,
so while we all know the aftermath of
this sort of thing,
right?
It was absolutely dreadful and we're by
no means out of the woods on that yet
you see in Europe and in the United
States increasingly calls for the
nationalistic enclosure of borders.
Again,
you saw that with trump and the building
of the wall between Mexico and the
United States,
so these things can get very badly out
of hand and it's a.
it's a very bad idea to allow things to
swing too far to one way or too far to
the other because all hell breaks loose
when you do that.
Well.
All right,
we'll see you on Thursday.