Hey everyone,
here we go.
So I,
I saw somebody ask right off the bat if
there were any women,
I think they said girls actually,
if there are any women in the audience,
um,
and if there are,
well that's good.
So welcome.
Um,
thanks to all you Patriot people for
your continued support.
It's a really big deal.
It's made a huge difference in,
you're a big part of the reason that
Biblical lecture was so ridiculously
successful.
I think more than 2 million people have
watched it so far.
So that's success by any stretch of the
imagination.
So let's start with some questions here.
I've got to live chat going and um,
we also set it up so that,
uh,
we had,
we had questions taken to begin with
without people could up vote,
which seems to be a good idea.
Let's start with one from practice cube.
What would be a practical approach for
developing your shadow?
Well,
that's a good one.
Let's,
let's do a little review of union
psychology.
The first thing is if you want to know
about this,
the proper sources,
Carl Jung's collected works volume nine,
volume nine,
and there's two parts to volume nine a
and be published as separate texts.
And volume nine is called archetypes of
the collective unconscious and the other
one is called a ion.
But in archetypes of the collective
unconscious,
there's a good discussion of the persona
and the shadow and the persona you could
say is a good way of thinking about it.
You know,
you watch all those Rom coms where
there's always kind of a Beta male guy
who's being real friendly and always
failing miserably with women because
basically he's lying to himself and to
them.
Um,
he's a persona and a persona is the face
that you show to the world when you're
trying to pretend and to convince
yourself and others that you're,
I would say harmless,
but we could say a good person,
but a good person isn't harmless.
A good person is capable of,
well,
maybe a good person is capable of
anything,
but is willing to hold that in a
beyonce.
I read this interesting commentary a
little while.
I'll go on a statement by Christ in the
New Testament.
And the statement generally interpreted
is that the meek shall inherit the
earth.
But I was looking up the multiple
translations of the word meek.
And Meek is actually derived from a
Greek word of course.
Um,
because the Bible,
at least some of the original forms of
the Bible were in Greek.
Um,
and that word didn't exactly mean meek.
It meant something like,
uh,
those who have weapons and the ability
to use them,
but sir,
but determined to keep them sheets will
inherit the world.
And that means that people who are
capable of force,
let's say,
but decide not to use it,
are in the proper moral position.
And Neat.
You commented on that a fair bit too.
You know,
he,
um,
thought of most moral morality has
cowardice not because morality itself
was cowardice,
but because most people who are cowards
disguise their coward,
cowardice as morality and they claim
that they're harmlessness,
which is actually a consequence of their
fear and inability to be harmful,
say,
or to be dangerous is actually a sign of
their moral integrity.
And that's a really bad idea.
So,
you know,
if you're an ax murderer but you don't
have an ax,
that doesn't mean that your moral.
So now with regards to it,
so that's the persona and the persona is
the mask that you wear.
And that's what persona means is the
mask that you wear to convince yourself
and the world that you're not a terrible
monster.
So that when you look at yourself in the
mirror,
you don't have to run away screaming.
You know,
when you might think,
well that's a bit of an overstatement,
but [inaudible] was very interested in
phenomena such as say,
psychological,
the psychological phenomena that would
characterize the actions of someone who
might be an Auschwitz camp guard for
example.
And uh,
you know,
that's pretty monstrous form of
behavior.
And the thing about Auschwitz camp
guards is that there's no reason to
assume really that they were much
different than normal people.
Now,
there would have been exceptions
obviously,
but,
and what that means is that perhaps you
two could be an Auschwitz camp guard and
perhaps he would even derive some
enjoyment out of it.
And you might think not,
but you shouldn't think not so quickly.
And what that also implies is that if
you could see what that meant when you
looked in the mirror and looked at
yourself,
you might run away screaming because
you'd have a revelation of just exactly
what the human being is capable of.
And that's a very unpleasant revelation.
And also one of the things that stops
people from being enlightened because
that revelation of the evil of the self
is part of the journey to enlightenment
and an early part.
Now the shadow be all the parts of the
personality that the persona rejects.
And that might be the aggressive
elements.
Certainly the case that's the case with
for people who are hyper agreeable.
And now you can tell,
I think one of the best,
there's two pathways to the development
of the shadow and they're tightly
aligned with one another.
Um,
the fundamental pathway is truth and
that's to face the bitter truth about
yourself.
But to break that down more
particularly,
you might think about that as the
capacity to observe your own resentment.
You're going to be resentful and bitter
in many situations because you don't get
what you want.
And if you watch that resentment,
bitterness,
clc,
that it produces fantasies that can be
unbelievably dark and that can be very
frightening.
And you might not want to admit to
yourself that you're actually capable of
having fantasies like that or impulses
like that,
or aggressive feelings like that.
But the thing is is that if those
aggressive feelings and impulses and
fantasies are integrated into your
character,
it's like you're opening up a dialogue
with a part of yourself that can be very
forceful and strong and dangerous.
And it's really useful to be dangerous
because if you can,
if you can be dangerous,
you often don't have to be,
and it's,
it's often weak people,
for example,
it's weak men generally speaking,
who rape,
you know that that's a very,
very common occurrence and that's a
violent act,
but it's born out of weakness,
not out of strength,
that's for sure.
And so anyways,
you attend to your resentment honestly,
and you observe yourself and what you're
actually like.
You got to pay attention as if you don't
know yourself as if you might harbor
hidden devils and then maybe they'll
emerge.
Now you'll also felt that sort of
embedded inside the shout at where the
contras sexual tendencies.
And so for example,
sometimes you see people who are well
developed men let's say.
And we can,
we can also talk about women in this
regard.
Men who've integrated their shadow often
also develop a kind of peculiar grace
that would be a consequence of not only
allowing their aggressive side to step
forward but also their,
their feminine and Compassionate side
that might,
that they may have kept squelched
because of embarrassment about it or
because they'd been harassed for being
weak or any number of things.
So,
but the practical approach for
developing your shadow I would say is to
contemplate and consider your resentment
and notice what it says and cause your
resentment will also tell you what you
have to say.
You know,
look at,
look at what happened to Google this
weekend.
You know,
James Damore wrote that memo and you can
imagine he was pretty angry and perhaps
even somewhat resentful at having to
attend that diversity seminar.
And I'm really just using this as an
example,
but what he did was decide that that
meant that he had something that he had
to say and then look at the consequences
of that man.
It's an absolutely unbelievable.
And so you know,
if your feet and pressed at work or
you're oppressed in your life for or you
know,
or you're oppressing yourself,
then you got a notice that you're
feeling oppressed,
then you have to notice that you're
feeling resentful,
resentful and angry and bitter.
And maybe even like Cain in the story of
Cain Abel Cause Cain is sort of the
architectural bitter man.
And then you have to decide what it is
that you need to do in order to remove
from yourself that bitterness.
And that's usually means that there's
something that you have to say.
And then you have to say it because
you're sold depends on it.
And not only does your soul depending on
it,
I would say the fate of the world
depends on it because you know you might
be wrong and then you should be
straightened out.
Maybe you're just being whiny and you
have to talk to somebody about that.
But it may be that you're actually
detecting something wrong,
some tyranny that's directed towards you
and other people and it's like your
moral obligation to speak up about it.
And so many workplaces become toxic to
use a terrible clash cliche because of
the people in them won't speak up for
what they actually want or they speak up
too late and then they're all twisted up
about it and,
and you know they're torturing other
people because they're so unhappy and so
forth and so on.
So practical approach for developing new
shout of fundamentally is radical
honesty.
And Young said that I know a genuine
moral effort was a good substitute for
psychotherapy.
Yeah.
What is my opinion on open
relationships,
polyamory,
other forms of non monogamy?
Well,
I think that as a medium to longterm
strategy,
they're completely untenable because
human beings,
as far as I'm concerned,
are fundamentally pair bonding.
And you know,
if you're just talking about casual sex,
first of all,
I think casual sex is a contradiction in
terms.
I don't think there's anything about sex
that's casual.
And I think that people are deceiving
themselves badly whenever they think.
So they might like to live in a,
you know,
1970s playboy adolescent fantasy.
But I don't,
I've never seen that work under any
circumstances whatsoever.
And I think people get hurt badly.
It's also a bad medium to longterm
strategy because,
you know,
pair bonding is,
uh,
is the most stable arrangement we know
of at least so far.
Well,
I won't even put it that way.
It's the only stable,
uh,
mode of being that we know for the long
run.
And that's especially the case when you
bring children into the equation.
So,
um,
I think it's delusional fundamentally.
And I think that people who are,
who believe that such things work,
I mean,
sometimes they're open people in their
creative and their exploratory and all
of that and fair enough,
but often they're just unconscientious
and they don't want to take any
responsibility and they want to live in
this wish fulfillment fantasy where
everybody can have all the sex they want
all the time.
And it's always wonderful and no one
gets hurt.
And it's like,
sorry,
that just doesn't work in the real
world.
So
my girlfriend is quite overweight,
but I really love her.
Should I try to encourage her to lose
weight?
Aside from personal preference,
is this likely to explode into a major
issue down the road?
Huh.
I don't think that you can fool yourself
about what you're attracted to and yes,
it's certainly likely to develop into a
major issue down the road.
Um,
it's tough,
you know,
uh,
because,
so
the devil's in
the details,
you know,
should you try to encourage her to lose
weight?
I guess the question is how would you do
that without disrupting the
relationship?
Um,
okay.
And without knowing more about the
details of that,
I would say that I don't know how to
tell what to tell you to do about that.
I think that it's necessary to be
truthful in a relationship period.
But I also think that you can't use the
truth to hurt,
you know,
the truth is a very complicated thing
and it's,
it's a sword and it cuts and you can't
use it to hurt.
Now,
you know,
maybe you would be subtle enough to
figure out some way that you could both
embark on a health promoting endeavor
together and that would work out.
Um,
but I would say,
you know,
if you,
if you're in under stable longterm
relationship with someone,
it's pretty much necessary for both of
you to address all the issues that are
making you unhappy with each other.
Um,
you know,
assuming there's some give and take on
that because otherwise the relationship
can easily come apart at the seams.
Like I would say,
my wife and I are both very hard on each
other about our physical appearance,
let's say.
And I had gained a fair bit of weight
from the time I was say 40 until the
time I was 50 about probably because I
was eating things that weren't good for
me.
And I would say that was primarily
carbohydrates.
I can tell you if you want to lose
weight,
you stop eating carbohydrates,
man,
you'll lose weight.
Like you wouldn't believe.
Um,
I wouldn't necessarily recommend it
because it has some dangerous,
but it certainly works.
But you know,
the,
the alternative to protect to the
alternative is to pretend that
everything's all right.
And all that means is that you're likely
to get drunk sometimes some day and have
an affair out of bitterness and spite in
the fact that you're no longer attracted
to your partner.
So it's pretty rough.
So that's a pretty rough way of thinking
about things,
but life's pretty rough.
So what is the story behind the logo
that you use in your intros?
Where did it come from?
That's,
that logo is called the meaning of
music.
And it's actually a sculpture that I
made in 1985 that's about s five and a
half feet by half,
five and a half feet and about eight
inches thick.
And it's made out of foam core,
which is this bay.
It's a subset.
It's a material that's often used as a
backing for paintings or for when you
get them framed,
it's it's styrofoam sheet about a
quarter of an inch thick with paper on
both sides and you can cut it very
accurately with an exacto knife.
And so what I did was make a stack of
those,
um,
uh,
those foam core sheets about 80 inches
high and it made the thing in quarters
and so that it would fit together on the
wall because it would have been too big
to maneuver easily.
And,
um,
it's a very complicated image.
It's actually a three dimensional
representation of a,
it's a three dimensional representation
of a two dimensional representation of a
four dimensional object and that four
dimensional object you could think of as
it's a representation of time and space.
And I can tell you,
I kind of have to hint at what the
painting means.
It or the sculpture,
it means the same thing.
That music means,
you know,
how music unfolds and then something
else unfolds within it.
And then it unfolds again within it,
like a rose opening into the,
into the day,
or like a lotus flower that sort of
comes up from the darkest steps up
through the dark water and then blooms
on the,
on the surface of the water and the sun.
And that's where the Buddha,
you know,
um,
what would you say?
Symbol symbolically rest.
So it can imagine that thing opening and
then imagine that that's what that
painting is an image of.
And that's the same thing as music.
So it's a Mandela image.
And for young,
the Mandela was a symbol of the self and
the self was something that unfolds like
music,
which is actually why we like music.
And it's like the,
the rose,
the rose that you see,
the,
the geometric rose that you see in stain
glass.
It's the same thing.
Um,
that's the Stain Glass Window that
Pinocchio's reprehensible,
compatriot.
Um,
what's his name?
Lamp.
Wick breaks when he's in pleasure island
and he throws it rock to destroy the
model home and to demolish the
substructure of Western civilization.
And so I had a very intense religious
experience at one point when I was
contemplating that.
So when I drew the image to begin with,
I drew it in about 10 minutes,
kind of rough.
And then I used a straight edge to
straighten it all open and a protractor
to,
or a compass to make the curves.
But I drew it very quickly and I'd been
thinking about,
I've been reading young a lot at that
point,
like for,
for months,
months of intense reading.
And that image sort of popped out of me
very,
um,
very suddenly.
But it took about three months to make
the actual image.
And then I had only a quarter of it
hanging on my wall because it was so
big.
And I had finished it after about three
months of work.
So this was back in 1985 when I was a
graduate student and I was listening to
the Jupiter symphony,
which is the piece of music that I use,
um,
that was used for the intro to my,
to my videos.
And it's a Mozart symphony.
And this happened,
man.
So this happened.
So I was really watching that,
um,
Mandela that quarter,
Mandela,
that I had made intensely and caught
listening to the music,
trying to understand what the music
music was signifying,
you know,
because music has intrinsic meaning,
which is a very strange thing.
Now,
the part of the reason for that is that
language has meaning and our language
has a musical quality,
right?
And that's process mostly by the right
hemisphere,
so that when people speak,
there's a,
there's a melody in their language and
that carries a lot of the emotional
import.
And then what musicians have done is
figured out how to use that,
that,
that musical faculty,
let's call it that,
no one semantic musical faculty to sort
of purely denote meaning.
That's part of what music means.
And so,
but I was still trying to understand
what the meaning was.
You know what,
because it's the meaning of music and I
was trying to figure out how to
articulate that.
And that's partly why I made the,
the sculpture was to get a grip on it
and to understand it in anyways,
I was really,
really concentrating hard on that.
Mandela and that sculpture and I had
been working on it intensely for about
three months,
you know,
so that's a lot of meditation on a
single idea.
And I was standing in my living room and
then I had this very strange experience.
I,
and I,
I can't explain this properly because
there's no way of really describing it,
but I'll do my best.
So you know,
when those renaissance painting
sometimes you see,
well first of all,
you see great cloud,
great,
great sunny skies with,
with massive what?
Stupendous impressive bills of clouds
and then light shining through the
sunlight shining through in streams.
Sometimes that's captured very
beautifully by especially English later,
later artists usually that or later than
the renaissance.
But you see it renaissance paintings
too.
And you all,
you also see it in,
in,
in renaissance paintings,
especially in the earlier phase of the
renaissance,
the sky opening up in God sort of
peering for through the clouds.
And that's exactly what seemed to happen
to me is that I had this sense,
it was like a vision,
although I was still in my living room
in Nuuk,
but inside the theater of,
of my imagination,
I could feel the,
the sky opening up now,
it wasn't the sky,
it was,
I would say the only way I can really
think about it is that with was
something like another dimension and
then I can feel this force descend upon
me,
which I think was something that,
you know,
would have been considered classically
something like the holy ghost I suppose.
And it filled me with this intense sense
of,
of Paradise.
A Paradise Ul.
Wow.
I don't know how to say it though.
Okay.
While it was like being in heaven for
some,
some brief period of time and I could
feel myself transformed,
transmuted as a consequence of this
experience.
And,
and it was as if I was in the presence
of something that was living,
you know,
and I,
I suppose that was an experience of God,
if you want to put it that way.
Um,
that's certainly what it seemed like an,
and I felt that I could live that way.
I could live transfigured like that
permanently if I desired it.
And I thought,
my God,
I wouldn't be able to walk down the
street in this sort of elevated state,
let's say.
I don't know how I would act.
I don't know how he would interact with
people.
I don't know how people would interact
with me.
I just don't think that I could do it.
And then I felt that whatever had
descended,
it seemed that as if it was soro full in
it and it,
and it departed from me slowly and um,
with no,
like with no punitive intent.
And,
and I wouldn't say with any
dissatisfaction,
it was as if the gift had been offered
that I wasn't in no position to receive.
And,
uh,
I went,
I talked to my wife soon afterwards.
I shook for about physically for about
half an hour after that,
uh,
experience like,
like I was shaking,
you know,
like,
like you shake after a car accident if
you've ever been in a car accident.
And my pupils were completely dilated
and I had a couple of experiences like
that,
like echoes of it a couple of times
after that.
And so anyways,
that was a very,
very powerful experience.
I've certainly never forgotten that.
And um,
well,
you know,
I dunno why,
I dunno what to think about that.
I mean,
God only knows what the world is really
like,
that's for sure.
And I've had a variety of very strange
experiences that have convinced me that
we know very little about anything.
So,
um,
for those who are very creative but high
in neuroticism,
how should one work to gain emotional
stability in order to go out into chaos
to do more creative things?
That's a really good question.
You know what?
I learned about that by reading Ewing's
works on El Camino,
weirdly enough.
And so back again in graduate school
when I was writing,
starting to write maps and meaning and
really tearing myself apart
psychologically,
I'm trying to understand evil,
I suppose the evil of the Cold War and
the evil of the individuals who compose
Nazi Germany and Stella,
this Russia.
Um,
uh,
I,
I was reading Carl Jung because he,
he,
he wrote his tracks on alchemy where a
lot about self transformation and he
talked about,
uh,
it's hard to explain his works on
Alchemy,
but suffice it to say that his advice
was something like,
the advice he derived from the alchemist
was that if you are going to make mess
around with very complicated and
dangerous matters,
that's a good way of putting it.
That you should really put your life
together.
And so I would say the right way to deal
with your neuroticism is to increase
your conscientiousness because we also
know that the higher your
conscientiousness,
the lower year neuroticism
conscientiousness does seem to keep
neuroticism and check.
And so I would say,
and have said this to many people,
um,
clean your room,
organize your life,
like get a routine,
get up every day at the same time.
Go to bed at the same time.
Established disciplined habits and that
will help a lot schedule like,
and here's how to use a schedule.
Use it.
Use a calendar.
I use Google calendar,
but don't use it as a tyrant.
You know,
you want to use your,
use a calendar as if it's your,
um,
your confidant and advisor.
And what you want to do is use the
calendar,
sit down and open the calendar and
think,
okay,
well here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to design a week of days that
I would really like to have.
So what that would mean is that you
would schedule things that you would
consider meaningful and productive,
you know,
on a daily basis so that you feel that
your life is justified by having a day
like that.
And also to schedule enough of your
responsibilities so that you make
progress day by day instead of falling
farther behind.
And what that'll do is it doesn't
directly affect your neurophysiology,
but you know,
you're reacting as a neurotic person,
a person high in neuroticism say you
react to uncertainty and the unexpected
with more physiological preparedness and
more expenditure of energy than the
typical person.
And so what you want to do is organize
your surroundings because it's a lot
easier to organize your surroundings at
least to begin with than it is to do
radical reconstruction on your
fundamental temperament,
which you might not be able to do at
all.
So I would say discipline,
discipline.
And the other thing I would say for
creative people,
and this is true for people in general,
but it's really important for creative
people,
is that if you want to be creative,
which is very,
very dangerous and very,
very unlikely to succeed,
although absolutely necessary if you
happened to be high in openness,
is that you should organize the rest of
your life except for your creative
endeavors in a pretty traditional and
conservative manner.
If you can do that,
because what that does is buttress you
against the unexpected and give you some
stability on many,
you know,
along many of the potential dimensions
of your life.
And that frees you up to take larger
risks in the creative domain.
Now it's hard for creative people to do
that because they're sort of blasting
out,
you know,
laterally in all directions
simultaneously.
But you exhaust yourself that way and
you also risk scattering yourself.
Um,
Louie waterson here at,
at a question,
how would you suggest someone who's a
jack of all trades and master of none
conduct themselves while you're probably
high in openness,
high in creativity.
And one of the dangers of being high and
creativity,
especially if you're also high in
neuroticism,
is that it's hard for creative people to
catalyze an identity because they're
basically pan like,
you know,
like Peter Pan or like,
or like Pan,
which means everything that God of the
forest is the god of everything to some
degree.
And the problem with being everything is
that you're also nothing at the same
time because you never specialized.
And so I would say that if you're,
I think that being a jack of all trades,
it's pretty damn useful.
But I would also say that it's really
necessary to buckle down and find one
primary motive discipline and Jack or
Louie.
If you can't figure out what you should
do,
then guess,
just pick something that you think that
you could hit hard and concentrate on.
You don't have to be perfect at it.
You don't even have to get it right,
but pick something rather than nothing
or pick something rather than all
things.
And then set yourself to master that
because you know,
you need to have a,
uh,
um,
discipline,
a primary discipline.
It's absolutely necessary to succeed in
life.
Now,
once you have a primary discipline,
then you can branch out and become a
multiplicity in your disciplined
approach.
And then you're absolutely bloody
unstoppable.
But you really need that initial
disciplinary routine.
You know,
this is something neat you knew,
knew very well.
He said,
for example,
I just wrote about this today,
that um,
it was the long unfreedom of,
of Europe subjugation to the dogmatic
structures of the Catholic Church that
in noble the European mind and gave it
the capacity to widely range that it
eventually developed.
But it was that initial subjugation,
that initial voluntary slavery that
produced the discipline that produced
the spirit that can then go out and do
other things.
And it's really,
really useful to subjugate yourself
something to something voluntarily.
You know,
I think that's partly why it's useful to
practice a religious faith because you
subject yourself to a disciplinary
structure that way.
And you might think,
well that's all oppressive and all of
that.
And of course that's true,
but it also makes you disciplined.
And once you're disciplined,
like you're,
you're like a sharpened sword man,
like well tempered blade and then you
can go out there and operate in the
world.
So,
and if you haven't found your passion,
then I would say,
well don't wait around till you find the
damn thing because you may never find it
is pick something and focus on it,
you know?
And if you move strongly and
forthrightly towards it for a number of
months at least,
or even a number of years,
and then you find,
well that wasn't the thing for you,
it isn't going to be a waste anyways
because most of the time the pursuit of
any discipline,
knowledge pays off even if it doesn't
pay off in the way that you initially
expect.
So Alex Burnstein said,
what is the female equivalent of the
hero archetype?
Hmm,
that's a great question man.
Um,
I spent a lot of time thinking about
this and of course the women in my class
and perhaps some of the women online to
are irritated or,
or put off or maybe just alienated and
perhaps properly sold by the fact that
the archetypal hero is masculine.
Now there's complex reasons for that and
I would recommend for those who are
actually interested in such things to
read Eric Noi Amens the origins and
history of consciousness and also the
great mother,
which are two great works of union
psychology.
Uh,
Camille Paglia,
by the way,
is a big fan of both of those books.
For those of you who might be interested
because Norman does the best job that I
know of,
of describing why the symbolism of the
hero is laid out the way it is.
Why Mother Nature,
his mother feminine and why the hero is
masculine now,
now.
But here's how I've come to understand
it and I'm going to use Christian
symbolic language because I uh,
because it's,
it's the quickest,
it's the shortest route to this sort of
explanation.
So I would say that in the male psyche,
the Dragon,
the dragon slaying hero is at the
forefront.
And so that would be Christ in the
architectural mode.
Because this dragon,
he defeats is the evil that that is
encompassed in,
in within the figure of Satan.
So that'd be like the ultimate dragon.
And then behind that is the feminine,
that compassionate,
the caring.
And that would be embodied say in the
Christian figure of Mary.
So you have an in both male,
in the male and female soul,
let's say you have Christ and Mary,
but in the mail,
Christ is foremost,
foremost,
that's the dragon slayer,
we'll say.
And Mary is the secondary character.
And although both should be very well
developed and,
and,
and that means that makes for a much
better character.
And in the female,
it's the other way around is that the
maternal slash feminine.
So let's say Mary is,
is at the forefront and Christ is in the
background,
the dragon slayers,
the background,
but should be well developed.
Um,
young felt that,
you know,
it was possible for men to develop the
more feminine side of themselves,
especially in the last half of life,
which is also when he felt that women
should develop the more masculine side
of themselves.
And you know,
we can,
could debate that,
but it's a perfectly reasonable
proposition.
Now we should note that the figure of
Mary is actually,
uh,
is,
is actually,
what would you say,
a heroic figure in and of itself,
because like you can really understand
this.
If you look at Michelangelo's Pieta.
So in that great sculpture,
you see Mary Who's holding the crucified
Christ and that's basically her son,
right?
Her,
her,
her son,
who's just being offered up to the world
and betrayed by his friends and broken
on the cross.
In other words,
he's being subject to the worst that
life can throw at him.
And the thing about Mary is that she
knew initially when she agreed to give
birth to the savior of mankind,
that he would be broken.
And that's an archetypal story because
women know in their heart of hearts that
their children are going to be broken
and killed by the world.
That that's the human condition.
And so there's a car.
And of course a woman who's a,
who's a woman who's well developed,
loves her child more than herself,
loves her job more than anyone else,
which is something you can't really
understand until you've had a child.
But he's still willing to bring that
child into the world knowing full well
what his or her fate will be.
And so there's a real heroism and APP.
And so,
and then there's the standard here
wisdom that a woman can undertake where
she develops her masculine side,
which is basically what happens for
example,
in sleeping beauty,
when,
when sleeping beauty is awakened by the
princess kiss.
You can think of that.
You can think of her being rescued by an
actual man.
But you can also think of that as the
masculine part of her psyche,
waking up her unconscious femininity so
that the two of them can unite and rule
the kingdom.
It's perfectly reasonable interpretation
of that story.
And so,
and so that would be the development of
the masculine side in,
in,
in a female that decide that stout
stalwart and forthright and willing to
go forth into the world and con and
conquer uncertainty.
And,
and then there's the beauty and the
beast archetype,
which I think is,
is in some sense the primary female
sexual archetype and beauty and the
beast is another kind of dragon slaying
story.
It's more like a dragon taming story,
I suppose,
where the,
the woman,
um,
the virginal woman who's,
who's out for an adventure finds a
beastly male.
And that's the dangerous man that I was
talking about earlier,
right?
The man who has the capacity say to kill
the capacity to harm the capacity for
violence at hand,
right at hand,
and then proceeds to tame him,
which is a real adventure.
And you know,
we know that this is the case because
again,
we can refer to those,
you know,
bro or those raw rom coms that are so
popular now with the failed Beta males
always trying to make friends with the
girl and failing.
The girls are interested in the rough
guys who have,
who have the capacity to also be
sophisticated and to be,
let's not say tamed,
but civilized into channeling their
harsh roughness,
their capacity for evil,
even into productive competition.
And,
and because competition can be very
productive.
And then the sharing fourth of the
fruits of that competition with,
with family.
And so those are all heroic aspects of
feminine being and,
and they're not to be taken lightly
there.
Major life tasks and major life
contributions,
you know.
And I guess another part of the heroic
element of the female is the subjugation
of her own privacy with regards to her
child.
Because my daughter just had a child by
the way.
So I'm a grandfather,
so hooray for that.
And it went really nicely.
And I'm so happy about that because a,
I love my daughter and be,
I really,
really liked kids.
I think they're so great.
And so now I've got to have kid around
again.
So that's great.
But I mean,
you know,
one of the things you notice very
rapidly if you're a parent is that you
bring someone into the world who is now
more important under all circumstances
than you are.
And there's a,
there's a heroic subjugation of
selfishness that's,
that goes along with that.
That's characteristic.
Deeply characteristic of the property,
develop feminine spirit.
So what is that that you are doing to
avoid becoming arrogant?
You're current situation is very
inviting for that.
Yeah,
well I would say a good dose of
existential terror curia that you know,
there's a,
there's a saying in the old testament
that the fear of God is the beginning of
wisdom and like,
first of all,
and there's some real truth in that,
you know,
like I don't want to make a mistake.
And so I live in constant terror that
I'm going to utter some damning phrase
that's going to sync everything I've
done.
And so I'll tell you,
if you feel that way about the
situation,
then either probability that you're
going to be arrogant.
It's pretty damn low and like I don't
feel I have any reason to be arrogant.
You know,
like here's,
here's something you could do if you're
really interested in this,
but it's really hard.
There's a paper by Carl Jung called the
relations between the ego and
nonconscious and it's an unbelievably
brilliant paper.
It's very difficult to understand,
but it has to do with what young called
ego inflation.
And so imagine that as you move up a
hierarchy of authority or competence,
we're not going to call them dominance
or power hierarchies because I don't
think that's reasonable.
But as you move up,
you know you're,
you have the,
you have the temptation of having your
ego inflate to match your hypothetical
position of status.
But what that is is in some sense the
taking on of the archetype as if it's a
personal triumph or a personal construct
or a per personal invention,
and you'll one very,
very strongly against that.
And he knew what he was talking about
because of course you had his followers
and was an extraordinarily powerful man
from a spiritual and a physical
perspective.
He was certainly no pushover and a very
brave person and he had the temptation
of becoming,
well,
a cult leader for example,
which people have accused him of being
in,
which he certainly wasn't and he knew
that,
you know,
if you,
if you have the privilege of in a,
in a hierarchy,
what that means,
if that rising is real,
is that the archetype is operating
through you and that you can't take
credit for that.
You have to,
you have to separate your personality in
some sense from the architect.
I can give you a funny example of that.
It's like,
and I hope that nobody takes this wrong,
but it's very comical.
You know how all the superheroes have an
alter ego.
So you can't be superman unless you're
also Clark Kent and you can't be,
well,
Batman isn't such a good example because
he gets to be playboy billionaire like
iron man,
but Superman's better example.
You know,
he's this mild mannered in meek reporter
and without that he can't be superman.
It's like,
well that's the reason that's such a
well established comic trope is because
comics are deeply mythological.
And there's the idea there that the
person has these two elements.
One is the archetipal and it's
associated with the infinite.
It's like the God in man.
You could say that.
Um,
there's a great icon by the way of
Christ as pantokrator.
One of the very earliest icons that show
him with two different facial halves.
The eyes are different and the face is
asymmetrical and one one face is the
face of God have faces to have face of
God and the other is the half face of
man.
And he's holding a book.
It's,
I'm having Jonathan Pashto who's a
brilliant carver.
I'm having him carved me that image so
that I can put it in my front porch
because I love it in a Christ is holding
a book.
And so,
you know,
it's,
it's such a beautiful image,
this idea of man as a duality between
the finite and the infinite and,
and simultaneously holding forth this,
you know,
wealth of knowledge that's been gathered
by the human race.
It's mine mind expanding visual imagery.
Anyways,
I mean,
back to the arrogance issue is that,
you know,
I'm,
I'm so Kara co I'm so what would you say
attuned to the fact that I'm barely
staying on that line between chaos and
order and that any foolishness on my
part or any attempt to manipulate the
situation for my own,
let's say selfish,
personal gain,
you know,
that sort of impulsive,
um,
and,
and shallow and immature and,
and shortsighted personal gain that,
that,
that willingness or wished to Lord it
over other people or to feel in some
sense superior man.
If I go there with the exposure that
I've got right now,
I'd be so fast that it wouldn't even be
funny.
And that would not be pretty and I would
not want that.
So I'm,
I'm doing my best man to keep myself on
the ground and whereas where I want to
be and I've got my family to help me
without and I've got my friends who are
offering me,
you know,
corrective criticism on an ongoing basis
and I listened to the negative comments
on eat on youtube and I try to pay
attention to them and evaluate them and
not just dismiss them out of hand.
You know,
if their crude or crass or any of those
things,
then I'm less likely to pay attention to
them.
But you know,
even when I'm called far right,
I pay attention to that.
You know,
because well you got to listen to your
enemy.
That's the thing.
That's another new testament.
In junction you should listen to your
enemy because your enemy will tell you
things about yourself that no one else
will tell you.
Now,
some of those things might not be true,
but some of the might be.
And if your enemy tells you something
terrible about yourself,
that's true,
then he's immediately become your best
friend.
Because you bloody well want to know if
there's something terrible about you so
that you can get it rectified before it
ruins your life and ruins your family's
life and you know,
detrimentally affects the course of the
world and all of that.
So,
um,
in one of your lectures you said the
film frozen was garbage.
I don't think I said garbage.
I think I said reprehensible propaganda,
which I believe it was.
Can you elaborate on your thoughts on
the film?
I can't because I haven't seen it
recently enough to,
um,
the only thing I can say is that I left
the film with a strong sense that it was
produced for ideological reasons and it
was produced as a sort of anti sleeping
beauty.
And I felt that was entirely
inappropriate because it wasn't a
genuine artistic attempt.
It was an ideological statement.
I actually really liked [inaudible] I
hope I'm pronouncing that properly.
I thought it was that.
I liked that,
you know,
that little girl in the movie allied
herself with is very,
very powerful but rather uncivilized
masculine force.
And I thought they got the archetypal
balance in that film really quite,
really quite nicely.
So I thought it was quite beautifully
done.
So I liked Marianna quite a bit.
What were you like when I was 25?
Hmm,
well,
I was obsessed.
I'm 25,
so that would have been 87.
I'd been in graduate school for two
years.
Well,
you know,
um,
when I was 25 or so,
I probably weighed about 138 pounds.
I smoked like a pack of cigarettes day.
I drank tremendous amount of alcohol.
I was from northern Alberta,
this rough little town up in northern
Alberta called fairview.
And you know,
there were long winters there and my
friends were heavy drinkers and most of
them dropped out of school by the time
they were 15 or 16.
Went off to work on the oil rigs.
And you know,
it was a rough town and we drank a lot.
And I started when I was 14.
And you know,
um,
and so I was,
I had a lot of bad habits,
let's say,
and,
uh,
things that were,
and I wasn't in great shape physically,
and I was also still intellectually
obsessed by as I am now.
And,
uh,
so that would've been,
that would've been an 85,
but when I,
but I decided around that about 85,
84 or something like that,
maybe a little earlier that I was really
going to try to get my act together.
And,
uh,
so I started doing that.
I,
you know,
first of all,
I quit smoking.
Oh,
that took a long time because I
eventually had to quit drinking too in
order to quit smoking.
And I started working out,
started playing sports,
which I'd never done.
I was a small kid.
I been skipped a grade and I was a
small,
small for my age.
So sports were never,
especially team sports were never really
a domain of expertise for me.
Um,
although I skied and went trapping with
my dad,
went,
you know,
cross country skiing and camping and all
that.
So,
but,
uh,
when I went to graduate school,
I started swimming the first,
the first,
uh,
physical exercise routine I did,
I enrolled in a swim suicides course,
I think it was called.
So it was me and this like really
overweight kid and like these 60 year
old women and men,
they could out exercise me like mad.
It was really embarrassing me in the
overweight kid,
you know,
we'd be just panting ourselves three
quarters to death at the end of the
bloody workout in these 60 year old
women who weren't in great shape or
like,
you know,
chatting away as if nothing was going on
at all in the pool.
So that was quite embarrassing.
And as was going to the weight room,
you know,
because when I started I could barely
best bench press 75 pounds and people
used to keep coming over and helping me,
which was last thing I bloody well
wanted but certainly needed.
And I got to the point where I could
bench press 225 pounds.
I think that was the best I did.
And I gained about 30 pounds of muscle
in a year and a half.
So that was good thing.
So like I was kind of a wild man and you
know,
I'm a little bit manic in my,
in my,
uh,
temperament and so,
you know,
I was,
I was kind of going every direction at
the same time,
so,
and uh,
you know,
I don't regret that I had a fine time
when I was a kid and uh,
I needed really to get disciplined and I
had to do it because I was working on
these hard problems that,
you know,
that I've been discussing with all of
you and I've been working on them
really,
you know,
obsessively since I was probably about
18,
maybe even earlier than that.
Got to the point around 25 when I was in
graduate school trying to get my Phd's
doing all my research.
Like I published 15 papers by the time I
graduated with my phd,
which was by I think by a fairly large
measure,
the most papers that any graduate
student at that time it ever published
at mcgill.
I think that's right.
Might have been twice as many or maybe
twice as many,
maybe even three times as many.
And at the same time I wrote maps of
meaning,
which was a terrible,
terrible,
terribly difficult thing to do cause I
was writing about three hours a day
doing that and I couldn't do all that
and continue with my misbehavior.
You know,
my sort of my,
what would you say?
My,
my,
my hedonistic,
my hedonistic
ma,
my massive hedonistic consumption of
alcohol and all of that.
I just couldn't keep it up and also work
seriously on the issues that were at
hand.
So you know,
I had to stop.
That's a sacrifice I had to stop messing
about and straight myself out.
And I,
I got married when my,
the woman who is my wife Tammy,
who I've known since she was eight years
old,
she lived across the street from me and
this little town called fairview and I
was in love with her like the first time
I saw her,
which is quite bloody thing.
So that's worked out pretty well for me.
But she came to live with me about the
same time.
And,
you know,
we decided jointly to get our act
together and we swore that we tell each
other the truth,
which I think she's actually done better
than me.
Like I don't think,
I don't think she's lied to me ever in
our entire marriage,
which is unbelievable.
You know,
it's been so useful because I can really
tell her things that we can really talk.
So I tell you,
if you want to have a good relationship,
man,
you embedded in the truth.
Because if you don't embed it in the
truth,
you don't have a relationship.
It's,
it's just lies.
it's a tissue of lies and it will,
it will dissolve in the chaos as soon as
a crisis comes along.
So the truth is a terrible thing,
but not,
not compared to false hood.
So,
all right.
So let's look at the live chat here.
MMM.
Please get a better quality microphone.
While I'm really hoping that the
microphone that I'm using right now is
working well,
um,
it should be,
it's a really good microphone.
It's a,
it's,
um,
what do you call on a road?
And I thought I was using it for quite a
while there,
but I'd reorganized my office and I
actually had unplugged the road.
And so my voice was unwittingly,
unbeknownst to me coming through this
little,
um,
large tech,
high def micro or a video camera that I
have on top of my speakers.
And it might even be doing that for now.
Right now as you know,
for all I know,
I hope not.
No,
it says the microphone is road in team n
t u s B.
So,
um,
maybe God,
I hope so.
Anyways.
You know,
I've been mastering a lot of technical
equipment in the last year and so I've
got most of it under control,
but I don't know if I have all of it
under control.
So some fan,
and I wish I remembered his name because
he deserves it.
Sent me this microphone.
So Hooray for him and hopefully I'm,
I'm going to get access to it.
So,
um,
let's see here.
I'm 20.
My parents had made it clear they don't
want me to leave home.
They are both drug addicted,
depressed and antisocial.
How do I leave without killing?
The only positive relationship they
have.
Well I think you'll have to ask yourself
a different question.
I think you might have to ask yourself
the question of how do you maintain that
positive relationship into the future if
you don't leave and have your own life.
You know,
cause you have to be thinking over five
year periods here or even decades.
And first of all,
you deserve to have your own life.
Like your parents should be fostering
your independence.
It's their moral duty to foster your
independence.
Now hopefully they can do that in a way
that makes you strong and that makes you
better able to have a relationship with
them.
But they have no right to use their,
their,
their dependence,
let's say as an,
as an impediment to you becoming
independent drug,
addicted,
antidepressant and anti antisocial.
Despite all of that,
they should be saying,
you get the hell away from us as fast as
you can and you get out there and have a
life.
And if you can put yourself together and
we get to see you from time to time,
wouldn't that be a wonderful thing?
So you know,
you,
you don't get in your children's way,
you don't get in your children's way.
So,
um,
I would say,
and I can't give you advice because I
don't know you and the devil's always in
the details,
but I can say generally that you won't
be able to maintain a positive
relationship with your parents if you
do.
So at the cost of your own destiny.
Let's say that that isn't going to work
out.
So when no one has the right to deprive
you of that destiny,
family or not,
man,
you're to operate out there in the world
like an independent soul and to make
your way through the world and to offer
what you have to offer and those who
love you should be behind you and
encouraging you to do that in every
possible way.
And if they aren't,
then you have to seriously think about
whether or not a,
whether or not they have your best
interest in mind and B,
whether or not it might be better for
you and for them if you went and did
what you needed to do anyways.
So I would say that.
So.
Okay.
Do you have in mind a more specific
breakdown of the social sciences?
I presume you mean in relationship to
the postmodern,
neo,
Marxist and have taken over so much of
the university?
I would say philosophy seems to be in
pretty good shape,
strangely enough.
It isn't exactly clear why.
Um,
that's mostly my impression.
I would say that in the rest of the
university,
if the discipline has at least one foot
in science,
then it's relatively safe.
And so I would say psychology is
relatively safe discipline because it's
quite nicely constrained by the
necessity of taking biology into
account.
That's less true with social psychology.
But it's certainly true with clinical
psychology and it's even more true with
neuroscience and the animal behavioral
side of things and stay,
well statistics,
statistics isn't science,
but at least it's a rigorous methodology
methodologically.
If the discipline is very heavy,
heavily theoretically theory dependent,
like say sociology or let's say women's
studies,
which I have virtually no respect for.
Um,
not that that's really relevant because
whether or not I respect it isn't the
issue.
The issue is whether or not it actually
is a high quality discipline.
And I don't believe it's a high quality
discipline at all.
I would also say though,
if you're,
and I'm going to make a video about this
in the next couple of weeks and advice
to university students when I launched
that website,
had been talking about that helps.
It'll help people identify their courses
as postmodern slash neo Marxist so that
they can either take them if they want
to be indoctrinated or avoid them if
they want to actually have an education.
I would say it's your responsibility,
you know,
um,
it's your responsibility to get educated
at university and sort of,
despite the university we could,
we could say that,
um,
you,
there are great books.
You can find out what they are and you
can read them and you know what the
university does.
And Society is our,
for you and identity for four years,
you're a student,
you're a university student.
And so that's a credible identity.
It offers you a lot of freedom.
And so you might say,
you might have to get educated despite
your courses and you know,
you think,
well that's a bad deal because the
courses should be educating you.
It's like,
well,
you got to look at it from a more
realistic perspective.
You can't expect the university to be a
perfect institution any more than you're
a perfect person and at least it offers
you an identity to shield yourself with
while you're undergoing the difficult
process of educating yourself.
And so I would say,
um,
you know,
uh,
take responsibility for education.
Find professors that you respect and
who's who and who,
who,
who challenge you.
And,
and don't,
don't fall prey to the,
to the,
to the cynical attitude that,
you know,
you take the course for the grade or
that you should write what the professor
wants to hear.
I mean,
you have to be a real corrupt professor
before you'll mark a student for,
for producing an opinion contrary to
yours.
That's high quality.
I mean,
even the more corrupt professors even in
the more corrupt disciplines I think are
fairly rarely guilty of that sort of
thing.
So,
um,
anyways,
if it's grounded in science,
it's more likely to be
b,
a
reliable,
that's the first thing to do.
But the second thing is,
and the second thing is to know what's
your responsibility to get educated.
And the libraries are full of great
books.
You can figure out what the great books
are.
You know,
in half an hour you could make list of
50 great books.
I have one on my website.
You can read all those,
you know,
that takes about two years probably to
really do a proper job of it.
We read the great classics,
Scientific and Literary,
historical,
all of that.
You'll get educated and then you'll be
sharp and coherent and articulate and
powerful and able to formulate arguments
and able to negotiate and able to
formulate problems and solve them.
And you know,
that's exactly what you should be doing
when you get educated and it has
tremendous,
tremendous economic value.
And that includes education in the
humanities.
So,
all right.
Did I fail any classes in university?
I had to retake stats.
I wasn't good at stats.
I got it eventually.
Um,
I needed to know,
well,
I'm no mathematical genius,
we can start with that.
But I also needed to know,
I couldn't take the assumptions on
faith,
which was really quite problematic.
And so I couldn't just memorize,
you know,
I had to understand and that didn't work
out so well for stats analysis.
It didn't understand at that time that I
had to keep up with it sort of
rigorously.
But I got to be a pretty decent
statistician.
At least I understand the statistics
now.
So yeah,
I didn't do very well in statistics,
but most of my grades otherwise were
they in my grades in high school except
for grade 10,
when I bet my dad that I could get a
straight eighties.
And I think God,
exactly that,
um,
my grades in junior high and high school
are pretty dismal because I absolutely
detested school.
Partly for my own reasons,
you know,
because of my own problems,
but an immaturity.
But also because I found it painfully
unchallenging
let's say.
Um,
but in university,
college and university,
I got very good grades and which was a
good thing because I would have never
got into clinical graduate school
without that.
So yeah,
to 25 pounds isn't bad.
Yeah.
Well I only weighed one 60,
so you know,
it was pretty good.
I thought it was funny because it was
only one day I was able to manage that.
I could do 200 with fair bit of
regularity and a bench press.
But one day man,
I did two oh five and that worked and I
did two 10 in that worked and I got all
the way to two 25 and I was never able
to duplicate it again.
So that was pretty interesting.
So jared,
chance as you claim hierarchies are
efficient enough yet you claim 99% of
creative people get stuck at the bottom.
Oh yeah.
Well that's not a contradiction.
Um,
what kind of propels you up?
Hierarchies of authority is intelligence
and conscientiousness.
Right?
And so then you might say,
well,
what about creativity?
And it looks like creativity.
Creativity is,
as you sort of know,
is an out of the box phenomena.
And the problem is,
is that if you're within a hierarchy,
there's a ladder upward that you can
climb rung by rung.
And basically to do that you have to do
your damn job.
Now.
Now you might say,
yeah,
well isn't creativity,
you know,
necessary.
And the answer to that is absolutely,
but it's not that useful when you're at
the bottom because who the hell wants to
hear your damn creative ideas when
you're just starting out?
You know you're just a pain in the neck
even if you're right,
even if you're brilliant,
you're just a pain in the neck if you're
creative at the bottom because you come
up with all these radical ideas that are
going to shape out,
shake up the structure of the hierarchy,
and plus you haven't what indicated your
credibility of demonstrated your
credibility to any great degree.
So people are going to just write you
off as a,
they'll just going to write you off
because it's easier than taking you
seriously.
Now,
the funny thing is,
is that as you climb up the hierarchy,
creativity becomes increasingly
necessary until when you're at the very
top,
it's absolutely vital.
And many,
many companies suffer from the fact that
they,
um,
would you say promote conscientious
people continually up the ladder and
then they end up at the top with no
creative people.
But it's hard for the creative people to
climb to the top because creativity
isn't one of those things that ratchets
you up a hierarchy of competence.
So,
so there are efficient on the
conscientious end and efficient on the
intelligent and but creativity is a
whole different thing.
I mean partly because how the hell do
you evaluate a creative person?
You can't by definition,
because to have a structure of
devaluation means that something has to
be done in a tried and true and
measurable manner.
And that is what a creative person does.
He like,
they make a left turn,
you know,
90 degree turn and they say,
well,
I'm going to do it completely
differently.
It's like,
well how are you?
How is someone going to evaluate you if
you do that now you might be right and
you know,
creative people are often wrong but
sometimes and vitally dead right when no
one else's.
But it's a really,
it's really problematic.
I mean,
if you're a creative person,
you're your best bet I would say is to
discipline yourself and ground yourself
in something relatively practical that
will enable you to eek out some sort of
living.
And then to practice your creative
endeavor on the side,
you can head,
ha ha,
you can head to head long into it and
try to make money and be creative at the
same time.
But I'll tell you,
man,
my experience has taught me,
and this is a lot of experience and a
lot of watching and it's not something
I'm happy to say,
is that it's very,
very,
very difficult for creative people to
monetize their creativity.
And most of the time it's an exercise in
futility.
So what you have to do is stabilize
yourself in some sort of productive and
traditional domain.
And then,
you know,
use your extra time to work creatively
and see if you can branch out that way.
You know,
you can always try to start a small
business to,
or even a big business.
But again,
not some,
that's a high risk,
high return proposition.
And Yeah,
actually there's a technology that goes
along with that too.
You can't do that like a fool,
you know,
you have to know what you're doing in
order to do that.
So,
um,
what evil daddy will enslave the human
race come the eclipse.
I think that's probably the god Keck.
That would be my guess as far as I'd
been able to tell us.
So forth.
Could you please tell the difference
between equity and equality and why is
equity dangerous?
Well,
it's not actually equity and equality.
It's equity and equality of opportunity.
Well,
you know,
it's a truism,
I think that's agreed upon by liberals
and conservatives alike,
that the interests of individuals and
society are best served by opening the
door to the participation of all who are
qualified regardless of their,
uh,
of attributes in domains that have
nothing to do with the qualifications
for the position.
So imagine that as a worker,
um,
and that would include managers,
executives,
et Cetera.
As a worker,
you have a function like a tool.
You're a tool.
And,
and I wouldn't,
you know,
I wouldn't be too down on that.
It's good to be good for something.
And um,
we W W it's in society's best interest
that those who are able to be the most
efficient tools are the ones that are
placed in the position.
And so you want to open up the
competitive landscape to all players,
not least so that society can most
effectively exploit the people who are
most productive.
Now it also has the side benefit of
allowing individuals to utilize their
talents and to take their place in the
social world.
But people are very diverse in their
abilities,
like incredibly diverse in their
abilities and that's mostly evidence for
example,
in the domain of intelligence,
you know,
because while the,
the,
the range that includes the majority of
people runs from an Iq of about 85 or
let's say 72,
an Iq of 130,
although there's plenty of people who
are outside those domains is like at 70,
you're pretty intellectually impaired,
right?
You're not going to graduate from high
school with an Iq of 70,
except under very,
very extreme circumstances with an Iq of
83,
which is about 10% of the population,
85 is 15%.
You're going to have a hard time reading
well enough to follow instructions it on
with an Iq of 115.
You're going to do pretty well at uh,
uh,
sort of mid level community college.
And so an Iq of 145 is going to prepare
you for like high success and complex
domain,
say like law or,
or managerial positions where the
environment is transforming very
radically.
There is immense differences between
people in their cognitive ability and so
and in their conscientiousness and in
their negative emotionality and all and
in their energy levels and oh and in
their creativity and all sorts of
traits.
And because of that,
that individual diversity,
there's no reason to assume that there
is going to be equality of outcome.
And that's what equity is.
I've got to change the battery in my
camera
and we're back.
Apologies for that.
With this Dlsr Dslr,
whichever it is.
Um,
there's some,
I won't go into it.
I have to change the battery boat about
after about an hour or so.
Anyways,
back to intelligence.
Um,
what was I saying?
Talking about individual differences and
the differences.
Differences in intelligence.
Oh yeah.
Equality of outcome.
Well,
the only way,
given the wide range of human capacity,
mmm.
First step for you don't want to,
uh,
organize your society
such that every single category of
outcome has exactly proportional
representation from every single
possible category of person.
Because that isn't you.
You have to use so much social force in
order to make that occur.
That the consequences,
the negative consequences will far
outweigh the benefits.
It's better to open up the marketplace
to allow a very large range of
hierarchies to emerge.
And then to let people compete for their
position to compete and cooperate for
their own positions.
And the other problem with equity is
like who the hell is going to make the,
who's going to decide which groups are
to be categorized?
You want to,
here's an example for you.
Let's imagine you stratify the
population by Iq,
which,
which we do by the way.
Although,
although we don't do it as evidently and
obviously as we do say,
buy sex or perhaps even by race,
are you,
would you actually recommend that an
equal number of people be drawn from
every category of Iq to be surgeons?
I mean,
that's palpably absurd.
So there's too much social engineering
required to produce equity of outcome
now,
well,
having said that as well,
um,
the,
the historical data on equity are
absolute declare.
The societies that have tried to aim at
equity are the terrible communistic
societies of the 20th century and they
were so goddamn ma so unbelievably
murderous.
And counterproductive that it beggars
the imagination.
And so I can't even believe we have a
conversation about equity because it's
such a pathological idea.
It's,
it's completely invalidated by the
historical data.
So,
all right.
What does my average daily schedule
consist of?
Well,
that's fairly straight forward.
I get up around somewhere between six
and eight and then I work till 10 as,
as hard as I can flat out every single
day.
So,
and I've been doing that for,
with very little variation,
although it's been much more extreme in
the last year for like,
since 1985,
like I work probably,
well I work,
I would say 14 hours a day,
at least 14 hours a day.
And so that said about a hundred hours a
week and that time that I don't do that,
I spend with friends and,
but mostly with my family.
And so,
um,
yeah.
And I work as efficiently as I possibly
can.
I'm always trying to do everything I can
as fast as I possibly can.
And I'm accustomed to that because like
I said,
I've been doing it for,
I've been doing it for 30 years.
So that's my daily schedule.
And I don't know even what I would do if
I didn't do that.
Um,
I have this cottage that I go to,
although I generally spend time writing
up there and I go swimming with my wife
and we go canoeing and I can take a
break in that way.
But most of the time if I take a break
even up at the cottage,
generally what I do is like carpentry
and fix the place up.
And I don't like to be unoccupied.
I have to be occupied doing something
productive all the time because
otherwise I'm not pleased with myself.
And so,
I mean,
you know,
I decided a long time ago that I was
going to try to live a hyper efficient
and hyper productive life.
And so it's been a challenge.
I,
uh,
it's an enjoyable thing for me to some
degree because I'm very interested in
trying to figure out how much I can
possibly do in the shortest period of
time,
all the time.
And that keeps you alert and awake and
it's a great challenge and it lends my
life a substantial amount of meaning and
it's,
it's been very successful.
So,
um,
you know,
so that's kind of what it's like.
Oh,
okay.
Let's see what else these chat people
say,
um,
oh wow.
Apparently.
Okay.
Broken mind.
In tolstoy's confession,
he talks about meaning in faith.
He had many problems with religion and
the church.
How can a nonreligious person find a
meaningful nonreligious faith?
Oh,
well,
you know,
it depends on what you mean by
nonreligious.
You know,
I would say for broken mind,
you know,
let's,
I was thinking about this today.
I was writing about this today.
I was reading about Dostoyevsky as
compared to Nicha,
you know,
and nature was a great critic of
Christianity and so as Dostoyevsky,
but dusty Yefsky I think trumped Nicha
with regards to his attitude towards
Christianity.
And I think you could really see this.
He could read the brothers [inaudible] I
would really recommend that broken mind.
Everything.
Get your hands on Dostoevsky,
read everything you can.
He wrote cause Dostoyevsky re really and
you like tolstoy's confession,
you know,
read Dostoyevsky.
But you know,
Dostoyevsky has this character in the
brothers Karamazov um,
Alioscha
and Osha is a monastic novitiate and
who's kind of a naive guy
intellectually,
although very good person.
I'm a simple person intellectually,
let's say,
perhaps not naive and he has this older
brother Ivan,
who is a devastating intellect and a
handsome man and a rake with a women and
like really,
uh,
like a well put together human being.
Although quite nihilistic and cutting
and his intellect and Ivan can
absolutely demolish Ellie Osha in a
debate and does quite regularly.
But Ellie Osha basically wins the
argument in the book,
let's say as the book plays itself out
by acting like a good person.
And I would say,
you know,
if you want to develop a religious faith
in some sense,
forget about trying to develop faith in
God.
I don't think you can will yourself into
that.
I'm not even sure that you should,
but I do think that you can decide that
you're going to do what you can to live
a meaningful life and be a good person
and start to meditate on what that means
and then to start to put it in practice.
And then you find your religious faith
in the domain of action rather than
conceptualization.
And that's really the primary domain in
which it should be manifested anyways.
Like the,
the primary Christian commitment for
example,
is the imitation of Christ,
not the belief in his divinity,
you know,
or the belief that he died for the sins
of mankind or any of that.
And I'm not making light of that.
But the primary moral injunction is to
try to live the archetipal life within
the confines of your own subjective
being,
to try to live the most divine life that
you can.
And if you try that and if you take that
seriously and if you meditate upon that
and ask yourself what it might mean,
that I think you'll find the religious
element of your life fleshing itself out
quite nicely.
So that's the answer to that question.
Thoughts on the drug epidemic?
Well,
I'm not sure there is an epidemic any
more than there always has been.
I know that there is now a tilt towards
drugs in,
in the u s in particular like meth and,
and,
um,
fentanyl and the other opiates.
Now it's quite a catastrophe.
Um,
a lot of that is occurring among people
who don't have meaning in their lives.
I would say you might think that's a
fast I'll answer,
but it's not,
you know,
like here,
here's the wrap literature.
Like it's,
if you take a rat lab rat,
typical lab rat is,
you know,
genetically bred to be identical with
many other lab routes and he lives alone
in a cage and he,
he's got a pretty miserable route life
because routes are social animals and
they don't like to live in cages by
themselves.
And you can get a lab rat in a cage
addicted to cocaine,
cocaine and no time flat.
And he'll,
he'll like press a lever for cocaine
reward to pretty much to the,
to the exclusion of all else including
sex and often including food.
But if you take that same rat and you
put them in a rat family,
you know,
in a rat social hierarchy,
in a rat environment and give him
something that rat rat like to do so
that he can be satisfied,
it's very difficult to get them addicted
to cocaine.
And so I would say the reason that
people take psychomotor stimulants and
all the drugs have serious abuse or
psychomotor stimulants regardless of
what else they might be,
they activate the dopaminergic system,
which is the system that tracks reward
and that that is associated,
that's activated when you pursue velop
valuable goal directed behavior.
Um,
if you don't have that,
if you don't have a valid goal,
if you don't have no,
no real valid meaning in your life,
you don't have a valid ambition,
then you don't have any way of
activating that system.
And why the hell wouldn't you take
drugs?
It's like you have to have something
better to do to not addict yourself,
you know,
so,
so I would say that a huge part of the
current epidemic in,
in,
in the u s in particular is,
is manifest among broken men who have no
real place in society and providing them
with money isn't going to help that they
need a productive and meaningful
existence.
And which is the paramount,
the paramount goal should be the
paramount goal of social,
of social policy.
For example,
we,
it isn't the alleviation of poverty.
That's really the issue because people
in the West aren't poor.
There might be a bit of a distribution
problem,
but we're not poor.
What we have is a,
uh,
what would you say?
Hey,
we have a problem of meaningful
engagement and that's what has to be
addressed and that's why I do the work
that I'm doing.
So
yeah.
Are you aware of the similarities in the
work of Anthony Robbins and with lot of
what you are doing in the self authoring
suite?
Um,
I'm not specifically aware of the
similarities,
although I know that Anthony Robbins is
a well known motivational speaker and
generally motivational speakers try to
motivate people to pursue something
productive in their life.
So,
um,
you know,
I would say likely that there are
motivational.
Okay.
There are people who are concerned with
motivation that are working at different
levels of the communication strata.
And I'm working at a fairly abstract
level and hopefully Mr Robinson's
working at a level that is productive,
helpful to lots of people.
He certainly had a very stable and long
career.
So,
um,
although I'm not aware of any specific
similarities past that.
So
what do you think about Adhd?
I have it,
I am frustrated by my failures in life
because of it.
I am trying to become a cam a chemist
and I am failing at school.
Um,
I think adhd is a catch all diagnosis.
I think that people who are extroverted
and unconscientious for example,
often manifest the traits of,
of,
uh,
attention deficit disorder.
Um,
I know that there isn't any real
evidence of longterm utility and cycle
and cycle.
What a psycho pharmacological treatment
for Adhd.
Um,
I would say though,
if you are having a hard time
concentrating on your goals,
that what you should probably do is set
yourself up with a therapist,
find someone you can talk to,
you know,
so see two or three therapists.
I know it's expensive,
but so is not having a life.
Find someone you can talk to and then
make it and someone practical,
probably a behavioral therapist would be
best.
And then have them set goals with you
and help you strategize to stay on track
week to week.
That's the best thing.
Or to set that up with a friend if he
can't do it with the therapist.
So that's,
that's the best advice I have for that.
And keep at it,
man.
You know,
but break your,
you gotta learn to schedule.
You got to learn to break your days down
into disciplined sub sections and you
got to practice out at and practice at
it.
And there isn't an easier answer that I
know of.
But having someone that will help keep
your responsible,
I think can be useful.
I've seen that be useful for people who
have attention deficit disorder.
Let's say
you compare at once compared religion
and science as tools that can be used
more accurately to understand your
position.
Do you think gender and biological sex
are two tools in describing an identity?
Not really.
I think that most of what I think most
of the work on gender is rubbish to put
it bluntly.
Um,
I get what is meant by it.
You know that there is a socio cultural
layer specifying gendered behavior on
top of biological sexual identity.
But I think it's been so polluted by
political idiocy that it's,
it's a concept.
It's almost entirely invalidated.
It's used for perverse purposes.
It's not used as a tool of understanding
in most situations.
So,
um,
I think that the concept of gender could
be useful if it was used to specify the
purely socio cultural layer of,
of like sex type behavior.
And I think it could conceivably be used
in that way.
But I see very little evidence that it
ever is.
So,
okay.
My brother is a soldier in Iraq as a
clinical psychologist.
What should one do when coming from such
a chaotic place back to a tame and
structured one?
Well,
I guess that would depend to some degree
on exactly the nature of his experiences
in Iraq.
Um,
so it's hard for me to elaborate on that
further.
I mean I would say though that one thing
he could really do,
and,
and this is somewhat self serving I or
could appear to be somewhat self serving
I suppose is I would strongly recommend
that your brother do the self authoring
suite when he comes back because it'll
help him and probably concentrated on
the future authoring program to begin
with because it might take a while when
he gets back,
before he can meditate on his
experiences without that meditation
being harmful.
So for example,
there's pretty good evidence if you've
had a traumatic experience that you
shouldn't re subject yourself to the
traumatic experience repeatedly before
say about 18 months or something like
that is past.
And it isn't exactly obvious why that's
the case,
but there's a pretty good literature
indicating that it is.
So I would say that when he makes the
transition from Iraq back to enormous
normative society,
that the first thing you should do is
generate a plan.
Yeah.
And our plan about how we would,
and this would be the same even if you
were coming out of something like prison
or,
or making a change,
a radical change in your occupation,
is you need a plan,
right?
You need a plan so that you can fake
because you can't just make that
adjustment without knowing what you're
doing.
So that's what I would recommend.
And if he does come back traumatized,
and I would say,
you know,
traumatic,
traumatized soldiers often have to
develop a very comprehensive philosophy
of good and evil.
And,
and so that would either mean perhaps
talking to a,
a decent clinical psychologist about
what his experiences were or perhaps
reading some of the literature.
And I've outlined those books on my
website@jordanbpeterson.com that can be
really helpful in understanding and
helping someone understand the evils of
atrocity and warfare didn't.
And even the necessary evils,
let's say,
of atrocity and warfare.
So,
okay,
let's see here.
Do you think a lot of your work is the
form of the bargaining stage of grief?
No.
I don't think that there's these stages
of grief that had been identified.
Uh,
I can't remember who did the work.
Um,
um,
it,
it seems to have been quite helpful work
for many people.
Um,
but I don't think,
I don't think I'm bargaining exactly.
I don't think I'm suggesting that people
bargain.
I think I'm suggesting that people work
in sacrificing,
you could think about that as
bargaining.
Bargaining has the connotation more of
pleading.
Yeah.
Well let's say,
and I don't think that work and
sacrifice constitute pleading.
I,
I think that they're actually really
effective means of dealing with the
world.
And I think that people can be highly
effective and competent much more than
they think.
And so,
uh,
it's an interesting question and I can
see why you posed it,
but,
no,
I don't.
I don't believe it.
So,
okay.
Could you comment on the Buddhist
concept of impermanence and the nature
of reality being given,
being what gives it meaning?
Oh yeah.
That's a good one.
And how that concept conflicts with
ideas of eternal life in heaven.
Jesus,
man,
that's a lot of questions.
That's a lot of hard questions.
Well,
whoa.
Let's start with,
I'm going to only answer one of those.
I think it's just too much effort to get
all three of them in the same.
It's like hitting three fast balls with
the same swing of the bat.
I don't think I can manage it.
How does the finite nature of reality
give it?
Meaning?
How is it that the finite nature of
reality is what gives it meaning?
God,
that's such a good question.
Well,
I can answer this.
Oh,
Bleakley I'm going to talk about
something that happened to the comic
book character Superman in the late
seventies so superman was
extraordinarily popular from the 1930s
right up to the 1970s but one of the
things that happened is that as he
became more and more popular,
he also got more and more powerful.
Right?
So by the 80s Christ,
you know,
you could bounce a hydrogen bomb off
superman's chest and he could,
he could juggle planets and you know,
that's all well and good.
Except what are you going to,
what kind of adventure is he going to
have?
Right?
Like,
you know,
if you can't blow them up with an a
hydrogen bomb and he can juggle planets,
nothing interesting can happen to him.
He can be anywhere he wants at any time
and he can do anything he wants with no
effort at,
at,
at an under any circumstances
whatsoever.
So he's like a permanent deus ex ex
Makena.
I think I've got that right,
which is superman is boring because God
always comes in at this last moment and
saves him from whatever predicament he's
in.
Well,
you know,
contemplating that perversely enough can
give you some appreciation for the
finitude of life.
It's like we're,
we're like infinity captured in,
in the finite,
like,
like a genie and capsulated in the,
in the lamp,
you know,
and genius,
the gene root word of genius by the way.
So that's not an accidental comparison.
And it's this strange combination of,
of infinite capacity that characterized
as human beings to some degree with this
terrible finite limitation that does in
fact make our lives the adventures that
they are.
And so this is quite nicely documented
in the Tao Te Ching,
by the way.
And I would really recommend,
uh,
the,
the translation by Seth Rosenthal.
I already think it's elegant and that
the Taoists are very good at,
at,
at formulating the utility of
nonexistence.
In fact,
I think there's actually a verse in the
Tao Te Ching called the utility of
nonexistence where they talk about the,
the,
the empty space in a part,
giving it its utility and the,
you know,
the,
so that's what the pot isn't in some
sense that makes it what it is.
And,
and that's also the case with human
beings is that we have these intense
limitations that we can then attempt to
transcend and that it's meaningful to
transcend those limitations in such an
interesting way.
And I don't know what that means in the
final metaphysical analysis,
but you see that we do this voluntarily
to ourselves too,
because board people will place
restrictions on themselves just for
entertainment.
That's exactly what we do when we play a
game.
So,
for example,
if you're playing chess,
you subject yourself to all sorts of
arbitrary limitations,
right?
There's only a certain number of things
you can do with the chessboard and the
chest chessmen and then,
um,
you,
you open up a whole universe of
possibilities by adopting those
limitations.
And there's something about that that
speaks deeply to the absolute nature of
reality and maybe justifies the,
the tragic finitude of being.
It's something like that.
And,
and that's,
that's how it looks to me.
And I've thought about that quite
deeply.
So
can an introvert thrive in the field of
law or should they avoid it altogether?
Yes,
actually we,
we gathered a lot of,
of data on lawyers and,
and extroversion.
It doesn't predict law.
Uh,
what would you say proficiency at law at
all?
It's not associated with it at all.
Um,
what predicts proficiency in law,
his intelligence and conscientiousness.
And then after that,
relatively low agreeableness because
it's a very competitive enterprise,
high emotional stability.
So low neuroticism,
but introverted lawyers do fine.
Now,
if you're an introverted lawyer,
there's going to be some challenges.
And those challenges would be developing
the social skills necessary,
say to stand up in the courtroom if you
happen to be a lawyer who's going to do
courtroom work,
but there's plenty of like solitary work
that a lawyer can engage in.
But then the other problem might be for
an introverted lawyer that you know,
you want to develop your web of
connections,
your social network,
and of course you want to do that in any
enterprise,
right?
So it's a challenge for introverts in
general.
But I would say there's absolutely no
reason whatsoever to assume that law is
a discipline that an introvert should
avoid.
So,
you know,
go for it.
But you need to be conscientious,
right?
Cause low.
It really matters if you're
conscientious as a lawyer and you should
have a pretty decent verbal intelligence
because otherwise it's going to be a
hard road because the lawyers have to
deal with an awful lot of verbal
material and they have to formulate
complex arguments.
They have to be able to write and
communicate.
And so,
you know,
you got it.
You want to think about those elements
of your temperament more.
I would say.
Okay.
Dr. Peterson,
do you believe the evidence for God lies
primarily inner inner,
inner,
inner personal experiences?
Okay.
Well,
it,
it lies to a great degree in
interpersonal experiences,
although I don't even know if you could
call that necessarily evidence for God.
It depends on what you're willing to
accept as evidence.
Like even that experience that I had,
um,
that I described earlier in the q and a
isn't evidence for the existence of God.
You know,
it was,
it was certainly a religious experience
and I found it extremely,
extremely compelling.
But from a scientific perspective,
it's almost worthless as evidence
because it's purely subjective.
Now,
I think there are elements of experience
that cannot be God at objectively.
And so I'm willing to take subjective
experience under some circumstances as
evidence in so far as if I have a
subjective experience that I find
credible,
I'm willing to act on what I believe to
be its meaning.
And so I'll test out my interpretation
of that experience pragmatically.
And that's good enough for me.
I'm willing to consider that evidence,
but you can't really consider that
scientific evidence.
So,
um,
but then what other evidence is there?
Well,
there's also,
let's call it the evidence that's
instantiated in the great religious
texts of mankind,
the great philosophical texts and the
great literary text as well.
And I wouldn't exactly call that
subjective experience because you can,
you can garner it through your exposure
to culture and,
but you know whether or not that
constitutes evidence depends on what
you're willing to define as and accept
as evidence.
So
I'm told that my overanalyzing is double
edged sword,
but I'm suffering from being this way.
Yeah,
well you're probably,
you know,
hi and openness and maybe you're very
verbally intelligence,
so you're pretty much stuck with that.
Maybe you've got a bit of mania to you
too.
And I don't mean that in a negative
sense.
I find relief when I drink alcohol,
smoke or take certain drugs because it
slows down my thought process.
How can I use my over analysis to my
advantage?
Well,
I would say find yourself a difficult
cognitive problem to solve.
You know,
pick a challenge,
pick a challenge.
But you know,
you also might consider,
you might consider talking to someone
you find relief when you drink alcohol.
That might be,
that might be an indication that some of
what you're overanalyzing isn't so much
a consequence of access cognitive power,
but an excessive of high negative
emotion.
And so that would be illustrated in say
high trait neuroticism.
We're going to release the big five
aspects scale here later this month and
you'll be able to take that and it'll
give you a pretty good detailed
description of your personality.
And there's two dimensions of
neuroticism,
withdrawal and volatility.
And you know,
if you're overanalyzing because you're,
you're um,
what do you call that?
Ruminating that can be a consequence of
high levels of anxiety.
And the reason I'm suggesting that is
because you said you find relief when
you drink alcohol.
And alcohol is a very powerful and
anxiety lytic agent,
antianxiety agent.
And so lots of people who have high
levels of anxiety do ruminate and so
overanalyze,
let's say.
And they find relief when they drink
because alcohol is a primary anxiety.
Lytic like valium,
like Benzodiazepines,
barbiturates.
So the fact that alcohol gives you
relief probably indicates that some of
what's driving your overanalysis is
anxiety and then you could exercise can
really help with that.
I would also recommend,
this is something we need to think
about.
I don't know what your eating habits are
like are your sleeping habits.
But if you are an anxious person and
that's manifesting itself in say
neurotic over analysis,
there's two things you can do very
rapidly.
Three things really that will help quell
that.
Um,
well for things even number one,
okay,
get up at the same time everyday and I
would recommend in the morning cause
that's when people generally get up and
it's good to do what everyone else does
is nuts.
You have a good reason not to.
Number two,
eat a large breakfast,
right?
Keep it carbohydrate light,
you know,
don't,
don't eat toast,
toast and like uh,
fruit loops.
That's not going to do the trick.
Make it fat and protein heavy and eat
more than you want.
You might say,
I'm not hungry in the mornings.
Like this has nothing to do with what
you want or what your appetite is.
It's like you need to eat in the
morning.
If you're an anxious person and you
don't eat in the morning and then you
stress yourself out,
your body hyper produces insulin,
it takes all the blood sugar out of your
blood and that disregulates your
metabolism for the entire day.
You can't reset it till you go to sleep
at night.
And I've had lots of anxious clients who
would say fall into the over analytic
category who were like virtually cured
by eating a large breakfast every
morning.
I would highly recommend that you could
try some physical exercise.
Weightlifting is really good for curing
anxiety.
And the other thing you could do,
as I alluded to earlier today,
is to make a schedule and start
attending to your daily micro routines.
So you know,
you've got to figure out what your over
analysis is.
It might be cognitive,
like maybe you have a very active mind,
you know you're fast,
verbally are you fast verbally.
One way you can find that out is to do
something like write down as many
letters,
words as you can that begin with the
letter s for example.
In in three minutes,
do that with a bunch of your friends.
And if you're someone who writes down
way more words than anyone else,
then you're verbally fluent and that
might be driving some of your over
analysis.
But my guess is that you're suffering
from some rumination that's related to
anxiety.
And so I told,
told you what I think the simplest ways
aren't to rectify that.
So hope that works out for you.
Let's see,
what else have we got here?
Okay.
Alhmad warrior says,
can you answer this question,
Dr. Peterson?
And the answer is I can,
but I'm not going to.
Okay,
let's see.
Yeah,
Loki doodle says I cleaned my room
finally.
That's good.
I hope that it has a pronounced positive
effect on the rest of your life.
You know it's funny because since last
September I would say I redid my house.
I'm going to put a video online about
that cause I had a camera crew in here
this week videoing the whole house
because it's quite interesting I would
say.
But since I've stepped into this chaotic
domain last September,
my room has been a mess.
The rest of the house hasn't been too
bad,
but I've never got to cleaning my room.
I finally did this weekend.
And what was interesting because when I
did it,
I mean I've been doing a lot of other
things,
but that's,
no,
that doesn't help.
Uh,
keep at bay.
The negative psychological consequences
of being in,
in,
in material chaos.
When I cleaned my room this weekend,
it made it easier for me to finish this
chapter that I've been obsessing about.
So that was quite interesting.
So,
you know,
cleaning and organizing your room is no
joke.
It's a great meditative exercise,
especially if you take it seriously and
you're not trying to make it look neat.
Although that's not a bad aim.
You're trying to turn the room into
somewhere that the person you want to be
could live.
So
what
do I believe that there was any
connection between leftist identity
politics of past decades in the emergent
white identity politics of the alt
right?
Yes,
I think there's a direct causal
connection.
It only stands to reason that if
identity politics is going to be the
acceptable mode of communication,
that the,
that there are people who are on the
white side of the equation.
Let's say we're going to decide that
they're going to play exactly the same
game,
clearly,
obviously,
and,
and horribly.
You know,
because I'm no fan of identity politics,
but what's sauce for the goose is sauce
for the Gander.
So,
but I would recommend that people don't
do it because you know,
the radical leftists and their damn
identity politics is,
that's unbelievably pathological.
And if you decided to fight that by
playing the same game,
you think,
well,
I'll play the same game and then I'll
win.
It's like,
you know,
you won't because by playing the game
you lose.
That's the thing about your political
opponents is you don't play the damn
game.
You play a different game.
And so,
you know,
what I've been trying to encourage
people to do is instead of playing the
collectivist game,
and that would include alt-right
identity politics,
say,
um,
is to play the individual's game and to
get their act together the best revenge
I would say,
but you shouldn't be doing it for
revenge.
But the best revenge against the
collective last of us collectivist
leftists is to live a stalwart,
meaningful and high quality individual
life.
And that's also the pathway that
requires the most responsibility and
sacrifice.
And so I think is the most honorable and
least self deceptive.
So
what is your view on the Book Slash
Movie Fight Club?
I thought fight club was deeply fascist
in a very interesting way.
Um,
I mean I,
I'm saying that I'm saying that some in
some way dismissively although I
actually liked the movie.
I also think it was a,
it was fascist because it,
it,
it was a celebration in some sense of
force.
It was fascist sort of in the same way
that the iron man character is fascist,
you know?
Um,
but I also thought it was a really
interesting exploration of the idea of
developing the shadow.
And so,
and I do believe that if men don't
become consciously dangerous,
they become unconsciously dangerous.
And so it's much better to become
consciously dangerous.
And it's something that every man should
really aim at.
So you should be someone that no one
will mess with now,
but then you should keep that under
control,
right?
You should be,
first of all,
you should be harmless and naive,
then you're a child,
then you should develop your capacity to
be dangerous,
then you should bring that capacity to
be dangerous under control.
Then that makes you a man as far as I'm
concerned.
So
Jared Chan says,
I just wanted to thank you very much.
Love you heaps,
man.
Lol.
I'm slowly reading all of hume's books.
Thanks to you.
Well,
you have to read them slowly,
man.
There's no way you can read those fast.
Like,
watch out for yourself because those
things play vicious games with your
mind.
So praying for you.
Well good.
I could use some prayer,
man.
So thanks jared.
Much appreciate it.
So good luck with the reading and,
uh,
you know,
make sure you're doing something
practical and easy at the same time
because young,
he's hard on person.
That's for sure.
If you really want to twist your head
and a knot,
you could do some reading.
You could read some niche at the same
time.
It's a nice adjunct.
Uh,
though you'll wrote some books on nature
like,
um,
his,
his commentaries on thus spake Sarah
Booster.
So,
uh,
yeah.
Good to hear from you.
Thanks.
Thanks very much man.
Okay,
so let's see.
Whoa,
still haven't quite mastered this live
chat thing.
It zooms around quite a bit.
Hey,
when was that high school student
program?
You were coming without coming out with
happening?
Oh,
that's the,
uh,
that's the future authoring.
But the self authoring program for high
school students,
man,
we're trying to get that out by,
within a month,
but I can't say for sure because it's a
software development program,
but we're aiming out to fall,
that's for sure.
So,
um,
I know we're hoping it'll be a killer.
Like,
like the university self authoring
program was,
you know,
uh,
for those of you who don't know,
you probably all know cause you're
patriotic subscribers.
But the future authoring program seems
to improve the performance of college
students by about 25%.
We're hoping with the high school
students to uh,
um,
we'll have the same impact at a much
earlier age and to teach kids to define
themselves voluntarily and to start
charting their destiny.
That would be a lovely thing.
And we're going to sell directly to the
high school students instead of trying
to go into schools and so forth,
which I think would be just an exercise
in frustration and utility.
I shouldn't say that.
And I don't know how this got set up.
I probably push some button that I
didn't even notice is that some of you
seem to be donating money and the money
is associated with questions and I've
clicked on some of those and I hope,
I'm not sure what to make of that
exactly.
Because I don't know how it happened
And I want to make sure that I get
questions from everyone as much as I
can.
So if I miss you,
I hope that you're not donating unless I
actually click on your question.
So,
but if that isn't the case,
then I apologize.
I'm trying to keep up with as many
questions as I possibly can't.
Thoughts on the Jews.
Well,
the first thing I could say about Jews
is that a lot of my friends are happen
to be Jewish.
And I think that's partly because Jewish
people and me and that's in part a
cultural thing,
are very,
very interested in ideas.
And I happened to be very interested in
ideas and so I have a great affinity for
Jewish people.
And so,
um,
and I think that Jewish people are
overrepresented in positions of
competence and authority and that's
often because they're extraordinarily
competent.
So,
you know,
hurry for them.
That's how it looks to me.
So
what do you have to say about girls who
grew up without fathers?
Be Very careful in who you choose as a
mate because you don't have that much
experience with what constitutes a good
man.
And so I would say be cautious,
Be Cautious.
Look for someone who treats you well and
not because of weakness.
You know,
who's who,
don't be,
don't confuse being afraid to offend you
with treating you well.
Someone who treats you well as someone
who's tough and forthright and self
reliant,
but who is able to listen and to
negotiate in particular and to tell you
the truth.
And so,
and,
and don't give yourself away too easily.
And that's what I would say to girls,
period is don't give yourself away too
easily.
It's a big mistake.
You'll regret it.
So
I'm starting to slow down here.
Nature was pretty fun to read.
Got All his works.
Nino,
the sinner.
Well that should really help you with
your sitting there,
Nino.
So yeah.
Nicha he's a,
he's a trip,
that's for sure.
If you guys are thinking about reading
each of,
don't start with thus,
thus spake Sarah through story.
You should read that last,
I would start with beyond good and evil.
And uh,
a fun is a pretty weird way to describe
it though.
Read Dostoyevsky too.
That'd be good for you.
What advice would you give to a person
high in agreeableness and
conscientiousness get a significant
other who is left leaning or one who is
leaning towards radical leftism?
I would say get a significant other.
Don't get a significant other based on
their political,
uh,
predispositions,
you know,
um,
get a significant other that you can
trust and that you are attracted to and
that you want to build a life with and
leave the political stuff for,
for when it's necessary because the
political stuff should only be engaged
in when it's necessary.
Do you think Islam is compatible with
the West?
Not In any self evident manner.
So,
um,
although I would also say that Islam is
part of the West,
you know,
we should actually give that some
consideration.
Do you mean is Islam compatible with
Christianity?
Um,
I hope so,
but it isn't obvious to me in what
manner it's compatible with
Christianity.
We'll see.
That doesn't mean that Muslims aren't
compatible with Western society.
You know,
I mean,
many Muslims are no more radical Muslims
than Christians are radical Christians.
In fact,
many Muslims aren't any more Muslims
than many Christians are Christians.
And so,
you know,
I would say generally speaking across
populations,
people are pretty decent and as
individuals,
you know,
generally speaking,
but that doesn't necessarily mean that
the belief systems that they inhabit or
commensurate.
So,
okay.
All Cap,
right?
Says I think you should fortify your
ideas on Christianity.
I am doing my best to do exactly that.
So Dr. Peterson,
what was your relationship like with
your mother and father hits pr?
It was,
andy is pretty good.
They're both still alive.
Thank God.
I just went up and saw my dad for his
80th birthday.
He's in good shape.
Um,
I actually gave him a Keka Stan,
he flag as a joke,
which he really appreciated.
So I think he's got that flying up in
his cabin way the hell up in northern
Saskatchewan,
which I think is pretty comical.
Um,
I loved my parents deeply there.
They've been a great source of support
for me.
My father,
I had some struggles with my father when
I was an adolescent,
partly because I think partly because I
was depressed and so was he.
Um,
he was a great father when I was a young
child.
He spent so much time with me and paid
so much attention to me and taught me to
read and like I have nothing but great
memories of him before grade six.
And then we had about three years that
were rocky mall,
more than that,
probably about five years that were
rocky,
um,
which we both contributed to.
And so did other circumstances,
but mean since I moved away from home,
which I did at 16,
um,
we've got along just fine and I think we
have an absolutely superb relationship
and they've been incredibly useful and
supportive in the last year.
So,
and my mother is a wonderful person.
She's a little too agreeable for her own
good,
but she's tough.
And she had a,
you know,
she raised three kids and she went out
and had a career and she's put up with
my dad who's a pretty tough,
stubborn guy.
And,
uh,
she's a lovely person.
I love her deeply and she's been very
good to my kids.
And,
uh,
um,
I've had,
uh,
I have,
I have had a good relationship with them
and I,
I would say it's just gotten better and
better as we've got older and straighten
ourselves out.
And I would say that about my whole
family,
including my sister and my brother and
their family and it's functioning pretty
damn well.
And so thank God for that man.
So
I have a friend who's considering
majoring in psychology.
What advice would I give them?
Um,
stick to the biological end of it as
much as possible.
Uh,
with the exception of the clinical great
clinical works because they're very much
reading master your damn statistics
because that'll open up career doors for
you,
nail your grades,
go get a degree.
In clinical psychology,
a phd in clinical psychology is so
valuable that it's,
it's almost incomprehensible.
So,
um,
that's what I would say and,
and uh,
learn to analyze the research reports
and pay attention and it can be an
absolutely great career.
All right guys,
it's been a long day.
I spent most of today writing my chapter
seven of my new book called 12 rules for
life,
which is absolutely deadly chapter.
It's just about killed me.
I have gone over today,
I went over every word and every
sentence and rewrote them.
And it's a chapter on sacrifice and work
and the battle between good and evil and
Christianity and,
and the nature of a meaningful life.
And it's,
it's been hard.
And um,
yeah.
And I'm tired and although this has been
great fun and I would like to say in
closing,
once again,
thank you very much for the support and
for all of the,
I mean,
I'm absolutely overwhelmed by the
positive response my work has got over
the last year.
It's been very,
uh,
I've been amazingly well compensated
both financially and psychologically for
my efforts,
which I'm thrilled about.
And I hope that I can keep delivering to
you what it is that you seem to be.
Um,
what would you say?
I hope that I can continue to deliver
whatever it is that I'd been delivering
in the past.
That all of you have been finding a
value.
I am doing my best to do that.
I think it's the right way forward out
of this bloody chaotic political mess
that we're in.
It's the,
Oh,
and I mean,
I've been thinking about that for years.
You know that the way out of the
ideological morass is the strengthening
and fortification of the individual.
And I hope you all participate in that
because it's,
there's,
it's a Cliche,
but I'm getting tired.
So it's the best I can do.
There's no limits to what a person who
decides to put themselves together can
do.
And so I would very much encourage all
of you to aim at that because what the
hell else have you got to do in this
like veil of tears?
That's tragic.
Veil of tears,
but put yourself together and prevail.
And so on that note,
man,
over now,
and I'll talk to you all in a month.