Well I won't back down.
You can stand at the gates of hell.
Good Morning Boys,
girls and interested others.
So the calls for my discipline and
silencing have begun in earnest.
Um,
so I'm going to read you two letters
that have been produced,
um,
publicly and,
and within the uh,
within the university community itself.
Um,
the first one has received some press
attention,
I don't believe the second one has yet.
So,
um,
October six,
2016 so this was produced by a variety
of student organizations and I'll
discuss who they are.
At the end of the letter to the
attention of the University of Toronto
Administration and the U of t community.
We the undersigned.
Community members at the University of
Toronto are appalled,
concerned and saddened by recent
transphobic,
racist and anti black comments made by
professor Jordan Peterson and an online
lecture series that he published on
Youtube on September 27th,
2016 in October 3rd,
2016 Peterson has abused his position of
power as a tenured professor and has
tried to use my,
his academic freedom to disguise his
bigotry and prejudice as an intellectual
disagreement.
However,
to suggest that these comments add value
to classroom discussion is absurd.
By the way,
that's not a suggestion that I've made.
We would like to bring attention to the
University of Toronto statement of
equity,
diversity and excellence.
No doubt they would like to bring
attention to that which states that the
University of Toronto will proactively
seek to increase diversity among our
community members and it is our aim to
have a student body teaching and
administrative staff that mirror the
diversity of the pool of potentially
qualified applicants for those
positions.
And,
and it is our responsibility to help in
the creation of an equitable community.
One that is diverse as well as inclusive
and that is respectful and protects the
human rights of its measure members.
Something that requires the work of
every member of the community across all
our sites and capitalists,
including students,
teaching staff,
administrative staff,
visitors,
alumni and guests.
The university is committed to internal
policies on issues related to equity and
also operates in compliance with all
legislation that bears on equity and
human rights.
In a recent two part lecture given by
Jordan Peterson,
which was published on Youtube,
see the relevant urls.
Peterson goes on a 57 minute rant
regarding his disapproval of bill.
See 16 which proposes to include gender
identity and gender expression has
prohibited grounds for harassment and
discrimination under the Canadian Human
Rights Act and the criminal code.
This same bill is considered by many
political scholars and members of trans
communities as an advancement of human
rights,
equal protection under the law.
Peterson is also a man who has
complained that the Ontario human rights
commission's terms and definitions are
over inclusive and all encompassing.
Surely inclusivity is an important
factor when discussing human rights
protections.
In one of his lectures.
Peterson includes various disparaging
comments about members of the Trans
Community.
He argues that there is no evidence to
support the existence of non binary
identities.
That is not something I argued by the
way,
a statement that is inaccurate.
Furthermore,
when discussing the use of his students
preferred pronouns,
Peterson stated,
I won't recognize another person's right
to determine what pronouns I use to
address.
I won't do it.
Yes,
that is true.
Purposefully mis-gendering a trans
person is an act of violence.
While you better pay attention to that
because what that essentially means is
that speech is now an act of violence
and that more importantly,
refusal to use the words that someone
else demands that you use is an act of
violence.
That's what I'm being accused of.
Okay.
In my second 57 minute rant titled Part
Two Compulsory Education,
political education,
a real world case study at the U of
Toronto.
Peterson states his disapproval of the
mandatory antidiscrimination and anti
bias training that the u of t has
mandated for its HR professionals and
opinion that he was not asked for by
anyone.
The black liberation collective was
successful in advocating for this equity
training to be done,
not for the comfort of those who have
always been accommodated in welcome
within the institution,
but for those who are made voiceless,
it was crafted from a place of wanting
better in the environments that we as
students daily partake in keeping in
mind the ways in which people in
powerful positions of this university
are allowed to dehumanize students
through microaggressions,
gaslighting,
and blatant disrespect without any
accountability or repercussions.
According to the U of t statements of
institutional purpose,
the University of firms,
it's dedication to fostering an academic
community in which the learning and
scholarship of every member may flourish
with vigilant protection for individual
human rights and a resolute commitment
to the principle of equal opportunity,
equity and justice.
The fact that a tenured professor
employed with uft refuses to acknowledge
the use of personal pronouns.
They mean preferred pronouns.
By the way,
I do actually use personal pronouns and
has the audacity to try and rationalize
and quantify racism is something
subjective I have.
I have no idea where that comes from.
Not only discredits the lived
experiences of students who have dealt
with this reality,
but also silences them more violence
occurs as someone in a position of power
who not only has the nerve to say such
statements publicly,
can still be a respected member of the
university community and not face any
formal university backlash and continue
to enjoy tenure.
We are sick of discriminatory faculty
members denying our expertise in our
experiences are not respecting who we
are,
especially when we merely ask for our
lived realities to be respected and not
disregarded.
While you'll see how much asking is
being done later in this letter,
we are deeply concerned about the
university's lack of action on this
situation,
especially as Peterson continues to
spread is transphobic and racist
ideologies through various media
outlets.
I really have no idea where the racism
thing is going and I'm not transphobic,
so Bam,
whatever.
The university has failed to act on this
situation and this ultimately showcases
that quote,
diversity,
inclusion and equal respect are simply
legalities and are not principles that
the u of t tends on upholding the UFT
has failed at maintaining a positive
space and campuses free of hate.
As a result,
we,
the undersigned are demanding
accountability from the university
administration and governing console
with the following five demands.
Now one thing you'll note about the
people who do this sort of thing is that
they're always demanding and that's for
sure and a demand means or else,
and that's also what legislation means.
A public apology from professor Jordan
Peterson and a full retraction of his
comment.
Yeah.
Well,
hello freeze over before that happens.
Removal of is transphobic and racist
lectures from Youtube,
thus affirming their commitment to free
speech.
A town hall with President Merrick
Gertler,
provost,
Cherrelle Regnier,
Vice President Angela Hilliard,
and professor Jordan Peterson,
where community members can explain the
issues that he does clearly does not
comprehend.
And here's a good one.
Mandated,
anti-oppression trevor training at all
levels of the University of Toronto,
including faculty administration to
happen every academic semester.
A commitment at the University of
Toronto will take action to defend
students in university community members
in future instances where tenured
professors have made prejudice comments
against an individual or group on the
basis of race,
sexual orientation,
ability,
sex,
religion,
gender expression or gender identity.
We would also like to remind the
administration at the University of
Toronto statements on equity,
diversity,
and excellence states our support for
equity is grounded in an institution
wide commitment to achieving a working,
teaching and learning environment that
is free of discrimination and harassment
as defined in the Ontario Human Rights
Code.
In striving to become an equitable
community,
we were also worked to eliminate,
reduce,
or mitigate the adverse effects of any
barriers to full participation in
university life that we find including
in physical,
environmental,
attitudinal communication,
or technological hateful.
Common should never be tolerated,
especially not from someone who was
considered to be an educator.
No student should have to endure a two
hour lecture,
whether gender identity,
existence,
and realities are being debated and
refused.
Ultimately Peterson's comments erode the
safe campus learning environment to
which the university states a
commitment.
We hope that the university will respond
to this situation within a reasonable
timeframe and in accordance with the
policies established by the Governing
Council.
We also hope that these demands are
approved when the Governing Council
meets on October 27th,
2016 and so here's the people that are
doing this.
Daniel Lourenco,
Utm Su Lgbtq coordinator,
I'll make their email addresses
available at the end of this video.
Marise Hopkins,
Utms,
you and black liberation collective
organization or Mela Cassia President
Association of parttime undergraduate
students.
Roya Guera,
manny,
executive director,
uh,
out at utm.
Julian Olivera,
lgbt out University of Toronto,
newer led utms you president.
And so,
okay,
students,
so these are your elected officials,
so you can decide if they're actually
speaking for you.
And then it's copied to all these
university administrators.
So that's the first letter.
So if you're looking for something to do
to help,
you could write a letter to the
individuals whose emails I have posted
in the information box and the
description box that that is associated
with.
This video,
so email them and email all of them and
send me a copy if you want.
That would be helpful.
Um,
be particularly useful if it came from
students.
Thanks very much.
Bye.