Sorry.
I think
this part of the course,
it's always a part I have difficulty
with because the conceptual
transformation is very,
very large because so far we've been
talking about,
um,
I would say biological and evolutionary
realities in a sense.
And we've been doing that in a
relatively standard manner.
I mean,
there are elements of Piaget Yeti in
theory that run through it.
There are elements of cybernetic theory.
There are elements of neurobiology in
neuropsychology,
and
none of it,
I would say in some sense,
is radically outside the way the sorts
of problems might be discussed
in,
uh,
in the typical,
in a typical scientific or social
scientific manner,
except for maybe the fact that we've
drawn a explicit distinction between the
world as a place of things in the world
as a place of action.
Now,
there are consequences to the idea that
the world is a place of action that
start to become more radical at this
point.
But drawing the relationship between
what I've already talked to you about
and the narrative domains that we're
going to explore now requires a
like a radical shift in,
in conceptual focus.
And so the way I'm going to handle that
is by hitting it from 10 or 11 different
directions and building up a pattern.
Know if you listened to a complex piece
of music,
or at least this is my experience with
complex music is sometimes the first
time I hear it,
I don't really like it and I don't,
I don't,
I think I also don't understand it.
I actually can't hear it.
You know,
maybe a musical genius could hear the
whole thing instantly,
you know,
say a Franz Liszt,
they say he could sight read anything on
the piano first try.
So,
you know,
some people are so intelligent musically
that it's incomprehensible and I'm sure
they hear things,
just find the first time they hear them.
But then what happens for me is that if
I listened to it a couple of more times,
there are pieces,
chunks of it,
it starts to fall into place that I can
follow.
And,
and you know,
I can see the beauty sort of shine
through those and then eventually the
whole thing links together and then I
can listen to it.
Especially if it's a complex complex
piece of music many,
many,
many times.
And the more complex and probably the
better the piece of music,
the more I can listen to it.
But if I listen to it enough at some
point then I've had enough of it.
And it's all very strange phenomenon
because one of the things you might ask
yourself is what exactly are you
learning while you're doing that?
You're,
you know,
it seems like you want the music,
it's something like you want the music
to be just exactly the right amount of
predictable and unpredictable.
And if it's too unpredictable then you
can't understand it.
And if it's too predictable,
it's boring.
And so it's just like a conversation
that way.
It's actually just like life as well,
you know,
because you want things to be
predictable and stable and you want
things to be unpredictable and
interesting and the degree to which you
want.
Each of those is going to depend on the
time and the context and also on your
own intelligence and temperament.
So
now I'm going to tell you a bunch of
stories and give you a bunch of a number
of pieces of information and hopefully
they'll click together.
Now I think the reason that this
information has always been transmitted
in story and image form is because it's
very,
very difficult to transform it into
articulated like into fully articulated
explanation.
It isn't really how it works,
you know,
we're not really accustomed to thinking
about the idea that there are certain
forms of information that and that that
are valid forms of information that
can't be transmitted verbally.
But of course if you think about it,
we all understand this deeply because,
well,
I can give you a bunch of examples.
The first example is that when you
speak,
not only view speak in words and phrases
and sentences and paragraphs,
but you also speak melodically.
And in fact,
part of the reason that you can
understand melodies and that they make
sense to you is that what artists have
done is separated the melodic element of
speech from the semantic element and
then played with the melodic element.
And the melodic element tends to carry a
lot of emotion and intent.
And so if you're listening to someone
speak,
you can tell when they're being ironic,
you know,
because they'd raised an eyebrow and
their voice changes slightly,
even though they might be using,
in fact they are using exactly the same
words.
And in fact someone who's very good at
being witty or ironic,
we'll set the situation up so that you
can barely tell that they're joking.
And the better they are at that,
the Tinier the hint they give you that
you can still catch on to the final
year.
The situation is so,
so we know that information can be
transmitted through nonverbal channels.
It even happens during speech.
And then of course we understand that
music presents to us an intimation of
meaning that's very difficult to fully
grasp.
And music for me has always been,
uh,
ineffable phenomena in some sense
because it carries the intimation of
meaning in a manner that can't be
rationally dismissed or that people
aren't interested in rationally
dismissing.
So you've even punk rock nihilists
listened to Punk Rock,
nihilistic music and they,
you know,
they find that meaningful even though
they don't believe in meaning.
And then,
you know,
in some sense they're victims of their
own rationality because they do believe
in meaning or they wouldn't be listening
to the music,
but they can't understand how they could
possibly believe in it.
So their rational mind has dispensed
with the idea.
And sometimes that's people dispense
with the idea of meaning for lots of
reasons,
partly because of,
because it's inevitable in some sense
with sufficient rationality,
but also because,
because it's always useful to look for
the underbelly of things because it also
justifies not bearing any responsibility
for your life and not had some fairly,
um,
what that can be a very desirable side
effect of a particular ideological
irrational belief.
And then there's dance of course,
and dances even more ineffable than
music,
although it's often paired with music,
you know,
and it's,
and if it grips people,
if you see a remarkable downs
performance,
well part of it is that you're sort of
thrilled and excited about seeing just
exactly what the human form can do.
You know,
because perhaps partly because you're
human and when you see someone extending
a certain ability far beyond the norm,
then it expands your sense of what a
human being is capable of.
So there's,
so there's that,
there's just the pure scale element.
And then there's the novelty element
because often if you watch a
particularly good dancer,
there's things they do that you haven't
seen before that you didn't know anyone
can do and that's pretty fun and then
often the dances is joined with the
music and the body is expressing what
the music means and even though you
can't tell what the music means,
you can tell that the dance is
expressing it and see,
I think what happens there is that music
represents the patterns of being,
it's actually because people think of
music has a non representational art but
I think that's wrong.
I think it might be the most
representational art is that being is
made up of layers of pattern,
layers of patterns constantly interact,
interacting and hopefully in a
relatively harmonious way and music
music demonstrates that,
mimics it in some sense abstractly.
And then the dance is an abstract
representation.
Like people adapt to the patterns of
being and the dancer adapts to the
pattern of music.
And so it's a,
it's a symbolic,
it's an embodied display of the place of
the person in the cosmos.
And you can,
you can also make that case when you see
people dancing in pairs because you can
dance alone or you can dance in pairs.
And that's basically standard human
adaptation.
So,
and music is interesting too because one
of the things that you'll notice is that
there's always music in a movie.
Almost always there's the odd movie that
doesn't have it,
but it's,
it's quite marked when it's absent.
You know,
the movie feels a lot more cold and
clinical,
although it can work.
But we accept the idea that music can be
used to fill in the missing context in a
movie without even ever questioning it.
Right?
Like it's very strange if you think
about it,
that you go to a movie that is doing,
at least at least part of its function
is to portray reality in a realistic
way.
But there's a soundtrack playing in the
background all the time.
And you don't,
you know,
it,
it's so useful and so appropriate that
you don't notice how strange it is that
that's okay.
So,
so my point is,
is that we,
well,
and then of course you can talk about
novels and plays the same way because
you know,
there's a lot more to a novel then than
the words themselves.
There's,
you know,
we had a novel is a deeply layered
thing.
And,
and part of your understanding of the
novel novel is your understanding of the
interrelationships between the layers,
especially if it's a profound novel.
And I mean,
I think this is why we have the sense of
depth in,
in artistic and literary works.
Like if it,
if work is deep,
then it has many,
many layers and the more layers it has
interacting at the same time,
the more it's a useful representation of
the essential elements of being.
And so the more meaningful it is to us.
So that's all to say that there are
modes of communication that provide us
with information that we can't
articulate,
but that we still act,
we still act as if that information is
valid.
And you might say,
well,
valid for what?
What exactly is it doing?
What is it representing?
What kind of information is it offering
that's so compelling?
And what's so interesting about it is
the kind of information that we're
talking about,
that information is so compelling that
you'll pay to expose yourself to it.
You know,
it's a rare lecture that you'll go to
and have to pay for the lecture itself.
I mean,
you'll come to the university and you'll
get your degree,
but if you had your option on a Saturday
afternoon or a Saturday night,
let's say,
it's relatively unlikely that you would
attend a lecture,
and certainly even more unlikely that
you would pay to attend one,
but you'll certainly pay to go somewhere
to dance to music.
And you know why that is is not obvious.
You know,
you say,
well,
it's,
it's entertaining.
It's like,
yeah,
it's entertaining.
All right?
But it's a lot more than that.
And I think that dismissing things that
are enjoyable as entertainment,
which means they're sort of peripheral,
they're unimportant in some sense,
which is often what?
It's a real,
it's a real terrible habit of
psychologists.
So for example,
when Steven pinker wrote his book,
it's the book on language and
unfortunate,
I can't remember the name at the moment.
Um,
he devoted one chapter at the end
basically to nonverbal cultural forms
and he talked about them as
s
epic.
Phenomenal.
Fundamentally,
you know,
they're just,
they're a byproduct and I think that's
deeply wrong.
I think that our culture actually grew
out of dance and drama and music and
science came way,
way later than
math.
And
yeah,
I was watching an old video today,
um,
was up to the animals playing house of
the rising sun in 1964.
It's a pretty good video and it's a
great old song.
I mean,
they didn't write it.
It's an old blues song,
but it's a great old song and they do a
pretty,
pretty good job of it.
And the audience was full of girls and
they were screaming madly away.
Now it wasn't quite as bad as the
Beatles,
which was completely unbelievable,
but it was still,
you know,
a fairly continual den of delighted
shrieks.
And you know,
I think that's extremely interesting
because you'd never see that at a
scientific conference.
Well,
it's,
it's strange,
like there isn't anything else that
elicits that kind of response.
Um,
maybe,
maybe sports to some minimal degree,
but certainly nowhere near the same,
nowhere near it with the same amount of
enthusiasm.
And you know,
one of the things you,
and I mean,
that's been happening for a long time.
It wasn't merely a phenomena of the 60s.
I mean,
I suspect it's been happening ever since
there's been wandering minstrels and
that's a very,
very long time.
And I suspect those wandering minstrels
left many offspring behind them.
I know.
And well,
what's interesting about that is,
you know,
I mean obviously part of the reason that
human beings can sing is because we've
selected each other for that ability.
Right?
Do you mean there's something very
attractive about someone who's
artistically gifted and
the idea that women will do back flips
for,
uh,
for a singer is not necessarily any
negative comment on their ability to
evaluate what's important.
It might be quite the reverse.
So,
okay.
So anyways,
the point is there's lots of different
ways that we can convey information and
you might say,
well,
it's only simple information that can
be,
can be conveyed that way.
And you have to convey the complex
information in more formal forms,
scientific and philosophical.
But I think that's exactly backwards.
I think we get,
we get to articulate the simple stuff
first,
which is only what you'd expect,
right?
Because if,
when you're,
when you're mastering something
difficult,
like the,
uh,
the unfolding of being,
the probability that you're going to get
to the simple things first and
complicated things later is pretty much
100%.
And I mean,
different fields advance at different
speeds,
but
about the artists and the musicians get
to the complex matters far before the
scientists and the engineers.
And it has to be that way.
One of the deep things I learned from
young was that,
okay,
well as soon as our knowledge expands
out into the unknown,
there are people operating at the
periphery.
And so they're,
they,
they really have one foot in the unknown
and one foot on dry land,
so to speak.
And some of the more and more in the
water than others.
And the ones who are almost submerged up
to their neck,
when they tell you what they're seeing,
it's it,
it has to be poetic and musical and
artistic because it's so far beyond our
capacity to articulate that we can't
represent it in words.
And so all that can happen is the
artists can get ahold of it and maybe
they're religious.
They're the people who are prone to
religious life sentiments,
which at least experiences,
which seems to be associated by the way
with trade openness to have the actual
religious experience rather than to be
an inherent of the dogma which is
associated with low openness.
So for young,
you know,
it was the artists and the entrepreneurs
because they're the same people who are
at the forefront of the expansion of
what we know into what is unknown.
And I think you can see echoes of that
in the way that cities are rejuvenated.
You know,
because what happens,
you can certainly see this in Toronto,
is that a part of the city that has some
architectural or contextual interest but
is badly run down,
starts to get at some point,
you know,
the artistic people show up and they
think,
hey,
you know,
this is kind of cool if we just did this
to it,
it would,
you know,
they're re we really something to it.
And it's usually,
it doesn't hurt that the rents are low
because of course artists never have any
money.
So then they go in there and civilize
the hell out of it.
And of course they're ranting and that
drag jacks up the property values and
then the people who are a little less
open but kinda interested in art start
flowing in behind them.
And then soon the whole place is
rejuvenated and expensive.
And of course the artists have to go
somewhere else.
But they,
so,
but that,
that's a very interesting phenomena
because what's happening is that even in
the cities,
they're taking chaos and turning it into
order.
And that's what artists do.
So now that's all to tell you that there
are different ways of,
of,
uh,
transmitting,
representing,
and transmitting information and that
you can,
uh,
incorporate the information without
having any articulated notion of what
you're doing.
So of course that's the case because
otherwise you'd have to claim that you
understand everything you do and can
articulate it.
And it's like,
that's just,
you just,
that's just wrong.
You know,
you have a theory of yourself,
but it's not a very accurate theory,
which is why you're always doing things
that are strange as far as your
concerned,
which is also extremely bizarre.
It's like,
who the hell are you if you can't even
control your own behavior,
you know,
and,
and what does it mean to control it and
what does it mean to not control it?
These are very,
very complex and strange issues.
So,
all right.
So I think,
I think the best way into this is
actually from an evolutionary
perspective.
And I'm not,
I'm not convinced that this is correct,
but I think,
I think there's something to it.
So
when you,
when you think about the nature of
experience then you think,
well,
the,
the nature of experience is quite
different for quite different for
different sorts of creatures.
And one of the primary difference
between creatures is the degree to which
they're capable of social interaction.
And then of complex social interaction
and primates generally speaking,
are very social creatures.
They live in troops or packs like dogs,
which is why we can get along with dogs
because we understand each other being
hierarchical troop animals.
We understand dogs and they understand
us and they can fit right in pretty
much.
And uh,
we're very,
very good at figuring out where we are
in the truth.
And by we,
I mean primates,
I mean us going back a very,
very long period of time.
You know,
monkeys and chimpanzees have very
sophisticated knowledge of the social
structure surrounding them.
They know who's who and they know what
status they are,
they know what rank they are
essentially.
And that's also the case with people.
And so one of the things that you might
say about people is that our reality
isn't nature.
Exactly.
It's culture.
Now you can make the argument that you
can't really distinguish nature from
culture.
And I,
I believe that
that's true and untrue in a sense.
You,
I think you can talk about the human and
nonhuman elements of reality and you can
identify the human elements of reality
as culture,
even though culture is so old that you
can also think about it as an inevitable
part of nature.
So anyway,
so most of our experience in our
evolutionary past,
at least,
let's say for the last several million
years,
we might as well go back to when the
ancestors of humans hypothetically
split off from the ancestors of
chimpanzees.
You know,
and,
and people know very accurately when
these sorts of splits occur by the way,
because what they do is they have some
sense of the rate of transformation of
DNA.
You know,
it's like,
uh,
it,
it transforms at a rate that's fairly
constant across time.
And so then if you take two creatures
and you determine how much genetic
similarity there is between them and how
much difference you can calculate how
far back they,
they,
uh,
diverged.
And so,
you know,
the fossil record helps with that,
although it's very sparse.
But the DNA record,
it's not really sparse at all in some
sense.
And so you can be very accurate about,
we can even tell when people evolved to
clerk or learn to wear clothing.
And the reason we can tell that is
because there are certain kinds of
lights that can only live on clothing
and they seem to have diverged from the
lice that live in hair about 50,000
years ago,
something like that.
And so the hypothesis is,
well we must be figuring out how to wear
clothes at that point because the lice
figured out of the live in it.
So you know,
it probably took them a little while,
but I doubt if it took very long,
you know,
those little little creatures that breed
fast,
man,
those things can evolve quickly much to
our dismay.
So okay,
so a big part of the experiential field
of advanced primates is the social
world.
And so we could that the primate world.
And then we could also say that another
big part of their experience is the non
primate world,
which would be roughly speaking the
natural world.
And then we could also say that the
other element of their experience,
the other elements of their experience
that are very constant is their
subjective being.
And we don't know much about the
subjective being of of creatures like
chimpanzees.
Although
you can,
you can understand,
I think this objective being of a dog
well enough to be friend the dog.
And so you have some insight and I think
it's also reasonable to assume that,
I mean for a long time people were
unwilling to admit that animals while
had a soul,
that was the first problem.
But after that that they were conscious
and even the behavior is fought that
notion.
But I think the simplest thing to do is
to assume that animals and human beings
are the same,
except when you can prove that they're
are different because we share so much
of our evolutionary paths.
But the logical inference is that if you
think a dog is doing something that's
sort of like you would do in that
situation and feeling that way,
it probably is with certain exceptions
for species difference.
And if that wasn't the case,
I don't think that you could have a
relationship with a dog or cat.
You can't have much of a relationship
with a lizard.
Although there are lizards,
there are lizards,
a bearded dragons in particular that are
social.
They like to lay on top of each other
and they hang around together and you
can actually have more of a relationship
with them.
And apparently the same is true if you
go on us.
So you can go quite a ways back in the
evolutionary,
you know,
backwards in evolutionary time and still
have enough similarity between you and
the creature that you're interacting
with so that you can get a pretty good
sense of at least some element of their
their being.
And so the idea that subjective,
our subjectivity is a very ancient part
of our experience.
It seems to me to be a perfectly
reasonable supposition.
We certainly know that it's been around
in all likelihood for at least 150,000
years on the conservative side because
there have been human beings that are
essentially identical to us from a
genetic perspective going back 150,000
years.
But I think you'd have to be a pretty
harsh judge to assume that higher order
primates,
like chimps don't have some
consciousness and you know,
and,
and some limited self consciousness.
You know,
if you market chimps knows with lipstick
and then show it a mirror,
it will at least sometimes take the
lipstick off its nose.
Although I've seen a gorilla try to
fight with a mirror,
which,
well not,
I haven't personally seen that,
but I've seen a very good video of that
happening.
But I think the gorilla and it would
eventually figure out that it was,
that was him in the mirror.
Um,
dogs will recognize a dog in the mirror,
but they seem to learn to ignore their
reflection very,
very rapidly.
And I don't know if that means that they
have a rudimentary self consciousness
and they,
they figure out that that dog is them.
Or if the dog just doesn't smell like a
dog and then the dog thinks while it
can't be a dog because it doesn't smell
like a dog and the dog's probably think
that something is a dog because of how
it smells and not because of how it
looks,
you know?
So that's why I think that's why dogs
don't seem to have any sense of relative
size because you can get a chimp,
you know,
a little Chihuahua barking,
like mad at a great Dane.
You think really,
you know,
it's like that's,
that's going to work is it?
The dog doesn't seem to have a clue
about that.
Like he's perfectly happy and great day
and weirdly enough we'll often back off.
So anyways,
okay.
So
we've been in the social world at deeply
social world for a long time and I'm
also going to make the presupposition
that we'd been in the stratified social
world for a very long period of time.
And I think that you could call that if
you wanted to.
And I would never want to,
by the way,
you could call that the patriarchy.
Um,
I think that,
I wouldn't call it that because that's
not what it is.
But I think that the fact that it's
called that and that that's accepted as
a reasonable representation is actually
a consequence of the action of an
archetype.
And the archetype is that it's the
archetype of the terrible great father
actually,
because you think there's a social
structure with striations in it and that
has advantages and disadvantages and the
advantages are you can live in it.
And the disadvantages are you have to
follow the damn rules and they might not
necessarily be to your individual
benefits.
So within a social dominance hierarchy
is always a bifurcated.
It also always has bifurcated
significance.
It can be good and he is good in so far
as it protects you from say,
from threat,
from without,
you know,
maybe from,
from other primates invading your
territory,
for example.
But it's also can be a very dismal
structure for if you happen to be at the
bottom of the hierarchy.
So,
so anyways,
as far as I can tell
that dominant structures typically
represented as masculine.
And I think the reason for that,
although I'm not absolutely certain of
this,
I think the reason for that is that our
social hierarchies are probably more
like chimps,
social hierarchies then they are like
honorable social hierarchy.
So the Bonobos are kind of a strange
breed of chimps.
I don't know how many of you know about
them,
but the Bonobos are extraordinarily
sexual and they use sex pretty much as a
standard means of communication and
tension reduction.
And um,
there's a lot of sex between the females
learnable troops and they,
the use of sex seems to bond them
together in a way that keeps male
aggression under control,
which is quite interesting.
And so,
but in the chimps,
the fundamental hierarchy is male,
although there's a female dominance
hierarchy as well.
And some females can certainly be more
dominant than some males,
but the fundamental structure seems to
be male.
And then I would also say,
well it's probably dependent to some
degree in the primate community and in
other social animals on other factors.
So we know,
for example,
that the,
uh,
the gender that has the highest level of
testosterone tends to be the dominant
gender.
And so in hyenas,
the females have larger,
have higher levels of testosterone.
There are actually bigger and more
aggressive than the males in the price
they pay for.
That is that they have to give birth
through structured.
That's very much like a penis,
which is not the world's most pleasant
experience and might account for the
hyenas temper.
So,
but in,
in human beings,
you know,
you,
you see sexual dimorphism men are
slightly bigger than women.
And that's also generally characteristic
of,
of creatures that have a dominance
hierarchy that's tilted towards
masculine.
And then the other factor seems to be
that
human beings have their be,
their infants are infants have very,
very,
very long periods of dependence.
And it's very difficult to maneuver your
way doing anything really,
especially anything that has to do with
competition and power.
If you're taking care of,
you know,
one infant,
let alone three.
And so it seems to me
that those are all valid reasons why the
primary power structures among human
beings have typically be male and why
they're represented as masculine.
Now I thought there are other reasons
too,
cause this is a multifaceted phenomenon.
I mean one of the things that's very
interesting about human females is that
they're selective maters.
Now chimp females are not selective
majors and what that means is that the
dominant males still have most of the
offspring.
But the reason for that apparently is
because they chase the subordinate males
away from sexually receptive females.
Although this sexually receptive females
will sneak off behind a rock somewhere
and mate with a subordinate male,
but as long as the dominant male is
around,
the probability of that is quite low so
that the female chimps aren't sexually
selective.
Whereas human females have concealed
ovulation so that no one knows when
they're at their most fertile and
they're selective maters.
And women in every society virtually
that's ever been studied have a typical
pattern of behavior,
which is that if you look at a female
dominance hierarchy and you look at the
male dominance hierarchy,
the females will mate across and up
dominance hierarchies and the males will
mate across and down,
which works fine both genders because
their interests align.
But uh,
but it also means that in all likelihood
that women had exerted tremendous sexual
selection pressure on men.
And that might be part of the reason,
many of the many reasons that we
actually,
you know,
the,
the theory is,
is that the common ancestor between
chimps and humans was a lot more like a
champ,
a modern champ,
then like a modern human.
So for whatever reason,
we've undergone a lot more
transformation in the last 7 million
years then chimps have.
And one,
one possible reason for that,
and I think it's a highly probable
reason,
is that sexual selection operated lot
more viciously,
so to speak,
among humans.
It's operated to the point where you
have twice as many female ancestors as
male,
and you might think,
well,
that can't be possible,
but here's how it's possible.
It's only every second Manhattan
children at Agile,
well,
all women had one.
Now of course that isn't what happened,
but on average,
that's what happened.
So the proportion of men who are
completely childless in any given
generation is far higher than the
proportion of women who are.
So you,
you see an element of expandability in
males,
and that's typical across the biological
community because you don't need as many
males as you need females in order to
keep the population moving forward.
Um,
and one of the things that happens as a
consequence of that,
at least in principle,
is that males are more behaviorally
variable and variable across a lot of
dimensions than females are.
And that's a plus because they're more
variable on the upside,
but it's also a negative because they're
more prevalent on the downside.
So now there's substantial argument
about that in relationship to people.
You know,
what the actual implications are of that
for human beings.
Um,
one potential implication is that
although women and men have equivalent
Iq is the standard deviation is slightly
different,
which means that there are more males
who are intellectually impaired,
but they're also more males who are four
and five standard deviations above the
population.
Me,
you don't need much of a difference in,
in standard deviation in order to
produce radical differences at the
extreme.
So for example,
I'll give you,
I'll give you an example,
males are more aggressive than females
among humans,
but the effect is only about half a
standard deviation.
And so what that means is that if you
take two females,
a female and a male random lead from a
population,
and you were trying to guess who was the
more aggressive of the two,
most of the time,
you know,
about 60% of the time the male would be
more aggressive than the female,
but 40% of the time it would be
reversed.
So,
you know,
that's,
that's a lot of overlap.
But then here's the rub.
So let's say just for example,
that among the population of men and
women combined,
only the most aggressive person out of a
hundred ends up in jail.
Those are all men because that tilt
towards aggression is enough so that if
you go way,
way out on the distribution,
the only people who are that extreme,
our men,
even though the population isn't that
great.
So anyways,
there's a massive debate in the,
um,
relevant literature about the potential
consequences of that for things like
cognitive function because there's some
indication as well that men are more
cognitively specialized,
but women are more cognitively robust.
And so anyways,
it doesn't really matter.
But what does matter,
what does matter is the fact of this
permanent dominance hierarchy.
Now the dominance hierarchy also has
another,
the male dominance hierarchy also has
another feature.
So we already said that,
you know,
on average men are half as likely to
leave offspring as women are.
And so what that means is that all
things considered,
uh,
this isn't,
I'm not trying to make this into a
circular argument because I could say
it's the more successful males that
leave offspring.
But then you'd say,
well that's a definition,
Darwinian definition of success.
But I'm not,
I don't mean Darwinian success.
Cause that's self evident.
What I mean is that if you look in the
modern world for example,
and you try to predict number of
available sexual partners for given
mail,
your best predictive measure of that is
income.
And the best predictive measure of that
is intelligence and conscientiousness.
And so what happens is that males orient
themselves in groups and then they
compete and then women peel off the top.
And so,
and so the women are in a position of
judgment on men.
And the judgment is the judgment of
nature.
Now,
from a Darwinian perspective,
you know,
when we think of nature,
we think of like a friend.
It depends on who you are.
But like if you're an environmentalist,
you think of a French impressionists
landscape,
you know,
forgetting that nature is also malarial
mosquitoes and cancer and all those and
you know,
rats infected with bubonic plague and
all those other lovely things.
Um,
but from a Darwinian perspective,
you can define nature much more
straightforwardly and more accurately as
that which selects now,
you know,
you hear a lot about natural selection
and natural selection basically assumes
that there are a random distribution of
alterations in genetic structure in any,
in any population,
in any generation.
And some of those random alterations
will be more suited to that particular
environment suited being they'll live
and they'll reproduce.
And genetic transformation takes place
across the millennia as the organism
chases the landscape,
roughly speaking.
But Darwin,
you know,
Darwin who is an unbelievably
intelligent person,
was also very,
very interested in sexual selection.
And as far as Darwin was concerned,
sexual selection was just as powerful a
force in modifying genetic structure,
modifying them,
driving evolution as um,
natural selection.
And that's the way have been very
underplayed by biologists.
And that's the only started to switch
maybe in the last,
I would say it hasn't switched that much
yet,
but it only really started to switch
probably in about the last 25 years.
And that's because the idea of sexual
selection makes things a hell of a lot
more complicated.
You know,
because,
well,
first of all,
you know,
in the standard Darwinian account of
evolution,
there's no place for mind,
right?
There's no place for a creator.
There's no place for teleology.
And teleology is something moving
towards an end goal.
Right?
But your thing is if sexual selection is
operative and if consciousness is
ancient than mine has been operating
through sexual selection and as long as
there's been sexual selection,
I mean,
so you think,
you think,
do you have any choice?
Do you make any choice in who your
partner will be?
A sexual partner will be an answer to
that as well.
It's hardly random.
You make a choice.
And what's interesting is that,
you know,
if you take 60 people,
let's say if you took 60 women and you
ask them,
you showed them a bunch of man and you
asked them to rank them in terms of
their attractiveness,
there's going to be fairly consistent
rankings.
You know,
I mean,
we know what makes up attractive facial
features for women and for men you,
it's easy to determine that.
What you do is you take 60 faces and
you,
you average the features so you don't
get the average person because the
average person is more like immediate.
You get the average person and the
average person has perfectly symmetrical
features that are nicely shaped and
fairly big eyes.
And,
and,
and they're,
they're very,
you know,
they're very nice looking.
They're very attractive.
And so that means that there's like a
central human form in the sense that
we're,
we find attractive and we see this in
other species.
For example,
there are butterflies who won't mate
with another butterfly if it's,
if it's like a 16th of an inch out of
symmetry because then it's not a
butterfly of that type.
You know?
And that's how people think too,
is the more you deviate from the average
person,
the less canonically human you appear
and the less attractive that you appear.
And so,
you know,
we're chasing this ideal in some sense.
That's an emergent property of the
nature of our species.
And then,
you know,
there are certain physical
characteristics,
um,
wide shoulders in men and narrow waist
and women.
It's waist to hip ratio is a very common
marker of beauty across cultures and
across body types.
Interestingly enough.
So
if you take federal women and heavier
women and you get men to rate the
attractiveness of the women within that
category,
the heavy women and the light women who
have a hip waist to hip ratio of about
0.68 are the ones that are judged most
attractive physically and so,
and that actually correlates by the way
with fertility because this abdominal
fat in a young woman is a sign of ill
health and also a mark or a decreased
likelihood of conception.
Now none of this is operating co
consciously,
obviously it's,
it's deeply wired into us.
It's part of our immediate perception.
But it still does indicate that there is
an ideal,
like a platonic ideal lurking at the
back of our minds against whom we
compare everyone that we meet.
And then you might say,
well what's the nature of that plot?
Platonic ideal?
And that's a very,
very complicated question.
You know,
I would say that I would say that you
could,
you could almost literally claim that
the,
well you can certainly claim that the
ideal male is represented mythology as a
hero.
So,
and that's actually what mythologies
about.
It's about representing ideal patterns
of behavior.
So it's hardly surprising.
And so you know,
if you go to a movie and it's a romance
and there's the main lead character that
you're supposed to fall in love with,
if you happen to be the kind of person
that would fall in love with that kind
of person,
then he's going to act out of particular
a particular pattern of behavior and the
pattern of behavior is quite
identifiable.
So for example,
he's going to be,
he's going to move forward and explore
and not hide in cower.
And the probability that is going to be
creative is very high and the
probability that he's going to be good
looking and strong,
it's very high.
And so those are architectural features
and those aren't all the architectural
features because those are in some sense
those are the,
those are the self evident once.
But you know,
people are also evaluating each other
for such things as intelligence and
personality and character.
And
you could say in some sense the men are
competing to be the best man and the
women are watching the male competition
to take the man who wins on the
presupposition that he wouldn't win if
he wasn't the best map.
It's a very,
very intelligent strategy,
you know,
because why not outsource the problem
you let the men sorted out while exists
to cognitive,
to cognitively complex to compute.
You could say that the male dominance
hierarchy is equivalent to the stock
market.
It's exactly equivalent to the stock
market is the mitten you'd like the
stocks or stocks are always competing
with one another and with every other
commodity for primacy of price and
value.
And that's exactly what happens with
male competition.
So one of the things that we've just
discovered in my lab,
this is Caitlin burtons work.
It's very cool.
We took a,
we were trying to understand the
fundamental substructure of conservatism
versus liberalism and we're,
and I'm going to speak in terms of
conservatism because that's how we,
that's how we construed the data.
Although we could have done the reverse
if we were going to construe liberalism
and what we did was we took,
we got a bunch of people to sit down and
write down statements.
They thought that conservatives versus
liberals would disagree with.
How do you know?
I think we had,
I don't remember how many statements,
300 something like that.
And we have a lot of people generate
them and take them from news items and
so forth because we didn't want any bias
in the,
in the initial questions step,
you know,
and,
or we didn't want to buy us that wasn't
there in the actual world.
So we have many people do this and then
we gave these questions too many,
many people online in a variety of
stages.
And we,
we extracted those out that seemed to
best fit the data and that we're,
and then assess them for the utility and
predicting things like party membership
or voting behavior.
And so we got a good structure.
It makes a lot of sense.
And what we found with regards to the
conservatism was,
um,
there was an ethnocentrism factor.
It was the third week is factor.
And that would be associated with in
group preference versus outgroup
derogation.
So those are anti-immigrant people
fundamentally,
you know,
and they're,
they're leather ethnocentric.
That's,
that's,
that's the simplest way to,
that's the simplest way to explain it.
And then the next block that,
the second smallest factor was basically
religious traditionalism.
And so that,
and most of this was done with
Americans,
you know,
for,
for a variety of reasons.
And that was really where the
fundamentalist Christians nested,
you know,
and not,
not,
not everyone.
That was not only a factor,
that wasn't only a factor made up a
fundamentalist Christian beliefs,
but they loaded ha ha.
Heavily.
Those were people who weren't for stem
cell research.
They were antiabortion,
they were anti gay marriage.
Um,
or they were pro traditional,
which is how they see themselves.
And then the largest factor was what was
a factor that we call masculine
independence.
And it was more characteristic of men.
And what it basically consisted of was
an attitude that winners win and losers
lose.
And that's just how it should be.
So there it was,
it was,
uh,
the men who the personality predictors,
one of them was extroverted
assertiveness for example.
These were,
these are hunting and,
and the right to own firearms also
loaded on this factor.
But it was like,
it was masculine competitiveness I think
is the best way of thinking about it.
And uh,
okay.
I think it's a good illustration of the
kind of individual attitude that makes
you more likely to attempt to climb up
dominance hierarchies and dominate them
from the top down.
You know?
And that's not necessarily something
that would be associated with factors
like compassion.
So,
and then we,
well,
I'll leave it at that.
It's just,
you can see,
I,
I'm telling you that because you can see
how these proclivities emerge and
manifest themselves in all sorts of
areas of behavior.
I can tell you something else that's
very interesting about,
about men and violence.
MMM.
I don't know if I can the story straight
because
it's been a while since I told it.
Yeah.
So there's this interesting phenomenon
that it's very characteristic of,
of,
of societies,
I believe pretty much everywhere it's
being studied.
Now you can calculate an index called
the Gini Coefficient.
The Gini Coefficient is a number that
represents how much inequality of income
distribution.
There isn't a given geographical area.
So you could calculate a Gini
Coefficient for a street or uh,
you know,
um,
an area in a city or a city or a state
or a country.
You can do it at all those levels.
And,
uh,
what you find is,
you know,
you always hear this idea that poverty
causes crime.
That's a classic left wing idea,
but it's wrong.
It's seriously wrong and it's
importantly wrong.
And it's d definitively wrong.
Not only that,
so there's no argument about this.
It's already been established.
What causes crime?
Especially aggressive crime is relative
poverty and relative poverty is not the
same thing as poverty at all.
It's seriously not the same thing.
Poverty is when you don't have enough to
eat.
Relative poverty is when the guy next
door has a much better car than you.
So,
and there's lots of relative poverty in
the United States and there's some
absolute poverty.
But even the absolute poverty in the
United States is nothing like the
absolute poverty say in places like
India or in sub Saharan Africa where
absolute poverty means you have nothing.
Now what's really interesting about the
Gini Coefficient is that if you go to
places where everyone roughly speaking
is,
is poor say by national standards.
Um,
I think South Dakota was often used as
an example or maybe one of the maritime
provinces like Newfoundland,
where there's,
where there's low average income,
but it's pretty flat distribution.
There's almost no crime.
And if you go to places where the
everyone's rich,
then there's almost no crime.
But if you go places where there were
poor people and moderately well off
people and rich people and the
distribution is really steep,
then the rate of aggressive behavior
among young men and it's usually within
their own ethnic group,
starts to spa,
skyrocketed out of control.
And the reason for that seems to be that
if the dominance hierarchy is too steep
than the young men have no likelihood of
climbing to a dominant position while
playing the standard social game.
And so what they do is turn to
aggression,
aggression to,
to make their mark on the world.
And it works too.
That's the other thing is that make no
mistake about it.
If you're,
if you're looking for status in a place
where status is hard to achieve and
you're the meanest,
toughest guy around then and you know
around a bunch of people who like you
don't have much money,
then you're going to benefit from that
status if it works.
Yup.
Would that be a part of the reason why?
Cause I know the,
I think the violent crime rate in the U
S is higher than it is in Canada.
Would that be part of the reason that,
sure.
Okay.
Sure.
Yeah.
I mean,
you can make a real conservative
argument for making sure that,
you know,
the conservatives are very anti income
distribution and we figured that's
because of the guys that have this male
independence,
you know,
they identify with this male
independence factor.
They don't want to be distributing
resources to people who are down in the
dominance hierarchy because they will,
they want them down in the dominance
hierarchy.
They want there to be a difference
between the people on talk and the
people on the bottom so that they can be
the people on talk so that it increases
the relative attractiveness.
Like it's a perfectly logical game and
they presume that while the rules are
set up and like every man can go for it,
do as fast in the winner wins and the
loser loses.
And that's just how it is.
And don't ask me to fix it because I
don't want to,
you know,
and it'd,
besides that it's,
I don't find it,
I find it distasteful to attempt to fix
it more than that.
Right.
Because it's a moral issue.
It's not just an intellectual issue.
So,
so you,
you can make a case,
however you can make a case from the
conservative point of view,
especially with regards to say beliefs
and religious traditionalism and the
desire to maintain social stability that
you shouldn't let income distribution
become two unequal.
Like one of the big things your society
has to do is to make sure that that
doesn't get out of hand because it tends
to get out of hand.
It tends towards a few people having
everything and almost everyone else
having nothing.
It's a natural in a sense,
it's a natural consequence of economic
progression,
which is actually something that marks
pointed out,
although an Italian named Burrito and
figured it out at approximately the same
time.
And I think with a lot more conceptual
clarity,
but the more unequal you let your
society get,
the higher the probability of of death,
roughly speaking through through violent
causes.
And you know,
um,
but,
but what I'm telling you why it is that,
you know,
men want to climb the dominant Turk and
the reason they want to call them the
dominance hierarchies because that's how
they get access to women,
um,
familiar and yet familiar and the
structure.
Um,
so it seems like we all want it within
the structure,
but we don't want the rule to apply to
ourselves.
Well,
we,
we have this contradictory problem.
We want to be protected by the
structure,
but we want to advance our position
within it.
And so that means what that should mean.
And this is,
I think the definition of civilized
behavior is that you're allowed to
advance your position within the
structure as long as you don't disrupt
it negatively.
You know,
and I think most people do do that.
In fact,
I think people in,
in civilized countries do that so
effectively that it's an absolutely
incomprehensible miracle.
I can't understand how or why it ever
got established.
But a psychopath will,
he climbed the ladder and cut the rungs
off underneath them fundamentally.
Right?
It's like he doesn't care.
He doesn't even care if the damn thing
maintains itself.
You know,
he's perfectly willing to have it
destroyed after he's exhausted it,
you know?
But if everyone acted like that,
or even if a fairly substantial
percentage of people acted like that,
the whole thing would come to a halt.
Virtually like in no time flat.
So,
so mean.
Why
c you might hear,
here's the reason likely,
you know,
cause one of the things we were talking
about was masculine violence.
Now the thing about masculine violence
is it only tends to emerge in situations
where there does,
there don't seem to be any other
reasonably viable means of advancing
status.
So it's not reasonable to say that men
are aggressive.
You can say that on average men are more
aggressive than women.
And you can also say that if that,
if you put men in a situation where they
have no,
where they can see status differences,
but they have no means of moving
forward,
that they're likely to turn to
aggression as a way of establishing
dominance.
And then you can say that that's the
reason for that is because it makes them
more attractive.
What the fundamental reason
I read this article was about how a
polygamous societies are more Marlin.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Like when one guy has two wives,
I mean 50% of the population.
That's right.
Yeah.
And that's exactly right that the,
the,
the evolutionary psychology explanation
for the pathology of polygamy is that if
once you let it establish itself,
then the men get ultraviolet.
So,
so would you say that
many people have said that and yes.
I think you can make a strong case for
that.
And I think the fundamental reason is
the one that you just pointed out,
you know,
the idea is,
well,
would you rather have one woman
or die,
you know,
or sorry,
that's not quite right.
Would you rather no,
that's not quite,
that's not quite right would you,
it's more like would you be willing to
limit yourself to one partner or have a
shot at many partners but a much higher
probability of dying.
Right.
And you know,
some guys will take that,
they'll take the high risk approach,
you know,
so now if this doesn't eliminate the
difference in individual differences in
determining who is going to be
aggressive,
because what'll happen is that as the
Gini Coefficient pressure rises,
the more aggressive men,
the men who are more aggressive by
nature will get more aggressive first.
Right?
So you could imagine there is a
threshold phenomenon in some sense.
So,
and I don't,
I should tell you as well is the
relationship between the Gini
Coefficient and male on male homicide
isn't like 0.2 or 0.3 which is about the
correlation that you'd get if you were
predicting something like that.
Using personality.
It's like 0.8 or 0.9 it's like it eats
up all of it.
It's the explanation.
So it's a huge effect.
You know,
it's so,
it's so big and effected.
You could basically say,
oh,
well we figured that out.
Although psychologists never know when
they figured anything out in.
They keep endlessly retesting it over
and over and over because you know,
we don't know how to bring our science
to a store,
but if you don't accept the Gini
Coefficient aggression down,
it's like you might as well throw the
rest of social sciences out the window
because the effect is unbelievably
powerful.
What you go play areas take place.
It depends.
You can do it at any level of analysis.
You can do it,
you can do it by county,
you can do it by city,
you can do it by state and you can do it
by country and it works on all of those
levels.
Predicted aggression,
you bet.
Yup.
Yeah,
and that's a great question.
I mean the methodologically
sophisticated studies have done exactly
that to ensure that while to ensure that
it's actually this phenomena rather than
other factors that might be operative in
that particular geographical area.
So countries with a higher gr Gini
Coefficient or more violent and cities
within that country that have a higher
than average Gini Coefficient for that
country are more violent on average.
It's a very,
very robust,
robust,
robust finding.
So,
all right,
so
we're good.
We're going to say for the sake of
argument that you've got the male
dominance hierarchy and it's represented
as masculine.
No.
One of the things you've said,
he thought that women carried an image
of Matt men in their unconscious and
she,
he thought that the image that women
carried of men in their unconscious was
a group of men,
not an individual matt,
he called that the animus.
Whereas he believed that the image that
women image of women that men carried in
their collective unconscious was of a
single woman and he called that the
anima.
Now I'm just,
I'm just telling you that like I,
I'm not going to justify it or even
discuss it,
but I just want you to keep that in the
back of your mind.
And
so I guess part of the reason that that
are telling me that come to think of it
is that I think it may provide some
insight into why the idea of the
Patriarchy has become such a well
accepted notion.
Um,
because it is an architectural notion
but it's a one sided architectural
notion.
Okay.
So back to sexual selection.
Now
we already talked about the fact that
biologists perhaps were uncomfortable
with the idea of sexual selection
because it brings a non random factor
into evolution.
Uh,
seriously nonrandom random factor
because you have to go back as far as
you can in history to where there was no
choice on the part of the organism to
attribute evolution,
natural selection alone.
And you have to go a long ways back.
As I said,
even butterflies are perfectly capable
of distinguishing between a high quality
butterfly partner in butterfly terms and
the low quality butterfly partner.
And you know that that insects have been
around for a very,
very long time.
So we have no idea what that actually
means is that we have no idea what rule
choice has made in,
in the evolutionary process.
But one thing that you can infer is that
the reason that human beings are the way
they are now and not like art chimp
slash human ancestor is because the
sexual selection process got started and
it was intense.
And so as a consequence of that,
well here we are.
And so,
you know,
maybe it was a good thing,
although it's,
it's very hard in some sense and all
those people who failed and that's,
you know,
roughly speaking twice as many men as
women.
So you know,
so then that also raises the question
like who exactly,
who's responsible for the male dominance
arc?
Cause you could say,
well it's male competitiveness,
but you could also say,
yeah,
well it's an inevitable function of
female selection.
And so,
which is not an argument that you hear
very often,
but I think it's a very difficult
argument to escape from.
And that leads us to our next
hypothesis.
So we're going to say,
well the masculine dominance hierarchy
is represented as masculine.
I'm going to call that the great father
for the time being.
And that's the permanent dominance
hierarchy of men.
And it's always there.
It moves through history.
It's different men all the time,
but it's like the men slot in and out as
they are born and die.
But the structure itself stays intact
across forever.
It's always there.
It's been there at least for millions of
years.
So for our purposes,
we'll just call it permanent.
It's a permanent part of the experience
and it's a big part of it.
And you know,
as culture it gets more and more
covers larger and larger expanses of
territory and gets more and more
sophisticated.
It's an ever larger part of reality.
So I mean,
most of us spend almost all our time
coping with the dominance hierarchy and
almost none of our time combating
nature.
You know,
you get wet and today you get wet for a
little while and that's it,
you know?
But most of the problems that you would
face in a purely natural environments,
like you're so distant from them that
you can hardly even imagine.
You can't even imagine what it would be
like in some sense to be in an
environment like that.
So yeah,
caution is meant to be compared with,
like for example,
Jersey resonated with women and there's
like some,
some sort of competitive fitness and
women with sandy worse from,
so was driving
hard.
Well that's a good question.
So the way I would answer that question
is two fold.
So the question was what drives women
to,
to move to the top of the hierarchy?
It's something that's worth discussing.
So if anybody objects to what I'm going
to say,
then please do.
Because I'm not,
you know,
dishing the cell does receive truth.
It's,
it's,
I've been trying to figure this out and
this is what it looks like to me.
The first thing is I think they're male
and female.
Dominic's archies both exist,
but they're different and that females
compete with each other intensely,
but they don't compete for the same
things and they don't compete the same
way.
So let me tell you a little story.
This is a bit of a divergence,
but it's an interesting point.
And one of the,
you know,
one of the questions I've always been
asked in this class is because I'm going
to lay out a hero story for you and the
fundamental hero archetype and the hero
is masculine in mythology.
And so the women always ask,
well what about the role of the woman?
And it's like it's very,
very complex,
which of course all you women already
know because it is very,
very complex.
So,
but it isn't something that,
first of all,
I don't think it was a question that
would have been asked before the
invention of the birth control pill
because we know what the table,
we know what the archetypal female is
prior to that.
It's the Virgin Mary with with child,
it's virgin with child,
which means like it means that the unit
for woman is woman with child.
It's not woman,
it's woman with a child.
And well that's obvious why that is.
Because as soon as you become a woman in
most societies you have a child before
that you were a girl.
And that's,
you know,
that's in some sense that's irrelevant,
in terms of your destiny.
Now you might say,
well,
what,
what's your architectural pattern if
you're not a mother?
While the way it looks to me is that
there's two archetypes for personal
development,
for the personal path,
roughly speaking,
there's the hero.
And that would be the person who
explores the unknown and discover
something of value and brings it back
and distributes it to the community.
So it's like a hunting,
it's like,
it's probably predicated on a hunting,
uh,
platform because we,
our bodies are hunting platforms
basically.
So,
you know,
and one theory about what men did,
which is a very probable theory,
is that they went out and hunted for
meat and chimps like meat.
They'll eat it whenever they can.
And although they're not very good
hunters,
but they will definitely eat meat.
And human beings are so good at hunting
that we probably,
well,
for example,
we probably wiped out the mammoth.
And when human beings came into North
America,
there was as many different kinds of
large animals in North America as there
was an Africa and human beings killed
all of them.
And that was just with,
you know,
like they didn't have our notion of
technologically sophisticated weapons.
It was bows and arrows and clubs and
spears and nonetheless,
like they got rid of everything,
you know,
large cats,
giant beavers,
mammoths,
um,
we're very,
very,
very dangerous.
And anyways,
so,
but then there's another archetype,
which is the,
I would say it's the maternal archetype
in a sense.
And one of the things that's very
interesting about human males is that
they're quite maternal by comparison to
other animals.
So for example,
like the mother bear doesn't have them
mail there.
The board,
he said bores and sounds with bears,
I think it is anyways,
um,
you keep the cubs away from the mail
because he'll kill them.
Now,
not all males will be that,
but many will,
they don't have any filial,
um,
attachment.
And that's the case for many,
but not all complex mammals.
You know,
pair bonding on a permanent basis is
relatively rare,
but joint provision of children,
that's exceedingly rare.
And men are pretty good at taking care
of children.
You know,
they're,
I would say they're not as good at
taking care of infants as women are
because they don't have the full range
of resources at hand and they're not,
I don't think they're,
they,
I don't think they have the same kind of
immediate intuitive understanding of or
attraction to babies that men have.
I think that switches around the age of
two or two and a half when the kids can
engage in rough and tumble play because
men are much more likely to engage in
rough and tumble play with children than
women are.
And rough and tumble play seems to be
one of the things that civilizes
children.
And it's partly because,
you know,
one of the things that you have to learn
when you're a child is what actually
hurts you and what can be ignored and
what actually hurts someone else and
what can be ignored and the best way to
learn that as in rough and tumble play.
Because what happens is that if you
playing with a kid,
they get more and more excited than they
do more and more crazy things until they
do something that either hurts them or,
or hurts you.
And then you have to say,
look,
you know,
that's,
you can't do that.
And,
and it's,
it's like a dance in a sense.
You know,
when you're wrestling with a little kid
and you have to let them win fairly
frequently because otherwise they don't,
they don't continue the game.
And you can tell him that because if
there,
if the game is going well,
they're laughing with insane delight
because kids just love rough and tumble
play,
you know?
And,
and they love crazy things.
I mean,
you can throw them in the air and catch
them and they think that's just great,
you know?
And,
but partly what you're doing is you're
extending their body in all sorts of
ways in getting them to learn in an
embodied sense where the limits of that,
where their limits are and where the
limits of other people are.
And that's embodied in children who
haven't had that man.
They're just so awkward.
It's unbelievable.
You know,
they might have some hypothetical sense
of how to interact with another person,
but they don't have an embodied sense of
it.
And they can't tell the difference
between what hurts them and what
doesn't.
You know,
cause often a young child,
if,
if they're startled,
they'll start to cry and then you can
say,
well,
you know,
that didn't hurt.
And then they'll notice,
oh yeah,
that didn't hurt.
And they'll stop crying.
But if they haven't had their limits
tested,
they'll cry at anything unexpected,
even if it doesn't hurt.
And that's not good because if you cry
under all conditions,
the probability that you'll make friends
when you're three is like zero because
another kid will start playing with you
and maybe play rough.
And if you burst into tears,
you know,
several times the person,
the kid is just going to go somewhere
else and find a different playmate,
you know,
they'll say you're just a baby,
which is roughly exactly accurate.
Roughly.
Exactly.
Roughly accurate.
So,
so anyways,
I'm back to the architectural
representation.
I think really the way to think about it
is that for men,
the hero archetype is the,
is the archetype that's dominant and in
the forefront and the maternal archetype
is his subordinate.
And in the background,
I mean in inside their own psyches.
Whereas with women it's reversed.
So each of the genders can play the role
of the other gender,
but there's a tilt in each of them
towards the,
what would you say?
Well,
towards gender,
I would say towards typical human gender
normative behavior.
Now,
the social constructionist believed that
no such thing exists,
but those people are so pathological
that even considering what they have to
say is a mistake.
So they act as if people have,
they act as if there is no biology and
everything's cultural and it's like,
well,
no,
that's just not right now.
What biology means in practice and what
you should do about it.
That's a whole different question.
But to think of all these differences as
socially height differences between men
and women are not socially constructed
and they they're relevant and the upper
body strength differences between men
and women are not socially constructed
and they're relevant to,
you know.
So one of the things I was wondering
about,
maybe you guys can help me clarify this
or tell me where I'm not thinking about
this property and if you think there's
any,
if I'm missing something,
letting me know.
One of the things my daughter said,
she watched my,
my son one day have a fight with his
best friend.
It was a physical fight,
you know,
and so his best friend did something
that my son didn't regard it as
appropriate and so he hit him and then
there was a fight and then you know,
three days later they were friends
again.
And my daughter said to me that she was
very annoyed by that,
which wasn't the fight exactly,
but the fact that they could have a
fight and then they were friends again
three days later because she said that
that option wasn't available to women
right now.
And the option is the option that the
men have is,
well if you get out of handle just Saki
one and then we'll have established
where the boundaries of of civilized
behavior begin and end.
And I would say that in my experience,
if I'm talking to someone who self
confident and masculine and
accomplished,
there's always an undercurrent of
potential violence.
It's an undercurrent and that's actually
an undercurrent of respect,
which means like there's things that we
can do to each other in a civilized way.
But there are rules that if you break
like all hell's gonna break loose.
And one of the consequences of that is
that it doesn't right now the typical
bullying pattern for women in high
school and junior highs is reputation,
destruction.
And I'm wondering what does,
what are the implications for the
conduct of behavior if there is no
recourse to aggression to solve disputes
cause they don't get solved.
You know,
I've tried to analyze what it means to
say no to someone cause no means
something,
right?
No means while if you tell a child know
what you're basically telling the child.
As far as I can tell is that if you
continue doing that,
something you don't like will happen to
you.
And then if you're civilized at saying
no,
what happens is you say no a couple of
times and then instead of devaluing the
word,
which is what you do,
if you just said it over and over a
hundred times with no consequences,
you take action that's nonverbal.
And so one of the things you might do is
remove the child from the situation or
you might put them on the steps or maybe
you put them on the steps and they run
away.
So you have to hold them on the steps.
But the point is,
the point to the child is there are
limits and if you exceed them,
you will be physically control.
What if there's no option for physical
control?
What happens?
Well,
I don't know the answer to that.
I don't know what women do about that,
but I also don't know what men do about
that in relationship to women.
So I was watching something the other
day.
It was this,
I posted it on my twitter account as an
as an example of animus possession.
So this a woman and a man,
we're having a dispute on the street.
It was a political dispute and this
particular woman was like the way she
was behaving towards this particular man
was such that had she been a man and had
he been a man,
he would have definitely hit her because
she was right in his face and she was
cursing at him and swearing and calling
them an idiot and like really like being
hyper aggressive.
Of course he couldn't do anything about
it.
So then I was watching that and I was
thinking just exactly what are you
supposed to do in a situation like that
because you're screwed no matter what
you do.
If you're on the male side,
it's like you can't eat,
you can't,
you certainly can't intervene
physically.
It's like you're dead in the water
instant instantly in your eyes,
the eyes of society and in the woman's
eyes instantly if you move past the
boundary,
if you leave,
well there's no glory.
And running away,
that's for sure.
So what exactly is supposed to happen?
I have no idea what supposed to happen
in a situation like that.
I think what happens,
what will happen over time is that man
just won't put themselves in those
situations.
I think what the male would have to do
in that situation is behave like a woman
in a female dominance hierarchies.
So he stands there and takes it and then
afterwards it goes off and bad smell,
bad mouth search,
social circle of uh Huh.
Right,
right.
But you know,
that's definitely not seen as an
admirable form of behavior among men.
So I mean,
I don't think it's an admirable form of
behavior,
period,
but,
but I mean,
you know,
I mean aggression is often not
admirable,
so that,
so that's fine.
Yeah.
When you take away emotion like it,
when someone's acting aggressively
towards you and you've reserved your
emotion,
it gives them a lot less to feed off of.
And that ends up taking power away in a
similar way that aggression does because
people react aggressively and they want
to feed back.
That gives them more.
Oh,
definitely.
Oh yeah.
Would it be a real victory for her if
she would've got slapped?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Because it would have,
it would have proved everything she said
instantly.
Yeah,
yeah,
definitely.
But when you dismiss power is gone.
Yeah.
You have all the power.
Well I think that that would be a
reasonably effective strategy for us.
A street con,
a street confrontation like that,
I'm not so sure how well it would work
in a,
in a prolonged competition inside a
company,
for example.
Right.
The short hair,
you know,
hierarchy.
Yeah.
Because you know,
the truth of the matter is,
is that men have no idea how to treat
women.
If they're in male power hierarchies,
they have no idea how to treat them.
And that's because we have no idea how
to do that.
No one has any idea how to do that.
It's only been happening in any,
you know,
pronounce since for about,
well,
on a societal level,
really,
probably since the mid seventies you
know,
it's,
it's three generations,
it's a drop in the bucket and it's in
very,
very difficult thing to sort out.
So,
I mean,
part of the reason that I'm thinking
about these sorts of things is because
I've been very interested in the fact
that male men are doing very badly in
junior high and high school and they're
bailing out of the universities like
math.
Like at the rate it's going,
there'll be almost no men in most
disciplines within 10 years.
So I mean,
you can tell that even in this class,
no,
although it's funny because on my
youtube videos,
I w I look at the gender distribution
for viewing and it's 80% male,
which,
you know,
it's interesting to me.
I,
I'm not sure exactly why that is,
but in lots of fields it's,
it's 80 20 women already.
And so I can't,
I can't see why that won't.
I think it will accelerate as we move
forward rather than slowing down.
So.
All right.
So anyways,
back to sexual selection and,
and the power hierarchy.
No,
from a Darwinian perspective,
one of the things that you might do is
call whatever's selects nature.
And so when we think of nature,
and when you think about nature from a
scientific perspective,
we don't ever think about humans as,
as agents of nature,
right?
We tend to conceive of the human being
as something that stands against nature,
right?
That's a mythology.
It's like the human being against the
natural world.
It's a very common,
it's very common plot in movies and in
stories.
So it's man against nature,
roughly speaking.
So we tend to think of those as separate
categories.
But
if women do the selection among human
beings,
at least they do the intense selection
than women are nature for men.
And that's exactly what the archetype
is.
It's mother nature.
And Mother Nature has a very vicious
element.
And the vicious element of Mother Nature
is rejection.
And that can be maternal rejection,
which is,
you know,
certainly something that causes a
tremendous amount of trauma.
But it can also be
the more,
the most fundamental form of rejection,
which is which,
and the most fundamental form of
rejection,
it's sexual rejection because it,
it means that you are judged as
biologically I'm worthy,
roughly speaking.
So there's other reasons why.
So the reason I'm,
I'm,
I'm telling you this because I've been
trying to puzzle out what you see in
mythology quite clearly,
is that the dominance hierarchy is
represented as male.
So culture is male and nature is female.
I thought,
why the hell would nature be female?
It's like,
okay,
well I've given you one reason.
And I think it's the primary reason.
There's other reasons,
because nature is also seen as that
which produces natural forms.
Of course,
women produce natural forms.
So that's,
that's a logical association.
And then
what's the other one that was about,
well,
we can leave it at that for the time
being.
So now let me show you how I think that
that's represented.
I think this is the,
I think this is the way the world is
structured when you consider it as a
place of action.
So the world has a place of action,
has characters not like the elements are
characters and the characters are
engaged in,
in dramatic behavior.
So,
and there are classes of characters.
And as far as I can tell,
this is a reasonably comprehensive
classification of dramatic characters.
And we'll start from the inside and go
out.
And you can think of any of these as
primary by the way.
And you'll see that reflected in
different kinds of mythology.
So sometimes the maternal is primary and
sometimes the culture is primary and
sometimes that the hero,
the individual's primary.
And I think that's because these three
things are irreducibly primary in that
from uh,
from the perspective of consciousness.
In that to be conscious there has to be
you.
But if you're conscious,
you have to have evolved within a
culture and that culture is necessarily
nested in the natural world.
And so wherever there's one,
there's all three.
And the individual is also the thing.
Without the individual,
there wouldn't be any separation between
nature and culture.
And so you can see the individual,
individual consciousness is the
generator of the entire structure.
But you can say that about any of the
characters.
So there's the architectural son cause
the hero tends to be masculine and then
it has a,
that character has a positive element
and a negative element.
And the positive element is the good,
the good person.
And the negative element is the bad
person.
And I would say the architectural
representations of those are like the
savior and Satan.
And that's basically,
there are portrayals like that in
virtually every system of mythology and
religion.
Now it seems to me that in some sense
Christianity,
and this was probably under the
influence of the zero astrons develop
the most articulated representation of
good versus evil at the individual
level.
And that's why you can identify two
fundamental characters in the Christian
story,
so to speak,
that play out these rules.
And they're seen as eternally
adversaries locked in battle across
time.
And that would be the battle it takes
place in the natural world about what
takes place in the cultural world.
And the battle takes place within as
well.
Okay.
So,
and you can see that reflected in
stories all the time because you know,
if it's so,
it's so frequently the case that you
know,
the hero,
the superhero has his nemesis,
right?
And it's the guy that he's
extraordinarily well matched with who
continually tests his wits and whose
motivation is essentially destructive.
And so you see that with Batman and the
joker for example,
for you see it with Sherlock Holmes and
Moriarty or,
I mean there's always,
there's always this,
this pairing is pairing.
And that's partly because I think there
are the archetipal realms of human
decision making or something like are
you working to make things better or are
you working to make things worse?
Are you possessed by resentment and
hatred so that you want things to
degenerate and burn?
Or are you hopeful and,
and,
and capable of manifesting faith in the
future so that you're working to make
things better.
And then there's a battle in everyone,
in their own psyches.
And then there's a battle in culture.
There's a battle every year between
those two fundamental perspectives.
And then
the archetipal son is the son of the
great farther in the great father
represents two things.
Order,
interior,
Neri,
tyranny.
So there's the hero in the adversary at
the individual level.
Okay.
And at the social level there's order
and tyranny.
And so roughly speaking,
that's that.
See that the wise king or the Desk Bach
and the desk bod is someone who tries to
eat his own sons,
which is actually a fairly common
mythological trope.
And you know,
you're under the thumb of a desperate
when you're not allowed really either to
be hero or adversary,
you're just a cog in the structure of
the,
of the social world.
So that's despotism on the orderly side.
Well,
culture is what,
that's what we're sitting in right now.
I mean this is social order that it
encapsulates us.
Everything about it is social order.
I mean there,
there are rows there roughly linear,
you know,
everyone's in their place.
Everyone knows exactly what to do were
unbelievably well protected from,
from,
from virtually anything you could
possibly imagine.
And so,
you know,
we're in our father's living room,
so to speak.
And in that living room,
it's a safe space.
Oh God,
I should've never said that.
Anyways.
It's a well protected space in which
people are able to play and explore.
And it seems to me that one of the
functions that fathers play in a family,
if they're playing,
they're,
if they're fulfilling their function
properly,
is that what they do is put a perimeter
around the territory so that inside the
wall,
so to speak,
it's safe.
And inside the safe walls the children
can play and explore and in their
playing and exploring and they developed
their own individuality.
And so you know,
you keep the darkness at bay and you can
certainly see that that's what children
want because as soon as you put them in
a dark room,
the first thing they say is,
you know,
come chase the monsters away out from
underneath the bed.
And you know,
they wouldn't be thinking that if they
hadn't had an extraordinary long
evolutionary history of being chased by
monsters in the dark.
So,
and there are monsters in the dark and
everyone knows that,
which is why you tell your children not
to go play at night after you know,
after it's dark even now.
So,
so order and tyranny are the,
are the representations of culture.
And the thing is,
is that there's a constant interplay
between those two because you can never
tell exactly when order has gone too far
and become tyranny.
So,
and you can,
can never tell really when,
when there's so little order that while
the next thing happens,
which is the emergence of chaos and
chaos is the great mother and it's
creative and destructive and that's
nature itself.
And so,
and then on outside,
the very outside,
and this is the most complicated
category of all,
is that it's the dragon of chaos.
And it represents something that's very
difficult to conceptualize,
but it's the UN configured substructure
of being that gives rise to these other
categories.
So Donald Rumsfeld at point made a very
famous comment.
It become,
it became famous because,
because it,
it fits in architectural structure.
He said,
there are known unknowns and unknown
unknowns.
Okay?
The dragon of chaos is the unknown
unknown.
It's,
it's so unknown that you don't even know
it's there,
but it can write,
raise its head at any given point.
It's the thing that leaps out of you in
the darkness.
It's like the,
is it Zika?
Is that the new virus?
It's like the Zika virus.
It's like no one saw it coming.
It's a completely new manifestation of
of being and so known.
Unknown's you can make plans to
circumvent unknown unknown's they
they're completely unpredictable and
what's so interesting,
this is where it's so bloody complicated
because you really have to think about
things differently to grasp what this
means.
This is part of the reason that I have
trouble with the section of this course
on alchemy because it's so complicated
that it's okay.
So here,
think of it this way.
What is the unknown made up?
That's a pretty weird question.
So,
so I'll,
I'll try to walk you through it and we
won't get very far with this because
we'll have to do it 15 or 20 times I
think before it starts to become
something that you can,
that you can grapple with.
All right,
so it's September 11th,
2011 in the twin towers have just
fallen.
Sorry,
2001 yes,
yes.
Nine 11 alright.
What's emerged?
What's happened?
Well,
one answer to that is that the tower is
fail,
but it's in very,
very poor answer because that was an
unknown unknown,
I would say.
And it traumatize people.
I mean,
everyone even in Toronto walked around
in shock for about two days after that.
And the reason was for that was that we
didn't know what felt the buildings
fail.
But the thing is the buildings aren't
isolated.
Like they're not some abandoned building
standing out there in the middle of the
field in a barren wasteland in the
middle of an abandoned country.
They weren't buildings.
Exactly.
They're only buildings at the most
superficial level.
First of all,
they had 5,000 people in them,
or 5,000 people died.
If I remember correctly.
And then all of those people were
networked out with all sorts of other
people and they were networked at
multiple levels.
So they were family members,
but they were also elements in the
financial and economic machine.
And then and in the political machine.
And then what,
what was hit was of course,
not just the buildings,
but the economic and political system,
whatever that means.
And of course the people who took the
towers down weren't trying to knock
buildings down,
which is what you saw happening.
They were trying to knock down the
things the buildings were invisibly
related to.
And then you might ask,
well,
what were those buildings related to?
And it's a simpler question to actually
reverse the question and say,
well,
what weren't they related to?
And the reason that people were
traumatized in the aftermath was because
when we,
when our bodies in some sense answered
that question,
the answer was,
oh,
those buildings were probably attached
to everything in every possible way.
And so God only knows what's going to
come leaping out of that.
So what,
what happens when you see the buildings
fall?
The fact that you see the buildings fall
actually blinds you to what's happening.
It's like as a very peripheral
representation of the actual event,
because you could also say,
well,
it was a psychological event.
You know,
it echoed inside of you.
Well,
you don't see that.
You feel it and you don't really know
what it means,
but it puts a wave of uncertainty,
a radical wave of uncertainty into
everything.
Right.
And not only the present,
but also the future for sure.
Because things took a vicious turn after
that and almost immediately,
right.
The whole political system readjusted
itself.
It became much more authoritarian.
You know,
airports became like little fascist in
enclaves.
It was for me,
it went for many people,
I could hardly go into an airport.
It just drove me crazy to be lined up
like that and then subject to search by,
you know,
faceless.
What would you say?
There are faceless representations of
the,
of the paranoid state.
It's like God,
that's a horrible thing to have to
encounter.
It's a bloody horrible thing to train
people to get accustomed to.
It's really dangerous to train people to
accept that sort of thing.
It was a way worse consequence.
I think that in the,
the buildings falling down on
themselves.
But,
so that was one thing that happened.
What else happened?
Well,
the 4 trillion,
the $1 trillion surplus that was
projected by the Clintons at the end of
Bill Clinton's presidency,
which was the,
the prediction for the next 10 years
that the economy was moving along so
well,
that the US government was going to have
a $1 trillion surplus over the next 10
years,
turned into a $4 trillion deficit.
So that happened while,
and then we got tangled up,
even worse in the Middle East.
And of course that,
that I think is probably got worse as
time's gone on rather than better.
And we have no idea where that's going
to end.
You know,
I mean,
Russia is involved now and Russia
rattled nuclear weapons at Turkey the
other day,
you know,
even though Turkeys,
their largest trading partner and a
member of NATO,
you know,
and then you know,
a million refugees flooded into Europe
and God only knows what's going to
happen as a consequence of that.
It's like,
and it's not like the people who planted
the bomb didn't know that.
Like here's what they thought.
They thought,
oh,
the Soviet Union,
that was the second greatest power on
earth.
And then they waited into Afghanistan
and they got tangled up in a terrorist
war and how poof,
10 years later they didn't exist.
It's like maybe could do the same thing
to the United States.
It's like,
well who knows?
Maybe you could.
I mean they certainly read their
response to the nine 11 disaster was a,
in my opinion,
much more expensive than the disaster
itself.
I mean,
one of the things that's quite
horrifying is that here's one statistic.
Nobody flew in the aftermath of nine 11
for a while.
Like airplane flight bookings were way
down.
More people died in car accidents
because of not flying,
then were killed in the bombings.
And no one ever noticed that cause
people are being killed on the highway
all the time.
Right?
So it's like it's background noise as
far as we're concerned.
But you know,
it's,
it's a really good example of how not
only do you know what the event,
not know what the event is,
you can't even tell who the event
killed.
And so it's your apprehension of that
when it occurs that paralyzes you.
And that's the dragon of chaos,
roughly speaking.
That's an unknown unknown.
It's like all of reality,
all of the multiple levels of reality
that exists around you are all of a
sudden altered in an incomprehensible
manner.
And then you could say that,
well,
what happened was the alteration of that
reality,
that is what happened.
It's that you can only perceive it
essentially as the explosion in the
building and the consequent collapse.
And so you might say that,
well the nine,
you know,
the trick twin towers were brought down.
It's like that's such a low resolution
representation of what happened,
that it barely begins to describe that
event.
And so it's that invisible background of
complex interrelationships,
like a very,
very complex melody that's always going
on around you.
And as long as it works,
you don't even notice it.
What happens is it manifests itself as
predictable and desirable order,
which you can understand,
which is the reason we have predictable
and desirable.
Our order.
This room is configured so that you can
walk into it without being afraid.
And what that means is that it's a
radically simplified version of reality.
You know,
and you can see that.
I mean,
it's even got padded walls,
you know,
and that's to stop the sound bouncing so
that it won't annoy you.
You know?
I mean,
it's warm,
it's comfortable,
it's,
it's sort of neutral.
So it fades into the background.
Everyone here is civilized beyond
belief.
You know,
you,
you hear about the radical individualism
up the west.
I think I'm the,
of all the nonsense I've ever heard
that's gotta to be the most nonsensical
were so bloody obedient that it's,
it's insane.
If you go to Edmonton at three o'clock
in the morning and watch pedestrians,
they will stop at the don't walk light
and wait until it turns green.
Now the roads are wide and so they,
you know,
but it's still the case.
It's like,
really?
How's it?
How's you think you're an individual?
Really?
It's like I'm not complaining about it.
I think it's an amazing thing because
you know we can really zip cars to our
cities because people don't run out into
the middle of the streets and get
killed.
They stay where they're supposed to and
so it's incredibly efficient,
but we're so being well behaved that
it's just,
it's beyond you.
If you think about us as chimpanzees
with clothes,
you know we're doing pretty damn well
and we set up our environment so that
they're so simplified that we never have
to encounter this multi dimensional
layered reality of patterns that's just
moving around,
moving around us all the time and that
actually makes up reality.
That's reality.
That's what,
that's what the world is made out of.
That's a way different way of thinking
about it.
Then to think about the world is made up
say of Adams,
because you think that way,
you just think,
well,
it's sort of,
it's like marbles in space,
you know,
and,
and of course Adam's ours marbles and
everyone knows that and god only knows
what they are.
But that's still the image.
That's the metaphor of reality.
But that's not what reality is.
It's an insanely pattern orchestra of,
of phenomenon.
And that's really what it is.
And then if what happens is that you're
in this little orderly sub compartment
in the middle of it,
it's like you're in a box and the box is
inside a box.
Well let's think about it.
You're in a box.
Okay,
this box is in the building.
That's a box.
The building is in the university.
The universities in the city,
that's a box.
The city is in,
in the province.
That's a box that it's in Canada.
Then it's covered by the American
nuclear umbrella,
you know?
And then it's embedded in this immense
history of individual rights and
freedoms that have manifested themselves
as part of the political and economic
order.
And all of that's going on around you
and people are working like mad crazily
to keep all of those boxes intact.
And here you are sitting and thinking,
well what you see around you is reality.
It's like it is.
Yeah,
but man,
there is a lot of people making that
this reality so simple that you don't
have to think about it.
You can come in here and think about
ideas,
you know,
for like hours at a time and like you
don't get eaten by a crocodile.
It's really,
and you know,
no one comes running through here
pillaging,
which is of course the crocodile eating
and the pillaging were very,
very common occurrences in our
evolutionary history.
You know,
I mean for lots of our ancestors going
down to get water from the local river
was a life or death mission.
You know?
I mean,
I can't imagine having to get water from
a crocodile infested stream,
especially when that's where the lions
are hanging out too,
you know?
So that's ordered.
That's the positive element of order.
Now you can say,
students say this a lot.
Oh my God,
I'm so constrained within all these
boxes,
it's destroying my individuality.
You know?
And that's the tear radical.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's pathetic in some sense because God,
you know,
and you're so privileged,
it's just beyond comprehension.
But,
but,
but having said that,
it is also the case and,
and it's,
it has,
the case has to be made that you,
you do have to sacrifice your potential
to cultural norms.
And that is it.
You can argue that that's destructive.
And sometimes it really is disruptive.
Like creative people don't fit very well
into nested boxes.
And in order for them to fit,
they have to do damage in some sense to
their psyches because they're not
naturally
made to,
that isn't their natural environment
boxes within boxes.
And so they might say,
well,
I'm being oppressed.
And it's like,
well,
of course you're being oppressed.
It's like if you're in 50 boxes,
that's going to constrain your freedoms,
freedom of movement.
But maybe you should be somewhat
grateful for the fact that the box is
exist.
You think,
well,
you don't even notice them.
The boxes are so effective that you,
You can even criticize them and and you
should,
you don't because maybe they could be
better and not quite as rigid and so
forth.
And you know the criticism is the
criticism is justified but you have to
keep both of the,
both of the representations in mind at
the same time.
You know,
your culture is the wise king and the
desk bought at the same time and people
hate that sort of thing because,
and you know our rational minds and our
logical and our,
our,
our history of logical intellectual
thinking has forced us to assume that a
thing can't be itself and its opposite
at the same time.
But unfortunately when you're talking
about very large scale categories,
things are there,
what they are and they're opposite at
the same time because culture is the
wise king and the tyrant and that means
it's very difficult to adjust your
behavior in relationship to it because
you never know if you're talking to the
wise king or the tyrant,
you know and you'll feel that if you do
your taxes or if you have to deal with,
say you have to deal with the university
bureaucracy in some way.
It's like you know you're a number and
you know you're just annoying like
patients in a hospital because hospitals
would read a lot better if they didn't
have any patients in them.
Obviously you know when you feel that of
course whenever you're in a very complex
bureaucracy it's like you're
exchangeable and that's very annoying.
But by the same token,
while here you are,
so you have to criticize,
this is also a very complex form of
moral behavior.
You have to criticize with gratitude.
And that's something that students
should really be taught in university,
you know,
because the opposite of gratitude is
resentment.
And there is nothing that's more
pathological than resentment.
The only thing that comes close to
resentment in terms of its capacity to
produce misery is arrogance.
And those things are often,
it's arrogance,
resentment,
and deceit,
and it's like that's the evil triad.
You get all those three things going in
your life,
and boy,
you're going to be in rough shape very,
very rapidly.
So then
let's take a break
for 15 minutes,
okay.