All right,
on to another trait.
So
we talked about extroversion and
neuroticism and I basically laid out the
case for you that extroverted people
were more sensitive to incentive reward
and people who are high in neuroticism
more and more sensitive to anxiety on to
emotional pain and that there are
fundamental biological subsystems
associated with those dimensions.
And that it's not a single dimension,
which is also a very important thing to
note because people tend to think of
happy as the opposite of sad,
you know,
and it's,
it's not,
it's not because you can be happy or not
happy and you can be sad or not sad.
And I suppose if you're really sad,
you're not happy and sad at the same
time,
right?
So that would mean that you'd be an
introverted,
somebody who's high in neuroticism and
high and introversion.
Um,
you know,
you're not very enthusiastic under those
circumstances and you're quite sensitive
to negative emotions.
So,
and
well,
that's just how it goes.
And now you know,
the traits,
you might think that in some sense you
could score high on a trade and low on a
trade in that maybe high would be better
than low.
It's very,
very complicated.
I mean,
basically what you have to assume is
that the traits are now normally
distributed.
I think I have a normal distribute here
in a normal distribution here.
And also that there's an average,
most people cluster around the average
and then there's,
you know,
increasingly few people as you move
farther and farther to the extremes.
Well,
the reason that there's normal
distribution is because there are
adaptive advantages.
Speaking from a biological perspective,
there are adaptive advantages to every
position on that distribution.
So you might say,
well,
what's the use of being extremely
anxious and easily hurt?
And the answer to that might be,
well,
it's complicated,
but some potential answers might be,
um,
well,
it's not clear how sensitive you should
be to distress if you're going to be a
good caretaker of small infants,
for example.
And I think that that's a relevant issue
because women tend to be higher in trait
neuroticism than men.
It's about half a standard deviation
that occurs.
Interestingly enough,
pretty much right at puberty.
So if you look at boys and girls before,
before puberty,
there's not much difference in
sensitivity to negative emotion.
There seems to be a hormonal
transformation and uh,
you know,
we don't know exactly why that is.
Although we do know that it manifests
itself in a couple of different ways.
First,
it never goes away after that.
So women and men never equalize again in
terms of their sensitivity to negative
emotion.
Second,
it's,
it's true cross-culturally,
pretty much wherever you look.
And we'll talk about the cross cultural
findings a little bit in more detail
today because they're quite interesting.
And third,
it's also in keeping with the clinical
findings that women are much more to
both depression and anxiety from a
clinical perspective.
So maybe three to four times a
susceptible.
It depends on how you measure it
obviously.
But you know,
there's a lot of converging evidence
that suggest that and then well
it's not the only gender differences.
The other big gender differences in is
in agreeableness.
And that's the trick we're going to talk
about today.
Agreeableness is a tricky,
tricky trade.
It's not that easy to figure out because
it overlaps to some degree with what you
might think about extroversion.
Like extroverts are enthusiastic and
assertive,
but they're also really social,
right?
They cause they're gregarious and they
like to be around people and they liked
to tell jokes and,
and you might even think of them as
friendly in that if you meet an
extrovert,
they're going to make friends with you
pretty quickly or they're going to try
or they're going to try to charm.
You at least are trying to amuse you at
least.
And then you think,
well,
agreeableness is compassion and and
politeness.
So how does that exactly differ from
friendliness?
And the answer is well,
warm,
compassionate are compassionate and
empathic people care about you,
whereas the extrovert doesn't
necessarily care about you.
I mean they're,
they're in,
they're interested in being around you.
That's not the same thing as caring for
you.
You know,
like you could be interested in being
around interested in being around dogs
to play with them,
let's say.
But that doesn't necessarily mean that
you'd have any interest in caring for
them.
And so agreeableness looks like a caring
dimension.
And I think the right way to think about
it seems to be to be something like
this.
Imagine that during your life,
you,
uh,
you engage in a sequence of reciprocal
trains are reciprocal interactions.
Okay.
And you might say,
well,
how often should you give and how often
should you take?
And roughly speaking,
it should be 50,
50.
Right?
And hopefully the consequence of that is
each person gains more in fact than they
would if they were just working in
isolation.
So it's a really good deal.
But I would say roughly speaking,
that as you become more agreeable,
it's more like 60 40 for the other
person or 70,
30 for the other person or 80,
20.
And then as you become more
disagreeable,
it's the other way around.
It's 60% for me and 40% for you and so
forth.
And so one tails off into extreme
selfishness and the other tales off into
extreme
self sacrifice and too much selfishness.
It puts you in prison.
And too much self sacrifice.
Well
that's more complicated.
I would say that part of the pathology
that fried identified as characteristic
of the eatable family was,
is actually a consequence of too much
agreeableness and sort of the Hansel and
Gretel story.
You know,
you all know the Hansel and Gretel
story.
Hansel and Gretel have their two little
kids and their mother gets remarried or
their father,
I think it's their mother,
but I don't remember.
And anyways,
the step decides that the kids are kind
of a pain and that she or he convinces
the alternative partner to take them out
in the forest and just abandoned them.
They make their way back once,
but then they take them deeper into the
woods the second time anyway,
so they're wandering out.
They're all lost in the woods.
Right.
Which is a kind of a symbolic descend
into chaos.
Right.
And,
uh,
they find a gingerbread house and you
know,
that's pretty good deal when you're a
little kid and you're lost and cold and
it's dark.
It's like,
it's such a good deal that you might be
a little suspicious of it because not
only is it a house,
which is right on,
but it's a house made out of cookies,
you know,
so,
and inside there's a woman who wants to
fatten up the kids and eat them.
And you know,
they eventually managed to fool her push
for in an,
and it's quite a bloodthirsty story,
like a lot of these fairy tales are,
but there's a really profound moral in
it.
And the,
and the profound moral is something like
beware of someone who does too much for
you because there's a devouring element
to that.
You know,
and this is why,
look,
most of the time when you hear people
talk about things like compassion and
empathy and you know,
on politeness and that sort of thing,
they're treated as if they're
untrammeled virtues.
And that's,
that's a mistake.
It's a mistake,
a grill.
This is a weird trait because there are
market advantages and disadvantages to
people all along the distribution.
So,
you know,
agree,
disagreeable people.
Um,
they're,
they're blunt.
So that would be the impolite element.
And there they don't shy away from
conflict.
And you might think,
well that doesn't sound very good,
but that's not right.
Lots of times,
especially if you're trying to solve
hard problems,
you want to have people around you who
are blunt and,
and somewhat afraid of conflict.
Because very frequently there isn't any
difference between thinking about
something and having conflict,
you know?
So if you're really committed to an idea
and I'm committed to an idea,
we're either going to act it out
mutually and actually engage in either
competition or direct,
you know,
combat roughly speaking or we're going
to hash it out so that we can exist
harmoniously as we move into the future.
And the problem with avoiding conflict
is that conflict's inevitable.
Like because sometimes a,
you don't know what to do and it's a
really complicated situation,
you know,
so you have one position on it.
Maybe your partner has another position.
Both positions are justifiable say with
regards to disciplining children cause
that's one or with finances,
those are common points of contradiction
between couples.
It's like it's not obvious who's right.
So how do you figure it out?
Well,
you either push each other around
physically or you push each other around
mentally,
which I think has made it even worse
over the long run.
Or you hit the problem straight on and
address it and then there's conflict.
But maybe if you're fortunate,
you get through the conflict and you
figure out the problem and then you can
have peace.
And so the de they downside to
agreeableness as far as I can tell,
is that it's over concerned with the
establishment of,
or the maintenance of peace in the
present and under concerned with the
establishment of peace in the future.
And I think that's what
conscientiousness does instead.
So my idea,
I have no idea if this is correct by the
way,
but,
so I'm,
I'm moving out towards the fringes of
knowledge on personality,
but I think one per what happened,
it's hard to get conscientiousness out
of animals.
You know,
like most things you can develop an
animal model for it,
right?
Conscientiousness,
that's a tough one.
We haven't been able to come up with a
reasonable animal model or
neuropsychological model.
Laura psychopharmacological model or a
theoretical model or a cognitive model
like the things we don't know about
consciousness.
Conscientiousness are are manifold,
but anyways,
I think what's happened is the degree of
illness is a good heuristic for
establishing harmonious egalitarianism
in very small groups.
So you know,
if you're in a family and you have
parents because generally if you're in a
family you do,
you know one of the concerns about the
parents is that resources are fairly
distributed.
You know,
in generally parents are loath to really
produce much of a dominance hierarchy in
terms of affection in relationship to
their children.
Right.
It seems kind of like a violation of the
parental contact contract.
So,
but then the question is what happens
when you enter into bigger organizations
where familial ties either can't be
maintained merely because of the size of
the organization or because the
organization is just too complex to be
run that way.
I think that's when conscientiousness
kicks in and conscientiousness is more
of a cold virtue.
It's not exactly based as far as we
could tell.
It's not based in any social emotion.
It's more like here are the articulated
rules whereby the social organization
functions,
I'm going to adhere to those and follow
them and that's what makes me
conscientious.
Now there's an order of the part and
that would be absence of rule breaking
and keeping things in their proper
position.
And then there's an industriousness
element,
which also seems to have something to do
with keeping social norms.
Like although there's an element of
going for the ideal instead of just not
breaking rules and industriousness,
conservative people are more
conscientious than liberal people and
that kind of makes sense,
right?
Because conscientiousness is concerned
with the maintenance of current social
rules and then playing the game
according to the rules.
Liberals are higher in openness and
lower in conscientiousness.
So they're more likely to transform the
rules,
which is something conservatives don't
relate because they're doing fine
playing the current gate,
you know?
And there's some real utility in
maintaining the current game because if
it's too unstable then well then you
have a descent into chaos and that's not
good for anybody.
Okay.
So,
so back to agreeableness now.
So the big difference men and women in
terms of traits seems to be,
so you could put,
first of all I should show you,
let's see if I got this here.
Yeah,
so there's two overlapping normal
distributions.
Okay.
And the blue ones are women and the red
ones are Nana.
And the blue is agreeableness.
Like the blue is shifted over to the
more agreeable side and the red is
shifted over to the less agreeable side.
The first thing that you should notice
about that isn't that the differences
exist.
The first thing that you should notice
is that almost all of the territory is
overlapped.
And so what that means is that if you
took men and women,
if you drew men and women randomly from
the population,
there'd be a deviation from 50 50 with
regards to who was the most agreeable
individual.
But at least,
no,
let's see if I can get this right.
I probably can't because I don't
remember exactly the effect size.
It's probably about 0.2 maybe it'd be
60% probability that you draw out a
woman who was as more agreeable and 40%
probability that you draw to man,
you know,
as a deviation from 50 50 so there's
lots of women who are more disagreeable
than men and there are lots of men who
are more agreeable than the typical
woman.
But there are differences.
And one of the things that's really
worth noting when you look at a normal
distribution,
because this is where things get weird.
So you could say there's not that much
difference on average between men and
women.
But the thing is the average is often
knock them relevant issue.
The relevant issue is often the extreme.
So for example,
if you're going to imprison people,
so look at that red curve.
What you see is that if you,
although it's not drawn exactly
perfectly,
but what you would see if the curve was
proper here
is that once you were out here,
say where the you could only,
you're only interested in the one out of
50 most disagreeable person,
all those people would be mad.
And that's why partly why almost
everybody in prison is male.
So the x,
because you don't put people in prison
unless they're very extreme.
And one of the things
criminals tend to be extreme in his,
they're low in agreeableness,
surprise,
surprise.
They're kind of callous.
They're in it for themselves.
You know,
they're stubborn,
they don't,
they don't care about you one way or
another.
And if they're low in agreeableness and
conscientiousness,
then they don't care about you and they
aren't going to play by the rules.
That started to touch on psychopathy.
So you can model psychopathy pretty well
with the big five,
low agreeableness,
low conscientiousness.
So then you get someone who could care
less about you,
who lies all the time or who doesn't
follow the rules,
won't work.
So they have a parasitical lifestyle,
which is actually one of the dimensions
of psychopathy,
a pair of civical lifestyle.
And uh,
yeah.
And then if you look over on the other
direction and you took the one in 50
person who was the most compassionate
then that be virtually all those people
would be women.
So,
oh I,
I've gone up,
there is probability is 63% so it's 63%
chance that the woman you drew wrote
would be more agreeable than 37% chance
that the men men would be.
So you can convert most effect size
statistics into odds ratios like that.
And I'll actually tell you about how to
do that later.
It's quite cool and it really gives you
a much bigger understanding of what an
effect means.
Like one of the things you won't be
taught about properly,
you don't likelihood when you take your
statistics,
although it might've changed,
is that they won't tell you how to
interpret the size of an effect.
And really the only thing that matters
is how big is the effect.
Right.
And that's,
that would be in most studies,
that would be
the size of the effect would be the
distance between one of those peaks in
the distance,
you know,
and the other.
That's how much the groups differ.
And then of course the group's
different,
but there's this spread up to the people
within the groups differ as well.
So the statistical calculation takes
into account how big the mean difference
is by well correcting for the,
for the spread of the numbers around
that meat.
And so and so you need well and you need
to know how big that effect is.
And you need to be able to understand
that in a way that's visualized.
So for example,
you might have a correlation Coefficient
of 0.2 so what you'd imagined,
imagine a graph like this and then a
bunch of dots and then align running
through them at 0.2.
There's a lot of dots that aren't on the
line because it's only accounting for
40% of the various right cause you
square it to get proportion of the
variance.
So 0.2,
there's some relationship that not much,
there's an awful lot of scattered.
So the two variables are related.
If you have an rf 0.2,
you can calculate an odds ratio.
It's,
it turns out to be 60,
40,
because the r is the difference between
the probability of one group,
Huh?
Probability of drawing.
Now a member of one group characterized
by that particular feature compared to
the member of the other group.
So you get a hat,
you've got to get,
have uh,
like a,
an ad hand way of,
of,
of understanding these effects sizes
because otherwise you can't understand
psychological papers.
Like what's a correlation of 0.1?
What's that good for?
What's a for you know,
what correlation point to a correlation
of 0.3.
And it's very,
very tricky because you're most of the
like there are people who've made sort
of tables of whether or not you should
consider an effect size,
large,
medium or small.
But it was basically a guests just like
the 0.05 level of significance was an
arbitrary,
somewhat arbitrary decision.
Now,
one of the things you'll find is that in
psychology,
you rarely see two variables that are
related to one another more than 0.3.
Okay?
You need to know that because if you
don't know that,
you have no idea what to make of a given
phenomenon.
So for,
and it's tricky.
So for example,
an optimized combination of Iq and
conscientiousness and predict your job
performance at somewhere between 0.5 and
0.6 so now if you square that,
that's 25 to 36% of the variants and you
think,
well that's not very much,
it's only a quarter of the variance in
job performance,
but it's hard to measure job
performance.
So there's lots of error in it and
there's error in the measurement of
conscientiousness.
So some of that's just noise,
but,
but importantly,
even if it's 25% of the variance,
so we said a correlation of 0.5 then you
could use it to raise the probability
that you'd pick up an above average
employee from 50 50 to 75 25 cause 75
minus 25.5 so it's a big effect.
And then the economic consequences of
that are Nassif because it turns out,
you know,
if you're a very good at what you do and
you're not very good at it,
I might say,
well how much more is it to my advantage
to employ you rather than you?
And one of the questions would be,
well,
how much difference in performance is
there between people?
Like if everyone lines up like maybe
it's a assembly line job and once you
get it,
once you're trained,
everyone has exactly the same rate of
production.
Well then it doesn't matter if you're,
you know,
if you have a higher Iq and you're more
conscientious because there's no
variability in the performance.
But in lots of jobs there's massive
variability.
It might even be nonlinear.
And we'll talk about that when we get to
our discussion of the prieto
distribution.
So what that means is that some people
are not only not productive in their
job,
they're negatively productive in a big
way.
You hire them and they take money out of
the company.
So this often happens.
For example,
if you hiring competent managers,
because not only are they not doing
their job,
they're stopping 20 other people from
doing their job.
Well they're,
you know,
eating resources like mad doing that.
So it can be,
it's a re can be a real catastrophe.
So bad hire,
if someone's making $100,000 a year,
a bad hire costs the company about
$350,000.
So you didn't need many of those before,
especially if you're a small company
before you're just done.
So,
and the,
the distribution between people in terms
of performance varies with job.
But with some jobs it's tremendous.
Like in sales,
you know,
so in sales you really see us prieto
distribution where almost everyone is
making no sales and then there's a few
people at the end of the distribution
who are doing all of it.
So,
and you know,
there's lots of jobs that are like that.
They're not normally diff production
isn't normally distributed.
So,
all right.
So anyways,
back to
aggression or agreeableness here.
So most of the time,
most of the time what you'll see in
psychology is that the statistical
assumption that's made in a paper when
they're comparing two,
you know is one group significantly
different than the other.
The statistics are predicated on the
assumption that the distribution of
those scores is normal.
And what you'll hear a psychologist
telling you is this central limit
Theorem,
which is this theorem says that if a
random variable x is the sum of a large
number of small and independent random
variables than almost no matter how the
small variables are distributed,
x will approximately be normally
distributed.
While you think if you take human traits
like,
like let's say intelligence for that
matter,
God only knows how many genetic random
genetic factors that could have been one
way or another have to sum up to cause,
you know,
to produce the influenced the
intellectual capacity of one person and
then to produce that amount of
variation.
It's a lot of random things.
And so what happens is it comes out
basically normally distributed,
so,
but some things aren't randomly
distributed and production seems to be
one of them.
And success seems to be another,
which is why,
you know,
1% of the people have 50% of the money.
Because what happens is,
well,
if you're smart and you work hard,
then you multiply how smart you are,
right?
But then it starts to accrue to you.
You know?
So if you have $100,000 in the bank and
it's making say 5% a year,
you make quite a bit of money just
because you already have the money.
So having the money puts you in the game
like it does if you're in the real
estate market.
And once you start to become successful
at something,
well then people expect you to be
successful and they open up more doors
to you and your,
your network of influence wines.
And so you have more opportunities and
then people come to you.
And so what happens is that as you start
to become successful,
the probability that you're going to
become increasingly successful
increases.
And so you can get into an exponential
rate of return,
which is exactly what you want to have
happen.
If you start a startup,
right?
You don't want linear growth,
you'll just die.
You want it to go viral and most things
don't.
But the things that do are super
successful and people go viral during
their lifetime,
especially if they're engaged in some
kind of creative in,
in some sort of creative enterprise.
And making money actually turns out to
be from the entrepreneurial perspective
anyways,
essentially a creative enterprise.
It's not that surprising.
Now,
one of the things that no one will
probably ever show you is why things are
normally distributed and what exactly
that means.
And so I'm going to show you something.
Um,
maybe I even have a,
I might even have saved video of it,
which would be smart and,
but unlikely.
Sorry,
I should have had this,
but I forgot.
I forgot about it till now.
So,
well we'll just look on youtube,
but that should do the trick.
Um,
gold,
that's a good one.
It's called,
I want you to do is you take a ball,
you drop it into the tall and it bounces
off all these nails before it makes,
going into one of these categories.
And when the ball hits is,
isn't it?
This is it go from bullet,
uh,
because the first person to meet one of
these,
and so it was cold Galton I want you to
do is you take a ball,
you drop it into the top and it balances
off all these nails before basically
going into one of these categories.
Uh,
and when the ball hits each night,
in theory there is a 50,
50 chance of it going left or right.
And so each path is pretty much
unpredictable.
If I was to take two balls and put them
in,
if I'm trying to get the exactly the
same,
they will end up in completely different
positions.
We cannot accurately predict where any
given board more go.
However,
we can make a few statements,
we can say that or is more likely to end
up then in the middle,
then the age,
because of they said two categories.
There are lots of different paths.
It ended up here.
There are only a few tasks to end up on
the edge.
So we can do is take this piece of
scientific equipment
and stop putting an easy it by the
handful.
Yeah,
if we put it absolutely loads of biggest
balls,
even though each individual,
while we could accurately predict where
it's going the way we can accurately for
date,
the overall package
I met pat and we ended up with is called
a normal distribution in fact to a
funeral.
Okay.
So now imagine when you're looking at
mean differences between groups.
That's in some sense analogous to asking
if all the have fallen
into a pattern because there's one entry
point or two,
right.
And you might say,
well,
what's the difference between one and
two?
Because maybe one entry point is here in
one entry point is here,
is that the same?
Or maybe they're here,
you know,
so there's a continuum of same and
different and you can calculate the
probability that one normal just that
had a distribution is a single
distribution from a single point,
which would be,
there's no mean differences or that it's
from two different points,
which would be a mean difference between
the groups.
So you get a curve like this and a curve
like this and then you can do a
statistical calculation that would tell
you what the probability of that shape
emerging merely from chance would be at.
What we've picked in psychology and many
sciences is this.
If there's less than a one in 20 chance
that the shape of the distribution is by
chance,
then you can infer that there's a
significant difference between the two
groups because you could have a pattern
like that emerge in this experiment.
Just out of chance.
In fact,
with if you see the one that's on the
board there right now,
you see there's two peaks in it.
You might say,
well,
those are the peaks of two different
populations.
It's very unlikely.
Now how you calculate whether the
difference between those two peaks is
significant.
From a statistical perspective,
it's partly based on chance,
right?
It's just,
okay.
It's just the probability that that
distribution would,
would manifest itself spontaneously.
But it's also affected by how many balls
you dropped down.
And the reason for that is that if you
only drop down one ball,
do you have a normal distribution?
Well,
maybe,
but you can't tell because there's only
one ball and maybe you drop 10 down and
while you're going to get something that
maybe is patchy and maybe has one or two
places where there's two bowls stack,
but it's still not much of a normal
distribution.
But if you draw up 150,000 of them down
here,
it's going to be virtually perfect.
And so basically what happens is that
the statistics in for are based on the
presupposition that the more subjects
you have in the experiment,
the better the shape of the normal
distribution,
which would be the tighter the
approximation of the sample to the
underlying population,
to the actual population.
And the less difference you have to have
between the groups in terms of magnitude
for that to not be a consequence of
chance.
Okay.
So you need to know three things when
you're interpreting the straightforward
statistics that have to do with group
differences.
In psychology experiments,
you need to know number one,
okay,
how big the sample is because the bigger
the sample,
the smaller effect will be significant.
You need to know how significant the
effect is.
That's the probability and you need to
know a big,
the effect is that's the effect size.
And you can't know one of those things
without doing all three of them.
So when you're interpreting and
experiment,
you always need to know effect,
size,
the probability that that effects sizes
due to chance and how many subjects
there are in the experiment.
Okay.
Because those things are related and you
can't interpret one of them in the
absence of the other.
Okay.
So
and all I'll show you I'm not,
I should show you this prieto just
right.
Maybe I can find this.
I might as well show it to you now.
Creedal distribution,
what's it called?
Animation.
Maybe it'll show up.
That would be lovely.
Well,
let's see.
I haven't looked at this one,
but statistics,
the general distribution is a family of
continuous probability distributions.
It is often use to model the towns of
another distribution.
It is specified when three parameters,
location,
scale,
and shape.
No,
I'm city specified.
Plan the scale and nothing like an audio
or only video.
Okay,
let's cycle physics.
Animation.
Yeah,
I can't find it.
So I'll just tell you about it.
Did he step?
It'll work.
All right,
so you're playing monopoly.
Okay.
Monopoly is an interesting game to some
degree,
but one of the rules in monopoly is that
there's a finite number of properties
and a finite amount of money.
Okay?
So it's,
it's an that's an important feature
because what that means is that there's
going to be winners and losers if you
played the game long enough.
Okay?
That's what it absolutely entails.
Now,
you know,
economists argue about whether or not
the economy is a zero sum game where
there has to be winners and losers or
whether it's more infinite game because
the amount of money continually
increases,
right?
So you know,
if the amount of money you continually
increases,
it's not obvious that anybody has to be
poor.
Okay?
So here's what happens in monopoly.
So first of all,
you all started out with the same amount
of money,
right?
So that's fair.
Okay.
And then what do you do?
You shake the dice and he make some
decisions.
And so it's not a bad model for life.
The dice shaking is the random element.
And you know,
what happens to you in your life is
going to be a reasonable chunk of
random,
you know?
I mean,
because you can be struck by illnesses
or a family member can,
you know,
there's arbitrary things that are going
to happen to you.
You need to know that because you have
to think when something bad happens to
you about whether or not that was just
random or whether you it and you know,
it's kind of horrible to think that it's
random because then you can't control
it.
But on the other hand,
it also means that sometimes when you
fall down,
it's actually not your fault.
It just happened.
And so you need to know that randomness
has a fair,
like it's,
it's a nontrivial contribution to
people's life course.
Okay.
So the dice represent the randomness now
and then you make decisions about what
you're going to do with your
opportunities.
And you know,
I think if you took 20 pete
and they had different levels of
experience and expertise with monopoly,
my suspicions are is that there are
better players and that they would win
more often if you play them across time.
That it's not purely a random game,
although maybe it is.
So anyways,
what happens is you basically start
trading,
right?
You trade with the bank,
you trade with the board and you trade
with other players.
And so,
and you do that randomly.
And what happens is that with each trade
someone gains a bit more and someone
loses a bit more.
But something always happens,
which is as you gain more,
your options increase.
And as you lose more,
your options decrease,
right?
So by the time you're down to $1,000 and
three properties and it's three quarters
of the way through the game,
you know you're in a whole,
your heart [inaudible] it's very
unlikely that you're going to climb out
of it because one little negative event
we'll take you out of the gate.
Now you know there's some trivial
probability that you'll get back into
it,
but everyone knows that sinking feeling
that occurs when you,
you're just more or less baggage on the
game,
you know.
But what happens to the other people is
that one of them starts to pull out way
ahead and what happens as you continue
to run the game,
we'll say for the,
for the moment merely as a consequence
of chance,
someone will end up with all the money
in all the properties now.
Like the importance of that can't be
overstated.
That's a non [inaudible] that's a non
normal distribution.
And although you won't hear about this
in psychology ever,
I didn't understand this until like five
years ago,
which is absolutely pathetic.
Maybe it's 10 years ago now.
But because I was under the assumption
that almost everything that
psychologists studied that was important
was normally distributed.
That's wrong.
Lots of things are distributed in a
prieto distribution.
And that's,
I think what happens is that you get
feedback loops developing,
you know,
as you fall,
the probability that you're going to
fall increases because you're not as
resilient and because things can take
you out faster.
And so you know,
you start to get poor,
well then you don't eat quite as well.
You're rushed off your feet more,
so you're sick more often,
then your income falls,
then you have to,
you're either under severe financial
stress or you have to move to a poor
neighborhood.
And then if you move to a poor
neighborhood,
the people around you aren't
characterized by as many opportunities,
you know?
And maybe it's rougher and so that makes
you more depressed and you can just see
it's this and then,
but on the other hand,
if you're starting to climb up,
you get exactly the opposite phenomena,
which is you start putting away some
money so you're more resilient to,
you know,
random economical occurrences.
And as you'd become,
well for this argument,
we'll just use wealth.
As you become wealthier,
you know,
you move into better and better
neighborhoods and then the people around
you have more and more opportunities to
distribute and you can go like that and
that's what happens to people.
So,
but most people end up stacked down
near the barely clinging to the edge of
the world and of the prieto
distribution.
You know,
when a huge part of our economic and
political discourse is really what to do
about that.
Like there's maybe two arguments.
One is,
should there be a burrito distribution
at all?
Shouldn't just be normally distributed,
which is kind of what a middle class
society would look like,
right?
Most people have the average amount of
money.
There's some people who are maybe three
or four standard deviations above the
mean and there's some poor people and
you just can't flatten it out more than
that because you'd end up with tyranny.
You know?
Cause if you push a system,
you can push a system to do anything you
want it to do.
But as you deformant warp it,
it takes more and more forced to
regulated.
Now the distribution of money isn't even
close to a normal distribution.
In fact,
if you take the top 1% of people who
have the money and you look at that
distribution,
it's a wild pareto distribution.
And if you take the top 0.1% and you
look at that distribution,
it's a wild pareto distribution.
And so like it's 1% of the 1% who own
half of what the 1% will,
you know?
So it just doesn't end until you get to
the richest person in the world,
you know?
And then they own something like
the richest person in the world probably
has $100 billion.
That would be my guess.
It might be potent.
So,
but $100 billion is a lot of money.
It's a very large amount of money and so
he's like 50 standard deviations above
the mean way where it's not even
imaginable.
Now you might say,
should it be normally distributed and
sort of the ideal ideal democratic
socialist society in some sense.
Then you might say,
well,
perhaps not because maybe you want an
undue proportion of the rewards to go to
people who are unduly productive.
Now you know,
you think you have a huge advantage,
for example,
to be born into money,
but it actually turns out that in the
United States anyways,
if you had to choose between being born
at the 95th percentile for wealth or the
95th percentile for intelligence,
you'd be better off at the age of 40 if
you were born at the 95th percentile for
education or for intelligence.
So wealth matters,
but it doesn't matter as much or
hereditary wealth matters.
But it doesn't matter as much as people
think it matters.
But that's partly because you actually
can get ahead in a functional society if
you're smart and hardworking.
You know,
if you're in a corrupt society and work
just makes you into a sheep to be
fleeced,
well then it's obviously better.
Dude born rich.
And so I would say the advantage to be
booked to being born is proportional to
the amount of corruption in the society.
If it's a corrupt society,
it's your only hope.
If it isn't,
it might not even necessarily be all
that good for,
you know,
um,
what's his name?
The best investor in the world,
the richest investor in the world,
whose name his name escapes me.
What's that?
Perfect.
Yeah.
He's not leaving very much money to his
kids.
Like it would be a lot by our standards,
but by his standards,
it's like,
you know,
the pennies in the bottom of this is
ashtray in his car.
So,
and the reason he doesn't want to leave
them a lot of money is because he
actually thinks it deprives them of
necessity.
And depriving someone of necessity is
not really a very good thing because you
know,
partly the reason you're motivated isn't
only because you want some good things
to happen.
It might also be because you know,
we,
you better watch out and get your life
together or you'll get cut off at the
knees and you know,
if you're too protective then that all
goes away.
And so it isn't necessarily obvious that
that's for the best.
So,
so then you might think,
well,
we should have a modified prieto
distribution because that'll enable
people who are hyper productive to be
rewarded for it.
But more importantly,
if you don't have a prieto distribution
in your society,
there aren't individuals who amass large
pools of capital.
And then it's very difficult for there
to be investment taking place because
some things are really expensive.
So for example,
if you want to build a fabrication plant
to make computer chips,
you need about $4 billion.
And it isn't really all that useful.
It seems to me that it wouldn't be all
that useful if the only institution who
ever had that much money was the
government.
Because that would mean that the
government would have to be the lead
investor in everything.
And that's just not tenable.
You know,
you're going to replace all the venture
capitalists with government agents,
you know,
government workers,
that's not going to work.
So you do want there to be fairly large
pools of capital and you can also make a
case that you don't want all the power
centralized.
And so if you take wealth away from
people,
I mean high levels of wealth,
what happens is again,
you start to centralize power in the
government because it's the only
institution that's large enough to wield
a lot of clout.
You know,
when they say in the u s that most
billionaires now are self made and so
then you might think,
well if someone is capable parceling out
the crux,
there's always going to be crooks.
If someone is capable of generating $1
billion by the time they're 40 it's
conceivable that that's the sort of
person you want to have that much money
because obviously they know what to do
with it,
right?
I mean it's easy to waste money.
You can do that.
I mean I've seen people blow through $3
million in two years with no problem.
Like you can,
you can distribute money if you're not
careful,
like like snow melting in your hands.
It's hard to keep it,
it's hard to use it.
It's hard to invest it properly.
And it's certainly possible that you
want fairly large pools of capital
distributed in the society.
So
there are multiple points of power,
so,
but you could still argue about exactly
what sort of premium distribution you'd
want.
And there's some good demonstrations in
the,
in the u s okay,
I can show you that too.
That's a good one.
Okay.
There's a chart.
I saw it recently.
I can't get out of a Harvard business
professor and economist ask more than
5,000 Americans how they thought wealth
is distributed in the United States.
This is what they said.
They thought it was dividing the country
into five rep groups at the top,
bottom and middle,
three 20% groups.
They ask people how they thought the
wealth in this country was divided.
Then he asked them what they thought was
the ideal distribution and 92% that's at
least nine out of 10 of them said it
should be more like this.
In other words,
more equitable than they think it is.
Now,
that fact is telling,
admittedly the notion that most
Americans know that the system is
already skewed unfairly,
but what's most interesting to me is the
reality compared to our perception.
The ideal is as far removed from our
perception of reality as the actual
distribution is from what we think
exists in this country.
So ignore the ideal for a moment.
Here's what we think it is.
Again,
and here is the actual distribution.
Shockingly skewed,
not only do the bottom 20% and the next
20% the bottom 40% of Americans barely
have any of the wealth.
I mean,
it's hard to even see them on the chart,
but the top 1% has more of the country's
wealth.
Then nine out of 10 Americans believed
the entire top 20% should have
mindblowing,
but let's look at it another way because
I find this chart kind of difficult to
wrap my head around.
Instead.
Let's reduce the 311 million Americans
too,
just to representative 100 people.
Make it simple.
Here they are,
teachers,
coaches,
firefighters,
construction workers,
engineers,
doctors,
lawyers,
some investment bankers,
a CEO,
maybe a celebrity,
or now let's line them up according to
their wealth course,
people on the left wealthiest on the
right,
just a steady row.
Folks based on their net worth.
So that's other complicated before based
on which 20% quintile they fall into.
Now let's reduce the total wealth of the
United States,
which was roughly $54 trillion in 2009
to this symbolic pile of cash and let's
distribute it among our 100 Americans.
Well,
here's socialism.
All the wealth of the country
distributed equally.
We all know that won't work.
We need to encourage people to work and
work hard to achieve that good American
dream.
Keep our country moving forward.
So here's that ideal.
We asked everyone about something like
this curve.
This isn't too bad.
We've got some incentive as the
wealthiest folks are now about 10 to 20
times better off than the poorest
Americans,
but hey,
even the poor folks aren't actually
poor.
Since the poverty line stayed almost
entirely off the chart.
We have a super healthy middleclass of a
smooth transition into wealth and yes,
Republicans and Democrats alive chose
this curve.
Nine out of 10 people,
92% said this was a nice ideal
distribution of America's wealth,
but let's move on.
This is what people think America's
wealth distribution actually looks like
that was equitable clearly,
but for me,
even this still looks pretty great.
Yes,
the poorest 20 to 30% are starting to
separate quite a lot compared to the
ideal in the middle class is certainly
struggling more than they were while the
rich and wealthy or making roughly a
hundred times that of the chorus
Americans in about 10 times that of the
still healthy middle class.
Sadly,
this isn't even close to the reality.
Here is the actual distribution of
wealth in America.
The poorest of Americans don't even
register.
They're down to pocket change and the
middle class is barely distinguishable
from the poor.
In fact,
even the rich between the top 10 and 20
percentile are worse off only the top
10% or better off.
And how much better on so much better
off at the top.
Two to 5% are actually off the chart at
this scale and the top 1% this guy,
well,
his stack of money stretches 10 times
higher than we can show.
Here's his stack of catch restaffed all
by itself.
This is the top 1% we've been hearing so
much about so much green in his pockets
that I have to give him a whole new
column of his own because he won't fit
on my chart.
1% of America has 40% of all the
nations.
Well,
the bottom 8% eight out of every 10
people or 80 out of these hundred only
has 7% between them,
and this has only gotten worse in the
last 20 to 30 years.
While the richest 1% take home almost a
quarter of the national income today in
1976 they took home only 9% meaning
their share of income is nearly tripled
in the last 30 years.
The top 1% half the country stocks,
bonds and mutual funds,
the bottom 50% of Americans and only
half a percent of these investments,
which means they aren't investing,
they're just scraping by.
And I'm sure many of these wealthy
people have worked very hard in,
but do you really believe that the CEO
is working 380 times harder?
It is average employee and if not as
lowest paid employee.
See that's the one error I think that's
in this video,
how hard you work is irrelevant in terms
of how much money are almost irrelevant
in terms of how much money you generate,
right?
Because obviously the people who work
really hard,
I mean who works hard,
those guys that are digging holes out in
the road in the winter there,
they're working hard,
right?
But
you're not rewarded for the physical
effort that you put in or rarely there's
some association,
but not very much.
And so it isn't whether or not the CEO
works 380 times harder.
It's whether or not their productivity
can be leveraged enough to justify that
level of,
uh huh
compensation.
Now you can make arguments on both sides
of that and it depends a lot on the
industry and on the individual and all
of those things,
but you don't want to,
you don't want to reduce this argument
to one of hard work.
It's not appropriate.
It's too unsophisticated,
but the average,
the average worker needs to work more
than a month to earn with the CEO makes
him one hour.
We certainly don't have to go all the
way to socialism to find somebody that
is fair for hardworking Americans.
We don't even have to achieve what most
of us consider might be ideal.
All we need to do is wake up and realize
that the reality in this country is not
at all what we think it is.
Okay,
so there,
there's a two minute explanation for
trump and sanders.
Really,
I'm dead serious about that.
You know,
because the right wing working class
right wing,
they think they'd been absolutely
screwed over and they have,
and then you know,
the left thinks,
well there's way too much power
concentrated at the top and the
distribution would be the answer.
The problem is is that,
and this is the real problem,
it's not that he's figured out how to
distribute the money.
Like first of all,
there's a natural proclivity.
You might say,
you can map model it with laws of
physics.
There's a natural proclivity of money to
rate rank itself out like that.
And so that happens in every culture.
Now you,
maybe you can modify the steepness,
but it's not easy to figure out how,
you know when there's a bunch of
problems,
because there's a bunch of problems that
are associated with the more dim witted
solutions.
For example,
lots of people think that poverty is
caused by lack of money.
And that's really not a very
sophisticated theory because there's
lots of things that cause poverty.
Low Iq causes poverty.
And I'm not saying that all poor people
have low Iq,
because that would be stupid.
But obviously if you have an Iq of 80
and you can barely read,
the probability that you're going to end
up poor is pretty damn hot,
right?
So,
so you've got,
and you know it's about 10% of the
population who has an Iq less than 80
that's a lot of people.
And so they're not literate.
So if you think about what they can do,
they can't run computers,
generally speaking.
Okay,
well then there's people who are ill,
you know,
there's a lot of them.
Then there's people who are alone,
and that's a big problem because they're
one step away from disaster,
right?
If you're alone,
then there's people who have alcohol and
drug problems and people was screwed up
families.
And you know,
you can go on and on to add up the
reasons that people fall off the edge of
the world and money won't scratch the
surface for many of those problems.
For addiction,
for example.
Now maybe spending on programs that
would remediate addiction would be
useful.
But if you're an addict and you get
money,
that's not a good thing because all that
means is that you're going to just rent
out the addiction until you run out of
money.
And so you've got to have a more
sophisticated idea of what constitutes
poverty before you can properly address
it.
And then you also have to take into
account that a lot of what's driving
people crazy say in places like the u s
isn't the fact that there's absolute
poverty,
cause there's abs actually not that much
absolute poverty in the u s so if you
take the bottom 5% of the US population
by world standards,
they're doing just fine.
So,
but by American standards,
they're doing terribly.
And so you have the relative poverty
problem and relative prob poverty drives
aggression.
And so that's something that's really
worth knowing and this is something that
the conservatives just haven't seemed to
figure out as far as I can tell because
the conservatives might say,
well,
you should let the money pile up on the
right hand side because you know the
system is fair and smart people deserve
to be rewarded and so on and so forth.
The problem is is that as that curve
increases in height,
the probability that the surrounding
society is going to become violent
starts to ratchet up tremendously.
And you see this in places like Central
America where if you have money,
you have to live in a bubble because if
you don't,
people will kidnap you.
And so then you might think,
well if you have $1 billion but you
can't go outside except in a helicopter
with armed guards,
how rich are you really?
You know,
in in,
in a place like Canada,
like in Montreal or Toronto.
There's good examples is the city is so
damn safe that you don't have to live in
your house.
You can live in the city and that's a
massive economic like that should be
calculated as part of your net worth.
And that's a consequence of reasonable
public programs.
And the fact that you know,
the distribution of income in Canada
hasn't gotten to the point where things
are destabilizing.
And so conservatives should be watching
out for that incredible
disproportionality of income as much as
anyone else if one of their prime
concerns is to maintain social
stability.
So,
but the problem,
the problem that we haven't been able to
solve as a culture from an economic
perspective is how to distribute money
down the prieto distribution in a way
that actually works.
It's way harder than you think.
You know.
So for example,
if you set up large social social
services institutions,
governmental institutions,
or charities even for that matter,
the problem is,
is that the,
the uh,
the,
what would you call it,
the baseline cost of the organizations
is so damn high that hardly any of the
money ever gets to the people that it's
supposed to be helping.
I mean that's really the case with
foreign aid in places like Africa where
the poor people virtually never did any
money.
You know,
so
you know,
so you think a corporation spends about
95% of its time just ensuring that it
survived,
but it uses that much resources just to
keep running.
You set up a charity or you know,
a social welfare institution,
you get the same problem.
All the money is eaten up by the people
who are running the institution.
And I'm not being cynical about that.
They have to live,
you know,
it's,
it's really expensive to hire someone.
You know,
if you want someone qualified,
if you pay them $50,000 that basically
costs you 100,000 because you have to
give them an office and it has to have
light and heat and all of that.
So you know,
10 employees,
it's 1 million bucks already.
And so if you're fundraising as a
charity to just get past the point where
you're surviving is almost impossible.
And then there's little logistical
difficulties of actually distributing
the money.
How the hell do you do that?
It's not easy.
Finland is instituted a guaranteed
minimum wage,
minimum salary per month.
They,
you know,
and they're experimenting with that,
but it's a small country and it's
relatively homogenous.
It's more like a big city or a moderate
size city actually.
So you could think that the logistics
would be a lot more straight forward.
But anyways.
Okay.
Well,
so that's actually a preview to some
degree of what we're going to talk about
when we get to conscientiousness.
But you do need to know these things
statistically and you have to,
you have to,
uh,
you know,
you have to understand what the
statistics are representing.
Okay.
So people,
I mentioned that there are gender
differences in,
in personality and you know,
that's a very controversial claim,
weirdly enough.
Um,
it's something that's always rather
shocked me that it is controversial.
Um,
this is from the Gender Equity Resource
Center at Berkeley.
Gender is a socially constructed system
of classification that describes
qualities of masculinity and femininity
to people.
Gender characteristics can change over
time and are different between cultures.
Well,
the amount,
the number of things that are wrong with
those two sentences is almost,
it would take about three hours to
actually point them out.
I mean,
first of all,
the fact that gender characteristics can
change over time and are different
between cultures in no way implies that
those things are socially constructed.
It implies they partly socially
constructed at best.
But it also,
it also indicates that some of the
reasons that things might change over
time and are different between cultures
could be biological.
Like there's no,
there's no saying anything.
There's no a priori demonstration that
that's impossible.
It's not impossible.
And gender is a socially constructed
system of classification.
Well actually no,
that isn't what the dad does seem to
indicate.
And so the best out of that,
I know on that or the Scandinavian
studies one personality and what we'll
take a look at them.
Nope.
Oh,
this is a good one.
So this is interactions with reach
rhesus monkeys in toys.
We compared the interactions of 34
rhesus monkeys living within 135 monkey
troop with human wheeled toys and plush
toys.
Male monkeys,
like boys showed consistent and strong
preferences for wheel toys while female
monkeys,
like girls showed the fit greater
variability and preferences.
That's the magnitude of preference for
wheeled over.
Plush toys differed significantly
between males and females.
As similarities to human findings
demonstrate such preferences can develop
without explicit gender socialization.
So exposure to prenatal life events,
stress is associated with masculinized
play behavior and girls.
So,
and that was,
uh,
an analysis of in utero exposure to
hormones.
Because one thing that seems to happen,
this is,
you know,
this is one of the many things that
contribute to the differences between
males and females is that the basic
human body phenotype is feminine.
So if you have x,
y chromosomes or xx chromosomes,
and you're not exposed to testosterone
in Utero,
you'll come out with a female
physiology.
So what happens is that in utero that
the,
the male embryo is masculinized by
testosterone,
no testosterone.
There's also testosterone production for
women,
you know,
but there's more for the male babies.
And there's some evidence that suggests
that the more testosterone that a fetus
is exposed to in Utero,
the more masculinized their cognitive
styles and toy preferences and behaviors
are.
But it's also the case for females.
Like if the more they're exposed to
testosterone in Utero,
the more that's also the case.
And that's what this particular study
showed.
So
this is,
yes,
this is Simon Baron Cohen's work he did
the work with,
with uh,
with,
with fetal development and he showed
that,
um,
fetal testosterone is inversely
correlated with social behaviors such as
eye contact and infancy,
peer relations and preschoolers and
mentalistic interpretations of animate
motion,
male fetuses are exposed to higher
levels of testosterone and then our
female fetuses.
So his theory actually is that autism is
the extreme end of masculinized
cognitive development because it's all
female oriented,
no peep people orientation at all.
And then the,
the opposite end of the distribution,
he's associated with predisposition to
psychosis.
Although I that I find that part of the
theory weaker.
Um,
but you know,
it's,
who knows,
it's certainly a possibility.
So yeah,
and I contact is one of the things
that's really lacking in people who are
autistic.
And you know,
he had an awful lot of social
information from observing the face and
you have specialized circuits for
pulling in emotional information from
face observation.
So,
so
yeah,
UN indices of gender equality and
economic development are associated with
larger gender differences in
agreeableness,
but not an extroversion or neuroticism.
So what's happened in the Scandinavian
countries?
So imagine that any given trade is a
combination of environmental variables
and genetic biological variables.
Okay.
Now you tend to think of those things as
isolated,
but they're not weirdly enough,
the relationship between biological
determination and cultural determination
is determined by the culture,
which is a very strange thing.
So what I mean by that is that
if you are two years old and I threw you
in a box and did nothing but beat you
everyday for 10 years,
the probability that you would come out
agreeable is very low.
Right?
So,
and the,
the point I'm making is that you can
take an individual and if you put them
in a radical enough environment,
you can pretty much shift them where
you're,
where you're going to shift.
Now the harder you want to shift them,
the more force it's going to take.
So,
you know,
like if you took a really agreeable
person,
you'd have to be pretty malevolent to
set up the circumstances that would
really make them self centered in
predatory.
But I suspect you could do it.
So what happens in the Scandinavian
countries is that there's been a lot of
attempt to,
to flatten out the contribution of the
society on gender differences.
And so all that's happened is that the
biological differences have maximized.
See,
because what you're really looking for
is his contribution for society to have
a contribution.
There has to be different treatment for
men and women because otherwise this
society has no effect on the differences
between men and women obviously.
And then there's nothing left.
But biological differences now there
could be no biological differences.
You know,
that's one possibility in the strict
social constructionists would predict
that.
In fact,
they still teach that universities all
the time and which,
which I truly believe is appalling.
I think the data is already in on that.
And um,
there are consequences of this too,
so that it's still the differences
between men and women to say with
regards to agreeableness still aren't
that baby even in the Scandinavian
countries.
But there are a lot more consistent and
larger there than they are in any other
societies that have been studied.
So that's pretty weird.
And these are big samples.
These are samples of tens of thousands
of people.
They're not trivial studies.
This is a cool one because it,
it,
it turns out,
you know,
there were a lot of reasons,
there were a lot of,
there has been a lot of discussion about
why the gender segregate in terms of
occupation and you know,
some,
sometimes that's,
that's,
that's taken the form of an Iq argument.
So probably,
I don't know if you guys remember this
because maybe it's too long ago,
but this president of Harvard University
whose name was Larry Summers,
he also served in whose cabinet I don't
remember at the moment.
It's probably Obama's,
but I'm afraid.
I don't remember.
Anyways,
Larry Summers is very high powerful
person in the United States and he was,
he was giving a talk at Harvard at one
point and he was when the Americans
started to get concerned about science,
technology,
engineering and mathematics,
the stem subjects say,
because they're kind of thinking we need
more people in the stem subjects in
order to kickstart the economy,
which may or may not be true.
But anyways,
that was the idea.
And one of the problems that was being
dealt with was the relative dearth of
women in the stem disciplines.
And Summers made reference to a body of
research that suggested that.
So there's take that normal distribution
there.
Okay,
you see that one on the screen.
Now imagine you search,
you put another one right on top of
that,
but you flattened it so you just pushed
it down right in the middle.
And so what would happen is it's a
little lower in the middle,
but it goes out a little farther on the
sides.
And so then what happens,
which is analogous to what I told you
happened with agreeableness,
is that if you go out four standard
deviations above me,
so let's say to the 99 what is it?
85 95 99 to the 99.9 percentile.
So one person in a thousand,
assume one person in a thousand becomes
a genius level is capable of genius
level accomplishment in the stem areas.
Okay?
So it's one,
maybe it's more than that,
but let's say one in a thousand,
you're going to get a pretty decent
person at that rate.
They're all going to be men if the male
curve is flatter.
But if you go down the other side of the
distribution and you look for the person
who's one in a thousand most,
um,
intellectually impaired,
they're also going to be men.
And so that idea was that the mean
levels of Iq between men and women are
the same,
but the standard deviation is different.
And the underlying biological
justification for that,
roughly speaking,
is there often is more variability in
male behavior across animal species
because males are actually more
expendable than females.
And so,
and there's a much,
there's a differential reproduction rate
among males that's high enough.
So that half of your,
you have twice as many female ancestors
as male ancestors.
Now you think,
well that's impossible,
but it's not.
If the average woman had one child,
sorry,
if the average,
yeah,
the average woman had one child
throughout history and the average man,
man,
man who had children had to then that's
what you get.
But what it would mean is that there's
an equal number.
Men would have had zero.
And the distribution for men in
fathering is a lot more like that.
It's a pretty high probability that a
woman will have at least one child where
it's a relatively high probability that
a man won't.
And so that's all you need.
And so given that that difference in
reproductive value,
in some sense,
it's not like the men don't have
reproductive value,
it's that the reproductive value can be
fulfilled by a relatively small number
of men.
So men aren't the limiting factor in
reproduction.
Women are,
and so not to cross species.
And so what happens is the male seem to
get more variable in their,
in their behavioral display because
there's more advantage to winning and
not.
And once you lose it doesn't matter how
much you lose by in some sense.
So anyways,
he got harassed to death for that.
I think they actually,
I don't remember what happened to them,
but I think he had to stop being
president of Harvard University.
But he didn't even say that that was
true.
He just said that it was one of the
possibilities.
But,
and you know,
there is debate about that.
There's no debate richly,
no debate about the average Iq.
There is some debate about the standard
deviations and I think the strongest
evidence is sort of enlightening in line
with the testosterone.
The fetal testosterone exposure is that
men have a small edge and spatial
reasoning and that's the main mental
rotation for example,
and that seems to be associated with
higher levels of fetal testosterone.
Now you do also see sometimes that women
have a small engine,
verbal and verbal intelligence and
verbal fluency,
but that might be more associated with
trait openness because trade openness,
the open,
the creative activity part of treadle
Vanessa is higher among women than it is
about men,
but regardless of all that,
what really seems to make the difference
with regards to the way that the sexes
distribute themselves in the in the
career landscape is interest and the
biggest differences between men and
women that are normally recorded are
recorded in terms of interest and the
basic distribution seems to be people
versus things which is quite cool
because that was derived as an
independent dimension before Simon Baron
Cohen started to do is work on fetal
testosterone exposure and those things
just happened to map on to each other
like his empathizing versus
systematizing is a lot light people
versus things and it also looks a lot
like agreeableness and in fact I have a
student,
we checked that out.
We took Simon Baron Cohen's
questionnaire and mapped it onto the big
five and the empathizing dimension is
indistinguishable from from
agreeableness systematizing.
It looks a bit more complex.
We haven't quite sorted that out.
But so men prefer working with things
and women with people.
And the,
the uh,
effect size is almost one standard
deviation,
which is,
well,
it's a,
it's a remarkably powerful effect size.
You rarely see an effect size of that
magnitude in,
in,
uh,
in psychology or in the social sciences.
It's a very big determinant.
So man show stronger people.
People have categories,
jobs into six categories using this
thing they call Riasec realistic
investigative,
artistic,
social and conventional,
realistic,
investigative,
artistic,
social,
conventional,
no difference in enterprising.
Yeah,
the middle one is enterprising and
that's kind of a factor analysis derived
categorization system to end it is
related in intelligible ways to the big
five.
So anyways,
men show stronger,
realistic and investigative interests
and women show stronger artistic,
social and conventional interests.
So,
and there's no difference in
entrepreneurial interest essentially.
So kind of know what you think about
that,
but see one of the things that's,
it's happened,
oh yes.
That's actually what this next slide
talks about.
So that's very good
difference between men and women
interested in engineering,
science.
And math.
So the men are much,
much more interesting engineering.
It's a big,
big effect.
There are somewhat more interested in
science and that'd be the harder ends of
the science that aren't social,
you know,
and they're more interested in math.
And so one of the things that you see
happens,
for example,
if you take high math achievers at grade
11 or grade 10 there's not a huge
difference in numbers between girls and
boys in the United States.
But if you track them across time,
the proportion of the high ability
people who go into mathematics or an
allied discipline is way higher among
the boys than it is among the girls.
Oh,
you can make a case that there's some
sociol you know,
there may be,
there's some social conditioning that's
associated with that except that it's
hard to make that case when all that
you're the only people you're picking
are people who already equally good at
mathematics.
Because if it was cultural,
you'd think that you wouldn't be able to
pull them out to begin with.
You have to make the case that all of
the cultural difference in terms of
ability is taking place after the,
the sorting is,
has occurred.
That just doesn't seem right.
But what the,
what,
what seems to be the case is the women
who are very,
very advanced and mathematical ability
aren't that interested in pursuing it as
a career.
So it's interest.
So women underrepresented in stem,
science,
technology,
engineering and mathematics.
Well,
women are walking,
Lee overrepresented in lots of
disciplines though.
So for example,
there'd be you becoming increasingly
dominant in,
in medicine.
So,
you know,
and not that's a real switch because of
course that wasn't the case 50 years
ago.
So high end,
cognitively complex jobs that involve a
lot of social interaction and a lot of
care for people are overwhelmingly
becoming dominated by women.
So,
but math,
physical science is computer science and
engineering don't seem to be,
at least at the moment in that,
in that group.
So,
and there's,
there's,
there's a,
you know,
um,
occupations where women are unbelievably
underrepresented.
So why do you think that is?
I mean,
if you looked at this list,
what would you,
what would you say?
Why would that be?
What's that?
Meetings.
Okay.
Anything else?
Well,
it's physical,
a lot of that,
right?
Construction,
forestry,
mining.
I mean those are very,
very physically demanding jobs.
So they require a fair bit of strength.
Generally you have to be isolated
somewhere,
especially for forestry and mining,
you know,
other dangerous jobs.
Men are way overrepresented and
dangerous occupations.
And so almost all the exceedingly
dangerous occupations are done by men.
It's actually part of the reason that
women,
that men make more money than women.
There's a bunch of reasons.
It's not pure arbitrary social prejudice
by any stretch of the imagination.
You need a multivariate equation in
order to account for the differences.
There's lots of different factors.
One of them is,
is that um,
male run small businesses make more
money than female run small businesses.
And I think the reason for that is that
females often do that part time when
they're,
when they're having kids.
So they're not devoted entirely to the
small business,
but it's a way that they can keep in the
economic game.
While they're also pursuing their
family.
Um,
men are more likely to move to work in,
they're more likely to do dangerous jobs
and they're also more likely to work
longer hours.
And so all of those account for some of
the reason that men are paid more than
women,
it's not pure prejudice.
So there's a good example of,
of the differences in male versus female
dominant dominated occupations,
brick masons,
block masons and stone masons.
There's virtually no women.
Cement Masons,
concrete,
fisher finishers and terasa workers,
electrical power line installers,
carpet floor and tile installers,
heating,
air conditioning,
refrigeration mechanics and installers,
structural iron and rebar workers,
Boston truck mechanics and diesel engine
specialists,
miscellaneous vehicle in mobile
equipment,
mechanics tool and die makers and
roofers.
All of those are 99% or more male
dominated female dominated occupations
in the u s number one secretaries and
administrative assistance.
You know,
that's the most common job category for
women that's unchanged since the Middle
1950s so,
and that's partly because those are
actually pretty good jobs.
They pay well,
they're regular,
they're secure,
they're not too demanding,
they're predictable.
Like if you have to have a jaw rather
than a career that's a,
you know,
cause a career or something,
I suppose that pays you outside of the
money that you're making for the job.
You know,
it's got additional benefits in terms of
status or discovery or accomplishment or
creativity.
But if you just want a job,
that's not a bad job.
Secretary is childcare workers,
receptionists,
Teacher's assistants,
registered nurses,
bookkeeping,
accounting and auditing clerks,
maids and housekeeping cleaners,
nursing,
psychiatric and home health aides,
personal and home care aides and general
office clerks.
So,
all right,
we'll go over agreeableness some more on
Thursday and we'll talk more about
conscientiousness as well.