I'm Steven Blackwood.
I'm part of a small team of people
founding a new university in Savannah,
Georgia.
I'm the president of that new institution.
I'm here today at Cambridge
University and ancient,
a gust and beautiful institution and I
have the great pleasure today to have
with me,
Dr. Jordan Peterson,
professor of psychology at
the University of Toronto,
and I think it is safe to say an
uninsurable figure of our time.
Jordan, it's a real pleasure to
have you here today. Thank you.
Thanks. Pleasure to be here.
Just unbelievable place.
Jordan and I are going to talk today
about what he has called the inflection
point and my hope is that
that conversation will lead us
okay
into a discussion of the
possibilities for cultural renewal.
Indeed,
the possibilities for the,
the renewal, the renaissance
of a more fully human culture.
John,
I think you've called that the inflection
point or called our cultural temporal
moment to kind of inflection point.
Why don't we start there?
What is the inflection point?
Well,
I think we're deciding,
we're trying to decide if there's such a
thing as a direction to move forward to
into the future.
That's what it looks like to me mean.
On the one hand we're making tremendous
technological progress in all sorts of
directions simultaneously.
And that seems to be having mostly
positive effects, especially economically,
especially on a global scale.
And another hand we seem more confused
about are the foundations of our culture
and the potential directions
that we're moving in.
Then we have been for a while and that
seemed especially acute in educational
institutions and that seems to be a
consequence of the constant cultural
critique that's been generated.
I would say mostly on the,
on the postmodern edge edge of
the academic, what would you say?
Academic uh, territory. So,
so we're trying to figure out
what's next,
what do we have to offer to students,
all of that.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
I know that it was,
it does.
Yesterday was published the
50th Anniversary Edition
of Solzhenitsyn's Gulag
archipelago with a forward
that, uh, you've, uh,
foreword written by you,
which I think you've described the writing
of is one of the greatest honors of
your life, if I got that
right. Yes. Academic. Now,
I suppose the question I have there is,
is why is that so important?
Well, the book was important
because it was the first,
it was the first work that succeeded in
undermining the Marxists project from a
moral and an intellectual
perspective simultaneously. I mean,
other people had pointed out the
terror of the Soviet enterprise,
Malcolm Muggeridge and George Orwell,
among others, often people on the left,
interestingly enough.
But it was always possible right up
until the end of the 1960s for the people
who held on to that collectivist utopian
dream in the west to rationalize what
had happened in the Soviet Union,
partly by sweeping it under the rug,
but also partly by,
um,
while using the old adage that you can't
make an omelet without breaking a few
eggs.
It became obvious by the end of the
1960s that the Omelet wasn't very well
prepared and that millions of eggs,
so to speak,
to Belabor a metaphor,
had been broken.
And so when Solzhenitsyn
wrote his great book, um,
it became impossible for anyone who was
willing to be part of the cultural moment
to ignore the fact that something had
gone dreadfully sideways and that it
couldn't be attributed merely to a cult of
personality or to some abnormality
that wasn't intrinsically part of the
doctrine itself.
And so that was partly what soldier
soldier Knutsen revealed about the Soviet
Union as such.
But at the same time,
the evidence that precisely the same
thing had been happening in places like
Maoist China perhaps to
even a larger degree, well,
undoubtedly to a larger degree.
And then in Cambodia and all the other
places where Marxism produced utterly
murderous consequences.
Um,
and so that was the book that did that
and it made Marxism morally repugnant.
Um,
it all,
it was also one of the
events that catalyze the
transformation of Marxism into
identity politics as far as I'm concerned,
because a lot of the people who held the,
the victim victimizer
narrative as sacrosanct,
that that was the appropriate
way to look at the world,
to divide people into identity
groups of whatever form.
And then to see history as the
battle between them, the history,
the present and the future that
that trans, that transmuted,
especially in France because even
though the Marxists had beaten, um,
unmasked, the murderousness of the
doctrine had been masked. That didn't,
the people who had held that doctrine,
we're still looking for
the easiest lateral move.
And so that was one of the driving forces
for the development of postmodernism,
not the only one.
It's the postmodernists are also figured
out something or run across something
that really is an intractable problem.
They ran across the problem
of categorization and that
that actually happened in
multiple disciplines at the same time,
including artificial intelligence
in psychology. People realize,
start to realize about
in the early sixties,
and it was probably under
the pressure of the AI types,
that it was very difficult to perceive
the world because objects aren't just
there for the looking because every object
is made of sub objects and as part of
a higher order structure of objects
and defining what constitutes the
appropriate boundary to put
around a phenomenon so that
it can be perceivable as
an object turns out to be a
virtually impossible task.
We're not sure how it can be managed.
And so the,
that realization of the intrinsic
complexity of things led to a crisis,
I would say an intellectual
crisis, which was, well,
if there's a near infinite number of ways
to perceive a finite set of entities,
how is it that you can call
any one interpretation,
either canonical or valuable?
And that's part of the
postmodern skepticism,
let's say a Meta narratives and it's
actually a reasonable critique. Um,
the problem is as far as I'm concerned,
that what the postmodernists
did was used that problem,
which is a genuine problem,
uh,
as a critique of the
structure of the West.
And then instead of addressing
the problem directly, which is,
well the world is very complex,
but we do in fact perceive it and
they're actually our value structures.
They just circumvented that and pop
back into a bastardized form of mark.
The bastardized form of Marxism that
we see today is identity politics and
that's been extraordinarily destructive
to the universities. Well, let's,
well let's, let's, let's talk, talk
about that a bit more
because it seems to me that,
that it would be a great shame if
people were to think that your,
uh,
your writing this foreword to Solzhenitsyn
was simply to document something as
an historic phenomenon as essentially
important as that historic documentation
is.
It seems to me that what is of interest
to you is not simply to shed light on
the terrors,
the hundred million slaughtered a in
the course of the various Communist
revolutions of the 20th century.
Those various etiologies motivated
by Marxism and other, uh,
other forms of, of, uh,
philosophical ideology.
But because it seems to me that
you take what was present in that
philosophically,
ideologically still to be at work in,
in to have been,
as
it were,
reborn in the west.
And so I suppose what I'd like
to ask you about is what are the,
what are the characteristics of
the Marxist ideology that
led to those, that, that,
that very obvious death and destruction,
which in a,
in a subtler way you see to be,
am I right to say you see to be at
work in the West? Uh, so I like it.
It seems to be very important that
we have a deep sense of what the,
the governing assumptions of our culture,
our or it's hard to transcend them.
Yeah.
Well that is exactly the issue because
the question is whether or not the past
is over.
I mean,
there's a Mark Zack Marxist
philosopher named Richard Wolff,
who challenged me recently
on youtube to a debate.
And really the answer that
I posted was this forward.
And he accused me of being stuck in
the past. You know, it's, well the,
you know,
the,
the wall fell in 1989 in the
horrors of the Soviet era are over.
And we, we, we can't paint,
we can't eternally tar Marxism with
the brush of these past events. I mean,
as if these events are over or as if 50
years is sufficient time to forget about
the corpse us. But that's
his idea, you know,
and to me it's the same idea that you
might put forward if you are a neo Nazi by
saying that, well, you know,
all that happened back in
1945 the fundamental doctrine
was sound and we cannot
allow our judgment about these eternal
truths manifested in the national
socialists doctrine to be forever tainted
by some unfortunate historical events.
And I think that that's just,
well, I don't even know what
to say about it. I mean,
one of the telling things about his
comments was that he only talked about the
Soviet Union and not all the other
terrible places that the same doctrine had
been implemented with
equally murderous effects.
And so that was quite the
argument by evasion. But I,
what I tried to do in the forward and
in my thinking in general is I'm always
trying to get to the bottom of things.
What's at the bottom?
And it seems to me that what happened,
if you look at what happened
in the Russian revolution,
like the first thing you want to
do is give the devil his due. Okay.
And the way you do that is by pointing
out that hierarchical structures,
not we'll,
we'll start even before that.
People have problems
that have to be solved.
Life is a sequence of problems
If you don't solve the problems that life
puts forward, you suffer and you die.
So assuming that you don't
want those two outcomes,
then there are problems you have to
solve. And, and so you have to set an aim.
And the aim is to solve the problem.
And then because we're social creatures,
we have to solve the problems
by organizing collectively.
And the way we do that,
generally speaking, in relationship
to an aim, is to produce a hierarchy.
And the reason for that is that if you
have a problem and you want it to be
solved and you a variety
of people working on it,
you're soon going to discover that some
people are much better at solving the
problem than others.
And that will inevitably produce a
hierarchy and it should because then the,
even the,
the structure of authority is,
is in sync with the aim and the aim is
valuable because it's a problem that
everybody agrees that
is an actual problem.
So you're going to get hierarchical
organizations and you should.
Now the problem with that is that as
soon as you produce a hierarchical
organization,
two things happen.
One is that a small minority of the
people do almost all the creative work.
That's the pre to principal.
And the other is that the benefits of the
hierarchy flow disproportionately to a
small number of people at the top.
So,
and that's another manifestation
of the pre to principle.
And it is something that marks pointed
out, although he blamed it on capitalism,
which, which is a big mistake.
Even if you're concerned for those,
the hierarchy dispossesses so you
produce a hierarchy, both the work,
the work flows from a minority of people
and the benefits flow to a minority of
people, and those might not be
the same people by the way, right?
Because hierarchies aren't perfect in
their ability to distribute resources as a
consequence of a productive effort
that that's part of the problem with
hierarchical organizations.
But then what the hierarchy does is
produce a layer of the dispossessed that
stack up at the bottom near zero, and it's
the majority. It's always the majority.
So that's the price you
pay for hierarchies. Now
what the left does is say,
look at the dispossessed and keep the
hierarchy flexible enough so that it can
twist and band and transform unnecessary,
but also so that the dispossessed
don't fall so close to zero,
that aid that they're done,
they're in misery B,
that the talents they might
possess can't be utilized.
And see that the whole structure doesn't
become so untenable that it destroys
itself because of the inequality,
perfectly reasonable propositions.
And so then you could say,
well,
there's a certain number of people on
the left who are genuinely motivated by
concern about dispossession as well
as the dispossessed of course, fine.
So that's to give the devil his due.
And so then you might say, well,
there was moral reasons.
There were more reasons for at least a
subset of those who are involved in the
Russian revolution to be involved.
They were interested in
helping the dispossessed,
but there's a problem and this is the
problem of the left. There's a problem.
So on the right as well.
The problem on the right is once
the hierarchy is established,
those who dominate the top have every
right to overstate the moral virtue of the
hierarchy because it privileges
them in particular on the left.
The problem is is that it's not easy
to distinguish between care for the
dispossessed and hatred for
those who occupy positions of,
well, you could say authority.
The leftists would say power.
You could also say competence, which I
think is more to the case or ability.
It's not easy to distinguish care for the
dispossessed from hatred for those who
occupy the preeminent positions in
the hierarchy. And if it's power,
then it's hatred for power, but if
it's competence and it is competence,
if the hierarchy is functional, then
it's hatred for the competent. Okay.
Then you say, all right, so those
are the two competing motivations,
care for the dispossessed and
hatred for the, let's say competent.
Let's play that out.
Historically speaking and see,
which is the more powerful force.
While that got played out very
rapidly in the Russian revolution.
And what happened was even if there
was a s a minority and perhaps even a
majority,
although there wasn't,
but perhaps even a majority of those
who truly cared for the dispossessed,
those who hated the
competent slaughtered them,
it turned out that the hatred
was a much more potent, uh,
geopolitical force than the compassion.
And then,
and another twist
occurred too because the,
the narrative was Bursch Waze
against proletariat, let's say.
And so that's those at the upper most
pinnacle of the hierarchy against those
who were the dispossessed. And that
was also the historical narrative.
And then it was the right
and responsibility of those
who are oppressed to rise
up. But that ran into another problem,
which is basically the problem that the,
that the, the postmodernists,
especially on the feminist side,
have now identified as
intersectionality. It's like, well,
it turns out that you're, you can so
easily be placed into one group. I,
in fact, this is the perception
problem that we talked about before.
There's a very large number of groups.
You can be placed in it.
It might be an unlimited
number of groups in fact.
And so then if you're motivated
primarily by hatred and your, your,
your desire is to produce
as much mayhem as possible.
You can take any given person and you
can analyze the multiple groups that they
belong to. And then you can find one
group in which they're the oppressor.
And then because there's no excuse
whatsoever for the oppression,
even if there's one dimension of your
identity along which you're an oppressor,
then you're grist for the,
for the,
for the bone crushing mill of the,
of the Soviet work cap.
And that's exactly what happened. And
so as the Soviet revolution progressed,
more and more people got
thrown into the cauldron,
let's say the socialists, the students
to religious people, the, all the, the,
the old, the original Revolutionary
Stellan had all of them killed.
Cause there was some,
and if it wasn't you that was guilty
because of your group membership,
then they just expanded
the capacity that the,
the parameters of the idea of group,
well you're not an MPR oppressor,
but your grandfather was a landowner.
Well that's good enough. That's, that's,
that's your class. That's, that's,
and so that's sufficient justification
to throw you to the wolves as well.
And so what you saw is this
just unbelievable expansion
of murderousness driven
by the twin improper presuppositions that
you could define people by their group
identity and that history was best
conceptualized as a battle between the
fortunate, the unfortunate long
those group identities. Yes.
If we could pick up that,
that notion of the,
the group identity and the
collect what you call the co,
the collectivist thinking,
it seems to me that might be opposed
to a kind of robust view of the human
individual as the site of
responsibility and agency suffering.
And so it seems to me that, uh, what
I'd like to ask you about is the,
is the connection between,
or the ways in which the collectivist
thinking results in the annihilation of
all human particularity,
whether it's economic or a familial or,
uh, uh, you might say,
it seems to me that what's going on in
the collectivist thinking is the absolute
enemy of
human particularity and freedom itself.
That's
the enemy of the idea of the individual,
the sovereign individual,
which is the central idea of the West.
I mean,
and that's manifested in the
underlying religious structure.
So if you think about
Christianity for example,
you think about Christianity
psychologically is strip
it of its metaphysics,
at least for the purposes of the argument.
You see the emergence of the idea of
the divine individual as, as well as,
as what, as, as part of what's what,
as part of divinity itself, right?
As an integral part that's part of the
trinitarian idea of the part of, uh,
of divinity itself.
And that divinity to me
is the capacity of the,
of individual consciousness to
generate order from potential.
So the way I look at people,
first of all,
so like people who have been
criticizing what I'd be doing,
think about my philosophy such as it is
not that it's mine as a sort of variant
of iron Rand's ideas of the centrality
of the individual individual above all,
that's not the issue. It's a
conceptual issue. Is that what,
what, what category is to
be primary? And for me,
the individuals to be primary.
And there's a variety of reasons for that.
First of all,
the individual is the locus of suffering
and also the locus of responsibility.
So,
so those are really the two reasons that
the individual has to be made primary.
Um, but, and, and the divinity
element of the individual. And,
and this I think is coated
in our deepest stories,
it's really deeply coded in genesis,
particularly in the opening chapters
of opening verses of Genesis,
is that what human beings confront in
their lives is akin to what God himself
confronted at the beginning of time.
And so it's easy for us to believe
that we're deterministic creatures like
clocks and,
and that it's the past,
the drives us forward in a
deterministic manner into the future.
But I don't believe that's the case.
I actually don't think there's any that
that's the case because people are so
complex. You actually can't predict
them as if they're deterministic,
excepted in very constrained
circumstances. And so it's a hypothesis,
but it's not a very good one. Um,
and although it has its utility,
what, what, what seems
to me to be the case,
and I think this is how people
conceptualize themselves
and how they act towards
themselves and towards other people and
how our social structures or political
structures are constituted,
is that human beings constantly
confront a landscape of possibility.
It's potential itself. And, and we
have a belief in the idea of potential.
We have an idea that there
are things that could be,
it's a very strange conception of
reality because it's not a materialistic
conception because things that could be
aren't measurable in any sense, right?
But we certainly act as if they exist
and we all treat each other as if our,
one of our fundamental ethical
requirements is for you to
confront that potential properly.
And that would be to live up to your
responsibility is you have these gifts and
talents and, and possibilities
that have been granted to you.
And if you fail to make use of
them, your talents, let's say,
then that's a sin of sorts.
And that's a religious
way of thinking about it.
But it doesn't matter because
that's how people treat each other.
If you have a child, for example,
or or, or a spouse or a friend,
brother to anyone you care about and
you see you have the intuition that they
could be making more of themselves
and what they have, then they are,
then you're deeply disappointed in that.
And the reason you're disappointed in
that is because there's a call to us,
an existential call to confront
that potential. That's,
that's everywhere that faces us in every
direction and to transform it into the
most functional and
habitable order possible.
And the way that that is to be done
properly is with truth. And, and,
and I think that all of those ideas
are integral to the Judeo Christian
substrate of Western culture.
They're fundamental ideas.
And so if you put the group
before the individual,
then all of that disappears when you're,
when you're debating
with the radical leftist,
postmodern types about free speech,
you're actually not debating with them
about free speech because they don't
believe in free speech.
It's not part of their conceptual universe
because for for speech to be free and
therefore valuable,
the people conducting the conversation
have to be sovereign individuals capable
of generating independent
thought independent of their
canonical group identity
and reach a consensus through
that process of dialogue,
none of that exists in
the postmodern world.
All of those preconceptions
would be attributed. Well.
Something like Euro centric
neocolonialism, something like that.
It seems to me that wasn't work at
that is a radical dismissal of the
possibility that the individual
has access to anything at all.
That is to say that that that in,
if you don't do believe in free speech
is fundamentally motivated by the,
by or,
or sustained by the confidence
that our discourse or dialogue,
that human thinking itself
can reach something stable,
that it has a relationship beyond the by
beyond immediacy and that and that and
that there's me on power and beyond power.
It reaches beyond power to truth.
There's no point in ever having a
conversation about anything if the
conversation itself doesn't have access
to something transcendent. Exactly right.
Well.
So what happens with,
and this is especially true for
people like food call Dera too,
to some degree as well,
the first thing you do is you define
the fundamental motivation has power.
Because that's all there is, is there's
the dominance of one group or the other.
And so then the dialogue has to serve
power because that's all there is.
And so yeah, all of that is
obliterated. And, and by,
by doing that actually, the, the,
the postmodernist make it impossible
for them to solve the conundrum that
validly drove poss
postmodernism to begin with.
So the conundrum is infinite set
of potential interpretations.
That's a real conundrum. That's the
problem of complexity, right? And,
and it's real. So then
the question is, well,
is there any solution to
the problem of complexity?
And this is where issues of moral
relativism start to become, um,
PR paramount. Because if there's no
solution to the problem of complexity,
then there's no canonical interpretations.
And all the interpretations are just,
well, what would you call
it? They're there expedient.
They have the expedience of power.
But see,
my best pathway through that essentially
I think has come from the developmental
psychologist,
Sean Piaget and Piaget could
be considered a Neil Kantian.
You know,
the cots fundamental doctrine was
act such that if your action became a
universal maximum that that would
be of universal benefit. And so,
and but by Piaget differentiated that and,
and,
and demonstrated how that evolved
naturally in the course of the spontaneous
maturation of children through play.
It's, it's absolutely brilliant.
So I can give you a quick example.
So my granddaughter who's 14 months
old has just learned a new game.
And the game is,
she plays it with her wooden spoon and
the game is she has the spoon and then
she looks at you and then she gives you
the spoon and then you take it from her
and she lets it go and then she watches
you and then you give the spoon back and
she's very happy to get the spoon back.
But she's also very
happy to give it to you.
And then she turns to the next person
and she gives them the spoon and then she
gets it back. And then you can play
with there. And the play is, well,
now you've, you've, you've, you've,
you've started to embody the
principle of reciprocity, right?
We can trade and, and it's a
repeating game. It's not one trade.
You don't end up with a spoon.
And I don't end up with this bone.
We both have the spoon some
of the time across time.
And there's some utility in
the exchange itself. Okay.
So she's playing without
in thrilled about,
and no wonder because it's a
walloping walloping discovery.
And so then you take the
spoon from her and maybe you,
you hold it a little longer
than she expects and that
makes her a little nervous.
But then you give it back and then
she's relieved and that makes her happy.
Or You cover the spoon with your hand
and then she's a bit confused about where
it might be a new,
show it to her and you give it
back and she's happy about that.
Or she reaches out to grab it and you
pull it away a little bit and move it back
and forth. So she has to do a
little more effort to get it.
And as long as you don't push
that, and it's a bit of a
challenge to her, uh, both,
both physically in terms of,
of coordination,
but also psychologically in
terms of delay of gratification.
She also finds that gratifying and the,
and the reason for that is that you're,
you're showing how her,
how robust and resilient the idea of
reciprocity is across sequences of
transformations. And it's just this little
thing you do at the table. You think,
well that's nothing. It's
like, no, it's something.
And so the P is Yeti and idea
is something like there's an,
there's an implicit morality that
emerges to constrain the infinite set of
interpretations.
And it has to do with the structure that
we'll maintain reciprocity optimally in
the largest,
including the largest number of people
across the largest amount of time. And so,
and so the way that I've been portraying
that for the people who've been
listening to my lectures,
is that what you need to
take responsibility for
yourself as if you care for
yourself. Okay. So first we
figure out what's yourself. Well,
it's not just you now
because you aren't just,
you now you're the community of
use that extra stretch across time.
So in order for you to take
care of yourself properly,
now you have to learn to play an iterative
game with yourself that's sustainable
and even potentially
improvable across time.
And there aren't many games
that you can play like that.
So that starts to radically
constrained the set of possibilities.
And then it's more constrained than that
because not only do you have to play a
game with yourself that can repeat
across time to minimize suffering,
to remove the possibility of death,
to allow for the possibility of
productive movement in a certain amount of
happiness. But you have to do that with
other people around you and across time.
And so there's you and the multiple
use embedded in your family and the
multiplicity of your family members
embedded inside a culture and,
and the extension of
that culture across time.
And so for you to act properly than all
of those things have to be harmoniously
balanced at the same time.
And that radically reduces the
set of potential interpretations.
And that's the antidote to
the, to the chaos of, of, of,
of the infinite array,
potential perceptual, uh,
worlds and, and well, and then there
are questions that emerge out of that.
Like, well, what's the
best way to play that game?
But we certainly know that a reciprocity
fairplay the spirit of fair play is,
is,
is immensely important to that.
And that's what Piaget documented
and that Wa it's what we all know.
And also that there's something about
truth that's absolutely integral to that
as well. So, and the
postmodernists just, they just,
they got the problem, right, but they,
they never went the next steps.
And it's partly because, well,
why is it,
why is it they had an easy answer at hand
that required almost no transformation
in their original worldview?
Well,
we'll just keep the Marxism will just
transform it into something that looks
different and that'll be good
enough. Minimal change. So
it seems to me that that, that the,
that the, the, the, the collective,
the collective is thinking that's at work
in the insistence that only the group
matters has the effect of radically
annihilating the integrity of the
individual. In fact, that may be even,
it's a, its essence. Well I think,
I think it's,
it's a actually that is the saying.
I believe so at the bottom
and because there's a,
there's a murderousness at
the bottom of the collectivism
that needs to be accounted for.
And so I see what's at the bottom.
And this is partly a consequence,
say of the insistence that the
west is a patriarchal tyranny. The,
the desire is it's the
Cain and Abel Desire.
See Cain was jealous of Abel.
Not so much because
Abel was God's favorite,
but because Abel deserved to be God's
favorite because he had done things right
and it's very bitter.
It's very bitter in life to see a gap
widening between you and someone else,
period.
But it's particularly bitter if you know
the gap is widening because the person
who is doing well is doing,
is actually doing good and doing well.
And that implies at least in eradicating
the vagaries and randomness of life,
and I'm, I'm perfectly aware
of those as factors. It's,
it's bad enough to be down,
but it's worse to know that you're down
because you've put yourself down and
then you have a choice,
which is do you do turn against the ideal
itself because it becomes so painful
to gaze upon it or do you destroy
the ideal out of vengeance and spite?
And that's,
and that's,
that's a simpler pathway forward then
decomposing and deconstructing yourself
and being reborn.
The Christian idea for,
for lack of a better word,
is that something has to be sacrificed
in order for the potential of the future
to be manifested in the best possible way.
There's always a demand for sacrifice.
The question is what should be sacrificed?
And the answer is you.
That's the answer. It's you that should
be sacrificed. And then the question is,
well,
what part of you and,
and the answer to that as the
part of you that's not worthy,
that needs to be put into the
flame that needs to be burnt off.
And that's a process of death.
And rebirth.
And if there's lots of you
that has become corrupt,
then most of what passes through
the fire will be burnt off.
And that's terribly painful for people.
It's, that's the desert. You know,
w imagine that your, that your essential
personality structure is tyrannical.
So you're a rigid idealogue,
you're cast in stone and so you decide
to move from the tyranny who escaped from
the tyranny. Well, where do
you end up where you don't
end up in the promise land,
you end up in the desert for 40 years
and maybe you die there. I mean,
even Moses did. So it's out of
the frying pan into the fire,
that's for sure. And it's no wonder
that people are loath to let go.
And then the more
tyrannical they've become,
the more they've restricted their
possibility and all of that and sold their
soul to the dogma of human beings. Let's
say a soldier Knutsen would describe it,
the less there is of them that will be
left after everything is stripped bare.
And that's a terrifying,
that's a terrifying possibility.
It's much easier to take the other
route and it becomes easier and easier.
And then while there are other motivations
that pile up as well, bitterness,
the hatred that bitterness can, because
you know, you've lost your chance, right?
You had your chance and you've,
and you've squandered it and the,
and the feeling of that.
I think that's why Cain tells God after
he gets caught after his murderous act,
he says that his punishment is more
than he can bear because it's the
realization of what he's done.
He's destroyed his own ideal.
And that's what you do
if you're a collectivist,
you destroy yourself as an
individual and that's all you have.
And so there's,
there's nothing in that except I
would say a continually opening pet of
hopelessness and despair.
And then that drives bitterness and
hatred and desire for revenge and all of
that. It's a terrible cycle and we've
seen it play itself out over and over and,
and, and, and we haven't yet
precisely learned from that. So to me,
it's part of an eternal struggle.
You know, it's been outlined as a,
as a war in some sense.
That's going on in the human psyche
since the beginning of time for for all
intents and purposes,
it seems to me, Jordan, that your position
is, is fundamentally a positive one.
It's an affirmation of human dignity,
the freedom that dignity demands
and an affirmation of the infinite
particularity of human life.
If one were to contrast
the collectivist thinking,
on the one hand we've, when might call
it a kind of abstract rationality,
is if there's one solution to fit them,
one size fits all kind of top down logic.
What's on the other side?
What's the,
what's the antidote to
that in the individual
it is particularly, I mean one of the
things I talk about in 12 rules for life,
and this is an in my lectures, this
is become a, a meme, strangely enough,
something that's widely
distributed on the web,
partly because there's
comical element to it.
It's to clean up your room and everyone
laughs about that because I'm taking
that seriously. It's like,
oh, clean up your room.
Everyone's mother has told them
that a thousand times. Right,
but I tried to explain why.
It's like,
well you have a bit of chaotic
potential right in front of you.
It's in some sense infinite
in its potential and the
the domain in which you can
manipulate that might be rather restricted
because of the restrictions that that
are part and parcel of your existence.
But maybe you have your room and you
might think you might have contempt for
that and so it's a complete bloody
catastrophe, but you don't have to,
you could think, well, I've
got a little, it isn't a room.
It's a place of potential and as
soon as you know that, then it's,
it's not your room anymore.
It isn't a room.
The room that you see is
your preconception of the
space that you inhabit.
What's there is,
is a fragment of infinity.
That's what's there and
what you see is the,
is the,
is the low resolution consequence of
your assumption and lazy habit and
blindness. That's your initial room and
you think, well no, that's not the room.
See part of what artists do.
For example,
when van Gogh Paints a room
and you look at it glowing,
he's trying to show you what's
beyond your perception of the room.
And I mean this technically,
like the way that your visual system
is set up is that whenever memory and
presumption can, can, can
replace direct perception,
it will because it's simpler.
So you literally see what you expect to
see and if what you see is dull and drab
and boring and pointless and, and, and,
and uninspiring, then that's
you. It's not what's there.
And what the artist does when he or she
represents that mundane reality is to
remind you of what's behind it.
The potential that's there.
And so what I'm suggesting to people
is that they take the potential that's
right in front of them. It's
like, okay, and here's the rule
you're aiming up.
There's something that you could change,
that you would change now might
be a very small thing. Could,
well that's within the
grasp of your power would,
is within the grasp of your
will to combine those two
things might be very small
shift. You might only be willing to make
a very tiny step forward. It's like fine,
good enough,
make a tiny step forward and that makes
you a slight bit stronger than you were
before. And then the next step
can be slightly larger and it's,
it's the path of humility.
It's what people,
it's what people act out when.
So there's this cathedral,
it's actually, it's not a cathedral,
it's an oratorial in Montreal,
I think it's the second
largest one in the world.
It's set on a hill at the top of a hill
and there's a huge staircase leading up
to it from the bottom of the hill.
And people often who are crippled and
who were on crutches and so forth are in
wheelchairs, go there and make
their way painfully up the hill.
Or maybe they do that on their knees.
And the idea is that they're
struggling incrementally uphill,
step-by-step despite their burdens to
reach the city of God on the hill and
they're acting out.
That's life.
It's like the proper aim is
the city of God on the hill.
And what is that?
Well,
that's that place that we talked
about already where these levels of
responsibility are stacked together
harmoniously so that you're acting in your
best interest and in your family's best
interest and in and in the world's best
interest. And I would say in the
best interests of reality itself,
right? Assuming that we have some
integral role to play in reality,
which is certainly at least
true at the human level.
That's the city of God on the hill
that beckons to everyone and you,
you move up that you
move towards that humbly.
So that's one step at a time and you
do it despite your burden and you're
suffering all of that. And that's
all dramatized in that and it's,
it's a perfect dram of that.
And would you even say it is not to
be despite your suffering, it's in,
in through your particular suffering.
We, one thing that strikes me about,
you know, clean up your
room, clean up your room.
Yes it is the affirmation of the
particularity of your life. I mean,
one thing that strikes me about deepest
in our human experience is that it is
infinitely particular. I
mean, you mentioned your, your
granddaughter. I mean the,
the, the loves, the people,
the experiences, the places
that were shaped by it.
They're not places in the abstract.
This,
this top down sense as if
there could be the, you know,
the same kinds of clothes and the same
kinds of experience for all human beings.
It,
that that's the enemy of the very
deepest truth of our human experience,
which it seems to me is
infinitely particular,
but not infinitely
particular in the center,
which those particularities
just go off into nothingness.
Those particulars are precisely our
points of access to the transcendent,
to the infinite, to the, to
the, to, to, to, to that switch.
That's where the reality is.
Yes.
So that's why young said that modern men
can't see God because they don't look
low enough. Yes. They're not,
there aren't paying attention to the
importance of the particularities because
the particularity is where the
pen meets the paper, right? Yeah.
And it's just a tiny dot
every, every, like when you're,
when you're writing, it's,
it's a dot.
And then it extends into a,
in those transform into words
and sentences and paragraphs,
but the particular act is where the pen
meets. Yes, yes, yes. That focal point,
right?
That's the center of the cross by the way.
Yes. Yes. Well, you mentioned
the cross, I mean certainly in
the, in, in, in, in, in the,
in the history of,
of the West,
one of the ways has come through as
a and in the east to is in Christian
theology is the very notion
of the incarnation. You
know, what does that to say,
but that the infinite is in the
particular and that they, that,
that they are,
that they are co
inherence that the infinite in fact has
no life except in the particular and the
particular itself has a relation
to her is comprehended by that.
Very infinite.
And so it seems to me that that what is
going on there is an affirmation that
every particularity,
no matter how tiny itself
has revelent Tori of,
of a transcendent, and I think
it was from the gospel of Thomas,
but I might have this wrong. The
Kingdom of God is spread upon the earth.
But men do not see it. And that's
that. That's that infinite,
that infinite possibility in
each moment of particularity.
And that is what artists, that is what
great artists are reminding herself.
They'll take
a slice of space and time.
It was it money who painted the haystacks.
He went out into the fields in France and
he painted the same haystack like many,
many times under different conditions of
lighting. And to show how different my,
if it's a, if it's a haystack,
it's the same thing, but it wasn't,
he paid attention to the particularities.
And so what great artists are
trying to do is, well first of all,
so imagine the painting.
So it's a painting of a landscape.
And so the first thing is that it's layers
of time because the painter has gone
out there and seeing the landscape and
then seeing it again and then seeing it
again and then seeing it again
and then seeing it again.
And it has to pay attention to the
particularities of the light and the color
and all of that to represent
it properly. So it's and, and,
and the mere fact that he's done that is,
it's,
it's the acting out of the idea that
in this tiny slice of time and space,
there's something worth attending
to for an infinite amount of time.
But you can't be because
you just can't do it.
But you need to know that you couldn't
do it and then it would be worthwhile.
And so the painter encapsulates
the landscape and then
frames that it says like,
look,
look through this window
at the transcendent that's
behind the low resolution
representation of your assumption,
the blindness that you, the,
the expedient blindness that
you by necessity bring to
bear, to every situation.
Remember, what's behind this.
Always remember what's behind this.
And that's what art calls us to do.
That's what beauty calls us to do is to
make contact with that. And then you say,
well,
the problem with the,
particularly the problem with the
particularly is that it brings suffering.
And the bringing of suffering
with particularly can also
allow evil to enter the
world because that particular suffering
can engender bitterness and resentment
and hatred and all of those things.
And the desire to destroy.
So the particularity carries with it a
tremendous risk and a tremendous burden.
And so the answer, the question is, well,
how do you tolerate the particularity
and take advantage of the potential?
And the answer is to make a relationship
with the infinite that's behind the
particularity. And that's the
fundamental religious idea is to,
if you can maintain the particularly,
but also stay in contact with what's
transcendent and infinite beyond that,
then you can then you have the potential
strengths to tolerate the catastrophe
of what's limited and then you get
to have your cake and eat it too.
In principle.
Yes, yes. I want to return to
education in a moment, but,
but on the way there, as it were.
Jordan, I want to ask you, uh,
you've, you've talked about
this, this the inflection point.
What is the inflection point and how
might it be understood relative to, uh,
what I would I take to be a very decadent,
a worldview in its last gasps?
It seems to me, even that, uh,
many of the, uh, frankly
simply slanderous, uh,
attacks on you personal,
personally blatant
misrepresentations of the,
the very plain fact what you're saying,
it seems to me that there's an
animus there that is precisely,
there's an animist there. But the
question is where is that coming from?
Well, we, if you look at
a Derrida for example,
and his critique of the idea of
logo centrism, you know, as, as the,
as the central Motif of the
West, let's say, and he,
and he knew at multiple levels what
that critique meant because he knew what
logos meant. Logos means embodied
truth. And there is of course,
a religious dimension to that.
And so he was criticizing the
notion of fowl logo centrism and,
and so he was going right at the core
of the doctrine of the individual.
Now the question is, why
might someone do that? Now,
I think the reason for that
fundamentally is that there's a terrible
responsibility that goes along with it.
So imagine that you offered people here,
here's the offer.
Offer one.
You don't matter.
It's,
it's a really say the
narrowest of materialist view
points is you weren't here
then you were for a brief period
of time and then you're gone.
And that all washes out in
the endless sands of time.
Nothing in your life is significant.
Nothing about humanity is significant.
Nothing about the world itself is
significant. It's all a matter of blind,
random chance.
And it's all the same in the end.
Who cares in a million years,
right?
And and the price you pay
for that is insignificance.
But the advantage that you gained from
that is that fundamentally you have no
responsibility because
nothing you do matters.
And so then there's no moral burden.
There's no obligation. And of course,
if you can gather expedient pleasure
while you're deteriorating pointlessly,
then that's all to the good. So
it's, it's a libertinism as well.
And that's inviting obviously because
short term pleasure is by definition
inviting.
And so you can abandon any pretension
to a relationship with the infinite.
And consider that only a sign
of delusion and weakness.
Assume that your life is material
and irrelevant. It doesn't matter.
And then you can shrug
off all responsibility and
pursue short term pleasure.
While there's some real advantages in
that, it's very, it's a very easy pathway.
The alternative is, as far as I'm
concerned, is no, you don't understand.
You are the,
you are the center of the
world as center of the world.
It has many centers and you do partake
in this process of casting the potential
of the future into the reality
of the present and the past.
That's what your consciousness does.
And the quality of what you
produce is dependent on your,
on the ethics of your choice.
Your choice between good and evil in
every moment is what determines the course
of the world. And that's on you. It's
like, well, that's deeply meaningful,
but it's unbelievable.
It's in it's ultimate
responsibility in the literal sense.
And I think that in order
for us to set things right,
we have to understand that we have
to take on that burden of ultimate
responsibility as if it's not
only as if it's ours, which it is,
but as if there isn't anything
better that we could do. And I,
and one of the things that I found so
gratifying about the lecture to her that
I've been doing is that and why keep doing
it. The live events in particular, um,
cause we've done about 100 of them now
so far is that when I explained to the
audiences,
and this is especially true,
it's speed seems to be especially
true of of men but of young men,
but not so young even to
say, look, you have, you,
you have an ethical obligation to lift
the heaviest load you can possibly
conceive of.
And that's the primary
call to adventure in life.
And that call to adventure
is so worthwhile that it
justifies the particularity.
Everybody, it's like lights go
on and they think, oh, I see.
So you need a meaning to set against
the suffering and to protect you against
that temptation towards men.
Malevolence you need that. Well,
where's the meaning to be
found? Well, it's not happiness,
it's not short term pleasure. It's
not, it's not self development,
it's not self esteem. It's none of
those things that are so focused on, on,
on the individual's psyche event.
It's,
it's literally the stumbling uphill
towards the city of God with your burden.
People go, well, that's
where the meaning is.
And they know that because they
know responsible people, they know,
they admire responsible people.
They already got that say, well,
that's what you should be calm.
And they think, and not only that,
that's what you could become because
that's what you are in the deepest sense.
Yes. Yes. Would you, would
you say that, that, that,
that the antidote denialism is meaning?
And if so, uh, you know, I think you've
described yourself Jordan, as you've said,
I think the surfer not the wave.
And I suppose I want to
ask you what is the wave,
because it seems to me where
it a moment of very great, uh,
cultural potential and it
could go any number of ways,
but that the very fact of
what one might call it,
the Jordan Peterson phenomenon,
a worldwide,
your book translated into
dozens of languages. Your
rec lecture halls packed, uh,
is a sign of a longing, a self
conscious longing for, for, for,
for meaning. How would, how would you,
how would you describe what that
wave is that, that you didn't create,
but that you will start speaking
some of its technological? So,
so I would say that wave is,
it's got multiple levels and so,
so we could start from,
well it will start from,
I would say what's most obvious and
that would be the medium rather than the
message. So I, um, and these people
that I'd been associated with,
this intellectual, dark web group, we're,
we're in the fortunate position of
being early adopters of extraordinarily
powerful technologies. So, and, and
the technologies are twofold. There's,
there's online video and
then there's podcasts.
And so they're technologically
revolutionary in a variety of ways.
So online video is revolutionary because
it brings something closely akin to a
live performance to an infinitely large
number of people on demand permanently.
So then you think, well, what's the
advantage of a book? Well, it's permanent.
It's relatively low cost. It's
easily distributable. Right. So what,
what's the advantage to online
video? Well, it's, it's inexpensive.
It's not inexpensive. It's free. It's
far easier to produce than a book.
Like the lag time from video
to publication is the day.
Like we can put this online today
instead of the three year lag that a book
would require and then far more
people can watch and listen,
then can read because reading
is a minority ability and
in some sense really fat,
real expert level reading.
You know that because such a tiny minority
of people buy books and people are
made uncomfortable by books,
they're intimidated by them.
Even if they have the intelligence
in principle to do the reading,
it's not part of their cultural mill.
You, that's a small minority of people.
And so all of a sudden
online video allows,
allows the spoken word to have the
same impact as the written word.
And that's deadly.
That's a good and Berg Revolution.
And then with podcasts
that's even magnified because
you don't have to sit and
watch a podcast. You can walk around,
you can exercise, you can do the dishes,
you can,
you can drive.
Many people who come to my lectures are
like long haul truckers and guys who run
forklifts and you know they're in their
machinery all day and all they do is
listen to podcasts and so all of us and
they can listen to the podcasts because
more people can listen, then can read
and maybe way more people can listen,
then can read.
We have no idea,
maybe the potential market 10 times as
big and so they can do it when they want
to. They can also do it in private.
If you read and you're on the subway,
people can tell you're reading.
If you're sitting at home and reading
well then you're with a book and if you're
uncomfortable with a book,
you think that's pretentious
or presumptuous or part
of a class that you don't
belong to or anything that
makes you feel inferior. Well,
you can just circumvent that you listened
in private and so people and people
are taking that opportunity like mad.
And so that's part of the way it's,
let's say that technological revolution
in communication that's illustrated that
people have far more depth and capacity
to concentrate that anyone would have
imagined.
You didn't see this with Netflix and HBO,
it used to be on TV.
There was an idea that while movie
was about as long as you could attract
people's attention for 90 minutes,
that's the most the typical
person could concentrate for.
It's like that turned out
to be complete rubbish.
People will follow these incredibly
complex like literary level net narratives
breaking bad,
for example,
that has multiple characters following
multiple streams of development for,
for endless hours and
they'll binge watch it.
So we have way more capacity for sustained
concentration that we thought and
these new bandwidth unlimited
technologies are revealing that to us.
And I happened to be an early
adopter of this and so that's,
that's part one of the wave.
And then,
then there's the message part and it has
something to do with cr culture for a
very long time has articulated
out a a right of rights.
You have rights, you need to demand them,
you need to claim them. It's like, but,
but that's,
that's,
that's half the story and it's not the
most salutary half because it turns out
that the meaning in your life isn't the
consequence of the claiming of rights.
The rights are in some sense
what other people owe you.
I know there's more to it than that,
but, but it's that in large part. Well,
you can just get what
you're owed. It's like, no,
that's not where you're going to find
your meaning. What you're going to find,
where you're going to find
your meaning is responsibility,
which is the other half of the
rights responsibility equation.
And people don't know that this
is the, the, the, the, the, that,
what would you call,
this is where,
this is where this is the point
where things come together properly.
You need a meaning in your life to
forestall the suffering and to make you
strong enough to resist malevolence
where's the meaning to be found? Rights,
impulsive, pleasure and
happiness. No responsibility.
Oh,
who would have guessed that?
It's not part of the narrative because
the responsibility narrative even is
usually about duty or patriotism or
something like that, which which is okay,
but it's, it's, it's an ideological
narrative too in its own right.
This is different. It's like, no,
you don't understand is that what makes
life worth living is to pick up the p
two two to take it's kits,
task atrophy,
and embrace it and carry it and to
realize through that who you are.
So one of the things I figured
out in this lecture tour,
there's this old idea that you go into
the abyss and to Nietzsche and idea that
you can gaze into the abyss.
You gaze long and what you
find in the abyss is a monster.
Tolstoy wrote about that. That's the
dragon at the bottom of the abyss.
Let's say that Satan himself for that
matter. And, but if you go into that,
into that as deeply as you can, what
you find is your, you find, you find,
you find your, your, your,
your fragmented father in a,
in a comatose condition, in a, in
a, in a, in a desiccated and, and,
and separated condition. And
then you revivify that. Well,
what does that mean?
It means something.
It means that if you look in the darkness,
you find the light.
That's one thing it means,
and that the light really
stands out against the darkness.
But the light is to be found
in the darkness. So that's
a very interesting thing.
That's a quest narrative,
but it means more than that.
It means something fundamental.
So we know, for example,
that if you take yourself
out of your current state of,
of predictability and safety,
and you put yourself in a new situation,
you'll learn, right? You'll observe,
you'll incorporate new information.
So that's a cognitive issue.
But that isn't all that happens.
What happens is that new genes turn on
within you and code for the production of
new proteins that happens neurologically.
New parts of you turn on.
And so the idea is that if you can move
yourself out into the world and push
yourself out against a
maximum array of challenges,
more and more of you turn
on turns on into, and then
the question would be, well,
what would you be if all of you that
could be turned on was turned on?
And the answer would be, you would be
the resurrection of the ancestral father.
That's what you would be.
And so that's why Christ says I am
the way and the truth and the life,
and no one comes to the
father except through me.
What that means is that if you take
on the unbearable burden of being
voluntarily, then that transforms
you into the ancestral father.
And that's true.
And so that's unbelievably optimistic
because what it is so interesting because
it's, it's dark beyond
belief rights to say, well,
the world is characterized by suffering
and by malevolence of a depth that's
virtually beyond comprehension.
But if you choose to comprehend that,
what you discover in that is the
light that destroys the darkness.
And that's, well, that's announced really
something to discover. It's, it's, uh,
it's,
it's the discovery that there isn't a
discovery that's more profound in that
that's the search for the holy grail or
the philosopher's stone, all of that.
It isn't that the,
isn't that the search and
indeed the finding that every
human being is made for.
Um, what I want to ask you, Jordan,
is about the role of education here.
So it seems to me that,
that what the meaning that people are
finding in your work that you can listen
to in podcast. You can, you can, you can,
while you're doing a long run, uh, uh,
drive, uh, across the prairies
or wherever it may be.
But it seems to me that,
that the,
the deconstruction of our culture by a
world view that has denied the integrity
of the individual that has denied the
individual's relation to the transcendent,
to any stable, knowing, denied
the dignity of the individual,
that, that deconstruction. It's
not for no reason that the, uh,
the postmodern view calls
itself deconstruction that
has very deconstructive
effects in my view, in the world. It seems
to me that the rebirth of, uh, or the,
the renaissance of a more adequate to
more fully human culture depends on more
than, um, it depends on
institutional life. We need
cultural forms. We architecture,
there's all kinds of, uh, fully
a full culture is a complex, uh,
uh, an infinitely complex
structure. Uh, but I think we've,
we've as it were,
deleted out the memory banks
in so many profound ways.
And so what I'm, what I'd like to ask you
about is the still have the libraries.
We still have the libraries. Well,
thank God for that. Thank God for that.
And this is where I want to turn to
education because you say in, uh, uh,
at one point you say that that we need
to rescue the treasure trove of the past,
the Chinese restaurant.
He rescued the values of the treasure
trove of the past and integrate them.
And I suppose I'd like to ask you
about the rules of the university
these are for, is to remind people
to, to, to lead people to doing that.
I mean,
we wandered around Cambridge today and
you showed me King's chapel for example,
which is so beautiful that it's just
beyond belief. And that's a call, right?
That's it's a call to a mode of being.
And it's a,
Socrates believed that all
learning was remembering. And,
and it's true in the sense that we just
discussed is that through encounter with
the tragedy of life and
the malevolence of life,
that that more of you will come to
manifest itself. But that can be,
that can be facilitated
by your incorporation of
the greatness of the past.
So you say, well, each great philosopher,
each great thinker is a fragment
of the ultimate ancestral being.
It's a fragment of, of
God the father, let's say.
And you get a fragment from Nicha and
you get a fragment from Plato and you get
a fragment from Vichtenstein and you get
a fragment from Shakespeare and, and,
and there's something,
imagine this,
there's something that makes
all those people great.
It's whatever greatness is
and it's broken up apart.
It's broken up across all of them.
But if you went, if you experience,
if you're exposed to each of them,
then you absorb what's your,
you're exposed to and have the
possibility to imitate it and absorb that
greatness across its, its fragmentation
across many people. And then you can,
that can come to awaken that within you.
And that is the purpose of
the universities. And the
reason for that, it isn't,
it isn't something casual. It's like,
well it's, it's, it's good to be more.
If you go to university and
you take a humanities degree,
you'll come out more well rounded. You
know, that's, that's not the, that's not,
it's such, it's such a weak way
of putting it. It's that no,
you wake up and realize who you are and
then you're ready to take the world on
your shoulders.
And that's what the universities are here.
And that's what students,
students are dying for. That,
that's why men are abandoning
the universities is because
that call isn't there.
Yes. Well there's just no answer
to the call. You might say the,
it seems to me that the
wave is the longing,
the longing for that call to be answered.
And it seems to be that
there are universities that
have failed us and utterly
failed. They're antithetical.
Do you might call them the,
the water main that is distributing
a worldview that is corrosive of,
of, of, of, of what is best in the human
being? Well, the, the, the doctrine.
So one of the fundamental
doctrines of the,
of the collectivists leftist,
especially on the feminist end of things,
is the idea that western culture
is a patriarchal tyranny.
And so first of all, we could say, well,
that's inappropriate psychologically
because the way that you represent culture
architecturally is with the
tyrant and the wise king.
And so you can say that there's
the tyrant and that's always true.
But you also have to say that there's
the wise king, but there's no wise king.
There's only a tyrant. Okay. And that
tyrant is, that's all men. It's all male.
And so, and so then, and so
that's a view of history, right?
Is that the view of history is that,
well,
women have been the primary force of
oppression in relationship to women
throughout history has been men.
No idea about the cooperative endeavor
of men and women or their mutual desire
to lift each other out of misery,
which is a much more accurate way of
representing history and a much more
grateful, inappropriate way. None of that.
No one's a patriarchal tyranny and
men are responsible. Okay, well,
so where does that leave young men?
Well,
let's say young men are attempting to
manifest competence in the world and to
become good people. Well, there's
no good and there's no competence.
There's only power and it's
related to the patriarchal tyranny.
And so that conflation
of competence with power,
which is an absolutely
pathological move in my estimation,
is also the desire to discourage
and to devalue and to destroy.
And partly it's based on fear
because the idea would be, well,
a fully fledged man is nothing but a
powerful tyrant and therefore dangerous,
better to emasculate him completely.
So it's nothing but harmless.
Even though he's useless,
he can't do anything that's bad,
which is an unbelievably horrifying,
that's the castrating mother,
the Friday and castrating mother.
That's the terrible element of, of the,
of the female body politic.
That's the evil queen.
That's the counterpart to the evil
king. Something we never talk about. So,
and that's what's facing young men is
that at least they're discouraged from
becoming what they could be. Um,
yeah, at least they're not encouraged,
but it's worse than that.
They're actively discouraged.
And so the universities have become,
they've become institutions of active
discouragement and especially for men.
And so what's the consequence of that?
Well,
especially in the humanities and
social sciences. Well, it's obvious.
All you have to do is look at the
statistics. All the men are leaving.
There won't be a man left
in the humanities and social
sciences in 15 years at
the current rate of, of gender
transformation of the disciplines.
And then you see this equally appalling
phenomena occurring phenomenon occurring,
which is that virtually all of the female
dominated disciplines are politically
correct.
And I think that the reason for that is
that the reasonable women don't know how
to regulate the behavior
of the unreasonable women.
The benevolent queen can't regulate the
evil queen and that and that hatred for
the patriarchy.
That's the feminist part of the
postmodern neo Marxist monster is,
is has decided that he masculine
[inaudible] and weak men are preferable to
tyrants and,
but,
and those are the only options because
there's no such thing as genuine
competence. What do you want to
call young men forward to do?
Is to take their place and say,
look,
you have to understand
it's not just about you,
is the world will be a lesser
place without, without that,
which you could reveal to it
because of your particular rarity.
And that whole that you leave by the
absence of your presence is going to be
filled with something terrible,
not just something neutral,
but something terrible. And
that's on you. And so you, you,
you have a calling that's,
that's vital. And, and people,
people need that. They are die. They die.
Yes.
It seems to me that the ideology that's
dominant and very much of the university
is not only destructive
and all these ways,
but chess boring and that it's patent
inadequacy to our deepest human longings,
male, female of, of,
of all of all races and kinds that the
deep transcendent longings that we all
have, the need for self
longing, for self knowledge,
that that idiotic elegy is,
it is patently inadequate
to at satisfaction.
And what I see in young people
today, many, many young pills,
I know you see this in the
thousands that you encounter is,
is they're not interested in
fighting some cultural war.
They simply want to discover
the deepest truth of themselves.
And, um, so I want to ask you a little
bit about, about the role of education.
We talked about the lighting up and the,
the awakening,
the encounter with depth
and truth. Um, you know,
there's a certain kind of abstract view
of education as though it's a kind of
inert process. So you're just sort
of downloading into the, into the,
into the mind. But in fact,
the nature, yeah, sure. Of
our, of our, of our, of our,
the nature of our souls is that,
that it's
an, it's a dynamic reality. You know,
the room who's not just the room,
it's the place in which you would, you
encounter yourself in the, in, in the,
in the rule of clean up your room.
But it seems to me that
that's what's going on in, in,
in all education at its best,
and that it's not enough simply for the
library to be there. Their needs there,
certain mediation of the institution.
So for example, we could have,
there's a piano in the other side of
this room, you know, we could say, well,
there's a piano, you're free to play the
piano. Uh, but I, I can't play the piano.
I don't know the cords and the
scales. I haven't, I haven't.
And yet if I, if I, if I did all that,
then what I can make happen on the piano
is infinitely richer than if I've never
learned to play the piano.
And I suppose,
I suppose when we talk about rescuing
the values of the treasure trove
discipline as the precondition
for freedom. Yes. Right?
Which is, which is, uh,
which is actually a Nietzschean idea,
at least in part.
I mean it's older than that.
It's the apprenticeship idea.
It's that it's that before,
before you can be a painter who can
paint what's beyond mere memory,
you, you have to inculcate
that discipline skill.
And a lot of that is painful
repetition and hard grinding work.
It's the sacrifice of the present for
the future. But once you manage that,
then things open up and virtually
everything you learn to value is like,
that's very, very, very difficult to
learn to write. And there's arbitrary,
arbitrary rules that you have
to follow and bind yourself to.
And while you're learning those rules,
the probability that you have any creative
freedom to speak of or any facility
with the rules is very low. You're
a, you're a rank beginner and,
and even to some degree,
whatever creativity you have is
going to have to be stifled. Well,
you're passing through that, that
key hole. But if you pass through it,
then something massive
opens up on the other side.
And it is definitely the case
that disciplinary institutions,
universities are exactly that
is their places of guidance and,
and their places to encourage people to
develop the discipline that's necessary
to see beyond the discipline. I mean
that's why we have disciplines, right?
I mean the words aren't there by accident.
You have to narrow yourself first
and then you can broaden outward.
And so that's, and that's part of the
process of maturation, that part of the,
that's part of the sacrifice of childhood.
Say in childhood you're
nothing but potential,
but it's not realized and you
don't know how to realize it.
And so then the question is,
well,
how do you get to a point where
you realize the potential?
And the answer is you sacrifice almost
all of it to a single direction.
This is niches,
commentary on the Catholic Church because
he a great admirer of the Catholic
Church, despite the fact that
he was also a radical critic.
Critic of Christianity said the cow.
The thing about the Catholic church
is that it forced everything to be
interpreted within a single
explanatory framework.
And that was a discipline.
And once that discipline was established,
then the discipline mind
could in every direction,
which is precisely what
happened. And so, and, and,
and that's the thing about growing up is
that when you're a teenager and a young
adult,
you have to sacrifice everything.
You could have been as a child to be
the one thing that you're aiming at.
But then that opens up and
the universities are part
and parcel of that process
and you need the guidance because the,
the,
the library is too large to wonder
through it unaided. Yes. And that,
and I think that comes down to, to the,
to the question of, of what you need to,
what are, what are the books that can be
read to be transformative. I mean we, we,
you know, the, the,
the otherness that realizes in
that awakens and opens up the self,
that light that turns those lights on
is not just a random otherness. I mean,
you can look at a brick wall
all day and never get anything.
Like would we get by looking at the
king's chapel that we just came from a few
minutes ago, that, that the,
the levels of pattern and depths and
beauty that are present in that building,
that's a kind of metaphor
for what the most wonderful,
most contexts of our own,
of our own past offered to us. You know,
they're, they are lying on the shelf,
but when opened up,
uh, and explored fully,
they open up in us the,
there are portals.
So I suppose in my book a book
isn't a paper. Yes, that's
you, that's your memory.
That's your perception of the book. It's
a portal. Yes. And, and, and you know,
one of the ideas,
the postmodern idea is that well,
there's no canon and if there is a
canon and it's only there to support the
tyrannical patriarchy because of
course the tyrannical patriarchy is the
explanation for everything.
But I've been trying to solve
that problem technically with,
I have a small staff that trying to
produce an educational system online and
we'd been trying to understand, well
what is it that makes a book canonical?
There's actually a
technical answer to that.
So you imagine that books exist
in relationship to one another.
That's a perfectly reasonable
postmodernist claim by the way.
Books exist in relationship
to one another. Okay,
well some books have hardly any
relationship to other books.
Those are trivial books. Now they
might be undiscovered works of genius.
That's another possibility
if there recently written,
but it doesn't matter because you can't
separate the wheat from the chaff at
present. It's too difficult.
There's too much chaff.
But if you go back into the past,
you can rank order books by the degree
to which they've influenced other books.
So it's like citations in some sense.
And the books that have influenced the
largest number of other books are the
canonical books and the
ultimate canonical book.
And the West is clearly the biblical
corpus because it's influenced virtually
everything.
And so you have to know it because
it's implicit in everything else.
And so you start there
and so you have that,
you have that knowledge at least to some
degree. And it gives you the foundation,
the metaphorical foundation,
the conceptual foundation,
the mythical foundation
that you can use to then,
well maybe you can now that now
Shakespeare opens up to some degree of now
Milton opens up to some degree in Dante,
opens up to some degree and you think,
well,
why should those open up and answer as
well as the social constructionist claim?
You're at least in part
a historical creature.
Well then those books are about you.
They're the,
the patterns in those books are the
patterns of your perceptions and your
actions. And without understanding
them, then you don't know who you are.
And you can't guide yourself properly
through life. And so you, you,
you come into university and you
encounter experts and they say, look,
this is canonical.
Why?
Because it's had a disproportionate
influence on everything else. So you need,
there's something here that you need to
know about because it's about you. And,
and it isn't about the
you that's here now.
In some sense it's about the you
that can unfold across time in the,
in the best possible way. So each of
those works is a call to adventure.
Every painting that's a great painting
or a building like that. King's chapel.
If that's not a call to adventure,
I mean, what else could it be?
We were talking about that.
So these ancient buildings,
these great ancient buildings
that Europe is littered with,
these were people would, we're aiming
at something beyond themselves,
beyond the span of their lifetime.
They,
they engaged in the co the collective
manifestation of these great works to aim,
to, to, to participate in aiming something
that at something that was beyond them.
It was a divine aim.
They had that,
that will to produce this beauty
that transcended centuries. You know,
and maybe the will that produces
beauty is always aligned with that,
which transcends centuries. Maybe those
are the same things. He even paintings,
oil paintings, you know, they,
they take a moment in time and they cast
it into a permanent form that can be,
it can be preserved across centuries.
And so there's something about,
there's something about the establishing
a relationship with eternity that's key
to the construction of
something that's beautiful.
And then that in itself becomes a call
to a relationship with an eternity. So,
and you need that people hunger for it.
I'm at the University of Toronto,
there's the, the, there's the European
cathedrals side of the campus,
the older part.
And then there's the modern factory side
of the campus and it's sold deadening.
My building is made out of cinder blocks,
you know, and my, my brother in law,
who's his own sort of genius
calls that hosel architecture,
anything could happen there and you
could wash it away. And it's like,
and it's just, it's, it's, it's,
I have my students now and then sit in
a classroom like that and look at it and
tell me how it makes them feel. Random
wires hanging from the ceiling, you know,
nothing but cinderblock the
cheapest form of construction.
Nothing that's beautiful, pure, boring,
dull utilitarianism with these bare
shiny desks and terrible fluorescent
lighting. It's like it's ugly, right to
the core and it, and it's corrosive. It
eats away at the heart of the university,
which is about the beauty that's eternal.
And,
and that isn't optional.
It's not impractical. It's,
it's the most practical. It's, it's,
it's that upon which the idea of
practicality itself is predicated.
And that's the university.
And people should be flocking to the
university's dying to be educated because
they are dying to be educated.
I have dozens of young men who come to
me all the time after my talks and say,
look, they give me a note. When
did last night, here's the note,
six weeks, six months ago, I was deeply
suicidal. I had no reason to live.
I was completely nihilistic, said,
I started watching your lectures.
I started to adopt a
more responsible outlook.
I realized that that was important.
I started to try to tell the
truth and to put myself together.
And without that I wouldn't be here.
And that's a little note.
And that happens over and over,
you know?
And then I go talk to journalists
and this happened in Scandinavia.
It happened with his GQ interview.
I just did.
While your message is primarily
directed towards young men, so I can,
there's this judgment about that. It's
like, oh, there's a problem with that.
Is there, I mean that wasn't the point,
but that is the audience is what,
there's something,
there's something wrong with talking
to young men and encouraging them.
It's like that makes me somehow somehow
suspicious the hatred of humanity that
is present in that critique is
mindblowing. It, it's, it's, it's,
it's absolutely beyond belief
and you think, well, it's
only misogyny. It's like,
no, it's not. It's like what?
Who are you leaving for the
women to have as partners?
These did demolished and week,
whether it's a zero sum quality of it.
I mean as if, as if, as if lifting up any
human being is not a good for all of us.
I mean there's the whole point about the
necessity of our care for the oppressed
is because they are part of us know
you only care about them in groups.
The individual impressed
person is irrelevant.
It's the group of oppressed
people that's relevant.
And so if you just help one
person, no. Well you see then,
then that's, that's that,
that, that flies at the heart
of the collectivist doctrine.
You said something very,
very powerful when you talked about
the people should be flocking to the
universities.
You're in an image that comes to
my mind is the image of a fountain.
And know people come to the
fountain to drink, to slake
their thirst. And, and, and,
and,
and it seems to me that we need,
we need new institutions
of higher education.
That's the fountain of living
water. Yes. Yes. Moses.
That's why Moses is a master
of water in the desert.
So we thought a master
of stone mass. Yes. Yes.
And one thing that really
excites me, Jordan, is that,
is that what we see right now is, is this
longing. There's so many thirsty people,
it seems to me we simply need to,
to build new fountains because as you
say, the books are in the library. We can,
we can,
we can give a rebirth to the past in the
form of the hunger and thirst that are
in young people simply by feeding
it. And that, it seems to me that,
that there's a kind of
cultural pacivity, particularly when it
comes to the university. People say, Oh,
well, you know, you could never do
anything about that. Well, you know,
the university, they're just, well, you
just have to kind of write them off. Well,
why don't you have to do that? Why
can't we start new ones? People,
there've been thousands of universities
started over over two years,
come into the university and they've
got this facade of cynicism. You know,
that partly because they haven't had
great experiences with the educational
system and it's no wonder partly,
but it goes all the way back to the,
to the beginning.
Yes.
I mean you've talked about this in dating
in your booklet into the university to
interrupt,
but that the,
what moves in in the whole k to 12
educational system in a certain sense,
was founded with in large part to bring
about that collectivist control and to,
to stultify. And to annihilate the,
the, the freedom of the individual.
And so that's,
that's pretty well ingrained.
By the time someone comes to university
and no wonder they don't like it,
they don't think they like educational
institutes as swab and then,
but they're still desperate enough
to come and they might say, well,
I'm doing this practically because I
needed a degree to get a job, which is,
you know, as perfectly reasonable.
It's perfectly reasonable as a,
as a fragmentary ambition.
It's a good fragmentary ambition,
but their, their, their,
their core is dying for something
deeper than that. And they're coming,
they're coming to university. The way
that you enter a cathedral properly,
if you enter it properly, they
come prayerfully. They're hoping,
but they won't talk to anyone
about it. They're hoping, God,
I hope that what I need is here.
And if you provide that,
then they're just overwhelmed by it.
And,
and then they're motivated to,
to work and to move and to put themselves
together because it doesn't take much
water on to really transform a part
surface. And these young people,
they have their cynical facade and it's
easy to be intimidated by that because
they're, they're judgmental in
their lectures, in your lectures,
and maybe they're not paying attention
and they're snapping gum in there playing
with their computers,
but there,
there is part of them that's at the
back listening and hoping that something
will emerge that will captivate them and
when that happens then well then well
then that's when it becomes something
absolutely remarkable to be an educator
because then you're providing guidance
and you're providing the guidance that
that's, that's well that's,
that's, that's the bread,
that's more than mere material brand
and then the students are extraordinary,
extraordinarily rewarding to work with
because there are so, it's not pleased.
It's way more than pleased.
They're so engaged by what's happening
that the whole thing comes alive. That's,
that's when it's a great thing
to be an educator. And what,
it's been great for me to go
on this lecture tour because,
which is why I keep doing it is
because every evening it's like that.
I get 2,500 people in an auditorium and
I start talking about the things we've
been talking about it. Everybody's
dead silent and they're locked onto it.
And it's an unbelievably gratifying
process. And then people come up and say,
you know, oh, this has
been so useful to me.
Things were so terrible and
falling apart in so many ways.
And like all of a sudden I'm just
stacking these things up and putting them
together. So interesting watching the
young men who come in and talk to me,
and it's, it's young women as well. Well
in North Idaho, always just so young, uh,
many of the women come and say thank you
very much for what you've done for my
sons for example.
But the men come up and they say,
it's like they're telling me a secret,
you know?
And it's the sort of secret that you'd
only tell an intimate friend that you
trusted. It's like, you know,
man, I wasn't doing so well.
And these are often rough looking
guys. You know, they say, look,
I've been really trying to
get my act together. You know,
I've been working it out with
my wife and I, I've been,
I've been trying to get my relationship
with my son straightened out.
And here's my father by the way.
He came along with me and we're getting
along just fine and it's really working
and they say it hushed voice, you
know, and they say thank you very much.
And I say, great, that's so great. I'm
so thrilled to hear that. And they,
they're telling me that because they're
hoping that I would in fact be thrilled
to hear that because they want to tell
it to someone who would be thrilled to
hear it. And I am thrilled to hear
it because I do believe that the,
that redemption is something
that is accomplished at the
level of the individual.
And every time you hear someone say,
um,
that they've, they're, they'd
oriented themselves properly.
It's like a bell rings in
heaven to exactly that and so,
well, so, well, so that's absolutely,
and chronically overwhelming,
but it's,
it's absolutely remarkable to see this,
to see how much desperation
there is for this.
When I talk to audiences about the
relationship between responsibility and
meaning, they inevitably go dead silent.
There's not a, there's not a Russell,
there's not a cough. It's like, is
that the secret? Is that the secret?
Is that it's the voluntary
adoption of responsibility?
It's like, well, that's the,
that's the central message of the West.
It's like to pick up your cross and it
and know and everyone's been told that,
but they don't know what it means because
if it's not being articulated enough
so that it becomes something
that's practical, it's like, yes,
look at the terrible responsibilities
you have right in front of you.
Your family is hurting, you're in
trouble. There's problems in the world.
It's like all of that's right there and
all you have to do is all you have to do
is take responsibility for it and
then you've got what you need.
All of a sudden think, oh, that's
what I needed. I didn't know that.
I thought that was something to avoid.
It's an impediment to short term,
hedonistic pleasure, you know,
went to happiness. There's
nothing happiness about,
happy about lifting the suffering
of the world. Onto your shoulders.
It's like this is way,
way better than happiness isn't
what you feel in the king's chapel.
It's something so magnificent that
happiness pales in comparison.
So it's, it's, it's thin,
grool happiness and young people know
they're pursuing hedonistic pleasure and
you know,
no wonder,
but there's nothing in it that sustaining
and all it does is make you cynical.
It's like is that's all there is
another one night stand, another,
another binge party.
You know,
and it's not like I have anything
against in principle against some of that
exuberant,
youthful hedonism.
But, but it's, it's not. If, look,
the universities have turned into
places of parties, why? Well,
because that's what the students find
best to do there. Well, that's not good.
What you want to offer them as a
reason to not party. It's like, no,
you got to understand, you
come to this class, hung over.
You're not going to be able to get it.
You don't go on to be
able to write properly.
You're going to pay a price
for that hedonism. It's like,
and the price will be too high
for you to bear. It's like,
oh well nef hedonism for me. Then I'm
like, I've got something important to do.
That's the way out of that.
But that,
that thing that's more important has
to be offered and it can be offered.
So when I've seen it happen over
and over to people and it's, it's,
it's extraordinarily good for them.
If you're an addict,
and I've talked to many
people who are addicted,
you need a reason to stop being addicted,
which means you need something
better than the drug.
Well that's what you offer at
universities. It's something better.
It's something better than everything
else. And if you're not offering that,
then it's all a facade. It's all
a factory, a knowledge factory,
which is the modern university
factory knowledge factory products.
It seems to me. And we'll conclude
here, I think momentarily,
it seems to me that that the time is ripe
for a radical in beautiful rebirth of
a more fully human culture.
And when I hear you speak Jordan,
about your lectures and you know what,
what moves me deeply is,
is the,
the love that you have for
the people who come to you.
And I suppose I want to just
conclude on a question, uh,
about,
I want to conclude on
an optimistic note by,
by drawing out what's in that love.
It's that the potential that is,
that lies in those,
in each and every individual
for deep transformation,
for connection to the transcendent
and, and, and, and, and, and,
and just to talk about that, that
longing, that seems to me that, that,
that longing is overwhelming.
And if only we can start to,
can refill the fountains with
water or build new fountains,
that the possibilities are beyond our
imagining for the point we're at right at
the moment. Yeah. That's what partly
why this is an inflection point too,
because so many things
that are transforming the
landscape of possibility is
opening up to us in a way that it,
it never has,
partly because of our
technological transformations.
And so the importance of
the particularities of our
ethical choices are becoming
more and more exaggerated because
while we're going to build artificial
intelligence and it's going
to be a reflection of us,
and so we better make sure that it
reflects the part of us that we want
reflected.
And you talked about that care for people
as they care for me is predicated on
my realization that I
prefer heaven to hell.
Having done what I could to explore hell,
let's say in my academic career
and in my private life and in my,
and in my clinical practice,
and to see what's there that unnecessary
suffering and not malevolence is like,
well, it would be best to move away
from that towards something better.
That's something I genuinely
believe that it's, it's,
it's for the best for
everything that we aim up.
And then when I see someone decide
to aim up, I think, well that's,
that's something that's one more step
away from hell. It's not just the,
it's not just the climbing up the hill
painfully towards the city of God.
It's move away from the abyss.
And I think it's easier for
people to believe in the abyss.
It was for me to believe in the existence
of malevolence and apocalypse and
catastrophe. I mean, all you have to do
study history to believe that they call.
Not that anything,
but that a way from that,
while away from that is a
morphous, right? It's, it's again,
it's like Moses leading his people from,
from the tyranny in Egypt. It's like,
well, where are we going?
Well away from that,
well, that's into the desert
and that's where we are now.
Well, that's not so good,
but at least it's a way from
that. Well, that's something,
but then there's something
beyond that. It's like, well,
what is it that we're striving
towards and and well, we,
we can each imagine that in our own way
in some sense, but I would say, well,
you start locally,
it's like fix up what you can fix up.
When you see a problem that announces
itself to you, a small problem,
that's your problem that you could fix.
That's your one step forward.
Take it.
Yes. It seems to me, in addition to
that, that life of the individual, we'd,
we need to think very broadly about the
institutional life that supports all of
that individual realization and freedom.
We need to think about universities
when you think about our architecture,
we need to think about that
is to say that, that the,
the whole horizon that lies
before us needs to be considered
for the fullness of possibility that,
that it holds.
And that those possibilities are
not realizable simply by, you know,
this individual doing this
and that and are doing that.
But that they also require a kind of,
um,
it requires that we think about the
whole and that we allow to give birth.
We allow to come into being the
kinds of institutional lives,
institutional life that,
um,
upon which our realization upon
which that awakening depends.
And so it's simply can't
be simply a matter of,
of our living our lives and
a kind of solitary way. No.
Or thinking about what do
we know what to think about,
what are the fountains on which,
you know, if we're in the desert,
it seems to me that, that, okay, so
we're in the desert. It's a, it's a,
it's a lonely and dry place,
but there are the dirty of fragments or
the narrative that the Israelites come
to worship the false idols because the
narrative fragments and that is the PR
precisely the moment paradoxically
at which we can rediscover ourselves,
what our, what our nature,
what our longing is for.
And so it seems to me that we're at
a time of astonishing possibility,
but that we must take it up.
Well, hopefully, you know,
when you train graduate students and
new train undergraduates, you know,
you orient them towards the truth and
then they learn to teach in accordance
with that and that,
and that facilitates the process that
we're describing and that they regard the
relationship with individual students
as a of paramount importance.
And see the teaching is something that's
noble and the research as well. Yes, yes.
The awakening of each
particular individual.
It's an educational institution
is precisely what allows
them to go on in 10,000
ways in 1,000 thousand ways throughout
their lives to to to transmit and open up
those transcendent possibilities.
Thank you Jordan. Very much.
My pleasure.