Hello?
Uh,
my name is Boris Chamber and we produce,
uh,
with,
the agenda at Tvo.
And I'm speaking with Jordan Peterson.
I'm a clinical psychologist and
professor of psychology at University of
Toronto and the security duration of our
conversation that we started a month
ago,
uh,
about his new project.
But your honesty project,
I called 42.
So reminders,
uh,
it,
Justin,
what the book is about.
Well,
the book,
I wrote a little article for an online
site.
He responds to questions about rules to
live by,
and the site's called Cora.
And you could post any question or any
answer on Cora.
And so for awhile I was kind of
interested in answering core questions
and I answered that one.
I came up with a list of 42 rules,
which is probably more than he bargained
for,
but the list became my core standards
quite popular.
So,
um,
I talked to an agent book agent that I
have been working with in Vancouver
about the possibility of working it up
into a book.
And so that's,
that's the origin story of this
particular project.
So last time we talked about about,
uh,
those items on your list would seem less
than absolutely serious that to do with
the reasons for why it is that we need
to make one of our rules,
uh,
beautiful.
Uh,
they had to do with skateboarders and
the respect they deserve and I such
items.
And today I would like to switch the
gears a bit and,
uh,
talk about perhaps the one item on your
list,
uh,
which,
which betrays a hint of a theme that
seems to be missing in the book,
which is the theme is death.
And the last item on your list,
the item number 42,
is be grateful in spite of your
suffering,
uh,
how much of that suffering that you are
referring to has to do with the,
uh,
inevitability of death.
It's broader than that.
I think in some ways.
I mean,
there's,
if there's a large psychological
literature on the human terror of death,
but I think that the people who think
that human beings are afraid of death
are,
are far too optimistic.
Okay.
We're afraid of a lot more than death.
We're afraid of degeneration and
deterioration and pain and betrayal and
insanity and death.
And you know,
you could say that death is the most
frightening of those,
but it isn't because otherwise people
wouldn't commit suicide.
Not to the extent that that has
universal as opposed to the other items
that you have mentioned.
Uh,
it doesn't,
uh,
that fair represents a kind of a
extension of frame that a,
that involves all of us.
Well,
I think it's,
I think the frame is better
conceptualized as vulnerability with
death being a sub element of that.
You know,
and I'm not trying to make light of the
universality of death obviously,
but,
but it's a broader category of problem
and when you're trying to address a
problem that that's,
that's that serious,
it's very important to get the
terminology perfectly straight.
You know what I mean?
People's relationship with death is
rather ambivalent because I'm mean,
there are any number of documented and
continue in cases of people putting
their lives on the line for things they
believe in.
So,
you know,
you could also make the case that the
absence of meaning is a more terrifying
prospect than the possibility of death.
So,
but regardless of old out there,
there's still something fundamental at
the bottom of this,
which is addressed by that particular,
um,
rule,
which is to be grateful in spite of your
suffering.
And the rule there is that the fact that
people bump up against their own
limitations and their own
vulnerabilities means that life is
characterized in an,
in a way that's,
it's not fundamentally addressable or
removable by suffering.
And that's Buddhists dictate,
right?
The Great Buddhist dictate is that life
is suffering.
But,
and people think of that as a
pessimistic claim.
And in one way it is.
But,
but I should point out too,
that that claim isn't limited among
religious thinkers to Buddhists.
I mean the,
the,
the primary symbol of Christianity is a
crucified person.
The relationship between that suffering
seems fairly self evident,
especially when you also consider the
drama of the crucifixion was also
accompanied by betrayal and,
and torture before death.
You know?
So it's kind of like the ultimate in
catastrophic stories.
And of course,
Judaism concentrates to a large degree
on a history of suffering and the way,
the manner in which that might be
addressed.
So with regards to being grateful,
well,
you might say,
how can you be grateful as if your life
is characterized by the necessity of
suffering?
Well,
that needs to be stepped through.
Very thoughtful.
So the first thing is,
why are you doomed to suffer?
Like,
why is life set up so that people are
due to suffer?
That's a constant existential complaint
that sort of echoes through the
centuries.
I mean,
you hear it in different ways.
Why do good things happen to bad people,
I suppose is the most cliched way of,
of formulating the problem.
But there's some deep answers to this
question,
like really deep answers and they're
really helpful.
And so one of them is,
and I learned this partly from reading
Jewish thought on the matter.
And at the moment,
I can't tell you what the sources were,
but I read two things that were really
helpful to me when I was trying to sort
this out.
And one was a common buyer,
uh,
Jewish commentator I think from the
Talmud who said that it was pc.
He made a,
he presented a riddle,
which is kind of like a Zen Koan.
You know,
Zen Koan is like the sound of one hand
clapping just that actually this,
so it's,
you know,
it's not that mysterious,
but the question was it was about the
nature of God.
And so the question runs,
if God is omniscient,
omnipresent and omnipotent,
which is sort of like the,
the,
the way that totality is being broken
down into its sub elements,
what could he possibly lock and answer?
That is limitation.
And so then there's a,
there's a corollary to that to that is
also derived from Jewish thought that
runs that man in God or in the sense
twins,
they're like poles on a continuum and
god is the infinite end of the continuum
and man is the fine idea.
Now the problem with the problem with
being without limitation is that there's
no,
okay,
there's no journey,
there's no transformation,
there's no change,
there's no progress,
there's no plot,
there's nothing interesting.
There's no differentiation between
things because everything can be
anything at any moment.
And so the point of this Jewish line of
thinking is that limitation is a
blessing because it allows for being
without limitation.
There's no being.
So that's okay.
So that's a hell of an observation.
Without limitation,
there's no big.
So then the next question might be,
well,
if,
if being necessitates limitation and
limitation generates suffering,
then maybe being is not something to be
respected,
are devoutly hoped for.
And that's been examined very carefully
to,
so for example,
Mephistopheles the character girth
girth,
this character in false Mephistopheles
who's obviously the devil,
his basic credo is that because limited
being produced as suffering,
it should be eradicated because it,
and the same argument is sort of made by
Ivan in the brothers Karamazov he
basically says,
well look,
the world's a corrupt place because
there's all these limited beings running
around in their suffering like mad.
Maybe it'd be better if the whole thing
was just done away with.
Well,
unless you think that's a good idea.
And apparently there have been people
who have,
it seems to be a really bad idea.
But then you might ask,
well,
what's the alternative?
And the alternative hypothetically is to
figure out a way of life that's
intrinsically meaningful enough so that
the suffering is justified,
not so that it can go away.
And I think that the core,
the purpose of religious thinking and
the,
and the goal towards which it's directed
is to outline a motive being that
justifies the suffering that life
entails.
And so if you live properly from a
religious perspective,
then the suffering is not so burdensome
that it warps and,
and corrupts you.
And part of that is to be grateful.
Could have been,
as I say,
that the purpose of religious thought as
to reconcile us to the fact of that.
Well,
yes,
religious thought is often criticized
thoughtlessly for that.
So for example,
this kind of started most mostly with
the Marxist send the Floridians back at
the end of the 19th century.
So,
you know,
Freud believed that religion was a
defense against death,
death,
anxiety.
He thought about it as an infant title
defense.
You know that people were afraid of
death and because of that they stayed
infantiles and regarded,
you know,
generated a delusional hypothesis about
the world being analogous to something
being taken care of by an all knowing
and all loving father who was going to
pay us back for all the terrible
limitations of suffering.
Being Freud thought about that is very
instant title.
And then at the same time,
Marx thought of religion from a
defensive perspective as the opiate of
the masses,
right?
Is that religion was something that the
powers that be promoted because it in
Europe,
people to the suffering that was a
necessary consequence.
Well for marks at least of capitalist
development.
And you know,
those critiques were extremely powerful.
They dominated 20th century thought,
but they're,
they're fairly shallow.
Yeah.
But they are by their reasons why they
were accepted.
I mean,
it's hard because they're half true.
Well,
no by,
but I would say it's more than that.
I mean,
I think,
I think that they,
uh,
obviously,
meant to offer people a sense of,
uh,
of,
of their own life somehow.
The idea of individualism and then
social mastery of,
of human affairs,
uh,
was to when there has independent of the
shackles of,
of uh,
religious,
uh,
dependents.
Yeah.
That worked really well.
We ran from the shackles dependence into
the shackles of video,
logical dependents.
No,
I,
I'm,
I'm with you on that.
But still,
when ideas take as widely and as deeply
as atheism has,
it means since pills at role,
it's not a false idea.
Oh yeah.
It's not like this was a trivial
conflict and I'm not trying to
trivialize either fried your marks.
Like I think Marx was fundamentally
corrupt,
but I don't think that if Freud,
I think the Freudian criticism is an
extremely deep one,
but it's,
it's,
it is basically half true.
I mean,
one of the things that Charles Taylor
pointed out,
Taylor zone,
philosopher Miguel and he wrote a book
called,
I think it was called the sources of the
self.
What?
I mean,
he took Freud's argument depart and he
said,
well,
that's all well and good.
If you,
you know,
you can think of religious belief as a
naive,
optimistic defense against death
anxiety,
let's say,
except that the facts don't bear that
out.
Because in Christianity,
for example,
in the middle,
the Middle Ages,
and later there are people who are
powerfully terrified of hell.
And I mean,
it's one thing to be afraid of death,
but if you believe in hell,
hell is a lot worse than death.
And so you might say,
well,
if you're going to conjure up a whole
religion just to make you feel good
about the fact that you know,
to help you deal with the fact that
you're going to die,
why bother conjuring up a hell that you
can suffer in forever if you make even
the slightest moral error.
And then,
you know,
that waits for you in infinitely.
And you know,
you'd have to be really cynical to say,
well,
you have to put something sour in the
medicine to make it believable.
It's like,
it's not like that at all.
But the develop medieval Christians were
terrified of hell.
Like modern people are terrified of
meaninglessness.
So you can't put at religions feet the
proposition of some simplistic antidote
to the fear of death.
That's I know what Freud why for I did
that and I think that religious belief
like any beliefs can be used in an
infant title manner,
but as a deep criticism of religion,
it's lacking and that's partly why you
own in Freud eventually parted ways,
you know,
because you'll notice that there was
more to religion than defense and that
that has to do with this suffering issue
because,
because the antidote to suffering has
meaning.
Now some of that meaning can be
encapsulated in religious belief and
that's sort of like the traditional
guide to meaning,
but if meaning is pursued properly,
then people don't get corrupted by their
suffering and that actually diminishes
the net total of suffering,
which is a really big,
that's a really big gain.
If you think suffering is the basic
problem,
you certainly don't want to approach it
in a way that makes it worse.
Like it's,
it's,
that's not an acceptable philosophical
argument.
If something's bad and you and you
believe it's bad,
you are not allowed to use an antidote
that makes that thing works.
If,
if you're going to play that game,
then people have to stop talking to you
because you're violating the principle
of noncontradiction and that's the basic
principle for community.
Without that principle,
communication cannot take place.
So you,
if you play that game,
you have to complete that by yourself in
a corner.
You can't actually have a discussion
with anybody if you've been to play that
game.
Now the gratitude issue is deeper too
because one of the things that's pointed
out,
for example in genesis in the second
chapter of Genesis or the second story
of Genesis,
that's the story of Cain and Abel
Caine's big problem is that he's not
grateful.
He's really resentful and Cain enabler
in some ways.
The first two people and Keynes,
a good guy and sort of like the model
for good guys and Cain is a bad guy and
he's the model for bad guys.
They're sort of like Christ and Satan in
their nascent forms and keynes.
Big problem is that he's resentful and
it really doesn't work out well.
That makes him the first murderer.
It also makes him the ancestor of the
first person who makes tools of war.
And so the in gratitude be characterized
as Kane.
I mean cane basically shakes his fist at
God and says,
you know,
what sort of
is there for a reason.
It's not meaning an accidental,
that appearance.
I mean,
Cain and Abel are what they are because
they intended to provide us with
bookends of human possibilities.
Like cain.
Cain makes the strongest possible
rational argument for the
meaninglessness of life.
He's just like Ivan in the brothers
Karamazov like,
and one of the really,
one of the things that's really
deceitful,
deceitful about rationality is that
rationality also claims that it can be
used to justify lights and it can't,
rationality can be used to take life
apart and to demolish its meaning,
but it can't be used to.
It can't be used as an antidote against
meaninglessness.
It's too narrow a conduit.
And Jordan,
what's your thinking on the queer by,
by the question of whether on uh,
we are today more or less afraid of that
than we used to have been,
let's say 20 years ago.
Any thoughts on this?
Objects?
I think that we are in some ways and
we're not in some ways,
so we are in some ways because we don't
really have to deal with it like people
once did.
And I think that a good thing or bad
thing,
no,
I don't think it's a good thing at all.
I think it keeps us permanently
immature.
I think it's a bad thing.
I mean all of,
all of the material that I've read that
deals with such issues in a deep way
suggests that the way that you overcome
your fear of something is by voluntarily
confronting it,
not by running away from it.
And I give you an example.
I had a client once who was terrified of
death.
And when I say terrifying to death,
I mean terrified of death.
This woman tried to force herself into
unconsciousness using various
pharmacological means for like 20 hours
a day for 10 years because she,
she thought life was so unbearable that
she didn't even want to be awake for it.
And she was a vegetarian because partly
because she couldn't,
she couldn't even tolerate walking into
a butcher store like,
so she,
she was,
she was too terrified.
And I mean,
I took her to a bunch of store at one
point and watched her,
I mean,
which is a,
it's a classic approach in psychotherapy
to have people come to confront the
things they're afraid of,
but she was so terrified of death that
it made it impossible for her to live.
Now what happened with her eventually
guided by her dreams because her dream
suggested what to do.
I took her to a embalming human and
momming,
you know,
uh,
a great reburial preparation and well
the first thing that happened was,
although she was absolutely terrified to
go there and didn't think that she would
be able to angle it and like it's not a
trivial thing cause we were only about
eight feet away from the embalming and
it was just her and me and the person
who was doing me and mommy and I mean
it's a pretty,
it's not one of,
it's a,
it's a pretty visceral experience,
let's put it that way.
And you know,
she looked away a lot during the
procedure for the first 15 minutes or
so,
but,
but she didn't leave.
Then after 15 minutes or so,
she was able to focus on the procedure
pretty closely.
And at one point she was even able to
lay your hand on the body.
I mean she had a glove on and it was all
very carefully done and that was really
useful to her cause it kind of
calibrated her in some way.
It taught her the difference between
what there is to be afraid of.
That's real.
And all the shades and nightmares that
people encounter that are just in some
ways there,
you know,
demonic or pathological figments of
their imagination.
It was also very useful to me because I
haven't done a lot of looking at a
human.
The caucus,
well,
I'm very squeamish.
I wouldn't say that I'm actually very
sensitive to discussed.
It's a biological proclivity and so this
is part of me.
I could have never been a surgeon than I
would.
I would have a very difficult time
dealing with people,
people's physiological trouble,
you know,
I don't have the stomach for it,
but it was really useful for me to go to
the funeral home.
Not so much because I viewed the moment,
but because it gave me a chance to talk
through the processes that are
associated with depth,
with someone who deals with it on a
regular basis.
You know,
if human beings,
primary fear was death,
there wouldn't be any funeral home
operators.
How the hell could they manage it?
Well when I talked to the guys about
that too,
you know,
and about how they,
what sort of effect dealing with death
on a nonstop basis had on their lives
and how they viewed the role.
And you know,
they view their role in some ways as
shepherds,
right?
They were shepherding people through the
process of death,
which throws everything up in the air.
And they were there to ritualize it in a
way,
and they took that responsibility
seriously.
But it was also useful to me to figure
out exactly what the practical steps
were involved in dealing with death.
Because at some point you're going to
have that responsibility.
Someone close to you is going to die.
And at that point you're either going to
run around,
you know,
in a complete neurotic fit and be more
trouble than you're worth.
Are you going to step up to the plate
and be helpful and um,
you know,
and be strong and help the people who
have to deal with that catastrophe,
do it in a straightforward manner.
And that's a,
that's a responsibility that people
have.
And to be a complete human being,
you have to be strong enough to do that
and you're not going to be that way if
you run away from it.
The thing about people is they're
stronger than the fear of death.
Death is terrible,
but we're stronger than that.
You had the reason to think about is
some,
some weeks or months ago we had a bit of
health problem and you didn't know what
it was or you thought that was worse
than it actually was.
And,
and you told me that you were thinking
about possibility of dying.
Yeah,
well I hadn't,
I had a lung shadow on a,
on an x ray and which I thought was,
you know,
radiological error or something similar.
But then for unrelated reasons,
a month and a half or so later,
yeah,
I started to get short of breath and
then my energy level's declined
precipitously and I thought,
Huh,
that's not a great combination.
Lung Shadow plus cancer symptoms,
you know?
So
some days thinking about that by the
possibility of,
of much to premature demise,
how,
how would you think,
uh,
what were your thoughts like?
Well,
the first thing I should say is that's
not unfamiliar territory for me.
You know,
I spent like really I spent,
when I was writing my first book,
I spent like a decade thinking about
death.
And I mean it was really in some ways an
obsession.
It was more the book's about me and not
about death.
But as you already pointed out,
those two things are very tightly
linked.
I mean,
for,
for months,
years,
even the first thought I had on waking
up was,
uh,
life is short.
You know,
I was very,
very conscious of time passing by and,
and potentially time passing by in a
meaningless and useless manner.
Now why that was the case,
God only knows,
you know,
it's very difficult to understand what
tribes are most spontaneous motivation.
You wouldn't have to go with the federal
fee for that,
you know?
Well,
I did,
but you know,
it was,
I just happened to be conducting the
therapy.
You can do a lot of therapy by reading
and by thinking and bike riding.
And I mean,
there's a technical literature on that.
Writing is unbelievably therapeutic.
It makes you healthier
the way you managed to think about the
possibility of an early death.
Yeah.
Well I mean what was,
there was an element of black humor to
it I think,
which is something that's often,
it's like the source of black humor
really.
Cause there's an absurdity about death,
right?
Because within the sort of human domain
of striving through our rules,
which has been,
if you work hard and you do the right
thing,
then good things happen to you.
It's like a game.
You're playing.
The game has these rules and if you play
it properly then you get the benefits.
But death is something that's sort of
outside the rules of all games and
whether you've been playing the game
properly or not,
it doesn't have that much effect on your
ultimate vulnerability.
And so there's a,
there's an absurdity about that,
you know,
having come this far to be cut down,
at 50 cause I'm,
I'm 50 seemed absurd.
And so there was that element,
although I'm kind of used to absurdity
in a way.
So that didn't bother me so much.
But what really bothered me,
I think it wasn't so much the
contemplation of my own disappearance as
what I would miss,
you know?
And,
and what the consequences of that would
also be for my family.
You know,
because when you leave,
you leave a hole and that's unpleasant
hope.
Hopefully it's up and you miss things.
And that's a tragedy.
I mean,
and you know,
so I had to,
I had to sort through that.
I guess it made it more personal.
I'm curious about this concern for the
wellbeing of uh,
uh,
you know,
Tammy,
your wife and your children.
Um,
Eh,
when you,
did you feel that,
that,
were you afraid?
I mean,
we're,
we're terrified of,
of,
uh,
of losing touch with that,
which is kind of the only true reality,
you know,
because,
uh,
or did you do have an access to thoughts
and feelings about the possibility of an
afterlife?
Okay.
First of all,
we mean the world is a very strange
place.
And for me,
ignorance,
one of the things about humility,
let's say something that's associated to
some degree with gratitude.
Humility is recognition of your,
of your ignorance.
And limits and people think that
recognition of your ignorance and limits
is a frightening thing.
So they often act in a narcissistic way
and lay claim to more knowledge than
they have,
but there comes a point if you think
things through that the fact that you're
ignorant is a great comfort.
Okay,
okay.
You know,
I mean for me to be properly terrified
and death in the sort of the classic
way,
I would have to assume that I knew what
life meant and how,
why and how it is that we're here and
how our consciousness operates and what
the relationship is between
consciousness and material reality and
how time works and what's the
relationship between the present and
infinity and like not only do we not
understand those things,
we don't understand them at all.
We don't understand consciousness at
all.
We know,
for example,
the physicists have taught us that
there's an intake or relationship
between consciousness and the
manifestation of the transformation of
possibility into actuality.
Consciousness transforms actuality into
our potentiality to actuality,
and it does that literally in that
before something is consciously
perceived.
It exists as like a set of
possibilities,
none of which are specified.
And it isn't till consciousness observes
it,
that it snaps into actual being.
This isn't metaphysics,
this is quantum physics and quantum
physics is why we're talking to one
another and underlies all the
electronics we use.
It underlies everything.
And it's the only scientific theory that
we've ever produced but has never made a
prediction error.
So it's as right as things get with
regards to an afterlife.
I mean,
I've had strange experiences that have
taught me things about the potential
nature of consciousness and,
and so that makes me unwilling to make
any final claims about what's immortal
and what's mortal and how those things
are related and how I'm tangled up in
that.
I don't know,
but I'm so ignorant about that,
that I can't say it really terrifies me.
There was the one thing is
okay
and obviously interesting about,
about being modern living,
you know,
uh,
at the beginning of the 21st century is
that,
is that so many of us have grown up
without any reliance on the thought of
the possibility of afterlife.
Uh,
though,
though what's also interesting is that
we also living in a time when there are
many,
uh,
people who increasingly imagine the
possibility of extending the lifespan of
consciousness,
if not of the physical bodies by,
by the process of,
of,
uh,
by imagining that consciousness can be
digitized and,
and,
and that can be then uploaded or
downloaded into,
into,
uh,
add the vehicles of life rather than the
uploaded into our digital reality where
there's at least 26 digital virgins
waiting for you.
I think that's the ultimate,
the number is 76,
seven.
Okay.
What,
do you have any response to that
proposition that that is possible to
imagine consciousness to be made,
to be a tonal?
I think it's silly,
technically silly because there's just
so many things it doesn't take into
account.
Like it's based on a very peculiar
apprehension of what constitutes
consciousness.
Like it's a shallow,
it's a shallow approach to a deep
problem.
So for example,
we,
it seems that consciousness requires
embodiment.
Now,
you know,
modern Kwanzaa,
I atheists have the idea that sort of
alerts at the bottom of their thinking
that the soul is sort of like a,
it's sort of like a disembodied ghost.
It looks like a body,
but you can see through it and have some
of the attributes of a body because
otherwise it couldn't exist.
But like it's very vague and ill
defined.
And so,
okay,
you're going to upload your
consciousness.
Okay,
fine.
So what exactly are you uploading?
You're not blowing,
you're not blowing your anxiety.
You can upload your pain,
you cannot devote your hunger.
Are you going to upload your sexual
desire or are going to be free of all of
that?
Okay,
well you want to be free of all that.
Well,
what are you then,
what's left of you?
If your limitations are all gone,
That's a weird thing because you think,
well,
if your limitations are all gone,
then you're,
you're without limitation.
It's like the genie has escaped from
the,
from the little lamp.
Well you need the lamp.
No,
no lab,
no genie.
So you're an upload your consciousness.
Oh yeah.
And then what are you going to do,
you know,
sit inside a computer,
why you can have any motivation to do
anything.
Because like your motivation,
we know your motivation is all tied
intrinsically to your physiology.
So,
so it's,
it's like to me that the engineers who
talk about it's Marvin minsky mostly
he's talked about uploading and Curt
Swan.
Yeah,
but it's from,
it's from Mitski essentially.
It's like there's lots of things that
are smart about engineers,
but metaphysical philosophy is not one
of them.
And so I read that stuff and I think
like
you guys are as bad at talking about
Meta physics as postmodernist humanists
are talking about engineering.
Like you should just stay out of it
because it's your,
the,
the approach.
I think the approach is basically
equivalent to that.
That characterizes a really curious and
precocious 13 year old.
There's no real thinking that goes along
with it.
It's like a dream while we could upload
our consciousness into a machine.
Well that's a dream.
It's a myth.
It's like the myth of the Golem or the
myth of Frankenstein.
Obviously,
if we can only transcend this body and
put ourselves into something else was
like,
sorry guys,
you're gonna have to do a lot more
thinking about that issue before you can
have an intelligent discussion about it.
Uh,
Jordan,
we will stop now because I think we've
talked long enough and the next time,
uh,
whatever that's going to be,
we will then talk about next topic,
which we then managed to squeeze into
this one,
which is we just have to think about the
future.
I want to say one more thing,
just talk
part of what I was this little,
this 42 exercises is sort of an
exercise.
I'm hoping that will involve the mapping
of very deep ideas onto sort of everyday
issues cause deep ideas should be
related to everyday issues in a niche
like indirectly because everyday things
are deep.
Now the viewpoint,
like
we've talked about this before,
you and I privately but,
but it,
it's something that has to be stated in
order to make this kind of conversation
intelligible.
I am not a materialist.
Like some people say that but they don't
mean it.
But I mean it,
I don't think the most real things of
the world,
our material,
and I think the fact that we think that
they are makes us ill.
That's existential illness.
It's actually an illness and the reason
it's an illness is it speak it because
it's predicated on a view of the world
that's solely incomplete that it can't
function.
Now,
one of the pieces of evidence that it
can't function is people's existential
angst and the fact that they're driven
to find systems of meaning,
especially in the 20th century that were
extremely pathological.
They're driven into the arms of
pathological replacements.
There's an alternative,
like if you're not a materialist,
you have to pause it.
That something else.
Is that the ground of being cause it's
material for materialists.
Even though if you look into material
hard enough like the quantum physicists
do,
it turns into something that's so unlike
material that you know you might as well
not if you've been bothered with the
whole materialism to begin with because
if you think religion is weird,
you know you should read quantum physics
for a while.
I don't think that material is the most
real thing.
I think the most real thing is meaning.
And I think that meaning is a real
thing.
Not only that,
it's real,
that it's the most real thing.
And I also think that you're set up
physiologically,
materially if you want all the evidence
is that your physiology responds to
meaning and not to material reality.
That's when,
when we talk about the future,
we'll talk about that a little bit more
because when you interact with the
future,
what you're interacting with is the
meaning of possibilities.
That is what the future is.
It's the meaning of possibilities.
And I don't mean that metaphorically.
I mean that literally,
and not only do I mean that literally,
I mean biologically in that that's what
your brain does.
Your brain apprehends the mirror,
yet meaningful possibilities of the
multiple futures that could manifest
themselves.
And that's what you interact with.
And modern people are so dopey.
They think they interact with material
and that makes them sick.
That idea because it's,
it's not a sustaining idea and they
don't even act that way.
They say things like,
well,
you know,
you have to make the most of your
potential.
And then they don't even notice that
they're saying something that's entirely
nonsensical from a materialist
perspective.
It's like,
what the hell is this potential that
you're talking about?
You can't measure it.
It only exists in possibility.
It only exists as something you could
conceivably bring into being or
interfere with.
Even though everyone knows that,
you know,
not living up to your po possibility and
not fulfilling potential is a great sin.
No one notices that.
You just can't say something like that
and be a materialist.
We will,
we will continue this next time and we
talk about the multiple futures,
uh,
but for the time being,
thanks Jordan and see you again.