So I,
I know you can't tell,
but you're looking at a new and improved
version of me today because I just
finished the Canadian government's
online ethics course and so my,
my capacity to manifest ethical behavior
has been improved by an immeasurable
amount.
So.
Okay,
so today we're gonna.
Talk about something that's actually
quite controversial,
although I guess what we talked about
last lecture was rather controversial to
people hate this topic generally
speaking,
and it's because like there's nothing
ever.
There's never any guarantee that if you
investigate things from a scientific
perspective that you're going to learn
things that you want to learn or that
you're happy about knowing or that you
wish were that way.
I mean,
I would say one of the big advantages to
the scientific method is that it
presents you with data that you don't
like.
Okay.
Be Most of the time when you learn
something,
it's because you're running into
something that you don't like or don't
want,
right?
Because otherwise,
when the world is unfolding in front of
you,
exactly as you predict and hope there's
nothing to learn,
you almost always run into an impediment
of one form or another before you ever
learn anything.
So we're going to talk about openness
today,
how that sounds rather innocuous in and
of itself,
but the problem is is that
openness is the place in the big five
were Iq hides,
especially
nonverbal Iq,
which is most specifically associated
with fluid Iq.
How?
The thing about intelligence is that
it's not like the big five,
it's unit dimensional in most regards,
so you know if you do the proper factor
analysis with the entire Corpus of trait
descriptors in language,
you end up with five dimensions.
There's no superordinate single
dimension.
You can make a case for plasticity and
stability,
but the actual utility of that higher
order factor structure has yet to be
demonstrated in a multiplicity of
situations.
We have some evidence for with regards
to plasticity and stability.
That plasticity is predicted more by
what people do and stability is much
more predicted by what people don't do.
Now I don't know how useful that is.
I mean it's kind of an interesting fact.
It was an incredibly powerful effect,
but
I'm plasticity seems to be associated
more with exploratory behavior and
perhaps with dopaminergic function and
stability,
perhaps more with the control and
constraint of behavior and Sarah Tender
Jake function,
but it's still pretty vague,
so you can certainly make a case for
the.
For the hierarchy of factor structure
with regards to trades to of top out at
the five factor level with some
possibility of a of an informative level
above that
ideal isn't like that.
It's pretty damn unit dimensional and
it's complicated because there does seem
to be some utility in,
in distinguishing between verbal and
nonverbal intelligence or fluid in
crystallized intelligence depending on
how you look at it.
And I think the distinction is basically
this is the fluid intelligence roughly
is a measure of how rapidly you can
learn things and then crystallized
intelligence roughly is an indication of
how much you've learned and then you can
see why those two things would be very
highly correlated.
Right?
Because how much you know is obviously
going to be a function of how fast you
can learn,
but you could also see that there would
be some circumstances under which those
two things could be dissociated.
So one of the things that happens,
for example,
as you get older,
your fluid Iq drops quite precipitously
and it starts doing that somewhere in
your mid twenties.
So there's some of you are already
getting stupider,
which is kind of annoying at least from
the perspective of the ability to learn,
but you're crystallized Iq or your
verbal Iq depending on how you look at
it,
can continue to rise for the rest of
your life as you put more information
into yourself,
so to speak.
And some of that might be a measurement
artifact somewhat because the way that
you test verbal or crystallized
intelligence generally is by asking
people about their knowledge of
something.
Maybe it's their vocabulary,
for example,
which is an excellent measure of verbal
intelligence as you might expect,
probably because it's an index of how
much people read.
That would be my guess or general
inflammation tests.
Um,
which is what a sample of your required
factual knowledge and so forth,
um,
that sort of thing can increase as you,
as you age,
as your ability to learn,
decreases the best way.
By the way,
if you want to keep your intelligence in
tact,
the best way to do that is to,
uh,
to exercise just so you know it.
Um,
both weightlifting and
cardiovascular exercise can maintain
your fluid intelligence to quite a
remarkable degree across the course of
your life.
And the reason for that likely is that
your brain is a pretty vascularized
Oregon and use uses a tremendous amount
of your body's oxygen and energy.
And so if your cardiovascular system
isn't in that good a shape than what
seems to happen is that it's harder for
your brain to get rid of waste products
that are produced during.
It's during it's metabolic processes.
And so you can't work as efficiently.
There's not a lot of evidence that brain
games of one form or another can produce
any real positive effect.
Although they're scattered reports in
the literature that video games can
improve,
that can improve spatial intelligence,
which is a subset of intelligence,
even though it's very highly correlated
with fluid intelligence in domains other
than the game.
Usually what happens if you.
If you get people to develop expertise
at a game that requires abstract
ability,
like a video game,
what happens is they get tremendously
better at the thing that they're
practicing,
but there doesn't seem to be a lot of
transfer of ability to different games
and and what fluid intelligence is in
large part is what's common across
multiple.
The ability that's common across
multiple complex tasks,
whatever that ability happens to be.
Now we don't know exactly what that
ability is,
partly because we don't really know very
much about how the brain works,
but we definitely know how to measure it
and that irritates people.
So Iq fits under openness and the
terminology is still a little bit,
I would say awkward
for a while when people were trying to
sort out what the fifth factor was,
the openness factor.
Some people thought about it as
intellect and some people thought about
it as openness and it it ended up being
named openness.
When we did our aspect study back in
2007,
we broke it up into openness to
experience proper and intellect.
So those seem to be aspects of the
higher order trait and the aspect level
differentiation actually turned out to
be realm rather useful,
at least at least so far.
So one of the things we just published a
study for example,
showing that if you are higher in
openness to experience the aspect,
you were more likely to be in the
humanities and if you were hiring
intellect you are more likely to be in
the sciences for example.
So anyways,
what we'll do first is we're going to
talk a little bit about intelligence per
se,
and then we'll talk about the trait.
The reason I want to talk about Iq
really,
because really that's what I'm talking
about is because the best measure of the
intellect aspect isn't a big five
personality questionnaire.
It's actually an Iq test and so and it's
very,
very important to understand ICU and
there's a bunch of reasons for this.
First reason is that Iq is more
powerfully predictive of long term life
success than any other phenomena that
can be measured among human beings and
not only that,
the statistics that were derived
statistics that were used to derive Iq
tests and then use to predict future
performance are exactly the same
statistics that every social scientists,
particularly psychologists,
every social scientist uses to do all of
their statistics.
So you can't criticize that derivation
of Iq tests on statistical grounds
without criticizing every single finding
in psychology that's ever been made by
anyone ever since.
We started to use statistics and I would
say not only that,
the best statisticians that psychology
has ever produced are the people who
invented and promoted and developed and
tested Iq tests.
So there's no getting out of it by
saying that there's something,
something faulty about the statistics.
So for example,
Stephen Jay Gould,
who is a famous evolutionary biologist
and pretty radical left wing thinker.
He debated.
He had a public debate at one point
about what he called the mismeasure of
man because he wasn't very much of a fan
of Iq tests and he claimed that Iq tests
were faulty because they relied on
factor analysis and because basically
what Iq is is the first factor that you
draw out of a huge battery of questions
that require abstraction.
Any kinds of questions you'll find that
if people do well on one question,
they tend to do well at all the other
questions.
That's the general factor and he said,
well,
that's just a factor and that's means
it's a mathematical abstraction and that
means that it's not real.
It's like,
well,
first of all,
the first factor that you derive out of
the performance indices for our very
large number of answers to abstract
questions,
it's almost perfectly correlated with
the average.
The mean,
and so that's tantamount to saying that
the mean is a mathematical abstraction
and therefore doesn't really exist and
well.
Then you have a problem which is.
Well,
exactly.
What do you mean by exists?
Because you can certainly make a case
that mathematical abstractions are more
real than the thing that they're
abstracted from.
If that wasn't the case,
then mathematics wouldn't be so
powerful.
So basically Gould's argument boiled
down to the idea that there's no such
thing as an average.
Well,
this is part of what makes me a
pragmatist philosophically.
I mean there is such thing as an average
in so far as calculating the average and
then using it produces certain results
that you desire in order to deal with
the world.
Right?
So the average of a group of numbers is
a tool of some sort and you know,
it's obviously doesn't contain all the
information that the entire set of
numbers contained.
You need at least a standard deviation
to get at that as well because that
talks to you about the,
the range.
No,
the variability,
but the idea that the average isn't a
real thing is,
you know,
it's silly,
it's a,
it's a shallow criticism.
It's also based on complete lack of
knowledge about exactly what factor
analysis does and doesn't do.
So now
here's a list of some inter correlations
here between the various facets or the
various aspects,
just so you know how tightly associated
they are.
So industrious and industriousness and
orderliness or correlated at about point
four.
That's from conscientiousness,
volatility and emotional stability at
about point five,
nine.
Politeness and compassion out about
point four,
four.
Assertiveness and enthusiasm at about
point four slash seven.
And openness and intelligence about
point three five.
So openness and intelligence seemed to
be somewhat maximally differentiated as
far as aspects Go.
So the average correlation between the
big five is our equals point two,
two.
And the correlation between the big two
is our equals point to four.
So God just gives you some idea of how
much segregation and how much overlap
there is between the different aspects
underneath the trait level.
Let's see.
So
what I should really tell you first I
guess is how is how to conceptualize
ICU.
Yeah,
this is a good one.
So you want to follow this carefully so
that so that you,
you,
you can explain it to yourself and so
that you can explain it to other people.
So here,
let's say you want to make an Iq test,
so this is what an Iq test is.
The first thing you might imagine that
is that
you have a huge library of questions and
there'll be questions that could be
formulated in language or some other
symbolic manner.
Often they don't have to be but often,
and then they require skill or knowledge
to answer.
So here's some typical questions and you
can generate multiple exemplars of
questions like this.
What's two times 68?
What's the capital of Georgia?
How do you fight?
How do you define hyper tricks?
Anemia?
Um,
complete the pattern.
Two,
four,
eight,
16.
Remember these numbers?
Two,
four.
Then you'd tell them back to me,
six,
You tell them back to me.
That's a working memory task by the way.
But working memory is basically
indistinguishable from intelligence in
many,
many ways.
So then,
you know,
another thing I might have you do for
examples,
I might show you a pattern made out of
squares and then give you some blocks
and so that you could make the pattern
out of the blocks.
And then time you to see how long it
took you,
or maybe I'm only giving you a certain
amount of time and if you didn't do it,
then you either pass or fail.
Um,
I might show you some patterns.
This is like a Raven's progressive
matrices test,
which is one of the most tests that is
the most accurate at assessing nonverbal
intelligence or fluid intelligence.
So I might show you six patterns,
six designs.
Each design changes are,
sorry,
eight designs.
Imagine that,
three by three array,
three here,
two here,
and a question mark.
And then over here I'd show you a bunch
of options of patterns and one of the
patterns would complete the sequence and
usually you could calculate the sequence
going down or across and,
and diagonally as well.
And that looks somewhat like a working
memory task in that usually the Raven's
progressive matrices patterns involve a
couple of different variables,
like it might be color and shape or
something like that.
And so in order to complete the task,
you have to figure out how the color is
transforming and figure out how the
shape is transforming.
Or maybe in a more complex Raven's
matrices question,
it would be color,
shape and position on the page or
something like that.
So you're increasing the number of
dimensions that have to be attended to
simultaneously in order to solve the
problem.
So,
so one of the things that's quite
interesting about the Iq test,
it really doesn't matter what the
questions are and so.
So anyways,
so imagine you have a whole pile of
these questions lying around like a
universal pile,
well universal library of potential
questions that require abstraction to
solve.
And then you take a random set of 100 of
those and then you give that to a
thousand people and then you just score
some up there.
You just sum up their scores.
Then you rank order them in terms of
their performance.
And that's Iq.
It's as simple as that.
Now you could do some other things.
You could correct it for the age of the
participant.
Now sometimes that's useful and
sometimes it's not.
But you could do that.
And generally if you standardize the
score and you correct it for age than
what you get as an Iq score,
I would say so actually the the total
would just be an indicator of general
cognitive ability.
The IQ score would be the indicator of
general cognitive ability corrected for
age.
And that's it.
That's all.
And so here's some of the strange
properties of,
of,
of that set of scores.
If you factor analyze the data set,
you'll pull out one factor and a few
little bitty factors after that.
And that factor will be very,
very highly correlated with the sub so
correlated at point nine,
point nine,
two point nine,
three,
like really highly correlated,
far more highly correlated.
Then most tests are
far more highly correlated that most
tests are reliable.
Now another thing that's very
interesting is you've taken another set
of 100 questions and you give them to
the same thousand people and then you
rank order the people and then you
correlate the rank orders.
You get what I'm saying,
the correlation between the rank order.
So be like point nine five.
So what it means is no matter which set
of 100 questions you take out of this
universal library of questions,
people are going to score in the same
order that they scored when they did the
first hundred questions.
And that means that Iq is extremely
reliable,
test,
retest,
reliability.
This is actually even strip more
stringent form of reliability,
which is alternative forum reliability.
So that's all there is to our ICU.
It's very simple.
Now why it is that the ability to do
well on one of those questions is highly
correlated with the ability to do all
the rest of them.
That's something that nobody really
understands.
I think it has to do with the human
capacity to abstract.
Like we can abstract and we can
manipulate abstractions.
It's not obvious that there's any other
creatures that can do that and it seems
to be in some sense modular.
Anything that can be abstracted and then
manipulated draws on exactly the same
set of underlying skills.
Whatever those happen to be.
Now
you might say,
well,
so what?
Which is a perfectly reasonable thing to
say,
and so what is.
If you then take that rank quarter
and let's say you take the same thousand
people 20 years later and you rank order
them in terms of how well they're doing
their job,
you could just use income,
say as a marker,
there's other markers you could use,
but for the sake of simplicity,
let's say income,
the correlation between their original
rank order and the rank order of their
performance will be something around if
you had a full sample of intelligence,
be something around point five,
which is
point five is a staggeringly high
correlation,
so you know,
you'll hear that when you hear people
talk about effect sizes,
you'll hear them say that.
Point two is a small effect size and
point three is a medium effect.
Size and point.
Sorry,
point point five is a medium effect size
and so forth.
What you find out if you look at the
literature empirically is that point
effect.
Size is a point five correlations of
point five are vanishingly rare in the
social sciences.
If you ever do a study with a reasonable
number of people with a novel measure
and you're predicting something with it,
if you get a correlation of point five,
boy,
you're jumping around the room because
that's only gonna happen like once in
your life,
unless you're measuring something that
someone who has already measured and you
just don't know it.
And so it's,
it's fair.
It's a,
it's a reasonable to point out that the
correlation between Icu say and academic
performance or the correlation between
Iq and longterm career success,
the size of that correlation is bigger
than the correlation between virtually
to,
uh,
virtually any other things that social
scientists have ever discovered.
And the thing about it too is it's very
straightforward.
You know what the procedure that I just
told you,
anyone can replicate that.
You know,
you're not going to come up with a
universal library of obviously,
but you can use the internet as a
reasonable proxy.
So not only is Iq easy to understand
from a measurement perspective,
it's also the tests are very,
very easy to replicate in.
They're extremely powerful predictors.
Now it turns out actually that Iq is
correlated more strongly with how
rapidly you learn a task than it is with
your performance per se,
so the correlation between rate of
learning of something novel and Iq can
be as high as six or point seven,
which you know,
the other bit of that would probably be
taken up by something like
conscientiousness or openness or
negatively with emotional stability.
So you're picking up a tremendous amount
of the variation between in people's
performances with that single measure
and you can derive a pretty decent
indicator of Iq in 20 minutes,
which is also pretty frightening,
you know,
so.
Well.
So that's our cute.
Does anybody have any questions about
that?
Yes.
Well you have to formulate them in
language.
That's all.
Now a lot of people have complained
about the idea of intelligence because
they don't like the idea.
They don't really mind the idea so much
that there are smart people,
but people really don't like the idea
that are,
there are dumb people and you know,
it's,
it's really not reasonable from a
logical perspective to have one without
the other.
And it's easy to see why people object
to that because whatever term you use to
refer to the low end of the intelligence
distribution rapidly takes on a
pejorative nature.
So and so what happens is the culture
cycle through various words,
decade by decade,
trying to describe the lower end of the
intelligence distribution,
but all the words ended up being
pejorative.
And so they're,
they're changed decade after decade.
But you and you can understand that
because first of all,
there's great danger in labeling someone
unintelligent perhaps period.
But certainly if there's measurement
error,
you know,
so if you're labeled on intelligent,
let's say,
and you're not,
that's going to be real catastrophe.
So there's measurement error problems,
but then you know,
you have to think about the problems of
not doing the measurement.
So this is something I've thought about
for a long time.
So
let's say that I assessed your verbal Iq
before you came to the University of
Toronto.
Forget linguistic differences as soon we
control for that,
which is very difficult at the
University of Toronto because there's so
many people who have English as a second
language.
But forget about that for a minute.
Let's say I got a entire population
distribution,
not only of the applicants from the
University of Toronto but over the
entire population,
and I said categorically that the bottom
30 percent of the people in that
distribution would not be able to
graduate from the University of Toronto.
Am I doing them a favor by not letting
them apply or am I harming them
while we know perfectly well?
I mean the probability that there's
anybody in this room that has an Iq of
less than 115 is pretty damn low.
And if,
if there is someone in the room who's
general intelligence level is at that
level,
you can bloody well be sure they're
working like mad dogs in order to keep
up.
And I'm not saying that all of you who
have to work like mad dogs to keep up,
you know,
are,
are necessarily a lower than you might
be an ICU.
I'm just saying that because Iq and part
seems to be a measure of something like
processing speed or rate of
understanding or something like that.
If you're not in the upper echelons of
the distribution and you're tasked with
extraordinarily difficult tasks that
require abstraction and quick learning,
the only way that you can compensate for
it is by working to an incredible degree
and you can do that.
And that's also why at the University of
Toronto,
we know this perfectly well and it's
true in other educational institutions.
Um,
conscientiousness is almost as good a
predictor of grades as intelligence and
that only makes sense to me.
It's like who the hell is going to get
the good grades?
The smart people who work hard and I
mean,
it wouldn't be good if that wasn't the
case as far as I can tell,
because hopefully what you get when you
get a great is an indicator of how fast
you are,
how well you know,
the material and how much effort you've
put into learning it.
Something like that.
The relationship between creativity and
grades at the University of Toronto is
zero,
by the way,
once you control for Iq,
which is,
you know,
perhaps rather appalling.
But the problem is,
is that it's very difficult to assess
creative people,
right?
Because they're annoying,
creative people do things in a new way,
and the problem with trying to assess
whether or not someone has done saying
something in a new way is that you have
to come up with a new scheme of grading
for that and you can believe that's not
going to happen,
you know,
and then it's worse because if you're a
creative person and you're graded by
someone who isn't creative,
they're not going to think you're
creative,
they're just gonna think that you're
wrong.
And so,
and you might be,
because lots of times if you're
creative,
you're also wrong because it's not that
easy to come up with a novel way of
doing something or a novel hypothesis
that actually is going to be an
improvement over the previous
hypothesis.
Right?
Most of the time you're off on a tangent
and it's an incorrect tangent.
Now,
various people have criticized the idea
of a single intelligence and so they've
made.
And I guess the most famous ones
probably in last 15 years or 20 years
have been Robert Sternberg and,
uh,
Martin Gardner.
Martin Gardner is not a scientist by the
way at all.
Um,
he claims directly that he doesn't
really care if his intelligence,
his can be measured.
Well,
that's not that helpful because if
you're working as a scientist,
if what you're talking about can't be
measured,
then it doesn't exist and you can even
make a philosophical case.
I think that if what you're talking
about can't be measured in any possible
way,
that there's no sense in assuming that
it exists.
Now Gardener is posited,
intelligence is like linguistic,
musical,
logical,
mathematical,
spacial body,
kinesthetic,
interpersonal and interpersonal.
Um,
one thing you might note is that we
already have a perfectly good word for
all of those performance variability
across all those domains in so far as it
actually exists.
And that would be talent.
So there's no reason to confuse the word
talent with the word intelligence.
And the next thing that you might know
is that a lot of these so called
intelligences are likely captured not so
much by intelligence but by variability
in personality traits,
which we already understand.
And so to throw a bunch of new terms in
like linguistic,
musical,
logical,
mathematical,
spacial body,
kinesthetic,
interpersonal and intrapersonal.
All that does is muddy that conceptual
waters,
it,
it adds.
Now there's a reason for that,
and the reason is fundamentally
political and the political reason is is
that
it is uncomfortable for people to admit
that there might be something like
actual differences,
inability that are important and under
radical.
Now I can understand why people would
have trouble with that,
but consider the alternatives.
We know part of the reason that you're
here and we'll perhaps stay here and
will perhaps be successful in so far as
you can define success along the
dimension of career attainment,
say in your life as it unfolds from this
time onward is because you work hard.
Okay?
But we also know that part of the reason
that you're here is because you're
smart.
Now the question is,
what should you do with that from an
ethical perspective?
Exactly.
Should you say,
no,
I'm no smarter than anyone else,
which means that maybe you're much more
hardworking than everyone else,
so you're still,
you know,
denigrating the non achieving end of the
distribution.
Or do you say,
I've been blessed by something that's
actually beyond my control and I'm
privileged as a consequence of that,
and then decide what exactly that means
in terms of your responsibility.
Those are your choices,
but,
but to not take into account the fact
that you've been blessed at at least one
level of analysis with a favorable roll
of the die,
after the randomness dice seems to me
they completely misstate the nature of
the causal sequences that propel you
into what's essentially a position of
privilege.
So,
but that by denying the differences,
the innate differences in people with
regards to important abilities,
all you do is attribute all your success
to your own particular individual
controllable actions.
And I mean,
I'm not saying that you don't deserve
credit for your work.
It's like more power to you and all of
that,
but
the idea that some people are smarter
than others,
that's not an idea.
That's a fact.
And it's an uncomfortable fact.
And the fact that we won't deal with it
means that people suffer unnecessarily.
So let's go back to those people in the
distribution.
I say the bottom 30 percent of the
distribution isn't going to be able to
get a degree at the University of
Toronto,
um,
unless they are capable of working to an
insane level and even than likely not.
Um,
so let's say that you have a ability
blind admission process.
It's random.
So everybody's name,
ms dot thrown into a hat and if they get
pulled out,
they get to go.
You think that you're doing the people
who are going to fail a service
or not,
you know,
and now you could make a case that you
are because it's likely that they'll be
a couple of individuals in the bottom
part of the distribution who will make
it through partly because of measurement
error,
right?
Because you're not going to measure this
perfectly and partly because,
well,
people are surprising and amazing
creatures and you never know exactly
what any given one of them is going to
do,
but you're going to torture a lot of
them to death.
At the same time.
You know,
I've been struggling with this because
I've developed tests that help
employees.
Employers decide who might be competent,
more competent than who,
when they're hiring,
and that's partly dependent on general
cognitive ability and we think based on
the statistics,
the relevant statistics that we can
improve the probability that a given
employee employer will hire an above
average worker in a cognitively complex,
um,
for a cognitively complex job position
from 50 slash 50 to 75 slash 25 or 80
slash 20.
It's quite a lot,
but it's not.
Obviously there's still a,
there's still a fair margin of error
there,
but you know,
having half as many employees below
average is definitely going to be of
tremendous benefit to your company.
And you might say,
well that's unfair because there's going
to be measurement error too.
And
that's not the question.
The question is,
it is,
it is more unfair than to do it any
other way.
Well,
you could use interviews,
but tall,
good looking.
Extroverted people tend to do much
better on interviews than short,
ugly,
introverted people,
especially if they're a little bit on
the disagreeable side as well because
agreeable people also do better in
interviews.
So not only are they tremendously biased
in all of those dimensions,
they actually don't predict performance
in the long run very well at all.
So actually that means in the states
they are illegal,
you know,
although companies,
lawyers haven't woken up to this fact
yet,
but you're mandated by law in the United
States to use the most accurate,
valid and reliable current means of
hiring available and interviews are not
that and neither are letters of
recommendation which are pretty much as
bad.
They're not so much bias that letters of
recommendation,
they're just useless because you know,
except in so far as if you can't get
anyone to write you a letter of
recommendation at all,
well maybe that's an indication that
you're very,
you're not very socially skilled or that
you don't have a very good social
network or whatever.
So maybe as a really blunt indicator of
isolation,
you could derive some information out of
letters of recommendation.
But as far as valid indicators of future
performance,
they're just not valid at all.
It's partly why I hate writing them.
It's they're,
they're,
they're also illegal.
At least they are in the us,
even though people don't understand that
yet,
but I know the law and I know the
validity statistics,
so,
um,
and what you're required to do.
So then you might also ask,
um,
so the,
so the other selection methods are also
biased and unreliable.
You could say,
well,
you could hire someone based on their
academic history,
but roughly that's an index of
intelligence and conscientiousness
anyways,
it's just not a very good one,
especially because there's tremendous
variability between schools.
So if you have a,
you know,
a GPA of four point zero from school x
and this person has a gpa of four point
zero from school.
Why?
There's no reason at all to assume that
those are comparable.
So you can use grades,
but that's full of measurement error.
So that's not very good either.
So you could guess that it'll give you a
50 slash 50 in terms of your probability
of hiring someone who is above average
versus below average.
But,
um,
that doesn't seem to be a very
intelligent way of going about it either
because.
And here's,
here's something to think about.
So
let's assume that there are 10 people
working and,
uh,
inappropriate selection method places an
incompetent manager above them.
So maybe the manager is less intelligent
than the workers.
That might be one possibility or maybe
the managers less creative than the
workers are.
Maybe the manager is less conscientious
or whatever.
It doesn't matter.
Some dimension of competence is not well
matched with the demands of the job.
Well then one of the questions is what
exactly are you doing to the manager
while you're basically setting them up
to fail?
And the tremendous number of managers
fail in the first two years of their,
of their promotion.
It's,
it's well above 50 percent and so that's
not so good for them.
But then you're also doing the 10 people
that they're supervising to a kind of
horrible pr,
no perdition for the time it takes for
everyone to calculate that the manager
is actually failing.
And what that means generally is that
the very highly qualified people in the
work approval,
we'll just leave because why would they
put up with that?
So then you might think,
well,
is it unethical to select properly or is
it ethical to select randomly or exactly
how should you solve that problem?
And the answer is,
well,
we do try to solve it because we use
selection methods,
but we usually use ones that aren't very
accurate.
It's funny too because I tried selling
accurate selection tests to corporations
for a very long period of time and one
of the things I learned is they didn't
want them.
That was mind boggling to me because the
economic utility and hiring people who
are competent compared to people who
aren't so high,
it's absolutely mind boggling because
the difference in productivity between
people isn't even.
It isn't normally distributed.
It's Prieto distributed.
Some people are staggeringly more
productive than other people.
So tilting your selection criteria so
that you pick from the more productive
end of the distribution means incredibly
powerful economic benefits for your
company.
But
at least when I was doing this to begin
with human resources,
people who are usually the ones
evaluating the tests weren't necessarily
the most competent people in the
corporate environment.
Which is something that hasn't changed
very much.
They were very badly trained and they
believed that there were no differences
between people that couldn't be
eliminated with training,
which is like,
yeah,
no,
that's wrong as anybody,
if you have any sense at all and you
think about it for 15 or 20 seconds,
you know,
that's the case.
You know,
I don't know what it was like in your
school,
but in the school I went to,
which was way the hell up in northern
Alberta in the middle of no man's land,
you know,
there was at least 15 percent of the
students,
I would say it was probably higher who
are still functionally illiterate by the
time they hit grade 10.
Functional illiteracy being they had
never read an entire book.
And that's way more common than you
think.
Like,
I don't know how common you think that
is,
but the stats basically indicate there's
as many people with Iqs of 85 and lower
as there are people with Iqs of 115 and
higher.
So.
And I already said that the minimum Iq
level of anybody in this room is likely
to be something around 115.
So the person in this room who has the
lowest general cognitive ability is
smarter than 85 percent of the general
population at 85 and lower,
which is there's just as many people
there as there is at 115 and higher at
85 and lower then you don't get
literacy.
So people with Iqs of 90 or less have a
difficult time translating written words
into action so they can't really read
instructions.
So.
And that's like
10 percent of the population is 15
percent of the population,
actually 15 percent of the population.
And it's.
So you might say,
well no way.
It's like,
well you don't get to have an opinion on
this by the way,
because the science has already been
done.
But I can tell you one fact that's
pretty unsettling.
So the United States army has been doing
Iq testing on its recruits for since
before World War One.
They actually did a lot of the research
that established Iq tests and validated
them.
And indicated that they were reliable
and so forth,
and that a variety of reasons for doing
that,
um,
partly I guess they didn't want to put
in competent people in charge of deadly
machinery,
which does seem to be a reasonable
proposition,
I would say.
But what they found as a consequence of
their hundreds,
100 years of testing was that you
couldn't teach anybody with an Iq of 83
or lower anything at all that would make
them anything but an obstacle to the,
um,
tasks that the armed forces had to
complete on a regular basis.
So that's 83.
So now in the United States,
it's actually illegal to induct anyone
into the armed forces if they have an Iq
of 83 or lower.
And that's more than 10 percent of the
population.
Now you got to think about that because
what it means is that approximately 10
percent of the population is
sufficiently,
um,
has sufficiently low general cognitive
ability that
one of the
complex enterprises that's chronically
most desperate for manpower has decided
that there no point in even trying.
Now that's a dismal outcome.
But I don't know exactly what you're
supposed to do with that fact,
but ignoring it doesn't seem to me to be
the right thing because it doesn't solve
the problem and this is going to become
an increasingly and increasingly
present and and,
and unavoidable and ignorable problem.
Because you know already,
that's what's happening in developed
countries.
Less so in underdeveloped countries,
but in developed countries,
the gap between the rich and the poor is
increasing.
So for,
for example,
almost all of the increases in wealth
that have accrued to people in the last
20 years have accrued to people who are
in the top one percent of the
distribution of wealth.
And that's not going to stop by the way.
And part of the reason is,
is that cognitive power has become even
more valuable than it was four years
ago.
And the reason for that is computers
basically.
Because if you're really smart and
you're good with a computer,
you're way ahead of someone who isn't
very smart and who doesn't know how to
use computers at all and you're not just
a little bit ahead.
You're leaps and bounds ahead and worse
than that,
you're getting farther ahead all the
time and the reason for that is that
computational power keeps increasing and
it increases a lot.
It's doubling about every 18 months,
so part of the problem that the human
race is going to have to face in the
next 30 years along with many other
problems is what are you going to do
with people who have neither the
cognitive ability,
nor the conscientiousness to find a
niche in society that's actually that,
that other people will value enough to
pay for.
Because that's really the question.
What do you do?
Well,
the conservative answer to that as well,
there's a job for everyone.
It's like,
no,
that's wrong.
There isn't.
And the liberal answer is well,
everybody's the same,
so it's just a matter of training and
that's also wrong.
They're both.
Both of those positions are there.
The scientific research has rented them
permanently outdated.
Well,
you know,
there is the possibility of providing a
minimum income.
The,
the,
the question,
what will that do is completely
unanswerable.
We have no idea what it'll do.
You know what I mean?
It might start people from,
from starving to death,
although the,
I wouldn't say in North America,
that's generally not a problem people
have anyways,
but we don't know.
See,
I think of,
I think of human beings as pack animals
fundamentally.
You know,
on I and I,
this is just,
it's a metaphor in some sense.
I don't think that people can be happy
and less.
They are burdened down with something
like a sled dog is burdened down with
something you know,
you,
you have to have a responsibilities,
they have to be important
responsibilities.
You have to be sequenced in your time.
You know,
most of the people I have in my clinical
practice,
if they're not employed,
they just fall apart and the
conscientious ones fall apart because
they eat themselves up with shame and
guilt and the unconscientious ones fall
apart because their sleep schedule goes
all over the place.
They don't eat regularly,
regularly anymore.
They do all sorts of impulsive things
that are counterproductive and you know,
they just sort of spiral into a pool of
meaninglessness.
So human beings are pretty social and
we're pretty altruistic,
you know,
in,
in some weird manner,
and it,
it doesn't seem to me that people can
live a life that's
acceptable if all they have is enforced
leisure.
So maybe that'll be wrong if you
provided people with a base salary,
maybe people would figure out what to do
with their spare time.
But,
um,
I doubt it.
I don't think people are.
I think it's very,
very difficult for people to regulate
themselves in the absence of a certain
minimum of,
of social structuring and guidance.
I've seen very,
very few people who can conjure that up
on their own and manage it for extensive
periods of time.
I think I've only met one person,
I would say in my whole life,
who's actually managed that.
And that particular person has a very
large array of talents and is extremely
intelligent.
So.
All right,
so you might ask,
well,
what,
what exactly is intelligence?
Maybe what exactly is the ability to
abstract,
and I think it's something like this.
The world is made out of
the world is a very,
very high resolution place.
No matter how much you zoom into
something,
you can zoom in more.
There's information that more and more
and more and more levels of detail and
then also no matter how far you back
away from something,
there's more and more and more levels of
detail.
So you know you guys are composed of a
whole variety of sub systems,
complex functioning subsystems all the
way down to the subatomic level and then
above your phenomenal logical level of
perception.
You're members of families,
members of cities.
You're members of provinces and and
nationalities and international
organizations and ecological structures
and so forth and so on and all of that's
characteristic of you all the time and
in every situation,
but you don't deal with all that
information and you can't.
And so one of the things that people
seem to have learned how to do is to
abstract from that.
And I'm not exactly sure what it means
to abstract,
but it seems to me that it means
something that's similar to producing a
low resolution representations.
Like a thumbnail.
And so actually when I look at each of
you,
what I'm actually seeing is a thumbnail
of what you are.
No,
first of all,
obviously I don't see the other side of
you that or,
or either side for that matter.
I only see you face,
so on.
So in some sense it's a two dimensional,
um,
thumbnail.
And then I have no idea what's going on
in the subsystems that,
that constitute you at levels outside,
you know,
underneath your mirror surface.
That's a complex diagnostic problem.
For example,
if there was something wrong with you
and I can't see your families are except
in very low resolution ways,
your nationality or any of the systems
that you're identified with an embedded
in.
So just looking at you as an act of
abstraction,
you know,
and part of that thankfully is done by
the fact that our sensory systems just
aren't that good.
So there's a whole bunch of things we
can't perceive.
And that simplifies the problem.
Now what we're hoping is that I can
perceive enough of you at a given time
so that if I interact with you,
I get what I want.
And you get what you want,
roughly speaking,
it's something like that.
So what we hope is the model,
the abstract model even of perception
itself is sufficiently accurate so that
it's sufficiently,
it's a sufficiently unbiased sample of
the reality that it reflects so that if
I interact with it,
things work out the way that I would
like them to work out.
But there's lots of times when that
doesn't happen at all,
right?
It doesn't happen when you're sick.
The fact is that you're.
The resolution of your sensory apparatus
is a huge impediment to figuring out why
you might be ill,
you know,
and it doesn't help much either when
people are engaged in struggles that go
beyond the merely personal.
So if we happen to be,
if I happened to be the member of one
ethnic group and you happened to be the
member of another and there is strife
between those two ethnic groups than the
fact that I can perceive you at this
level of resolution might have very
little to do with my ability to solve
that particular problem.
Now obviously people can obstruct and
you know,
part of that's just built into us so
that we abstract the phenomena that we
see,
but then human beings,
I think in some sense are capable of
metta abstraction.
So I think what happens is you can
imagine that there's the phenomenon in
and of itself,
whatever that is,
that complicated multilayered thing
that's always in front of you and then
there's your representation of it,
which is what you perceive which is
already extracted to a tremendous degree
and limited to a tremendous degree.
And then there's abstractions of that.
So what seemed,
what it seems to me to be the is that
language is a thumbnail of images that
are a thumbnail of the reality of
things.
It's something like that.
So it's a dual compression.
So if I say to you,
you'll what,
what the word cat does for you is
produced the image of a generic cat,
which is already a kind of abstraction.
And then that's attached to your
understanding in some sense so that you
can.
You can generate the understanding that
would go along with at least in part
with perceiving or interacting with a
real cat,
so in some sense what you're doing is
I'm compressing the information down to
a tremendous Lee.
I'm a low resolution thumbnail and I'm
throwing that at you and you decompress
it into a low resolution image and then
you decompress that into something
that's roughly equivalent to reality.
That's what you're doing when you're
reading a book,
for example.
Right?
Because when you read the book,
you can conjure up images of the places
that the author is talking about.
You conjure up images of the characters
themselves,
so to such a degree that if you go see a
movie that's made of your favorite book,
you might be irritated because of the
person in the movie looks nothing like
the person that you read about,
at least as far as your imagination was
concerned.
Now intelligence in general seems to be
whatever underlies the ability to
generate those low resolution
representations to and to utilize them,
so that would mean to manipulate them in
your own mind,
but also to communicate them to others.
A big part of intelligence is working
memory and working memory is well,
while you're sitting there thinking
if you're thinking,
how many of you think in words primarily
as far as you're concerned.
So how many of you don't
thinking images?
Anybody?
Images?
Uh,
well that's another possibility.
How many of you think in words and
images?
Okay.
So,
so,
okay,
well that's fine.
You know,
the images are already a representation
and in many ways the words are a
representation of the images.
And so your ability to abstract and then
your ability to manipulate those
abstractions seems to be at the core of
whatever intelligence is.
And that's what Iq purports to measure.
Um,
your working memory.
So when you're,
if you sit there right now,
um,
so let's do this.
Here's the sentence to think about.
Okay?
Now think about that sentence.
So the faculty that you're using to
represent that sentence to yourself is
working memory and it's not very
powerful.
You can't contain very much in your
working memory.
Seven digits is about the maximum.
Now people vary.
Some people think that four bits of
information is actually the limit to
working memory.
Some people think it's closer to seven,
but it's not very much.
That's why telephone numbers tend to be
seven digits long,
so you can kind of easily remember seven
things,
which is not very many things,
you know,
so part of what your intelligence is,
the breadth of that working memory and
then the speed with which you can run
abstractions through it.
So now you know,
I've put a little map here up.
So the thing on the top left,
well that's sort of a multidimensional.
It's a scheme of a multidimensional
reality and I,
you know,
if you look at that,
what it is,
it's a collection of dots or circles
arrayed in a variety of different
arrays.
My proposition is that you can represent
that array in a variety of different
ways.
I've called them object one.
You can't see object to slide error
object three d object for an object
five.
Those are all low resolution
representations of the thing that's in
the top left hand corner.
And you can see that in some sense they
capture something important,
they capture some important element of
the thing in the top left hand corner,
but they don't capture all of it.
Now,
it might be that capturing all of it is
a good idea because you don't want to
use any more information than you have
to.
And then at the bottom,
well those are words or semantic symbols
of one form or another.
And they represent the representations.
Um,
I saw temple grandin speak once,
I don't remember if I told you about
this,
but she's a very famous autistic
researcher.
Um,
and she's quite autistic and she's very
fun to listen to.
Um,
she's quite a good public speaker,
which is quite remarkable.
Um,
she's trying to figure out,
she thinks that autistic people think
like animals and,
and she actually works with animals and
she seems to be very good at
understanding them.
Uh,
she believes that what things that
frightened her are the same thing that
frightens animals and for the same
reasons.
And so her proposition for example,
is that if I say the word church,
all of you people are going to have what
you might describe as a schematic,
abstraction like a hero glyphs that's
more or less representative of the class
of churches and so.
Or maybe I can say house kids are good
at this.
You see this house.
It's like it's got a little rectangle on
the top and it's got a kind of a square
on the bottom.
It's got a door and two windows and the
windows have crosses in them and there's
always a chimney on the top with smoke
coming out.
Which I think is quite remarkable
because you actually don't see that many
houses now that have chimneys with smoke
coming out.
But still that's the canonical image for
a child temple grandin's claim was that
she cannot see house.
She can only see a house.
And so if you say to her something like
house than what comes to mind is a
particular house that she's actually
experienced.
She can't take the next level of
abstraction past that,
which seems to be something like a
deficit in generating like a hero
glyphic image.
One of the ways to think about
children's drawings.
You know how they draw people with
sticks and circles.
You know,
you think,
oh,
that's so primitive.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's unbelievably sophisticated because
those aren't pictures.
They're here glyphic and the child
automatically produces them and that's a
protocol linguistic development.
So some autistic kids can draw like
Leonardo Davinci with no training
whatsoever and that's partly because
they don't use here glyphic and that
means that they don't really
conceptualize the thing they're looking
at as an abstraction.
They see nothing but detail and if
you're training yourself to be a visual
artists,
you have to stop looking at the
abstraction and you have to start
looking at the thing and that's very
unsettling.
So if you take your hand for example,
and you look at it and you snap it out
of hand representation,
when you do that property,
it all of a sudden it looks like some
kind of like octopus claw.
It's very bizarre looking thing and as
soon as you see it that way you can draw
it,
but as long as you're seeing it like a
hand,
you're going to put,
you know,
a,
a balloon with four balloons on it or
something like that.
And that's going to be the hand.
So,
all right.
This guy's name is John Carol.
Carol's a real scientist.
Um,
he looked at
the structure of Iq for a very long
period of time,
wrote a very thick book on it,
um,
which nobody likes to read because it's
almost entirely technical.
So it's really more of a reference book.
But what,
what Carol hypothesized and I think his
hypothesis is as close to state of the
arc as,
as any,
is that
there is a stratum three level which is
fluid intelligence
g,
and it's the main factor that unites all
these other tests.
And then net stratum one,
you get fluid intelligence,
crystallized intelligence,
verbal intelligence.
I don't remember what the rest of them
stand for.
And then each of those can be subdivided
into specific tests in each of the tests
can be subdivided into somewhat
particularized individual cognitive
abilities.
Now they're not that individual because
there's a single factor that accounts
for most of the variability in the
performance.
So
in a sense,
what this theory says is that the
intelligence is sum up to one
intelligence and that seems to be
essentially correct
this,
although you can't see it very well,
if you look at ge,
they're on the left,
the lines leading to the first or the.
I think that's the second strategy,
the next strata anyways,
show you the correlation between Ge and
each of the individual intelligence is.
And what you see is the correlation
between Ge and fluid intelligence is
point nine four,
which is such a tight correlation that
it might as well just be the thing
itself between
Ge and crystallized intelligence is
point eight,
five m all of the first order
correlations there above point eight.
That's exactly.
And then at the far right,
you get concepts that you might think
about as particularized.
And so those include concept formation,
analysis and synthesis number,
series number matrices,
spatial relations,
picture recognition,
block rotation,
visual matching,
decision speed,
um,
block rotation,
cross out visual and auditory learning,
memory for names,
sound blending,
incomplete word that would be incomplete
word completion,
sound patterns,
auditory attention,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
And you can think of those each as
individual tests in that you could make
a test that theoretically only
individually assessed that thing,
but you couldn't help but be testing all
sorts of other things at the same time
because they're not actually
individually.
One of the things you will learn
is that
there are neuro psychological tests and
the neuro psychologists like to think
that Iq is something that's primitive
and that they've already,
um,
what would you say advanced past.
And so they have specific
prefrontal tests say that hypothetically
assess specific prefrontal abilities.
And then they'll note that if you take a
single test of prefrontal ability and
correlated with Iq,
it'll only correlated about point three
or point four.
And then they'll assume because it only
correlates that low,
that it's measuring something other than
what Iq is measuring.
But really what happens is that it's
just not a very good Iq test and the
reason that the correlation is so low is
because of measurement error.
So if you gave the same test to the same
person 20 times and then you varied the
tasks so that were 30 variants of it and
you gave those all to the same person 20
times,
then what would come out would be a
score that would be much more highly
correlated with Iq and probably
indistinguishable from it.
And so you'll learn from
neuropsychologists that there's such a
thing as prefrontal ability and that's
associated with executive control and
that's associated with self regulation
which would be control over your
impulses.
And as far as I can tell,
that's all completely wrong.
And it took me like 10 years to figure
that out because I was taught that it
was right and it wasn't until I plow
through it painfully and understood that
there was no evidence for that.
So I can tell you how that works.
So for example,
we gave a neuro psych battery that
consisted of Dorsolateral prefrontal
test to 3000 people.
It was a 90 minute battery,
so it was exhaustive and when we factor
analyzed it,
when there was only about 200
participants,
we got four factors,
but then when we factor analyzed it
after we had 3000 participants,
we got two factors and one was one on
which almost all of the tests loaded and
it was undoubtedly fluid intelligence.
So,
but it's worse than that,
you know,
because you hear about how the
prefrontal cortex regulates behavior.
Well,
here's the problem with that.
What's the correlation between Iq and
conscientiousness?
Zero,
roughly speaking,
it's probably a little off zero,
although it might not be and you know
that because the dimensions of the big
five or roughly orthogonal I showed you
at the beginning of this,
that each trait of the big five traits
is correlated with the other trade on an
average of about point two.
Now why that is,
it's probably because of something like,
um,
what would you call?
It's probably a halo effect.
If you tend to rate yourself as positive
on one trait,
more conscientious,
more agreeable,
more emotionally stable,
you're going to tend to rate yourself as
more positive on the other traits,
so that would artificially inflate their
correlation.
That's one way of looking at it anyways.
Weirdly enough,
the correlation between
conscientiousness in ICU is essentially
zero.
Now,
that's a big problem,
isn't it?
It's unconscientious people that seem to
be behaviorally dysregulated,
right?
They can't stick to a task.
They,
they,
they jump about,
they're,
they're not on track.
They appear impulsive.
Although we don't know how to define
impulsive by the way,
but your hill psychologists use that all
the time.
It's like,
well,
if prefrontal ability regulates
behavior,
how come the correlation between
intelligence and other forms of
executive control are correlated with
conscientiousness at zero?
Right?
Zero is a very bad number when you're
testing out a hypothesis.
So,
and you know,
if you think about it,
it has to be that way and the reason it
has to be that way is this,
so if you're dreaming,
you're going to just lay there and
dream,
but your eyes are going to move back and
forth.
Now you might say,
why aren't you running around acting out
your dreams while you're dreaming?
And the answer to that is there's a
little switch in your head roughly
speaking,
that shuts off your motor apparatus when
you're dreaming.
And so what happens is you can't run
around and act out all your dreams
because you're paralyzed and sometimes
people wake up in that state.
It's called sleep paralysis.
They wake up,
they're sort of half awake and they
can't move,
and then they often hallucinate all
sorts of weird things and thinks aliens
have come and abducted them and various
peculiarities.
But if you take a cat and you take out
that little switch,
then the cattle run around while it's
dreaming,
until it runs into something which is
the problem with running around acting
out your dreams.
So what does that allow one to conclude?
Well,
if you couldn't abstract away from your
behavior,
you couldn't think right because what
thinking means is to represent an
alternative world or maybe just a tiny
little fraction of the world,
whatever,
to represent it abstractly to manipulate
it around,
but not to simultaneously acted out that
then it wouldn't be abstracting it all.
It would be fiddling about with the
world through trial and error.
So you have to be able to pull what you
think about out of your body,
so to speak,
play with it,
and then implement it back in.
Now it looks maybe like the ability to
implement a plan is associated with
conscientiousness,
but we don't understand that that would
be industriousness and we don't know a
bloody thing about industriousness like
it's just a black hole.
But the idea that it's your ability to
think that allows you to regulate your
behavior strikes.
Well,
there's no evidence for it.
There's no evidence for it.
Smart people are not necessarily better
at regulating their behavior.
So because for you can have a very
unconscientious smart person and I see
them in my clinical practice now and
then they come and say,
well,
I'm really smart and here's the
evidence,
but I'm doing very badly and everything.
They're under achievers roughly
speaking,
you know,
so they can't implement their thoughts
not in any stable manner.
So the fact that they're smart
on average across their life,
smart people are healthier mentally and
physically than people who aren't as
smart.
But the reason for that isn't because
their intelligence allows them to
regulate their health.
The reason for that is because their
intelligence allows them roughly
speaking to succeed.
So they're higher up in the dominance
hierarchy and if you're higher up in the
dominance hierarchy then your life isn't
as stressful and you don't get sick as
often.
But that doesn't indicate that there's a
direct control between your intelligence
and your behavioral output.
There's very little evidence for that.
Well,
I think there's no evidence for it.
So that's rather shocking.
So you know,
to me that just wiped out a whole a
whole substrata of psychological
theorizing and it's,
I'm sure how many of you have come up
against the proposition that prefrontal
ability was associated with behavioral
control.
Yeah.
Well it isn't.
So you know,
not anymore than I.
First of all,
it's not differentiable from ICU
regardless of what the neuro
psychologists say,
because they don't know anything about
psychometrics generally.
And they don't like Icu because if they
studied Iq then what they'd find is all
the things that they're studying are
basically variants of Iq and that would
suck because other people have already
figured out Icu and then there's the big
problem which is well variation in
prefrontal ability which is equivalent
to variation in Iq,
isn't correlated with behavioral
control,
is a really big problem.
So.
And so I would like to say,
well what is correlated with behavioral
control and then.
But the problem with that as well,
I don't know what you mean by behavioral
control.
I don't know how you're going to measure
it.
And if you do measure it,
the probability that you're going to
come up with something like
conscientiousness is pretty much 100
percent.
So
all right,
let's see.
Yes,
effect sizes.
This is from a very important paper by a
guy named Hemphill called interpreting
the magnitudes of correlation
coefficients from the American
psychologist number 58.
What handheld did was look at all,
he didn't gas it,
how big an effect size had to be for it
to be a big effect size.
What he did was go into the literature
and study a whole bunch of papers and
then empirically rank the effect sizes.
So that would be the standard deviation
difference or the correlation or the r
squared.
You can convert those and then decide
you know,
what proportion of papers had which
effect size and decide that well,
you could empirically rank them and then
you'd know how big your effect size was.
And what he found was that
about three percent of social science
studies showed a correlation Coefficient
of point five or above.
And that's about the correlation between
Iq and and general life success in
relatively complex conditions.
Point three,
five,
two point five,
only about one in four papers to one in
point one,
five,
two point three,
25 to 57 percent of papers and then are
of less than point one five was about a
quarter of papers.
So what that means is the ability of Iq
to predict whatever it is that you want
to predict with it is way the hell up in
the,
in the rare,
rare,
uh,
what would you call it?
Well,
it's up in the stratosphere with regards
to effect power.
Okay.
So what does it mean practically
speaking?
This is from a company called the
wonderlic company and the wonderlic
wonderlic sales Iq tests to businesses
now.
It's actually illegal for businesses to
use Iq tests in the United States.
So actually it's illegal to do anything
to hire employees,
employees in the United States as it
turns out,
because you have to use a test,
you have to use the tasks that's the
most valid and reliable available that
doesn't produce any ethnic or gender
differences.
Well,
there's no test like that.
So it's,
it's illegal.
So,
so it's illegal to use,
um,
interviews.
It's illegal to use letters of
reference,
it's illegal to usability tests.
You might build to use conscientiousness
tests because conscientiousness tests do
seem to be completely free of
not exactly because older people are
more conscientious than younger people.
So that's also a problem.
So anyways,
wonder,
lick,
it's a good company.
It makes really.
It's Iq tests are genuine tests,
but they are Iq tests and people do use
them in business even though they're not
supposed to,
but so,
but what they've done over over a long
period of using the test is to come up
with approximations for different forms
of employment opportunity.
So how smart do you have to be in order
to be
placed in a given occupation with a
reasonable probability of success?
So we,
we can tell you here.
So,
um,
let's see.
You said exactly the right place.
Okay.
So if you have iqs of 116 to 130,
that's pretty much you guys,
although I suspect there's a fair chunk
of you that have an Iq of over 130 130
makes you 115 makes you 15 percent.
One hundred and 30 makes you a 98
percentile.
One hundred and 45 makes you 99th
One hundred and 60 makes you 99 point
nine percent or something else to think
about.
Percentiles are strange things because
you might say,
well there's no difference between
someone who scores 95th percentile on an
Iq test and 99th percentile because it's
only four percentile is different.
But that's not for percentages.
The person who scores Ninety five is one
in 20.
The person who scores 99 is one in a
hundred.
The person who scores 99 point nine is
one in a thousand.
So,
and you might think,
well it doesn't matter because as you
know,
once you get to a certain degree of
smart that smart enough and now that's
wrong.
In fact,
it's,
it's probably radically wrong in that
the differences between people actually
increase as you go up the Iq scale.
So,
and that's because performance isn't
distributed in a normal distribution,
it's distributed in a prieto
distribution such that almost no one
does anything in a very small number of
people do everything.
So,
which is also a very dismal fact.
Okay.
So anyways,
if you're in the upper echelons of the,
of the cognitive distribution,
so
from 116 to 130,
you could be an attorney,
a research analyst and editor and
advertising manager,
a chemist,
engineer,
an executive,
a manager,
a trade manager trainee,
a systems analyst or an auditory from
115 to 110.
One hundred and 10 to 115.
So that's,
that'd be in the upper half of a high
school.
Graduating class,
roughly speaking,
upper quarter copywriter,
account manager slash supervisor,
sales manager,
sales man,
programmer analyst,
teacher adjuster,
general manager,
purchasing agent,
registered nurse sales account,
executive
hundred,
eight to 103 administrative assistant
store manager,
bookkeeper,
credit clerk,
drafter designer,
lab tester,
secretary,
accounting clerk.
Medical debt collection,
computer operator,
customer service Rep,
automotive salesman,
clerk and typist,
102 to 100.
So that's pretty much right at the mean
dispatcher,
General Office dispatcher,
police patrol officer,
receptionist,
cashier,
general clerical work inside sales
clerk,
meter reader,
printer teller data entry,
or an electrical helper
for ICU from 95 to 98,
machinist quality control Checker,
claims clerk,
driver delivery man,
security guard,
unskilled labor maintenance machine
operator,
arc welder,
mechanic,
medical dental assistant from 87 to 93
messenger,
factory,
production,
Assembler,
food service worker,
nurses aid,
warehouseman,
custodian,
janitor,
material handler and packer.
And then that's it.
So you see that things are getting
pretty damn dismal for the people who
are have an Iq of 85 and below.
So
now
what's the difference between intellect
and openness?
Proper?
Well,
one difference is that men seem to be
higher intellect the trade and seem to
be higher in openness and openness seems
to be associated with verbal
intelligence and with imagination and
with fantasy and with aesthetic
experience.
And it seems to go along with the fact
that women read more fiction than men.
So men read nonfiction,
roughly speaking in women,
read fiction,
you know,
it's obviously there's a lot of overlap,
but fundamentally that seems to be how
it distributes.
Maybe that's also partly because women
are more agreeable and so they're more
interested in human relations and
characters and you know,
that's the central,
that's the central theme of fiction.
People who are high in openness.
Think divergently.
Here we can do a quick little divergent
thinking tests.
So why don't we do that.
Take out a piece of paper and a pen and
a or,
or you can type on your computer.
I don't care.
You can scratch it onto the desk for all
I care as long,
but get out a piece of paper so you can
write on.
And we'll do this.
So
I'll only give you a minute since you're
all so fast and we only have six minutes
left.
So write down as many uses as you can
think of for a brick.
You have one minute.
Oh,
okay.
That's all the time you get.
Okay.
So the first question is,
I'm just going to ask,
you are going to point at you and you
can answer how many,
how many users did you come up with?
13.
Five.
Youtube?
Yeah.
That's okay.
Eight,
seven,
seven.
Okay.
Did anybody come up with more than 13?
How many?
14 did anybody come up with?
More than 14.
Okay.
So you two are the most idiation Lee
fluent people in the class.
And fluency is a matter of the rip
rapidity with which you can generate
exemplars from a category.
So one of the things that we might ask
just as much would be how many words can
you write the begin with the letter ass
in a minute.
And there'll be,
you wouldn't believe the bloody range of
that.
There'll be people will be people who
get six and there'll be people who get
50,
you know,
so idiation will fluency is actually
pretty decent predictor of creative
ability.
Now you know,
that's not a great test,
right?
Because it was very short and I do that
multiple times with multiple time
durations and different exemplars in
some across that.
But the correlation between the ideation
of fluency in longterm creative
achievement is about point three.
It was pretty major.
Okay.
So let's hear a use for a brick.
How about you?
You can draw on the sidewalk with a
brick.
You a paper weight.
How many people got paperweight?
Yes.
That's a low creative response.
Now why?
That doesn't mean that all your
responses are,
but it's a technical definition,
right?
So here's what makes a response low
creative.
Everyone has it.
Now it's a perfectly reasonable
response.
But for it to be creative virtually by
definition,
it has to be a low probability response.
That actually makes sense.
So draw on sidewalk is,
is,
is more low probability response.
Somebody got a weird use for a brick.
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
Anybody else have that?
They ground their brick into dust for
something?
No?
Yes.
You could kill someone with a brick.
Anybody have that?
Yes.
Low agreeableness.
Low creativity.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we'll go.
Anybody else?
Go to like a peculiar one for a brick
here.
Look.
Yeah.
Anybody else have that?
Okay.
So,
you know,
it's,
it's kind of a lousy musical instrument.
But in a pinch it would work.
Yeah.
Well that's a good one.
First of all,
you can kill it and then you can drown
it.
Yeah.
So the way you would score this,
by the way,
it's quite straight.
It's not that straightforward actually.
First of all,
you count the number of responses and
you get rid of ones that are repetitive
and then you also get usually a couple
of people to throw the ones that are
just like they're neither original nor
practical.
The best responses are original and
Now there's a bit of a judgment call
there,
you know what I mean?
But if you get a number of people to do
the rating,
you can get pretty decent interrater
reliability and so then you score
originality and the way you score
originality is merely by something like
listing all the responses and then
calculating how probable or frequent the
responses are in the more infrequent
responses you get a higher score for.
So it's,
it's basically a population,
a sample.
So.
And those things actually work those,
those tests.
Just so you know,
now I'll stop with this.
This is a,
this is a measure that I derived with
one of my students when I worked in
Boston,
her name was Shelly Carson,
and this thing is actually become one of
the standard measures of creativity in
the creativity literature,
which is quite fun and it's creative
achievement questionnaire.
So what I gave you just now is a
creativity test.
It's one of many creativity test.
It wasn't a creative achievement test
because you can generate uses for a
brick without running out and becoming a
brick entrepreneur,
you know,
so there's a difference between being
able to think divergently and with loose
associations and then also being able to
put that into practice so you achieve
something.
And so here's some levels of
achievement.
So there's the scientific discovery
domain.
I do not have training or recognized
stability in this field.
I often think about ways that scientific
problems could be solved.
I have won a prize at a science fair or
other local competition.
I've received a scholarship based on my
work in science or medicine.
I've been arthur or core author of a
study published in the scientific
journal.
I've won a national prize.
I've received a grant,
my work has been cited by other
scientists in national publications.
Okay.
And then the same thing for say theater
and film and Culinary Arts.
Zero is I do not have training or
recognized stability in theater and
film.
Number seven is my theatrical work has
been recognized in a national
publication for culinary arts.
I do not have training or experience and
the highest one is my recipes have been
published nationally.
Okay.
So
there's 13 different domains
and that's the distribution.
It's not normally distributed.
So what you see there actually it's not
quite right because the the median
answer,
it's about 66 percent of the respondents
to the creative achievement
questionnaire have a median score of
zero,
right?
Zero.
They do not have training or talent in
any of the 13 areas and then there's
some people who are way out on the right
hand distribution
[inaudible].
You can imagine that once you have
national exposure in one magazine as a
writer,
the probability that you're going to get
national exposure again for your second
novel starts to go up pretty damn high.
Right?
And so you get this terrible step down
function so that almost everybody
aggregates that nothing.
And then a few people are way out in the
distribution and they just get
everything and there's actually a law,
it's called the matthew principle that
economists use and it's from a statement
in the New Testament from matthew and
it's a statement where Christ says from
those who have to those who have
everything more will be given and from
those who have nothing,
everything will be taken away.
And that seems to be how creative
resources are distributed in the
population and to a large degree that's
dependent on intelligence,
openness and conscientiousness.
So
you can understand why none of that very
popular with people since you're all
smart and conscientious though it's
going to work out well for you.
See you on Tuesday.
I'm going to post your mid term marks.
What we're going to do after that with
regards to the strike,
I don't.
I can't.
I don't know yet.