Yeah.
So I was thinking today about how to
explain this a little bit further.
So let's say
you're going for a job interview
and uh,
you're nervous about it
and you go in to the job interview and
there's some people there and some
chairs and tables and it's a room that's
like this,
maybe not quite as ugly,
but,
but something like this.
What's in the room?
You're nervous,
you've seen chairs,
the tables before,
you've seen people what's in the room.
Okay.
How about a set of alternate futures?
Right.
You know,
that isn't how we think,
it's how we act.
And you know,
if you talk about it,
I was nervous about going to this job
interview.
Why?
Well,
I thought I might be evaluated.
Okay,
well why does that matter?
Well,
we know partly why it matters.
Look at this figure again,
pretty happy with his figure.
All things considered,
you know,
and you might say,
well,
if I,
maybe it'll shake my faith in my,
you know,
in my belief that I'm a good person.
That'd be a little silly for an
interview,
you know?
So if you're thinking that way,
I would say you're thinking you're,
you're not thinking specifically enough
cause there's lots of reasons you might
not do well at a job interview,
including the fact that they might have
already given the job to someone else
for all you know.
So,
so you don't want to leap to the top of
the hierarchy without cause.
Okay.
Now,
so one of the things you might say is
that in the room there,
there are threats that might be posed to
any level of the hierarchy
of beliefs and behaviors that you use to
interact with the world.
Now,
the terror management people would tell
you,
let's assume that this is a belief
structure.
I don't care whether you agree with the
way it's represented graphically or not
for the time being,
but let's just assume that what we're
talking about is a belief structure.
Now,
the Tara management people would tell
you that you have that belief structure
far in large part to protect you from
the fear of death,
right?
From Maine,
from death,
anxiety.
But there's a bunch of problems with
that idea.
Not least that it actually sidesteps the
issue of the function of the belief
system.
It's like you don't exactly have a
belief system to make philosophical
sense out of the world.
You have a system of tools
that are embodied that allow you to
actually act in the world.
Now you might also have an articulated
representation of that on top that's
more or less accurate,
probably less all things considered.
And you know,
maybe if your faith and not as shaken
your faith in what you do,
we'll also be shaken because the two
things are are associated,
but we should always remember that I
believe system doesn't just protect you
from the fear of death and protects you
from death and that's a lot different,
you know,
I mean this whole thing is,
it's your set of skills and and,
and the perceptions and thoughts and
emotions that go along with those
skills.
And then it's an integrated structure
consisting of the particular manner in
which you've integrated all your own
little sub parts.
And then in relationship to the whole
community,
you can also think about it in some
sense as a holographic representation of
the culture.
Now
I don't know how much you guys know
about holographs.
I don't know very much about them
either,
but there's some things I know about
them.
So if you shine a light on a holograph,
you'll get it.
Three,
the image that of whatever it was there
when the holograph was created,
it's created by lasers now.
And if you take a holograph and you
break it into pieces and then you shine
a light on the pieces,
you get an object in each piece.
So,
but it's lower resolution.
It's a nice way of thinking about a
person,
you know,
like if your brain is damaged,
you'll be there,
but sort of as a lower resolution
representation of yourself.
But it's also really nice way of
thinking about what culture is.
Culture is this massive structure of
multiple levels and domains,
but it's reflected in each of us.
Like we're each partial carriers of it.
So we have a partial representation of
the structure that we embody,
a partial representation of the
structure.
I mean literally we embody it and then
we also represent it abstractly.
And you know,
part of the reason that you go to a
university is to in some sense,
improve your capacity to articulate your
structure,
right?
Because you're a cultural creature.
It's like,
why are you the way you are?
Well,
some of it's psychological,
some of its sociological,
some of it's historical,
like a lot of it is historical.
So when you go and you study social
science or humanity,
you're studying your own personality.
Now
I wrote a paper a while back with a
couple of my graduate students and it
was,
I think it was called the entropy.
God,
you'd think I would remember this.
Entropy doesn't matter.
The hypothesis was,
and this is something I'd been thinking
about a law for a long time,
is that,
you know,
the world is very,
very complex.
And so what that means is that the act
of getting from one place to another is
often very,
very difficult.
And partly what you're doing when you
put together a functional submodule is
you're putting together a little routine
that will enable you to transform some
part of time and space from what it is
and to what you want it to be.
And in some sense,
what you're doing is reducing the
complexity of that situation.
So imagine this,
so you go for your job interview and
you're,
you're knocking them dead.
What happens?
Well,
a whole bunch of possibilities,
all that,
that set of possibilities that was
concerning you starts to collapse
towards a single solution.
And that single solution is if you're
doing very well in the interview,
it's like it's a positive solution.
So your anxiety disappears and it's
replaced with positive emotion.
You get enthusiastic and excited because
what's happening in that room is that a
path to the desirable future is opening.
Now you can't see any of this,
you know?
And because we're so blinded by the idea
that we see objects,
we,
we failed to perceive in any articulated
sense what it is that we're actually
dealing with them.
You know,
I think that one way of thinking about
it is that you're always on the edge of,
of,
of something that's potential.
That's where you exist.
You exist on this moving,
um,
boundary of potential and you can
interact with it such that you form it
and it passes,
it passes by you into the past,
you know,
and hopefully you're forming it in a way
that is in concordance with your better
health and perhaps with the better
health of the people around you that
would sort of be optimal.
So you're realizing that potential inner
inner,
inner genuine,
non metaphorical sense that that's the
thing about these representations in
other,
they're often described as mythical or
mythological or metaphorical,
but you know,
they're really not metaphorical.
Well,
it's not exactly right because the great
mother,
the great father,
those,
they're partially metaphorical,
but the medic,
the thing that they stand for as
metaphors is something other than the
things that we conceptualize when we
look at the world from an objective
perspective.
Now we've talked a little bit about the
figure of the dragon of chaos.
And I think of all the metaphorical
images,
it's the most difficult to grasp because
it's,
it's that which has not yet been
encountered.
So it's neither unknown nor known.
And you think,
well,
you can't even describe that.
It's,
yeah,
but you can encounter it and you
encounter that when you go into a
situation that's radically new.
So I would say,
let's say it's just the second before
you walk into a high stakes interview,
you know,
just before you open the door,
I would say that's as close as you get.
You know,
in a normal day,
do a direct encounter with the dragon of
chaos because you don't know what's
going to happen and to say,
well,
you're in a room and there's a door in
front of you.
You know,
it's almost moronic to think of it that
way,
right?
Because what the hell does that have to
do with anything?
It's what's in there is unbelievably,
I like,
it's the localized,
it's the localization of unbelievably
complex webs of causality.
That's what's waiting for you inside
that room.
And then you might say,
well,
is it structured in any real way?
And the answer to that is not really,
it's no more structured then it's even
less structured than a book that you're
reading.
You know,
like you're,
if you're reading the book,
you might say,
well where's the meaning in this book?
And the answer to that is it,
well it's not in the book.
Like it's partly there,
you know,
because you need the words in the
sentences and the paragraphs and all
that,
but you need the whole cultural context
around it in order to interpret it.
So you're not reading it blank.
You know,
you come to it with a set of a very
large set of presuppositions,
enough of them so that you can
understand the,
the author.
Now maybe you can't and the book's over
your hand or it's badly written.
But typically you come at it with the
machinery in place so that when you
interact with the words and the phrases
and the sentences and so forth,
revelations of new meaning poor forth.
And so,
I don't know how to say it any clearer
than that.
That's what the meaning of the book is.
And,
and it's,
it's in the dialectical interaction
between you and the book.
Well,
if you walk into an interview room,
it's even less given in some sense than
the book,
right?
Because what's going to happen in there,
which really means which of the many
futures that that room contains is going
to manifest itself.
It depends very much on how you act.
So it's in that way that you collapsed
the potential that's in a particular
place and you extract something out of
it.
That's well that,
and then that's when it gets tricky,
neutral,
positive or negative may be bombed the
interview,
right?
And then you might say,
well,
what,
what does,
what happened?
What happened?
Well,
that's a very complicated question.
Then you're stuck with this hierarchy,
right?
And that's what you're going to do when
you go home.
You're going to say,
well,
you know,
maybe I didn't dress properly or maybe I
didn't get to the interview on time,
or they ask me a bunch of questions I
wasn't prepared for,
or Jesus,
I didn't know anything about what's
going on.
My whole education was a waste of time.
And what the hell am I doing?
And then he might go,
I'm never going to get a job.
And you,
you know what you could say in some
sense that all of those hypotheses as
you move up and down the hierarchy,
you know,
you move from trivial trouble to really
not good trouble as you bounce.
And all of that is an attempt to specify
in some sense what that room contained.
And it's not easy.
You know?
And it's weird too because the room can
contain things that alter your past,
you know,
because maybe you say,
well,
maybe you're going for a computer
science job.
Maybe you're not,
whatever.
You know,
you go in there and you think you're the
top person in your class and maybe you
were,
but you know,
the people in there are so far ahead of
you that you can't even imagine ever
catching up.
And you know,
when you come out of there,
the manner in which you construe your
educational history is going to be
radically transformed.
So there's a lot of,
a lot of trouble in that room.
There's a lot.
Now,
one of the things we thought in this
paper,
you can think of each of those little
eggs,
they're really eggs as a container.
And what they contain is entropy
trouble.
And the smaller ones contained smaller
amounts of entropy and the bigger ones
contain bigger amounts of entropy,
you know?
And so here's another example.
You're driving down the highway and your
car sputters and grinds to a halt.
Maybe it makes some nice red radical
noise as well.
It's doing it.
It's okay.
Well what happened?
Well the answer is the simple answer is
your car mental function and you had to
pull off the road.
That's a really object oriented
analysis.
But what's actually happened is that you
had a conceptualization of the car as a
pragmatic tool.
Cause what do you know about the damn
car?
You know,
the car was uh,
uh,
the car was a,
an affordance that's the right word that
would get you from point a to point b.
And you could have a very little
resolution model of it,
right?
It can just look like a plastic shell,
which is sort of what a car looks like.
And as long as you see how low root
resolution that is,
you could replace it with a cartoon and
you wouldn't even notice
that's,
that's good enough representation.
As long as the thing is doing what it's
supposed to be doing.
But as soon as it stops doing what it's
supposed to be doing,
then it could be any old thing.
And you think,
well,
what does any old thing mean?
Well maybe you're on a deserted highway
and it's one o'clock in the morning.
And you know when someone pulls over to
is to help you.
Okay,
well what's that?
Well,
you know,
we believe me,
your imagination will rapidly span the
world of possibility from oh good,
someone's come to help to I'm going to
be dragged off in the bush and killed.
You know,
and that's all contained in that,
in that sequence of events.
And then even if no one does stop,
well then you know,
and,
and you have to worry about exactly
what's gone wrong and you would have to
worry about how you're going to fix it.
You have to worry about the mechanic
that might help you.
And you have to concern yourself with
whether or not you're going to need a
new car and then you have to think about
your finances and it's like the idea
that that car is a bounded entity like
it looks is only true when it works,
as soon as it doesn't work,
then God,
it's any old thing and that in some
senses the dragon of chaos.
It's this.
Now what seems to me to have happened
because you might think,
well,
how do people come to conceptualize such
a thing?
Because I would think of of all the
things that are different are difficult
to conceptualize.
The category of all things that you have
not yet encountered is the most
difficult thing to discover it,
right?
It's kind of like zero.
It took people a long time to figure out
zero and no wonder we need a symbol for
nothing.
Well,
this is even worse.
We need a representation for potential.
While you think,
well,
why?
Well,
because it's actually potential that
you're interacting with all of the time.
Now,
what seems to me to have happened was
that,
you know,
this is a evolutionary just so story.
So I'm not assuming that it actually
worked precisely this way,
but it doesn't matter cause it's got,
I'm going to touch on the appropriate,
you know,
uh,
the appropriate features.
Well one of the things we know about
social animals generally speaking and
animals in general,
is that they have a territory,
right?
And so you think,
well what is their territory exactly?
And he might say,
well,
you can mark it out.
Here's,
here's a,
Oh,
what will we think about
what would have a territory?
It must make it make it a like a tiger.
They're pretty solitary.
So it'll be simple.
They have a big territory rights as
hundreds of square miles.
And the reason for that is while there
are tigers,
you can't have like 50 of them cause
they'll just eat everything that's
there.
Even though you have to have a big
territory to support one apex Predator.
So then you might say,
well what exactly is the territory of
the tiger?
And you'd say,
well,
here's its boundaries.
This is where it there,
this is where it roams,
but that's not the right way of thinking
about the territory of the tiger because
the territory of the tiger is actually
all the places where when the tiger does
its thing,
the things that the tiger wants to or
expect happens,
that's the Tigers territory.
It's the same with you.
You know you're at home wherever you
know what to do and what you're doing
when you knew what to do is you know how
to match this hierarchy,
which is partly action oriented.
You know how to match the hierarchy with
this situation so that when you put it
into practice,
the potential that's there transforms
itself into what you're aiming at.
And that's your territory.
And you know,
and you need to think about it that way
because your territory can shift very
rapidly on.
And if you think about geography
geographically,
it's kind of confusing.
So let's say you're on the subway that
you always take and then someone sits
down beside you and they're muttering
away madly and have a pretty malevolent
look on their face and you get a glimpse
inside their code.
And it's like there's a knife,
it's like you're not in your territory
anymore.
And the fact that all of the objective
entities are still there,
arrayed around you is it's just an,
it's nothing more than a,
what would you call it?
It's a delusion at that point to think
that those things characterize where you
are.
Okay.
So if you're willing to consider
territory as that,
it's a space time continuum.
Okay.
And the reason I'm stressing that,
I mean first of all,
whatever reality is,
is a space time continuum,
right?
It's got three dimensions of space and
one dimension of time.
And everyone knows that as we sit here
more or less stable in three dimensions,
time flows past us in some sense.
And so the,
the three dimensional reality is
transforming all by itself just because
of time.
Okay.
And so when we're mapping out our
territory's,
we map out spacetime territory's.
And so that means that not only do you
know where you are,
you know when you are,
and if you're in your territory,
you know how to act for that place in
that time so that you transformed the
potential that's there into whatever it
is that you're aiming at.
Okay?
So that's your territory.
Now that territory is isomorphic
evolutionary,
evolutionarily with lots of things which
you could also confuse geographically.
So you know,
you might think of a human territory as
something like,
it's probably the fundamental human
territory is probably a fire,
right?
And so the fire is a place of light in
the darkness,
and then you can think of row rings,
concentric rings of relative safety,
uh,
surrounding the fire.
So right beside the fire where it's warm
and light and there's lots of other
people,
man,
that's explored territory,
you know?
But then if you start wandering away
from the fire into the Bush,
especially if you're in a very
biologically active area,
then the farther away you get from the
fire,
the more you're going outside of your
territory.
And you can tell that it's happening
because your whole nervous system starts
to function differently.
What happens is is that the nervous
system parts that you were using using
while you were in known territory,
just they just shut down.
And the other nervous system elements
that you use an unknown territory start
to turn on and generally you're not very
happy about that because where you're,
when you're aware you've mastered the
territory,
you can presume that neutral or
moderately good things are going to
happen with the possibility of something
great now and then.
But as you move away from that,
it flips in some sense too.
I don't know what is going on here and I
might fall to something's going to bite
me too.
I'm going to die a painful death.
You know,
and you don't use the same circuits to
process the first situation as you do
the process the second you don't even
like having the second one on,
you know,
so you know what it's like you're you.
Maybe you've been feeling a bit down
because that always helps.
And then you wake up at three in the
morning and you're worrying about six
things and you hear some random noise
somewhere.
There shouldn't be around him.
Noise.
Well how you feel right then.
That's what it is like to have the
system that deals with the unexpected on
your like a prey animal really,
really exactly like what because that's
actually what you are in many ways and
so you know your whole biology
transformed so that you're prepared for
God only knows what.
Well,
what seem to have happened in the course
of evolution was that when we were
smaller creatures all and far after
that,
before let's say we figured out how to
use throwing sticks and slings and then
later maybe bows and arrows or maybe
even sticks like we're getting eaten
lot.
I think I told you guys last week that
they just discovered this damn cat in
Africa that it looks like it prayed on
our fore bearers and or we have pretty
hard skull.
So the normal cap can't really know all
three of them.
But this cat had a special set of teeth
and if it grabbed the front of your
head,
it would drive one of its teeth right
through the back of your skull.
So you know,
the hominids were preyed on enough so
that they had their own predators.
Well,
so you know,
that's just not,
that's just not very pleasant.
And then that's why the time we were
hominins you can go back farther than
that.
So when we were little tree rats,
roughly speaking and then all sorts of
things we're eating us,
you know,
there were a lot of reptiles around back
then and s 60 million years ago and they
weren't pleasant.
There was phil dinosaurs around 60
million years ago.
And so you know,
that's a lot of evolutionary time for us
to have developed biological systems
that distinguished between places were
safe and places we're not safe.
Well,
you roughly have one set of
neuropsychological neuropsycho
physiological functions for familiar
territory and another set for unfamiliar
territory.
Now what I would say this is,
this is where this becomes I think
radically different.
The terror management theory.
What these,
what this hierarchy is doing.
When it's functioning is shutting off.
It's keeping the system that operates an
unexplored territory shut off and you
like that.
And that's when you're calm and like you
are in here,
you're know you're relatively at home
here because you assume that you know
how to act here as long as you sit and
you ask questions more or less
appropriately and he don't bother people
and you don't talk on your phone,
various other things,
the probability that you're going to be
confronted by an angry primate or some
other Predator is a very,
very low.
And so so,
so you'd say,
well you're normal,
you feel like you do normally here.
And,
but I would say the only reason you feel
that way normally to begin with is
because you don't go places where you
feel not normal.
You stay away from them and everyone
knows what those places are.
Like.
I saw a real cool example of this once I
was down by,
by old cad about midnight on a Saturday
night.
You know,
there was,
it was in the summer.
So there are all these kids really
wandering around in their party clothes.
And,
you know,
go into the clubs.
And I was standing there watching and I
looked through a park at this street
that runs by near Oca and there were
these houses,
there was a row of houses and there was
like three houses here and they're all
really nicely taken care of.
And there was a house here.
And then there was some more houses over
here that were well taken care of.
And that house in the middle was
condemned,
you know,
so the roof was pro rotting and they
boarded up all the windows,
you know,
and the fences were falling over and
there was garbage in the yard.
It was a derelict place,
you know,
so that's kind of a spooky place.
Well,
while I was standing there,
this guy walked down the street and he
was very intoxicated and he wasn't very
happy and he was sort of muttering to
himself and he passed the three houses
that were in pretty good shape.
And then as soon as he got in front of
the House that was derelict,
he just started to rant.
And he was,
you know,
pounding up and down and muttering
paranoid things and yelling and you
know,
it was sounding really dangerous,
but he kept more or less moving forward.
And then just after he got past that
border line and back into the more or
less normal neighborhood,
he switched back to just mumbling
quietly and walk forward.
You know,
he was so damn intoxicated.
There isn't a possibility that he
noticed what had happened,
but he was being cued by the
surroundings,
you know?
And it was a different hand when he was
in unexplored territory.
You know,
it was something that had degenerated
back into chaos.
So the anger and aggression came out of
them because that's often necessary if
you're going to be where there's chaos,
you know,
and chaos can burst forth and does all
the time in people's lives.
You know,
if you're sitting around the dinner
table with your family and everything's
going pretty well,
but someone touches on,
you know,
one of those topics that you should just
shut the hell up about,
you know,
it can take almost no time at all before
the whole thing unravels.
And then God only knows where you are
and it's not pleasant.
So instead of our belief systems
protecting us from death,
anxiety are hierarchical,
pragmatic systems for interacting with
the world stopped the parts of our brain
that deal with the unexpected from being
on.
And they don't do that because we
believe they do that.
Because when we enact those structures,
all hell doesn't break loose.
So there's nothing illusory about it.
Now,
you know,
you might say,
well,
in the final analysis,
does it really protect you from chaos?
And you know that's an okay question.
But most of the time,
most of the time that's irrelevant.
It isn't always irrelevant,
but most of the time it just doesn't
matter.
And the other thing is,
is that much of the time it doesn't even
matter if you believe this,
you know,
which by which I would mean you have an
articulated representation of it.
It's also a self representation.
And you carry that around and maybe you
have a crisis of faith and you don't
believe in that.
You still act all this stuff out and
most of the time you're still extremely
well protected by it.
So it's a little,
it's more robust than merely the
articulated or imagined version.
It's a lot deeper than that.
It's only a tiny part of its structure.
And so we should never really talk about
belief systems.
Exactly.
Especially not if they're shared with
very many other people because they're
not structures of,
they're much deeper structures and that,
and the belief part is only a pale
reflection of the underlying reality.
Okay.
So that,
I presume that makes sense and you can,
when you can make sense of that in your
own life.
And you know,
there's other things that can happen to
that that I should mention is lots of
times people have chaos.
You know,
you think your body has explored
territory.
It's sort of like the ultimate explored
But I would say don't get too convinced
about that.
That can also switch in a moment.
And it happens to people all the time.
So if you get a tooth pulled,
it takes your tongue like three months
to map the inside of your mouth.
Again,
so that's refamiliarizing your brain
with the new territory,
right?
And that is very,
very complicated.
So your body representation is insanely
complicated and it's really easy to
screw up.
So if you go to have someone go like
that and then you point to one of their
fingers in the middle and get them to
move it,
don't touch it,
they often can't because just that's
enough to boggle up their visual
representation of their body.
And so you can play all sorts of tricks
on people that way.
And so,
you know,
so that your map of your body and your
body are sort of reasonably well
associated,
but they can be dissociated quite
rapidly.
And you know,
that happens when maybe you get a little
hypochondriacal and start worrying about
your health.
Something's bugging you,
you know,
and you don't exactly know what it is.
It's like,
well,
all of a sudden you get alienated from
your body.
And that can get really serious.
You know?
And I've seen people after a car
accident,
this was the most striking case of this
client.
I had had her shoulder up like this.
And I noticed he never really looked in
the direction of that arm.
And when she moved that you'd only move
at about this far.
And after seeing her for awhile,
I thought,
oh,
she's afraid of that arm now.
It had been hurt.
Well why would you get afraid of your
arm?
Well,
doesn't act like it used to.
So that's annoying.
And then when you move it wrong,
it hurts.
And then you also don't know that if you
move it wrong and it hurts whether
you're making it worse,
so then you just kind of ignore it and
then it sort of your arm and sort of not
your arm,
you know?
Well I had her at one point,
we just practice doing this.
I said,
well,
can I do it?
The action,
can you do this?
She'd do it.
And then I'd go,
well can you do this?
And then she'd do it.
Now can you do this?
We just kept doing this and only took
about half an hour until she was up
here.
She said,
I hadn't put my arm up there for two
years,
you know?
And then I get the same thing with their
shoulder.
You know,
can you lift it cheap?
I said,
can you lift your shoulder?
No.
Can you lift at one 16 seven inch while
she could do that,
well you know,
16 times at one 16th of an inch and
that's an inch and that's starting to
get there.
And you know,
she did this a bunch and then her arm
went down so she'd been holding the damn
arm up for two years.
Just try that,
you know?
I mean you just do this for five minutes
and see what happens.
You just hold your shoulder up there for
two years and see what that does to the
entire right side of your body.
Like it's really,
really stressful.
Man.
I did something strange then,
which was a whim,
but I think it was because I was
embodying her because I was paying so
close attention.
I asked her to come and lean over my
desk.
There's something about the way she was
holding herself that was really bugging
me.
And so I asked her just to lean over her
desk,
my desk,
and I pounded on her back down her
spinal cord and she dropped her
shoulders again.
Then she cried for about half an hour.
So,
and again it was because she got hit by
a car.
That's how she was like,
she just walked around like that,
you know,
and it permanently,
more or less.
And you know,
we work it out of her reasonably well,
but
you know,
even your own damn body can become
unexplored territory.
And you know,
that's another,
that's another way of understanding that
Yin Yang symbol,
right?
You got the black serpent Paisley and
it's got a little white dog in it,
which means that sometimes when things
are really broken all to hell,
a solution can come blasting fourth.
And you know,
chaos turns into order,
but more likely,
you know,
everything's going pretty nicely and op
something comes and the chaos builds
into the order and that's the world you
live in.
And that's not a metaphor.
And it's really interesting to know that
because then the question becomes,
okay,
well what do you do in order?
And what do you do in chaos out?
Those are useful things to know.
We kind of know what to do in order
because order that sort of defines
order,
but we don't really know what to do in
chaos,
you know,
in fact the field of mental health in
some senses and attempt to figure that
out.
But I can tell you some things to do
when you're in chaos.
So let's say you're dealing with someone
who's very,
very ill or maybe it's you that's very,
very ill and so god only knows what's
going to happen in the future or even
next week.
Well the first thing you do is stop
thinking about next week and the future
because it's not calculable,
right?
The,
the pathways have become so multiple and
so uncontrollable that if you think
about them,
it's just going to hurt you.
And so,
you know,
you can't just not think about it
because that doesn't work.
But what you can do is narrow your
timeframe of analysis,
you know,
so instead of worrying about the week,
you think,
okay,
well let's make this day as good as it
can be.
And then if you're really stressed it's
like,
no,
we're going to really work on this hour.
And so what happens is you hyper at 10
to the local space time area and that's
what you've got.
You can work with that.
And it really works.
Like if you're dealing with people who
are dying,
for example,
that's what you do.
He was zero in to the,
to the right level of resolution
fundamentally.
And you can tell when it's the right
resume level of resolution because you
don't feel like you don't know what
you're doing anymore.
What am I doing here?
What am I supposed to do here?
What does all this mean?
You don't feel that anymore.
Cause those are the wrong questions at
that point in time.
And maybe,
you know,
try and make the person comfortable and
you pay attention so that you can take
the right micro movements and the right
micro attitudes in those critical
moments.
And that's what you do.
And so that's one way of dealing with
the underworld.
And you need to know that because it's
going to happen.
So,
so if you're really stressed,
you think about less,
you think about smaller amounts of space
and time and you could try to get them
right.
It's still important to get it right,
but the entropy is so high at that
point,
the landscape is so complicated that
there's no way you can map more of it
than a few moments out of time.
But it turns out often that that's,
that's okay,
that's good enough.
You know,
it's obviously it's not optimal,
but one thing you can be sure of is you
can take a terrible situation and you
could make it a hell of a lot worse.
So you know,
if it's a terrible situation and you
manage it as well as it can be managed
and maybe it's only terrible,
but if you take a terrible situation and
you manage it really badly,
then it can be something you'll never
ever recover from.
So,
you know,
I'm not trying to be hyper optimistic
about this.
I know that people go through rough
times,
but there's a difference between tragedy
and hale.
And tragedy is when something terrible
happens and unit and you're awake and
hell is when something terrible happens
and you're not awake and that's a place
you really don't want to go.
You know?
So then the death of your father could
turn it into the obliteration of your
entire family.
Well,
you know the first is bad enough,
but the second might well be unbearable.
You know,
cause people often fight in
circumstances like that.
And you know,
the family gets very,
very stressed.
It's very common.
For example,
if someone,
a couple has a sick child or a child
that dies that they get divorced,
it's not surprising.
You know,
cause it's not like they have a
psychological problem,
they have a real problem and they might
be amplifying it with their
psychological problems.
But all problems are not psychological.
You know?
And that's also useful to know because
if you end up somewhere that you don't
expect,
you're going to be thinking,
especially if you're conscientious,
if I wasn't such a useless fool,
I would've never ended up here.
Where,
and there's a much more pessimistic
thought than that.
That's much more useful,
which is whether you are a fool or not,
you are going to end up somewhere like
big now and then.
And you might think,
God,
that's a horrible thing to think because
you know,
that means that you know,
our destinies are uncontrollable.
At least in park.
It's like,
yeah,
they are.
So partly what that means is prepare
yourself for that.
And don't pound yourself into the ground
when you get there because it happens to
people.
And it isn't necessarily the case that
the reason it happened to you is because
you're useless now that might have
furthered the process and all that,
but you just don't need those thoughts
at that time.
You know,
all they do is undermine you.
And when you know,
yeah,
you know,
everybody's dog dies,
which is true.
It's like,
well,
it takes some of the guilt out of it and
the guilt is something that at that
point you don't really need.
Okay.
So
you've got your explored territory and
we've kind of walked through what that
is and then you have your unexplored
territory.
No.
And then you have the sort of things
that exist on the fringe.
I W I would say in some sense the things
that exist on the fringe,
closer to the unknown,
those are usually symbolized by the,
by the terrible mother.
And then the order is symbolized by the
terrible father.
And then the chaos that's beyond order
beyond knowing,
that's beyond order in chaos.
That's the dragon of chaos.
Now it's a reptile,
right?
A reptilian carnivores.
It's a reptilian carnivore that has a
variety of interesting properties.
So let me show you some of the pictures
that I've got here of the,
of the dragon of chaos.
This is a good one.
So that's a figure called a neuro
burrows.
And you could say in some sense that
that's one of the first graphical
representations of the infinite,
you know,
we have a symbol for infinity,
right?
And so,
which is another thing that's pretty
weird to symbolize because you're
encapsulating something that can't be
encapsulated inside a capsule.
Right?
It's very sneaky to be able to do that.
And you actually need it to do advanced
mathematics of all sorts of kinds.
So you know,
so it's real,
at least in so far as you can use it as
a tool.
So let me tell you a few things about
this symbol.
This representation,
it's kind of like the Judeo Christian
idea of God being the Alpha and Omega,
which is this thing that exists at the
beginning of the time,
time,
all the way to the end of time.
So it's something that that exists
outside of time.
So you could think about this at one
level as the eternal presence of the
Predator,
predators come and go.
The Predator never goes away.
So it's got this God,
like you can say the spirit of the
Predator never disappears.
And as soon as you think that way,
well then you have some idea about what
archaic people were doing when they were
populating the world of spirits.
The difference between a spirit and an
abstract idea is like there's no
difference.
You know,
the spirit of the Predator and Hannah
inhabits the jungle.
It's like,
yeah,
that's for sure.
And you should be very careful about
disturbing such spirits when you go in
there.
Well,
so then you might ask yourself,
well,
what is a predator?
Well,
that's a complicated thing because you
know,
we would say because we're
scientifically minded that you can take
predators and you could classify them
according to their species and there are
subspecies in their Fila and all that
sort of thing.
Right?
Then we think about classifying them as
objects and then maybe in terms of their
evolutionary origins,
but that's not very helpful.
You know,
if something jumps out in and he's wants
to eat you,
I mean,
knowing what it is might help you plot
your escape,
but all those additional complexities,
they're just not the relevant issue at
that point.
The realm of the issue is how do you
keep the predators out away from your
explored territory?
Well,
that's a complicated question because
you might say,
what do you mean by that?
Do you mean right now,
while you're walking through the Bush,
you mean right now for you and your
family?
Will all of you are walking through the
bush.
There's this old joke about these two
guys that go out in the forest and one
guy says to the other,
there's grizzly bears here and
so you have to be careful.
And then the other guy says,
well,
how fast can you run?
And the first guy says,
well don't you mean how fast does the
Grizzly bear rug?
And the first guy says,
no,
that is not what I mean.
I just want to know if I can run faster
than you.
Right,
right.
So,
so right.
And the reason I'm telling you that
stupid joke is because what you want as
an answer to the question depends on
exactly how you put the question.
And so the answer there was,
well,
I don't care if the grizzly bear eats
someone as long as it's not me.
Okay,
fine.
So that's one answer to the question.
But then you might think,
well,
let's keep the grizzly bears away from
me now my family now,
ah,
my tribe now me tomorrow,
my family tomorrow,
my tribe tomorrow,
then across the week,
then across the month,
then across the years,
then maybe forever.
Okay.
So how is it that you have to act so
that you keep the predators away?
Wow.
That starts to become an extraordinarily
complicated problem because the simplest
solution might be,
well,
when there's a Predator around climb a
tree or run into a whole,
which is what lots of animals do,
you know,
but it's pretty partial solution.
They don't get eaten that day.
But what about tomorrow when the
predators little hungrier and kind of a
bonehead and solutional things
considered.
So then you might say,
well if we thought of the spirit of the
Predator,
which is more like the fact that there
is a class of predators and they're
never going to go away,
then miss that question we have to
answer is how do we act so that that
class that's eternal doesn't bother us
anymore than necessary?
Well that's really complicated,
really,
really complicated because it might mean
in some sense,
well how should you act because
conquering the problem of having your
territory invaded cause there's not just
like reptilian and Mammalian predators.
Right.
Like third things with teeth.
There's other people and like there are
a lot worse than anything else that is
going to come at you.
So you also have that problem.
How You keep yourself away from the
predatory people and the foreign tribes
that are going to invade your land
didn't take it well.
So there's,
there's no difference between that
question.
And how do you establish the security of
a nation,
roughly speaking or maybe even how do
you establish peace?
You know what I mean?
It's a question that it doesn't have
obvious borders.
Okay?
So one answer might be stay away from
the dam.
Predators.
Okay,
so you build a big wall or someone else
does and you hide inside the walls.
Well that's not a bad solution.
And of course that's what people started
to do when they originally built cities.
They built these big walls like trump is
going to build between Canada and the U
S and,
and it'll keep the predators out.
But of course,
what do we know from the story of
genesis and from the Taoist symbol,
no matter how big the wall is,
you can't keep out the damn snakes.
So you build a wall and all the snakes
pop up inside.
So it's not a very good solution.
And you know,
that's pretty obvious,
right?
I mean,
my suspicions are that,
uh,
mass shooters who are native to the
United States kill a lot more people in
the u s every week that Mexican,
illegal Mexican immigrants.
So,
well,
soul looks like what problem,
exactly are you solving?
Yup.
Okay.
So the first question you have to solve
when you're,
see,
there's no point,
there's just no solution to this
problem.
Okay.
So why did you laugh at that
do you think?
Cause it opened again and there was
unexpected.
Yeah,
but why didn't that terrify you walk.
But you know what's related to the
hierarchy at she,
right?
Because like the door isn't behaving
properly.
So like what's funny about that?
Well,
it's funny to watch someone,
someone's little routine not work.
When the consequences are trivial.
It's like,
oh well he knows how to close the door.
It's not working.
So now he's got the problem of this door
and that's a stupid problem.
So everybody could laugh about it,
you know?
So little,
little,
little anomalies that you could bind
quickly are comical,
you know,
and I think it's an indication to tell
you the truth.
I think it's an indication of people's
transcendent ability.
Because what happens,
comedians do this with you too,
you know,
so you'd be,
you'd be sitting in the audience,
a comedian,
I'll say this thing,
and then this thing,
and they're connected some way,
but it's not obvious.
And then you go click and you,
and it's like everybody celebrates their
brilliance together.
It's like,
oh,
I get it.
Ha ha ha aren't nice,
smart.
And it's,
it transforms you into the pub from the
puzzle thing into the thing.
And everyone really likes that.
It's like,
yes,
we solved.
It's like,
wait,
we can go and,
you know,
combat down,
known together.
So,
all right,
so you got this chaos thing here.
Now that's,
as I said,
that's called a neuro burrows.
And they're,
the reason it's got its tail in it's
mouth is,
it's,
uh,
the idea that that's trying to represent
is that this thing is complete unto
itself.
So it's a symbol of totality.
It's everything.
How well you walk into the room where
your interview is.
You might say,
what's in there?
While a better question is what's not in
there.
That's a better question because your
whole damn futures in there,
and you don't even know how much that
branches your futures.
They're the future of your children is
in there.
The future of your grandchildren is in
there.
You know,
there's these waves that go out from
that room that that in some sense,
especially if you stretch them forward
in time,
they have almost no boundary.
You know?
I mean,
I dunno.
Each of us is descended from one person.
I don't remember how many millions of
years ago,
but it's not that many to,
maybe it's even earlier than that,
650,000 years,
something like that.
So for all you know,
what do you could be like the person who
through whom the entire human race
lives,
and maybe it's because you made the
right decision in that interview.
My point is,
is that potential itself has no
boundary,
no obvious boundary,
and you don't know what you're messing
with when you're messing with it.
It's very,
very complicated.
So how should you do it?
Well,
this figure says,
well,
you better watch out because some of
it's predatory and the crawls along the
ground and it's got teeth and it's no
damn joke.
And so then you can think it's sort of
snake,
like a snake,
sneak around through the,
through the grass and then it sort of
crocodile light because snakes don't
have teeth,
but crocodile.
Sure the hell do.
And so do other predatory lizards.
And you know,
as we've talked about before,
the probability that our ancestral
planes dwelling African ancestors were
regularly lunched upon by crocodiles.
It's pretty damn high because how else
would they get water?
You know,
and you gotta be pretty mean before you
can take on a Nile crocodile.
I mean,
I'm sure we did that fairly early in our
evolutionary history,
but before that we were,
a lot of us were snacks for lizards.
So,
which seems like just not good,
you know?
So,
okay,
so this thing also lives in a whole
dragon.
It's usually live in holes or
underground,
like Harry Potter's Basilisk and usually
they're immortal.
They live in a cave,
there were mortal,
right?
They live forever.
You don't want to bother them because
then they pop out of their whole,
like they do in the hobbit and they come
and burn down your village.
Like leave the damn dragon alone.
Well,
yes and no.
Why not leave it alone?
Well,
maybe it would be better to go get the
dragon before it gives you that
certainly possible.
And then there's this other weird thing
about dragons,
which is that they hoard.
So maybe you can go and confront the
dragon and you get the treasurer and the
treasurer takes basically two forms.
So there's the St George story where the
treasure is often an,
uh,
like,
trapped young female and other version
is,
well,
the dragon sits on gold.
Now what's the whole idea there?
Well,
maybe the best way to overcome
predators,
the spirit of the creditor is to
confronted.
Well,
that's a hell of an idea.
Then you might think,
well,
how deep an idea is that you confront
the Predator,
you get the gold.
Well,
this is that you confront infinite
possibility and you get the,
the,
the reward you encounter infinite
possibility properly.
You derive from it the rewards that it
offers.
What are the rewards that infinite
possibility offers?
Who knows?
Right.
We have no idea.
And it's so interesting because we live
at a time in history where that's
literally true.
Like I would hesitate to predict
anything about 50 years from now,
I have,
I quit worrying about the future,
about 20 years ago because I thought,
oh,
I get it.
No matter what happens,
the probability that it's something I
predict is zero.
So it's like whatever you're worried
about,
well I'll go ahead and worry about it,
but something completely different is
going to happen.
So,
so it's not really all that useful.
Just be ready for whatever comes because
here it comes,
you know,
like I think where I'll have fully
functional autonomous robots within
three or four years.
So,
and that's like,
that's a real game changer,
you know?
And God only knows what's going to
happen after that.
Transplantable organs,
those things.
Or you can print those on three d
printers already.
What else?
Well,
augmented intelligence,
while you're,
you all have augmented intelligence
already.
What good are facts?
He's look them up,
right?
Everyone's an infinite supply and facts.
Can you explain and different words why
the Dragon?
Because it has everything it needs.
That's,
that's another way of thinking about it.
So it's,
it's self contained.
It doesn't,
it doesn't need anything outside of
itself and there isn't anything outside
of itself.
So it doesn't rely on anything to exist.
That's another way of thinking about,
it's just there.
And so there's an echo of the idea there
that that of have an idea of beyond time
or,
I don't know so much beyond space but
certainly be on time.
Time has no effect on it.
So it's beyond time in that sense.
Yeah.
There's another reason has its tell
snuff and that's because it represents
the border between the known world and
all its goodness and badness.
Unknown world order can get smaller
as it gets more of its tail.
Right,
right.
Okay,
so now it has wings.
Why does it have links?
Okay,
well this is another horribly
complicated thing.
I'll show you a diagram.
This is the closest I've been able to
get to it.
I often don't talk about this diagram,
but I guess I am today.
Yeah.
Okay,
let's,
we must go through this completely.
Okay.
So here's you.
So
if you look right in the middle there,
here I'll,
I'll make it bigger
so that you can see it.
You kind of think that you're right
here.
This is sort of where your consciousness
normally sits.
Like you know,
are you yourself that's sort of your
conscious body envelope and all that.
Are you your family?
Well you know the border there is rather
pliable.
Well then you can go,
you can drill down into the self and
this is sort of the idea of the
hierarchy.
You know,
you can look at principles.
So those are your general philosophical
beliefs and then your programs and then
the sequence of behaviors that you
instantiate that in and then your
behaviors.
And then you can go below that even.
And you can think of yourself as well
because when you're behaving well,
how,
what's under that?
What,
what,
what's the support for that?
The platform for that?
Well,
it's your body,
right?
So what's there?
Well,
once you get past the level of arm,
it's sort of like musculature and then
you might say,
well,
what's,
you know,
what's under that?
Or what's,
what's,
what's next?
Well,
you have your cellular structure.
And so that's what cellular biologist
studying God,
that's so complex.
And then below that,
while you have your molecular structures
like Dna,
and then underneath that there's an
atomic structure.
And then underneath that there's the
subatomic structure.
And what are you going to say about
that?
There wasn't even time at that level.
So,
and then you can do the same thing if
you go up,
it's like people say,
well you shouldn't just pay attention to
your family.
It's like you're,
you're in a cultural group.
They're important too.
And well,
what about the biological group that
that's nested in?
And maybe you should be paying more
attention to the ecosystem rather than
to yourself.
And you know,
you shade upward into this thing that
you can't really,
you can't really dissociate yourself
from Arthur now.
So you know,
so that's what you are.
Make no mistake about it.
Like you will,
your consciousness is such that you only
are located at in some sense at one
level of observation and that God only
knows why that is.
It's almost as if,
you know,
being has to come to a pinpoint in order
for,
for things to exist.
The way I've been thinking about it in
some senses,
like you could take ever all of this
structure and you know,
narrow it down to a single point of a
pencil that's writing and the writing is
the transformation of potential into
actuality.
But in order to do that,
you have to,
you there has to be a point of contact
between you and potential.
And that's,
that's your body and part.
But it's even narrower than that.
It's whatever occupies your,
this tiny little laser beam of attention
while you're wandering through the
world.
And it's like burning reality into
being,
you know,
so why that is,
I mean,
God,
who knows?
It's beyond strange.
Now,
you know,
one way of thinking about this whole
structure is that you can think about it
as the psychological world because
you're at the center of it.
Or you can think about it as the
spiritual world.
If you think about spirit as a
manifestation of consciousness,
it's not a material world anyways.
Or if it is,
it's the material world in so far as
it's you as a living conscious being.
So you know,
we tend to separate out consciousness
and matter,
right?
I mean I'm conscious that that's
something we are,
we don't take this table is so we think
of them as separate substances in a
sense.
Spirit and matter.
Well that's what that dragon is.
It's half matter.
That's the thing that's crawling around
on the ground and it's half spirit and
that's the Wayne's.
And that's many might say,
well why the hell is the dragon half
spirit and half matter
while we've got the spirit park?
I just showed you it.
So now I'm going to show you the
mattered park.
That's worse.
Okay.
So we could say,
well what's that?
Well,
it's,
it's a chair.
You think that's pretty straight
forward?
It's actually not.
And I can tell you why very rapidly.
Um,
why is it a chair?
How would a bean bag,
is that a chair?
Because we can sit in it.
That's right.
Yes.
Because we can sit in it and that seems
to be the fundamental issue.
Is this a chair?
It can be,
yeah.
Yeah.
You'd say it's not a canonical chair and
neither is a bean bag chair.
It could be a bean bag or a stump.
But you know,
that's sort of a canonical chair.
But part of my point is,
you know the typical answer that people
will give when you ask why is that a
chairs that they'll lay out the
objective structure,
which is really no,
that's only a tiny bit of why it's a
chair.
You know,
if it was that high,
well would it be a chair?
It has to have the right structure and
the right function in order for it to be
a chair.
And so what that means is that thing
which is an object is already only
existing in relationship to you in some
important sense.
But I can also say,
well,
it's part of the classroom.
What's the classroom partner?
Well that's part of Sid Smith.
This chair is part of Sid Smith.
And what Sid Smith part of,
well it's part of the university.
And what's the university part of?
Well God,
it's part of all sorts of things,
but we could say it's,
it's a piece of the city.
It's a chunk of the province.
It's a bat of the country.
And then it's west nested inside a much
broader civilization than that.
So that's sort of going up from the
chair and you could say,
well that's not read the chair.
And I could say,
well,
if that thing was floating at some point
halfway between the sun and Pluto,
I don't think considering it and a chair
would be reasonable,
you know,
because well,
for obvious reasons,
you know,
you can decontextualize something so
completely that it isn't what it is
anymore.
It's not that hard.
So you know,
when you kind of do that to yourself,
when you say,
well,
who cares?
Why is this important?
Who's going to know in a million years?
It's like,
poof,
you're decontextualized.
It's like it's a stupid trick.
It's like a party trick for intellect.
It's a stupid trick,
you know,
because anybody can do it.
And what does it mean?
It means you're looking at it from the
wrong perspective.
That's what it means.
So it's not like it's an ultimate
question.
You wouldn't be able to think about in
15 seconds if it was an ultimate
question,
you know,
so,
but then you can do the same thing with
the chair that you did with yourself
when you zoom into it.
Right?
So it's,
it's made of parts obviously.
And then the parts are made out of sub
parts and so forth,
all the way down to the subatomic level
and the chairs,
all those things at the same time.
Okay.
So then you might say,
well what do you encounter when you
encounter the unknown?
And that's what you'll encounter?
I think.
So let's take a look at this and you can
think about this.
So weird idea.
Okay.
So you've got your little frame of
reference,
right?
You're going from point a to point b and
then when you're going from point a to
point b,
something that you didn't want to happen
happens.
And we already know that it can be a
little thing that happens and then you
know,
Haha it's funding or it can be like your
whole world falls apart and then it's a
catastrophe.
But let's say it's something like the
interview.
So I would say that sort of a mid level
anomaly,
right?
You walk in,
there's a lot in there,
but you can handle it weirdly enough.
And I suppose that's because there's
other places you can go where there are
potential futures lying.
So it's not like you're out of potential
futures just because you walk through
that.
So when you say,
well,
what's in that room is,
it's anomalous,
you don't understand it,
it's unformed matter.
Now you might say,
someone might say,
uh,
does this interview matter to you?
You think?
That's pretty weird question because
things are made out of matter.
So what does it mean when you say,
does this matter to you?
Well,
partly what it means is that before
matter was our matter.
It was a matter that was more
complicated linguistically speaking.
So back,
if you go back far enough,
what people meant by matter wasn't this,
it was,
it was more like,
I would say it's more like potential or
it's more like information.
That's another way of thinking about it.
So you could certainly say that room was
chocked full of information.
So,
so let's go with the information idea.
Just for the sake of argument.
We already talked about it as potential.
Let's talk about it as information.
Both of those work.
You walk in there and you start
interacting with people.
Okay.
And then you leave later and you know,
you,
you tell your partner,
they say,
well I went for this interview and they
say,
how did it go?
And you say,
well I didn't go very well but I learned
some things cause you could say that.
Right.
Well so I would say you went into that
room and you extracted some spirit out
of the potential.
Now that's exactly how piaget looked at
it,
by the way.
Well I shouldn't say exactly because you
know,
it's probably not exactly the way he
looked at it.
But basically what piaget proclaimed
with children was that children have
tried a little routine and then
something will happen that doesn't fit
in their little routine.
And so they all investigate it using
whatever tools they have at hand.
Some of it's trial and error and some of
it's,
you know,
they try out other tool like embodiments
of their body that have worked in the
past.
So for example,
the first thing I say a nine month old,
we'll do crawling around on the floor.
If it encounters something that's
roughly mouth sized,
we'll put it in her mouth.
Why?
Well they don't know what it is,
but they don't kind of how to use their
mouse.
So they throw it in their mouth and then
they,
Tom Hinten,
you know,
they get some sense of how it tastes,
which is very important and what its
shape is and all of that.
Cause they're very wired up in their
mouth and so they can investigate like
mad.
And so what they encounter is a thing.
And then when they throw it in their
mouth,
they practice doing something with it,
you know,
getting a shape.
So now they know something about it.
So that changes them from a spiritual
perspective,
a psychological perspective.
Now they're slightly different than they
were.
They've incorporated some information
and they've also transformed the thing
into a specific thing with specific
features.
And so what you might say is that out of
potential spirit and matter arise,
and it's a very interesting way of
looking about looking at it.
Also,
it fits well with the phenomenological
philosophers because they believe that
we encountered phenomenon and phenomena
where those phenomena were those things
that sean forth.
And so that's like a reversion to the
idea of meaning,
because you got to think about it this
way too.
It's like when you walk into a library,
God,
what's in there?
Well,
it's inexhaustible.
The library.
Well,
how come you just don't get exhausted?
that's because you're not actually
interacting with the whole library.
You've got this focal point like the
laser again,
and you've made it into a focal point
because you're inside that hierarchical
structure,
right?
And so you say,
well,
I'm in the library to get this book.
I'm getting this book to read this
chapter.
So chapter book,
Library,
I'm going to university,
I need to become educated and get a job
so that I'll be a good citizen and a
good person.
And so that's what you're doing in the
library.
You're just doing one little fragment of
that.
And the more you have that whole model
developed,
right all the way from good person right
down to why you were in the library,
the more precise your aim is,
the more you know what you're doing,
the less encumbered by doubt and
uncertainty you are and the higher
probability you have of focusing on your
task and then writing the past that you
want to be into Ba and so well.
So it's very useful to think about
things this way and it's also very
interesting to note that that's how you
act.
You actually act like the world has made
this way and it's even weirder because
this is the case that I made for you
when we were talking about the structure
of the brain,
it actually looks like this is how your
brain construes the world and because
you have systems,
you've got the system that works.
When you know what you're doing and
you've got the other system that works
when you don't know what you're doing.
And so basically the world is divided
just like the dallas say into the
orderly domain and the chaotic domain.
And you need to know how to operate in
both and you need to balance them and
you need to transform one into the
other.
And that's basically what you're doing
when you're interacting with reality.
And you know,
one of the things that I would,
I will claim,
and this will become more important as
the course progresses,
is that when you're doing something
meaningful,
you're doing that property.
And the sense of meaning that you have
is actually an indication that your
psychophysiology is manifesting,
that you're in the right place at the
right time doing the right thing.
And it's real.
It's not only real,
it's like it's the most real thing.
It's where potential is transformed into
reality and it's hard to get any more
real than that.
So that's partly why I'm telling you
that these things aren't exactly
metaphors.
You know,
they have to be represented by metaphor
in some sense.
But the reality of this underlying them
isn't,
it's not just a story.
Even though it is a story,
It's a real representation of reality.
So you know,
the other thing I kind of outlined here
is that when you hit an the,
normally it's sort of the anomaly is the
thing from which everything shines
forth.
You know,
when it's still really anomalous,
what happens is it,
it manifests itself to you in sort of
like a burst of contradictory meanings.
And that can be paralyzing.
You know,
you can be really,
really,
really excited and reading,
reading,
nervous,
which might happen.
For example,
if you were going to a job interview and
you actually wanted the job,
it would be even worse if you went to a
job interview and like 30% of you wanted
the job because you know that's the 30%
that wants to develop and now they're
30% would just soon fail so that you
crawl under your bed at home and stay
there with the dust bunnies til you're
40 and you know another 25% of you is
resentful about the fact that you got to
have to go get a stupid job at all.
And so then you go in there and it's
really,
really complicated because not only is
that all that potential there,
but your fractured and those fractures
make the whole situation way more
complicated and unstable than it would
otherwise have to be.
So,
and that happens to people all the time,
you know,
I mean people hedge their bets in job
interviews all the time cause they
think,
eh,
I don't really care.
It's like,
no,
you care.
You just want to have a story to tell
yourself.
If you fail while and then if you have
that story,
well then probably you're going to fail
because you don't get to do that.
You can't go in there at 60% and hope to
win.
You have to go in there at 100% now
that's cool too,
because what it implies is just what the
clinical psychologist have been telling
people for 60 years or 70 years,
right?
You have to voluntarily face the things
that you're afraid of.
Now,
it's a little more complicated than that
because otherwise you could just go play
in traffic,
you know,
so it's,
it's not a call to stupid adventure.
What it does is assume that you've gone
a direction and that the direction is it
valid direction,
and then that what happens is as you
pursue that,
obstacles emerge,
anomalous,
threatening obstacles,
and then you either confront them or you
abandon the whole project,
while generally speaking,
if you chop them into little pieces,
then you can confront them and digest
them,
and then you get stronger because you're
doing all this digesting.
It's like you're eating,
you're eating the monster of chaos.
And that's a classic metaphor for,
for developing wisdom to ingest piaget
than uses that,
right?
Assimilate.
It's exactly the same idea as ingesting
instead of what you're eating is
information instead of matter.
And so,
you know,
and the information restructures you,
it makes you more informed and that puts
you more information.
So,
so you know,
you,
you encounter the anomaly and it's a
burst of contradictory potential.
And so that's exactly how you respond to
it.
Your body's going everywhere at once
because God only knows what's going to
happen.
And then as you interact with it,
it collapses.
You're collapsing it.
That's what happens when you take
control of the situation and then you
reduce it to a single path where
everything's going properly.
And you might say,
well,
you're bending it to your own selfish
wills,
but that's not right.
Because if you're in,
let's say you're in an interview and
there's five or six people in there,
you can't just bend the damn thing to
your will because you have to interact
with those people.
And so if you don't do that with,
you know,
you can be a psychopath and manipulate,
but that will only work for a short
period of time.
You'll get caught and then you'll have
to move because that's what psychopaths
do.
But if you're,
that's how they keep being psychopaths.
You know,
they exhaust everyone's trust and then
they have to move and then they go find
some other people who are trustworthy
because they built up trust capital with
other people and then they betrayed
them,
but they have to keep moving.
So it's an unstable solution.
So you go in there and you do it
properly.
Well,
what are you doing exactly?
No,
I would say that if you're really,
really nailing that interview,
you're saying,
well,
here's a,
here's a future that we could all march
together into consonantly and happily
that's what you're saying.
And I'm the person to do that.
Now you might be saying that on a
relatively low scale,
like if I'm your assistant,
you're never going to have to worry
about me because I'm always going to be
there,
you know?
And then if maybe you're the CEO,
you're going to say,
well,
you know,
this is,
this is the way that all of us are going
and here's why,
and this is what it's going to look
like.
And the better you are at that,
the more that potential will turn into
it multiplies.
That's what happens if you're good at
dealing with it,
the potential that's accessible to you
multiply.
So,
which is really cool.
And also how you'd hope it would be
cause you don't,
you hope that more potential would
manifest itself to people who are more
competent.
Things worked well.
That would be good.
So,
so that's the spirit matter idea.
And so that's represented in that
drag it.
So let's go back to him.
No.
Okay.
So are you remember this character here?
So what to do about that?
What to do about chaos?
Well,
one thing you might want to start by
doing is admitting that it exists.
You know?
So let's say that you're,
you're not a terror management advocate.
Let's say you're an advocate of positive
illusions.
Does everybody know what those are?
Just do you or are you still taught
about those in social psychology?
Positive illusions?
Yes.
No.
How many people know about them?
Okay.
Where did you learn about them?
Your class.
Okay.
Sexy 30 in two 30 yeah.
No one else has taught you about this.
Anybody else learned it to anywhere
else?
You learned it online.
Okay,
well thank God for that.
Well,
what happened was the paper where
positive illusions were first pouted and
that was in social psychology.
So it was in the Journal of Personality
and social psychology.
That was the most cited,
the most cited paper ever in social
psychology.
It's up there.
Yeah.
And it's an appalling paper because it
basically says,
it says something like this,
if you scrape away all the nonsense,
things are so horrible that if you just
looked at them,
you'll be so depressed.
You want to die so you better not you
better.
We've around yourself an illusion that
things are better than they are and that
you're more powerful and wonderful venue
actually are.
And if you do that but not too much,
then you're going to be happier.
Well,
you know,
the error is in that are just manifolds
first.
Like,
well who cares if you're happy,
what the hell does that have to do with
anything?
You know,
it could be happy stepping on ats,
you know,
so well really it's like what the hell
stupid ideas that you've got.
Positive emotion,
Caucasian cocaine will do that.
You know,
bullies are pretty happy when they're
pounding out someone like mill house,
you know,
so happiness is,
what the hell is that?
It's shallow.
It's a dopey idea.
So,
and then,
well,
how big should these lies that you're
telling yourself be?
And answer that as well.
Just exactly the size that will make you
happy.
Well that's not helpful because if
you're going to have a theory,
let's hear about exactly how big they
should be.
Well,
sometimes they should be this big and
then other times they shouldn't be this
big,
but there's no real way of telling a
priority while.
So that's not really very helpful
either.
So,
and then there's another id underneath
that that's even worse,
which is reality is so awful that you
can't look at it.
Well that's,
that's nasty man.
Because that means,
and that,
and that is what the pause to pollution
stuff,
man.
Sort of like the terror management
theories.
If you got an unvarnished look at
reality,
it would just destroy it because you're,
you're not strong enough to look at
reality in an unvarnished manner.
Well,
you can imagine why people would believe
that.
I mean you,
you could,
you could thank God.
Yes.
I mean,
you know,
it's pretty damn awful,
but then you think,
well,
wait a minute,
is it read the case that everyone who's
out there coping with the world is like
blind and diluted?
Or maybe is it that the people who are
not coping with the world very well or
blind and diluted,
I mean,
ask yourself that you see people in your
life that you know,
you admire.
I presume as certainly you've seen
people you don't admire.
Well also like let's take the ones you
don't admire.
Well,
how bout blind in diluted?
Does that partially described them?
It would be blind,
diluted,
bitter,
resentful at mean that sort of covers
the territory.
So,
and then the people you admire?
Well,
they're strong people.
Generally.
They can do things that are really
ridiculously difficult,
like have a baby and raise it without
destroying it,
you know,
or work in a palliative care board or be
a nurse in a cancer ward for children or
you know,
or,
I mean there's a lot of awful things.
I talked to this guy the other day,
I just met him sort of randomly and he
had had a motorcycle accident that was a
bad one.
He rolled like 200 feet at 60 miles an
hour when he broke seven ribs and you
know,
had a brain hemorrhage and like it
really took it out to them.
And he was a good athlete before that.
And so it probably aged him 20 years,
you know,
and he's still recovering.
And he was telling me he works for a
power company,
so he's climbing up these power poles,
you know,
because that's part of his job.
Well now he's pretty screwed up.
He's in his mid fifties he's still
climbing up power poles and he was
working with a guy who had Parkinson's
disease.
And so the guy with the Parkinson's
disease is at the top of the power pole
doing his job,
but he's getting shaky.
So they're afraid things are going to
fall.
And then this guy comes up behind him to
help him.
He's only really got one arm that works.
It's like Jesus,
that's tough.
Those people are tough,
man.
You know,
because Parkinson's,
that sucks and well,
so just having half your arm more or
less destroyed by a motorcycle acts and
not staying at home,
hiding under the bed,
you know,
they're out there still making sure the
lights are on.
Well that's a pretty ardent unvarnished
confrontation with reality as far as I'm
concerned.
You know?
So I couldn't say.
All right.
So here's another story.
So
I probably told you a little bit about
this before,
when the behaviorist first proposed that
you could use exposure to treat anxiety.
The psychoanalysts were all skeptical
about that because they thought while
you're just treating the symptom,
they usually thought of a full bi as the
manifestation,
the visible manifestation of something
that was more that learn more deeply
underground and there's real truth and
not like,
okay,
whatever a mouse is to someone who's
mouse phobic isn't what MLC is.
Cue the mouse is a bunch of other things
because otherwise they wouldn't be
afraid of it.
And so all those,
you could say the mouse is an exemplar
of the category of all things that
they're afraid of.
And that's a good way of thinking what
it might mean symbolically.
And so I had one client who was afraid
of mice and she thought one would run up
her leg and she was also afraid of being
raped.
And those two things were,
there was a,
a metaphorical union between them,
even though they weren't,
you know,
are obviously not exactly the same.
So the psychoanalysts,
they're making their point,
you know,
but it turned out that it now,
so the original behavior theory was you
can't be anxious and calm at the same
time.
So what you do first,
if you're going to teach someone not to
be afraid of a mouse,
is teach them how not to be afraid.
So you put them in the chair and you do
a relaxation exercise with them and then
you show them a picture of a mouse and
you say,
just breathe.
You know,
calm down.
And so they all,
they calm down and then sooner or later
they can look at the pictures of mice by
themselves.
And then maybe you could throw a like
stuffed mouse them and then maybe,
you know,
they could walk by a pet store and look
at her house and so on and so forth
until you get them like holding rats.
And so,
you know,
that works works,
but it works even if you don't relax
them.
Fact,
it works just as well.
So the oil behavioral idea that was
countered conditioning was wrong.
Just like the idea that the reason you
were afraid of a rat was because of
conditioning.
It's like,
of course you're afraid of a rat.
It's a rat.
You know?
It's just like you're afraid of snakes,
you know,
to a lesser or greater degree in people
actually become more afraid of stakes as
they get older.
Interestingly enough,
which is not what you really expect,
right?
Unless it was a biological function.
So anyways,
all you have to show people the thing
they're afraid of and what did they
learn?
They don't learn that the thing isn't
frightening.
They learn that they're tough.
And so one of the things,
and that's why generalize it.
So which is the behavior.
See No psychoanalysts predicted what
would happen is as well,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
You're not afraid of a mouse anymore,
but like you're,
you're twice as afraid of being raped in
your cabin when you're up there alone.
It's like,
no,
that isn't what happens.
You're not afraid of the mouse anymore
and your half is afraid of being alone
up in your cabinet.
It generalizes.
And so if you take someone who's
agoraphobic and in their mid forties and
somewhat dependent,
and you treat them for their
agoraphobic,
and then they'll go home and give their
husband tail,
cause they're usually women and tell
them all the things that they'd been
wanting to tell him for 20 years.
But it'd be too afraid to because they
thought he might leave.
And then they were afraid that,
you know,
he'd leave and they fall apart and all
of that.
So they get you teach them that they
don't have to run out of the subway and
all of a sudden they get more
confrontation.
And the reason for that is because they
get more courageous.
And the reason for that is they go do
something difficult and they watch
themselves and hey,
they could do it.
And so one of the things you might ask
about yourself is how do you know what
you have to run away from?
You know,
you might be so damn tough,
you just can't bloody well imagine it
and you're just,
you know,
you just sort of a sheltered,
you know.
Now look,
you're a lot less sheltered than you
were when you were three,
I presume.
How many of you live on your own?
Okay,
now that was a transition,
I presume.
How many of you were depressed and
anxious their first year of university?
Okay,
how many of you work?
Yeah.
Okay,
so it's about 50% well,
that's about right.
Both the third of first year u of t
students meet clinical criteria for
depression according to the Beck
depression inventory.
Well,
why?
it's hard.
You know,
you leave your family,
you're kind of protected there.
You go out,
you have to figure out all the things
you have to do to keep yourself alive.
And then you have to go to university
and they're going to give you an
impossible amount of work that no one
could ever possibly master.
So it's daunting.
And then you're surrounded by people who
are smarter than the people you're used
to being surrounded by.
So that means you're not as smart as you
thought you were.
And you meet people now,
men who are way smarter than you,
and way harder working and way better
looking.
And all of those phases.
So,
you know,
it's,
it's depressing,
but by the same token,
how many of you feel less armed to take
on the world then you get five years
ago?
You're not gonna admit it probably.
But I presume that that's a very small
number.
How many of you feel more prepared?
Okay.
So that's pretty cool.
So what that means is that you went out
there and get a whole bunch of difficult
things and some of those things you've
been reading each other's
autobiographies,
right?
How's that going to be an interesting,
yeah.
Is it worthwhile?
Anybody think it isn't worthwhile?
I really want to know,
you know,
because you know what's,
it's kind of an experiment,
some sense to see how this was working,
what's good about it
so you can get to know.
So why do you like that?
Cause it makes the class feel more like,
yeah,
you know,
I'm,
I'm thinking about working with the
company and the Edmonton is setting that
up as a,
we increase increasing trust among
people who work together with the same
company.
They're not going to be sharing your
deepest secrets.
But what they will be doing is having
structured conversations where they find
out a little bit about each other.
You know,
when it sort of,
it seems like have a relationship with
someone,
you'd kind of have to get to know their
hierarchical structure.
Right.
And if it's just the,
like the sh the tiniest things,
well that person sits at the desk and
types,
well it's a shallow relationship.
If it's a deep relationship,
you know much more about the whole
structure.
Right.
Which I think is why the,
the metaphor of depth works so well,
you know?
Okay.
So,
so you found that it like catalyze the
classroom a little bit more,
sorry.
Yeah.
And like,
isn't it like you fall in love with them
when they're applying for,
yeah.
So that's an interesting thing to a
about the whole vulnerability issue.
Yeah.
It's like
if you're forming a relationship with
someone,
what you do is you basically mutually
open up your shells and you know what's,
or you kind of go like this,
you know?
And if you could ask to close
permanently,
well then you go.
But yeah.
So that's another thing that's
interesting too,
because one of the prizes that unless
you,
you know,
voluntarily expose your vulnerabilities,
you'll never find partner or they won't
be a real partner cause they don't know
who the hell you are and then you're
weak because there's only one of you,
you know,
so.
Yep.
Yeah.
So why'd you like that?
Because I can share it,
like making decisions but not feel like
anyone really,
you know,
there's some evidence that people like
computer guided psychotherapy for
exactly that reason.
It's like you can be completely honest
with the computer cause like it doesn't
care.
Not yet.
It's will soon,
but,
but you probably won't judge you any
more harshly than you said it too.
It's like love and affection today.
Well that won't be very far away.
Okay.
So what are other people have to say
about the autobiography?
Yeah,
I find really interesting because like I
never sold dp on that person as be
stokes share.
Then as we get has to be taught what
weight thinking beginning of their
childhood up to this point.
You never really had that conversation.
Hmm.
So you liked that too?
Yeah.
Like why,
why,
what was good about it for you?
Thank you.
See,
you get to see usually as,
even if you're like say just like you
want to reach out to your agent and
every student like holistically,
but watching them grow,
it's Kinda like,
it's Kinda very strange because we don't
think about people in that.
Right.
Well you're seeing more of this say.
Yeah.
You know,
because the person actually extends
across time and you're right.
All you see as a slice,
well they're not a slice at the whole
damn thing and this thing that grows
across time.
Yeah.
So,
okay.
Who,
who else has something to say?
That's interesting.
Ha.
Half the people don't want to talk now.
So anybody else?
Okay.
After doing that and writing so many
things about myself,
I actually,
I was talking about the assignment to a
couple of friends and it really thought
I'd actually be okay if the people who
read my assignment,
like identified who I was and like even
like engage in conversation with me.
And it really kind of inspired me to be
more honest about sharing myself.
Like do my existing relationships.
Huh.
So why did you conclude that it would be
okay if someone identified you?
Because I felt a desire to be seen more
and it was kind of,
I felt more with myself when I was
disclosing more information about
myself.
And so it made me want to be more with
myself in my existing kitchen shit.
Okay.
Back to what is a very good observation.
So I'm going to say a couple of things
about that and you tell me if you think
they're accurate.
Okay.
So the first thing is,
yeah,
it's an act of courage to expose
yourself to someone.
No,
we're not going to say that precisely.
It's an active car.
It's an act of courage too,
to be truthful with someone because
they're actually interacting with the
actual you.
So there's no facade.
Okay.
So that's one thing.
So you get more courageous.
But then the next thing might be,
I would say that you have a more
sympathetic relationship with yourself.
Yeah.
You know,
because let's say you have this stupid
memory about some dumb you did when you
were 13 and you're still carrying that
along.
It's like Jesus,
you know,
you were 13,
what the hell?
You expect 15 year olds,
they're just dumb as sticks.
They're going to do all sorts of stupid
things.
They're brains are all addled from
hormones and they're trapped in those
little educational prisons and you know,
so they're going to do stupid things.
But if you're carrying that,
it's like it's you that did that.
It's not some stupid 13 year old that
you once word.
So then you can start to see yourself in
perspective.
You know,
as a 13 year old like other 13 year
olds,
you know,
no better but perhaps no worse.
So you can get on your,
you can get on your side in some sense
by walking through your story and seeing
what the causal elements are.
Does that seem reasonable?
Okay.
Yeah.
Well,
so that's a good thing.
That's a good thing.
I think.
Um,
I really liked it again,
because you really get to know other
people and that's,
that's,
um,
I really liked that aspect of it.
I think it was also interesting that I
think other people
not necessarily knew more about you than
you did,
but they can talk a little bit
information that you gave them.
The,
I know,
um,
someone looked at something that I'd
written a completely different light
than I did.
I thought that was so interesting.
And just like the idea of looking at it,
I guess a little bit more from the
outside and getting a different
perspective.
Well that's what's the famous poem about
the best gift we could possibly be given
us to see ourselves as others see us.
I think it's Robbie Burns and I just
mangled the hell out of them.
But that's basically what it meant.
And Yeah,
you do get that opportunity and,
okay.
And it's weird and this is something the
positive illusion people never think
about either,
is that sometimes people think they're
better than they are,
like objectively whatever that means.
But lots of times the opposite is true
or not.
And I think often it's true even more
often it's like people think they're a
lot worse than they are.
No one's as anxious as me or as
concerned about acts or,
you know,
was confused about this,
or,
you know,
as socially awkward or is not funny,
or,
you know,
everybody's got their paranoia about
this part of the niche,
the worst that anyone could possibly be
in the entire world.
And it's almost never,
almost never true.
You know,
other people are a lot more like that,
then you think,
and they're running around trying to
hide it madly as well,
so,
so that's a good thing.
Well,
you know,
you also allow your,
in some sense,
you're allowing yourself out into the
light.
You go through your life and you think,
well,
I can allow other people.