Hello everybody,
my name is Angelo and I am your Mc for
the evening and uh,
on behalf of the UBC free speech club,
we would like to welcome you and thank
you for attending our third Dr Jordan b
Peterson event.
Thanks.
Now.
I know you were all very excited to hear
the man,
so I'm going to keep these opening
remarks very short.
The UBC free speech club is devoted to
the sanctity of liberty in our society
and the necessity to keep liberty safe
from those who want to destroy it within
just the York club has grown to over a
thousand members and is now in the
process of incorporation so that we may
continue to bring speakers and host
events such as this one.
None of that would be possible without
Dr. Peterson who has inspired countless
students all over North America to start
speaking up on their campus.
And in fact this club's sprung up around
the same time when Dr Peterson publicly
came out against bill.
See 16
now is just over a year ago.
And since then,
his philosophy of cleaning your room and
sorting yourself out has a better than
influenced the lives of countless
people.
He's an accomplished psychologist,
professor and author.
His book maps of meaning is an
analytical window into the myths and
cultures of humankind.
And now he's written a new book,
it's called 12 rules for life and had to
go to chaos.
And it's available for preorder on
Amazon with the release date of January
23rd 2018.
And on that note,
uh,
on behalf of the UBC free speech club,
we would like to introduce you all to Dr
Jordan b Peterson.
Well,
thank you very much for that.
That's,
that's quite something.
Alright,
there's a house,
Mike,
Right?
I don't need this one.
Perfect.
Okay.
Well then let's just move it out of the
way,
right?
So I'm going to talk to you tonight
about the ideological nexus of
postmodernism and Marxism and I want to
get into it fairly deeply so you can
have a thoughtful,
thoughtful,
a talk and then discussion afterwards.
So it's a confusing topic because it's
not obvious by any stretch of the
imagination.
Why postmodernism.
And and neo Marxism,
Marxism proper would be aligned because
postmodernism is an anti grand narrative
philosophical movement and Marxism is a
grand narrative and so the fact that
those two things seem to coexist in the
same space needs definitely needs some
explanation and it's a very tricky thing
to get to the bottom of
so we won't get to the bottom of it,
but we'll get farther to the bottom of
it.
Then I've got before and hopefully
farther than many of you have got
before.
So let's see what we can figure out
here.
So I'm going to start with some.
Some definitions all returned to them as
we continue.
You know,
with philosophical movements,
there are often not named by the major
thinkers in the movement.
They're sort of named afterwards.
The name covers a very large range of
ideas and actions and perceptions.
Like it's not that easy.
People talk about existentialism,
for example.
It's not that easy to come up with a one
paragraph summary of what constitutes
existentialism.
My sense for the existentialists is that
it's a.
it's,
it's fundamentally a movement.
It's predicated on the idea,
at least in,
in the psychological sense that,
um,
you know,
Freud tended to attribute human
suffering and mental disorder to
childhood trauma.
Um,
it's more complex than that,
but that'll do for,
for a quick overview,
but the existentialists thought that
there was enough suffering intrinsic in
life so that it wasn't insanity.
That was the question.
It was sanity.
It was how it was possible for people to
be saying and,
and,
and let's say normal,
for lack of a better word,
given that there was brutality and
malevolence intrinsic in life,
and the fact that you had to rise up as
an individual and,
and stand in relation to that
relationship to that is part and parcel
of what constitutes existentialism.
And there's all sorts of different
people who were thinkers who were
existentialist.
Some of them atheistic,
some of them deeply religious like
Dostoevsky,
but so it's not.
I'm using that as an example to show you
how difficult it is to bring a set of
thinkers under one umbrella.
You're bound to over simplify,
but
we'll go ahead and oversimplify
postmodernism.
You can think about it as an attitude of
skepticism,
irony towards and rejection of grand
narratives,
ideologies and universalism,
including the idea of the objective,
notions of reason.
That's a big one.
Human Nature.
Social Progress,
absolute truth in objective reality.
All those things being questioned.
Um,
I kinda think of the head joker at the
top of the postmodern hierarchy as
Derrida.
Foucault is often mentioned as are a
number of other people.
Um,
here's some other attributes of
postmodern thinking.
There's a recognition of the existence
of hierarchy,
that's for sure.
And there's an echo of that idea,
the recognition of hierarchy in the term
patriarchy because of course patriarchy
is a recognition of hierarchy.
Now it's a very particular kind of
recognition,
but the postmodernists also tend to
define hierarchy as a consequence of
power differential.
And so the world day envisioned,
as far as I can tell,
it's something like a,
it's a sociologically hobbsy in
nightmare.
So hobbes thought of the philosopher
Thomas Hobbes,
thought of the natural state of human
beings as every individual in some
sense,
at the throat of every other individual
so that the basic state of man,
mankind,
unlike the Rousseau's state of say
virgin innocence and the Primitive
Garden of paradise was an all out war of
everyone against everyone else and that,
that required the imposition of the
social order to keep peace essentially.
So it's a,
it's a fairly dark view of,
of humankind.
Russo on the other hand,
we think of people as intrinsically good
and the social order as intrinsically
tyrannical,
you can actually think about hobbes and
Rousseau in some sense of,
as,
as opposites that need to be paired
together in order to get a relatively
comprehensive view of human nature.
Well,
the postmodern view is like the hobbs
and view in some sense,
except you want to replace the
individual with,
with,
with pyramids of,
of social organization.
So hierarchies of social organization
that are based on group identity,
um,
and that the landscape in which those
pyramids exists is one of unbroken
enmity and inability to communicate.
So it's a very dark view as far as I'm
concerned and I.
I think it's fundamentally wrong in many
ways.
I mean it,
it's right in that there are groups of
people and there is some difficulty in
communication between them and that
power is an element in the formation of
hierarchies,
but you can't reduce hierarchy or group
relationship to those premises.
It's too simplified because people also
cooperate.
We're also not groups.
Men,
we,
many of us belong to many groups,
so it's to the actual situation is far
too complex to reduce it to that degree,
to reduce it to that degree.
Even though you can come up with a good
explanatory story if you do so,
it doesn't capture the nuances and
they're not just nuances.
It doesn't capture the essence.
Now,
the thing is is that when you make the
presupposition that the reason that
hierarchies exist is because of power,
then essentially what you do is turn
every hierarchy into a tyranny.
And so if you,
if there is a hierarchy,
then you assume it's a tyranny.
Well,
that's really the patriarchy.
The Patriarchy is hierarchy assumed as
tyranny,
and that's also just not true except in
pathological hierarchies.
So for example,
we know from the psychological
literature that the best predictors of
longterm life success,
our intelligence and conscientiousness
in in western countries at least.
Well,
that's what you'd hope for,
right?
More or less,
if you,
if you wanted even just set up a
society,
even if you weren't particularly smart
or hard working,
you might want to set up a society where
intelligence and hard work,
we are good predictors of success
because then the people who were smart
and hardworking would produce a bunch of
things that you could have if you could
trade for them.
And of course that is actually the
situation that most of us are in.
So,
and of course,
the other thing about people who
believed that hierarchies in the West
are only composed of power and tyranny,
is that their own actions belie that
because whenever they make a decision to
interact with that hierarchy,
they attempt or to make a purchase or,
or to make a trade,
let's say,
or to obtain a service,
a service of any importance.
Let's say a medical service,
they are going to definitely act as if
there are less and more competent people
within that hierarchy and seek out the
ones that are more competent obviously,
but you don't do if the,
if the hierarchy is only composed of
tyranny and power,
there's no point looking for competence.
But anyways,
in the west and in functioning
societies,
hierarchies are basically predicated on
competence and not power.
And,
and you might say,
well that's pretty naive.
It's like,
no,
actually it's not very naive.
Um,
I'm not saying at all that inappropriate
powerplays don't play a role in
corrupting hierarchies of competence
that happens.
But generally what happens is if the
hierarchies of competence get corrupted
enough by power,
then they crumble because they can no
longer function.
So the,
you know,
the evidence that are hierarchies of
competence.
Work is everywhere because everything
around us works all the time.
Ion.
Here's the elite tells to two
interesting stories in her book,
infidel,
which is a great book by the way.
Um,
she came from Africa and from a country
that wasn't very functional.
And when she came to Holland,
she said there were two things that
really amazed her,
um,
and this really struck me because,
you know,
now,
and then you get lucky and you can see
the world you live in from an outsider's
perspective,
right?
You get to see through someone else's
eyes.
Um,
she said the first thing that knocked
her off her feet was waiting for a bus
in,
in Amsterdam,
and on the,
you know,
she's standing at the bus stop and
there's a pole there and there's digital
sign on the pole and the digital science
says when the next bus is going to come
and counts down.
And then when it hits zero,
the bus appears and she,
she just,
she absolutely could not believe that
that would happen.
That there could be a sign that told you
when the bus would come and that it
would change and the bus would actually
appear.
And you think,
well,
yeah,
no,
that's a miracle man.
That's an absolute miracle.
It is.
You got to think that through,
you know,
the amount of timing and organization
and and and and reliability,
mechanical reliability and sociological
or social organization and dedication on
the part of the bus drivers in the
entire company and the organization if
the whole city and the state to make
that possible is absolutely beyond
belief,
especially when it's time to,
well perhaps not the second but to 10
seconds or something like that.
That is absolutely beyond belief and her
inability to comprehend.
That was the correct response.
And then the other things she was amazed
by was that you could go talk to
policemen and they would help you.
That was just,
that was just a no go for her because
for her,
her experience was policemen were there
to shake you down and hurt you.
And so you think,
well,
you know,
I won't.
I won't dwell on that point any longer.
The point is,
is that it's absolutely ridiculous blind
to make the assumption that the
hierarchies in functioning Western
democracies are fundamentally predicated
on power and tyranny.
And then,
you know,
I can use a biological example too,
which would place me outside of the
postmodern realm of argument because the
postmodernists don't believe in biology,
but,
but they act like they do because they
all die.
So,
so,
uh,
this primatologist named.
Well,
I'll tell you two stories.
Okay.
Because these are,
these are really useful.
So the ones about rats,
and I got this story from Jaak Panksepp
who is a great neuroscientists.
He wrote a book called affective
neuroscience,
which by the way is on my reading list
that's on my website.
It's a really good book affect of
neuroscience.
He's a great scientist.
He was one of the people who he learned
that he learned that rats laugh.
They laugh out ultrasonically like bat.
So if you're gonna you take a look with
a pencil eraser,
they laugh,
but you have to record it and then slow
it down and then you can hear them and
you might think,
well,
rats laugh,
like,
who wants to eat?
Get a grant for that.
What kind of idiocy is that?
It's like,
no,
no.
Just don't,
don't,
don't get ahead of yourself here,
you know,
he was showing that,
that that capacity for social
interaction,
for social interaction that was mediated
by physiological touch activated the
same,
excuse me,
activated the same circuits in rats,
that it doesn't people and that those
are actual biological circuits,
and we share them even with rats.
Now,
rats are quite similar to human beings.
As it turns out,
I could say especially postmodernists,
but I won't.
And uh,
and,
and so the fact that,
that,
you know,
the little rats giggle when you tickle
them is actually extraordinarily
important.
He also identified
surprising.
I've been talking too much lately.
He also identified the primary place
circuit and mammals.
And that's a big deal too from a
scientific perspective.
That's like discovering a new continent,
like discovering a whole brain system
that people really didn't know existed.
That's a big deal.
So here's a little story about rats.
Young rats like to engage in rough and
tumble play,
especially juvenile males.
It's also the case for puppies.
If you've ever had a puppy,
dogs are like that.
They liked to wrestle and it's one of
the things that male human beings tend
to do with their offspring and it's a
really,
really good thing like rough and tumble
play with children really helps
socialize them because it helps them
figure out the difference between touch
and even rough touch and pain because
one of the things you're doing when
you're rough and tumble playing with the
little kid is you know,
you throw them up in the air and you're
wrestling around.
I built my.
I had two couches when my kids were
little that were sort of face to face,
so we built this little wrestling ring
and I used to go in there and pound them
half to death every night.
You know,
so they love that.
I mean they get so excited about that.
They love that so much.
It's just crazy.
But the reason for that is like you're
stretching out their bodies and you're
showing them that they can't put their
thumb in your eye and you're teaching
them to be graceful and,
and,
and you're teaching them the difference
between something new that's happening
to the body and something painful.
You're really teaching them to dance and
it's this really complicated
physiological dance that,
that is indicative of a socialized
being.
That's partly why women like men who can
dance by the way,
um,
because it shows that you can pay
attention to someone else first of all,
that you're coordinated,
but even more importantly that you can
take the fact of your coordination and
coordinate that with someone else's
coordination.
So,
and that's very primal and
physiological.
It's built right into your body and
rough and tumble play helps without a
lot.
Anyways.
Rats also like too rough and tumble play
for much the same reasons and sort of
sort of pretty much all social mammals.
So you can tell that rats like it.
See how do you know if a rat likes
something?
Well,
he'll work for it.
And one of the ways you can figure out
if a rat wants to work for something is
that,
you know,
you get them in a state where maybe he's
desperate for whatever he's working for
and you can put a little spring on them
and figure out how hardy poles to go
somewhere.
He knows where he's going to get that
and then you can measure the force that
he's willing to apply and that gives you
a rough estimate of his motivation or
maybe ask the bar press like a,
you know,
like a cocaine addicted rats to,
to receive the reward and you can count
rate of bar pressing and you can get an
estimate of how excited the route is to
go do whatever it is the rats going to
do.
And so panksepp used to put rats in,
pair them one riot against the other in
kind of a play arena,
not a very big thing and uh,
and the juvenile males and they would
work to do that.
Okay.
So they liked it.
And then maybe one rat was 10 percent
bigger than the other.
And then when you paired them,
the big rat would beat the little rat
because 10 percent weight advantage was
enough to make the bigger rep dominant.
Okay.
So then they established basically
dominance and submission.
You might think about that as a power
relationship.
And to some degree it is,
but it's more complicated than that.
And this is very important.
So,
so the rats play together once and the a
big route pins the little rat really
very much like wrestling,
like rats wrestle,
just like people wrestle 'em.
And if you pair them together,
then the big rat campaign,
the little rat,
okay.
So now you got dominant rats,
subordinate rat,
roughly speaking.
And,
but then you see if you stop the
experiment there you'd think,
well the rats play to establish
dominance and submission.
But the thing is is that rats don't just
play once,
they played many,
many,
many times.
And that's also the case with human
beings is that you don't just play once,
you play many,
many times and there is a difference
between the rules of a game and the
rules of a set of games.
And that's so unbelievably important.
So you keep that in mind because we'll
return to that.
So anyways,
the next time the two rats get together,
the little rat house to ask the big
route to play because the rule basically
is subordinate entity asks dominant
entity to play.
And so the little rat does what mammals
do to play,
you know,
they kind of put their paws down and put
the rear end up,
bit up in the air.
You see dogs do that.
And unless you're completely clueless,
you know that,
that doesn't mean he's going for your
throat,
means he wants you to whack them on the
side of the head so he can sort of
pretend to bite you.
You know,
it's,
it's pretty obvious if you've played
with dogs and children.
So,
um,
yeah.
And I make that comparison because dogs
and children understand each other,
right?
They're pack animals,
they followed the same basic rules.
They know how to play.
They can become friends,
otherwise you wouldn't have them as
pets.
I mean the dogs,
not the children.
Um,
so anyways,
the little rat asks the big role to play
in big rep thing.
So yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Are they will play,
they wrestle and you pair them multiple
times.
Well,
if you compare them multiple times,
what you find is the less the big rat
lets the little rat win,
30 percent of the time the little rat
won't ask the big rat to play anymore
and that you think,
well,
who cares what?
Like why is that important?
It's like,
it's really important.
That's a really important discovery
because it shows you that the,
that even rats have a set set a sense of
fair play that emerges across iterated
games.
It's,
it's,
it's inevitable.
It's evidence for the biological
instantiation of a social morality.
It's a big deal,
man.
That's a big discovery.
And,
and it shows you that even at the level
of rats,
they're very social animals by the way.
Um,
the interactions between rats are,
are mediated by something like a sense
of fairness or justice.
And so that's extremely cool because,
you know,
we tend to think of animals as having
dominance hierarchies and that's
predicated on power.
And that idea,
even though the bloody postmodernists
don't believe in biology,
they extend that analogy up to human
beings.
It's just not true.
Okay?
Well,
at the same time,
turns out to be true with chimpanzees.
So Frans de Waal,
who's a,
a Dutch primatologist,
a very smart one too.
He's been interested in the biological
basis of morality as well.
Um,
and he really,
he's written a lot of good books on,
on,
on primate behavior.
Chimps in particular.
Chimps are brutal creatures,
man.
Like they go to war a.
and so if you have a chimp territory out
in the jungle,
then the juveniles will,
the males in particular,
the band together in groups of four or
five.
There's often but not always a female or
two with them.
And if they come across chimps from
another troupe that aren't within their
hierarchy,
let's say they will,
if they're,
if they outnumber them because they,
they can't really count,
but they can estimate magnitude
visually.
It's not the same as counting.
Um,
but if they outnumber them,
they will tear them to pieces.
And chimps serve at least twice as
strong as a really well developed human
male.
And so they can tear you up pretty good.
And chimps are perfectly capable.
They hunt,
they're carnivorous like human beings.
And they hunt,
they hunt colobus monkeys,
often they weigh about 40 pounds and
they'll basically eat them alive at the
monkey screaming away like mad because
you know it's in pain because it's being
eaten and that doesn't slow the chimps
down a bit.
There's no cross species empathy
stopping them from having their snack.
And so chimps are very brutal creatures
and it isn't obvious they have a lot of
internal inhibition of the regression at
all.
Most of the inhibition is sociological.
It's out in the hierarchy.
And so the reason chimps aren't always
aggressive with one another is because
they know who can pound them and and who
will gang up on them and who won't be
established their hierarchy anyways.
You know,
you think about a champ hierarchy and
you're talking about a fairly strong and
aggressive creature.
You might think it's biggest,
ugliest,
meanest,
most vicious,
irritable,
unpleasant chimp that rises to the top.
But all that's kind of the postmodernist
view of human society.
But that's not the case.
It happens sometimes.
But what happens in has documented this
quite nicely,
is that tyron chimps lead unstable
regimes.
Now,
you know,
that might sound familiar because the
same thing of course is true human
beings and why is that?
Well,
it's because you know,
people don't like tyrants and chimps
don't like them that much either and
chimps are actually quite reciprocal and
their social interaction,
so they don't just dominate each other.
They groom each other,
they have friendships,
they can track social relationships over
very long periods of time now and they
do that and so they engage in reciprocal
interactions,
let's say prosocial reciprocal
interactions and you might think,
well what's the,
what's the weak point of the biggest,
ugliest,
toughest chimp in the troop?
And that is he doesn't have any friends.
And so,
you know,
maybe as a bad day he's a little hung
over or whatever for meeting fermented
bananas or whatever is partying with and
to have the slightly less ugly,
slightly less mean.
Chimps decide,
well this is a good time to take them
out and they tear them to pieces.
And so one of the things do all his
pointed out quite nicely is that if you
want to have a stable chimp dominance
hierarchy,
let's call it a regime,
the stable ones aren't ruled by the
tyrants tyrants get taken out by,
by paired up friendship dyad,
something like that.
So that's really worth thinking about
too,
you know,
because
because it indicates that even in
creatures that have less complex
sociological orders and they do because
one of the things that predicts how
complex your social order is,
how big your brain is compared to your
body,
it's encephalization essentially.
And the more encephalitis creature,
the larger the social groups that
contract.
And of course human beings are very
highly encephalitis.
So we have quite complicated group,
um,
we have quite complicated group
organizations,
but even in simpler group organizations
like the chimps,
it isn't the tyrant who rule stable.
And that turns out to be also incredibly
important.
Okay.
So,
so,
so much for the idea that power is the
only game in town.
Then you got to ask.
The question is,
well,
this is actually a postmodern question.
So you know,
one of the things Derek just said that
the main postmodern joker is that by
categorizing you,
you,
you privilege one concept and you,
you force other concepts out to the
margins.
And so he believed that when you
constructed a hierarchy of power,
that the hierarchy of power,
privilege,
certain people and marginalized others,
and you know,
that's really not that brilliant
observation as far as I'm concerned.
It's rather commonplace.
All it means is that when you categorize
something that there are things that are
in the category and whole bunch of
things that aren't.
And so you actually can't categorize
anything,
which means you can't perceive anything,
which means you can't think or live
without making some things in the
middle.
And everything else on the outside.
It's part of categorization itself.
And so maybe the postmodernist would go
far enough to question the utility of
categorization itself.
And I think to some degree they do do
that.
But,
um,
the point here is that
if you,
you have to ask why it is that you
would,
if you were a postmodernist yourself,
why it is that you would privilege the
idea of power above all else.
It's exactly what is it that you're
pushing to the margin.
And so that's something that we're going
to talk about.
Now,
here's one thing you might push to the
margin.
Let's say that you believe that
hierarchies are a consequence of power.
Well then you push competence to the
margin and then applying the postmodern
mark modernist logic,
you might say,
well,
the reason you're privileging power is
so that you can produce so that you can
push competence to the margin.
And so you want to keep that in mind
too,
because that's going to become important
as we discussed the relationship between
postmodernism and Marxism.
Maybe you're after the destruction of
the idea of competence itself.
All right,
so postmoderns,
and we talked about it a little bit.
We'll return to it.
Now we're going to talk a little bit
about Marxism.
I've got a quote here from mark's.
The proletarians have nothing to lose,
but they're changed.
Uh,
well.
That was pretty good for like 18,
80 or 80,
90 or whenever it was.
He wrote it.
Somewhere around that period of time it
turned out the proletarians had a lot
more to lose the interchange they had
their lives and their families to lose.
That was demonstrated amply as a
consequence of the,
what would you call it,
the sociological movements that were put
into place when the Marxist
presuppositions began to govern
societies like the Soviet Union.
So,
all right,
so let's take the same postmodernist
approach.
So here's some basic tenants of Marxism.
It's Berge Lousy against proletariat.
The bridge was the year,
the capitalists,
the property owners,
those sorts of people,
the proletariat,
the working class,
for all intents and purposes.
The basic idea is that history itself is
nothing but the,
what would you call it?
The documentation of the struggle of one
class against the other.
Okay.
No,
that's wrong,
but it's okay because it's too simple,
obviously.
It's obviously too simple.
There's all sorts of motivations that
people have.
Some of them are economic,
some of them are associated with power,
but that's okay.
We will leave that.
Let's let's give the devil his due and
say,
well,
yeah,
fair enough.
There is still a fair bit of tension
between the haves and the haves and have
nots and maybe that was even more
intense in previous societies than it is
now.
And it's no,
there's no doubt that economics plays a
role in,
in virtually everything that human
beings do in a fairly significant role.
So let,
let's,
let's accept that as a potential theory.
It's,
it's simple,
but maybe it's practically useful.
And then there's kind of an offshoot of
that theory,
which is that,
well,
if you're a Marxist,
that means you have sympathy for the
working class.
Right?
Because that's what you're saying all
the time.
It's like,
well,
the poor working class,
they're all oppressed.
The poor,
poor proletariat,
you know.
And then you're also saying,
well,
we're the good guys because we're
standing on the side of the oppressed.
And so then you might also ask what
you're marginalizing when you claim that
you're the good guys,
because one of the things that you would
be marginalizing is all of the ways in
which you're not the good guys,
but we can leave that aside for a moment
too.
So,
but there's the claims is that,
you know,
there's the working class against the
ruling class.
Another claim is the ruling class is the
ruined class because they exploit the
working class basically stealing their
excess labor from them.
Um,
another very,
very,
uh,
what,
surfacely attractive claim that lacks
any reasonable justification,
you know,
because it's predicated on the idea of
the world as a zero sum game.
And clearly the world is not a zero sum
game.
So when someone creates wealth,
when someone is wealthy,
it can be at least at times because they
created it,
not because they swiped it from someone
else.
I think,
you know,
you can think of someone like Bill Gates
or Steve Jobs is a good example of that.
Um,
you know,
they're,
they're what they produced pad to value
that far exceeded what they garnered.
As a consequence of their production,
even though what they garnered was
fairly substantial.
So anyways,
but we'll get,
like you said,
we're going to give the devil his due.
Okay.
It's the bourgeoisie against the
proletariat will accept that it's class
warfare is the primary historical mover.
No problem now,
but here's what I'm not willing to give
away so easily.
Uh,
we have sympathy for the working class
primarily and we're good because of
that.
Now I'm not gonna.
Just give that away.
So simply.
So let's investigate that a little bit.
Let's see if we can actually figure it
out.
If that's true.
We'll say a use a pragmatic approach
because I'm a pragmatist in that William
James,
Sansa,
um,
uh,
or maybe you can think about even more
deeply in anciently.
Uh,
there's a statement in the New
Testament,
I think it's by their fruits,
you shall know the fine.
So we're going to walk down that road
before we do that.
So now that's another thing you have to
keep in mind.
Before we do that,
I want to make one more detour.
Okay?
So I like making detours and then
tangling the oil back together,
so I want to give you a bit of a history
of theories of suffering and I'm going
to compare the Marxist theory of
suffering to the Judeo Christian theory
of suffering and the Judeo Christian
would be.
And the reason I'm doing that is because
I think the Judeo Christian theory of
suffering is actually one of the
foundation stones of our entire culture.
And so it actually matters why you think
they're suffering.
And so the story that describes the
entry of suffering into the world,
that mythological story is the story in
Genesis,
the story of Adam and eve and basically
what happens in the story of Adam and
Eve as Adam and Eve are unconscious to
begin with and they're sort of in this
paradise will state there's no death or
at least there's no knowledge of death.
There's also no knowledge of self.
And then eats the apple that the serpent
gives her and the scales fall from her
eyes and she gives the apple to Adam and
he eats it as well.
So she makes him self conscious.
They both wake up,
the first thing that happens is they
realize that they're naked and they
cover themselves up,
and the second thing that happens as a
consequence of that realization is that
they come to know the difference between
good and evil and I mean that's an
insanely complicated story that's
dealing with a re absolutely in
comprehensible number of complex
phenomena simultaneously,
but it basically goes something like
this is that to be aware that you're
naked is to be aware of your fragility
and your mortality when when you have a
nightmare about being naked in front of
a crowd,
it means that you're exposed to the
crowd.
All your flaws,
all your mortal vulnerability is exposed
to the crowd,
for for for them to see,
for you to be ashamed of,
for them to judge.
That's partly why we're all close.
That's partly why human being a human
white clothing is a human universal.
There's many human universals,
by the way,
clothing is one of them,
although it's used for many different
purposes,
so Adam and eve cover themselves up and
so because they've realized that
they're,
that they're vulnerable,
they're naked and vulnerable.
That self consciousness,
human beings are self conscious animals.
We're really the only self conscious
animals.
Other animals have the glimmerings of
self consciousness.
Some of them can identify themselves in
a mirror,
for example,
but we have whole theories of ourselves.
We have whole articulated verbal and
philosophical theories of what a human
being is and what we each are as
individual.
So really those aren't in the same
conceptual universe.
It's a whole different.
It's a qualitatively different issue.
In the case of human beings were self
conscious,
selfconsciousness loads on trait,
neuroticism,
technically speaking,
which means that self consciousness is
primarily something that manifests
itself in the form of negative emotion
and we all know that you're onstage.
You get self conscious.
Is that a good thing?
No.
You can give.
So self conscious that your tongue tied,
right?
It's not good.
You don't want to be self conscious
onstage or maybe ever you get self
conscious in the in the face of someone
you're trying to impress.
He turned all red.
You Stammer.
It's like self consciousness is a rough
business and it's no wonder because you
know yourself for the for the fragile
fool that you are and it's even worse
than that because see,
it took me a long time to figure out why
it was that when Adam and eve woke up,
they also develop the knowledge of good
and evil.
I just couldn't figure that out because
it didn't make sense to me.
Why?
How selfconsciousness knowledge of
vulnerability and the knowledge of good
and evil we're tangled together or even
really what the knowledge of good and
evil meant,
but I figured it out.
Eventually I thought,
oh,
I get it.
It was like a real revelation to me.
As soon as you know you're vulnerable,
you know the difference between good and
evil,
because as soon as you know you're
vulnerable,
then you know everyone else is.
And as soon as you know that everyone
else is vulnerable,
you know how to hurt them.
And so that means you consciously know
how to bring suffering into being and
that's the knowledge of good and evil.
And you know that because let's say that
you're really good at torturing people,
hadn't,
there's no doubt a number of people in
the audience who are actually quite good
at that and maybe you all have a bit of
an affinity for it.
Um,
if you're married,
I'm sure your partner would testify to
that.
So if you're going to hurt someone,
what do you think essentially is,
okay,
what would really hurt me?
Then you think,
well,
I'll just do that to them.
And it's like,
that's,
that's a,
that's a good theory.
It's a very sophisticated.
So anyways,
so,
okay,
so what happens?
Adam and eve,
wake up,
they weren't supposed to do this.
God told them that they are going to be
sorry if they did that,
but they did it anyways because that's
what people are like and because we
learn things that knock us out of our
present paradises we're curious and we
won't leave things alone and maybe
things are not so bad and then you,
you know,
ask some questions that maybe you're not
so happy about asking.
Once you find the answer and you fall
out of your little paradise into history
and you gotta work to set things right
again.
Anyways,
God gets wind of this and,
and he chases Adam and eve out of the
garden of Eden,
but he said some interesting things when
he chases them out,
he says,
all right,
now you know,
what's the consequences of that?
And he says,
Dad,
if you're going to have to work.
Oh,
that's cool.
That's really cool.
Well,
he is God after all.
It also,
he,
he's.
He knows what he's talking about.
He says,
you're going to have to work.
So why would you have to work now that
you knew you were vulnerable?
Well,
the answer to that is,
well,
if you know you're vulnerable,
that stretches out into the future,
you know you're going to die,
you know that you're fragile.
It's like maybe all your problems are
solved right now.
You're all sitting here,
you're safe,
you're not hungry,
you don't want anything to drink,
etc. But what about tomorrow?
What about next week or next month or 10
years from now?
It's like,
just because you got all your problems
solved for this second doesn't mean
you've got them solved for the rest of
your iterations through time.
So you got to work and the work is the
sacrifice of the president for the
future.
And so that's exactly right.
You have to work now you see?
See what's interesting aBout that,
and this is the theory that I was,
oh,
and then of course god tells that eve,
well,
you've really,
you know,
screwed things up to,
you're going to have these big brain
babies and,
and that's a big problem.
You're going to suffer in childbirth and
then they're going to be dependent on
you forever.
And because of that,
you're going to be dependent on this.
man that you just woke up and that's not
going to be very pleasant for either of
you,
but tough luck and so that's it.
That's the curse in some sense and it's
exactly right,
but the thing is,
there's a theory in there.
There's an interesting theory of
suffering that's implicit in that story
and the theory of suffering is that
suffering is built into the structure of
self conscious being.
It's built right into the structure,
so if you're a self conscious being,
that's your lot.
It isn't someone else's fault.
It isn't a consequence of sociological
oppression.
It isn't the consequences of the fact
that our society isn't organized
properly.
It's just part of being.
All right,
so that's a big deal because that's a.
That's an important theory because one
of the questions is,
well,
what we know why is there suffering,
but what are you going to do about it?
And it's a big.
It's a lot different if it's just the
Way it is for you and if it's actually
your fault that he's suffering,
those are,
or maybe it's the group's fault that
you're suffering.
Those are major.
Those theories are really,
really different and then in the second
story in cain and abel,
cane make sacrifices to try to get it in
good with god enabled,
make sacrifices and sacrifices are kind
of archaic from our perspective.
They're burnt offerings so the smoke
goes up where god can detect it because
he's up there somewhere up there where
the stars are and uh,
god rejects cane sacrifices and we don't
really know why,
but it kind of looks like cain is a
second grader and then god king goes and
complains to god and says like,
what kind of stupid universe did you
make here?
I'm breaking myself and half trying to
get things together,
making the proper sacrifices and
nothing's going well for me and abel.
Well,
you know,
he's everything he touches turns to
gold.
Everyone loves him.
He's even a really good guy.
It's like so annoying.
What's up with this place you built?
And god tells kane don't become an and
telling me that the entire fabric of
reality is wrong because it isn't
working out for you.
Says sin crouches at your door.
Like a,
like a sexually aroused predatory cat.
That's basically the metaphor that,
that god uses and he says,
and you let it in and had it and let it
have its way with you,
and that's really an interesting way of
putting it because what god says to cain
is that,
you know,
you're all bitter and resentful and
really it's no wonder because you know,
things aren't going well for you and
then you've got able who's over shining
you in every way and uh,
but it's your fault,
this terrible thing waited at the door
and you let it in and then you entered
into a creative union with it and you
produced something as a consequence and
that's this tormented spirit that you
have now and it's polluting your
relationship with reality.
And that's why things aren't working out
very well for you.
So go put yourself together before you
come and tell me just exactly what's
wrong with the structure of reality.
And cain isn't very happy about that
because really is that really what you
want to hear,
right?
Like you have more misery than is
necessary because you really didn't put
your act together and you know it and
you've done it creatively and so kayden
goes and kills abel.
That's the story of how resentment
enters the world and it's the first
story in the judeo christian canon,
let's say about actual human beings
because adam and eve were made by god so
they don't really count.
Cain and abel were born and so that's
something so there's a reaction to
suffering,
right?
The necessIty of sacrifice and the
consequence of the necessity of
sacrifices that some sacrifices work and
others don't,
and then if your sacrifices aren't met
with the,
with the good will of god,
let's say,
well then that makes you angry.
Well,
of course it does.
You can take god out of this story if
you want.
If you're not happy with that kind of
mythological or narrative statement,
but it doesn't really matter because the
whole point is is that if you make
sacrifices,
especially if they're second rate,
things aren't going to go very well for
you and you're going to get bitter and
resentful and murderous and maybe
genocidal and it's really interesting,
you know,
because cane has descendants and if you
bug,
if you transgress against them,
they don't just kill you.
They killed seven of you and then his
later descendants kill 49 of you.
There's this exponential growth of
murderousness as a consequence of canes,
primary,
primal fratricide,
and then the next story is the flood.
And that's not an accident.
There's nothing in those stories is an
accident.
Okay,
so now you've got two different theories
about the nature of suffering.
You've got the one I just laid out,
it's called the foundational story of
suffering and malevolence,
and you have the marxists story,
which is while there's an oppressed
people and the reason they're oppressed
and suffering is because of the
oppressors are oppressing them.
Those are not the same theories.
Right?
And there's a utopianism that's implicit
in marxism,
which is if you could just get the damn
old pressers to stop oppressing the
oppressed,
then the utopia would arrive.
And so not only are the oppressors
responsible for the suffering of the
poor,
they're also responsible for the fact
that the utopia isn't here for everyone.
And so how reprehensible can you get?
Well then that certainly justifies that
degree of malevolence justifies pretty
much anything you'd like to do to them.
So anyways,
so let's take this apart in a little
more detail.
Don't do the marxists.
Have sympathy for the working class.
George orwell was interested in this
question and so he wrote this book
called wiggins road to wigan pier,
which I would highly recommend it.
So on a reading list I've made,
it's on my website.
You can check that out.
Those are books that have been
particularly influential to me.
And so orwell was a socialist.
he wrote the book for the left book
club,
which published a kind of a socialist
book once a month or.
Well,
by the time he wrote this book,
he was already awake.
No buy in the 19 twenties after the
russian revolution.
No one really knew what to make of what
was happening in what would become the
soviet union,
right be.
It was after world war.
One planet was in ashes,
pro intents and purposes.
The old aristocratic order was
crumbling.
Um,
it was a horror show and these
revolutionaries came out with these new
ideas and tried to give the in
principle,
give the working class a break and
everybody watched to see what would
happen then,
um,
the honest people and the intellectuals
watched and I separate them for a
reason.
Um,
but by 1920,
21,
22,
something like that,
it was obvious already that something
was rotten in the state of Denmark.
Malcolm muggeridge went over to the
soviet union to check out how the
collectivization of the farms was going
and he found out it was actually pretty
murderous,
right?
Because what the,
what the communists did was roundup all
the successful farmers and rape them and
kill them and steal everything they had
and send them off to siberia,
which turned out actually to be a pretty
bad idea.
Now you think you think about it,
those people were serfs not very long
before a couple of generations at most,
they were so not much more than slaves
and some of them had risen up to the
point where the media had a nice brick
house and a couple of cows and maybe a
person working for them or too,
and there was a small proportion of the
agriculturalists in the soviet union
that we're producing most of the food
and that's just how it goes because
that's a prieto distribution issue in
any field where there's human
productivity,
a small proportion of the people produce
almost all of the output.
It's actually the square root of the
number of people in the field produce
half the output.
So if you have 100 farmers,
ted of them produce half the food,
but if you have 10,000 to 100 of them
produce half the food.
Okay?
So what happens when you kill all the
good farmers?
You starve 6 million ukrainians to death
in the 19 thirties.
And you know,
that's not something that's all that
widely known,
but if you want to
provide some additional fodder for your
nightmares,
you could go online and read about what
happened to the ukrainians in the 19
thirties.
So underneath the,
under the collectivization principles.
So let's say you're a mother and you
were starving to death and so are your
children and you know,
the communists had come in and forcibly
collectivized you and then they took all
the grain that your collective farm and
producing,
they shipped it all to the city say.
And so that's all done.
And you think,
okay,
you know,
the city's got eight.
So then you go out in the field to pick
up the grains that the harvesters missed
so that you can,
you know,
the ones that they'd be lying there,
they're not so good.
There's not that many of them.
you go out and glean,
you pick up the seeds that weren't
picked up a so you can feed your kids so
they don't die.
And so what's the punishment for that
death?
Because you were obliged under the
collectivization orders to turn in any
additional grains that you happen to
pick off the ground to the authorities
so that they can be,
well,
who knows,
but at least so you.
So they could be shipped to the cities,
I suppose,
which is of course absurd because of
course that would never happen,
but it was mostly so that you could just
actually die.
So.
Okay.
Anyways,
back to the road to wigan pier.
Now
I'm going to read you a little bit about
about from the book.
So orwell went out to this mining town
in the northern uk and coal miners
had sympathy for the working class.
He really worked on that hiS whole life
because he was a middle class,
upper middle class,
snobby type englishman,
and he knew it and he tried really hard
to overcome that.
He,
he,
he served in the spanish civil war.
He wandered around as a tramp.
He worked in,
in low end restaurant.
He worked as a low end worker in
restaurants in paris and in london.
He has a very good book,
I think it's called down and out in
paris and london that describes that he
was seriously committed dude and really
a smart guy.
And so he's going up to these terrible
towns in the northern uk where the coal
miners worked and have their families
and you know,
they had hard lives.
They had hard lives and that's just say
it,
nothing,
you know,
the coal miners that he met,
they didn't have any teeth by the time
they were 30.
He said the women he talked to you said
teeth or just a misery.
It's better to get rid of them as soon
as you can.
Um,
and,
and they went and the man went and mined
coal and that was rough.
You know,
they all have black lung by the time
they were 40 and they were,
they were done fundamentally.
But here's a,
just a bit,
a bit of a story about how hard their
lives were.
So they had to go in the mines during
the day so that they never saw the day.
So that's one thing.
They had to go to the mines and then
they ended like not coal off the walls.
That's hard with hammers and picks and
all of that and they had to move it,
but that was.
That was their job,
but there was the commute,
so here is the commute.
So imagine that the typical tunnel was
about that high,
something like that,
and the typical coal miner was about
that high.
Lots of problem maybe because you've got
to walk through those tunnels to get to
work so you have to walk like this.
Then the question might be,
well,
how far do you have to walk to work?
And that answer is three and a half
miles and that's how far you have to
walk back from work after you put your
eight hour shift in the coal mine and
the you don't get paid for the commute.
And so orwell said that was more or less
like climbing a small mountain in the
morning before you went to work and then
climbing another one at night before you
went home.
And so that was just.
I mean,
believe me,
I'm telling you very little about how
tough their lives were,
but that gives you a little flavor.
I said one day like that for a modern
person,
you're just your dad or you wish you
were dead anyways,
and so orwell talks about going up there
to stay in terrible places he lived in
while he was up there and the terrible
food he ate and and the miserable and
wretched scenes that he saw.
And here's one of the miserable richard
scenes.
He's on a train through the
neighborhoods.
He says,
the train bore me away for the monster
scenery of slag.
Heaps,
chimneys piled scrap iron fall canals,
paths of singery mud,
criss cross by the prince of clogs.
This was march,
but the weather had been horribly cold
and everywhere there were mounds of
black and snow.
As we move slowly through the outskirts
of the town,
we passed row after of little gray slum
houses running at right angles to the
embankment at the back of one of the
houses.
The young woman was kneeling on the
stones poking a stick up the lead and
waste pipe which ran from the sink
inside him,
which I suppose was blocked.
I had time to see everything about her.
Her sack apron,
her clumsy clogs her arms,
reddened by the cold.
She looked up as the train passed,
and I was almost near enough to catch
her eye.
She had around pale face,
usual exhausted face of the slum girl
who's 25 and looks 40 thanks,
two miscarriages and drudgery and at war
for the second in which I sought the
most desolate,
hopeless expression I've ever seen.
It struck me.
Then we meaning the middle class at that
time,
our mistake,
and when we saY that it isn't the same
for them as it would be for us,
and then people bread in the slums can
imagine nothing but the slums for what I
saw on her face was by no means the
ignorant suffering of an animal.
She knew well enough what was happening
to her,
understood as well as I did,
how dreadful of destiny it was to be
kneeling there in the bitter cold.
On the slimy stones of a slum backyard
poking a stick up,
a follow drain pipe.
All right,
so orwell rates the first part of the
book and it details the lives of these
people and then he makes an argument he
says was like,
how can you read about this?
How can you know about this without
having some sympathy for
redistribution schemes and social and
socialist ideas.
And so he's actually asking himself this
question.
It's not just a rhetorical question.
He's,
I mean,
he's a serious guy,
right?
He went,
he goeS up there and he tells you a
story that you have to have a heart of
stone if you,
if you don't,
if you read that you don't think,
man,
something should be done about this.
It's really awful.
So he set up this situation where your
sympathies are completely with the
people that he's describing,
but socialism wasn't all that popular in
britain at that time.
And,
and so,
and socialists weren't all that popular
with orwell.
He didn't really like them that much and
he was trying to figure out why that
was.
So this is what he wrote in the second
part of the book.
Now this card have been a lot of
trouble.
they didn't want to publish this damn
book after he wrote the second part.
Oh,
but he fought with him and he got it
published and it's a classic and,
and people still read it and you should
read it because it's a great book and
orwell's great writer and orwell is
another one of those people and
intellectuals who woke up pretty early.
You know,
orwell wrote animal farm and 1984.
He wrote 1984 and 1940 eIght wrote
animal farm approximately around the
same time.
He knew what was happening under stalin
and he wasn't afraid to say it,
but it was a that in some sense fell on
deaf ears,
especially among the intelligentsia.
And there's complicated reasons for
that.
But.
But it wasn't like the facts weren't
there for people to see them if they
wanted to.
And has already said muggeridge.
Malcolm muggeridge had made it pretty
clear in the 19 twenties and that was
widely publicized by the way,
throughout the uk.
What was happening during d kula,
the kulaks being the farmers that I
talked about earlier,
who,
who had committed the unspeakable sin of
crawling out of their surf status over a
couple of Generations to the point where
they weren't mirror property and half
starved,
so this is what oracle had to say about
socialists.
It might be sad,
however,
that Even if the theoretical oriented
book train socialist is not a working
man himself,
at least he has actually by a love of
the working class.
He's endeavoring to shed his joie status
and fight on the side of the
proletariat.
Obviously that must be his motive.
What is it?
Sometimes I look at the socialist,
the intellectual tract writing type of
socialist with his pullover is fuzzy
hair and his marxist quotation and
wonder what the devil is.
Motive really is.
It's really difficult to believe that
it's a love of anybody,
especially if the working class from
whom he is of all people,
the furthest removed.
The truth is that too many people
calling them socialists revolution does
not mean a movement of the masses with
which they hope to associate themselves.
It means instead of set of reforms which
we,
the clever ones are going to impose on
them the lower orders.
On the other hand,
it would be a mistake to regard the book
train socialist as a bloodless creature,
entirely incapable of emotion,
though seldom giving much evidence of
affection for the exploited
is perfectly capable of displaying
hatred,
sort of queer theoretical in vacuum.
Oh,
hatred against the explorers.
Hence the grand old social sport of
denouncing the bourgeoisie.
It is strange how easily almost any
socialist writer can lash himself into
frenzies of rage against the class too,
which by birth or by adoption,
he himself almost invariably belongs.
No,
I worked for the ndp when I was a kid
and I had privileged access to the
leadership for provincially and
federally for reasons that I won't go
into.
And I thought that
many of them were honorable people who
were really striving to give the working
class of voice.
And I believe that the working class
needs a voice,
a political voice for obvious reasons.
Um,
I think the democrats in the United
States have made it absolutely dreadful
abysmal mistake replacing their working
class,
political ethos with identity politics.
We're going to talk about that and,
uh,
and I don't think the situation has
changed that much.
I think one of the things that's
happened in the United States is that
world stability and peace in some ways
has been purchased at the expense of
north american working class wellbeing
now because the chinese have gotten rich
compared to 30 years ago,
40 years ago,
50 years ago,
the,
the indians have gotten rich again,
same comparison basis.
There's more middle class people in
India now than there are on the United
States.
Um,
the trade arrangements that have been in
north America allowed for the rise of
middle classes globally.
At the same time,
they opened up the working class in
north America to competition from those
low wage sources.
And maybe that's a good deal.
It's hard to say,
right,
because it's not such a bad thing that
the chinese aren't starving and it's not
such a bad thing that the indians aren't
starving and that those societies are
transforming themselves.
actually into communities that are quite
wealthy,
it's like hooray for that.
It's an absolutely miraculous
transformation.
It's the most rapid growth of human
wealth in the history of humanity,
so we should be pretty happy about that,
but we should also remember at least to
some degree who's paid the price for it
and so as far as I'm concerned,
the working class needs a voice
and
it isn't obvious that they have one at
the moment.
Having said that,
however,
it isn't obvious to me at all
that the people who purport to stand for
the working class actually do so or that
if they do so that the reason they do so
is because they're all compassionate and
sympathetic and loving and kind and st.
Like I'm more convinced by orwell's
argument.
So back to the mdp,
the people I met at the leadership
level,
a lot of them I had a fair bit of
admiration for,
but as I worked with the party over
about a five year period,
there's this contradiction that kept
emerging for me and that was that I
didn't really like the low level party
functionary activist types.
Like they just weren't personally
appealing to me.
They seem peevish and resentful and then
at the same time I was going to college,
I was about 17.
I got elected to the senate on the
college board of governors and at that
time alberta was conservative
politically,
right.
It still is of course,
but they.
It was part of the progressive
conservative
empire because they ruled alberta
forever and all the board of governor
members were basically nominees,
right.
TheY were conservative nominees.
So these were conservative people and I
was an ndp member and I thought I'd
worked for small businessman to who
weren't mdp.
They were,
they were conservative.
It can never figure that out.
I'll tell you about that in a minute.
But I had a bad case of cognitive
dissonance because they actually turned
out that I admired the people on the
board of governors and they were mostly.
It was in grand prairie.
It's not a very big place and it's not
very old.
And so if you were reasonably successful
in grand prairie,
the probability that you would inherited
your money from the aristocrat
aristocracy was like zero.
Cause there wasn't one,
right,
it's the whole damn town was 50 years
old,
so if you had any influencer or wealth,
you are a small businessman,
small to middle sized businessmen and
you'd.
You knew what you were doing.
And I actually admired these people.
I thought,
well that's not very good.
I mire them and I don't share their
political views.
And then there's these other people with
whom I hypothetically share political
views and I don't admire them at all.
What's going on?
And then I read road to wigan pier and I
thought,
oh,
that's it.
They don't like the poor.
They just hate the rich.
It's not the same thing.
It's not the same set of motivations.
And so let's say that you're a
postmodernist and you privileged
compassion for the oppressed.
Think,
well,
what are you pushed to the margins?
Well,
what are you doing with all your hatred
and your resentment and your evil?
It's like you don't have any of that.
That's a bad theory.
That's a really bad theory.
Okay,
so fine.
So you can say,
well yeah,
you can say that,
but I don't buy it.
I still think that the people who stand
to speak for the oppressed are in fact
motivated by empathy and sympathy.
Their hearts are in the right place.
See,
I don't really buy that either because I
don't really think generally speaking,
that it's a credible claim for someone
to make that their heart is in the right
place.
Now you can ask that of yourself and if
you think your heart is in the right
place,
well more power to you.
You know,
I,
I can't see the halo from here.
However,
and so given that you're just as
malevolent as your neighbor or maybe
even more so and that that's actually
pretty malevolent given the intrinsic
nature of human beings.
I cAn't help but wonder what you're
doing with all those traits that you're
not admitting to,
but you can.
You could even object.
Well,
you know,
that's a pretty pessimistic view of
humankind.
It's not by the way,
it's just not naive,
but anyways,
you could object that and you can say
no.
Actually,
the weight of moral authority is in fact
on the left,
even the radical left with those who
identify the oppressed and who are
working to better their conditions.
Okay,
fair enough.
So then let's say,
well,
let's give those people some power
and if they're actually motivated by
compassion and empathy and desire for
the working class,
if you give them power and you give the
ideas power,
then as those ideas unfold in real time,
you're going to find out like,
did things get better for the working
class,
let's say?
Or did they get worse?
Because we could.
We could consider that like an
experiment.
We could consider the outcome proof.
I don't know what else you would do.
I don't know how else you would.
You would come to your decision because
it's just theory until you see it
happen.
Now,
nature said back in the 18,
late 18 hundreds that
after he said that god was dead,
and I suppose that would also Mean the
theory that of suffering that I outlined
at the beginning.
That is that the basis of judeo
christian civilization,
that god was dead in,
that people had killed him,
and that we'd never find enough water to
wash away the blood.
It's a paraphrase,
but I got the basic message right,
and he also said there'll be two
consequences of that nihilism because
there's no transcendent meaning and a
move to totalitarianism because people
can't tolerate nihilism.
He said the most likely pathway to
totalitarianism would be communism.
Essentially.
He didn't quite use those words,
but he meant that he,
the words are close enough.
He said socialism,
but I'm going to use communism to
distinguishing it,
distinguish it from democratic
socialism,
and he said that probably tens of tens
of millions of people would die in the
20th century as we played out that
experiment and then he said,
but it might be worth it if we learned
something from it.
Rough man.
I mean,
and and unbelievable like I cannot
figure out how in the world he knew that
that was going to happen.
Especially so far in advance,
but dostoevsky knew the same thing.
He wrote this book called the devil's
are the possessed.
You could read that,
that's a great book.
It takes about 150 pages to get going,
but once it like everything,
everything snaps together after that,
you know,
and then it moves and it's basically his
prophecy about it's an examination of
the kind of person who had arisen in the
aftermath of the death of god in Russia
who would lead the communist revolution.
That's essentially it.
It's brilliant.
It's,
it's,
it's terrifying and it's a great intro
to solzhenitsyn's gulag archipelago,
which describes what did happen when
those sort of people took over the
revolution.
So let's look at what happened after the
revolution and we might say,
well,
this,
how about we replicate the experiment a
few times because you know how it is.
If you're running this scientific
experiment,
you want to find out what something
does.
If you allow it to behave,
you don't want to just run it once
because while maybe there was something
specific about those conditions that
lead to the outcome.
You want to generalize it across
multiple circumstances.
So we might say,
well,
let's take this set of ideas and let's,
let's run it on large scale over very
long period of time in a variety of
exceptionally diverse cultures and
languages.
So let's do that.
Okay,
well we could first start with the,
with the soviet people even now because
it's like the 100 anniversary of the
russian revolution are celebrating
lennon.
it's like,
that's not good.
that's like celebrating hitler.
okay,
I'm dead serious about that.
It's not good.
And the fact that people can dare to
think that that's okay means that
there's something wrong with the way
that we look at history.
Landon was a monster and if you want to
know about that,
you can read solzhenitsyn's writings
about lending because they communist
apologist say,
well,
it wasn't landing.
Len was a good guy.
He was all motivated by love of the
working class.
It's like,
well,
his henchmen was stolen and if you're
hansman is stolen,
you're not a good guy.
And and lenin was around during the
early collectivization and if you read
what he wrote,
you'll find out that he is perfectly
willing to have any number of people die
as long as his ideological system could
be brought into big.
So there's no celebrating lennon.
There's no.
We're cool young marxist hip
revolutionaries and he's our idol.
It's like there's none of that.
Not if you know anything,
not if you're decent,
whether it's death of the kulaks I told
you about that there was a ukrainian
famine that's 6 million.
Go there.
There was the rise of the gulag state
because it turned out that Russia,
the soviet union couldn't run on the
principles that it had,
that it had a laid down as sacrosanct.
It just didn't work.
So you had to enslave everybody and run
your economy as a slave state
essentially.
And try not to kill the people into
gulags so fast that you can't suck some
productive labor out of them is the
death of tens of millions of people.
We don't even know.
The estimates range from 15 to $60
million and like we won't get too picky
even about the numbers because after the
first 10 million you kinda made your
point and the fact that we don't know
between 15 and 60 is actually an
indication of the horror
of it
because our count is off by tens of
millions and that's only within the last
century and then there was the 1956
crackdown on Hungary and the 19 eight
invasion of czechoslovakia.
Then there was the whole like thermo
nuclear holocaust thing that was going
on at the same time and the fact that in
1962 and in 1984,
we were seconds away from complete
annihilation,
right.
During the cuban missile crisis,
the keys were in the intercontinental
ballistic missile release systems and
castro,
as he admitted to jimmy carter case,
any of you are castro fans,
which you shouldn't be.
That he was perfectly willing to have
Cuba annihilated if it would've meant
the defeat of the United States.
And then in 1984 approximately,
I may have the date exactly wrong.
The russians received
an indication
from their early warning systems that
the americans had launched five thermal
and nuclear missiles and one russian
decided that it was a mistake and
refused to launch the retaliation and he
just died about two weeks ago.
So,
you know,
that was pretty close.
And uh,
so that was experiment number one.
Let's say that that wasn't good,
that experiment,
let's put it that way.
IT wasn't good.
It was exactly the antithesis of good.
It was precisely the antithesis of good,
but that wasn't all.
I mean,
there's the people's republic of China
has a different country,
like seriously,
a different country,
right?
Different tradition,
different language.
How many people died in China under mao?
No one knows.
Same issue with the soviet union.
Although myra was a bigger monster than
stalin.
And that's,
that's impressive.
You know,
because there's hitler,
there's stalin and mao and of the three
mile was probably the worst.
He's still revered in China.
Maybe that accounts for their affinity
for North Korea,
which could still destroy us.
All the remnants of that horrible state.
Maybe 100 million people died in China
during the great leap forward.
That's a hell of a leap forward.
Well,
maybe it wasn't a 100 million,
you know,
maybe it was only $40 million,
but as I said before,
when you're counting in the tens of
millions,
your points already made.
And then there was Cambodia and the
killing fields and Bulgaria at east
Germany and Romania and the democratic
people's republic of Korea.
That's North Korea and Vietnam and
Ethiopia,
Hungary,
et cetera,
et cetera.
There was never a successful communist
state.
Cuba I suppose came closest,
but it was radically,
um,
the soviets poured money into Cuba.
So that doesn't really count.
So then the first question was,
well,
are these marxists motivated by love or
hatred?
Well,
is it love or hatred that produces $100,
million dead people?
Yeah.
Is that enough evidence or not?
And if it's not enough evidence,
if you think to yourself,
well that's not enough evidence,
it was never really given its proper,
a proper try.
it's like,
well,
what would have been a proper try?
See,
I always think when I hear someone say
that I know what you think,
you think in your delusional arrogance,
did you understand the marxist doctrines
better than anyone else ever has,
and that if you were the one
implementing those doctrines,
you would have ushered in the utopia.
That's what you mean when you say that,
and
no,
they're say,
and there's an idea in the new testament
that there's a sin.
It's a sin against the holy ghost.
If you commit that sand,
no one really knows what it is
that you can't be forgiven,
and I would say,
well,
if you want a candidate for the sin
against the holy ghost and the 21st
century,
the statement
communism,
real communism was never tried with the
underlying idea that if you had been the
person implementing it,
it would have worked.
I think that's a pretty good contender
for something for which you should never
be forgiven.
Okay.
Alright,
so that's marxism.
So let's go on to postmodernism.
We talked a little bit about it.
Now,
hypothetically,
it's an attitude of skepticism,
irony towards rejection of grand
narratives,
ideologies and universalism.
CriT criticizes objective notions of
reason,
human nature,
social progress,
absolute truth in objective reality.
It's predicated on the idea that the
reason that you categorize especially
the reason that you categorize is to
marginalize you.
Categorize,
to marginalized,
to obtain power.
Power is pretty much all there is.
There's other elements of postmodernism.
One of them is that human nature is
merely a social construct.
See the reason for that as far as I'm
concerned,
and this is a postmodern critique as
well,
I'm going to move the center to the
margin and the margin to the centers.
Why would you think that human nature is
only a social construct?
Well,
here's why.
It's because that means you could
construct it any way you want to.
That was a very common idea among this,
among the communists.
You know they.
That's why michael wanted to wipe out
chinese history.
That's why the red guard went around in
China and tried to destroy everything,
every element of china's history prior
to approximately 1960 at that great
culture.
Thousands and thousands of years old as
well.
So you could bring in the new man,
but what does the new man.
Well it was whatever slave mile happened
to fantasize about,
or it was the utopian person.
You take your pick.
But like I said,
if you take a look at the corpses,
you can pretty much figure out which of
those two it was.
So what's up with these people?
These deconstructionists postmodernists.
What are they up to exactly?
Well,
here's the first thing
they came about pretty much when marxism
was no longer credible,
no longer tenable as an intellectual set
of intellectual propositions.
Now,
if you were a french intellectual,
you had to have a lot of corpses piled
at your feet before you were willing to
think that you were wrong.
So here's an example,
I don't remember his name.
He was the architect of the killing
fields in Cambodia,
wasn't pol pot.
It was one of his advisors.
Unfortunately,
I can't remember his name.
He took his phd at the bomb
and he developed the thesis in the
sorbonne what marxists thesis that the
cities were parasites on,
on the land.
You know,
it's an extension of the whole
bourgeoisie proletarian thing.
The cities were full of bourgeois types,
educated and educated parasites
essentially who were doing nothing but
stealing what was rightly the farmers,
so when he came back to Cambodia,
he put that into action and emptied out
the cities and put all the intellectuals
and the city dwellers either to death or
to work,
which generally resulted in death and
killed about one six to one quarter of
the population,
but he got his phd from the bomb
and that's a good story because that's
exactly how complicit the western
leftist intellectuals were in
facilitating the horrors of the 20th
century and it's not like we've learned
anything since then.
Quite the contrary,
but just gone underground and that's
what I see.
That's what I see when I see
postmodernism.
So what happened was
despite the affinity of western
intellectuals for marxism,
maybe because they weren't paid as much
as bankers,
let's say if we're being cynical about
it,
because I've often thought that if you
paid sociologists as much as investment
bankers,
they'd be capitalist very rapidly.
Which is also to say that you may
underpay intellectuals at your peril and
you know that's actually dangerous
because one of the things that's
happening is that as the universities
have become corporatized and corrupted
in a variety of ways,
more and more of the professors or
adjuncts,
right?
I think it's up to 30,
40,
50 percent,
something like that.
Now they've got no tenure,
they've got no job security and they're
paid like $24,000 a year.
It's not a good idea to radicalize the
people that are teaching your children.
But anyways,
yeah,
by the end of the sixties,
so much data on the catastrophic
failures of communism had accrued that
even the most intransigent of french
intellectuals had to admit that the jig
was up.
but that's a problem because that's the
whole ideology,
right?
That's the whole raison d'etre.
He says in his terrible alberta french,
you're going to just give that up.
What are you goIng to do after that?
Well,
what happened was postmodernism was
invented and so it's a slight of hand as
far as I can tell.
So and,
and with postmodernism identity
politics,
and so the postmodern transformation is,
well,
we're a little wrong with the working
class thing.
Turns out that communists killed them
all and capitalists make them all rich
and that's actually exactly the opposite
of what we predicted,
but maybe there's still a way this could
be salvaged.
How about if we,
we don't say working class capitalists,
we say oppressor or oppressed.
We'll just.
Well just trends transformed the
terminology a bit and we'll start
thinking about all the other ways that
people plural pressed and then and all
the other ways that people are
oppressors and then we can play the same
damn game under a new guys
and now lord the postmodernists were
marxists.
So let's make no mistake about that.
Darren himself said that postmodernism
was a transformation of marxism.
I'm not making this up.
The question is why?
Well,
because you could say what?
Postmodernism is a valid philosophical
school and we'll get into that for a
minute and they make some valid claims.
One of them,
for example,
this is a central postmodernist claim,
is that there's an infinite number of
ways of interpreting the world and that
actually turns out to be technically
correct.
Part of the reason that we've had a very
difficult time building robots,
ai robots that can operate in the real
world,
is because perceiving the real world
turns out to be so difficult that we
really can't figure out how human beings
do it because it is susceptible to an
infinite number of interpretations.
So that's actually correct.
Now I'm not going to give the
postmodernists a tremendous amount of
credit for discovering that because it
was discovered simultaneously in about
five disciplines at pretty much the same
time,
but you give the devil his due,
so.
So what's the logic?
Something like,
well,
there's
an infinite number of interpretations of
the world.
You can't tell which of those are
canonically,
correct?
Correct.
The basic narrative of human struggle as
oppressor versus oppressed,
we use category structures can constrain
that infinite number of interpretations
because the basic narrative is an
oppressor versus oppressed.
We choose those narratIves that serve
our function as old pressers,
so it's
deeply cynical but credible,
you know,
and you can say if you're not naive that
people are motivated by power and that
our interpretations of the world can be
self serving.
I mean we do want to serve ourselves
after all because otherwise we die and
so and we are centered in one place and
so we can't see everything and we're
biased so,
so there is the probability that the way
that we look at the world will be
tainted by narrow self interest and
maybe even tainted by ingroup interests
beyond narrow individual self interest.
And we know thIs is true,
but it's also not all bad.
You know,
like we,
a good person takes care of his or her
family.
What does that mean?
It means you prefer your family.
The outsiders are going to get rid of
that.
It's a form of prejudice.
Like it really is like your choice of
sexual partners.
A form of prejudice,
right?
I mean maybe it should be distributed in
an egalitarianism manner.
Hey,
that would be a lot funnier if it isn't
a possibility like in,
in,
in huxley's brave new world.
That was the rule you,
you shared yourself with whoever asked
because it was rude not to and you know
what it is actually rude not to.
It's seriously rude.
Now,
is that something you want to take away
from people?
You want that to be distributed in an
egalitarianism fashion.
How prejudiced are you when you choose
someone to sleep with you choose that
person and not everyone else.
It's the ultimate in prejudice.
If you say,
well,
that's not prejudicial.
Oh yes,
it is.
Usually go for the most attractive
partner you can find.
Usually go for the healthiest partner
you go for the best person you can find
who could tolerate you prejudicial in
every possible way so
well,
so okay,
so your self serving and you construct a
view of the world that serves those
selfserving causes and some of that has
to do with power.
Fair enough.
That doesn't mean it all has to do with
power
though.
It means that some of it has to do with
power.
It's like racism,
people are kind of racist or maybe
people prefer their ingroup.
It's not that easy or maybe people
prefer the familiar to the novel.
You know that I eat that the social
psychologists have come up with implicit
association test that measures
unconscious bias.
We don't know what the hell that
measures the people who invented that
bloody thing.
They know we don't know what it
measures.
They know it's not reliable.
They know it's not valid enough to be
used as an individual diagnostic
instrument.
That's technically the case.
They also know that you can't train
people out of their unconscious biases
because there is not much difference
between the unconscious bias and
instantaneous perception,
but they don't really care.
I've I've written to mazda and banerji.
He's one of the inventors of the iet
several times saying,
how about you come out in public and say
what you already know?
Which is that people are misusing your
damn test.
Silence.
Well,
that's partly because her discipline,
social psychology is a corrupt
discipline as the social psychologists
have discovered over the last four years
and be turning themselves inside out
trying to rectify which they haven't
anyways,
we're giving the devil his due.
There's an infinite number of
interpretations of the world and it's
highly probable that you'll lay a self
serving one on top of it.
Yes,
and also that will serve the interests
of your group.
However you define that,
yes,
but it only accounts for a fraction of
your behavior.
There's all sorts of other things that
work as well and you don't get to reduce
all human motivations to one motivation
power,
and then you might also ask,
well,
why would you want to reduce all human
motivations to power?
It's so you can use power.
That's why you can justify the use of
power that's force.
You don't have to engage in civilized
debate.
You don't have to give a damn about the
facts,
especially if you're not a postmodernist
because you don't believe in facts
anyways,
and you might ask,
well,
why don't you?
Hey,
I'm not kidding.
Postmodernists don't believe in facts.
They believe that the idea of fact is
part of the power game that's place
played by the white dominated male
patriarchy to impose the theoretical
structure of the patriarchy on the
oppressors.
It's like I'm not making this stuff up.
It's embedded,
right?
In theory,
all you have to do is read it and you
find this out so they don't believe in
facts.
While facts would constrain the use of
power,
at least that's how it looks to me.
Okay,
so fine.
We gave the devil his due.
There's an infinite number of
interpretations and you're likely to use
bias compression algorithms on the world
and they're likely to be biased in your
favor.
True,
but
only partly true.
And the difference between an idea log
and the thinker is that a thinker knows
the difference between things that are
only partly true and things that are
completely true.
Things are complicated.
Like I like to think everything is as
complicated as a military helicopter.
You have to like,
I think it's eight hours of maintenance
to keep those things in the air for one
hour because they don't fly there rocks.
They plummet.
It's really hard to keep them in the air
and they're full of parts and if you
don't know all those parts,
you don't go in there and monkey about
with them because just wreck it.
And that's just a helicopter.
Like everything is way more complicated
than the helicopter,
so you don't just go muck about in there
hoping you're going to make it better.
That isn't how it works.
You need to be
competent.
Alright,
so look,
here's where the postmodernists sarong I
think there's three places and they're
serious errors.
The first is that there is an infinite
number of interpretations,
but there is not an infinite number of
viable interpretation.
So there's a very finite number of
viable interpretations and I don't think
that this is theory.
I think that game theorists have already
demonstrated this to some degree and
it's going to be built into ai systems
very rapidly.
Okay,
so what are the constraints?
Okay.
First of all,
you can't have an interpretation that
leads to immediately to your death or
your dad.
Now,
if you want to be dead,
that's fine,
but if you don't want to be,
then you got a lot of limited options,
right?
You don't get to run naked across an
eight lane freeway at night blindfolded
because probably you'll be dead.
That's a bad interpretation.
Okay,
so you might say because you're fragile
and vulnerable and mortal,
that there's a limited number of ways
that you can look at the world that
don't result in,
let's say death or serious damage or
agony.
That's a bad thing.
Agony is a bad thing.
Most people agreed on that.
So you're constrained by pain and
anxiety.
At least your interpretations are
constrained by pain and anxiety and you
know you can make pain worse or better
by thinking about it to some degree,
but only to some degree.
When push comes to shove,
pain is your master.
Okay?
So that's a big constraint.
That's a big,
big constraint.
Well,
but the constraints are worse than that
because not only do you not
get to have an interpretation of the
world that produces anxiety and
suffering right now,
but you don't get to have an
interpretation of the world that if you
iterated across time produces pain and
suffering.
And so that's,
that's a big problem because there's
lots of.
You could go out tonight and get
yourself blind drunk on cocaine and
sleep with hookers and you know,
maybe that,
maybe that'd be a good night.
You know,
you might not think about it being so
good tomorrow,
but then maybe your dad of aids in a
year or maybe you're addicted to cocaine
or maybe you're a street alcoholic or
whatever.
It's like as an iterable game,
that's a downhill.
And the thing is you play iterated
games.
You don't play one,
you play iterated games.
And so your interpretation of the world
has to be one that will sustain multiple
iterations across time because you have
to worry about 40 year old you and 60
year old you.
And that's a big problem.
That's a lot of use stretched over a
long period of time.
And it's worse than that because it's
not just you,
it's like you and your family,
right?
And not only so,
not only do you have to take care of
yourself now in a manner that allows you
to take care of yourself when you're 40,
you have to take care of yourself now in
a manner that takes care of you when
you're 40 so that other people are happy
to have you around now and continually
so that they'll cooperate and compete
with you in a positive way.
And so that's getting ridiculously
complicated.
It's not just you now when you in the
future,
it's you surrounded by other people
doing the same thing now and in the
future and there's a lot of other
people.
It can even just be you and your family,
you know,
like,
like the psychopathic burglar mob that's
just not going to go so well,
right?
Other people are going to object and the
world's going to object and so fine.
There's an infinite number of
interpretations,
but it doesn't mean there's an infinite
number of viable interpretations.
In fact,
there are hardly any.
There are hardly any playable games.
Now piaget,
piaget,
the developmental psychologist who's a
very smart guy,
he pointed out something very
interesting.
He said,
now imagine you ran a set of iterated
games as a competition and in one
iterated game the rule was you bloody
well do what I tell you to,
and the other one is,
well,
we'll all get together and decide how
we're going to do this.
Okay,
now we run the competition.
Uh,
piaget's claim is you do what I tell you
fails.
And the reason for that is I have to
impose force in order to keep you
cooperating.
And the imposition of forest is a cost.
It's an efficiency cost.
And across time that efficiency cost is
going to multiply.
And the equilibrated state solution,
which is the one where we all agree it
winds.
Now that's worth thinking about.
You can think about that locally.
So you've got,
you're trying to organize your family,
you have a little family conference
about who's doing what in the household
and what do you.
If you want peace and harmony and an
iterated game,
you get everybody to say,
well,
here's the tasks and we they have to be
done.
People have to agree on that,
and then you say,
well,
which task would you do?
You have to some how about you and you
know which task would you do and
everybody agrees and then you say,
well,
unless you can come up with a better
solution,
that's the one we're going to go with,
and then people can be a little
resentful and angry about the conditions
of existence where they have to work,
but they can't really blame that on
anyone else and maybe that's the best
solution you could come up with.
And that was pIaget's idea of the
equilibrium state.
It was like it's a voluntary agreement
that can be iterated across time.
That works at multiple levels of social
organization.
Man,
that's a serious,
serious,
serious set of constraints.
And piaget,
by the way,
was looking for a way to reconcile
science and religion.
He was looking for biological origin to
morality and he thought he found it in
the idea of the state and it's even
deeper than that.
So imagine this equilibrium state ideas.
Actually there's something to it that if
you set the the state up property,
it will iterate across time so long that
it becomes a permanent part of the
environment.
Hierarchy is exactly.
That's exactly what the hierarchy is.
Hierarchies are 350 million years old.
They're not the patriarchal invention of
white european christian males in the
last 300 years.
There are 350 million years old.
They're stable,
they're stable solutions to this
iterated game problem and they've been
around so long that we're actually
adapted to the and that's part of the
reason we have archetypal
representations of the social structure.
So and then we also have archetypal
representations of the relationship of
the individual to the social structure.
Your job as an individual in
relationship to the social structure is
to embody the social structure,
but also to serve as as its eyes and its
mouth so that can update itself when
necessarily so you take on the mantle of
your father,
let's say,
but he's dead.
He's the path he can't see.
You can see,
so you take the structure that's already
there and you modify it where it's
necessary and that modification process
is necessary or the state becomes too
static and collapses and that's why the
state has to be subordinate to the
individual and that's what western
culture has discovered and we can't just
let it go.
That's the idea.
The logos,
that's a big idea and you'd want to live
somewhere where you want to live
somewhere where the individual is
subordinate to the state.
It's like,
hey,
go right ahead.
There's lots of places like that,
man,
emigrate go there.
Ninety percent of the world's countries
are like that.
If you want to live like that,
man,
go find out what it's like.
You don't see immigration going there.
That's for sure.
Okay,
so that's a big mistake that the
postmodernist made.
It's not trivial.
That's a big mistake,
but it's not the only one.
Well,
here's another one.
They don't like inequality.
Well,
who does?
I'm against poverty.
You know,
that's like classic protest sign.
It's like,
really?
It's like I'm against torture.
It's like it's so obvious.
You don't get any brownie points for
being against poverty.
No one in their right mind is for
poverty.
You,
you ever watch the simpsons?
You ever see the republican party in the
simpsons,
they all meet in an old haunted castle
at night with like lightening bolts
going off and there's a vampire and a
crazy texts and then even the simpson
republicans don't sit around in the
haunted tower at midnight saying,
hey,
we need more poverty.
Here's an interesting thing.
So one of the postmodernist claims is
that diversity is necessary and they
make it racial and they make it sexual.
They may get ethnIc and all of that.
That's actually technically incorrect by
the way,
because
I study individual differences.
So those are the differences between
people.
I know the literature.
So you know about James Morris memo
right from google.
He wrote that partly because he was
watching my videos,
which is why he wanted me to interview
him and I'm a believer that there are
biological differences in temperament
between men and women apart from the
other obvious differences and that
they're actually not trivial and that
they maximizing the societies that have
the most have moved farthest to
producing egalitarian states,
the scandinavian countries,
and that.
The reason for that is that there's two
reasons why men and women,
different temperament.
One is biological and the other is
environmental and if you remove the
environmental variation,
which you do,
if you make the state egalitarian,
you maximize the genetic variation and
that's been demonstrated in the
scientific literature over about four
decades and no one wanted it or hope for
it and they weren't biased and looking
for it because that was exactly the
opposite of what social scientists
wanted to find.
BecAuse social scientists lean heavily
to the left and what they wanted to find
was you flatten out the state so that
everyone has equal opportunity and the
differences between people disappear.
That is not what happened.
The opposite happened that wasn't wrong
and no one was happy about it and no
one's happy about it.
Now you can actually tell when you've
discovered something in a social science
because you're not happy about it,
but
if you take,
let's say there's a big difference
between men and women in terms of trait,
agreeableness,
compassion and politeness.
On average,
women are more agreeable than men and
the difference is approximately this.
If you take random pairs of men and
women out of the population,
let's say you had to make a bet on who
was more agreeable.
if you bet that it was the woman,
you'd be right 60 percent of the time,
well that's not that much means you'd be
wrong.
Forty percent of the time.
That's almost 50 percent of the time.
So this is a big difference by social
science standards,
but that's the magnitude of the
difference.
There are some differences that are
bigger,
like the difference between men and
women's interest in people versus things
is actually bigger than that.
that's the biggest difference we know,
but it's a big difference.
Let's say the agreeableness difference,
but still they the shared attributes of
men and women far outweigh the
attributes that differentiate them
because you could ask are there more
differences with any groups or between
them?
Now the postmodern answer to that is
between them.
That's why you need diversity by group,
right?
That's why you need different races.
That's why you need different
ethnicities and sexual preferences and
all of that.
Well,
that's wrong.
There's more differences within the
groups than there is between them.
You don't get diversity by crossing the
groups.
You get diversity by group,
by selecting across individuals.
In fact,
the idea that there is more differences
between groups and there is between
individuals is actually the fundamental
racist idea.
It's the fundamental racist idea which
is,
well,
let's say you're asian oriental to use
the old word to discriminate the one
type of asian say from the other.
You're so different from me that there's
no overlap between our groups and you're
also so different and there's so little
difference within your group that now
that I know that you're not me,
you're not one of mine.
I actually know what you're like,
no,
technically that's incorrect.
That's wrong.
That isn't how you get diversity.
Now,
diversity is actually necessary because
people differ in intelligence and a
different temperament and the different
skills and so you actually need
diversity because otherwise you can't
take advantage of all those differences,
so you need diversity,
but you need genuine diversity and like
what would genuine diversity mean?
If you're trying to put together a work
team,
you want enough,
you want people have sufficient
diversity so that they more or less so
that you gathered together the
appropriate talent to produce the
implement that's necessary to work
properly in the world.
That's a competence marker because
otherwise your business is going to fail
and so the proper diversity with regards
to employment is the diversity that
meets the requirements of the business
essentially.
obviously that's why you try to hire
people carefully and not randomly.
Let's say
third error,
first errors.
There's only a finite number of valid
interpretation.
Second error is that
there are real differences between
groups of people,
but there's more difference within the
groups.
Then between them.
Third difference is social status and
payment.
Especially in a free democratic
capitalist society is based more on
competence than on
power.
In fact,
we would say that when a person in a
hierarchy starts to act like their
position entitles them to power,
then that hierarchy has become corrupt.
Harvey weinstein is a good example of
that.
I'm serious.
It's like he acts,
acted like a tyrant.
What happened to him?
It's not good.
Not good for him.
What he did was not good,
but it's an indication.
It's revealed.
It's an indication that that misuse,
so he's competent,
fine.
He gets to have position because we need
people who are competent,
but that doesn't mean you get to turn
into a tyrant.
If you turn it into a tyrant,
then that overshadows your competence
and you go as the definition of a
functioning state and our state
essentially functions.
It's not perfect.
That's for sure,
but compared to what?
That's the issue compared to your
hypothetical marxist utopia.
Well,
compared to your hypothetical marxist
utopia,
I mean we're living in auschwitz,
but you're what?
Your actual marxist utopia is
indistinguishable from auschwitz,
so we're not listening to that
comparison.
We're going to take a look at what we
have and we're going to compare it to
other places that actually existed in
time and geographically and by those
criteria.
It's like,
is there another time you'd rather live?
there's another place you'd rather live.
I mean the real place and real time.
I mean you want to live back in 18,
95.
Even in the western world where the
average person lived on less than a
dollar a day.
In today's money,
you want to live like those coal miners
like the answer to.
That's no.
If you have any sense,
you should have some gratitude.
That's another problem with the
postmodern neo marxists like zero,
zero,
zero gratitude.
It's all,
oh my god,
I'm more pressed.
Of course you're oppressed,
but you're not oppressed by the
patriarchy for god's sake,
so you have status in the hierarchy.
You might say,
well,
that's like a reward to your.
You're a high status person.
It's a reward.
The reward should be shared equally.
It's like a badge of merit that you get.
It's a privilege.
It's not the reason that in a capitalist
society,
filthy selfish capitalists put you in a
position so they can extract maximum
productivity from you,
and that's exactly why you're there.
You get paid,
you get paid,
so you keep working.
Why do we want you to work?
BecAuse your work is actually valuable
to us and so we're going to pay you so
you don't quit.
It's not a reward because you're a good
guy.
it's not a privilege.
That's not what It is.
You don't hand those things out like
merit badges.
That's not how it works.
The society is setup on selfish
principles.
We pay people who are competent so they
won't stop striving because we want what
they can produce.
So you don't just distribute that like
like it's a gift.
It's not a gift.
It's not a gift at all.
So that's another place where they're
wrong.
Social status and payment is the
consequence of the selfish desire of
individuals and the group to extract
resources of intellect,
creativity,
and industriousness from those who
possess them in excess.
Now,
of course,
it's not 100 percent like that.
There's the incompetent people who rise
to the top,
you can fool people and you can
manipulate them and you can act like a
tyrant and you know,
we might say maybe the system is like 30
percent warped,
something like that.
It's not much more than that because we
can account for people's success across
life by looking at their individual
differences,
intelligence,
con,
conscientiousness,
emotional stability,
creativity.
We can do a pretty good job of
predicting their trajectory.
So there's error,
some of its health,
right,
because sometimes you've got what you
need but you get cut off at the knees or
your family members do or you know,
some tragic thing befalls you.
There's a randomness in the system that
accounts for a fair bit of it and then
there's a certain amount of corruption.
Fair enough.
But not so much that the lights go off.
Okay.
What time is it?
Eight.
15.
And I started when.
Sorry,
it's been
6:30.
I should stop them.
Thank you.
I'm going to go for five more minutes
and then I'll wrap this up.
I want to talk about intersectionality
and,
and white privilege a bit.
So.
So I first said,
well,
we analyzed marxism,
we analyzed postmodernism.
I suggested that postmodernism was a way
for the marxist to keep going under a
new guys.
I suggested that marxism was
fundamentally based on hatred rather
than sympathy and an empathy.
I suggested that the corpses were the
the evidence for that.
I told you why I think postmodernism is
fundamentally wrong.
Oh,
now I want to talk to you a little bit
about white privilege.
So
the first thing that I,
and I haven't got this quite figured out
yet,
I can't quite figure out why the
postmodernists made the canonical
distinctions.
They've made race,
ethnicity,
sexual proclivity,
sexual,
gender identity.
Let's say those are four dimensions
along which people vary,
but there's a very large number of
dimensions along which people vary,
right?
In fact,
given that there's an infinite number of
ways of interpreting the world,
you could immediately pointed out if
there's an infinite number of dimensions
along which people vary.
And so then the postmodern question is
why would you privilege some of those
dimensions over the other?
And I would say,
well,
because it sustains your bloody marxist
interpretation.
That's why.
But you're not going to say that because
it marginalizes,
right?
You've marginalized that so you can
ignore it.
So that's one of the fun things about
organism.
You can.
I have a very vulgar image in my mind,
but
I won't share that with you,
but you can infer it.
Here's some ways people differ.
Intelligence,
temperament,
geography,
historical time.
You live now in 100 years ago.
Attractiveness.
That's a big.
That's a big one.
Would you imagine?
You could.
You won't.
We won't go there either.
Youth eat it's advantageous to be young.
You've got potential.
It's advantageous to be old.
You've got wealth.
Health,
that's a good one.
Sex women have advantages.
Men have advantages.
Maybe one has more than the other.
It's not self evident.
Women live about eight years longer
there.
Multiorgasmic,
athleticism,
well,
family structure,
friendship,
education.
Well then there's the classic,
you know,
postmodern once,
race,
ethnicity,
et cetera.
Why not those other dimensions of
variation.
There's no evidence that they're less
important.
In fact,
there's quite a bit of evidence that
they're are more important.
so like why not consider them?
Then you get intersectionality.
This is one of the things that's really
comical,
I think because the postmodernists
identity politics types actually
realized this.
They thought,
well,
okay,
race and gender.
Fair enough.
What if you're.
What if you're a black woman?
Well,
that's a problem because,
well now you've got two dimensions of
differentiation.
What the hell are we going to do about
that and what if you're,
what if you're gay and black and female?
Well then what if you're not very bright
and gay and black and female,
and then what if you're ugly and not
very bright and gay and black and female
and like you can keep playing that game.
You can keep playing that game and the
infinite number of ways because there's
an infinite number of ways to categorize
things.
As The postmodernist sorority pointed
out,
and so the intersectionality theorists
came along to plug the hole,
but they don't know where they're going.
They don't understand that the logical
conclusion of intersectionality is
individuality because there's so many
different ways of categorizing people's
advantages and disadvantages.
If you take that all the way out to the
end,
you say,
well,
the individuals,
the ultimate minority,
and that's exactly right,
and that's exactly what the west
discovered and you know the intersection
list,
so get there if they don't kill everyone
first,
so onto white privilege.
So it's really interesting to find out
where these ideas come from because it's
usually the scholarship is so awful,
you just cannot possibly believe it.
It's just absolutely.
It wouldn't end at the university of
toronto in the psychology department,
the original paper on white privilege
wouldn't have received a passing grade
for the hypothesis part of a
undergraduate honors thesis.
We're noT even close.
There's no methodology at all.
The person who wrote it,
it was called white privilege and male
privilege,
a personal account of coming to see
correspondences through work in women's
studies.
Well,
first of all,
personal account.
It's like,
sorry.
No.
So she,
she listed a bunch of ways that she
thought she says these are personal
personal examples of her unearned
privilege or unearned privilege that she
saw as she experienced in the 19
seventies,
19 eighties.
So this part of the way,
so this idea is the opinion of one
person who wrote one paper that has
absolutely no empirical backing
whatsoever,
which is a set of hypotheses which had
never been subject to any statistical
analysis.
Like if I asked you a bunch of
questions,
it's not obvious how many questions I'm
asking you because I could say,
how tall are you?
Or I could say,
if you're laying on the ground,
how extended would you be?
It's like that two questions.
It's like,
no,
it's one question.
It's just asked two ways and the way you
figure out if you ask someone a bunch of
questions,
how many questions you're asking them is
by doing something called a factor
analysis,
which is kind of an elementary form now
of social science investigation.
If you make a questionnaire,
you have to subject it to a factor
analysis beCause you've got to find out
how many questions you're asking because
you might think it's 60,
but it's probably not.
It's probably five.
That's the big five,
by the way anyways.
Who cares about that?
There's no such thing as methodology.
Anyways,
that's all part of the oppressive white
male european patriarchy,
so we can just not bother with that and
we can pin a few notes about how we
think the world is constructed and then
we can screw up the entire political
system two decades later.
Okay,
so here's your white privilege list.
Some of it,
there's like 50 things I can if I wish
arrange to be in the company of people
of my race,
most of the time,
if I should need to move,
I can be pretty sure of renting or
purchasing housing in an area which I
can afford and in which I would want to
live.
That's actually a wealth thing by the
way.
I can be pretty sure that my neighbors
and such a location will be neutral or
pleasant to me.
I can go shopping alone most of the
time,
pretty well assured that I will not be
followed or harassed.
I can turn on the television or open to
the front page of the paper and see
people of my waist race widely
represented.
When I'm talking about our national
heritage or about civilization,
I am shown that people of my color made
it what it is.
There's 50 of those,
I think,
something like that.
Okay.
Is that white privilege?
Is that majority privilege?
It's the same tree.
You go to China,
you're chinese.
Is the same?
True.
If you're chinese,
does the majority privilege benefits?
Majority privileges.
Like isn't that just part of living
within your culture?
So let's say you live in your culture,
you're privileged as a member of that
culture,
while obviously that's what the culture
is for.
That's what it's for.
Why would you bother building the damn
thing if it didn't accrue benefits to
you?
Now you might say,
well,
one of the consequences that it accrues
fewer benefits to those who aren't in
the culture.
Yeah,
but you can immediately associate that
with race.
You can't just do that.
Say it's white privileGed does many
things.
It could be certainly could be well and
the intersection of people have already
figured out that there's many things
that could be so like what the hell?
Seriously.
Well,
what's going on while we let these
pseudo disciplines into the university
because we're stupid and guilty
seriously and they have no
methodological requirements and plenty
of power and plenty of time to produce
nonsensical research and produce like
resentful activists and now we're
bearing the fruits of that.
It's not pretty so white privilege.
Well,
the other thing you might notice is that
to attribute to the individuals of a
community,
the attributes of that community on the
basis of their racial identity is called
racism.
That's what racism is.
There's no other way of defining it.
It's attributing to the individual the
characteristics of the group as if the
group was homogenous.
Now the intersection people have already
decided that's not a fair game because
there's so many differences between
people,
but the postmodernist don't care about
logical coherence because they regard
logical coherence.
Here it comes again as a creation of the
white,
european male patriarchal structure
that's designed to oppress the
oppressed,
and that's technically the case.
So logical,
incoherence,
it doesn't matter,
and you could say,
well,
if you act out your logically incoherent
ideas in the world,
you're going to run face first into a
brick wall,
and the postmodern answer to that is
there's actually no real world.
it's all interpretation.
So there's no,
there's no having that discussion,
but the postmodernists don't care
because they don't believe that
discussion between people of different
power groups as possible.
Anyways.
So here we are.
Well,
so I made a case tonight,
you know,
I'll go over it.
What's the case?
The postmodernists are wrong.
They're philosophically naive,
they're right about an infinite number
of interpretations and wrong about a
finite number of viable interpretations
and that's like that's,
that's death.
That's the end of postmodernist theory
and that's not the only way in which
they're wrong.
They're wrong in a bunch of other ways,
but they're more subsidiary.
The marxists.
They're not just wrong,
they're wrong and murderous or wrong,
murderous and genocidal.
Unless you think murderous and genocidal
doesn't mean wrong and you,
you can think that there's lots of would
be revolutionaries who would be happy to
have blood running in the street if they
had their chance for revenge and the
opportunity to move up the hierarchy of
charity so you can.
You don't have to think that murder and
genocide is wrong,
especially if the right people are
murdered in genocide.
Right?
That's actually part of the part of the
whole equation,
but if you're willing to think that
murder and genocide on a mass scale
across many cultures over decades is
wrong,
then marxism is wrong and the
postmodernist don't get to just come
along and a dark marxism as a matter of
sleight of hand because there are
marches.
Theory didn't work out and they figured
out a rationalization.
They don't get to get away with that
because it's too dangerous.
It's too dangerous to the rest of us
and we don't,
and it isn't necessary for us who are
trying with the small part of our hearts
that might be oriented towards the good
to allow people who are manipulating us
with historical ignorance and
philosophical sleight of hand to render
so god damn guilty about what our
ancestors may or may not have done so
that we allow our shame and our guilt to
be,
to be used as tools to manipulate us
into accepting a future that we do not
want to have.
Then.
That's.
Thank you.
Okay,
so we're just gonna do the uh,
we're gonna.
Move on onto the q and a now.
but before we do the venue wants to do a
little announcement.
Excuse me,
ladies and gentlemen,
I'm sorry.
My name's cameron mcneil.
I'm the managing director here at the
chan center.
As you are all leaving tonight,
please be where something has come to
light tonight.
Outside the building,
there is an individual impersonating a
ubc security guard.
It is not in the building.
It was in the rose garden.
There was no damage done.
Nobody was hurt,
but there is an impersonator out there,
so just please be aware of that.
Thank you very much.
So for those of you in the first two
rows,
you can either line up here or at the
mic over there and,
uh,
ask your questions
and also try to keep it short because we
don't have that much time.
Hello,
Jordan B.
Peterson.
I'm a huge fan.
I'm in your lectures.
Use the term postmodernism
interchangeably with cultural marxism,
nihilism and moral relativism.
I wonder if you've considered or heard
alternative beliefs that the term
postmodernism is not necessary,
is necessarily always congruent on a one
to one scale of these other terms.
And some limited circumstances is
positive.
Specifically the idea that when you use
the term postmodernism to vilify as by
some others referred to as pseudo
modernism,
whereas as some would call what you
endorsed to not be modernism,
but in fact metta modernism,
post millennialism or post
postmodernism,
which unfortunately has a terrible name.
And then I have a brief,
uh,
definitions of those words if you need
me to.
No,
as I said tonight,
you have to give the devil his due and
so we'll do that.
So yes,
there is a very large number of ways of
interpreting the world.
There's no doubt about that.
Yes.
People use biased interpretive lenses to
as means of interpreting the world to
put their own
priorities forward without necessarily
knowing that they're doing so and that,
that can corrupt them and society.
The psychoanalysts figured that out way
before the postmodernist so they don't
get any credit for that,
like really not.
Um,
so it's useful to keep those things in
mind.
It's when they're put,
but when they're put forward is absolute
truth that disturbs me.
It's like,
yes,
people are probably racist.
They miGht even be implicitly racist,
although we don't know what that means
and we don't know how it's related to
their explicit behavior and we can't
separate from ingroup preference or
necessarily from reaction to novelty.
So it's a tricky business,
you know,
and we don't know how to separate
stereotypical racial perceptions from
perceptual heuristics.
We don't know how to do that because
you're always oversimplifying the world
because you're not smart enough to live
in the world as it is.
You have to oversimplify it.
So yes,
there are times with postmodernism is
useful.
Are used it quite usefully tonight to
deconstruct postmodernism.
In fact,
so but but way it's when it's turned
into an absolute,
especially a moral absolute that it and
winded allies itself with marxism,
it's like,
sorry guys.
No,
you don't like grand narratives.
You don't get to go there.
while that's where you.
that isn't where you went,
that's where you came from.
You've never,
you've never left there.
So
that's,
that's basically what I have to say
about that.
Thanks.
Hello,
Dr. Peterson.
Thank you very much.
Now my question is regarding adhd,
which is something I haven't heard you
speak a whole lot about,
maybe a little bit now.
It seems to me that we are at least
maybe just me,
do not quite understand adhd to what
could be at full capacity maybe,
and because there's many,
many voices sayinG that it's an
overdiagnosed overblown,
small mental variants that's prevalent
in boys or it's just young boys being
young boys and then there are some that
would fight and advocate for a very
different treatment in the academic
world and I was wondering what you,
what your thoughts are on adhd itself
and on the,
whether you think it's overdiagnosed and
maybe advice for me as someone who has
been diagnosed with adhd on how to
overcome it without maybe becoming
completely reliant on prescribed
medication.
Okay,
so first of all,
it's definitely overdiagnosed.
Second,
it's very unreliable.
Psychiatric diagnosis.
Many psychiatric diagnosis are
unreliable and that's because
psychiatric diagnosis aren't precisely
scientific categories.
They're weird hybrids,
right?
First of all,
psychiatrists aren't scientists.
They're engineers.
Engineers are trying to do something
rather than to describe the objective
world and psychiatrists are trying to
make people healthy.
Whatever that means.
It's actually partly ethical.
It's very complicated.
We don't know how to distinguish it from
temperamental variation,
so for example,
if you're high in openness and high in
extroversion and low in
conscientiousness,
low in agreeableness,
and and high in neuroticism,
you're likely to manifest symptoms of
adhd.
It's because your exploratory,
you don't like to sit down.
You're full of ideas.
Your attention scatters across a wide
variety of topics and you're not very
stable.
Temperamental variation is also much
more common among boys.
Panksepp showed same guy with rats that
if you deprive young routes of rough and
tumble play,
which is what the young boys are
deprived of in school,
let's say that they get hyperactive and
then their prefrontal cortex is don't
develop very well because they're not
having the right kind of experienCes and
that you can treat that quite
effectively with psychomotor stimulants
like ritalin.
so that's kind of an interesting bit of
scientific information that no one pays
any attention to.
There is also absolutely no evidence
whatsoever.
That longterm use of psychomotor
stimulants produces increases in
cognitive gain,
zero,
and there's plenty of evidence that it's
harmful.
So
then the second part of that was what
about.
Yeah,
adjustments for in the academic world,
say that disability adjustments.
It's like that's such a rat's nest that
I don't want to even discuss it.
I mean it it,
I'll discuss it for like 15 seconds.
There is a never endinG multiplication
of disability.
That's what's happening right now.
The disability offices in the
universities are like,
I know some people have it rough,
like believe me,
I know that I,
I,
I seriously know that I've dealt with
extraordinarily damaged people in my
life.
It,
you,
you're,
you're bloody hard pressed to find
someone who doesn't have a serious
problem or who doesn't have a serious
problem in a close family member.
It's like,
where do you draw the line with regards
to disability where you can't,
you can't.
They multiply just like lgbt identities.
Multiply.
Just knows.
She really technically just like that.
Just like intersectionality cateGories
of oppression multiply.
It's,
it's,
it's inevitable the way that you deal
with it.
As you have objective standards,
you apply them to everyone.
Not because that's fair.
It's not fair.
If you,
if your criteria for fairness is that
everyone has the same outcome,
it's not fair at all.
it's not even close to fair.
It's just less piratical radical than
the alternatives.
Now we don't know that yet because we
haven't seen the full range of the
tyranny of the alternatives manifest
itself.
Not in our culture,
but it certainly did in other cultures.
I think it's a bad idea now.
I don't want to be absolute about that.
Like
it's tricky,
you know,
because if you have a disability
that
would allow you to do the work in the
university and in the workplace with a
modification,
then perhaps the modification could be
made,
but I think that was done a lot better
when I was in the hands of the
professors and not in the hands of these
crazy bureaucratic structures that have
risen up around the disability issue.
Like they're one of the 10 things that
are going to kill the universities or
maybe have already killed them possibly
because they may their walking corpses.
As far as I can tell zombies so and that
might be wrong,
but it's what it looks like to me
versus I want to say thank you so much.
Those an amazing talk and I was
wondering if you could elaborate.
What I noticed a lot,
I go here to ubc is that a lot of
students and young people,
they're often desensitized to,
for example,
the atrocities that communism or
ideologies that forced terrorism and
maybe it's some sort of stockholm
syndrome that I'm seeing where it's like
people are just there,
they're trapped and they can't.
They feel in a way they can't do
anything about it and then they start to
like,
like communism or they start to see more
socialists or adopt socialist policy
that in the end we'll get them killed.
We'll get them hurt.
As long as you kind of elaborate on what
you think can be done about that or even
if something can be done in that
respect.
Well,
I think something can be done.
I mean I've been trying to educate
people about the horrors of
the nazi regime and the soviet in
particular.
I've concentrated mostly on those two
because that's good enough and trying to
let people know that it was through the
fault of people,
much like them,
that those systems are rows and,
and that there are steps you can take to
limit the probability that you would
participate in such a thing and that
those steps are associated with trying
to be truthful in your speech and
actions because the stability of those
systems depends on the willingness of
individuals to lie and,
and also on your willingness to take
responsibility for the malevolence in
your own heart that manifests itself in
those social movements.
And so that when I don't,
when I do my lectures,
when I do talks like this,
when I put them on youtube,
what I'm trying to do is exactly that
because that was the best pathway
forward through such things that I could
think up over 20 years of thinking about
it.
Um,
you know,
one is so habituated to suffering that
they can read the gulag archipelago,
which is actually quite hard to read
without having an effect them like your
psychopathic.
If that book doesn't affect you,
it should.
If you read it properly,
it affects you deeply and it's not the
only example of that kind of literature.
So the people who are habituated aren't.
They've just been shown low resolution
representations of things they don't
understand that looked vaguely bad.
You don't know a damn thing about them,
and our education system has done a
tremendously appalling job of educating
young people about the absolute
catastrophe of radical left isn't now.
It's not much better with regards to say
the actions of the nazis,
although I would say on average people
are more aware of that,
but they don't.
But it's shallow,
shallow knowledge.
So you make the knowledge deep and deep
knowledge changes people and wakes them
up.
You know?
I mean,
the only reason that I ever got
convinced that they're that good and
evil,
we're real more real than anything else.
It wasn't because I learned that good
was real.
That's hard.
It's hard to learn that.
You have to find examples of
transcendent good.
You know,
they're rare,
evil.
All you have to do is look,
read history a bit and read it like it's
about you and there's no way that you
can do that without a transformation,
but people won't do it.
It's like you want.
Imagine yourself as an auschwitz guard.
That's a rough thing you see because you
have to figure out.
See young said,
if you confronted the shadow,
which is the dark side of people,
the aggressive side,
that malevolent side,
that it.
It really reaches all the down to hell
and dante sort of was trying to put
forward the same thing when he wrote the
inferno,
right?
With the levels of evil,
Because it was a voyage through the
levels of evil,
right to the bottom.
He thought the bottom was betrayal.
it's pretty good.
The,
the most,
the,
the center of malevolence is be trail.
I liked that because to be trained
someone,
you have to get them to trust you,
and trust is a moral virtue,
right?
especially if it's courageous trust,
because it it,
it puts you in alignment with other
people and allows you to move forward
into life and if you'd be trained that
you really,
it's like a knife in the.
It's like knife in the heart through the
back,
especially if it's someone who loves,
loves you,
betrays you,
and especially if they be you for your
virtues.
That's a really nice twist.
So
I believe because I think that people
are capable of good,
that if they know enough about evil that
that will straighten them out.
So,
but who wants that?
No,
this is one of the things I really like
about young.
He's often regarded as a new age
thinker.
That's wrong.
He's no new age thinker.
He knew that the,
the pathway to enlightenment was barred
by the necessity of a passage through
hell and that no one was going to do
that.
That's why there isn't a world full of
enlightened people,
you might say.
I think it was just a matter of doing
nice things following your bliss,
let's say however you might put it.
Then why wouldn't everyone walk up the
stairway to heaven?
That isn't how it works.
That's not how it works at all.
I don't think you can be convinced of
the necessity for moral action until you
understand exactly how dark and terrible
things can get and that it's your fault
that they're getting that way.
Who wants to think that?
So you can think it though,
but not,
not without it burning you.
So thanks so much,
lou.
Dr. Peterson a thank you for coming.
We appreciate it a lot.
Uh,
I wanted to get your opinion on
censorship that we're seeing on the web.
Uh,
it's accelerating.
You were a very notable example.
You were locked out of your g male
indian trump account.
Pardon me?
Yeah.
Trump's got a deleted by an in person,
you know,
now they're saying that perhaps this was
just a contractor and you know,
maybe someone from twitter who's gone in
a very far left direction.
A youtube has gone very far left
direction.
I'm just wondering,
I've started an alternative to youtube
called youtube.
Uh,
what kind of,
um,
what do you see for possible solutions
and just your thoughts in generAl.
Here's a crazy thought,
but I'm going to tell it to you anyways.
So I Was just reading one of ray
kurzweil's books,
I think it was called how to make a
mind.
I really liked it actually.
It helped me understand how the brain
compresses information because the world
is really complicated so you have to
make a low resolution representations of
it to live in it.
And he actually explained to me in a way
that I hadn't really understood how the
brain might do that neurologically.
So that was cool.
But you know,
kurtzweil is this guy who thinks that
he's a smart guy,
very smart guy,
and he's invented a fair bit of high end
technical technological software and
hardware and he's the guy that thinks
that we're heading towards the
singularity.
And so the singularity is,
you know,
how processing speed doubles every 18
months and hard disk capacity every
year.
And there's a bunch of doublings going
on,
a huge number of them and they
accelerate exponentially.
And so it's probably,
we're probably three years away,
maybe even less then from building a
computer that has the capacity to make
as many calculations as reasonable
estimates of the calculating capacity of
the human brain are currently set up,
18 months away,
two years away,
something like that.
And then we're 18 months away from
having one that's twice that fast and
then 18 months away from having one
that's twice as fast as that.
So that's like say six years
and we've got something that's eight
times as smart as a human being.
But there's a twist on that.
And this is kurtzweil twist,
which is as soon as you make a machine's
smart enough to make the next machine
that's smarter than it,
which is sort of what we're doing
because computers are so fast that that
will scale up to near infinite computing
power computing power almost
instantaneously.
Now,
let me think.
No,
probably not.
And Alan Gates partner has written
critiques of kurtzweil and you know,
you might think if something's
impossible then it won't happen.
Even if you don't know why.
And there's reasons to,
to not think that that will happen.
But kurzweil's traced to back the
doubling of computing power way before
the existence of the transistor and it's
been ridiculously stable,
crazily stable,
so god only knows what we're coming up
with here.
You know,
and you don't know what something have
infinite computing power might be like,
like you seriously don't know.
And there are serious people who are
very,
very worried about that.
They're very worried,
for example,
that companies like facebook and google
will manage that first.
And you know,
tHose companies are already making
censorship,
ai bots and that's not that smart.
It's sorta like making really fast
robots that can shoot people.
It's not that smart.
And we're doing that to very rapidly.
And you know,
I know some guys who work in advanced
ai,
you know how you look,
you watch the term terminator movies and
you see the robots that miss when they
shoot at you,
like they're not very bright because the
bright ones not only shoot at where you
are,
but they estimate where you're going to
be when you make your escape moves and
they shoot their simultaneously and
their death rate is 100 percent.
And so there's no war against the
robots.
I mean,
when those things get going,
they're going to be so much faster than
us that will look like we're moving
through molasses to them.
So
you know,
so maybe what we're deciding now with
all of our individual decisions about
censorship and the way that we're going
to construct the world and all that is
exactly what kind of super intelligence
we're going to bring into being.
And I would suggest that we try to bring
one in that's good and moral rather than
one that's evil and demonic.
Right?
So what can we do about that?
The.
There's only one answer to that.
As far as I know that that works is gay
rock together.
You're going to be the person who is
working in ai,
right?
I know some of these people,
it better be good people because they're
going to build whatever they're like
into their machines.
They better have their heads screwed on
straight because they're going to get
amplified like mad.
And I don't like What's happening with
google and facebook and youtube.
They're building censorship bots
predicated on a certain kind of
ideology.
The kind of videology that we outlined
today,
it's a very bad idea.
hopefully good people will stop that.
So then that,
what that means is that your moral
obligation is to be good and the way you
do that is first by stopping being bad
and everyone can do that a little bit.
So I hope that's what everyone does
because the consequences of not doing it
are not going to be pleasant.
They never are.
Thank you.
Hi,
this question is about your biblical
lecture series.
Um,
I liked that one because it's about
genesis,
which is usually ignored as being where
this post enlightenment society,
you don't need these ancient creation
myths.
And also I thought revelations kind of
gets the same treatment has been
dismissed because it's the crazy
hallucinogenic trip,
some isolated madman in the middle of
the mediterranean.
So I was wondering if after you're done
with genesis,
if you were thinking about doing
revelations,
not without traversing the,
the geo geography in between.
Okay.
Yeah.
I want to walk through the whole thing
if I can do that before they expire.
So I mean,
I've read it and thought about it and
like it's such a strange book,
a because it's really big among the
evangelical republican types and you'd
think really,
really that's the book,
but you're relying,
have you read it?
It's,
it's,
it's A crazy hallucinogenic trip.
That's what revelation is now.
That's not to play it down because God
only knows about crazy hallucinogenic
trips,
that's for sure.
I mean there's,
there's accruing evidence.
I would say that a tremendous amount of
the religious orientation of human
beings,
you Know,
that deep mythological,
symbolic orientation is in no small part
a consequence of humanities
experimentation with psychedelics
substances.
I think that's,
that the evidence for that I think has
become virtually an overwhelming.
So
anyways,
I will get there.
Maybe probably not because at the rate
I'm going through the first stories,
it'll take me forever to get there,
but that's okay.
So.
Right.
Thank you.
Yep.
Dr. Peterson.
Thank you.
First of all,
it's great.
Pleasure being here.
It's awesome to see you live.
Um,
I basically got into your work's just
earlier this year and I had an original
question,
but your talk today kind of made me
decide to change my mind and I was going
to ask,
um,
do you feel as though would you agree
with me in the sentiment that the left
has pushed so hard for total control of
our society over the last however many
years?
It's almost to a point where st 2013 was
a different time.
Would you say that because they pushed
so hard,
they've created this backlash and the
backlash created caused them to backlash
back again.
So they doubled down with their ideology
and then they get,
they lose another argument,
they lose another ideological war,
they lose,
lose another me more and they double
down and then doubled down again and
again.
And they can't seem to mean.
They can't seem to argue.
They can't see,
they can't,
they don't want to have an intellectual
discussion.
And as an interpretation of what you
were saying,
there is no,
there doesn't seem to be any,
any,
any care of what's right with them.
They just want power.
They just want,
they just want to win.
Um,
do you,
would you agree with the sentiment that
they're burning themselves out and
creating the mass red pilling of the
conservative movement that we see going
on?
Would you possibly think that maybe
they've committed suicide and,
and talks like this,
people like yourself,
ben shapiro and others who talk to
people like what?
The subjects that we do the taboo of
nowadays,
um,
possibly that this,
this is the answer to defeat the,
the leftist stranglehold.
It's society.
I
will untangle some of that.
Okay.
So first of all,
well first of all,
the first observation is a really
interesting one because you know that
things can go out of hand very,
very rapidly and the reason they do that
is because of positive feedback loops.
Now,
the thing that kurzweil talks about is a
positive feedback loop and intelligent
machine makes another intelligent
machine that makes another intelligent
machine and that's a positive feedback
loop and now can spiral upwards out of
control very rapidly.
And that's when polarization is,
it's like,
I,
you,
you tap me,
I slapped you,
you punched me well up.
It goes well,
I think that's partly why in the new
testament,
for example,
there's an injunction that says,
turn the other cheek,
resist not evil.
Why?
Because otherwise you get into a
positive feedback loop and then you
better look the hell out and things can
tilt very,
very rapidly.
I mean,
all you have to do,
look at what happened in world war one.
No one expected that.
It waS like one,
one relatively minor member I think of
the aristocracy,
if I remember correctly,
waS assassinated in one minor little
Country.
It's like bang,
everything fell apart and that's
positive feedback loops.
Right?
And so that's what we're in right now
and we've got to be.
That's a really chaotic time and so I
would say maintain self control and
don't aim to win.
Amen.
Peace.
Because winning,
that's,
that's not peace.
It's better to aim for pace.
You know,
I've got this tart coming up in November
11th.
I'm quite worried about it because I
know there's going to be protesters
there and that they've been emboldened
by the fact that they shut the torque
down before and I want to make a video.
I'Ll probably do it tomorrow telling
everyone that comes to that meeting to
like watch their bloody step and stay
out of the gutter because you just,
we're at,
we're at.
We're at a point now where under the
wrong circumstances,
if the wrong person does the wrong
thing,
that the consequences will be very
great.
Now we can't predict which action is
going to precipitate that and or even if
that will happen,
but it's chaotic enough so that it could
happen.
So you know,
so govern yourselves accordingly.
Now the problem is that there are people
who would be happy if there was blood
running in the street.
They the same sort of people that shoot
up high schools or kill innocent,
you know,
elementary school kids just to show what
they're made of and what they believe.
And that's a big problem.
But for the rest of us,
like hopefully calmer heads can prevail.
And so it really is important not to
win.
It's like fighting with your wife.
You don't when you can't because you
have to live with her.
I just can't win,
but maybe you can solve the problem and
bring about peace and so you've got to
practice doing that practice restraint
now and remember too that these people
that you're talking about who had
radical leftist is most of the time,
they're not like they're 95 percent like
you and if you pull them out of the mob,
they're just like your neighbors.
Nineteen year old kid who's kind of
clueless and rebellious.
Right.
And who you might even like you put them
in the mall,
but it's a whole different thing.
And so you got to remember that too.
Oh,
the fear of social isolation kind of.
You're saying no,
it's just that they're possessed by
these ideas,
but,
but only partially,
you know,
you hardly find it full blooded.
Absolutely committed radical leftist
activist,
you know,
like there are some but not very many.
Most of it is just fragmentary behavior
and you have to remember that like when
the students come out to protest me was
a case,
particularly at mcmaster.
I have to remember these kids,
they're not much different than my kids.
They are when they're in a stupid mob
behind a hammer and sickle flag,
you know,
but,
but
you don't want to make a low resolution,
homogenous representation of them and so
and so you.
That's why,
again,
I think instead of winning,
you turn to your own development,
you do what you can to stop doing the
things that you're doing that aren't
good because you're not going to hurt
anybody if you do that.
All you're going to do is help and
otherwise you'll participate in this
polarization and that's unless you want
that.
And you know,
there's a dark part of people that it's
part of the part that voted for trump
would like to burn things to the ground.
It's like to help.
I know how people felt when they went
into the voting booth.
It was like hillary hillary to hell with
it.
Trump,
you know,
and that's,
that's a hell of a thing to say to hell
with it.
You know.
Although I could,
I could certainly understand that
sentiment.
So we have to be careful and all of you
people who are here who are advocates of
free speech and who are theoretically
happy to come hear me speak,
it's like I really do believe it are
truly believed this and this is
something I learned in part from social
units and then part from you all missed
that.
The way that you set the world straight
is by constraining the malevolence in
your own heart.
And that's no joke,
man.
That's no easy thing and that's a good
voyage for people to go on if they want
something difficult and worthwhile to
do.
So.
Thank you very much.
Okay,
just a quick thing.
We're not going to have time for
pictures,
so you're.
Unless you're yours is the last
question.
Okay.
So sorry to everybody else,
but you're the last one.
Okay.
Hi Dr. Peterson.
Thanks for coming.
Uh,
my question is a little bit off topic
from everything else tonight,
but I really wanted to hear what you had
to say about it.
Um,
I work in residence life here at ubc and
in the community where I am,
we were recently effected by a suicide
of someone who lived in our community
and that I was upset about it,
not just because obviously it's a
horrible thing to have happen,
but also because rez life in the
university,
like they talk all this talk about self
care and your mental health is so
important to us.
But then things like this still
happened.
So I wanted to know,
like if you think like,
what do you think the university should
be doing?
Keep stuff
like this from happening in the future?
Well,
it's not self evident that it's the
university's responsibility and the
reason for that.
I'm not saying it isn't.
Okay,
I'm,
I'm saying it's not self evident that it
is because different institutions can
only do so many things,
you know,
and we were already requiring that the
university is to educate and to act as
substitute parents increasingly and to
take on the role of judge,
jury and executioner as there are more.
What should be criminal cases are being
handled within the university.
Say,
um.
Having said that,
you could ask the broader question is,
well,
what do you do to help people be
sufficiently in love with life so that
they don't wish to end it now?
And I've tried to puzzle through that
for a long time and that's partly why
I've written the things that I've
written.
It's partly why I've produced the online
programs that I've produced,
you know,
and so we know that if you do,
if you have students do the future
authoring program,
for example,
they're much less likely to drop out of
university about 30 percent less likely
and their grades go up.
And That's especially true if they're
male and marginalized.
It has a bigger impact on those
communities.
And so,
you know,
I've tried to get university's interests
now the data's there,
but they're not.
And it's very difficult to get a big
bureaucracy to move.
A big,
big is immobile.
So I'm not sure there's anything they
can really do about it.
It's certainly possible that the things
that they're trying to do about it or
making it worse,
you know,
that's another thing that you learn if
you're a good social scientists.
Just like there was evidence,
and I don't know if this is still the
case,
but there was good evidence.
I looked into this about 15 years ago.
Say you want to prevent suicides,
produce suicide hotline in your town and
you advertise it.
What happens?
Suicide rate goes up because you're
advertising suicide,
right?
And lots of lots of interventions are
like that.
It's really,
really hard to make thinGs better and
it's really,
really easy to make them worse.
And so that's another problem.
You get these big bureaucracies,
let's say,
and there hypothetically motivated by
positive intentions and I would say
hypothetically,
again,
because it takes an awful lot of work to
help someone straightened out.
It's no joke,
especially if they're in real trouble
and they put in place these
structures that are designed to help but
they don't ever evaluate them and they
could easily be making it worse.
So.
So I don't have a straightforward answer
to that question.
Um,
I think that.
Well,
that's,
that's the only answer I have.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yep.
So that's the end of the show.
Uh,
if you're in the first two rows,
you can stick around and get some
pictures.
Otherwise,
a drive safe and yeah.
Thank you.