Many of you will no doubt.
Remember Lindsay Shepherd,
she was the teaching assistant in the
Department of communications at Wilfrid
laurier university who was subjected to
a three member panel of inquiry after
she showed a video taken from Canadian
public television of me debating the
compelled speech legislation introduced
in federal bills.
See 16 she showed my discussion with
Nicholas Matt who held the opposite
position.
Here is part of the discussion and
question,
what do we do this?
Let's take a moment.
We're going to explain a few basic
things here.
The issue of so called non traditional
pronouns goes together with
nontraditional gender identities.
New York City for example,
recognizes 31 such gender expressions.
In other words,
besides man and woman,
there are 29 other gender expressions.
For example,
Penn Gender Queer,
gender,
gender fluid,
crossdresser by gendered gender blender
and the list goes on and Nicholas,
this is where I want to bring you in the
discussion because you teach this,
you teach trans studies,
so if you would give us a brief primer
on so many gender identities that in
your view require non traditional
pronouns.
Basically,
it's not correct that there is such a
thing as biological sex.
And I'm a historian of medicine.
I can unpack that for you at great
length if you want.
But in the interest of time,
I won't.
The three member panel included
professors,
Nathan Ramboo,
Canna,
her supervisor,
her bird Pimlott in charge of the
master's program and Adriana Joel
Manager of gendered violence and sexual
assault prevention,
shepherd tape the meeting and released
it publicly producing what I think was
the biggest scandal that ever envelop
it.
Canadian University and certainly the
only one in living memory that became
news internationally.
Nothing has,
can you share people from those ideas?
Am I supposed to come for them and uh,
make sure that they are insulated away
from this?
Like is that,
what's the point of this is because to
me that is so against what a university
is about.
So against it,
I was not taking sides.
I was presenting both arguments.
Okay.
So the thing of it is about this is if
you're presenting something like this,
it,
uh,
you have to think about the kind of
teaching climate that you're creating.
And this is actually,
these arguments are counter to the
Canadian human rights code.
Uh,
ever since I know that you talked about,
um,
[inaudible] ever since this past,
it is discriminatory to be targeting
someone,
um,
due to their gender identity or gender
expression.
So bringing something like that up in
class,
not critically,
and I understand that you're trying to
like,
it was critical.
I introduced it critically.
How so?
Like I said,
like I said,
it was in the spirit of debate.
Okay.
In the spirit of the debate is slightly
different than being like,
okay,
this is,
this is like a problematic idea that we
want when we want to unpack.
But that's taking sides.
Like it's taking sides for me to be
like,
oh,
look at this guy.
Like everything that comes out of his
mouth is bs,
but we're going to watch anyway.
Okay.
So I understand the position that you
were coming from and your positionality,
but the reality is that it has created a
toxic climate for some of the students.
Hey,
you know how many,
it's great.
Ooh,
like how many,
okay.
One,
yes.
May I speak?
I have no,
I have no concept of of like how many
people complained like what their
complaint was.
You haven't showed me the complaint.
Yes,
I understand that this is upsetting,
but there's also confidential at the end
of confidentiality matters.
The number of people's confidential.
Yes.
Although the university apologize
publicly for its treatment of shepherd
as did Ramboo Kenna,
it is not clear at all that the powers
that be so to speak learned their lesson
and the mistreatment of shepherd not
only continued but arguably intensified,
so she decided to press her case legally
and presented the statement of claim
against the three and Wilfred laurier
early in the second week of June.
It lists in painful detail the many ways
that this situation was mishandled
during and after the initial
inquisition.
I also discussed the situation with
Howard Levitt shepherds lawyer.
I decided that Wilford Loria had learned
very little from its public
embarrassment and the shepherds claims
were valid,
justifiable and necessary,
including her statement that our future
lack of employability in academia was
improbable to say the least.
I've been on hiring committees and I can
tell you that even then the slightest
whiff of scandal is enough to disqualify
a candidate
and consequence.
Not only did I decide to read and post
the entirety of shepherds claims,
which I will do in a few minutes,
I also decided to launch a claim of my
own against the same defendants.
I thought that two lawsuits might make
the point better than one.
I'll read some of my claim to after
shepherds and you can all make up your
own minds about the suitability of this
course of action.
Ontario Superior Court of Justice
between Lindsay Shepherd,
plaintiff and Nathan Ramboo,
Canna Adria jewel,
Herbert Pimlott and Wilfrid laurier
university.
Defendant's
statement of claim two the defendant,
a legal proceeding has been commenced
against you by the plaintiff.
The claim made against you is set out in
the following pages.
If you failed to defend this proceeding,
judgment may be given against you in
your absence and without further notice
to you.
Yeah,
to Nathan Ramboo Cana and to Adria Joel
and to Herbert Pimlott and to Wilfrid
laurier university
claim.
The plaintiff claims the following
against the defendants individually and
cumulatively the following 500,000 for
the tort of harassment,
500,000 for the tort of intentional
infliction of nervous shock 500,000 for
the tort of negligence,
100,000 for constructive dismissal,
aggravated damages in the amount of
500,000 general damages in the amount of
500,000 punitive damages in the amount
of $1 million.
The plaintiff resides in the town of
Waterloo in the province of Ontario,
the defendant's Herbert Pimlott Lord and
Nathan Ramboo.
Kenna are professors at the defendant
Wilfrid laurier university.
Pim Log was the coordinator for the
Master's program of the university and
Ramboo.
Kenna at the relevant time was the
professor for the course which shepherd
was a teaching assistant for both had
considerable influence over the
plaintiff's employment as a teaching
assistant and status as a master's
student.
The defendant,
Adrian Joel was at all relevant times
acting manager of the university's
diversity and equity office in charge of
gender violence prevention.
The defendant university is a creature
of statute created pursuant to the
provisions of the Wilfred Laurier.
Hey Act.
The university is vicariously liable for
all of the conduct of the individual
defendants referred to herein and at all
relevant times,
created an environment supporting and
facilitating acquiescing to and
implicitly and sometimes explicitly
endorsing that conduct.
The constituent statute of the
university to Wilford Laurier Act 1973
as amended 2001 and 2016 in providing
the fundamental jurisdiction and
authority for the university to operate
states as its object in section four
that the objects of the university are
for the pursuit of learning through
scholarship,
teaching,
and research within a spirit of free
inquiry and expression.
The university has no other object and
no jurisdiction and no jurisdiction to
operate otherwise.
The university has no other object and
no jurisdiction to operate otherwise
pursuant to section five powers of the
university.
The act further states that the
university has all powers necessary and
incidental to the satisfaction and
further its of its objects as a
university.
The constituent statute creating an
empowering the university provides it
with no other power or authority.
Shepherd was at all relevant times.
A student in the university master's
program pursuing your master's degree
and employed as a teaching assistant for
a course under Ramboo Cana.
And following that under Professor
Judith Nicholson as a teaching
assistant,
shepard supported a class taught by
professor Rambo Kinda.
She was generally responsible for
teaching to groups of approximately 25
students,
was assigned topics and was entitled
pursuant to the policies of the
university and have ramboo Canna to
devise her own curriculum.
Rambo Ghana wasn't indifferent mentor
who had only met with Shepard twice
about his course and only then briefly
ironically given his complaint against
her as delineated below.
He provided her with very limited
direction as to the content to provide
to her students in his classes.
The topic for one of our communication
classes held on November 1st,
2017 was grammar.
She taught three classes that day.
Shepherd introduced the topic of the
grammatical correctness of gender
neutral language in the evolution of
various languages and do facilitate.
Discussion on this subject showed a
field minute extract from a TV Ontario
program moderated by and Pakan
consisting of a debate between professor
Jordan Peterson of the University of
Toronto,
Psychology Department and Nicholas Matt
from the University of Toronto's sexual
diversity studies program,
Peterson and Nicholas Matt.
We're debating compelled gender
pronouns.
Peterson argued against being required
to use these new words,
which he argued had not developed
organically.
Matt took an opposing position shortly
following that class,
Ramboo Kana ordered her to attend a
meeting the very next day with himself
Pimlott the program coordinator for the
entire Master's program and Adrian Joel
Acting Director of the diversity and
equity office.
Both Rambo,
Kana and Pimlott had considerable
authority over shepherds.
Fate at the university,
apparently so to Joel Shepherd had never
been called into such a meeting.
Indeed,
Rambo Kana to that point had barely
acknowledged her existence at this
session.
All three lambasted shepherd viciously
attacking her personally,
falsely alleging that there had been a
complaint or complaints about her
tutorial and insisting that in playing
the TV Ontario clip,
she had been threatening to her
students.
Ramboo Kanick claimed that are showing
this TV Ontario clip breached the
Charter of rights and freedoms and
federal bill [inaudible],
which is not even govern provincially
regulated universities,
created an unsafe learning environment
and was illegal.
Shepherd was accused of Targeting Trans
folks even though Shepard had chosen no
side had up until that point,
disagreed with what she understood to be
Peterson's perspective and presented the
arguments and the debate neutrally.
Rambo Kana attacked and slandered
Peterson claiming that he was part of
the alt right and that playing a clip of
Peterson without first providing any
previous context to the students was
like neutrally playing a speech by Adolf
Hitler.
Shepherd argued the doing is he asked
would be taking sides and that was not
her role.
She was then further rebuked for taking
that position at various points during
that almost hour long vicious and
abusive attack,
shepherd was reduced to tears.
Ironically,
rather than being a present day
personification of Adolf Hitler as
Ramboo county implied Jordan Peterson
has spent decades educating his students
about the evils of the Holocaust and
specifically as part of his
psychological teachings has studied and
taught how individuals degenerate
ethically to the point where they take
place.
Okay.
To the point where they take part in
atrocities.
Okay.
As part of his psychological teachings,
he has studied and taught how
individuals degenerate ethically to the
point where they take part in
atrocities.
During the meeting,
shepherd was effectively attack as a
protege and supporter of Peterson.
Pimlott continued to libel Peterson
explaining that people like him live in
a fantasy world of false conspiracy and
accusing Shepard of being an agent of
those ideas because she had neutrally
shown this video with it's opposing
viewpoints.
Ramboo can have falsely but
imaginatively claimed that shepherd
herself was targeting people based on
their gender identity or gender
expression and in doing so had violated
the Federal Human Rights Code of Bill.
See 16 although shepherds conduct was in
no way violet of of that or any law.
Yeah.
Sheppard asked the individual defendants
whether her job as a teaching assistant
was to shield her students from debate
and ideas.
Ramboo Kana asserted that it was,
and then accused her of targeting
students due to their gender expression
and identity.
When Shepard pointed out that she had
not taken sides in this debate,
the three rebuked her for creating a
toxic climate.
The three refused to advise shepherd
what the complaint was or who
complained,
claiming that even the number of
complaints was confidential.
As was subsequently ascertained,
there had been no complaint at all.
Yeah,
shepherd protested that she did not
understand how we're teaching methods
constituted any disservice to the
university since the idea is in the
video were already part of social
currency.
Joel responded without any foundation
accusing her of spreading transphobia.
Ramboo Kana added to jewel's attack by
essentially comparing her actions to
white supremacy.
Contrary to the allegations of the
defendants at this meeting,
shepherd conducted herself at this
seminar precisely as her role required
and singularly represented the
principles of the Wilfrid laurier
university act for this,
she was viciously attacked by Rambo,
Canna Pimlott and Joel.
They continued to abuse her even after
she began sobbing,
accusing Shepard of causing harm to
unnamed students.
Shepherd apologized for crying during
the meeting.
Pleading.
I am stressed out because to me this is
wrong so wrong,
noting that the very spirit of the
university to challenge ideas that you
already have and reminding them that she
had not taken any side or position.
The meeting concluded with Shepard being
advised even after she promised to show
no further videos of Peterson or
anything of the like that she now had to
run all of her seminar notes passed
Ramboo Kenna to obtain specific approval
for any future clips of anyone that she
attended to show and that Rambo Canna
might have to sit in on her future
classes.
She was prohibited from showing any
further videos.
Finally,
they suggested to her that her job might
be in jeopardy.
The conduct of the defendants was
objectively outrageous and flagrant.
They had reckless disregard for the fact
that the foreseeable consequences of
their conduct would cause shepard to
suffer emotional distress,
which it did.
There are various policies of the
university which constitute a contract
between the university and its members
including Shepherd Article 1.01 of the
procedures relating to the prevention of
harassment and discrimination policy.
6.1 of the university notes that
informal resolution possibilities as
well as emotional academic and
departmental supports will be explored.
None of this occurred.
It also noted in article 1.02 of the
procedures relating to the prevention of
harassment and discrimination policy 6.1
that if the concern falls outside of
this policies jurisdiction or could be
more appropriately dealt with elsewhere,
the individual will be referred to the
appropriate office that also did not
occur under article 3.02 of policy 6.1
the office of dispute resolution and
support will determine whether a
complaint may go forward.
Article Three Point Oh four states that
the office is available to provide
guidance on the preparation of a
complaint or response to a complaint.
That guidance was not provided to
shepherd.
Article 5.01 of policy 6.1 states that
an investigation may be required when
other efforts to resolve the complaint
have not been successful or not
appropriate in the complaint by Jackson
referred to below.
No other efforts to resolve the
complaint were considered before
proceeding to the formal investigation
of shepherd article 8.03 of policy 6.1
states that Wilfrid laurier university's
prevention of discrimination and
harassment policy is not intended to
inhibit academic freedom.
It was used by Ramboo Kana,
Joel and Pimlott for precisely that
purpose.
Article 8.05 notes that the university
may take disciplinary action against
those who make allegations of harassment
or discrimination which are reckless,
malicious or not in good faith.
Although Pimlott Ramboo,
Kana and Joel had acted recklessly,
maliciously and in bad faith and it was
ultimately determined by the university
that this meeting never should have
occurred.
No action has been taken by the
university against them and shepherd was
provided no protection from their
predations.
The prevention of harassment and
discrimination policy provides in
article 1.02 that each member of the
campus community is responsible for
helping to create an environment that
promotes mutual respect and
understanding for the dignity and rights
of others.
This policy was violated by Rambo
counter pim law and Joel.
The prevention of harassment
discrimination policy defines workplace
harassment in article 2.04 as engaging
in a course of vexatious comment or
conduct against a worker in the
workplace that is known or reasonably to
be known to be unwelcome or workplace
harassment.
This provision to was violated by Rambo,
Canna Pimlott and Joel.
Article 2.07 defines a poisoned
environment as were harassing or
discriminatory behaviors are severe and
or pervasive and cause unreasonable
interference with a person's study or
work environment.
A poisoned environment may be created.
A poisoned work or learning environment
is one that is intimidating,
hostile,
and or offensive.
A poisoned environment can arise even
from a single incident.
It may be created by the comments or
actions of any person regardless of his
or her status.
Ramboo Bukana,
Pimlott and Joel created a poisoned work
environment for shepherd and thereby
breached the university's contractual
obligations to shepherd.
Article Four Point Oh four states that
the university will take appropriate
steps to fairly investigate,
respond to allegations of discrimination
and or harassment in accordance with the
procedures relating to this policy.
No such steps were taken.
Instead,
shepherd was wrongly attacked by the
members of the administration until
public and alumni outcry forced the
university to retreat from its position.
Following this meeting being publicized,
mcclachi president of the university was
interviewed on the agenda by Steve
Pakan,
the same show,
from which the clip of the debate
between Dr. Peterson and Matt was taken.
She was repeatedly asked by Pakan
whether Shepard had done anything wrong
by showing this clip from his earlier
show,
mcclatchy effectively defended the
conduct of Ramboo County,
Joel and Pimlott.
She refused to acknowledge the shepherd
had not acted improperly,
despite pagans continuing to press her
on this shepherd had the foresight to
taper inquisition when it began and
after outrage from the public and alumni
erupted.
The president of the university,
Debra mcclachi and Ramboo.
Kenna issued apologies in Ramboo Kennis
forced apology.
He continued to lie,
still insisting that there had been a
complaint and that he had been doing his
duty by addressing it.
It was only when public and alumni
outrage group that mcclachi was
ultimately forced to admit that what
happened to Ms. Shepherd in the meeting
was shameful and that the material she
showed was entirely appropriate.
That was a quote.
This was only after an investigator
found that there never had been any
complaints,
formal or informal,
and that Ramboo Kinda Pim.
Lots and Joel statements to the
contrary.
We're false and deceitful.
The university admitted in this
statement from its president that this
meeting never should have happened at
all.
No formal complaint,
nor even an informal concern relative to
university policy had been registered as
to the screening of the video.
The president only when besieged
acknowledged that these errors and
judgment were compounded by the
misapplication of the university's
policies and procedures,
that basic guidelines and best practices
on how to appropriately execute the
roles and responsibilities of staff and
faculty were ignored or not understood
that procedures on how to apply
university policies and under what
circumstances were not followed and that
institutional failure allowed this to
happen.
The president noted that as there was
institutional failure,
the responsibility ultimately started
and ended with her.
She further acknowledged that Ms.
Sheppard was targeted with vitriol by
members of the university.
Mcclatchy admitted that shepherd was
involved in absolutely no wrongdoing and
publicly stated that the university was
taking action to ensure that this did
not occur again,
a claim that was and remains entirely
false.
Shepherd has never received redress of
any kind,
nor has she been consulted about the
input that this treatment has had on her
and her career prospects.
Instead,
she was subjected to continuing abuse
and it talks at climate from the
university and its representatives as
described below
in mcclatchy's apology on November 21st,
2017 she states that quote supports were
in place to support student involvement
in a situation who are targeted with
extreme vitriol through the situation
and quote.
Yet she and the university offered
shepherd no such support in mcclachi
claiming to be troubled.
By the way,
quote everyone and quote involved in the
situation was targeted with extreme
vitriol.
She showed the same and equal concern
for shepherds predators.
As for Shepard herself.
The president also acknowledged that the
rationale for invoking the gender and
sexual violence policy did not exist,
that it was misapplied and that this was
a significant overreach.
Shepherd relies on mcclatchy's
admissions here in mcclachi claim that
quote Lauria is committed to the abiding
principles of freedom of speech and
freedom of expression and quote,
her conduct throughout entirely betrayed
that goal in Ramboo Canis disingenuous
apology to Shepard on November 21st,
2017 he stated open quote.
While I still cannot discuss the student
concerns raised about the tutorial and
quote,
but no student concern had even been
raised about the tutorial prior to his
and his codefendants bullying of
shepherd.
He acknowledged that his meeting with a
panel of three people would be an
intimidating for shepherd and would not
have invited a productive discussion
ramboo can.
His apology claimed that he quote did
not do enough to try to support her
shepherd and quote when he did
absolutely nothing at all,
but instead attacked her following the
public outcry the next time shepard met
with her students,
the chair of the Department of
Communications.
Peter Erkhart attended that tutorial and
offered shepard students but not
shepherd emotional support suggesting
that they would be welcome to go to the
campus wellness center.
He sat at the back of the room for the
entire tutorial,
effectively shutting down any discussion
on the issue and undermining shepherd's
role in her classroom.
Erkhart proceeded on behalf of the
university to publicly insult shepherd
when asked by email,
by Maclean's magazine why he appeared in
her class on that day.
He responded,
quote,
I assume she recorded it.
Why not ask her for the recording and
quote.
He then sent maclean's a second email.
Open quote,
sorry.
You're a pro.
I should have assumed that you've
already heard that particular recording
and quote.
Using his position of power and
authority over shepherd to intimidate
and embarrass her publicly.
Professor Elisia Slowinski,
who shepherd was taking a masters course
from asked in front of the class for
Shepard to put away her laptop and then
said in front of other master's students
that she gave this instruction because
she did not want to be recorded even
when shepard assured her that she was
not recording the class.
Further alienating and creating a toxic
environment for shepherd.
Following these events,
Ramboo Canis course ended and shepherd
was assigned to be the teaching
assistant to Professor Judith Nicholson,
a professor of communication who had
publicly taken a negative position
against shepherd prior to shepard being
assigned to her.
Before that semester even started,
Nicholson had signed an open letter
supporting Pimlott and Ramboo.
Kenna.
This made the university assigning
shepard to her tutor.
Lich entirely inappropriate,
created a poisoned environment for
shepherd and made it impossible for her
to succeed.
Shepherds apprehensions about
Nicholson's lack of objectivity toward
her.
We're quickly born out on three
occasions during their relatively brief
dealings,
Nicholson without provocation,
harassed and abused shepherd and
deliberately create a difficulty for her
from the outset of their meeting,
Nicholson told shepherd that it was her
quote,
academic freedom and quote and that no
one is permitted to make the university
look bad,
implying that shepherd had improperly
done.
So.
On the second occasion,
she sent out a course syllabus with a
territorial acknowledgement,
I.
E.
A reference to the aboriginal tribe
which had once been on the land,
which Wilford Lauria was on shepherd.
Considering this irrelevant to the
syllabus and a ludicrous act of
political correctness and virtue
signaling.
Cut that part of the note and tweeted
it,
noting that such acknowledgements were
now even on the syllabus of university
courses,
Nicholson demanded in front of the other
teaching assistants that she delete her
tweet when shepard protested,
that all she was tweeting was the
university logo with the course name and
territorial acknowledgement.
Nicholson threatened to take her to the
dean if she did not remove it.
Nicholson also absurdly claimed that
this territorial acknowledgement was her
intellectual property.
She proceeded to complain to the Dean
about Shepherd's tweet in an attempt to
further endanger shepherds position in
the university.
The Dean informed Nicholson that the
acknowledgement was not her intellectual
property and called an urgent meeting
with the two departments which shepherd
was associated with the communication
studies and the cultural analysis and
social theory departments at least in
part to discuss these issues.
It was clear that if shepherd had
tweeted positively about the land
acknowledgement she would not have been
in difficulty with Nicholson.
The third occasion was in March,
2018 when shepard needed to reschedule
her last class of the year and utilize
polling software with a link to
available alternate days for her class
to fill out their available alternate
dates.
When Shepard found times that all of her
students were available to meet,
she emailed Nicholson to seek her
approval for the new dates.
Nicholson reprimanded her copying two
deans claiming falsely that shepherd had
moved these classes without Nicholson's
consent in advance even though the
letter was just such a request and the
request on its face was premised on
Nicholson's consent.
When Shepard advised Nicholson that she
never had any intention of changing the
date without Nicholson's approval,
which was why her letter explicitly
requested that approval.
Nicholson counseled shepherds tutorial
entirely.
This was despite the fact that alternate
dates were available for Shepard and our
students to attend.
Nicholson instructed shepard students to
attend sessions of the other teaching
assistants on dates which were largely
coincident with dates which shepard and
her students had arranged.
Since this was to have been shepherds
last class,
she never saw her students again.
Ethan Jackson,
a transgender activist who has attacked
shepard throughout the events described
herein,
launched a formal,
patently frivolous harassment complaint
against her to which even after Ms.
Sheppard had completed her coursework at
the university so she would not see
Jackson again.
The university responded by proceeding
with a formal investigation.
Despite its inherently vexatious bad
faith and frivolous allegations which
pursuant to the applicable policies the
university should not have proceeded
with.
Jackson had an online crowd funding page
seeking a sex change operation,
which was initially denied because of
his mental health issues.
Additionally,
Jackson was banned from the University
of Waterloo campus in 2013 for
protesting and d platforming,
a member of parliament who was to give a
speech on abortion by dressing up as a
giant vulva and yelling.
Jackson was invariably hostile to
shepherd Jackson's allegations against
shepherd where that a,
she was on her telephone during one
class and purportedly disengaged from
participation in that class.
B,
Ms. Sheppard had made four tweets with
screenshots from Jackson's controversial
social media account.
Sea Shepherd responded to Jackson
walking into the printing room and
angrily ordering her to leave the room
and cease using the communications
department printer,
which she required for communications
coursework by referring to him as petty
and pathetic.
D when Shepard and two others were
putting up posters for a lorry,
a society for open inquiry meeting.
He claimed that they had followed him
and his colleague as they were walking
around the halls and that shepherds
posters had signage which he found
offensive posters,
which he acknowledges removing from the
walls without authorization.
The complaint of Jackson was made
maliciously after classes were over for
the year at a time when he and shepard
would not ever be interacting again.
Since shepherd is not enrolled in a
courses for the following session,
despite Jackson's complaint being
inherently self contradictory and
ludicrous,
the university not only proceeded to
summon Shepard for an investigation,
but threatened her with repercussions if
she disclosed Jackson's complaint to
anyone.
The attacks on shepherd have rendered
her unemployable in academia,
resulting in her abandoning her previous
ambitions of obtaining her phd or even
teaching at a university as a masters
graduate.
Shepherd has suffered nervous shock as a
result of the conduct of the defendants,
which was the foreseeable and intended
result.
In the alternative,
it was the reasonably foreseeable
outcome of their conduct and the
defendants were negligent in their
treatment.
Of Her.
So that's shepherds claim.
As I said,
after I reviewed this and talked in
detail to shepherds lawyer,
I concluded that Wilfred Laurier had not
learned what needed to be learned and
launched a claim of my own this week.
It reads in part
the plaintiff that's me,
claims against the defendants,
Nathan Ramboo,
Canna Herbert Pimlott Atria,
Joel and Wilfrid laurier university,
the following 500,000 for defamation,
500,000 for injurious false hood,
500,000 in punitive damages,
prejudgment and post judgement interest
in accordance with the courts of Justice
Act costs on a substantial indemnity
basis and such.
Further and other relief as counsel may
advise and this honorable court may deem
just the plaintiff's claim against
Ramboo,
Canna Pimlott Joel and the university
defamatory statements on Youtube on or
about November 2nd,
2017 Rambo Kana his then teaching
assistant Lindsay Shepherd to attend
what turned out to be a disciplinary
meeting with himself,
Pimlott and Joel to discuss her having
shown an extract from a TV Ontario
program to our students.
The TV Ontario program moderated by
Steve Pagan consisted of a debate
between Peterson and Nicholas.
Matt at the meeting on or about November
2nd,
2017 Rambo Kana Pim lot and Joel each
made numerous defamatory statements
about Peterson,
all of which the others endorsed both
expressedly and implied.
The meetings content has since been
posted online on a video sharing
website,
youtube and is available on the Internet
where it is open to the public and
easily accessible by anyone who wishes
to view its content.
I'm skipping a bit here at the meeting
on or about November 2nd,
2017 Rambo cannot Pimlott and Joel
falsely and maliciously made numerous
defamatory statements about Peterson
including but not limited to the
following defamatory statements made by
Ramboo Canna.
A Peterson identified student protestors
by posting their social media accounts
for the purpose of other people bullying
and threatening them online.
B Peterson is basically debating whether
or not a trans student should have
rights.
See,
Peterson's position would be the
equivalent of debating whether or not a
student of color should have rights or
should be allowed to be married.
Contrary to the charter of rights and
freedoms.
Dee Peterson has engaged in the
targeting of trans students,
giving out their personal information
for the purpose of having them attack,
harassed so that death threats will find
them.
This is something that Peterson has done
to his own students,
Peterson has done to other students.
He playing a speech by Peterson is
basically like playing a speech by
Hitler.
F Peterson's opinion is like alt-right
opinions,
white supremacist opinions,
Anti Trans Opinion,
anti gay opinion,
anti woman,
misogynist opinion.
G Peterson's view is whether trans
people are people or not.
Defamatory statements made by Pimlott
Peterson is academically suspect to say
the least.
He does not have the substantial
academic evidence to be a credible
person.
B,
Peterson's positions don't have credible
evidence just like Charles Murray with
his race claims of white superiority.
See,
Peterson brings hatred and targets
groups.
Dee Peterson Exhibits Charlatan Ism II
Peterson has nothing really that is
credible in terms of research defamatory
statements made by Joel.
A Peterson's position is causing harm to
trans students by framing their identity
as invalid or their pronouns as invalid.
Contrary to the Ontario Human Rights
Code.
B Peterson is spreading transphobia.
Now I'm skipping ahead a bit.
Again,
the said words in their natural and
ordinary meaning and the connotation of
the comments obvious to any reader were
meant and were understood to mean that
Peterson is comparable to Adolf Hitler.
The greatest bought in world history
deliberately spreads hatred both
generally and in particular to students
is a member of the alt right,
is unfit to be a professor.
Breaches the code of ethics of his
profession and university is a white
supremacist,
has and expresses opinions,
which are uninformed and uneducated,
is sexist,
is misogynist,
is racist,
is homophobic,
is transphobic,
is a deplorable person,
is in competent,
is a reprobate,
lacks integrity,
lacks the appropriate ethics to be a
psychologist.
And professor is a bully and abusive
towards students.
Wants to deprive minorities of any
rights,
organizes attacks,
even death threats on students,
breaches.
Canadian law dehumanizes certain of his
students and lacks credibility and
credentials.
The statements made by Rambo,
Kana,
Pimlott,
and Joel in for all of the above,
including,
but not limited to,
that Peterson has unsavory,
sexist,
misogynist,
dangerous,
racist,
homophobic,
transphobic,
analogous to Adolf Hitler and
incompetent in his profession as an
author,
teacher,
and professor,
and were false and specifically designed
to impugn his reputation.
These defamatory statements were
malicious and designed specifically to
damage his personal and professional
character.
As a professor,
author,
lecturer,
and public intellectual.
Well,
you get the picture.
That's the end of that.
I'm hoping that the combination of the
two lawsuits will be enough to convince
careless university professors and
administrators blinded by their own
ideology to be much more circumspect in
their actions and their words.
We'll see how that plays out.