Thank you ms Dot Peterson for being with
us.
Thanks for the invitation.
Yeah.
Uh,
what I found most interesting in your
book is the stuff you write about child
development and child upbringing and for
example,
you explain how overprotective parents
contaminants that are children who,
um,
you say it's far better to run beings in
your care,
competent on,
to protect them.
Do you think that parents today are more
protective of their children than
previous generations?
I would say that it looks like that.
Yes.
I think there are complex reasons for
that.
I don't think that you can necessarily
lay that at the feet of the parents.
People are having fewer children and
they're having them later in life.
And so I think both of those things,
those are major demographic shifts and I
think that one of the consequences of
that is the children's lives are much
more organized than they used to be,
which might have some advantages,
but that also parents are more likely to
overprotect they're older and more
cautious and the children also don't
have as many siblings and of course
siblings were part of the child raising
process.
And,
and it's hard to be over protected in
some ways when you're competing with a
bunch of siblings.
So it's complicated.
But I think that overprotection is a
problem.
Room 11 is to not politics when they are
skateboarding.
This is a recurring theme in your book.
Um,
if we are over protective with our
children,
we will create weak individuals while
you demolish people's resilience that
way,
I mean life is difficult and you cannot
protect your children.
What you can do is prepare them and you
can prepare them to be strong and
courageous and truthful and resilient
and reciprocal in their interactions
with other people.
And that means you equip them for what
life will be,
which is at minimum a series of
difficult challenges.
And,
and often more than that because of
course,
people go through very difficult times
in their lives and a resilient person is
capable of standing up to things in the
face of fear and moving forward,
voluntarily convinced of their own
competence and ability to prevail.
And so the primary,
your primary goal as a parent,
apart from facilitating your child's
social desirability,
which is a major obligation on your
part,
is to encourage your children into.
And I mean that literally to instill in
them a sense of courage in the face of
the difficulties of life and not to
protect them from that,
we don't even want to be protected from
those difficulties because a major part
of life and its meaning is the,
the challenge that comes with
confronting difficulties.
So yeah.
What do you want to say to those parents
that allow their eight or nine year old
sons to sleep in their beds at night
instead of sleeping in their own rooms?
Well,
I.
The first thing I would say about that
is you might want to ask why you don't
want privacy with your spouse.
You know,
the last thing you want to do is use
your child as an excuse to not interact
properly with your wife or your husband.
There's all sorts of reasons that people
allow their children to interfere with
their relationship.
And so and by eight or nine,
a child is more than capable of spending
time on their own and they need to do
that anyways because you don't want your
child to be either unable to spend time
alone or terrified debit you.
You also destroyed to some degree their
while,
their ability to cope on their own,
but also their imagination by not
requiring them to rely on themselves for
their own like co two for self calming
and safe.
And also for self amusement.
There's a rule when you're dealing with
people who might be dependent,
and this includes includes the situation
where you're dealing with sick people or
or elderly people,
and the rule is do not do anything for
anyone that they can do for themselves
because you take away their competence.
By doing that.
I want to ask you about the use of
physical force on children because you
think it is important to allow kids to
explore and harm themselves,
to get experience.
Stiller,
belief,
strict parenting is important and you
think it is justifiable to flick the
index finger to certain types of two
year olds.
Why use the use of force justifiable in
the bulletin change on the context,
and it also depends on what you mean by
force.
There isn't a disciplinary strategy that
you can utilize that doesn't involve
something that's unpleasant while you
can use reward,
but that that's a different.
There's different circumstances under
way and you should use reward every time
you can because it's more effective,
but you often need something that's
instantaneous and that gets the message
across.
And a flick is a very good technique
because it's instant,
it's harmless,
it gets the message across.
You can use it publicly,
it can't be misused,
you won't hurt the child.
Um,
you'd have to have an effective
disciplinary strategy for you since in
social situations.
For example,
you talked about the minimizing
minimums.
Yeah.
Well the basic rules are quite
straightforward.
Minimum number of rules because
otherwise the enforcement costs accrue
and you end up constraining yourself and
the child too much and then minimal
necessary force.
And you might ask,
well,
what's minimal necessary force?
And the answer to that is,
um,
minimum intervention necessary to bring
the behavior to a halt as rapidly.
And harmlessly as possible,
and that has to be negotiated with the
child because some children are much
more difficult to stop than others,
but isn't the political divide.
The Pot and child relationship can be
diamonds.
If basic trust and safety is lost or
it's absolutely the case that it's,
it will be damaged,
yes,
but the application of judicious
disciplinary force doesn't damage the
relationship.
It actually strengthens it and everyone
knows this.
Look,
if if you have a relationship with your
wife,
let's say the relationship is partly
based on mutual respect,
not merely on mutual love,
it's also based on mutual respect and
you.
Everyone tests out there partner to
determine what their limits are and if
you're not some subject to corrective
action on the part of your partner,
you will have no respect for them.
Your relationship will deteriorate very
rapidly,
so it's very important to understand
that the limits that you place on
children are not something that impede
the child parent relationship,
but actually further it substantially.
I want to talk about John Three quality
now and chapter 11.
You write the ball,
the soul called oppression of the
patriarchy and you ride it loose to me
like the sole colt oppression or the
patriarchy,
awesome.
Start on imperfect collective attempt by
men and women stretching over millennia
to free each,
all different providers and disease and
so the oppression of women happened
because it was practical.
No,
the the,
the oppression of men and women happened
because life is difficult and
treacherous and so we were subject and
still are to all sorts of terrible
burdens that are intrinsic to life
itself in.
One of the things that's happened is
because we're so technically in
materially wealthy right now,
we don't understand what privations our
ancestors even a few generations ago
faced.
I mean it was very difficult for women
to function,
let's say,
as as technical equals in the absence of
reliable control of menstruation.
That's only been a reality for say,
70 years and the birth control pill as
well as a major technological
revolution.
You mentioned technological advancement.
Yes.
So you hotels have been removed in
particular,
but you talk about the shoal cult
oppression of the patriarchy that women
were oppressed for centuries.
I mean,
well,
that's one way of looking at it.
The other way of looking at it is that
men and women were oppressed for
centuries.
I mean,
there are certain burdens that women
bore that men didn't bear,
but the opposite is equally true.
Yeah,
but in suffered dreadfully,
for example,
in incredibly dangerous occupations,
but it's the fact that women suffered
more than than men.
I don't believe that.
No one.
I don't think it is a fact.
I think that most people suffered by
modern standards,
it measurably,
and that I don't buy the historical
narrative,
that the fundamental reality of our
history was that men were oppressing
women.
First of all,
women aren't that easy to oppress.
As you might've noticed,
if you've ever had a relationship with
them and you might say,
well,
it took women a long time to struggle
forward until they attained civil rights
status.
That was equivalent to men and I would
say that's true,
but it also was the case for men that it
took very long time to struggle forward
before there was anything approximating
individual rights and that they were
granted to women quite rapidly in the
aftermath of that and that a lot of that
was a consequence of technological
transformation that made that sort of
thing even possible,
but we are both privileged.
White males can be really understand the
suffering of women.
Well,
it depends on how.
How useful your your capacity for
understanding the suffering of others is
or how well developed that is.
I don't see that it's necessarily any
more difficult to understand the
suffering of women.
Well,
I would never pose the question that way
because I don't know how you understand
the suffering of a group being an
individual.
I don't think a woman can understand the
suffering of women because that makes
the.
That's predicated on the assumption that
an individual can take on the burden of
a group and I don't buy that assumption
to begin with.
I think we.
We very in the ability to,
let's say,
empathize with others,
but I don't think there's any evidence
whatsoever that you can't empathize
across a gender barrier.
Otherwise no relationship would even be
possible.
A lot of people aren't given the
cultural oppression is still a fact in
modern society.
Uh,
for example,
something feminine is Conservative and
shopping.
Doesn't that sustain the oppression of
women?
Well,
I think that there are negative
stereotypes associated with both forms
of gendered behavior and that if those
are utilized inappropriately,
they can result in prejudicial
attitudes.
I think that most enterprises are
imperfect enough so that some residual
prejudice remains.
It might be sex,
it might be preferenced by gender or
prejudice by gender,
might be prejudice by race,
might be prejudice by ethnicity or,
or attractiveness or intelligence or
character.
There's all sorts of things that warp
the proper subjectivity of hierarchies,
but I think we're doing an unbelievably
good job at getting rid of those as
rapidly as is humanly possible and that
we've moved so fast in that direction so
quickly that we deserve some credit for
it.
There's,
there's one line in the book,
would you say you don't agree with the
theory of the Feminist Revolution of the
20th century,
but it's not the fact that the feminist
movement of the 20th century had a
significant impact for gender equality?
No,
I don't really think so.
What I will see my thing was equal pay.
What about,
oh,
what happened in the sixties?
I think that I think that to,
to lay that to the,
to attribute that primarily to the
feminist political movement is to give
far more credit to the feminist
political movement than it deserves and
I think the people who are pushing that
are primarily feminists.
I think that most of what freed women
was the extension of the idea of
individual rights to everyone,
including women and that that was
happening not only on the on the front
of women let's say,
but also with regards to people of
different races and ethnicities.
I think it's part of a much broader
cultural movement to extend the idea of
individual rights universally.
I think that's deeply embedded in the
Judeo Christian tradition and I think
that a very large number of
technological innovations played a far
more important role in the emancipation
of women.
Then feminist political ideology,
even though you can point to certain
movements like the suffragette movement
for example,
that pushed hard to have the vote
extended to women,
but even that I would say it was a
manifestation of deeper transformations
at a cultural and technological level.
I think the people who are pushing the
idea that it was the feminist,
it was feminist political machinations
that produced the equalization of the
situation between men and women are
mostly diehard ideological feminists who
like to think that way,
but it doesn't look to me like that's a
valid historical interpretation in the
least.
I would like to move on now.
I would like talk like to talk about
truthfulness in chapter eight on rule.
If you write about the law,
the lifeline,
it's a.
You say someone living in lifeline is
attempting to manipulate reality with
perception based on what you write into
the chapter.
Want to say that a large part of the
population in 21st century live a life
flight because they avoid conflict.
They say what they think pleases to
their spouses or their bosses instead of
telling the truth.
Oh yes,
they do what is convenient at every
given moment.
Instead of saying what they really want.
Yes.
Well perhaps not at every given moment,
but they certainly fall prey to that
temptation.
It's conflict avoidance.
Yeah.
Well,
as a psychologist,
psychologists deal with a variety of
problems,
but I would say the two most common
normal problems are anxiety and
depression.
That would be one class and the other
would be lack of assertiveness and lack
of assertiveness.
Subsumes the the problems that you just
described.
People won't stand up for themselves and
say what they need and want and then
they don't negotiate properly and you
might and they're avoiding.
They're avoiding conflict in the short
term,
which is a form of lie by omission,
and what that means is that problems
aggregate around them.
That's often why people end up divorced.
You know,
people will stay married for a long time
and one partner will say to the other,
eventually,
we'll I've been unhappy for the last
eight years.
It's like,
well,
that might have been something to
announce in increments,
say weekly or even daily,
long before everything accrued to the
point where the only possible solution
is a catastrophic disillusion.
There's a lot of conflict involved in
setting a relationship straight.
You have to let each other know who you
are and because you're different,
that's going to cause conflict.
You're going to conflict about whose job
takes priority and when you're going to
see conflict,
have conflict about how to spend your
free time,
but how to raise your children about how
to manage the domestic economy,
about what disciplinary strategies you
should use about where to vacation,
about what to eat.
Like all of those things have to be
negotiated through.
And all of that requires truthfulness so
that each of you know what the other is,
wants and will be with and conflict.
It's very,
very,
uh,
what would you say?
The only thing more exhausting than
telling the truth and negotiating with
your spouse is not doing it and waiting
for the divorce.
Both of them are difficult,
but I would recommend the former.
Yeah.
If we talk about the workplace,
what do you want to say to those viewers
that the regularly,
you know,
agree with her bosses instead of telling
the truth,
what am I doing to themselves in the
long run?
Well,
they're taking the soul out of their
work.
You know,
let's say,
well,
just imagine for the sake of argument
that you encounter one annoying thing a
day at work,
small annoying thing and then let's say
for the sake of argument that you could
have a little battle about that and
improve it somewhat.
Or You could just say it doesn't matter.
It's like probably doesn't matter today
or it might not even matter tomorrow,
but if you make a thousand decisions
like that,
which you will do over three years,
then now you have a thousand things
bugging you at work and if you wait for
five years then it's,
well then it's 2000 things and the same
thing happens with your kids and the
same thing happens in your marriage.
Those things accrue and they turn into a
monster,
but you would agree the conflict
avoidance is practical.
Sometimes people just go on with.
No,
I don't actually.
I think in a marriage for example,
there's almost nothing so small.
You shouldn't fight about it,
but the question is what does flight
mean?
It doesn't mean when,
like if if you and I have a
relationship,
let's say it's a business partnership,
it doesn't really matter if we have a
relationship and we have a difference of
opinion,
we need to battle it through,
but the purpose of the battle isn't so
that your viewpoint prevails or that my
viewpoint prevails because either of us
might be wrong.
The purpose is to engage in the conflict
jewel exchange of opinion so that we can
see a joint path forward to peace and
that's,
and that's the thing is like if you're
fighting with your wife,
the first thing to remember if you're
fighting with your wife is you have to
live with her,
so maybe beating her in the argument is
not the right outcome.
What the right outcome is is saying what
you have to say,
listening to what she has to say and see
if you guys can come up with a mutually
agreed upon solution that will make the
problem go away.
So if we explored conversation between
people in society,
if you.
I'll also,
these conversations are full of
falsehoods and lies.
People are nice to people that dislike
there are being fake because we try to
be friendly.
Yeah,
I mean it's.
Is it morally wrong to live your life in
that way?
Yes.
Yeah,
it is.
It is.
I mean,
you can't avoid the necessary conflict
of negotiation towards peace if you
avoided all that it means is that it
accrues and multiplies.
So the oldest one of the oldest stories
we have,
the oldest stories,
we have point to that as part of the
prime moral doctrine.
You know,
it's,
it's a form of impulsivity.
You know,
if you only do what you want in the
moment impulsively that there be
consequences of that into the future,
which is why you shouldn't act
impulsively,
impulsively.
Avoiding conflict is exactly the same.
And people,
same problem.
People know this.
You know if,
if someone's casually rude to you in,
in a bus driver for example,
and you'll,
you,
there's always the possibility that
you'll stew for hours over what you
should have said.
It's like when someone transgressed
against you,
let's say you have to say what you have
to say.
You don't have to say it as if you're
the totally correct authoritarians
tyrant.
You can say it in the spirit of,
of inquiry or inquiry,
you know,
because there's always the possibility
that you're wrong and you want to
listen.
This is also why you want to listen to
your partner,
your,
your spouse.
Even if what they're saying to you is
you find very annoying.
It's always possible that they're right
and you should listen because if they're
right,
then they can stop you from heading for
trouble.
In the future.
I want to go backwards.
I want to talk about rule number seven.
Yeah.
Pursue.
What is meaningful,
not was this expedient.
You write in the book,
there is no faith and no courage and no
sacrifice and doing what is expedient.
What do you say to those of you?
Where's that?
Don't pursue their dreams are locked
into their cadets because they are too
afraid to take risks and pursue
something meaningful.
Well,
the first thing I would say is,
well,
you shouldn't be afraid of taking risks
and pursuing something meaningful,
but you should be more afraid of staying
where you are.
If it's making you miserable,
it's like the first thing you want to do
is dispensed with the idea that you get
to have any,
any permanent security outside of your
ability to contend and adapt.
It's the same issue with children.
It's like you're paying a price by
sitting there being miserable.
You might say,
well,
the devil I know is better than the one
I don't.
It's like,
don't be so sure of that.
The clock is ticking and if you're
miserable in your job now and you change
nothing in five years,
you will be much more miserable and
you'll be a lot older,
but this isn't the luxury to pursue what
is meaningful.
Our viewers have with,
they have children,
they have payments in loans.
It's a luxury to pursue because we lack
the resources.
Well,
I don't think.
I don't remember now.
I'm not talking about what makes you
happy.
It's a luxury to pursue what makes you
It's a moral obligation to pursue what
you find meaningful and that doesn't
mean it's easy.
It might require sacrifice.
If you need to change your job to,
let's say you have a family and and and
children and a mortgage,
you have responsibilities.
You've already picked up those
responsibilities.
You don't just get to walk away Scott
free say,
well,
I don't like my job.
I quit.
That's no strategy.
But what you might have to do is you
think,
well,
this job is killing my soul or right,
so what do I have to do about that?
Well,
I have to look for another job while no
one wants to hire me.
It's like,
okay,
maybe you need to educate yourself more.
Maybe you need to update your
curriculum,
veto your resume.
Maybe you need to overcome your fear of
being interviewed.
Maybe you need to sharpen your social
skills like you.
You have to think about these things
strategically.
If you're going to switch careers,
you have to do it like an intelligent,
responsible person that might take you a
couple of years of,
of,
of effort to do properly.
When you say pursue something
meaningful,
is it important to have a vocation?
I think it's more important to to have
a,
an ethos and ethic,
so I have a program,
for example,
called the future authoring program,
which isn't writing program that enables
people to develop a vision for their
life and then to develop a strategy and
so it's based on the idea.
Imagine that and it's an extension of
the ideas in the book or at least
something along the same lines.
The first thing that you want to do is
figure out.
Imagine you were taking care of yourself
like you were someone you cared for,
which is rule number two,
by the way.
Essentially then you should figure out,
well,
if you could have what you needed and
wanted,
what would it be?
What sort of friends would you have?
What would your family relationships
look like?
How would you conduct yourself with your
children?
How would you educate yourself?
You need to think through how it is that
your life could be properly arranged if
you had that ability and then you can
name it that,
and the funny thing is is that if you do
pause it,
a goal of that sort and work towards it,
you will move towards it.
The goal will change because you'll
learn things along the way,
but I mean I've.
I've dealt with hundreds of people in my
clinical and consulting practice and we
set a goal.
We develop a vision and work towards it
and it things inevitably get better for
people.
So it's not a luxury.
It's,
it's difficult.
It's a moral responsibility and it isn't
happiness.
It's,
it's not.
The pursuit isn't for happiness.
It's a moral responsibility to push you
what is meaningful.
Absolutely.
I would like to end the interview with,
uh,
with site and criticism from your front.
Oh,
yes.
I'm Bernard shift.
Yes.
Your friends many years.
Some former colleagues at the University
of Toronto.
Yes.
He wrote an article about you in the
Toronto Star recently.
Yes.
Uh,
it was quite hard criticism on what do
you have been doing in the last few
years and he wrote,
Jonathan is fighting to maintain the
status quo to keep cares bay or so he
believes he is not a free speech
warrior.
He is a social author,
warriors are,
you were social author warrior.
I think that people can decide that for
themselves.
I mean,
one of the things that Bernie criticized
was my lecturing style at the
university.
Now all those lectures are online.
All the essentially like a
representative sample of my lectures
from the last 30 years are online and I
hundreds of hours.
It's not a few fragments and hundreds of
thousands of people have watched them.
And the criticisms that Bernie leveled
at me have not been leveled at me by the
watchers.
And so people can go watch the lectures
and make up their own mind about that,
but he also crashed into her motives.
He,
uh,
he wants to know what your endgame is
all about.
I mean,
what is your primary motive?
My primary motive as a clinical
psychologist and educator is to help
individuals live more meaningful and
productive lives in harmony with their
families and their community.
That's my motive.
And the evidence for that I think is.
Well,
if people go online,
first of all,
he could watch the lectures and decide
for yourself,
but you can also go,
there's a suspect,
probably maybe 250,000 people have
commented on the lectures and their
effects on them.
And so that's what people say.
I'm watching the lectures.
I'm trying to develop a vision for my
life.
I'm trying to become more responsible
and it's really helping.
And that's.
And that's what I hear all the time when
I do these public lectures like which,
which aren't political,
but when we gain success,
really raised the bar,
we set our ambitions higher.
I mean,
what is your end game?
What do you want?
That's all.
That's what I want.
I want.
I want to help as many individuals as
possible become more courageous,
more truthful,
and more engaged in the pursuit of
individual,
familial and social harmony.
That's what I want.
You're pursuing what is meaningful?
I'm pursuing.
I believe that to be the case.
It's certainly meaningful to me.
I mean,
there isn't everywhere I go now,
it doesn't matter where I land in the
airport or if I walked down the street,
three or four people will come up to me
and they'll tell me I was in a dark
place.
I was anxious,
depressed,
nihilistic,
drug,
addicted,
alcoholic,
homeless in jail.
You name it.
Bad relationship with my girlfriend,
bad relationship with my parents.
I've been watching your lectures or
reading your book.
I've been trying to tell the truth and
get my life together and everything is
way better and so then you think,
well,
if you could have what you wanted and
what would be meaningful,
you imagine you could go anywhere in the
world and people would come up to you
that we're strangers and tell you that
that's as good as it gets.
What about politics?
Do you have political ambitions?
No.
No political ambitions?
I.
I have ambitions to speak with people
who are politically motivated if they
want to speak with me,
but personally I've already decided that
what I'm doing at the moment is more,
and I thought this my.
I've made this choice multiple times in
my life that this approach is more
suitable for me.
Okay.
Ms Dot Peterson.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you very much for the interview.