[inaudible]
Bjorn Lomborg.
It's a Danish author and president of
the Copenhagen Consensus Center,
a project base us think tank.
We're prominent.
Economists are seeking to establish
priorities for advancing global welfare.
He's the former director of the Danish
government Environmental Assessment
Institute in Copenhagen.
Bjorn became known internationally for
his book,
The skeptical environmentalist in 2001
and how to spend $75 billion to make the
world a better place.
Cool it in 2007 which is also a movie
and lately published in 2018
prioritizing development,
a cost benefit analysis of the UN
sustainable development goals among many
other works in books.
And so I'm hoping we'll have a very
productive conversation today and
welcome to this discussion.
Thanks a lot of term.
All right,
so why don't you just start by letting
people know what you've been up to over
the last,
let's say two decades.
I know that's a very broad question and
and why.
I mean I've been interested in talking
to you because I read a number of your
books a few years ago and I was
interested in their economic analysis
and and as a way of determining which,
which crises,
let's say,
or which potential crises are real and
also how they might be managed most
intelligently.
Thank thanks a lot drew.
So you know,
fundamentally what I tried to do is to
say [inaudible],
this really is very,
very obvious.
We only have a limited amount of
resources,
so let's make sure we focus those
resources on the places where we can
help the most,
where we can do the most good.
Remember,
what is it that we mostly focused on in
the world?
It's very often the things that get the
headlines,
the things that people talk about,
it talk about.
And very often that ends up being the
things that have the cutest animals.
So the most crying babies of the groups
with the best pr and surely that's not
the right way to prioritize the right
way.
It should be to look at if I spend a
dollar or a peso or rupee here,
will I do more good than if I spent that
same dollar a rupee,
a piece out over here.
So basically asking across all the
different areas you can spend resources,
where do I help the most?
Now obviously that's a huge conversation
in and of itself because it's not easy
to just determine that.
But the basic idea is simply to say
let's focus on the places where you can
do the most good rather than the places
where it makes us feel the best about
ourselves.
So that's really what I've been trying
to do for,
for,
for two decades.
And you know,
prioritizing the world and trying to say
where should you spend money,
of course makes the,
the projects that we say these are the
really,
really great interventions.
They all love us and think we're the
best thing since sliced bread.
But of course the,
the projects and the policies that are
not so effective,
we think we're terrible.
So,
you know,
it creates a lot of antagonism and makes
a lot of people annoyed and interest in
it.
But I think it's crucial to ask these
questions.
Well,
one question would be,
what's the alternative?
You know,
like when I was looking at the UN
development goals,
for example,
if I remember correctly,
there was something approximating 200 of
them.
And this was a few years ago,
I worked on a UN panel and I thought,
well the problem with 200 goals is that
you can't have 200 they're not goals if
there's 200 of them,
because you absolutely have to
prioritize in order to move forward.
Assuming some limitation on resources,
which is exactly what,
what you,
what you just described.
And so then,
then the question would become,
well,
how do you calculate benefit?
And that's a really difficult problem,
which is I think why it wasn't addressed
with the mishmash of 200 goals,
apart from the fact that you're going to
offend people by rank ordering their
priorities.
So why don't you tell people a little
bit about the,
about the methods that you used?
Because I think they're extremely
interesting.
So you're absolutely right.
The sustainable development goals.
We actually work with the UN back in
2015 when they were doing this.
I,
uh,
it was,
it was about a 60 to 90.
It was very unclear,
uh,
UN ambassadors.
I actually met with a quarter of them,
uh,
in New York,
can talk to each one of them said,
shouldn't we try to,
you know,
focus on the targets that would do the
very most good.
And of course,
each one of them said yes individually,
but the,
the,
the combined effort of all the UN
ambassadors was of course not to
actually do the best goals.
It was to get everybody's goals in
there.
So,
you know,
the Norwegians had three ideas and the
Brazilians at four and everybody else
had,
you know,
three or four that they want in there.
That's why we ended up with 169 targets.
Uh,
which of course simply means you
promised everything to everyone
everywhere.
And that means a lot of people are going
to be very disappointed when 2030 rolls
around and we haven't actually dealt
with all the things that we promised.
Right?
So what happens there?
What happens there is that you,
the people who are doing that and
including everyone on the list,
maximize short term emotional wellbeing
of the people who had been doing the
consultation at the cost of medium to
longterm progress,
but then again,
they're not going to be around in 2030
and all possibility to suffer the
consequences of that.
So yeah,
or at least they're not.
Nobody's going to see that.
We failed to do as much good as we
possibly could because we will have done
a little bit of good everywhere,
but doing a little good everywhere.
It's not nearly as good as doing an
enormous amount of good in the places
where you can view the very most good
with extra resources.
Again,
remember we're estimating the total cost
of the sdgs as somewhere in there in the
range of two and a half trillion dollars
and the actual amounts available,
there's about $140 billion.
So we literally have 5% of what we're
promising.
So we're promising the world and then we
say,
hey,
here's a small amount of money and let's
spread it similarly.
So everybody gets a little bit of it.
Okay.
So that's,
so that's partly where you derive your
premise that we're dealing with limited
resources is that you're actually using
a real number and the number of you're
using is what's actually available.
And when you wrote how to spend 75
billion,
you basically go calf of what it was
available that yes,
that was about much,
much earlier on.
And that was mostly sort of a,
it's a fun idea to say how would you
spend a specific amount?
Yes.
And that was half.
Uh,
so,
so we weren't saying we should spend all
of it in the exact way that we were
talking about how would totally agree
with you.
So to agree with you,
people have to agree that everything
can't be done for everyone all at once
at infinite expense.
And that it's useful practically.
And,
and also even in a Utopian sense in
desirable sends to rank order so that
the obvious money that's available,
the money that's genuinely available can
be targeted best.
And so then the next question would be
how do you go about that in the least
controversial and most empirically sound
manner to,
to do the rank ordering.
So we use cost benefit analysis,
which is a very well established
economic tool that tries to say,
all right,
for each of the proposals that you come
up with,
how much will that proposal cost?
Now remember,
this is not just economics.
Most of the costs will be money.
But for instance,
if you want to immunize,
uh,
small children,
you also have to ask the mothers to
spend packs a day to go to the place
where their kids will be immunized.
That'll both cost them labor.
They can't do Labor that day.
Maybe they'll have transportation costs,
I'll have food costs,
there'll be extra the cost.
So we try to add all of those costs up
and say,
so what's the total cost of this
project?
Then we look at all the benefits and I
remember the benefits of both economic,
yes,
uh,
but there are also social,
for instance,
kids not dying or kids not being sick
and they are often also environmental.
So we tried to take all of those costs,
all of those benefits of both the
economic,
the environmental and social benefits at
them all up into one number that is
denominated in dollars or rupees or
whatever your currency is.
And then you can say,
well for this many dollars you can do
this much good.
And that means you can also say for
every dollar spent you can do this much
good.
Now obviously I'm simplifying this,
but in a sense what it means is if you
do it right,
a lot of economists has spent a lot of
time trying to make those right.
If you have all the same parameters
across all these different areas,
it actually means you can start
comparing different interventions across
all the different areas and say,
where do you get the biggest bang for
your buck?
And of course that is what matters if
you're actually going to do good.
So we did a,
and this is not,
please don't buy this book because this
is,
this is a very long at an academic book,
but we did this long and academic book
with with more than 50 of the world's
top economists looking across all these
different areas.
But the beauty is you can actually put
it in just one chart and I'm going to
show you that.
And then we'll also put it up on your
website.
So this is the ones,
one page chart that has all the targets
here.
And for each of the targets there's an
analysis that says how much will this
cost,
how much good will it do?
And then it shows for every dollar
spent,
how much good will it do?
If it's a long line,
it'll do a lot of dollars of good.
If it's a short line,
not too much.
So it really becomes this very simple
menu for the world to say,
where can you spend your resources?
And of course this doesn't mean,
you know,
just like when you go into a restaurant,
you get a menu.
Doesn't mean you buy the cheapest thing
or the most nutritious thing.
Maybe you're in the mood for it,
you know,
uh,
an unhealthy cake.
But it's incredibly important to know
what is the cost and what's the benefit.
And knowing this makes it a lot more
likely that the world is going to focus
itself on some of the really long bars
where it can do a lot of good for every
dollar or group you're a peso spent.
Okay.
So now if I was thinking about
critiquing this,
let's say from a social science and an
aura or a political perspective,
the first thing that I would object is,
well,
how do you,
how,
how is it that you know that your
calculation of the costs and the
benefits are accurate?
So you and,
and how do you know that they're
essentially as free as possible of any
undue political bias?
So because the critics,
no doubt we'll object as perhaps they
should,
that there will be,
let's call them implicit biases even
though I'm not a fan of that idea.
In some sense there's going to be
underlying presuppositions that weight
the manner in which the economic
calculations are made.
And then of course you also have to buy
the idea that the cost benefit analysis
approach is actually valid.
So can you tell me what you guys did to
forestall such to take such criticisms
into account?
And so first of all,
we don't just ask one team of
economists.
We also have other teams critiquing
those economists and we exactly tried to
make sure that there's sort of critique
some both sides if you will.
So we know that this is not just an
ideologically driven number,
but it's actually an empirically pretty
clear number that says,
for instance,
if you focus on on vaccinations,
you're actually going to do.
And what we find is you're going to do
$60 to social good for every dollar you
spend.
Now you could argue,
well,
what?
What would be sort of the ideal
ideological spin you could put in that?
Well,
one thing is to say,
well,
did you measure all humans as equal?
Yes,
we actually did.
And of course you could argue from an
economic point the same point that they
are not.
I think very few people would want to do
that,
but what we do is across all this,
all these areas,
all people are ranked as equally
important.
That is equally valuable and that's
obviously political consideration.
But I think one,
if we're looking across a world that is
the right one,
if anything,
that probably means that most rich
country people are valued at way too
little compared to what they're actually
willing to do themselves.
But this means that we actually get the
waiting right intensive sense of saying,
where are you going to spend extra money
if your goal is to help the most in the
world?
Right.
Okay.
So you used an approach that was
basically,
I would say a solid measurement
approach,
uh,
from,
from the theoretical perspective because
the idea would be to have multiple
measures of the same phenomenon or set
of phenomena and,
and to see where they are dovetail.
So that would be an issue of
reliability.
So if you have multiple teams of
economists and they all converge on
something that approximates an agreement
and you look at a diverse range of
opinions,
then you can be reasonably certain that
you've conversed on something that's
real.
And then you also have an element of
peer review in there.
Yes.
Another way of go,
go ahead and exactly what both of these
are obviously important to make sure as
you say,
that you get the reliability of the,
you actually get something that
resembles somewhat of a truth.
But the real point here is of course,
in some way,
if we just take a step back,
this is not a question about getting the
absolute numbers exactly right.
I mean,
that would be wonderful if we could do
that.
Uh,
but when I just told you that,
you know,
vaccination,
every dollar you spend,
we'll give you $60 back and it'd be
very,
very unlikely that that's the right
number.
But it's much,
much more about getting the order of
magnitude right.
Is it 60 or is it six or is it $600 you
get back?
Because really the point here is to
compare across all these other things
that you could also have spent that
money on.
And there we have a much greater uh,
sort of reliability because we're pretty
sure that even if you change the
assumption very much,
you will still get much of the same kind
of picture.
You won't get exactly the same picture,
but you'll very much get the same sort
of picture,
which indicates that there's a few
targets that we'll do an amazing amount
of good.
And there's a lot of targets.
I'll just do a little good.
And so again,
we tried to say is do the amazing
targets first.
Okay.
So the critical thing for you guys to
get right as the rank ordering and not
the absolute magnet as well.
So as long as your method is stable
across all the different domains,
then the rank ordering should be
relatively stable.
Now did you get a prieto distribution
with regards to um,
positive impact of investment?
Like is there a handful of interventions
that are clearly head and shoulders
above the rest in terms of generating
positive economic outcome and,
and what,
and what proportion of the total number
of say 170 goals,
like if you did,
if you accomplish 10% of the 170 goals,
how much of the Economic Bang for your
buck would you,
would you accrue?
I should actually just say I didn't
plant that question.
That's wonderful because that's exactly
what we tried to do.
So if you do across all these areas,
every dollar spent,
we'll do about $7 of good if you just
did it across all of them equally,
which is probably unreasonable to
assume,
but it's not,
you know,
unreasonable.
And the sort of first order
approximation,
if you spend it on the best 19 targets,
you would do $32 of good.
So more than four times more.
Good.
So you can simply spend you're the same
dollar and do more than four times more
good than you would do if you just
scattershot it across all areas.
And again,
what you also have to remember is a lot
of the things that we're looking at,
which are really,
really effective.
Also things that are much easier to do.
So two of the best things that we point
out is actually contraception.
So family planning for women.
Why?
Because if you do that,
not that there's,
there's about 13% of women that still
don't have access to contraception.
Uh,
and if they got that access,
they would be able to better space it
kits.
And we know that that means that you can
actually have your pubes when you're
ready to have them.
That means you put more effort and
investment into your kids.
So they'll grow up better,
they'll be fed better,
they'll have a greater chance of
surviving,
but they'll also become more productive
in the long run.
It also means fewer of those kids are
going to die,
few of moms are going to die.
So we actually estimate you'd see about
600,000 fewer kids die and you would get
a demographic dividend that is basically
because you have slightly,
if your kids,
you can invest more in them,
you get better return on every kid.
You have slightly higher growth rates
and so we estimate for every dollar you
spend that family planning you will do
$120 of social good.
The other great thing is invest in free
trade.
Free Trade is something that we've sort
of forgotten.
Uh,
we actually had the last big free trade,
a discussion from Doha,
uh,
back in 1999.
It's basically,
you know,
stop being a concern obviously with
trump but also with many other people
who have sort of given up on free trade
yet.
We have to remember that one of the
basic things that have made us wealthy
is the fact that we trade with each
other.
You do what you're good at and I do what
I'm good at.
And that means when we change,
we actually all get better off.
There are some issues here
in some,
in some detail.
What,
what,
what that would mean practically.
Like what are the sorts of barriers that
you guys determined were particularly
troublesome that need to be addressed.
So we actually estimate it,
what would it take to get a reasonably
successful dough around,
which would not be free trade,
but it would be free yard trade.
So it would simply be reduced.
Harris,
make it easier for everyone to trade
across the world,
especially from the developing world to
the developed world.
And one of the outcomes we found was not
only that,
on average,
every person in the world would be
about,
sorry,
in the developing world would be about a
thousand dollars richer per person per
year in 2030 so by the end of the
sustainable development goals,
we would lift 145 million people out of
poverty.
But we would simply make everyone better
off because if you're in a poor country,
you would be able to sell the things
that you do best.
How little easier,
a little cheaper,
and hence be able to market more of it.
And you'd be able to buy back more from
other developed countries and that would
make everyone better off.
So again,
this is not,
this is not rocket science.
I mean if you look at China,
for instance,
uh,
China over the last 30 years lifted what
had 680 million people out of poverty,
very largely driven by the fact that
they could trade with the rest of the
world.
Imagine if we could make that happen for
sub Saharan Africa if we could make that
happen more for Latin America.
So again,
it's more about realizing that for very
little money,
some of these things can do an amazing
amount of good and we tend to forget
because there's no focus on these
issues.
We don't think about a family planning
or or,
or a free trade or indeed vaccinations.
We think about all kinds of other things
like plastic waste or global warming or
many other things that have a lot of
sort of,
uh,
attention from,
from celebrities and getting the
newspaper.
And that's because there are no
problems.
But it's about getting a sense of what's
the magnitude of how much good we can do
with little money.
And let's talk about global warming
because by,
okay,
so my,
my,
I've talked to lots of people about your
work and you know,
you obviously have a lot of admirers and
you have a lot of detractors.
And I'd be listening to the detractors
because I believed after I had reviewed
the UN development goals,
I had come to the same conclusion that
you had come to before I knew what you
had done,
which was these things need to be rank
ordered because otherwise it's not a
plan.
It's not a strategy.
And so then there has to be some
mechanism for rank ordering them.
And I ran across your work and I
thought,
well that seems to be exactly right to
me from an agnostic perspective,
let's say it's an interesting idea
because what you have to start with is
the willingness to be agnostic about
what the worst problems are and while
the worst and most solvable problems,
let's say at the same time,
you have to be agnostic about that.
And I actually think that that's part of
the reason why what you do bothers so
many people because they have an a
priori commitment to what constitutes
the most salient catastrophe.
And that's clearly at the moment is,
is the eye,
the idea that,
uh,
climate change or global warming,
depending on how you want to phrase it,
um,
constitutes such an immediate and
pressing threat of,
of overwhelming economic magnitude that
a sacrifice of any amount is worth some
probability of forestalling that.
And so,
um,
one of the things that striking about
your list and maybe what I should do is
have you tell us what the top seven or
eight are just so that we have some
sense of what the priorities are.
Because one of the things I noticed was
that they don't tend
to include measures that are designed to
forestall global warming.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
we actually,
we,
we had two Nobel laureates,
um,
look over all of these evident,
all of this evidence and set priorities
and then come out with 19 targets that
they focused on.
Actually one of them was,
uh,
stop fossil fuel subsidies,
which is obviously a stupid idea in so
many different ways.
Uh,
remember this is most of them developing
countries where it's very often done,
uh,
to basically pacified population a
little bit.
Like you make a subsidies for bread or
other things.
Uh,
but of course the idea of subsidizing
fossil fuels like that.
So it was done in Indonesia has done,
uh,
is basically a way of subsidizing fairly
wealthy people to drive their car that
you have to have a car in order to enjoy
this a and drive it more and actually
create more congestion,
more inclusion and with very few
benefits.
Uh,
so clearly what you should be doing is
scrap those subsidies for fossil fuels,
not only because they lead to more,
uh,
air pollution and co two emissions,
but also because they're just terribly
bad use of public resources that could
have been spent on education or health
or other places they could have done a
lot more.
Good.
But just to give you a sense of some of
the other ones that we were talking
about,
uh,
expanded immunization as we talked
about.
That's an incredibly good way.
We know that we're right now cut child
mortality that is under five mortality
from about 12 million kids dying every
year in 1992 about 6 million.
That's a fantastic achievement.
Of course,
6 million is still a mind boggling
number that's way,
way too large.
And we actually know that by investing
about a billion dollars,
we could save a million kids every year
that you've got to almost say that again
for $1 billion.
You could save a million kids' lives
every year.
Why the hell is that not one of our top
priorities?
And that's also why we show for every
dollar spent,
you actually do $60 worth of goods and
other incredible,
uh,
investment is in nutrition.
Uh,
so,
you know,
everybody kind of knows that it's,
it's not right that people are starving
and we know that we could actually feed
everyone.
The main reason why people are still
starving is because they don't have
enough money.
It's not because we can't produce it.
So it's because they're poor and they
don't actually have the demand capacity.
But the real tragedy of malnutrition is
a,
if you get it when you're really small,
so from zero to two years of age,
your brain develops less.
And that means when you get into school,
you're actually less able to learn and
that stays with you for your entire
life.
You stay less long than school,
you learn less than you come out and you
actually are not very productive.
We know this now we,
we've had this as a theoretical argument
for a long time.
Uh,
but researchers in some of the
researchers that we work with have not
actually proven this because they went
back to an old study done in Guatemala
and the late 1960s,
uh,
where researchers went to two small
villages,
ruled water model and gave the kids
there.
So the really small zero to two year
olds,
good food,
and then they took to other rural
villages nearby and gave the kids
essentially sugar water.
Of course you couldn't do this today.
But the brilliant thing about it is,
as our researchers then refound these
kids,
they now in their late thirties early
forties and you could see what had
happened,
and it was exactly what the theory
predicted.
If you had gotten good food,
you stayed longer in school,
you'll learn more every year in school.
And so when you came out,
you were much more productive.
And one of the ways we measure that is
you had higher incomes.
If you're avoiding being stunned,
it you had 60% higher income.
That's just a phenomenal outcome.
So again,
spend money,
for instance,
a malnutrition by getting good food and
also research and development into
better yielding varieties.
And you can do an incredible amount of
good for every dollar we estimate $35 or
thereabouts,
right?
And so what you're doing is for stalling
cognitive deterioration in the,
in the first two years.
And because cognitive ability is a great
predictor of longterm success,
then you're producing people who are
much more likely to be economically
productive for themselves and for other
people.
Right?
And so,
yeah,
it is.
It's also for other people,
right?
If you're yeah,
you're good.
You're likely to make other people
better too.
Yeah.
Right.
Oh yes.
That's an absolutely crucial issue.
So,
so yeah,
so,
so it's quite striking.
It was quite striking to me when I came
across your work to find out to what
degree it was focused on targeting
children's health in some fundamental
sense in the developing world.
That seems to be,
if you had to put it in a nutshell,
correct me if I'm wrong.
That seemed to be where are you guys
focused or where,
where your focus took you and
what else can I just say?
Because there's also some other very low
hanging fruit.
For instance,
uh,
what you're seeing increasingly across
the world is
that more and more people died,
not of infectious diseases because we've
actually tackled many of those.
But they died from old age diseases like
cancer and heart disease.
Those,
it by far the biggest issues,
cancer,
it turns out to be fairly costly to deal
with.
But heart disease,
we've actually now figure it out pretty
much how to deal with,
not to the extent that we will live
forever,
but that we can make people live much
longer.
And that's basically by giving very
cheap and off Patton,
a heart med medication.
So we give this a lot of middle aged
people and the developed world and it's
very,
very cheap to also do in the developing
world.
So we can save about three years of life
for these elderly people,
both men and women.
And it costs peanuts and you can
basically make all lives longer.
And so that's one of the places where we
also show there's a huge benefit.
We also emphasize,
and this is again one of the depressing
things that we should be focusing a lot
more on tuberculosis,
tuberculosis.
Now the world's leading infectious
disease killer.
It's no longer HIV aids.
Uh,
that's still a good idea to invest in,
but it's actually needing better idea to
invest in tuberculosis.
But again,
because it's an old diseases,
you know,
it's been with us for hundreds of years
and we kind of learned to how to fix it
a hundred years ago.
It's not an issue in the developed
world,
so most people don't want to hear about
it,
don't care about it.
But it's a crucial killer that kills 1.4
million people every year in the
developing world.
And we have the means to eradicate
pretty much all of those that's very,
very cheaply.
So again,
that's one of the places where we say
spend money here because you can do an
amazing amount of good.
So I think we were just simply looking
for where are the really good deals?
If you want to do something about global
warming is an issue,
then you should ask yourself,
well,
how are we going to fix it?
So there's two things to global warming.
One is,
as you mentioned,
there's a sense in which people believe
it's the overwhelming danger that's
going to undermine the entirety of human
civilization and just like pretty much
all other problems.
That's just not true.
This is a problem.
It's not the end of the world.
Uh,
if you look at the economic system done,
uh,
the Nobel prize was just a water and
climate economics to Willy North House,
uh,
this year.
Uh,
and he's been a,
a guy working almost three decades on,
uh,
on,
on what are the costs and the benefits
of,
of climate action.
And he finds the cost of climate.
So climate change is about,
and he's backed up on a lot of other
economists,
is somewhere between two and 4% of GDP
by the end of the century.
So remember by then we'll be,
you know,
say four or five times richer.
So we'll be 400,
5% as rich as we are now,
but we will see a drop in our incomes
worth about two to 4% less than we would
otherwise have had.
That's a problem.
But it's by no means the end of the
world.
And that's the first thing you sort of
need to recognize.
This is a problem is not the end of the
world.
Because if you think you're,
it's the end of the world,
as you rightly pointed out,
then you're willing to throw everything
and the kitchen sink at it.
But if it's a problem,
you will act exactly like what I think
we should do with all problems.
Say,
all right,
there's a lot of problems.
Let's ask,
where can we spend a dollar and fix most
of that problem.
And unfortunately that's not climate
change.
It's actually really,
really hard to just change it.
A tiny bit of climate change with a lot
of money.
And that's why we find that most of the
interventions that you do for climate
change,
it turns out to be fairly poor.
They're not necessarily bad investments,
some of them are.
Uh,
but even,
you know,
for instance,
adaptation or,
or get more energy for,
uh,
for poor countries give you sort of,
you know,
two,
$5 back on the dollar,
which is nice.
But in the big scheme of things here are
much,
much better place as you can spend your
resources on.
So,
okay.
He's,
Oh so,
so let's look at God.
Look at this.
Well,
cause I'm really curious about this,
hey,
because I can't see any a priori
problems with your method.
It seems to me to make a
lot of sense.
And if your goal is to do the most
amount of good in the shortest period of
time with the least amount of resources,
which seems like a pretty damn good goal
then and to be realistic about what's
attainable then I can't see that
anyone's done a better job from a
methodological perspective than you guys
have.
Okay.
But now,
but you still face a tremendous amount
of opposition and most of that does come
from the climate side of things as far
as I can tell.
So it's,
I've been trying to think through why
that might be.
And so when I reviewed the climate
literature,
which was a few years ago,
um,
I had some real concerns about
measurement,
accuracy and so forth because it's a
very complicated issue and it's not the
constants that should be associated with
increase in carbon dioxide aren't
obvious.
And there's quite wide error bars around
them.
And then carbon dioxide has all sorts of
weirdly complicated effects like
increasing green global greening,
which is quite an interesting one.
And so anyways,
it also struck me that the,
if you project out the climate change
estimates across about a 50 to 100 year
period,
the error bars grow very large as you
move outward,
obviously because the errors multiply.
And then it struck me that we're in a
situation where the error bars out 50
years or so wide that even if we did
what people recommended now,
we could never be sure that it actually
worked because you can't,
the,
the propagation of error across all
those decades makes the picture so
blurry two or three,
four decades down the road that there's
no way of garnering evidence about the
effectiveness of your intervention.
And if it's a high cost intervention,
that seems to be a really bad idea.
So,
okay.
and I'm going to step one more step
backwards,
which is,
so
I also found it difficult to trust the
climate science.
And the reason for that was that it
struck me as motivated by,
um,
issues in la,
at least in some part that were outside
of the science.
It seems to me that a tremendous amount
of what motivates people's psychological
commitment to the idea of climate change
is an underlying,
something like an underlying anti
western or anticapitalist ethos.
And that the idea is that we should
restrict growth and we should
restructure the economic system and that
would address climate change.
And that would be a positive thing.
And it's forced all the apocalypse.
But the real goal seems to be more to
find an ethical justification for the
political position that requires the
retooling of these economic systems.
And so,
so,
well,
I guess the first thing I'd like to know
is what you,
does that strike you as a reasonable
argument?
Cause I can't see otherwise why people
would be objecting to what it is that
you're doing now.
So there's,
there's a lot of questions and then let,
don't unpack some of those.
Uh,
so,
so we,
I think
if you look out,
yes,
there's a lot of uncertainty,
uh,
going forward.
Um,
some of that actually cancels out when
you were saying,
well,
we're uncertain about how much the
temperature rise will be,
but we do know that it's a causal
mechanism is CEO to lead to higher
warming.
If you take some of the Sio two hours,
you will get less of it.
Now we don't exactly know how much,
where you get less,
whether it was a lot down here a little
bit or whether it was here in down a
little bit,
but did you actually get a little bit
the same thing?
So you can take some of the error bars
up because you're only looking at the
difference,
uh,
and you're not actually looking at the
actual input.
Uh,
the other thing I,
I'm in no doubt that there's a lot of,
you know,
other reasons why people latch on to
social phenomena.
So,
you know,
when,
when some climate scientists say we
should cut carbon emissions because this
is leading to a really dangerous issue,
there's a lot of other people who will
see,
oh,
that actually fits with my ideological,
a priest,
the substation.
So I'll actually join in,
uh,
in this,
in this conversation.
I think that happens in a lot of
different areas.
Uh,
tried to do is to sort of step back and
say,
look,
I'm not going to get into all of that.
I'm simply taking as the starting point.
We're,
we're economist.
I'm actually not,
I'm a political scientist,
but all the people I work with,
our economists,
we just take as given what the climate
scientists are telling us.
I think it's a,
it's a,
it's an interesting conversation and
say,
did they actually get it somewhat wrong?
Um,
and I think certainly,
you know,
somebody should be looking into it.
But you know,
I,
I've met a lot of these climate
scientists.
My sense is that they're good,
hardworking,
you know,
scientists are actually trying to find
out what's the up and down in this area.
So we said we'd take our starting point
with you and climate panel.
What we do is we ask how much will it
cost to cut carbon emissions so much
that we will see a significant change in
temperature.
And of course remember we emit co2,
not because we want to bother Al Gore,
anyone one else.
It's a byproduct of having a life that
is incredibly much nicer than one we
would have if we didn't have access to a
lot of energy.
I mean we can sit and talk here across
the continent,
but also you have heating and cooling
and a fertilizer that subsidize I
official fertilizer.
It basically feeds half the world's
population and a lot of other benefits
that come from mostly using fossil
fuels.
So if you want to get rid of some of
those fossil fuels and pot,
possibly all of them,
you will have to replace it with more
expensive,
uh,
energy.
And that's why it costs to cut corporate
emissions.
Now that may be worth the cost,
but that's exactly the question that we
tried to ask and that's what William
Nordhaus,
the Nobel laureate and the climate
economics and many of us fast.
And so it's really important.
It's really important to note that
you're not questioning the science as it
stands now.
It's so that this is purely a
consequences,
economic calculation.
This is,
this is only a bad thing.
Good co2 impacts warming,
and it does so in the way that the UN
climate panel tells us.
Now,
that's not entirely true because there's
a lot of things that they tell us and
there's a whole variability and we tried
to take that into account,
but honestly it turns out that if you do
it on the central estimates,
you get pretty much what I'm about to
tell you.
So what you find is if you cut carbon
emissions,
now you can have a little bit of impact
in a hundred years,
but it will have a significant cost.
Now it's not going to put us to the poor
house that nobody's talking about that
just like we're not talking about the
end of the world.
If we don't do something about climate
change,
we're not talking about the end of the
world.
If we do something about climate change
drivers.
So I want to sort of dial it back on the
rhetoric,
both from the alarmists that say,
oh my God,
the world is coming to an end.
Or the people who are saying,
oh,
we can't afford this.
And we all going to the poor house.
If you want to have solar panels and
wind turbines.
These are both manageable costs,
thesis sort of in the order,
you know,
two to 4% but the problem is that if we
do sort of things that cost one to 2% of
GDP right now and for the rest of the
century,
we basically solve almost no,
no part of the global warming problem.
We'd probably saw about 1% of it.
So basically by incurring a cost of one
to 2% of GDP now and every year
throughout the rest of the century,
you will have solved almost none of the
problem come 2100 so you still have to
pay all the same problems that global
warming is as encouraging,
minus a slight amount and then you paid
one to 2% every year.
That's the basic idea of why most cost
benefit analysis show that unless you do
it very carefully and only do a little
bit of cutting and do it really smartly,
you're actually incurring higher costs
than the problem you're trying to solve.
So we can thread the needle and do
really carefully,
but that requires a lot of smartness
from a lot of politicians.
But if we do it really bluntly,
we're just going to incur lots of costs
to actually not get very many benefits.
Okay.
So when the people who are not happy
with you for not prioritizing climate
change to the degree that it should be
hypothetically,
like how do they criticize your
statements?
Like on what basis do they decide that
your conclusions are inappropriate?
I think,
I mean if you read most of the Internet,
there is a lot of things they'll just
say,
oh,
you're a denier.
You can't say that.
It's sort of we're going to
excommunicate you.
We don't want to talk to you.
That's not right.
Uh,
I'm,
I'm not really going to talk about those
people because that's just,
yeah,
that's political posturing that rather
than anything else,
I think there's a reasonable argument to
be made to say that's not the only way
that you can approach this.
So there's two ways you can think about
cost benefit analysis,
actually showing that climate impacts
are worth doing.
One is to say,
ah,
but there might be a tiny risk,
even just a tiny risk to the whole world
is going to spin out of control and
we're all going to die kind of thing.
And you know,
that's not implausible.
Especially if you say sort of,
I'm not going to put a percentage on it,
but it's not,
it's greater than zero.
So there's a non zero chance that global
warming will spin out of control and
we'll basically,
it'd be,
you know,
rally get a few,
couple a hundred couples of,
of humans living on an ice free Arctic
as well.
That's a positive feedback loop
argument,
right?
That we might trigger mechanisms like
the melting of the greenland ice sheet
for example,
that would flood the world or cause some
irreparable catastrophe of unparalleled
magnitude.
Okay.
So,
so I have a question about that because
that's a tricky one to address,
right?
That's kind of an apocalyptic argument.
And then the argument would be,
well,
if there's a 1% chance of an infinite
apocalypse,
it's worth any donation of resources to
stave it off.
So one way of thinking about that is
actually to multiply the catastrophes
because my suspicions are that that same
argument could be used in relationship
to a lot of the other problems that you
are trying to address.
Like I don't know what the probability
is that if we keep a substantial number
of people in abject poverty over the
next 20 years,
let's say more than we'd have to,
that we would increase the probability
of the generation of um,
um,
epidemic and infectious diseases because
poverty,
poor people are risk to everyone in this
court is a horrible way of thinking
about it.
But poverty is a risk to everyone.
That's a better way of thinking about it
because decreased global human health,
it's also a breeding ground for all
sorts of catastrophes that might emerge.
And then there's also the possibility of
political instability and a nuclear war
and all of those things that are also
equally apocalyptic.
So it's,
it seems to me to be reasonable to some
degree to say,
look,
there's the possibility across a wide
range of potential crises of unforeseen
positive feedback loops spiraling out of
control.
But we can't introduce them into the
argument less.
We can parameterize them because all it,
it,
it's,
it's an unfair game move in some sense
because you can't be not wrong about
that.
You can exactly.
And,
and,
and you're,
you're basically saying,
if you allow it in,
in this area,
just because you like that,
cause they go there a area and say,
I want you to focus more money on my
thing,
which is climate change.
You could equally well do it in all
kinds of other areas.
And I actually think you can make your
argument even stronger.
It's just not,
it's not just the poverty sort of breeds
a lot of risks,
but it's also that they breed terrorism
and willingness to,
you know,
uh,
do a lot of bad things and you know,
focused.
So it's not just something that happens
but you know,
uh,
threatened by terrorists and our ability
to keep all the plutonium in the world
under,
under law and,
and you know,
you can get catastrophe from anything
nor Canto App.
So abject poverty for example.
You could imagine that there might be
two socioeconomic contributions to that.
There would be the absolute number of
people in abject poverty who are
therefore desperate.
And then there would also be maybe
another contribution of excess
inequality and a sense that the world
isn't laying itself out fairly and that
that would justify political,
political and revolutionary and
stability and also a state failure and
many other things that we know make it a
lot easier for everyone to,
to make really bad things like we saw
out of Afghanistan,
uh,
with nine 11 and a lot of other things.
You know,
once you,
once you get failed states,
you get a lot of bad things happen.
We try to make people better off.
We tried to make people federoff
globally so that we decrease the
probability of,
of large scale political instinct,
political and economic instability.
And that's another way of staving off an
apocalypse.
Yes.
Okay.
And then on,
can I just say,
so northouse actually looked at this,
they know about Lauren,
uh,
because some people aren't exactly what
you said.
There's a tiny risk that things go
really,
really bad.
So we should spend all of our money on
this issue.
But of course that's a failed argument
because likewise,
there's a lot of small risks everywhere
else.
We know one risk which is being hit by
an asteroid that could wipe out the uh,
the earth yet.
And Nordhaus did that.
I thought that was very,
very elegant.
Uh,
we know that we can track all of those
asteroids out there,
99.99% but we chose to only track 90%
because tracking the rest was too
expensive.
So you can actually see that we put a
price on how much are we willing to do
this.
And of course,
that's just one place where we have a
very clear example that we say we cast
somewhat for the future,
but we don't care about it entirely.
We have lots of other issues that we
want to focus on right now.
So that's every other area you have to
rq,
what is the risks and what are the
opportunity to do this?
And absolutely,
given that there are some risks and
they're probably more downside risk than
upside risk for global warming,
we should probably do a little more than
what we would otherwise do.
And that's exactly what the model show
us.
And those are the models that we use in
making the estimate of how much should
you be paying for global warming.
So yes,
we should take that into account,
but it's not a good argument.
That was,
that was one argument.
I'm sorry,
I'll,
I'll try to be a little with the other
argument.
The other argument is that people will
say one of the reasons why it doesn't
pay to do global warming,
it is because you have to pay now,
but the benefits come far up into the
future.
So basically you do something now that's
fairly costly and then you get a tiny
benefit in a hundred years.
So you have to really say the future's
incredibly important economic speak.
That is that the discount is really low.
They really care a lot about the future.
Now a lot of people would argue we
should,
you know,
we're rich,
we should be able to care enormously
about the future.
And if you change that parameter enough
and you say we care enormously about
future generations,
it actually turns out that global
warming becomes a good deal.
You know,
doing something about global warming
actually becomes,
goes from,
you know,
saying you spend a dollar and you do a
couple of cents of climate damage to,
sorry to avoid climate damage,
you actually spend a dollar and you
might do $2 of climate benefits.
So it actually turns it into good idea.
But here's the kicker.
If you care that much about the future,
you change every other one of all of
these priorities and make them Whoa,
right?
Because we're obviously happens is
you've just said,
I care so much about the future that the
guy that I will save from not having
tuberculosis and dying from it tomorrow,
we'll now go on to have a successful
life.
His kids will live longer,
they'll do better,
he will have a better,
his nation will do better.
That means there'll be much,
much better off in 2100 and so on.
And that means that this is no longer a
question of saying you spend it all in
you to $43 worth of goods,
but you spend it all,
you $1,000 worth of goods.
So what you've achieved as basically
just make everything a great idea.
That's also intellectually what making
the discount rate very,
very small.
What it means is you should basically
starve.
You should just eat porch every day and
spend all of the rest of your money on
the future because you care so much
about it right now.
If you do that,
I,
I applaud your are sort of your,
your consistency,
but most people just don't do this and
we certainly don't do this in the way
that,
you know,
we don't seem to care all that much
about our pension systems,
which are in many rich countries got to
fail in the next 20 to 40 years.
All these other issues.
So as long as you were saying no,
no,
what you're really saying then is on
climate.
We want to care a lot about the future,
but we don't want to do it in all other
areas.
Okay.
You're going to be consistent.
You need to do it across all areas and
then you need to be very hungry and only
parch.
Right.
Okay.
So your claim basically from a
methodological perspective is that your
rank ordering remains constant across
variable discount rates.
Yes.
Right.
And that's a really,
that's a really important,
that's a really fundamentally important.
It's not until I got to say it does
change some of these because obviously,
you know,
education for instance is one of those
where you pay now and you'll only get
benefits 10 20,
50 years out when the kids grow up in
the actual become much more productive.
So there is a change,
but mostly the rank order ordering
remains the same.
And I'm simply just insisting that
people need to be consistent.
You can't just say,
uh,
the future is important when you talk
about climate.
You have to want to say the future is
important,
it's important across all areas and then
you really have to do everything and you
know,
forego a,
having a good life for yourself.
Right,
right.
Okay.
Well,
so the other thing that's worthwhile
pointing out about the discount rate is
that,
you know,
you can make a case that the future is
more important than the present.
Especially cause it's extends out so
far.
But,
but the other reason that people
discount the future is because you can't
make the case that you can predict the
outcome of your actions.
And that means that the error in
prediction magnifies itself as you move
out farther in timeframe.
And so what happens is you get to a
point where there isn't a lot of point
in adjusting your behavior in the
present.
If you look like a hundred years out,
let's say,
or a thousand years out,
because you actually can't calculate
with any accuracy the consequences of
your actions or inactions.
And so the,
the cumulative error makes discounting
the future,
the appropriate thing to do because you
can predict what's going to happen if
you act now,
now and maybe tomorrow,
but you get much less accurate as,
as you move forward.
So even in the best case scenario where
we had the best wishes for the future,
that doesn't mean we could justify
incredibly radical sacrifices now
because we can't calculate their
cumulative impact.
No.
Uh,
there's,
there's a good,
there's a good way of thinking about
this.
You know,
if you look at what previous generations
has done for us,
the only thing that they really managed
to do is to give us a lot more
knowledge.
So investment in knowledge is actually a
great way to help future generations
because it helped them in all kinds of
ways and we can't really predict how,
but it's probably a good idea to leave
them with a lot of books.
I'm,
I'm using that as a metaphor,
but trying to help them in a specific
way in matching back a hundred years
ago,
our forefathers back in the 1920s,
no 1910s would have,
would have done reasonably to help us.
Now,
chances are they would have wasted a lot
of money on things that never turn into
problems.
There's a wonderful book called today
now,
uh,
sorry.
Oh God,
I'm forgetting now.
Oh God.
Anyway,
it has a great and clever title,
which I've clearly screwed up now,
but it was back in 1893.
Uh,
the,
uh,
the world's fair in Chicago,
I believe,
ask 50 of the world's smartest people to
predict what would the world look like
in a hundred years.
And so all of them,
first star said,
you know,
I love the fact that I'm not going to be
around when this prediction comes true
or not.
Uh,
but then they made all their predictions
and they were almost entirely off.
Yeah.
There's some pretty close or you know,
there's one that it predicted sort of
email in the sense that you know,
those [inaudible] and then up,
I can't pronounce that pneumatics
pneumatic tubes.
Yup.
Which has sent away and it would sort of
suck it out.
And so you could send a letter somewhere
they imagined that that would be a
worldwide thing.
And so you could actually send a letter
everywhere.
You just sort of put it in the very,
very long tube,
which is kind of right.
And you can sort of say,
yeah,
that's not entirely wrong.
You know,
got the whole technology wrong,
but the right idea.
But the fundamental point is we are
probably wrong about so many things as
you say,
that I am to help the world in the
future by,
for instance,
cutting temperature might be one of the
least effective ways of helping also.
So there's another thing that's
interesting about that.
I think that speaks to the fundamental
intelligence of your approach.
So one of the things that has struck me
as highly likely is that given complex
things are and how rapidly they're
changing that the best thing we could do
to prepare ourselves for the future
would be to make better people,
smarter people,
wiser people,
more responsible people,
all of that.
So there's a psychological element to
that.
And so I would say some of my work has
concentrated on that and the public
lectures that I've been doing.
But what's interesting about your
approach,
the economic approaches that you're
diverting a lot of resources to the
creation of better people for tomorrow
by investing,
especially in in childhood nutrition.
So if you,
and I suppose this is kind of how we
economists look at the world,
but maybe biologists could look at it
this way too.
If you think of people as general
problem solving machines,
which is not a bad way of thinking about
us,
then it might be that given that you
don't know which problems are going to
be paramount,
what you want to do is improve the
machines that will solve the problems,
whatever those problems happen to be.
And so that investment in early
childhood development seems particularly
Apropos in that regard.
And so having said that,
I want to return to the climate issue
one more time because here's something
peculiar.
This is something I don't understand.
It's a real mystery.
So let's say that just for the sake of
argument,
that most of the people who are
concerned about climate change and its
relationship to economic development or
on the left side of the spectrum,
okay,
but led,
and let's also say that those who are on
the left side of the spectrum are
hypothetically also concerned with the
economic wellbeing of the most
dispossessed and that those might be
equally important concerns and their
integrity locked together.
Well,
the strange thing about so many of your
recommendations is that they're directly
aimed at addressing the immediate now
concerns of the fundamentally
dispossessed.
And so you'd think that that,
that's part of the reason that I can't
understand why there's so much objection
to your methods because it's not like
what you came up with looks like support
for something that's like a right wing
agenda by any stretch of the
imagination.
I mean,
first of all,
it's predicated on the idea that there's
a certain amount of development aid,
especially directed to children.
You said not exclusively.
There would be of great use.
And it seems to me to be undeniable that
the most dispossessed people in the
world are impoverished infants of
impoverished people.
So,
so what if some of the objections to
what you're doing are ideologically
motivated?
Why doesn't that cancel it out?
As a good question and I don't quite
understand it.
My sense is that in some ways,
so,
uh,
I was in New York in September.
Uh,
there was,
uh,
the first I heard a summit at the UN,
for tuberculosis and I was there because
one of the things that we've identified
as this is a great investment and of
course all the tugboats,
tuberculosis,
people love us because,
you know,
we're finding out you should spend more
money on their problem.
Um,
and,
and almost
nobody went.
Uh,
I wrote a,
an orbit together with the South African
health minister and it was widely
published in the developing world,
but almost no one in the developed world
picked it up.
It was only when I wrote and other offit
where I said there were two meetings
taking place in the New York.
One was this TV place where,
you know,
biggest infectious disease killer in the
world.
We're almost nobody turned up.
And then those,
the other meeting,
uh,
which macron and the French president
and uh,
Bloomberg and others attended to,
which was the climate summit,
which everybody attended to.
He sort of pointed out the disparity and
then it was picked up in all kinds of
developed country,
pick the papers.
I think fundamentally it goes down to
saying,
while everybody says they care a lot
about the world's poor,
the reality is that you care somewhat
for but most rich,
well meaning people probably care a lot
more about the fact that they worry that
their kids might be in a position where
global warming is really going to
undermine even that.
Because look,
we already established the fact that
there's equal reason to be
apocalyptically concerned about uncheck
poverty and inequality.
So this is why I suggested to begin with
that.
The one of the lovely things about the
idea of climate change is that it,
it really justifies the idea of
overthrowing the current system or of
undermining the current system.
And that if you're inclined to do that
rather than inclined to truly help the
dispossessed,
let's say,
then you'd be more inclined to support a
theory that justifies that sort of
radical,
let's say interventionists policy.
And I can't see a way out of that
logically given that the work that
you're doing on tuberculosis is a great
example is directly and Evett
evidentially associated with a market
increase in the wellbeing of the
dispossessed.
And so you'd think that they would
attract the proper amount of ideological
attention,
but it doesn't.
And that's,
that's a great mystery.
There's something about that
extraordinarily good and it's as,
it's a good point and,
and I think you have a consistent
argument.
The,
the thing that I've,
I've decided a long time ago that I
don't want to argue and I think that's
probably the difference between,
of being more psychologically focused.
I don't want to argue,
I think might be people's,
uh,
sort of inner motivations.
I want to actually take them on face
value.
And you know,
many people I meet,
they say,
I worry a lot about climate change.
I worry a lot about the world's poor.
And then I try to show them,
well,
if you actually do that,
why the hell would you be focusing on
spending lots of money?
They'll almost to no good instead of
spending possibly less money.
And during the fall you about more and
it creates some cognitive dissonance and
I think it switches people a little bit
towards spending smarter.
But yes,
you're right.
But telecall ignorance,
you know,
it's like what you're doing is pretty
new and it takes a long time.
I mean it's not new for you,
what,
it's not new considering the span of a
single lifetime,
but you know,
what you're doing is very radical in
some sense.
There is,
and there isn't anybody else doing it.
And so it might own,
it might be that will take 20 years or
25 years or something like that for the
approach that you're
publicizing and have developed to for
people to actually know about it,
you know?
And so what,
what did they say?
You should assume ignorance instead of
malevolence when you can.
I do think that ignorance is a part of
this.
It's not obvious to everyone that there
is this method of rank ordering that
people have done it and,
and that there are consequences to that
that could be laid out in an intelligent
economic plan.
You know,
and I,
I know that it takes a finding in the
scientific literature if it's going to
make its way into the public,
something approximating 15 years.
And that's only the ones that actually
do manage to make it.
And so it could be that just way more
people need to build what you're doing
and why and how it was done before it
gets the steam going.
I'm interested in the psychological
issues in part to try to help figure out
what it would take to motivate people to
be more attentive to the sorts of
solutions that you and your people have
been putting forward and hit and to
eliminate those barriers.
But,
but,
uh,
but it could just be,
as I said,
it could just be ignorance and,
and one of them,
one of the problems that we're facing
constantly,
and I know why there's no one else doing
this than we,
the weird thing because when you do
prioritization and you inevitably end up
antagonizing a lot of people,
I mean a climate change is the most
obvious one.
But for instance,
a sanitation,
water and sanitation,
huge problem.
Uh,
so you know,
the,
there's two and a half million people
affected by this.
One of the points that we emphasizes
that Dune sanitation,
while a good thing to do,
it probably only pays you back $3 back
on the dollar.
Why?
Because it's actually fairly costly to
do sanitation and also because the
benefits not nearly as great as what
many have assumed and this is new global
burden of disease estimates that the
real problem is that what you're doing
with sanitation is that you're not
removing fecal matter from the
environment.
You simply reducing the amount so you're
not actually having all that much of an
impact on the sea shore.
Having a little bit,
but not nearly as much as what we would
like to say.
That obviously pisses off all the people
who are doing sanitation and we ended up
pissing off a lot of people.
And the truth is I think it's necessary
if you're going to do this when you rank
order,
of course the,
the,
the cost is to come out of top.
Love it.
And the cost is don't,
don't love it,
but it's also important to make that
argument.
And so,
so at the end of the day,
so I mean,
my sense is it's necessary to do it,
but it will always entail a great amount
of,
of sort of,
uh,
anies,
because it doesn't feel like we're
saying,
you know,
Kumbaya and we should do everything,
but we're actually saying,
no,
you should do these things.
But not all of these things,
although they seem nice,
they're just not in the same league.
Right,
right,
right.
Well that's,
it would be nice if we could do
everything good that we possibly could
all at once,
but it's not,
it's not realistic because you can't do
everything at once and you don't have
infinite resources as we've already
pointed out.
So.
Okay.
So what would you say would be,
if you're going to play devil's advocate
against your own position,
which I presume you've done a lot of
anyways,
what are their criticisms against your,
let's say your,
your aims and your methods that you
regard as unresolved?
Like,
what is it that you're doing that still
weak and wrong in your own estimation or
what,
where the,
where the limitations in your methods?
Well,
there's no method does everything.
So we have two very obvious problems.
One is not all issues is about money.
So we're looking at how do you
prioritize money.
But sometimes money is not the issue.
For instance,
on free trade as we talked about before,
we estimate the benefit is incredible.
But we actually look at the cost as the
cost of subsidizing western farmers
because those are the ones that
basically make a killing from not a
freeing up,
uh,
Martin global markets.
And those were the ones that usually
kept held it back.
But what has happened is it has become
much more sort of an emotional thing.
It's sort of an identity thing and I'm
not sure how you would cost that.
So to the extent that things have not
nothing to do with money,
but they just simply about political
willingness or interest or,
uh,
what,
then we are not making the argument,
uh,
that is going to convince you.
So in some sense we are telling you
where can you spend money,
but we're not talking about the things
that don't require money.
Right?
So people would object that you're,
that the problem with your method is
that you're measuring everything that
can be tangibly measured from an
economic perspective.
But that's actually a small fraction of
the universe of properly attended to.
I would tend to say it's probably sort
of 70 or 80%.
I'm not quite sure how you'd make that
up,
but,
but you know,
the biggest,
the biggest policy decisions in most
countries is the national budget.
Uh,
it's very clear that that is a very
substantial part of what we decide.
How are we going to allocate money?
Well,
the problem lately,
that's a big issue.
We don't move.
Not the only issue.
Right?
Well,
the problem with the objection is that,
well,
the people who are objecting could be
right.
That your methods are narrow.
I mean,
you're making the case that they're not
in an arrow as a,
yeah.
As a,
as a pessimist might assume.
But that puts the onus on them to come
up with an alternative way of ranking.
Right?
I mean,
I would just say we're,
we're not talking about those last 30%
that are purely about,
uh,
you know,
should we have transgender bathrooms or
something?
Yeah,
well that's possibly a bad idea because
that actually has cost them and building
a third bathroom or something.
But,
you know,
there's some things that are mostly just
about w what do you think?
What do you believe?
What are your intuitions?
Uh,
rather than actual costs.
But there's no way of adjudicating
between those claims.
That's the problem that all the people
that he was pushing each other around
about them.
If they can't,
with the rational there,
there's still a substantial amount of
issues where you do need to look at
resource allocation.
And there we have a good argument.
The second part,
the second sort of criticism,
uh,
which is a very fair criticism is we
don't look at inequality.
So economists are very,
very bad at dealing with inequality
because fundamentally that's a political
issue.
So when we look at you spend a dollar
and you do $60 worth of good,
we don't look at who gets that $60.
Now to be fair,
most of the things that she was all you
also pointed out,
most of the things that we actually
indicate are really,
really low hanging fruit of the world
are things that will help the world's
pores mostly because the world's poorest
have so many things that they haven't
gotten that would be hugely beneficial
for them.
So it mostly actually help also
inequality,
but we don't measure it.
And so we don't actually look at would
this be a good expenditure in the t in
the sense of helping the world's
poorest,
mostly wood,
but it's not part of our framework.
And there's how me making that.
Well,
because uh,
because cost benefit analysis is
basically assuming that everybody's
equally worth talking about that
earlier.
There's no way of,
of sort of,
well you can,
but it becomes incredibly unclear and
very unintuitive if you start making
weightings and on who is actually worth
more.
So.
So we are,
we're getting saying it's a little bit
like the menu,
you know,
you get in the restaurant,
we're telling you,
hey,
the Spanish is cheap and it has lots of
vitamins and the cake is expensive and
it's bad for,
you know,
you go ahead and make the choice.
And I think that's the fair way to have
that conversation that we're telling you
some important facts about your
decisions.
But these are not the only things that
are going to guide your decision.
And I'm absolutely happy to say that.
So.
So in some sense you asked me to be
devil's advocate.
I just think it's important to clarify.
We don't look at all issues because we
only look at issues that require
resources and we don't feel with
inequality,
which is also an important issue.
But apart from that we have to make
priorities and we're simply making it a
little clear.
At the end of the day,
you can choose to totally disregard it.
But I would imagine that you would at
least like to know what does the
evidence tell you?
If you spend it all here,
how many people will you save?
How many lives will be improved,
how much environment will be improved
and so on.
Versus all the other things where you
could have spent that dollar and done
different amounts of good in all those
different areas.
And that's what we provide for the menu.
So do you,
okay.
Okay.
Well I appreciate that very much.
Um,
do you have any sense,
what do you,
off the top of your head,
what the total capital expenditure for
the minimization eradication of
tuberculosis actually would be?
What are you talking about?
An absolute dollar amounts.
So,
and,
and it depends a lot on,
uh,
because,
we estimate it you need about $2
billion.
The,
uh,
the,
the global funds that we were also
campaigning with,
uh,
our,
it's saying it's about five point $8
billion.
And to be quite honest,
I'm not quite sure which of these two
numbers is the right number.
I think the,
uh,
you know,
compared to,
just to give you a sense of proportion,
uh,
the amount of subsidies that we give to
solar and wind,
uh,
is about $120 billion right now.
Uh,
so,
you know,
we're,
we're talking about a very,
very small amount,
uh,
and certainly it's a very small amount.
You know,
it's,
it's about what,
three,
4% of global development,
uh,
spending the amount of spending that we,
that we spend every year to try and help
improve the world.
And it will probably be one of the very,
very best things that we could do.
So again,
very,
very small leanings.
I need to know these things.
And I think that if they did
no,
that would start to care if they
actually knew.
So.
Okay.
I got,
I got two final questions for you,
I think,
and then I'll ask you if there's
anything else you wanted to bring to
people's attention that,
that you thought was particularly
necessary.
Okay.
So the first one is,
um,
to what degree do you think,
oh,
I'll ask all three questions.
To what degree do you think you've been
making headway?
Like obviously you're,
you've been successful in putting
together your institutes and your work
is garnered a substantial amount of
attention published and otherwise,
and so it's not like you've been
silenced and,
and imprisoned or anything like that.
And so are the reasons for optimism as
far as you're concerned.
And then the next thing that I'd like to
ask you about is what's happening in
France because one of the things that
the people who are pushing for radical
current interventions with regards to
longterm climate change haven't factored
in is the reverse apocalyptic issue,
which is that there's going to be
substantial resistance to the short term
costs that will cause spinoff disasters
of their own.
And so the French example seems to be a
very interesting case in point.
So,
so the first question was,
how do you feel about the impact that
you're having in the second is,
what do you have to say about what's
happening in France?
Yup.
And can I,
I'm gonna answer it in reverse.
The France point is,
is really a good,
uh,
a good argument.
If you ask people around the world,
uh,
do you care about global warming?
Almost everyone will say,
yes.
Uh,
do you want to do something for global
warming?
And they'll say yes.
Then when you ask them,
how much are you willing to pay the
typical answer,
uh,
both in rich and cork countries,
there's a couple of hundred dollars per
year.
So Yup.
It goes from 100 to $200.
So fundamentally what people are saying
is,
yes,
I do worry about this issue.
I'm willing to spend a little bit of
money,
but not very much.
And I think this is the fundamental
thing that we just have not been able to
get to the attention of a lot of people
who are pushing for really,
really radical solutions.
You're never going to succeed in a
democratic situation.
Uh,
if,
yeah,
if you keep ramping up,
uh,
the taxes on fossil fuels,
if you keep making energy more and more
expensive,
it's going to harm,
first of all,
the poor,
the most very,
very regressive.
And that obviously
means a lot of heartache for a lot of
poor people.
These are typically also the people who
are at least able to defend themselves
because they're just so busy just
surviving the day today.
So it typically has to hit the
middleclass before you really get sort
of an eruption as what you've seen in
France and elsewhere.
Let's remember,
there's also a lot of other issues in
France,
so it's not just because they put three,
three sets on a,
on,
on a liter of diesel,
but,
but it is an issue of saying if you push
people too far,
you will actually not be able to do the
solution for climate.
And so you're very,
very expensive.
Solutions are never going to be a
longterm viable,
you know,
when you predict these ideas of saying,
if we had Obama,
uh,
and if he would actually have managed to
put a carbon tax on,
on,
on co2.
Remember he actually had a democratic
congress,
uh,
the first two years of this presidency
and they were still not able to get a
carbon tax implemented.
Of course when you have a Republican
congress,
it becomes really hard when you have a
republican president.
Also,
it falls apart.
You just can't do this for a hundred
years.
It's just not going to work out.
And that's why,
uh,
and,
and we never got to that.
We actually did a climate consensus
where we brought together 27 of the
world's top climate economist,
three Nobel laureates to look at where
can you do good for climate?
And what they found was the by far best
investment to tackle global warming is
to invest in Green Energy R.
And.
D.
So fundamentally,
if we could invest in making better
green energy for the future,
hopefully eventually get it to be so
cheap that it w out compete fossil
fuels,
we will solve global warming just simply
because the green energy became cheaper.
If you'll allow me a slight detour
people,
you do it,
do it.
Uh,
uh,
back in the 1860 [inaudible],
the world was hunting whales to
extinction because whales have this.
Wonderful,
should I just say that again?
Yup.
All right.
Um,
back in the 1860s,
we were hunting whales to extinction
because whales have this wonderful oil
that just burns a lot cleaner and a low
point.
And so it was wonderful for the houses
and in,
in North American and Europe to burn
these,
uh,
this whale oil and they're all excited
about it and it,
the bad side effect there was actually a
pushing whales to extinction.
Now the sort of global warming approach
to that problem would have been society.
Could you please turn down the light,
could you please have it a little less
light in your room?
And of course you would have been
entirely failed.
What did save the whales was we
discovered oil,
fossil fuel oil,
which were actually burning cleaner.
It was much cheaper and you didn't have
to go out and kill whales for it.
And so what happened about a decade was
to stop killing whales because you've
got a better technological product.
And we've seen this a lot of times that
technology can simply invalidate an old
issue,
a problem that you thought was almost
intractable.
If you get cheaper,
smarter,
new technology,
people switch,
right?
That's opposing imposing limits on
expensive limits on people is not an
appropriate longterm solution because of
implementation resistance and cost.
And the best solution is to come up with
a,
well let's say,
to put it in a cliched manner,
is to come up with a better solution,
which is cheaper energy.
That's that it has all the advantages
and fewer disadvantages.
And that's really how it would be a
problem.
Wind turbines,
solar panels,
and,
and I'm just taking the two most popular
things and batteries together.
If they were cheaper than fossil fuels,
which they aren't right now,
but if they were,
of course everyone would bond them
buying coal,
fire power plants.
So it's really not rocket science in
that way.
Now I'm not saying it's going to be easy
and it's certainly not going to happen
right now,
but it's the only viable long term
solution.
It's much cheaper and much more
effective.
So we estimated that for every dollar
spent you'll actually do about $11 a
climate benefit.
Okay,
so that's that.
So an alternative energy.
Our index,
I fart,
you know,
so,
so it's,
it's not the best thing,
but it comes down here.
So it actually,
you know,
it's a pretty good investment.
Yeah.
It's not the best in the world,
but we should definitely be doing okay.
The second question that you had was
the,
you know,
the optimism.
So fundamentally,
how much of an impact does this have?
Well,
it's half the impact.
Very predictable impact that when we
come out and say,
for instance,
uh,
more immunization gives you $60 back in
the dollar,
the people who are doing immunization
tells you all the time you should fund
us because we do $60 in good humor,
every dollar you spend.
So very clearly,
I sat down with a guy from,
uh,
from,
a family foundation,
a big family foundation.
Then,
you know,
where we were at a malaria event and we
sat and politely conversing here.
Uh,
he would say,
so what do you do?
I,
well,
I worked with the Copenhagen Consensus
Center,
you know,
totally blacks there.
And then I asked him,
what do you do and what we work with
malaria.
We did,
you know that actually it's,
you spend a dollar in malarial do $33
worth of good.
And I was like,
yeah,
we did that.
And you know,
and,
you know,
this is exactly the point.
We're not,
we're not there to,
you know,
get attention.
We're there to make sure that we get
attention to some of these top ideas.
And I think we definitely helped a lot
of these top ideas get a little easier
right in the world.
Okay.
So let me ask you another cost benefit.
So,
yes.
So what if I said,
wouldn't it be interested interesting in
doing a metta cost benefit analysis on
how much money you would need to raise
and spend to effectively market your
findings.
You don't want to hire people who are
really good at doing such marketing so
that you had the appropriate
advertisements and so that you,
cause you're,
you're,
this is not a criticism,
believe me,
but your approach is very academic and
very objective and,
and that's all well and good and
reliable and valid and all of those
things.
But
do you,
could you reconna [inaudible] compute to
utility in dollar value of establishing
an ex,
an extensive inappropriate marketing
scheme because you'd think that there
are,
let's see,
cause I've been watching what's been
happening with the Democrats in the U S
and they've,
a pack that I know about has been,
uh,
making new ads for the Democrats trying
to move them towards the center and
they've had a substantial amount of
impact because the advertisements have
been very professionally crafted and
constructive.
And so,
well,
I don't,
I don't know what you think about that,
but I'd been,
part of the reason I'm interviewing you
today is because I want to put this up
on youtube and I want to get it out
there in podcast so that more people
know about this.
And so,
all right,
well,
yeah,
so the short answer of course is we have
tried to do that because we're economist
and we think,
yeah,
that would be a good idea.
So let me just tell you about something
else that we had done.
So,
uh,
so we've been working a lot and we were
just talking about the cool.
Uh,
so when you do prioritization on the
planetary scale,
it's academically very interesting.
But unfortunately the impact is mostly
that people say,
yeah,
that's probably true somewhere else.
You know?
So when we go and tell the immune
system,
they'll say,
yeah,
that's probably true for Mexico and
Mexico.
Say it's probably true of Argentina.
And so,
so everybody just push it off to
somebody else.
The bowl was never anyone's problem.
Yeah.
Someone else needs to fix us.
And so what we've increasingly done it
as to do this in nations.
Uh,
so we did this a couple of years ago in
Bangladesh,
a w and,
and the nation of course,
is an overlap between who actually
decides where to spend the money and the
problems that we analyzing.
So we did the exact same thing for just
for Bangladesh.
So we did a list of all the things.
So we talked to everyone in Bangladesh.
We got them to say,
what are the best things that you want
to focus on?
What are the smartest new solutions we
worked with?
Primus think tank,
the finance minister,
everybody else and talked about where
can you actually spend money.
Again,
this is,
this is a menu that's not entirely
politically correct.
Certainly the politicians don't like all
of this,
but what the,
you know,
the finance minister would go like,
no,
Oh yes,
yes,
I like this.
See Him.
So they did some of the things.
So that solves the Tower of Babel
problem to some degree.
Is that too much distance?
Yeah,
there's too much distance between the
local and the global.
And so you're using the nation state as
a,
as a psychological intermediary.
So there we actually estimate that every
dollar spent on what we were doing,
uh,
does,
you know,
at least $10,000 worth of good simply
because we help shift spending in
Bangladesh both on their national budget
but also the development budgets
spending in Bangladesh.
And again,
we didn't change,
you know,
Bangladesh to suddenly become super
rational.
Anything.
I'm simply changed the bowl little bit
we gave,
if you will,
headwind to the poor ideas and tailwind
to the good ones.
And so we will not Haiti,
we are,
we're now doing this in India together
with Tata Trust.
I just came back and said,
that's why I'm a little jet lag or a
little bleary eyed.
I just came back from,
from Ghana,
uh,
where are we going to do our next
project?
So we want to bring this to Africa.
Three.
I used to do it globally and locally.
Yes.
And I think when we'll have a lot more
opportunity to actually get people's
attention when you talk specifically to
the nation states where you're actually
going to be making these decisions.
But obviously if it's true Ghana,
it's probably also true in the
neighboring state.
You're going to get the overlap.
Exactly.
So I think I would love to,
you know,
uh,
have,
have a lot of,
uh,
of extra sort of pr ability.
But I think what we,
what we really need is just simply to be
able to come up with all these great
ideas and I think we are reasonably
successful but,
but the problem in some ways is we're
advocates of all the boring stuff.
You know,
all the stuff that gets the attention
are the ones that have the crying babies
and cute animals.
The thing is it's not true.
It's not what you're doing isn't boring.
It's absolutely exciting beyond belief.
I mean I don't believe that it is dry
and I don't believe that it doesn't have
a powerful narrative message.
It's just that there are reasons that
the narrative messages I'm scared.
And I think putting your finger on the
gap between the local and the global is
a good one.
That's smart because you see the same
problem starting to emerge.
For example with the EU where the
overarching bureaucracy is so distant
from the people on the ground that
there's a disconnect in identification.
And so to harness the latent power of
the nation state and its patriotism and
it's at its economic,
what would,
it's rather local economic structure
seems to me to be a rita smarter
solution.
But I,
I really,
I was thrilled when I came across your
work and I mean on an emotional level
because I thought,
well wow,
if we really want it to do good,
if that was the goal and we wanted to do
it intelligently and carefully and
agnostically to some degree.
Um,
and in a non he ideologically
self-serving manner,
which would be a lovely thing to manage
if it was possible,
then this seemed to be an incredibly
exciting approach.
And I,
I believe that there's every reason to
assume that
with proper publicity that people could
really get behind the idea that we
wouldn't have to have tuberculosis in 10
years,
you know?
And,
and that some of these things could
really,
you know,
I've talked to people in on my lecture
tour about the things that we could do
to make the world a better place.
And there's no shortage of enthusiasm
for that.
It's just that there's a fair bit of
cynicism,
but there's a lot more ignorance is like
what will,
we just don't know what to do.
But your prescription say well here's 10
things you could do one of them and one
of them would work and so you've got a
bit of a choice there.
We wouldn't have to take our number one
priority as your own,
but you could take number five and you'd
still do a lovely job and it might be in
accordance with your own motivations.
Okay.
Can I can,
can you get me pdfs for example of the
relevant whatever you think is relevant
that would inform people in short order.
I will post in the description of the
video so that they get access to that.
So whatever material you'd like to have
disseminated as a consequence of this
conversation,
just get that to me and I'll post it and
any blurb you want me to put it in the
description.
Then I'll also do that with whatever.
What,
when do you need it for?
As soon as,
as soon as you can get it,
cause I'll put this very soon.
Like in the next day.
Right.
All right.
Okay.
Is there anything else that you would
like to say that we haven't covered?
All right.
For first of all,
I think it's wonderful the way that
you're,
you're talking about this as sort of an
outside of that.
It's actually exciting,
uh,
because we,
we,
and we probably make this mistake that
we think of ourselves in a little bit
and sort of technocrats and,
and,
you know,
fiddlers and the margin kind of thing.
And it actually,
you're right and it is exciting.
It is exciting actually,
if we could actually spend our resources
four times as well as what we're doing
right now.
So instead of saying all the things that
are politically cried and making us all
feel warm and fuzzy,
actually doing the things that perhaps
are not top of mind,
not top of the,
uh,
the,
the agenda,
but we just do an amazing amount of
good.
Why the hell are we not doing that?
It's not,
yes.
Thank you very much for getting me back
into the group and excellence.
I really,
I really believe that.
And incredibly useful.
Yeah,
I think,
I think it's a mistake not to view what
you're doing as a,
as an exciting adventure.
I think it's a form of,
of what,
uh,
it's a form of non-helpful humility.
Yeah.
And,
and I think I,
I'm,
I'm Danish,
uh,
background and,
and one of the things we're very,
very good at as self-effacement.
Uh,
and so yes,
you're probably right.
So like you're following people,
you're calling people to a great
adventure here saying,
look,
we have enough resources so that we can
deflect a small fraction of them and do
an unbelievable amount of good.
And the,
and there were no downside to that.
There would be no downside.
Anyone,
there would be nothing but upside even
with some error and there's going to be
error.
And so of course,
no,
I think we'll find that people will
respond to this video in a very,
very positive way.
And because I do believe that there as
people become more aware that we are
becoming richer and that we do have more
resources at our disposal and that
that's genuinely true.
And that with a bit of intelligent
consideration,
we could make things a lot more less
dismal for a lot of people.
I think that they will start to view
that as something that's part of a great
global,
national and global adventure.
And,
and because you're agnostic and because
you've done the leg work,
then people can also,
I think get behind that without any real
cynicism,
they can say,
look,
our money spent here is not going to be
wasted.
We can be reasonably assured that if
we're charitable in this direction,
we're going to do something positive.
And so,
so anyways,
like I said,
I found it an incredibly
wonderful,
let me just say,
uh,
again,
we said a couple of times,
it's something that I've done.
I need to say,
you know,
I'm,
I'm just the sock puppet that talks
about all these things.
The,
this is the work of an incredible amount
of really,
really smart economists.
So one of the three end of the world's
top economists,
seven Nobel Lawrence,
those are the guys who have actually
done the work and who are giving you the
credibility to all of this.
Uh,
this research and that's why we can say
with great amount of certainty,
this is not just sort of a,
a whim,
but something that is probably the best
we know now.
It's probably as you point out,
not entirely true,
but it's certainly better than anything
else we have right now.
That's it.
Well,
actually the right comparison,
it's like it's not absolutely true.
Yeah.
But no one's got a better idea.
Right.
So we go with the best idea that we
have.
Exactly.
Right.
All right,
well look,
it was a great pleasure talking to you
and,
uh,
I'm hoping that,
you know,
a million people will watch this and
that we'll get another million podcasts
out of it and that this'll help
disseminate what you're doing
broadly.
I think that would be,
I think that would be lovely.
You Bet.
Thank you.
It was,
it was great.
Awesome meeting you.
And I hope our paths will cross again
soon and,
uh,
you know,
we should,
we should make a habit of this.
Yes,
we definitely should.
Well when you start to develop some more
of the national indices,
have you worked on any Western countries
like Canada or the United States or so?
So
we,
I want it to do that.
So we,
we haven't done it in the US just
because it's too dysfunctional,
so many different ways.
We've seen a couple of other people
trying to do this without our
involvement.
And one of the things we're really,
really good at is it,
you know,
you get all these economists who do all
of this stuff and the first draft of the
paper is,
this is really hard.
We need 10 years,
a lot of research money,
and then we'll probably get you
something and you know,
we say hello and that's,
that's nowhere.
You've got to give it your best shot.
Give,
use the information that's out there now
and give us a knowledge because
politicians are going to make decisions
next year.
Uh,
and,
and what has happened in those two
places.
So they did one in Holland,
they did,
it might actually be Canada,
but that was like 10 years ago.
Uh,
in ends up very much like a very
interesting anthology of,
of of points that I have no sort of
consistency is what we're trying to save
cost.
What would it cost to have something
like this done for Canada?
Uh,
so the shirt,
the short version is it cost about two
and a half million dollars.
Simply it's,
it's,
it doesn't really scale well.
Uh,
so you know,
doing it for Ghana,
it's the same thing as doing it for
Canada.
How long would it take?
18 months.
God,
that's such a good idea.
So two and a half million dollars.
18 months.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well I'm going to wrap that around.
Well maybe we can figure out how to
raise the money.
We should.
We should try and do that.
That be would be good.
I think there'd be a lot of interest in
Canada and Canada would be great way to
also get sort of bridge point into the
US without doing it in the u s Yup.
Yup.
Well,
that would be good cause we're flailing
about politically and it would be nice
to,
okay,
so,
so that's,
that's,
that's fodder for another conversation.
We,
I've got a couple of other conversations
that I'd like to have with you about
policy development and also about
marketing,
but we'll save those for another time.
Brilliant.
Them,
it was great talking to you again.
Thank you.
Very good at this stuff basically
tonight.
That's wonderful.
Wonderful.
Yeah,
I'll get this up as soon as I can.
Wonderful.
All right.
Talk to you soon.
Okay.
Bye.