Yeah,
you really can't tell the meaning of
someone's life till the very end.
It's for the same reason,
right?
Is that
how all the pieces fit together in the
story or in the life is not necessarily
determined until the final moment and I
think that's part of the reason too.
Why among Catholics,
for example,
in Christians in general,
there's an idea that salvation can
always be attained,
right?
Right up until the last moment.
No matter what your life was like and
you think,
well that's a pretty cheap trick because
you can run around doing terrible things
your whole life,
but as long as you get it together the
last second,
then you're Scott free.
But if you think about it in terms of a
story,
then you can understand how that could
conceivably be the case and it's for
this reason,
of course,
that this lecture in particular makes me
nervous more than any of the other ones
I do because I've been telling you a
story that's basically 40 hours long.
Right?
And it's spoken for them and then who
knows how long and it's written for him
and it's.
It's complicated to pull it together
properly and that's partly because as
far as I've been concerned,
we've been talking about issues in
psychology that are more difficult than
any other,
first of all,
conceptually,
even from a neuropsychological
perspective because I've been offering
you a model of the way the brain
processes the environment that I think
is really novel and and I think it
reflects the current state of
neuroscience and but,
but more than that,
there's the problem that we've been
dealing with issues all the way along of
life and death and of war and
destruction and have the possibility for
all clearheaded optimism.
A possibility which as we've discussed
more or less escape tolstoy say for most
of his life.
Right?
Because when tolstoy woke up from his
delusions,
he looked at the world and he said,
well,
clearly it's such a terrible place.
That as if you're not looking at it
through the veils of illusion,
there is no way that you can do anything
but stand in opposition to it.
Once you understand its basic structure,
right?
Suffering and innocent suffering and
complete vulnerability and the whole
existential mass that makes up life out
turns out that tolstoy overcame his
rationally induced cynicism in a kind of
mystical way.
He had a dream that he was suspended
from some transcendent space by a belt
around the middle of his waist,
which hung them over a period of chaos
and in that image he found and fair
enough,
it's a powerful image,
but it's not well delineated.
Right,
and it worked well for tolstoy and you
can see that the image has power,
but you can't.
You can't grab it with your rational
mind.
You can't take it into pieces and
analyze it as an argument and that's
what we do if we're intellectuals,
right?
We try to understand the detailed
structure of something and I think the
detailed structure of what tolstoy
apprehended as optimistic is actually
comprehensible and we've been working
towards that and circling around to the
entire course of this lecture series,
but I found with this material that with
each circling around the target,
it gets clearer and clearer.
It's a funny thing.
It's like you're looking at something
that's too complicated to see all at
once,
so you have to look at it from multiple
different perspectives and again and
again,
and each time you look at it,
it becomes clearer and clearer.
That still the case for me when I go
through this material,
every time I go through it,
I think,
oh yeah,
that piece fits there and that piece
fits there and that's how that makes
sense and oh,
that's a lot more remarkable than I
thought it was to begin with and so on,
and it seems fundamentally
inexhaustible,
and of course that's what you'd expect
from deep,
deep stories,
right?
Stories that have been around for
thousands and thousands of years
wouldn't have been around for thousands
and thousands of years unless they were
in some sense,
inexhaustible,
and we've talked about some of the
processes that might contribute to that.
Inexhaustible it.
So at the beginning of the lecture
series,
I told you to consider the assumption
that there was more than one way of
looking at the world.
Right?
There was the standard materialist sort
of scientific viewpoint,
which was that the world was made up of
objects independently existent us among
them,
the objects have no intrinsic value one
way or another,
and the issue of meaning per se wasn't
included in that account,
and then I said,
well wait,
there's another way of looking at the
world that we spent just as much time
developing that we utilize even more,
and that's the narrative.
That's the narrative way of looking at
the world to consider the nature of the
experience rather than the nature of
objects as real to consider your
experience as real,
even though it includes things that
can't be easily and tangibly identified.
Things like emotions,
which of course you find compelling
sometimes even beyond your will.
Things like motivational states,
fantasies,
ideals,
all the things that compel your behavior
and give you some sense that there's a
direction to life and people who study
emotion and perception have come.
To understand that the act of
transforming the world into something
simply made out of objects is incredibly
difficult.
It's so difficult that we haven't been
able to design machines that can do it
at all.
It turns out also that when we look at
the world,
we're not just looking at it with our
visual systems,
but we're looking at it with our motor
output systems and our emotions so that
when you look at something like a chair
which just stands there for you,
like an object,
it turns out that the mechanical
systems,
the motor systems that you would use to
use the chair to sit on it,
are activated during the act of
perception.
It also turns out sometimes that when
you look at something,
especially if it's something you've done
to understanding that it's and that
scares you,
you actually react to it,
conceptualize it with your body and with
your emotions before you have any idea
what it is from the perspective of an
object.
When you look at the world and when you
think about the world,
you have to do it from a motivation.
I'm motivated perspective and an
emotionally written perspective.
You can't even see the world without
being gripped by your motivation and
emotional states,
and so the idea that rationality or
perception is somehow separate from or
or superordinate to
perception and emotion is just wrong.
We understand now that you can't even
think without being motivated.
You can't see the world without being
motivated and that means you always look
at the world through a kind of Lens and
the Lens is a narrowing lands and it has
to be because the world is so
complicated.
You can't see it all at once.
You're only seeing tiny slices of it in
time and tiny slices of it in space and
and even then you have to narrow it to
only those things that are relevant to
you at that moment and we don't know
exactly how you do that.
We know that it takes years and years of
perceptual work in infancy say so that
you managed to build up an object
conception of the world.
That's probably all you're doing in the
first two or three years of life and
you're doing it constantly and it's just
as complicated as learning language say
are even more complicated.
Most of it's invisible and we don't know
how children do that and by the time
they can talk,
they've already done it so they can't
even tell us what they're doing.
It takes a long time to build up an
object world and when you look at the
world,
when you go from point a to point b,
even when you're doing something as
simple as looking for food and in the
kitchen,
you ignore everything about the world
that isn't relevant to making yourself a
peanut butter sandwich and you focus in
on those few things that are the
refrigerator,
the food,
the knives,
the cutlery and so on and everything
else is screened out.
Then you can't help but look at the
world through that kind of lance and the
lenses change and you can be
indifferent,
motivational states and they can change
because of internal transformations.
You're not hungry or thirsty or you're
not thirsty.
You're interested in someone or somebody
is telling you a story and then you
adopt their motivational framework and
you can see the world through their eyes
and now we know what the neural
machinery for that and we already talked
about that so we can toss back and forth
these motivational rains that frames of
reference and that gives us insight into
someone else's world.
You can look at the world endless
numbers of ways and what you're trying
to do is out of its infinite richness,
so to speak,
is pull out parts of it that are useful
for you while you're moving from point a
to point b,
and this can be a chair if you want to
sit down,
but if you want to take the light bulb
out of the ceiling,
then it's then it's a stool or a table
and whether or not it's a chair or a
stool or a table depends just as much on
what you're doing as it does on what it
is.
And I think that's part of the reason
why human beings can be so infinitely
creative.
Right?
For us,
the world isn't fixed.
We never know what it's going to bring
forth,
so 100 years ago,
if someone would have said,
well,
you could build a machine on a wafer,
a centimeter square out of sand,
and if you have enough of those
machines,
then everyone in the world can be
connected and everyone in the world can
have an infinite library of verbal
material.
Right?
That's impossible,
but it's not impossible.
It turns out that Silica has those
properties and we can build unbelievably
powerful machines out of nothing,
and so then that kind of makes you think
about just what this.
Nothing that we're building things out
of his right because it seems to be able
to reveal a constant array of
properties.
Properties that are essentially
unlimited and its capacity to reveal
those properties seems to depend as much
on our ability to interact with it.
Whatever that is,
as it does on whatever the stuff is,
and we know even from a strict object
perception of the world that the stuff
that things are made of is a lot more
complicated than we had originally
presumed.
Even as materialists,
because materialists realists,
their philosophy only holds down to the
subatomic level of analysis.
Deterministic worldview below the
There's nothing deterministic at all and
the stuff that things are made of is so
mysterious that we can't even.
We can't grasp,
but we can't comprehend it.
So it turns out that rather than the
story world be being dependent on the
object world,
it might be the other way around.
The object world is dependent on the
story world and that implies at least to
some degree that the story world is
actually more real.
Whatever that means,
and then I told you that,
well,
the real problem of life isn't so much
what do you do when you're around things
that you understand?
The real problem of life is what do you
do when you encounter something you
can't conceptualize?
And I think a good recent example of
that was the bombing of the world trade
towers,
which people were compelled to watch
over and over and over and over.
And if you ask someone,
well what is it that you're watching?
They would say,
well,
I'm watching the world trade towers fall
down,
but then you might say,
well,
why are you watching it over and over
and they would say something like,
well,
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it's happening,
and what does that mean?
It means something like whatever it is
that's happening here,
whatever's being blown apart exceeds my
ability to model.
As a consequence,
I have to expose myself to it again and
again and again and again to try to
understand what's falling,
what's falling exactly.
Is it just the.
Is it just the Towers is at 20,000
people,
is that the financial system of the u?
S is the stability of the Western world
is at the beginning of world war three
or as the former CIA director just
mentioned in theu ,
s the beginning of world war for what is
it exactly that you're looking at when
something happens that you don't
understand
and then you say,
well,
how do you react to that?
And it turns out that you react mostly
with your body,
not with your mind,
not with your perceptual systems,
not with your thoughts,
but with your emotions and your body,
and that means you sweat and you panic
and you feel depressed and you feel hurt
and you feel ashamed and you're prepared
for a catastrophe,
which is stress and all that basically
noncognitive.
And what that means is that when you
encounter something you don't
understand,
the first manner in which you conceive
of it is embodied emotional,
physical way.
Before you develop up an object
representation or cognitive
representation,
you may not ever get it like an event
like that,
or a worse event can throw someone into
a tailspin that's so extreme that they
never get out of it.
So you'll see,
for example,
sometimes,
and this is more true among elderly
people,
if their spouse dies,
the probability that they'll die in the
next year,
say from a heart attack or something
like that,
increases substantially.
Why is that?
It's because they're conceptual frame
was so dependent on the existence of
their spouse.
Say someone they've lived with for 25
years that the anxiety and uncertainty
caused by their anomalous disappearance
there death is so extreme that it sends
their body into a physiological state
that's basically unbearable and that
does the men,
and when you start to understand what
having your preconceptions rattled
really means,
then you also start to understand why
people are so motivated to protect their
ideological territory.
Right?
Because ideological territory,
that's how you see the world.
That's your story and you can't have
your fundaments rattled all the time
because it throws everything into chaos
and that puts you in this terrible,
panicky cortisol written stressful state
that's really hard on you physically.
So we know for example,
that if you're in a state where you're
chronically exposed to threat or
punishment,
which is the case in depression,
say you produce a lot of cortisol,
which is a stress hormone and cortisol
is toxic.
So the more of it you produce,
the more you kill off your hippocampal
cells and you really need them because
they are key to memory.
You do in your immunological system.
There's all sorts of negative side
effects of cortisol poisoning,
increased incidents of cardiovascular
disease,
heightened grade of cancer,
plus it's just no fun,
right?
It's the worst thing that can possibly
happen to you.
Essentially.
If something I know it happens to you in
blows frame of reference,
right,
knocks you for a loop,
sends you to the underworld,
however you want to construe it,
that's really going to upset your
bandwagon and throw you into a state
that you do virtually anything to avoid.
But by the same token,
there is a possibility that inside that
chaotic mess,
there's something you really need,
and what's the logic there?
Well,
the logic is something like this.
When you look at the world,
you only see a fragment of it and that's
good because it's pretty overwhelming
and the fragments generally more than
enough,
but all the information that you've ever
gathered in your entire life to build
yourself out of and to make your life
stable has come as a consequence of your
ability to explore what you don't
understand,
and that's an unlimited capacity,
right?
No matter how much you explored,
how much information you gather,
there's always the possibility that
there's way more information out there
and that means if you have a problem and
you see that it's a problem,
even though that's frightening,
it's also a gateway into a domain of
possibility and the possibility is this
richly informative background that could
in principle provide you with any answer
you need,
but and then you can take one more
thing.
The old Gods Mars,
say the God of war,
Venus,
the god of love,
they're all internalized for us,
right?
We know that angers the psychological
state and that love is the psychological
state,
but if we look at our great religious
traditions,
Christianity say or Buddhism,
just to take two as an example,
we still have this notion that what
these figures represent is something
external.
Well,
you might say how primitive,
right?
Just as primitive as the idea that the
god of war is something external,
is the idea that this sort of figure is
supposed to be something external.
It's supposed to be something embodied,
right?
It's a story about the nature of
individual moral responsibility.
So the idea is something like this,
well,
reality itself,
the existence of things seems to depend
on the existence of a finite observer so
that we can see things from a
perspective.
If you don't see things from a
perspective,
everything is the same.
There's nothing delineated.
But if there's going to be delineated
things,
small things,
insufficient things,
and they're going to be aware they're
going to be vulnerable as a part of
their limitation.
And so you say,
well,
limitation is a precondition for being
and that means suffering is part and
parcel of being.
Dostoevsky said,
clearly,
look,
I'll give you all the cake you want.
You got a big house,
you got nothing to do,
but watch TV,
right?
And propagate the species.
Are you happy?
Dostoevsky says,
well,
no.
Why?
Well,
because human beings are really
fundamentally know,
ungrateful and insane,
so if you give them some little
comfortable niche to occupy themselves
with so they don't have anything to
worry about,
the first thing they're going to do,
just like Adam and eve,
basically are just like Gautama Buddha.
They're going to run around looking for
the apple,
looking for the snake.
Looking for the trouble to smash the
frame into bits,
no matter how comfortable it is,
just so they can get access to little
chaos and have some fun,
and so then you think,
well,
maybe it's more like the purpose of life
isn't to avoid chaos because we like
chaos.
It's entertaining,
right?
It keeps us alert and awake and it gives
us something to do that really has no
end and so maybe the answer is something
more like,
well,
forget the frame of reference and forget
the chaos,
but hit the balance right between the
two.
Right?
So that you've got one foot where it's
reasonably comfortable and you've got
one foot out there where it's kind of
exciting and dangerous and that's
perfect,
and then you think the state you want to
attain that makes you resistant to even
the greatest anomalies.
Anomalies of death say,
or vulnerability or mortality is
exactly.
That's that position,
right?
Balance Straight between the forces of
chaos and the forces of order or between
Yin and Yang and how do you know you're
there because that's what it really
boils down to.
How do you know that you were there and
then you think,
okay,
it's pretty simple.
You Watch with your eyes open,
just like Solzhenitsyn Watch.
Do you think I don't know everything,
so let's see what I do.
No,
no preconceptions.
I'm not going to shield myself from the
truth with some second rate frame of
reference.
We don't believe in those anyways
because they're always fragmental.
I'm just going to watch.
So when am I not miserable?
And then you think,
well,
I'm not miserable when I'm interested in
something,
I get interested in something.
I don't exactly know why I get
interested in.
It catches me.
What are the,
what's the phenomenology of being
caught?
Are Not self conscious.
When I'm engaged in something,
I'm more like a child,
which is why children have intimations
of immortality.
I mean engaged in this process.
I don't think about myself so I'm not
self conscious.
I lose my sense of temporality because
it seems like I can do whatever it is
that I'm doing thing that I enjoy for
hours and the time flies by and I'm not
even really aware of the surrounding
world and none of my existential
concerns are paramount at that time.
Every need is suppressed by my
engagement in the activity.
And then you say to yourself,
well,
yeah,
I find that only happens like you know,
10 minutes every three days or something
when I'm being particularly miserable,
but you might say,
well,
the fact that it happens at all is
probably worth paying attention to.
I mean if you believe that your
experience is real,
like real,
the fact that you can get into a state
like that at all,
it's worth paying attention to and so
then you might say,
well that's,
that's where your sense of ethics really
starts to arise is what makes you
interested.
Well,
it might be just as cracked and,
and,
and peculiar as.
It's something you could possibly
imagine,
right?
Your parents are against your friends or
against it.
Even you're against it when you're
thinking clearly,
but there's still this reality that
something compels you and then you
think,
well,
can you trust it?
And I think,
well that's a tough question because I
read a long time for a long time,
I read accounts of serial killers
because I was really interested in what
motivated them.
Right?
And they're an interesting breed in many
ways,
which is why there's such a popular
fascination with them.
And so then you think about a story like
that and you think,
Geez,
maybe you can't trust your interest.
Right?
Maybe it'll take you somewhere.
You don't want to go like seriously
where you don't want to go.
How do you know that if you really let
yourself be who you could be,
that you'd end up somewhere good.
And so then the income to the second
part of the story,
which is something like this.
Let's say that you're a very,
very,
very finely tuned biological machine,
right?
Kim Do a computer and then you say,
okay,
you take a computer and you feed it
false information.
What do you get out?
False information,
right?
Well,
you've stuck with this computer,
it's very complicated.
You kind of reside in it in some manner
you don't understand,
and yet you're prone pawn occasions
either to deny it information
altogether.
When you walk away from something you
know you shouldn't walk away from or
defeated it,
bad information,
and so then what if,
what if this was the case?
What if it was the case that the systems
that Orient you with regards to your
interest can become pathologized by any
relationship you have with yourself
that's predicated on bad faith,
and so then you think,
well,
that's why there's an ethical aspect to
this redemptive process,
like a real strenuous and strict ethical
aspect.
It goes something like this.
There are things that you can do.
Find yourself engaged with the world at
such a level that your existential
concerns could disappear and we can even
understand that biochemically to some
degree because if you're really
interested in something,
you get a dopamine release and
exploratory dopamine release.
That's great.
I mean that's associated with positive
effect with confidence,
with increased immunological
functioning,
with better memory functioning with
learning everything you want.
It's also potently antianxiety,
lytic and analgesic,
which means that if you're really
pursuing something that's compelling to
you,
you're much more resistant biochemically
to punishment,
disappointment,
depression,
pain,
threat,
etc. And it's not because you're blind,
it's not blind.
It's becAuse your nervous system is
optimally tuned to make you maximally
resistant.
And so then you might think if you were
optimally tuned,
how resistant would you be?
You don't know,
right?
Because it's a spiral that never stops
moving uphill.
We don't know what the upper end is.
We have exemplars that might indicate
what that upper end could be,
but we don't actually know.
So then you think,
okay,
well here's the,
here's the rule.
Say something like this.
If you looked at the world from this
perspective,
which is something you have to decide if
you're,
you know,
you find compelling and reasonable.
The rule is this,
you're always gonna run into anomaly,
right?
And,
uh,
normally it's always going to look to
look to you like,
like this,
and it's no bloody wonder.
You want to run away from that.
I mean,
in some ways is your whole body's
telling you,
watch out.
And for good reason,
because It's no joke,
but then it was more to the story
because the anomalous thing,
that's everything you don't know and you
might say,
well,
you're going out with someone and you
want to have a longterm relationship.
They betray you.
How could there be any good in that?
Because that certainly what you're going
to ask when you first encounter the
unexpected information,
but then you might think could be that
I'm a little too naive for my own good,
right?
People pull me in a little more than
they should or I'm not sufficiently
careful when I enter into intimate
relationships with people or I don't
treat people right or I don't have a
good conceptualization of myself or I'm
chasing after the wrong person.
Well,
that's all going to be very annoying to
learn,
but if you don't learn it,
you're going to be in big trouble.
So maybe the best thing to do and then
normally have that sort of hits you this
to think,
okay,
yeah,
it's a dragon.
No doubt it will eat me,
but if I don't let it eat me,
then they'll just be another one waiting
around the corner and it will probably
be a little bit bigger and if I get
eaten by enough of them,
I'm not really going to want to be
around much and maybe I'm not going to
be willing to help other people be
around much either.
It doesn't seem like a very good
alternative to me.
Back in 1957,
some new gnostic writings were
discovered in a,
in a cave.
They were discovered by these two arab
guys who went out to kill the man who
killed her father.
They took them out into this cave and
they killed them and when they were
burying them,
they found exam for a full of papers and
papyrus and they took them home and
their mother used a bunch of them to
like cooking fires with and one day one
of their friends who is an antiquities
dealer showed up and he said,
you know,
you shouldn't be burning those.
Those are about 1500 years old and they
look like very early gnostic gospels.
And the gnostics were this branch of
christianity that was pretty violently
suppressed by the emergence of orthodox
christianity and the gnostics believed
that faith was a good thing,
but knowledge was all right too.
And they wrote gospel accounts say of
christ's life that were knowledge
predicated as much as revelation
predicated say,
and this is one of the quotes from one
of those gospels,
the gospel of thomas,
which is actually one that the only one
that got out,
Carl Young,
got ahold of him interestingly enough,
and this is one of the quotes,
and I really liked this.
This is a non canonical saying of
christ.
And the saying is,
if you bring forth what is within you,
what you bring forth will save you.
If you do not bring forth what is within
you,
what you do not bring forth will destroy
you.
And I think that's a pretty good line to
close off the class.
So thank you for attending.