Yeah.
And now I get dry in into a dive.
I worked for Svenska dog about,
which is a newspaper,
one of the,
the second largest with daily
circulations.
And then I ask sometimes on twitter and
facebook,
what kind of people you think I should
interview?
And your name has come up a lot.
I think you've heard this before.
So,
uh,
and then,
recently I wrote a piece in
a freedom in,
in Sweden and,
and you shared it on twitter and
facebook.
So then I,
that's when I may leave because then I
thought that perhaps now I have a
perhaps now you will respond.
I can get me into you.
Yeah.
Well cool.
Apt is really turned out to be quite,
quite the platform man.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it's,
I'm really,
I did an interview with Claire Lehmann.
I interviewed her,
um,
which I haven't released yet.
Uh,
but I,
but we'll in the next probably two
weeks,
something like that.
But,
um,
she's hitting it out of the park is fall
as far as I'm concerned.
It kind of reminds me of what magazine
Leica Harper's used to be,
or at the Atlantic before
for mainstream journalism collapsed
virtually,
completely and became so politicized.
So yeah,
it's cool.
It's been really impressive.
It's fun.
That's something that,
uh,
like a mother of two or one
and just being fed up with the political
correctness of her psychology
department,
I think it was.
And then she starts quill it and now
we're all like sharing in her project
from all over the world.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
It's really amazing.
And she,
well,
she has really good editorial sense.
She must be really smart that,
that girl.
Yeah,
I would say so too.
Uh,
but,
uh,
I'll try,
I don't know if you remember,
I'll just begin by asking you about the
Sweden Sweden case.
I don't know if you remember what the
article was about,
but I wrote about,
uh,
Eric Green Murray is a professor at the
political science department and he was
forced to include,
uh,
Judith Butler.
Butler.
Oh yeah.
Right.
Judith Butler.
Yeah.
Great.
And,
uh,
the course is about modern society and
its,
and its critics.
So it's basically about the reactionary
forces and uh,
left wing extremist forces during the
turn of the last century.
So in the early 20th century,
late 19th century.
And then you riff butler.
Um,
and actually one of the course,
not Eric,
but uh,
his,
um,
his teaching assistant interviewed
and she said that she disagreed with
the,
so she agreed with the professors that
Chili Cheese thought that the academic
freedom was more yeah.
Important than,
uh,
being forced to teach about feminist
authors and gender science.
So she was actually
on the other side.
Gender Science.
Yeah,
exactly.
Or is by no means a scientist or even a
credible academic?
As far as I'm concerned,
I think she's a straight out idealog and
um,
and the fact that anybody would be
forced,
well,
first of all forced to include anything
on their curriculum I think is
absolutely reprehensible.
It's topped down interference with
academic freedom and it's
extraordinarily dangerous because once
that
precedent is established,
then you open the door for political
interference in the,
like,
I like organized political interference
from outside the academy and it'll
collapse very rapidly under.
Sir,
we saw that happening in Germany and
also in the Soviet Union.
It like that can happen so quickly that
people can't,
can't,
it's almost impossible to believe.
Now we're in this weird situation where
the same thing seems to be happening to
a large degree within the academy
itself.
And so,
and what to do about that is by no means
obvious,
but,
but I don't think that allowing external
control of any sort over the contents of
the courses the professor teach
professors teach is,
it's a very,
very bad idea.
We,
they have a rule,
rule of thumb they call it,
but it's basically,
it's much more a rule.
And the rule of thumb that at least 40%
of all the literature has to be written
by women.
So unbelievable.
If you're holding a course,
for example,
about modern society and its critic
critics with a lot of primary literature
from turn of the century,
then you run into a problem because
women weren't,
uh,
so,
we weren't a lot of women who were
authors back them.
So unbelievably,
I would say resentful.
I really think that's the fundamental
issue here.
To push a doctor resentful and
uninformed to push a doctrine like that.
Look,
it's unbelievably widespread.
So I'll give you an example that's very,
that's very similar.
Our Prime Minister,
Justin Trudeau announced in 2015 that
half the cabinet that he put together
would be women,
right?
The fact that only approximately,
I think it was 20 to 25% of the elected
officials were female.
And so what he basically admitted,
as far as I'm concerned,
it was two things.
Number one,
he was incapable of judging people on
their competence because when you put
together something like the cabinet for
a country,
what you do is you find the most
competent people,
period.
Because
it's so bizarre that it even has to be
said because it actually turns out that
the cabinet is important.
And so to me,
all he did was default on his,
said his central moral obligation to
screen every single one of his members
of parliament with exceeding care and to
pick the most qualified people.
And his rationale was that it was 2015,
you know,
so,
and we to reduce competence to racial
ethnic,
gender identity,
something like that is an absolutely
appalling move philosophically as well,
as far as I'm concerned,
to assume that diversity is somehow
represented by group membership.
There's no evidence for that.
There's absolutely no scientific
evidence for that whatsoever.
In fact,
the scientific evidence suggest quite
the contrary,
which is that there's more variability
within groups than there is between
groups,
which is actually an antidote to the
central racist claim,
right.
Because the central racist claim is,
there's more difference between groups
than there is difference within them.
And so,
you know,
you seen one black person,
you've seen them all.
Yeah.
And Wow,
well this is,
we actually have in Sweden it's called
the,
I think the procedure is,
um,
gender mainstreaming in,
in English.
But,
um,
uh,
basically you have to include a gender
scientific perspectives,
uh,
into all this is happening within all
Swedish universities right now.
Uh,
so you have to include the perspective
of gender,
gender,
scientific,
scientific perspective in all parts of
the university.
So it's not just literature lists of
courses,
it's also the who are you going to
recruit?
And we have a goal in Sweden and,
uh,
from the government.
This is all the government's doing.
MMM.
We have a goal that I think it's 40% of
all the professors,
uh,
by 2020,
they should be women.
Right.
Which means that if you're a young man
who's entering academia,
the probability that you're going to get
a job as zero.
Yeah.
Right.
And that,
yeah,
the same thing's happening here.
So for example,
this,
they're our minister of science who was
one of the people,
let's say selected because of Trudeau's
insistence upon gender equity in his
cabinet.
Um,
you know,
he could have,
pick a number of women that was
proportionate to the number of women
elected.
Like even that I wouldn't have agreed
with because I think he should've gone
on street competence and,
and,
and taken on the heavy moral burden of
trying to figure out what competence
meant,
but just,
but no,
it had to be 50 50 because I guess that
was,
you know,
this is a very snide thing to say,
but that seems to be at the level of
arithmetic intelligence that he could
manifest.
You know,
it's,
and,
and one of his ministers,
our Minister of science has,
we have this program called camp.
The Canada chairs in the Canada research
chairs were set up so that Canadian
universities would have an additional
amount of money to hire the most
qualified people they possibly could for
senior named chair positions.
And the idea was to attract
international talent,
like high level.
Now what has happened,
because it wasn't very well designed,
this program was the Canadian
universities mostly ended up poaching
from each other,
which was,
you know,
relatively counterproductive because it
just elevated the salaries of the
professors,
which maybe they deserve rather than
bringing in a lot of international
talent.
But man,
we're radically overrepresented in the
Canada research chairs now.
The administer of science is very
annoyed about this and thinks that
that's a consequence of systemic
misogyny or some some bloody thing.
Failing to note entirely.
See,
if you look at scientific productivity,
it's very interesting because,
and gender,
the median professor,
male and female publish approximately
the same amount.
So the typical,
but the,
the exceptional professors are almost
all men who even though the typical male
and female can't really be distinguished
in academia,
if you take that tiny subset of hyper
productive professors,
they're almost all male.
Now why that is is my suspicions are
that it's pretty straight forward.
I suspect that the reason it is is
because to be a hyper productive in any
given field means you have to be
absolutely single minded and obsessed
about it as well as being very
intelligent,
conscientious.
So it's rare,
right?
You have to be intelligent,
say 99th percentile,
conscientious,
95th percentile.
So that's hard.
The anybody right there.
And then you have to have the time
available to do nothing whatsoever,
but concentrate on your work.
No family,
no friends,
nothing like that.
If you're going to be at the very top of
your profession,
because obviously you'll get out
competed otherwise.
Now that's a lot harder for women
because,
well for obvious reasons.
I mean so,
so the mere fact that most of these
people were,
see the other thing people don't
understand is that people can on average
be very similar.
So their distributions,
but if you go way out on to the edges of
the distribution,
small differences in the middle can make
massive differences at the edge.
And so,
and that's the kind of phenomena you see
where you are selecting the highest
qualified people.
It's a,
it's an edge of the distribution
phenomena.
So here's an example.
This is really cool one.
So if you look at the overlap between
male and female aggression,
it's pretty high.
So if you randomly select a man and a
woman from the general population and
you bet that the woman was the more
aggressive of the two,
you'd be right 40% of the time,
which is actually pretty often.
So,
but if you go way the hell out to where,
let's say only imprisoned the one in 100
most aggressive people,
they're all men.
Yeah.
Even though on average,
you know,
it's 60,
40,
you'd go out to the 99th percentile.
It's all men.
Which is why almost all the people in
prison are men now.
So people,
well it's,
it's,
yeah,
what you're describing in Sweden,
that's the death of the universities.
It's another,
it's another sign of like,
the universities are killing themselves.
They're hiring adjunct professors and
not faculty members.
Like I think it's up to 70% in some
American universities.
They have no salary,
no power,
no autonomy,
no job security,
nothing.
It's,
it's,
you know,
some of these adjuncts teach four or
five courses a year and make $25,000.
So it's,
I read about one who lived in her car.
Yeah.
Okay,
so they've jacked up tuition.
Proletariat.
Yeah,
exactly.
Well there you go.
You know,
um,
if jacked up tuition,
oh,
they've jacked up tuition to the point
where it's unsustainable.
They've made it impossible for kids who
rack up tuition debt to declare
bankruptcy.
Because they've taken that out of the
bankruptcy laws.
Now you can take away their driver's
license if they don't pay their,
their,
uh,
their tuition,
their student loan bills.
So it's basically indentured servitude,
right?
The administration has become completely
top heavy.
The academy is completely infested by
these terrible equity ideas that you're
laying out.
I mean,
and,
and the people who are in the radical
leftists disciplines,
which increasingly are spreading there,
influence out through the entire
universities,
are tenured and won't be moved for 25
years.
So as far as I can tell,
it's,
it's done,
would like to ask you,
Oh,
you take about on gender science and all
these sort of like ethnic studies and
theology.
Because I was a sociology student back
in 2004,
and I was 22 years old.
And so a lot of these perspectives,
we were taught postmodernism and queer,
queer feminism and all these things.
And it was,
I mean,
I was just starting out as a student,
so I,
but I,
I must have been wired for faulty
because he didn't,
uh,
I was very critical about it.
But,
but all those perspectives was,
uh,
was back then was fringe in Sweden.
So like,
um,
like identity politics or everything
that's now in the mainstream was at the
institution back then.
And the professors,
they were,
they are the same.
I mean they are now,
it's their,
their phds and most of the students that
are taking over the public discourse,
uh,
so even they lost a lot of debate back
then and they still do like public
debates.
They're still teaching students year
after year of the year.
The students should ask you about that
and also about your,
your critique of gender,
gender studies in Swedish,
it's called gender science because we
turn all this into science.
So it's not even studies,
it's science here.
That was a good move on the,
on the,
on the ideologues parts,
that's for sure.
Really smart.
So it's a two pronged question,
but
yeah,
well I think,
well,
I listed about seven things I think that
are killing me.
Universities.
I actually think that I've watched major
institutions collapse and being privy to
the manner in which that occurs.
Like what happens is that as the
enterprise pathologizes,
the good people leave,
the people who have other things that
they could do,
they leave first knows are the most
productive and talented people.
As soon as the most productive leave,
then the bloody thing just spirals
downhill.
Because what,
what's going to happen?
You've,
you've,
you know,
because the rule is,
is that within a certain discipline,
whatever it happens to be,
the square root of the number of people
in the discipline produce half the
productive work.
So if the university has,
let's say a thousand professors,
um,
30 of them produce half the
publications,
right?
Which is staggering,
It's staggering.
That's the pareto distribution or
price's law.
And so,
and those people are often have more
opportunities than they know what to do
with.
And so as soon as whatever they're doing
becomes unstable,
it's like they go off and do other
things and then the,
then the institution loses its most
productive people.
And that's it.
It's done.
It can't recover from that.
And so,
and the introduction of these so-called
science,
uh,
disciplines that we call studies
disciplines.
You know,
it was a market lowering of standards.
It involved in market lowering of
academic standards,
a blurring of what actually constituted
discipline,
um,
refusal whatsoever to consider anything
methodologically rigorous because
anything goes including author,
what do they call that auth no auto
ethnography,
which is where you just write a diary
essentially about your own experiences.
Next,
got this fancy name.
So auto ethnography as part of gender
science,
you know,
it's positively or Wellington and
it's,
and the other thing that's interesting
about that is that what's happened is
that the people who have these radical
viewpoints have been given a permanent
sign.
It cure right there,
there their state and tuition sponsored
activists who spend every single moment
of their time on what I would consider
their fifth column agenda.
So we're basically funding a cohort of
people who stated purpose is to demolish
the patriarchy.
Um,
you know,
one of the things Carl Young said,
which I really liked and haven't talked
about that much,
is that the unconscious representation
of men in the female psyche,
he called the animus and the animus was
always in his estimation because of the
dream analysis he did and so forth.
That although the unconscious
representation of a woman in a man's
psyche was an individual woman,
the unconscious representation of the
male psyche in the female unconscious
was men as a group.
And there's a very large number of women
and and also some men whose conception
of male yes is,
has been damaged very badly by their
failure to establish any positive
relationship with any male whatsoever in
their developmental history.
And then they project this paranoid
representation of what constitutes
hierarchical masculinity onto the world
and then fight too,
bring it down.
And it's,
and the thing is they're being
successful.
That's the problem is this is,
this is it,
this is another one when I was actually,
I know that you are very popular with
the,
a lot of young men,
but I was actually introduced to you by
a,
a mother or two professor in,
uh,
in education.
So she's really,
she's not in her,
uh,
at the,
at home,
so to speak,
ideologically or a,
but uh,
okay.
One thing that's worrying me is
the,
okay,
there are certain,
certain parts of a certain ideologies
that take on a religious overtones
though.
And I think that feminism has some of
those characteristics.
I mean,
in Christian,
they were all born sinful or we need to
come to grips with our sinfulness.
And in the end,
only God's grace and forgiveness can
redeem us.
And,
uh,
in,
in Lutheranism at least a,
it's,
uh,
we don't can,
we can be forgiven by priests.
It's only dog.
Yeah.
Doctrine.
There's no escape.
Rob and I totally sympathize with it,
even though I don't in a lot of ways,
but um,
I realized,
uh,
but within feminist and the sin is
situated within males instead,
well,
no,
not only with within nails,
but within males as a collective,
which has even see that's the thing
about the Christian doctrine that you
referred to,
is that it makes each individual
responsible for their own darkness.
Now the Catholics say,
look,
that's unbearable and people need to
have the slate wiped clean.
Now in that and confessional do that,
and there's an intermediary and you
considered that merciful.
And there's some real power in that
argument.
You know,
that the cynical argument is,
well,
you can just wipe the slate clean at any
time and you don't have to bear any
responsibility.
But I think that's cynical.
The Protestants put themselves in a much
tougher position because there's no
escape.
And,
but the upside of all of that is,
is that the darkness is to be regarded
as within,
not without.
Yeah.
And as soon as you move away from that,
then well,
you're,
you're the good person.
And so is everyone that thinks like you
and all the evil is wherever you want to
put it.
And then as soon as the thing that's
really dangerous about that,
especially if the evil is conceptualized
as contemptible and,
and parasitic and,
and using disgust related language,
for example,
instead of fear related language than
the logical directive is to purify it.
Boy,
that's,
that's not good.
And this is something that I think is
happening.
Uh,
if I read some,
a dissertation about how male feminists
I think about themselves and how they go
about having sex,
for example,
every one of the men said that he's,
he's way to a approach sex was that he
didn't take any initiative because he
would,
he would foul,
uh,
the,
the file,
the whole situation and the woman.
Yeah.
Well,
it's like Andrea to work in a back in
the 70s that horrible.
She's a horrible creature,
Andrea to work.
And uh,
you know,
she said that men engaged in sexual
behavior with an erect penis,
that that was,
uh,
that,
that was equivalent to violence.
Right?
That was equivalent to rape.
So,
I mean,
I don't even know what to say about that
except that that's exactly what Andrea
to work and was like.
And she was a real heroine to the
radical feminists,
you know her.
And there was someone else around that
period of time.
Andrew Catharine Mackinnon,
I think her name was equally equally
well.
I think I read a book.
Oh yeah.
Well you,
you would've,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
from,
from my perspective as a clinician,
those people have clear every indication
of serious personality disorders.
And I actually think to some degree that
we've made a haven for people who have
serious personality pathology in these,
in these pseudo disciplines,
in the universities.
And you know,
you said something interesting,
you said that,
uh,
you know,
when you went to,
to,
when you took your sociology degree that
these were basically fringe views.
Now there's center views in the
university,
but also implying that they're
increasingly dominant views in society.
And that's the thing is that people
think that these are somehow ivory tower
arguments.
But what happens in the university's
happens in society five to 10 years
later.
And so,
and that's exactly what's happening
right now.
So
one,
I think this,
this leads us into the me to a debate
with them because all you have people in
Sweden right now,
I think the me too phenomenon is much
larger in Sweden than in any other
country.
I mean it's,
it's dominated the media for one month
now.
And,
uh,
every profession has,
collect has an a me too,
uh,
sort of article with thousands of women,
signing on to it.
So the teachers and the lawyers and the
doctors.
So,
but one,
one thing is interesting about this is
how the men are,
are handling it because um,
there are a lot of men writing that I as
a man,
uh,
have a responsibility for this
happening.
I as a man,
as a male,
I'm responsible and I'm guilty.
And actually it was one.
So there are a lot of articles like
that.
And then one of them,
one of the men that was accused of doing
something inappropriate,
it was the former,
the for the left Radical Party.
And if the thing he had done was not so
reprehensible approached the woman and
then she had said no and he had
apologized,
but then she didn't accept that the now,
now he's under investigation police
investigation and we have this sort of
witch hunt
that almost all all manifestations of
male sexuality are going to be brought
under legal control.
And he actually wrote an article that
said,
yes,
I am responsible because I say I'm
responsible.
I'm better than the majority of men's
reactions to this.
So actually he turned the thing that he
was being under investigation into
because he showed that because he
admitted he showed that he was better.
Yeah.
So,
so
it's very our stay,
I mean the whole idea was that you were
supposed to come to terms with your
class guilt and then confess and then,
and then indicate that you could be
brought back into the ideological fold
properly.
The thing is,
it's a lot of muddy thinking.
It's like,
well man should take responsibility for
their aggressive sexuality and they
should incorporate it.
Right?
Because if you repress it,
it just comes out in the most ugly way.
So,
I mean,
part of the ideas that men,
boys should be socialized like little
girls,
you know?
But that's complete rubbish.
In fact,
even little girls perhaps shouldn't be
socialized like little curls,
but whatever.
I mean that's beside the point that that
aggressive capacity that's associated
with sexuality as well as Freud pointed
out so long ago,
needs to be integrated within the
personality so that it's under control,
right?
And then it's,
it's the hint of darkness and it's the
capacity for malevolence,
but it's,
but it's brought,
but it's brought under civilized
regulation.
And so then you get to have your cake
and eat it too.
Right?
You can be strong and potentially
dangerous and mysterious and all of
those things that are definitely
attractive.
That's an attractive features of men,
not only to women,
but also to other men.
Um,
so you have to take responsibility for
that.
But that doesn't mean that you should
identify yourself as the member of a
guilty group because of a class based
accusation.
Right.
That's just,
you're not guilty as the member of a
class.
I mean,
that's part of the reason that I've been
pushing so hard against these postmodern
neo Marxist ideas because one of their
essential predicates is that you can be
guilty as the member of a class.
And that is,
I don't know if there's a more dangerous
idea then then that there might be,
because you know,
there's a very large number of extremely
dangerous ideas,
but that one's,
that one's up near the top.
It's happening to great degree in the
United States to lesser so in Canada,
but every day there's another,
you know,
slew of,
of influential man who are being outed
for their past sexual misbehavior and
you know,
and that,
and,
and that's,
that's uh,
I don't have much to say about that
except that to use that as evidence for
the
group based guilt of men as such.
Yeah.
Well,
whatever,
it's going to get a hell of a lot worse
before it gets better,
I'm afraid.
I think this is also,
I would like to ask you about this as
well,
because as a,
as a man growing up in a,
in a country like Sweden,
you have to,
I wouldn't say that.
I think a lot of boys at least,
or are confused what it means to be a
man.
And,
and then you have these public figures,
adult males admitting to collective
guilt and trying to be sort of the new
new mail,
which admits to guilt the feminist,
the good man,
um,
tom of a man resting on top of the warm
TV.
Who's,
who's,
what would you say moral virtue consists
in his harmlessness exactly.
What,
what's,
I mean how,
what's the advice to give to,
because what I find,
I see a lot of men trying to find their
way in,
find out what it means to be a man.
And I think that's a lot of them turns
to you and a,
or a person like Jocko willink and let,
let interviewed you.
And because you are,
you're,
uh,
and why do you think that it's,
I mean,
is it the because it doesn't seem so
you're sugarcoating
life,
you're not giving them the funny thing
about,
well,
there's a couple of things that are
doing that are different from what
people usually do.
You know,
so in the last 20 years,
the constant message to young people is
self esteem,
feel good about yourself.
It's like,
I don't buy that.
I think that you look at yourself in the
mirror and you think,
Jesus Christ,
I could be a hell of a lot better than I
am.
And so,
and the thing is,
there's nothing more complimentary to
tell a young person than that.
It's like,
look at you.
You're a wreck.
Grow the hell up.
There's so much more to you than your
manifesting.
Then you can hardly imagine it.
It's like,
what you think?
That's a criticism.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's a great compliment.
It's like,
look at how much more you could bring
out into the world.
Get your aggression under control,
strengthen yourself.
Like take on some responsibility.
See if you have enough bloody courage to
tell the truth.
Put your life together,
stop whining.
The man,
eat that up because no one's ever told
them that.
Which just makes breaks my heart.
It's so bad.
And you know,
the boys are pulling out of everything.
They're pulling out a university,
they're pulling out of life,
they're pulling out of marriage,
and,
and because of that,
they're more awkward and unsophisticated
than they would otherwise be in much
more prone to make sexual errors,
some of which are,
you know,
predatory malevolence in a small
proportion of cases.
But it's another one of those
situations,
you know,
like imagine that one in a hundred men
are sexual predators.
Probably.
Maybe it's one in 50 but let's go with
one in a hundred.
Well,
they,
that small proportion commit all of this
sexual predation.
Like if you look at criminals,
it's the parade.
Oh,
distribution again,
5% of the criminals produce something
like,
well,
the overwhelming majority of the crimes,
right?
It's a small coterie of specialized
people who are responsible for all the
criminality.
Lots of people are in prison because
they did one highness thing.
You know,
like they got enraged or drunk and did
something violent.
But there's the serial criminal types
and they're the ones that are,
they do all,
they,
they like we had one guy in Toronto for
example,
who ran a bike theft ring and they
finally nailed him.
And like there weren't any bikes stolen
in Toronto after that.
It was just him and his little coterie
of,
you know,
organized bike thieves and these guys
that are being outed,
the serial predators,
they are responsible like one,
one spread predatory guy can prey on who
knows,
500 females,
thousand females into lifetime,
you know.
So
it's a little,
seems like everyone listens.
A lot of guys,
I
was one of these guys who sort of turned
away from society for,
for awhile,
like into computer games,
like this slacker identity where,
which is sort of,
I guess it's always been there.
Like you turn to a,
like a way from all responsibilities and
you got reimbursed.
But the opportunities to do this,
it's so much Florida now,
right?
Yeah.
Well it's,
it's the lost boys like in Peter Pan
Right there.
It never land.
And they never grow up.
And Peter Pan is their leader.
That's,
that's the story.
And it's not surprising because it's
easier to do.
It's easier to occupy yourself trivially
than it is to do something difficult.
So like there's a big tendency in that
direction to begin with because it's
easier to do nothing than to take
responsibility.
It's easier to play games than to plan
for the future.
It's easier to be resentful and angry
than it is to be,
you know,
to shoulder you're vulnerability
properly.
And then when you add on to that,
the idea that if you go out into the
world and try to strive forward,
that you're nothing but a predatory
patriarch,
then well,
it's just one more.
It's just the icing on the cake.
You know,
I had a friend who was like that he
pulled back from the world.
Um,
and because he believed that active
masculinity was a pathological force
and,
um,
he poisoned himself terribly because of
that.
And he committed suicide.
When he was 40,
he hooked an exhaust Noah hose onto his
exhaust pipe and gassed himself up in
the mountains in Alberta.
And that was the logical consequence of
his self hatred.
It's like,
well,
if you're so pathological,
why don't you just do it yourself in and
hiding like that is it?
You know,
it's not,
that's obviously not the full fledged
manifestation of that,
but,
but it's,
it's,
believe me,
it's on the road.
So,
and so.
Yeah.
I've been talking to all these young
guys,
they come to my biblical lectures,
for example,
and the message is always the same.
It's like,
stand the hell up.
Get the hell out there in the world.
Take local responsibility.
Put yourself together because there's
nothing more dangerous than a weak man.
And the problem is,
is that we're encouraging men to be weak
because we have this pathological idea
that there's that strength and tyranny
or the same thing.
And that's that Animus I was talking
about earlier though,
women start only women,
but the feminist types,
let's say,
who insist upon the pathology of the
Patriarchy cannot distinguish between
competence and power.
They see everything because they have
this vague and undifferentiated sense of
masculinity.
They say they see everything that is
associated with authority as equivalent
to tyranny.
Failing to understand completely that
authority in a properly function society
is based on competence.
They don't believe in competence
anyways.
You know,
that's part of the whole postmodern.
Yeah.
That's just the cost or to keep power.
Yeah,
exactly.
What everything's about.
Power for the bloody postmodernists and
that also excuses their use of power.
And this is a,
I mean,
in Sweden,
we have a,
girls have always outperform boys in
school.
Ever since we started having schools in
the 19th century,
in the middle of 19th century,
girls have been outperforming boys and
being better at sitting quietly in a
classroom.
But the last 2030 years,
the divide between rural girls and boys
is widening.
In Sweden it's a widening in other
countries too.
But in Sweden,
it's really,
really you guys,
you guys are ahead of the curve.
So congratulations on that.
Proud about this.
I'm not so proud about that.
But uh,
so,
eh,
actually why don't you talk to people in
Sweden,
they're more worried about bringing up
boys then bringing up girls nowadays
because girls,
they can be girls or they can be like
boys.
Yeah,
exactly.
The boys.
Boys,
boys.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yup.
Boys should perhaps be like more like
girls,
but they should most definitely,
it may not be like boys,
they should not play war.
They should not compete so much.
Well the competition thing is really
interesting because yeah,
the people who are,
who are hyper cooperative,
no regard competition as a positive evil
without understanding,
without,
they have no understanding whatsoever of
developmental psychology.
You know,
one of the things I really liked Sean
Piaget and you know,
one of the most intelligent things he
ever said about children's games
competitive games was that the
competition is nested inside a higher
order structure of cooperation.
So you think about a hockey game,
we can talk about that cause we're
Swedes and Canadians don't you say,
well are the hockey players competing,
are cooperating?
And the answer is what you have to do
with micro analysis.
So fundamentally they're cooperating
because they all agreed to abide by the
same set of rules.
So they occupied the same perceptual
space.
They occupied the same value space
because the value is score goals and win
the game.
So that provides the overarching frame.
So fundamentally they're cooperating now
within that,
they're competing because it's team
against team.
And even within a team,
it's individuals vying for,
uh,
let's say athletic supremacy.
But it's also more complicated than that
because a hockey isn't one game.
It's a sequence of iterated games.
And the proper strategy is if you're an
individual athlete,
is to adopt a strategy that makes you a
victor across iterated games.
And that means you have to cooperate
with your teammates.
And even with the,
with the other team,
if you're going to sustain your career
across time,
you know,
so you get honorable,
very honorable hockey players,
say like Wayne Gretzky,
who were unbelievably stellar in their
individual performance,
but also great team players and
inspirations to those who played against
them.
Perfect.
You know,
so,
so that's a really good example of well
developed masculinity and that's all
shunted off into pathological
competition by fools who are motivated
by hatred and resentment and who are
willfully blind to the complexities of
the situation.
So it's the rise.
It really is the rise of the,
like of the,
of the,
the goddess of the underworld.
It's,
it's,
it's the right way to think about it.
Uh,
and,
um,
I mean,
this is also a,
I would like to move on to discussing
and God a little bit,
but,
uh,
this is so interesting.
So I would just say one more as one more
thing because I,
if you,
uh,
if you talk to these people about how
you can reconstruct homosexuals,
I mean,
can you say,
can you send them to a straight camp?
I mean,
all of them would say that's horrible.
Okay.
But if you ask about how can you
deconstruct and then reconstruct boys
and their masculinity,
all of them are a board.
So part of the,
yeah.
So,
so it's,
it's a very inconsistent,
well,
I mean,
one of the things I complained about
last year with regards to this bill cc
Stu [inaudible] legislation in Canada,
as I said,
look,
you're instantiating a social
constructionist view of gender,
gender expression,
sexual proclivity,
all of these things into the law.
Okay.
So it's socially constructed.
So wake up.
The Conservatives who have been,
uh,
opposing homosexuality for the last
hundred years have used nothing but
social constructionist arguments.
They basically say,
well,
if it's socially constructed or an
individual choice,
which is,
by the way,
now it's stantiating into Canadian law,
then why the hell can't you just be
reeducated out of it or just drop it if
it's just an individual choice?
Well,
I tried to say you're,
you're playing with fire,
the fire that will consume you.
Yeah.
You know,
nobody,
no,
I shouldn't say nobody.
These arguments are,
these arguments are subtle and,
and they're not easy to follow.
And so,
and the problem is,
is that the consequences of producing
legislation like that unfold over
decades.
Not minutes.
So I don't know.
Did you see what happened at Wilfrid
laurier university in Canada last week,
two weeks ago?
Lindsay Shepherd?
Does that ring a male?
I listen to the conversation she
recorded.
Yeah.
So in Canada now,
three things are happening.
The first is,
despite the fact that I predicted this
and that the only reason my reputation
was ever,
let's say tarnished,
was because I predicted that this was
going to happen.
I'm still being vilified by people who,
even,
who,
who are admitting nonetheless that what
happened at Wilfrid laurier was
reprehensible.
Okay.
So that's one thing.
The second thing is the people at Lauria
who used,
who accused Lindsay of breaking the
Canadian federal and provincial laws are
being accused of misinterpreting those
laws,
which they aren't as far as I'm
concerned,
but that enables people to save face.
And third and most dreadfully a fair
number of faculty members and public
commentators are claiming that Ramboo
Kana and Pimlott and Joel,
who were the interlocutors in the
inquisition,
are the true victims.
Really?
Oh,
absolutely.
Because now,
now that people have been,
well,
first of all,
they were only standing up for trans
rights and second while,
because they'd been the target of
substantial criticism,
let's say,
like overwhelming,
punishing,
brutal criticism,
unending for weeks while they're,
that they're now victims because that's
just not fair.
And so when the president could Wilfrid
laurier university apologized to Lindsay
shepherd,
she also said,
but you know,
I also feel,
I also feel that what has happened to
the faculty members in the aftermath of
this faculty members and administrators
was also raw.
It's like,
it's that typical thing,
you know,
you see this when kids get bullied in
schools now is that the idiot,
um,
intervenors and they're,
and they're blind humanitarian impulses
bring the bully and the victim into the
principal's office to discuss it,
assuming equal,
equal causal,
what would you call it?
Responsibility on the part of the victim
and the perpetrator.
And they think that,
well,
if they just had a nice talk about it,
then,
um,
w we could,
could be settled,
not understanding at all that the bully
who's,
let's say one of these one in a hundred
Predator types,
it's just going to stand on the outside
of the school ground and wait for the
victim to come by and just pound the
hell out of them.
Because that's how bullies work.
It's like,
well,
we could settle it like reasonable
people.
And he's like,
yeah,
right.
You're so God damn naive that,
you know,
if evil ever popped out and made a face
at you,
which it likely will,
you'd be scared into post traumatic
stress disorders so fast,
you wouldn't know what hit you.
And I've seen that plenty of times in my
clinical practice.
So,
and,
um,
yeah,
these all,
all this Lindsay shepherd that you're,
you're,
uh,
you're now trans folk.
I've written about these issues in
Sweden as one of the few that's
sweetened about two snot an activist.
And,
uh,
recently I wrote about how it coincides
with the autism diagnosis.
And I think it's the same in the United
States.
And it's,
I mean,
the number of,
of,
uh,
especially young women who's never had
any doubts about their sexual,
about their gender identity,
but then they found find a likeminded
people with problems connecting socially
on the Internet,
and all of the sudden they decide that
I'm,
I'm not a woman.
I'm a man.
Yeah.
They,
most of them have a diagnosis within the
autism spectrum.
And to even say this and say that this
is something we need to investigate
is
sort of transphobic because then you're
uh,
you're questioning the motives within
the person.
So you,
you,
you're basically saying that it's not,
maybe it's not an gender identity or
feeling full kate's company.
Well,
it's like maybe it's going to be worse.
Yeah,
well it's going to get worse because
look like,
here's,
here's the logical fallacy.
Not all transsexuals have mental
illness,
but many people with mental illness are
going to be confused about their
identity,
right?
So that the pool of people confused
about their identity is extraordinarily
large.
Now,
if you produce a social fad,
which is exactly what we're doing with
gender transformation,
then everyone who's unstable is going to
gravitate very rapidly towards that fad
that's happened many times with
different forms of pathology.
So for example,
there's a book called the discovery of
the unconscious by an existentialist
psychotherapist named Henri [inaudible],
which is a great book,
Great Book,
and he tracks the cyclical recurrence of
multiple personality disorder over the
last 300 years.
So a case will be reported after
everyone forgets about it.
For a generation or two,
a case will be reported and then it
spreads like wildfire and there's
multiple personality everywhere.
And then people get skeptical about it
and the reports dropoff to zero and it
goes underground again.
And then three generations again,
somebody reports a case history and poof
up it comes again.
And so the,
there,
there are these in Carl Jung wrote about
this a lot.
There are these psychic epidemics that
occur from time to time.
And uh,
the same thing happened for example,
in the 1980s when,
um,
there was a huge outcry in the United
States in particular about,
uh,
satanic ritual abuse daycares and that,
that produced an absolute uproar for
like five years.
And you,
did you have that?
Yeah.
One of the professors here and hope solo
at Umsl University,
she wrote a book about,
and most of them men of power were in on
it in a hospital.
Right,
right,
right.
Uh,
even though it was,
I mean,
it's blatantly,
it's,
it's crazy.
Yeah.
But it was gender scientists call
because he would criticize.
It was sort of a,
okay.
She,
she,
she's actually one of the architects
behind our,
uh,
how we view men's violence against
women.
But you also wrote about this satanic
rituals that men in power had against
children.
Are they in daycare?
It was just like against children
everywhere.
Ah,
AH,
yeah.
Yeah.
Well there's a great book written in the
United States called Satan silence by a
social worker and the lawyer that
investigated that,
uh,
see tannic ritual abuse epidemic and it
makes the Salem witch hunts looked like
nothing.
I mean,
the longest prison sentences in history
were handed out for the hypothetical
perpetrators of these satanic ritual
abuse.
They dug under whole towns in places
looking for the tunnels where the,
where the sacrifices were being
performed.
I mean they invented a whole new
categories of clinical diagnosis,
late onset female sexual Predator of
whom there are zero.
Right.
That is a category that does not exist.
Unbelievable.
It sounds like a great book.
I mean like a great horror horror movie
or something like these satanic circles,
but to actually believe in it,
this is,
it's really crazy.
Yeah.
I would like to move on to,
if you have time,
I would like to move on to a question
about the religion because I'm really
interested in,
in the,
in musth and religion and,
and,
okay.
What one thing that's,
um,
I mean if,
if you call something a myth,
then it's probably not,
it's not a not alive anymore.
Perhaps.
I mean,
if,
if you're actually calling it a myth,
if you really believe in it,
you're not believing that it is a myth.
And so where we are now,
we've,
we've been studying the,
uh,
the Bible like scientifically and,
and so we'd reconstruct the,
my first subject in university was
religious studies and then you
deconstruct the Bible and you'll learn
about [inaudible] when everything was
great and everything.
But,
uh,
what would you do right now?
This,
you sort of,
you making the Bible in your Bible
lectures,
you making it accessible for people that
of our,
our age or our,
uh,
yeah.
And uh,
and people who would,
I don't think would match or wouldn't
have naturally turned to the Bible for
accounts.
You,
I think
it's completely,
it's just an indication of how surreal
the current circumstances really are.
I've been selling out the theater that I
booked in Toronto for these biblical
lectures and it's all full of,
it's almost all young men.
Like they're not that young,
you know,
they're between say 18 and 30,
something like that.
Although they're,
you know,
there's women in there and there's older
people too,
but that's the main audience.
And it's like,
well that's crazy,
right?
That's impossible that that's happening.
But it's an attempt to revive a Phi the
myth.
Yeah.
So what's your,
what's your take take on why?
Why is
I asked,
uh,
which a Dork is this?
When I interviewed him,
like there are people there were worried
about the postmodern challenge to
everything.
Like,
like deconstructing everything.
And so you,
you look for something from in,
in,
uh,
in your,
in your life and what I see you doing,
and I would like you to,
your thoughts on that.
You will bring some,
like from you're trying to bring in sort
of a firmer foothold.
Yes,
exactly.
That it's like I'm journeying to the
bottom of the ocean to rescue the father
from the,
from the fire breathing whale.
That's exactly it.
It's like the thing is,
is that when everything shakes,
then you look for the foundation.
Right,
right.
And to me,
the foundation,
the,
the thing the West got right is the
divinity of the individual.
That's right.
It's true.
And it's the myth idea.
This is partly where I had a discussion
with Sam Harris.
You know,
that was quite a difficult discussion,
um,
to discussions.
I wasn't in the best of physical health
when I had them,
unfortunately,
but that's life.
But you talk when you talk about myths,
you know,
it sounds like untruth,
but I think about it sort of as Metta
truth.
It's truer than true in some sense
because it consists of abstractions that
have guided human behavior properly for
forever insofar as human beings have
been successful.
Um,
and even in so far as we define success,
it's embedded within these mythological
ideas,
which are ideas that we act out,
essentially not ideas that we hold or,
or believe or state their ideas that we
act out.
And the idea of the divine individual is
at the center of our law,
which is why,
for example,
even if you're accused of murder,
even if there's overwhelming evidence
against you,
you still have value that the state
cannot nearly trample on.
And that's,
well,
first of all,
it's unbelievable.
That's the case because you know,
the typical barbaric society,
let's say,
which is what we're trying to reproduce
very rapidly,
is the one that assumes that if you're
accused of something,
we might as well just shoot you on the
off chance that you're guilty.
That's a way easier to,
to adopt that as a principle.
And it,
and it certainly satiates the Ma,
the blood lust of the mob much more
effectively.
The idea that we could have constructed
a worldview that put the pathetic week
malevolent,
insufficient,
vulnerable individual at the center of
the value structure is just,
it's an accomplishment who's grandier
cannot possibly be overstated.
And we,
we are the beneficiaries of that system.
We live within its protective conf
confines and we're doing everything we
possibly can to destroy it as rapidly as
possible.
So,
so if Campbell,
which it was a one of my idols growing
up and uh,
I read the hero with a thousand faces,
isn't too,
is a power of myth lectures.
Uh,
because uh,
I mean as,
as a lot of young men,
I loved Star Wars and the Lord of the
rings and then you sort of,
you read his work and you find out that,
okay,
so your look is he based his storyline
or he changed his story,
like fit more into the hero where the
monument and the,
the Hero's journey story and he said
that you need,
you need sort of a living myth or Ology
to be,
to have psychological health and
spiritual health.
You need to live with him sort of a
living mythology.
Yes,
absolutely.
Yeah.
While the mythology tells you who you
really are,
yeah.
Like you know,
you,
you really are a divine son of God.
I mean people,
people,
people and and you know,
you actually know that because you feel
guilty about not living up to your
potential.
Why in the world would you possibly feel
that?
But everyone feels that if they have any
sense at all,
unless they're narcissistic or
psychopathic,
everyone feels that burden of the
perfection to which they have to
perfection to which they have not yet
aspired nor attained.
And so,
and that's a testament to the,
to the overwhelming potential that
characterizes each individual.
And that's really what I'm trying to
point out in the biblical lectures.
There's these continual stories about
the nature of humanity and the nature of
proper being in the face of the tragedy
and malevolence of life.
And the Bible is Western.
The Western world's attempt to,
to,
to formulate that as a,
as a comprehensible set of stories and
also a set of principles for behavior.
It's,
it's the collective struggle of our,
of our imagination stretched across tens
of thousands of years,
maybe hundreds of thousands of years,
maybe even more than that.
You know,
cause some of these stories,
the story,
the story of confronting the malevolence
serpent,
like I believe that in one form or
another,
that story is if you also consider it as
something that could be acted out,
that story is at least 60 million years
old.
So because Lynn is veiled,
is anthropologist at Ucla has
demonstrated quite nicely that our tree
dwelling relatives coevolved with snakes
and our continual battle with snakes and
predatory reptiles was part of what gave
us our acute vision.
Cool.
I hate grades.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
uh,
I know,
I know that I have to ask this because
this is one of the,
I'm seeing you answered this question,
is that do you believe in God?
And I saw a youtube video with you when
you said that you didn't like that
question because you were,
you were being boxed in.
And I sort of,
I felt that because one of the things me
and my wife have been wrestled with is
we've talked a lot about this.
What do we mean when we say that we
believe in God because in Sweden to be
Swedish,
to be Christian,
it was sort of what it means today to
say that you are Swedish.
So if you said that you a Christian,
you were sort of a good family father,
you had a lot of values within that
being like a good Christian man is
today.
When you say you're a good Swedish
brand,
perhaps,
so it used to mean a lot more,
but then you had the,
the Evangelical Christians criticizing
exactly this and saying that you are
lost contact with God and then they
meant it in a much smaller sense
and so they tend to confuse the biblical
stories with lit with empirical history.
Yeah,
and it's not surprising they do that
because they're trying to defend their
faith against,
let's call it the postmodern assault or
even the modernist assault for that
matter.
I have some sympathy with their
motivations,
but the problem is is that they don't
understand that not all truth is
empirical truths in in fact the
fundamental truths as far as I can tell,
paradoxically enough our Darwinian and
they actually line up with religious
truths,
which is the point that I've been trying
to make when I discussed this.
Such issues with people like Sam Harris,
like Sam is a very,
very smart guy,
but he's,
he worships the intellect.
That's the first thing I would say.
And the second thing is that I was never
able to push him to his solution.
He'd never let me go there because you
know,
his idea is that we could rationally
order society so that the wellbeing of
people was maximized.
And you know,
he even said to,
I think it was,
I can't remember which interview it was,
but he said explicitly to the person
that he was interviewing,
that he could sit down right now and
come up with a religious system that was
much more rational,
inappropriate than any the ones that
have that have existed to date.
And I think,
well,
you know,
you're falling right into that
rationalist Utopian pitfall there.
You're just not that smart.
No one can do that.
And as soon as you do it,
you end up where the socialists,
like the radical Soviet socialists or
the Nazi utopians ended up,
we will be speaking as grown.
Combined.
Yeah.
Wallet.
Yes,
exactly.
Exactly.
The rest of the language than,
than Swedish.
Much more.
Most languages are.
Yeah.
Well that it's,
it's like,
you know,
one of the things I really liked about
Dostoyevsky is that this was a notes
from underground.
He,
he just states it very clearly.
He said,
you know,
the one thing that you cannot claim
about the history of the world and he
meets the history of being is that it's
rational and it isn't that he's
criticizing the idea that you could use
scientists,
scientific investigation and rationality
to lay out a clear representation of
objective reality.
What he's saying is that if you take the
terrible suffering and malevolence into
account as fundamental realities that
are rationalist perspective is
absolutely insufficient to tell the
story.
And that's,
there's no doubt about that.
It's just rationality just breaks down
in the face of those things.
It hits an obstacle that it cannot
contend with.
So you need something else.
And you know,
there's this great image of Christ as
Patrick Crater,
very,
very old image.
Um,
fortunately can't remember which
cathedral it's represented in,
but it's a great image and I'm having
one of them carved for me right now.
It's so,
it's a medieval image of Christ and his
face is divided into two halves.
So it's very asymmetrical.
And one half the eyes are different than
the facial expression is different than
the other.
And he's also,
he's on portrayed on the top of the Dome
and holding a book.
So the book is sacred,
right?
So that's a great idea that the book is
sacred.
That's a great idea,
man.
And the idea that the word is sacred,
but then the picture also represents
human beings as creatures with one foot
in the,
in the profane and one foot in the
sacred or one foot in the finite and one
foot in the infinite.
And I actually think that that's,
that's empirically true.
Like we are these weird creatures that
are both finite and infinite at the same
time.
And we have experiences of that,
even like deep religious experiences,
psychedelic experiences for that matter.
Um,
invoke that feeling of that invoke the
reality,
I would say,
of our connection with the infinite.
Now what that infinite is,
so let's call that God.
I mean the Christian ideas that that's
actually outside of time and space
itself,
which is quite a grant,
no ship and not the least bit
unsophisticated bar the way it's a
tremendously sophisticated idea that
something actually exists outside the
fabric of time and space that transcends
it,
that they are at the beginning and at
the end.
That's an unbelievably sophisticated
idea and I think that people can
experience that and do quite commonly,
which was why the psychedelic revolution
in the 60s was so absolutely potent.
So these sorts of things can't just be
dismissed with some rationalist sleight
of hand and,
and,
and some discussion of the idea that
Christianity Judeo Christianity,
let's say it's some like primitive set
of wish fulfillment superstitions or
some power game.
It's like you just have no depth of
scholarship whatsoever,
if that's what your criticisms are.
And also I would say when,
when uh,
when you your ass,
when you ask someone,
do you believe in God?
You.
I ask myself if I say that I don't
believe in God what within me,
when I say what is different within me
when I say that I don't believe in God
compared to a person that says that he
does believe in God.
I mean is if I feel sort of a
irrational,
I wake up or I take a glass of wine and
then suddenly I'm overwhelmed with love
for humankind,
for my fellow man or something like
that.
So if I,
if I was a person who will say that I
believed in God,
would that be something,
is it something qualitatively different
between the person,
between me compared to that person?
You understand what I'm [inaudible]
I haven't quite got that yet.
Like what is the experience of believing
in God and how is that qualitatively
qualitatively different from a person
who says that he doesn't?
Oh yes.
I see what you mean.
While that is,
that is part of the question.
The question is here while the,
when someone says,
do you believe in God?
There's three parts to that question.
The first question is who is the you to
which they are referring?
And that turns out to not be a simple
question.
I mean Neesha did a very good job of
taking apart the idea of the eye,
you know,
cause he was,
he was critiquing descartes' I think
therefore I am.
And and so the,
the first question is,
well who is the you to which you are
referring.
The second is what do you mean by
belief?
The third is what do you mean by God?
It's like you can't just leap to the
assumption that the person asking the
question and the person answering the
question have the same views on those.
And I think that that's,
that's part of the reason why I don't
like the question.
You know,
like I said,
well I act as if I believe in God.
And so I would say that's the more,
that's the most fundamental
manifestation of faith.
But I could also say I believe and don't
believe in God.
And you think,
well you can't,
you can't think both of those things at
the same time.
It's like,
well yeah,
that's what you think.
It's,
it's,
it's in,
when you were asking something that
complicated,
then there's absolutely no reason to so
that you can't have paradoxical
responses to it.
So you could,
you could even say maybe that the
injunction in the old testament is
something like you should believe and
not believe in God cause it's very
complicated.
It's not,
it's not by any means.
A simple a question.
I know,
I don't remember his name though,
but I think perhaps it was a burger or
something like that.
He said that myth is about reconciling
contradictions within the union.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's it.
That's exactly,
well that's what a successful myth does.
And part of the reason that these
etiologies that we'd be discussing,
like feminism have so much power is
because they actually draw their motive
force from an underlying religious
substrate.
But they only tell half the story.
That's what an ideology is.
So when the feminists say culture is the
tyrannical patriarch,
it's like,
yeah,
that's true.
But it's also the benevolent wise king.
So like,
well then they say,
well I can't be one and the other at the
same time.
And the answer is,
well,
it's a multidimensional phenomena that
you're encapsulating within a single
category.
It can contain contradictions.
In fact,
it does because society obviously
constraints and and kills you.
Even like you dye into your neural
configuration cause that when you're
first born you have more neural
connections than you will ever in your
life.
And most of them die.
And so,
so you dye into your four year old self
and then between the ages of 16 and 20
you dye into your adult self.
And so the idea that that the society
that you're in is a terrible tyrant.
The shapes you by death is exactly true.
But Oh,
by the same token,
it's also almost everything that
ennobles you and enables you to function
in the world.
And so the critic,
critics of the Patriarchy say tyranny,
tyranny,
tyranny.
And it's like,
yeah,
tyranny,
but not only tyranny.
And they say evil man,
evil man.
It's like,
yeah,
obviously,
but not only evil men.
Not only that,
and that's why a genuine mythologies,
and I would put Freudian psychoanalysis
in that category because Freud had a
very balanced view of the nature of
being
talks about both parts of the paradox at
the same time.
You know,
it's the dragon and the gold.
It's the terrible devouring mother and
the,
and the Virgin Mary.
It's the tyrant and the wise king.
It's Christ and Satan.
It's all of those paradoxes stacked on
top of one another.
And then the story about how you go
about dealing with them.
That's a true religious myth.
Yeah.
And an ideology just takes a part of
that and says,
this is the whole,
right.
I mean,
in early Christianity,
there was a large battle between many
keystrokes and,
uh,
the,
um,
gnostics and,
uh,
what would turn out to be the Catholic
Church and the,
the mainstream church.
And they said that the evil evil was
like the,
the world we live in is created by this
other force,
the demiurge so that the,
they had a very split vision of,
of,
of good and evil.
But what you're saying,
what you were saying about these
ideologies is that basically it's
perhaps it's a new formal theological
battle between glowsticks and uh,
and people that say that this is,
we have both sides,
both sides.
That's a perfectly reasonable way of
looking at it,
you know,
and like young tended towards manic.
He as a,
to some degree because he was so struck
by say the evils of,
of Nazi-ism and he had a hard time with
the idea that evil was only the absence
of good.
But,
and I've thought about that a lot
because I'm a great admirer of yoga.
You criticize anything he said at your
peril,
you know,
because he was a great genius.
But I think that,
I think the Manichaean view is wrong.
I think that what evil is,
is the absence of good and then it takes
on its own life.
I think it's,
I mean it's called,
I've written about this in my new book
quite extensively because I have a book
coming out in January called 12 rules
for life,
an antidote to chaos.
And I'd be trying to take those ideas
apart and to grapple with the well with
the fact that human beings hate
themselves because they're vulnerable
and malevolent,
which,
which is original sin,
you know,
which is something I'm a great believer
in.
Um,
okay.
I think it's an unbelievably
sophisticated way of looking at the
world.
You know,
that there's something
that there was something damaged in the
fabric of being itself.
I believe that to be the case.
I think we experienced that as human
beings and that our ethical obligation
is to rectify that and to determine how
to rectify that,
to overcome the vulnerability and
malevolence that like the terror of
vulnerability and the subjection to
malevolence that characterizes our day
to day existence.
That's our,
that's our primary mode of proper being
in the world.
That seems to me to be correct.
So,
and again,
that's the sort of thing that I've been
trying to tell.
Well those who will listen,
let's say,
but it's so far,
it's mostly been young men who are dying
for this message.
Like they're,
they're dying for it.
You know,
it's really copies.
I go to these talks now,
you know,
public talks and where I speak about
responsibility and truth.
And like after the talks there are like
crowds of mostly young men who line up
and say,
you know,
I was nihilistic.
I was desperate,
I was suicidal,
I was malevolent and resentful and like
going bad places.
And I've started to what you've been
saying about myth and it's like brought
me out of that horrible hold.
And that's just one person after another
says the same thing.
You know,
it's so,
and I've had thousands of letters like
that and maybe tens of thousands now,
I can't even begin to keep up with them.
And well,
thank God for that.
You know,
personally or turning to you for,
uh,
for this,
counselor for guidance.
Well,
you know,
I read this paper along time ago called
relations between the ego and the
unconscious,
which is one of umes.
Maybe it's his most stellar work.
And,
and it's not a paper you can understand
unless you know what it's about.
And cause he talked about the danger of
ego inflation.
That's so,
so imagine that you're dealing with
archetipal ideas and that you can fall
prey to the temptation to assume,
because you started to understand the
ideas and maybe communicate about them
that they are somehow yours.
And then what happens is,
is that can produce a mess cyanic
inflation.
And so that would characterize someone
like Hitler for example.
Um,
and that's,
it's tantamount to a form of mental
illness because what happens is that you
take on the grandeur of the mythological
ideas and the archetypal ideas and the
power of those ideas as if they were
your own creations.
Well,
that's a very bad idea.
And so I read,
I read those,
that paper after I had a dream where I
was blown by a wind into the,
the top of a cathedral.
I was in the chandelier in this huge
cathedral,
like say 20 times bigger than Saint
Peter's.
You could hardly even see the walls.
And I was put up in this at the center
of this cathedral,
right way above the ground.
And then I got down somehow because I
didn't want to be there.
And then the wind dissolve me.
And blew me back there and I woke up and
I thought,
oh my God,
that's a,
that's a crazy dream.
Uh,
the dream put me at the center of the
cross at the center of being,
and I thought,
what the hell?
That's,
what am I supposed to make of a dream
like that?
It's like,
it's,
it's delusional,
let's say orders on delusional.
And it was a very powerful dream.
Like I can still,
I can still see it.
And I read the relations between the ego
and the unconscious at that time and
started to understand what was happening
is that I was starting to understand
what these archetypal ideas meant.
That the place of the individual is
actually at the crucifix,
at the Center of reality.
The point of maximal suffering and the
acceptance of that.
That's all true,
but it's not true of me.
Right.
Everybody is a center of the cosmos.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and so you have to detach yourself as
carefully as you can from the archetypal
ideas themselves because otherwise you
end up identifying with them personally
or people identify you with them and
that that's,
that's the ultimate,
what would you call it,
the ultimate temptation of pride.
And so,
no,
that's,
so I'm,
I try to be very careful of that.
I'm very cognizant of that and,
and to keep a good eye on my,
yeah,
it's a,
you,
it's like these,
uh,
you know,
when the emperors in the Roman Empire,
when they wrote in their trials,
they had a slave behind them telling
them a mental moray.
Right.
Exactly.
I always,
I,
I really liked that idea and I liked the
idea of reminding yourself about,
okay,
death to keep humble,
keep yourself humble.
It sounds a little
well,
death and sin because the other thing
that you have to,
and maybe this is the advantage that the
Catholics have over the Protestants,
is that the Catholics at least put their
sins in front of them constantly,
which is very analogous to what you just
described.
Because it,
and I,
you know,
I try to be very,
very careful about paying attention to
all the things that I'm doing wrong.
And I have people,
my family and friends who are helping me
do that.
And,
and cause it's a strange to call it a
strange situation to be in is just
barely scraping the surface.
Yeah.
Oh,
I would like to ask you,
uh,
one,
at least one more.
I mean,
I,
I could,
uh,
ask you,
talk to you for four hours,
but I know you are a busy man.
Yeah.
I should,
let's do one more question.
We can always talk again.
You know,
so yeah.
The Church of Sweden,
uh,
it's our old a state church.
It,
it's,
it's contemplating replacing the
gendered pronouns,
other guide for Church services and
they've already starting to replace the
Lord.
And he and him with God in a lot of
places are more inclusive.
Yeah.
And uh,
the people who,
while the people who were running the
church have absolutely no idea about
what any of its doctrines meet.
Yeah.
It's as simple as that.
Like,
I mean there is insistence in
Christianity on the Androgyny of Christ
and there are elements of God that have
been portrayed as feminine like Sophia,
which is wisdom,
but you don't mess with those things.
You don't rewrite them like that.
Not Not without having your soul tremble
and quake at your presumption
and the idea that you can just casually
rewrite these ancient texts.
It's like these people who rewrite
fairytales so that they're more in
keeping with modern sensibility.
It's like their soul unbelievably
intellectually narcissistic,
that while it's,
it's positively say titanic in its,
in its overreach and I mean that in the
most technical sense,
it's the,
it's they say titanic temptation of the
untrammeled and unbound intellect.
It's exactly what Milton warned against
in paradise lost.
So it's a complete catastrophe.
All it will do is speed the demolition
of the church.
So,
and I think that's what it's aimed at
actually because of course the church is
just a patriarchal construct anyways and
it's oppressive and so oppressed women
forever,
despite its assistant insistence that
men and women were both made in the
image of God.
Oh,
churches pretty much do when it comes to
these issues.
It's very,
it's more political than a lot of
politicians.
Yes.
Well that's it.
It's that when the church becomes
political,
it's done.
Yeah.
So I mean,
as I said,
I have a,
I think I've got the most out of this
interview.
It was really,
really informative and really nice
talking to you,
talking to you too.
And you know,
maybe we can do this again in January if
you want to.
One of the things I could do is send you
a galley copy of my book if you want it
to.
Great.
Because I would really like to review it
and then we could perhaps making the,
I could ask you a couple of followup
questions to your book or something like
that.
Yeah,
that'd be good because we could get
deeper into some of the issues that we
discussed.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I'll publish this on Saturday,
this interview,
and I'll send you the recording.
Okay?
Yeah.
Thank you,
kate.
That's great.
Thank you.
All right.
You bet on her.
Nice to meet you.
Bye.