On Tuesday,
obviously I wasn't here.
And so I prepared that combination
slideshow,
powerpoint thing that took me like 12
hours to make it.
But I'm wondering something,
I mean I have quite a bit of tape
material and I'm going to,
obviously I'd be taking this courses and
I was wondering,
one of the advantages of doing it that
way was that I could sink the material,
like the slide material with the lecture
much more precisely.
You know,
when you can imagine that if I,
once I got good at that,
I could put a lot more material into the
lectures and I could edit them very
carefully.
So then I'm wondering like what did you
think of that use of technology compared
to a spontaneous lecture?
What was your attitude towards that?
I think that,
well we could present more,
less responsive and so I prefer the 11
pictures watching the tapes.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
no,
I understand.
I mean there is some mute.
The thing about lecture is that it's a
conversation.
If it's a good lecture right there
because the lecturers hypothetically
paying attention to the audience.
And so then it's,
it's,
it's more dynamic.
But you know what if suffers a bit cause
it's not as structured.
That's the thing.
Anybody else?
Just we did it.
Yup.
Pretty good substitute.
Like I'll be a say prefer an in person
lecture.
But given the circumstance I thought it
was definitely a good substitute,
the information.
So I was wondering like what would
happen,
do you think if I prepared like a really
tightly edited half hour presentation
like that and then followed it up with a
looser lecture,
do you think that,
would that be a reasonable combination
of the two things?
Because that way I could more,
you know,
I can be much more certain that I
covered a wide range of material,
you know,
in depth and then hopefully the lecture
could be maybe a little looser and a bit
more fun.
So what do you,
do you think that would be a reasonable
thing to try?
So any,
anybody up?
Yup.
Um,
yeah,
you've got to be a really good idea,
especially because during the lecture
section,
the chance to sort of ask some more
questions,
whereas,
uh,
you know correctly,
there's a lot of time.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
I was thinking that maybe that would
allow me to increase the degree to which
it was interactive,
so.
Okay.
Did anybody particularly object to that
mode of presentation?
I mean,
I know you wouldn't have to be in the
lecture hall for it,
obviously.
That's one thing,
right?
You could look,
you could watch it at home.
I think there's some danger in just
having the lecture material online.
So you're at home because,
well,
the Internet is full of things you can
watch,
you know,
so there's gotta be some utility
bringing people together by anybody else
have any other comments?
Okay.
All right.
So today we're going to talk about
conscientiousness and I'm going to stick
closer to my notes in some parts because
a lot of this stuff I'm going to tell
you about is really only stuff that I've
learned in the last year or so.
And so I've known,
I've known,
absolutely familiar with it yet.
Uh,
there's actually been a fair bit of
progress,
made an understanding conscientiousness
and in very surprising ways.
Some of the stuff that I'm going to talk
to you about today really shocked me
when I learned it.
Um,
you'll see,
I mean,
I've been in interested in belief
systems and new technology for a long
time and um,
the role that I'd never really
understood the role that
conscientiousness plays in that.
So,
so particularly,
but it's really starting to come
together.
So not only we're going to talk about
conscientiousness today,
we're going to talk about,
I think some of the pathologies that are
associated with conscientiousness,
both at the individual level and at the
social level.
Now it's a,
it's a tricky topic because act what
we've discussed this before to some
degree,
you know,
that intelligence and conscientiousness
are the best predictors of life success,
right?
At least in managerial administrative,
um,
professions and in academia and also in
professions like the law,
you know.
Um,
so conscientiousness in many ways seems
to be a very good trait.
I don't think that you can have a
civilized society without
Wifi,
without it,
without conscientiousness being at the
base of it in some sense because
conscientious people do what they say
they're going to do.
They're industrious,
they keep things in order.
Um,
a lot of that's the basis for the kind
of interpersonal trust that's necessary
to set up complex trading systems.
And so,
and as an individual trait,
as I said,
if you're conscientious,
not only do you do better in life,
but by the time you're middle aged or
so,
um,
your life quality seems to be much
higher.
So you know,
we'll be in conscientious seems to be a
good longterm,
medium to long term strategy.
So that all sounds pretty positive.
But then one of the things that multiple
multitude of labs have been looking at
over the last few years,
including mine,
is what happens if conscientiousness is
taken too far and it kind of looks,
this is work that hasn't been published
yet,
but it's based on some of the new
personality models that I'd been looking
at that are,
that have been derived using a different
technique,
a semantic analysis technique instead of
factor analysis.
And what appears to be the case is that
any of the traits become pathological if
you push them too far.
So,
so whatever virtue is,
it can't be identified with a particular
trait.
I mean,
I don't know what virtue would be from a
big five perspective,
but it doesn't look like you could
localize it specifically.
Maybe it's something like the
appropriate situational balance of the
temperaments or one of the things I've
been thinking is that maybe as you
mature,
your,
your width of temperament increases,
you know,
that maybe your,
your baseline for a conscientiousness is
sort of average.
But as you mature,
your ability to be very conscientious
when it's necessary and your ability to
not be conscientious when it's necessary
are more thoroughly developed,
a differentiated so that you can match
your behavior more particular to the
demands of given situations.
Maybe that's something like the
development of wisdom.
But anyways,
it turns out,
it turns out that it appears that
conscientiousness can take a very
vicious turn if it's pushed beyond a
certain point.
And it also appears that perhaps the
point at which conscientiousness is
really positively associated with the
success of individuals and maybe the
success of nations is also relatively
close to the point where if you push it
any farther,
it starts to kick back very badly and
things go downhill.
And so that's the sort of thing that
we're going to discuss today.
So,
um,
well put it in its context first.
You remember the highest order
personality traits or plasticity and
stability in plasticity is made up of
extraversion and openness.
Those are good predictors of longterm
creative achievement.
And then there's stability and stability
is associated with conscientiousness,
emotional stability and agreeableness.
And we're going to concentrate on
conscientiousness today,
which is obviously that's industrious in
orderliness at the big five aspects
scale level.
Now,
um,
when we derived the big five aspect
scale sold,
broke the big five down to 10,
it wasn't clear to begin with what the
aspects we're going to be useful for.
Because when you do statistical analysis
like that,
you're just pulling out a semantic
structure and there isn't really any
necessity that those additional
differentiation so that you make are
going to have practical utility.
But it's turned out that the distinction
between Oh,
orderliness and industriousness is
extremely useful.
So one of the things we know for
example,
is that orderly people tend to be more
conservative.
So we know that conservative people tend
to be more conscientious,
but it seems to load specifically an
orderliness.
Now you might say,
well,
that's not so surprising to associate
the right wing with orderliness.
But it is surprising because we didn't
know that orderliness was a subset of
conscientiousness.
And so people have been trying since the
end of World War II to slop the idea of
the authoritarian personality into
standard personality models.
And that's been extremely difficult to
do.
You know?
And so,
so one hypothesis is being that
conservative people because they're more
zen,
a phobic,
and they're more,
you know,
they're more anti-immigration and there
and they're more anti gay rights and
that sort of thing.
And one,
one primary theories being that that's
because they're more afraid,
you know,
there.
But the problem is,
is that conservatism isn't associated
with neuroticism to any degree at all.
And when it is,
it seems to be reverse.
It seems that the conservatives are less
plagued by neuroticism than liberals are
say so.
You mean you could make the hypothesis
that the conservatives are so
conservative that they're covering up
their fear to such a degree that it
actually reverse it.
But you know,
really you gotta you gotta be Pretty
Damn convinced of your theory to hold on
to it when the data seemed to indicate
that the opposite,
the actual opposite is true.
And so,
oh well here,
here's some items you guys can take a
look at this.
So this is how you would distinguish
orderliness from industriousness.
Um,
I wouldn't worry about the slides.
Okay.
Because I'm going to,
I'm going to cut them in.
Okay.
So anyways,
so if you're ordering,
you don't leave your belongings around.
Obviously you like order.
While there's a surprise,
you keep things tidy,
you follow a schedule,
so you order your time.
Um,
that's definitely a good predictor of
productivity.
You're bothered by this and people and
bothered is an interesting word,
right?
Cause if you're orderly and you're
somewhere messy and it bothers you,
you might think,
well exactly what it is that you're
experiencing when you're bothered.
You know,
I know if I go to a place that's in real
disarray,
it looks like people have been failing
to live up to their responsibility.
Say it,
it's a visceral sensation.
I really don't like it.
I'm very strongly compelled to put
things in order,
you know,
and it,
it,
but,
but it's obviously a negative emotion,
but it's not the kind of negative
emotion that seems to load on
neuroticism.
So it doesn't seem to be fear or anxiety
or emotional pain or frustration or
disappointment or any of those things.
So then you might ask,
well,
you know,
what's left bothered,
wants everything to be just right.
Um,
dislikes,
routine,
opposite,
obviously orderly.
People like routine.
They see that rules are observed and
they want every detail taken care of.
While you can see that,
in some ways,
orderliness is the soul of bureaucracy,
right?
Because everything in its place and a
place for everything is basically the
sort of hallmark of an orderly person.
Well in my clinical practice,
I've certainly observed that people who
are really disorderly and really high in
neuroticism,
they just,
they're just never improve.
You know,
they're because they're their fear and
their anxiety sort of paralyze them into
an immobility.
And the fact that they're low in
conscientiousness are low in orderliness
means they will never do anything and
then disorder grows round and then that
exacerbates their anxiety and their
theorists like it's a real catastrophe.
So,
and then on theirs,
so that's where the conservatives are
different.
They're more orderly that liberals are
industriousness.
Liberals and conservatives seem to be
about the same.
So industrious person carries out their
plans.
They don't waste time,
they don't find it difficult to get down
to work.
They don't miss things up.
They finish what they start,
they put their mind on the task at hand
to get things done quickly.
So this is an efficiency element to it.
Uh,
they don't postpone decisions and they
aren't easily distracted.
And so industrious people tend not to
procrastinate.
And procrastination actually seems to be
something like low industriousness and
high neuroticism.
So I know it's a very pernicious
phenomenon.
And procrastination can really drive
people.
Start branding now
it's reversed.
Yeah.
So the ones that don't make sense or
every post,
so,
so now it isn't exactly obvious why
orderliness and industriousness are
related so tightly or why there's
somewhat differentiable,
but it turns out that that is the case
statistically.
Now I thought a lot about why
orderliness and industriousness really
is a mystery.
We started to associate ordering with
sensitivity to discussed,
and I'm going to elaborate on that quite
a bit.
Industriousness,
we haven't been able to get a handle on
at all.
And I,
I,
and so conscientiousness is somewhat of
a mystery because up until maybe a year
ago or two years ago,
even though it was a really good
predictor of longterm life success and
happiness,
um,
we didn't have any models for it because
it just came out of this statistical
analysis of,
of the semantic structure language.
Right?
So it was atheoretical.
So there's no theoretical model.
What,
why are people conscientious?
Well,
we have no idea.
There's no neuropsychological model.
We have no idea what part of the brain
is,
is associated with conscientiousness.
And weirdly enough,
the sorts of things that are associated
with conscientiousness are very close to
what theorists have identified as the
function of the dorsolateral prefrontal
cortex say,
which is the part of the brain that's
the deals with the highest order of
abstractions and the whole prefrontal
cortex.
People have associated with the ability
to plan and the ability to inhibit
impulses and the ability to think in the
longterm.
And that all sounds like
conscientiousness,
but if you assess people's dorsal
lateral prefrontal function with tests,
cognitive tests that she,
that are characterized by activation,
when when people are doing those tests,
their prefrontal Cortex is activated in
say functional Mri.
The correlation between the prefrontal
ability assessed cognitively and
conscientiousness itself is zero.
So it's really weird because this also
means to me that most theories of
prefrontal function or wrong,
so you can think about it this way,
is that in order to,
the prefrontal cortex does seem to be
good at manipulating abstractions.
But by definition an abstraction is
something that's obstructed from the
real world,
right?
It's no longer connected to the real
world.
And so when you're thinking about your
future,
say you've pulled abstract
representations of the world up into
this space where you're,
where you're doing your thinking and
it's a disembodied space,
obviously you're not acting it out.
And so you have to be able to dissociate
the abstractions from the real world in
order to manipulate the abstractions,
which is thinking without acting them
out.
But the thing about conscientious people
isn't that they make plants so much,
it's that if they make a plan,
then they do it.
And so that means that there's this
ability to take the abstraction,
you know,
while I promise to do x,
okay,
well that means you've been able to
think up acts.
But the next question is,
if you promise to do it,
will you do it?
And the answer to that could easily be
no and that it is the answer generally
if you're not conscientious.
But that doesn't seem to be associated
with prefrontal function at all.
And you see these weird dissociations in
a lot of clinical cases.
So borderline people with borderline
personality disorder,
a good example because they're very
unconscientious and very high in
neuroticism.
And they're often very smart.
And so there are these people,
you talk to them,
you know,
and,
and they're perfectly capable of
identifying what their problems are and
even telling you what the causal
pathways and even telling you about what
they should do in the future.
But they absolutely will not do it.
So the ability to think and the,
and the willingness to put those
thoughts into operations seem to be set
completely separable phenomenon.
And,
and we don't know much about the system
that motivates people to put their plans
into action or to keep a promise or to
not procrastinate.
We don't know what that's associated
with.
So there's no psychological model.
There's no pharmacological model.
We don't know how to increase
conscientiousness.
You know,
you might think that when you give kids
with attention deficit disorder,
um,
Ritalin,
for example,
that that might make them more
conscientious,
but,
well,
first there's no evidence for that
because Ritalin is an amphetamine and
that would make them more extroverted,
generally speaking,
because it's a dopaminergic agent.
And plus there's no evidence whatsoever
that if you follow up people who have
adhd who were on Ritalin in the long
run,
that the Ritalin does them any good
whatsoever.
In fact,
there's the evidence is actually the
reverse is that the longterm
consequences of Ritalin user negative
rather than positive.
So now it's worse in our lab,
like we've done all sorts of things to
try to measure conscientiousness.
So one of the things we did for example,
because we thought of it as kind of
persistence,
you know,
maybe like conscientious people will
persist at boring tasks longer than non
conscientious people.
Sounds reasonable.
Right?
Because you know it,
it sounds like you're kind of grabbing
yourself at saying focus on this and
don't be distracted.
It has nothing to do with whether you're
interested in it.
So we had people do things like we made
lines and lines of ends and amps and use
and we had people count the use,
which is pretty boring,
you know.
And it's also difficult because ends and
ams and use look a lot the same.
And all that we found was that
intelligence predicted it smarter people
could do it more accurately and faster,
right?
No correlation whatsoever with
conscientiousness.
We couldn't get a correlation with any
prefrontal tests,
no Iq tests.
And then we test use tests that were
associated with the orbital frontal
Cortex,
which is sort of lower and a little bit
more hooked into the limbic system.
And we couldn't find any correlation
between conscientiousness and
performance on those tests either.
We looked at like 200 different
performance measures and conscientious
did conscientiousness didn't predict any
of them.
We can't get people who are
conscientious to do something better in
the lab and people who aren't
conscientious.
And it's,
it's a real puzzle because,
you know,
because it's such an important predictor
of things like longterm life success and
performance and political,
the political affiliation,
you'd think that you'd be able to
discriminate between people who are
conscientious and people who aren't
conscientious the lab.
Um,
but I know that,
that the chair of our department has
recently used some attentional tasks to
and showed a differentiation between
conscientious people and hit
unconscientious people.
And so I'm hoping that I'm going to
follow up with her to find out exactly
what that is.
But I mean it's been deadly different.
Cool.
So,
so you know,
Robert's the references for all this or
at the end of the slides by the way,
so I'm,
I'm not going to go through the complete
references,
but research a researcher named Roberts
has defined conscientiousness is the
tendency to be planful organized task
and goal oriented,
self control and to delay gratification
and to follow the norms and rules.
So we looked at things too,
like future discounting,
you know,
so future discounting would be,
can play a future discounting game.
So I'll do that with you very quickly.
So I'm going to point at you and ask you
a question so you can,
it's not a trick by the way,
so you don't have to worry about your
answers.
So I might say,
okay,
here's the deal.
I can give you $10 today or I can give
you $15 in a month.
What would you take?
Okay,
good.
so fine.
I give you $50 today or $50 in a year.
15 today,
15 today.
Okay,
I'll give you $5 today or $50 a year.
so now imagine that I played that game
with one of you a hundred times,
say or 200 times using different
amounts,
small and big over different timeframes.
And what you can calculate is how much
people value the present compared to the
future.
Now you should value the present a bit
more than the future,
right?
Why?
That's right.
The future is uncertain,
so,
so you have to discount it.
So because you know,
there's some probability that it isn't
just going to occur,
like maybe something will happen or
maybe I'll,
I won't be here.
And then the farther out you go into the
future,
the more you have to discount it because
it becomes really unpredictable.
And you know,
my experience,
and I don't really know of any data to
support this,
but my experience has been that it's,
it's pretty hard to plan in your life.
It's pretty hard to plan more than three
to five years into the future because,
because there's so many variables that
start to the effect of the variables
that you're not accounting for.
Start to,
it starts to become exponential as you
move out into the future.
So you should discount the future
because the present is more certain.
Plus if you have $5 now,
you can do something with it right now
instead of waiting for two years to get
your 50 and so that might be useful.
But we thought that maybe conscientious
people would discount the future less
than unconscientious people.
Right.
It sounds like they would because it's
sort of like delay of gratification.
Can you wait for your $50 and we found
that there was no correlation whatsoever
with conscientiousness.
If people were extroverted or if you
made them happy,
then they just counted the future.
And w w the way we interpreted that was
that,
well if things are going well now you
might as well capitalize on,
you know,
if,
because if all the signals that are
coming towards you say,
well this is a good time,
why not take the resources now and use
them?
So anyways,
that's,
that's just an example of how tricky
this is.
You,
you will notice if you know anything
about prefrontal cortical function
theories that all of these descriptions,
planful,
organized,
task oriented and so on,
have been attributed to the prefrontal
cortex butter that,
that uh,
that research haven't found any evidence
for that even though it's the prime
theory of prefrontal function.
Okay.
So what,
what is conscientiousness associated
with?
Well,
denise and Heller have showed that if
you measure it over any reasonable
amount of time,
it's associated with life satisfaction
and happiness.
Now you might want to ask yourself,
well,
what is life satisfaction or happiness?
Which is a really good question,
especially if you measured with the
questionnaire because we've already
established that if you measure with a
questionnaire or something like emotion
or personality,
you get the Big Five.
So it's not obvious that you can derive
something like a life satisfaction or
happiness questionnaire and have it
measured something separate from the big
five.
And so what happens is that most people
who report that they're satisfied with
life or happy are high in extroversion.
They're happy and low in neuroticism.
They're not unhappy.
So that eats up a big chunk of the
various and unsurprisingly,
right?
And so that sort of puts whether you're
happy or satisfied with your life firmly
in the domain of temperament,
but it does turn out the
conscientiousness also influences that,
especially over longer spans of time.
So hard work pays off.
But it's tricky too because you also
have to understand that hard work only
pays off in a society that's very
stable.
And so maybe that's part of their,
the reason for the association between
industriousness and orderliness,
right?
Because maybe you work really hard to
gather up your little pile of,
of,
uh,
what would you call acquisitions and
assets,
which you need obviously.
And then the whole society collapses and
you know,
the thugs come in and steal it all.
It's like,
are you stupid?
Because you should have just spent all
that money before the thugs could steal
it.
And that's obviously the case in very
many human societies.
It's dangerous to be industrious because
you'll gather up property that's
valuable and then that just makes you a
target.
So it might be that industriousness
doesn't pay off without order.
Something like that.
So,
and I've also wondered too,
it's like,
well,
I'll talk to you about that a little bit
later.
Okay.
Now recently a researcher face guard,
also working with Roberts,
was looking at the emotions that might
be associated with conscientiousness.
And this is rather a new approach
because we kind of thought that we had
the emotions tied up already in the big
five,
right?
There were the positive emotions and
they loaded on extroversion.
That's nice and simple.
And there were the negative emotions and
they loaded gun neuroticism and that's
that.
But it turns out that that's not that,
that there are emotions that fall
outside of the rubric,
simply negative neuroticism and simply
positive extroversion.
And they seem to be what people have
often called,
like social emotions.
And so those would be guilt and shame.
Those are two of them because like you
feel guilty maybe when you haven't lived
up to an obligation.
And so an obligation is usually
something that occurs because it's,
you're embedded in the social context
and you feel ashamed.
That distinction between guilt and shame
is a tricky one.
You feel guilt for yourself and shame in
front of other people.
Something like that.
You know,
guilt won't necessarily make you turn
red,
but shame will.
And so there's,
you know,
there's actual behavioral displays that
are associated with these emotions.
It turns out that conscientiousness is
associated with guilt.
Proneness but not the experience of
guilt.
That's a tricky thing.
So let's say you're prone to guilt.
Well that'll make you conscientious and
if you're conscientious and now if you
do the things you're supposed to do,
then you don't have to feel guilt.
So you can see why that would be rather
tricky to discover.
So guilt seems to be associated with
conscientiousness and although this
hasn't been assessed yet,
we think that it's,
it may be particularly associated with
industriousness rather than ordering
this.
And the reason I'm pausing that,
and it's not demonstrated yet.
The reason I'm positing that is because
we know that orderliness is associated
with something else.
It's associated with sensitivity to
discussed and discussed as a whole
different emotion than fear or,
or pain,
let's say.
And it's tricky because,
you know,
think of a horror movie.
Okay,
so what exactly constitutes horror?
Well,
there's the,
um,
what's that movie called?
The witches of Blair witch project.
Have you seen the Blair witch project?
Okay.
The Blair witch project is all fear.
Nothing ever happens in the movie.
It's just this horrible sense that
something awful is going to happen at
any moment.
Pure fear.
And so that's a horror movie.
But then there's the other kind of
horror movies where people get like
sought up with chainsaws.
And so then you think,
well those,
those both come under the horror rubric.
But the one is almost pure fear.
And then the other is what is it
exactly?
Is it fear and disgust?
So it looks like the splatter film,
so to speak,
capitalize on disgust and horror.
And the,
the,
the sense of horror is partly fear.
But also partly discussed.
And so does disgust.
Sensitivity system looks very old,
evolutionarily,
although it looks particularly well
developed in human beings because it's
not that obvious.
It's not that obvious that animals show
discuss the same way human beings do.
I mean,
think about dogs,
right?
Jesus,
those things,
they're,
they're like,
everything smells good to a dog,
you know,
and they'll eat virtually anything too.
But humans aren't like that at all.
We're very picky.
Maybe because we're on numerous,
I don't exactly know.
We're very picky and you know,
there's also specific facial expressions
that are associated with disgust.
You know,
they're like that me,
it's partly an expulsion facial
expression.
You're closing your eyes so you don't
have to see it.
You're closing your nose so you don't
have to smell it.
It's like repulsion and re repugnant or
associated with disgust sensitivity.
So,
so here's the things that,
yes.
Do you have any questions?
Yeah.
Um,
so people that have eating disorders,
do you think that are,
because you said orderliness,
you don't think that's related to deal
with as much as the
are high guys.
Do you think that they have any sort of,
because of sensitivity to discuss where,
because of the video where I feel
fields?
No,
I think it's,
my experience has been,
they're pretty sensitive to discuss.
And part of that seems to be,
this is this constellation that I want
to talk about.
So being sensitive to discuss it seems
to go along with a lot of other things
like black and white moral thinking.
It's like things are either good or
they're not.
And there's no gray area in between him.
And I like anorexics are like that too
to a great degree.
Like it's black or white,
there's no gray at all.
And um,
they're also very judgmental people who
are orderly.
And I think the black and white thinking
goes along with the,
with the,
with the judgment.
It's like while you read they're doing
well or you're not,
there isn't,
there's no mucking about in the middle.
And so they're hard on themselves,
orderly people,
but they're also hard on other people.
And one of the things we know for
example,
is that if you're conscientious,
although it predicts workplace success
and that sort of thing and general
wellbeing,
if you're conscientious and you become
unemployed,
you're in real trouble.
Because you know,
maybe because you're conservative in
your fundamental orientation,
you think all those people without jobs,
they're just fundamentally useless.
You know,
if they just tried harder,
they would get to where they're going,
which of course has some truth to it,
but not completely.
So then you fall into that category and
well then you're kind of,
they say hoist with your own Fitara,
right?
Because now you're among the,
the great unwashed and because your
disgust sensitive,
that's not going to make you very happy.
So conscientious people suffer a lot
when things happened to them that are
bad because they also assume because
they seem to be very fond of willpower,
they also assume that well,
with just enough effort and with just
enough willpower,
you can get yourself out of out of
anything.
And you know,
that's sort of true.
If you put a lot of effort into
something,
the probability that you'll do well
increases.
But that isn't the same as if you try
hard enough,
you can get out of anything.
Right?
You don't,
you know what I need and the is they're
really matters.
So,
um,
cause there's lots of things that hard
work isn't going to get you up and
sometimes persisting and per separating
if something is actually the wrong thing
to do rather than the right thing to do.
So it's very tricky.
So the orderly types are conservative.
To make you conservative,
you have to be high in order to be this
and low in openness,
especially the more creative element of
openness say rather than the intellect
element.
So that's interesting too because of
course people tend to think that their
political preferences established by the
rationality,
you know,
I'm a liberal because being a liberal is
the right way to be.
And here's a bunch of reasons why that's
the way to be.
And you know,
I've thought that through and that's why
I'm a liberal.
It's like turns out that's probably
completely wrong or at least mostly
wrong.
You have your temperament and your
temperament makes you intrinsically
value certain things.
And then because you intrinsically
valued them,
the arguments about why those things are
good or attractive to you.
And then you remember those arguments.
And so liberals for example,
are much more concerned with harm and
care than conservatives are.
And conservatives are more concerned
about things like purity.
And so,
and those are basic,
you know,
those are basic,
you should be concerned about both of
those things.
So the purity issue,
it's like,
well what happens if your living
quarters are filthy and,
and your hygiene habits are terrible.
The answer to that is your house gets
full of parasites,
rats and mice and bugs and you get sick
and then you die.
And so,
and maybe people around you do too.
So you know,
the purity issue really matters.
You don't want to eat rotten meat.
Do you want to make sure it's stored
property?
You don't want to have the rats eat all
your grain,
so you're grading.
These have to be in really good order
in,
there can't be any holes in them.
And so on.
And so like orderliness and food
preservation and,
and preservation from illnesses and
contamination and all those sorts of
things.
It's like,
yeah,
that's really important.
You can't,
you can't just push that away and say
it's irrelevant.
It's not irrelevant at all.
So,
but then again,
you can make it to relevant,
you know.
So one of the things you see with the
anorexics is that,
you know,
they're so sensitive to discuss that
they can't stand their own bodies.
And that's a weird thing,
right?
Because like as a body,
a good thing or a bad thing.
Well here,
here's an example.
So here's an experiment.
So you have,
you give someone a sterilized cup and
you say,
well,
you know,
put some saliva in the cop and then you
let it sit for 10 seconds and then you
say,
well drake,
that right now in La,
do you record like this?
Right.
And that's discussed,
said,
now you won't do that.
But then you might ask,
well,
why,
why wouldn't you do that?
I mean,
it was in your mouth like 10 seconds
ago.
So like what's the big problem while
people,
people won't do it.
And you can see a heuristic at work
there,
right?
The heuristic is don't drink saliva.
And it's not like moderated by any sort
of trivial situational determinants.
You're just not going to do it.
But I suspect that you do kiss your
partner for example,
right?
And then you think,
oh,
well that's kind of a weird exception.
It's like,
oh well my partner turns out not to be
disgusting.
At least that's what you hope.
And then,
and so,
you know,
there's this and that,
and,
and there's also this weird inhibitory
process that goes on between sexual
attraction and discuss to,
you know,
and,
and the psychoanalysts,
you know,
they were,
they thought of that as something that
was perhaps somewhat pathological,
sexual guilt,
sexual shame,
disgust and all that.
But far as I can tell,
it's a,
it's a biological moderating factor in
part of the reason for that as well.
You know,
just how many sexually transmitted
diseases do you actually want to have,
especially that many of them are,
you know,
syphilis in the 19th century.
Man That was,
that was deadly.
It was transmissible from generation to
generation.
It acted like every other kind of
disease and there wasn't any cure for
it.
And then of course we had aids in the
1980s we kind of got a handle on that,
but it was just bloody lock,
you know?
And it was a very transmissible and so
sexual contamination is a big issue and
it always has been for the human race
because it turns out that sexual
activities really good way of
transmitting disease.
So you know,
the,
the borderline between discussed as
something that protects you in your life
and discussed as something that turns
you off of life completely.
It's,
it's a really tight and,
and contradictory set of like mutual
inhibiting forces.
It's a real problem for people.
So,
okay,
so,
so what do you,
what do you have orderliness?
Okay.
Orderly people are black and white
thinkers.
They're judgmental.
If you talk,
if you show orderly,
people imagine that you have them dis,
you described to them some kind of
crime,
like maybe it's living off the fruits of
prostitution.
So maybe you talk to them about a pimp
and you know,
you give them a little story about the
pimp and then you say,
how long should this pimp you thrown in
jail?
It's like the orderly people think you
just lock them up,
throw away the key.
You know,
they're,
they judged moral transgressions very
harshly.
And so that's part of the,
that's part of the aspect that's
judgmental.
They're nodding Galitary and either they
don't think that everybody should have
the same amount all the time.
They're pretty,
they're pretty interested in hierarchy
and structure.
And you know,
there's some real advantages to
hierarchy.
Um,
people think that they'd be happier in
an egalitarian situation.
But the problem with the egalitarian
situations is people are always arguing,
right?
Because no one's right in an egalitarian
situation.
There just,
everybody gets to have their opinion and
it's like,
you know,
when are we going to stop with all the
opinions and do something.
And the thing about a hierarchy is the
advantage to a hierarchy is there are
things you are responsible for,
but there's also things you're not
responsible for.
And that's a big advantage.
And then you also know who is
responsible for those things.
So it looks like people are more
comfortable in hierarchies then they
think even if they're liberals.
So that's kind of interesting to be.
So anyways,
all those things seem to chunk together.
Now the industrious people also seem to
want to climb up the hierarchy,
right?
Cause you know that industrious people
become more successful as they move
through life.
And so you think,
well that's sort of a motivation.
But then you might ask,
is the investment is person trying to
get to the top or is the industrious
person trying to get the hell away from
the bottom?
And my suspicions are that the
industrious person is trying like hell
to get away from the bottom.
They don't want to be down there with
the,
you know,
like I said,
the unemployed and the great unwashed
and now why?
Well,
here's a bunch of reasons.
First of all,
we know pretty clearly that if you're in
a dominance hierarchy,
the closer you are to the bottom of the
hierarchy,
the more likely you to die.
So when that's independent of absolute
income,
like obviously if you're poor enough
that's going to make a difference cause
you're just,
you're going to starve to death.
But assuming you have enough money to
take care of your basic needs,
then dominance,
hierarchy position is a big determinant
of mortality even in heart disease and,
and,
and more if you look at songbirds or any
other kind of animal that lives in the
dominance hierarchy.
And that's pretty much the case for all
animals.
So imagine you have a garment in Turkey
of songbirds in your neighborhood and
the high dominant songbirds.
So there may be industrious songbirds.
They get the best nest and then you
think,
well what is the best nest mean?
Well,
it's close to nesting material so they
don't have to like exert a lot of energy
building the nest and it,
it's,
it's dry when it rains,
so that's a good thing because then
their eggs don't get wet and get cold
and there aren't a lot of predators look
lurking around and it's well hidden and,
and it's well ventilated.
Like there's a bunch of things that make
an optimal nesting site really useful.
So there's a bunch of birds and some of
them have great nesting sites and some
of them have like,
you know,
slum nesting sites.
And then some kind of epidemic comes
through.
Guess what happens?
The birds die from the bottom of the
hierarchy upwards.
Well,
why?
Because the ones at the bottom are
chronically stressed and stress shuts
off your immune system.
And so it's like poof.
Epidemic comes through dead.
And so one of the things that may well
have been built into human beings as the
biological basis of industriousness is
the desire to get the hell away from the
bottom of a dormant.
It's Harkey as fast as possible because
you're much more likely to die if you're
down there.
And you know,
we know that your trait preferences have
emerged as a consequence of evolutionary
pressure.
And if the bottom of the dominance
hierarchy happens to be the place where
diseases,
right,
which is exactly how it is,
then of course you should be motivated
to get the hell out of there.
And so I think a lot of the class
distinctions that people draw and their
desire to have markers of status and so
on are are a reflection of their high
motivation to be associated with the
high levels of the,
of the economic classes.
Here's something interesting.
For example,
you know that names go down the
dominance hierarchy,
you know,
so what are you gonna name your
children?
Well the origin nater of names are the
people at the top of the dog.
It's hard and you know,
and then once they established the names
then the next group starts to copy them
and then the next group copies them.
And then by the time the name gets
common at the bottom of the dominance
hierarchy,
the people at the top are no longer
using it.
They've got some other,
Dave's figured out.
And so names get not only generated that
way but also recycled that way.
So,
and you never want to underestimate the
motivation of people to not be at the
bottom of the dominance hierarchy.
And so it's kind of the reverse of
achievement motivation,
right?
It's sort of like getting away.
But if conscientiousness is mostly
associated with these kind of negative
emotions,
guilt,
shame,
and disgust,
then those are all getting away from
emotions.
Those are,
oh,
it's good to go that way.
Emotions.
But those would be more associated with
extroversion and openness.
So when conscientious people seem to be
dutiful,
so they're not doing things because
they're interested in them.
In fact,
they would say,
who the hell cares?
If you're interested in it,
do it anyways.
That's what a good citizen does.
And of course there's some truth in
that,
right?
You do your damn duty.
So,
okay,
so you kind of get the sense of how
conscientiousness is,
is structured now that's often be called
a behavioral immune system.
So the other thing we know about orderly
people and conservatives is there,
anti-immigration,
as I said,
and their aunt and their xenophobics or
they're much more pro in group and
they're quite harshly judgmental in
their attitudes towards nonstandard
sexual behavior.
And you can explain that all in terms of
contamination fear.
And so,
and you might think to,
you know,
like,
hey,
you know what happened to the native
Americans when the European showed out
pay because the Europeans,
they lived in these like filthy,
filthy cities.
They're just crammed together and they
lived with their animals too.
So like they,
they were parasite written and they had
all sorts of diseases but they got it
good,
good immune systems functioning as a
consequence of that.
And over,
you know,
a period of a long period of time they
developed immunity to things that would
have otherwise killed them.
Like,
well chicken pox and measles and that
sort of thing.
So the Europeans came over to North
America and they shook hands with the
natives.
It was like Poof,
95% of them died in the next 50 years.
So it was like,
by the time the settlers came to
Plymouth Rock,
you know,
the pilgrims,
there are so few native Americans
laughed that they were happy to see them
cause they couldn't get the damn crops
off.
There were enough people left.
So part of the reason that North America
looked empty when the European showed up
is because three successive waves of
absolutely catastrophic plagues had
decimated the entire population of the,
of the continent.
You know,
in the same thing still happens when,
when,
when the,
you know,
when in places like Brazil and Peru when
they find isolated native groups in the
jungle because you know,
that still happens now and then it's
like,
oh look,
some natives shake your hand,
poof,
they're all dead in like a year.
So the,
the idea that the,
the foreign person is a danger has,
has been like critically,
critically correct for much of human
developmental history.
And that's a real problem,
right?
Because obviously in the modern world we
better get along with everybody because
of course we're all powerful enough to
wipe each other out.
But you know,
the problem is is you might think about
things like xenophobia,
you know,
preference for your own group and out
group,
uh,
prejudice and that kind of thing as like
a cognitive issue.
While you could just sort it out if you
thought it properly,
but this is all this research indicates
it's a lot worse than that.
It's some sense because it's grounded in
something much deeper and nor reason
grounded in something much deeper.
It seems to be grounded in something
that's necessary,
right?
If you're not disgust sensitive,
well then your hygiene habits aren't
very good.
Well then you get sick more.
Plus you don't work as hard,
then your life isn't as good,
you know?
So it's,
it's another one of those examples where
where the virtue is and where the vices
is very,
very difficult thing to tell.
So,
so I'm going to read this.
This is from a paper that I wrote with,
with one of my students named Jacob
Hersch.
We haven't published this paper yet.
I want to read it to you because like I
said,
I don't have this information at hand
point as well as I would like to.
So this way I can get the information to
better.
Disgust is considered to be one of the
basic human emotions defined by a strong
revulsion and desire to withdraw from
enlisting stimulus or event.
Darwin noted this fact that 1872 so he
was the first person to note that
discussed was a basic emotion,
physically disgust.
It's accompanied by a distinct facial
expression involving constriction of the
oral and nasal cavities.
You know,
and that's a really good way to insult
someone.
You know,
all you have to do to really insult
someone's making discussed face at the
Mar.
It's something they said.
They really do not like that because
basically what you're saying is you're
kind of like a parasite or an infectious
disease.
Evolutionary models of discuss propose
that this emotion involved to help us
avoid contaminated or harmful foods or
other potential sources of diseases such
as sexual content in addition to its
role in directly helping to expel
harmful foods from the body discussed
also forms an important component of the
behavioral immune system.
The suite of psychological mechanisms
that aid in the detection and avoidance
of potential contaminants before they
can make contact with the body means
obsessive compulsive disorder.
You know,
people will touch something that they
regard as contaminated,
then rush off to wash their hands and
wash and wash and wash.
If some of them are washed,
delete the soaps,
gone.
They'll have showers until they run out
of hot water.
Like they just can't stop.
That's part of obsessive compulsive
disorder.
It looks like it's a disorder of
disgust,
even though it's classified with the
anxiety disorders,
harsh inducing disgust responses,
whether via a foul order,
a disgusting work environment,
or we calling it disgusting experience
leads individuals to assign harsher
punishments to others who had committed
moral transgressions.
Ha.
Here's something else.
So if your judges,
if your judge is easily disgusted,
then you've done something relatively
disgusting.
Or maybe if the court room doesn't smell
so good that day,
well then you're going to end up in jail
longer.
It also,
here's the worst situation.
You go into cart and you're applying for
parole.
Okay?
And it's just before lunch and the court
room doesn't smell good.
It's like you're not gonna get parole
because Hungary judges are much more
likely to deny you parole.
And then of course judges who are
sensitive to discuss are going to regard
your moral transgression as harsher and
you can prime that.
And so you,
I think the data showed that judges
after lunch or like 70% more likely to
grant parole.
It's like it's whether or not the judge
is hungry is more,
it's a bigger determinant of whether or
not you get parole than what you've
done.
It's really quite,
it's really quite funny.
You know,
unless you're up for parole,
harsher moral judgments can even be
induced following the consumption of a
bitter drink because people are often
disgusted by bitterness and addition the
same disgust related facial expressions
or observed in response to unpleasant
tastes,
disgusting photographs and receiving
unfair treatment in an economic game.
So our sense of justice,
that's a weird thing.
Our sense of justice seems to be,
who would guess that day that it's,
that it's,
that it's centered in our,
you know,
from a biological perspective in the
systems that mediate discussed.
So I've seen this,
you know,
among people who've,
who've received an injustice,
you know,
so,
so some things being done to them that's
not good and they're often unable to let
it go,
partly because they're disgusted with
themselves for not responding to it
properly.
It's like,
you know,
if someone throws a dark at you and then
it's like you have a moral obligation to
respond to that,
right?
And you can think about it as anger or
something like that.
But part of it also seems to be that
you're ashamed if you don't respond.
And you can see that sort of thing
happening in cultures of honor,
you know,
where if,
if purity is violated,
you see these in these situations where,
you know,
a father maybe kills his daughter,
which happens reasonably often because
she's violating some sort of social
norm.
Part of the idea is that,
well,
you know,
if you don't respond harshly to
something that's associated with
disgust,
then you bring dishonor on your entire
family and maybe your own,
your entire community.
And you know,
we don't like that sort of thinking in
the west,
but,
well,
but the reasons that we don't approve of
that sort of thinking,
we think it's because we're liberal.
But I think the evidence suggests that
the reason that we don't approve of
those sorts of behaviors is because we
live in a very clean environment and we
have plumbing.
And so there's all sorts of things that
we do that reduced the probability that
we're going to be contaminated by
parasites or infectious diseases.
And so that means that we don't feel
that it's necessary to respond as
harshly to moral transgressions.
And you know,
you might think,
well I doubt it,
but let me show you the evidence because
it's,
it's unbelievable.
Concerns about cleanliness and feelings
of disgust have likewise been related to
political attitudes,
situational reminders of the importance
of physical cleanliness,
such as asking participants to wipe
their hands with antiseptic wipes tends
to increase self reported political
conservatism.
Such a finding is consistent with the
notion that purity tends to be valued
more by conservatives than by liberals.
Individuals who report being disgusted
more easily also tend to hold more
conservative political views on topics
including abortion,
gay marriage,
tax cuts,
and affirmative action.
In addition to the effects that have
emerged when using self report disgust,
sensitivity,
more conservative political views have
also been associated with stronger
physiological reactivity to disgusting
images.
We've found that conservatives are not
only more aroused by disgusting
stimulant,
they're more aroused by any stimuli.
Happiness,
hunger,
fear,
you name it,
it affects the conservative than the
liberal.
And then we've also found that if you
put,
you take undergraduates and you expose
them to videos,
but induced various physiological
states,
happiness,
sadness,
fear,
disgust.
And then we also asked people how long
it was since the last eight.
Well,
if you put people in one of those
emotional or motivational states and
then you show them political speeches,
the more emotional they are or the
hungrier,
the more they like conservative
speeches.
So that was actually very interesting.
So
a large literature is converged on the
notion that there are two core
dimensions of conservative political
ideology,
resistance to change and tolerance of
inequality.
Okay.
Resistance to change reflects the extent
to which people wish to maintain the
status quo.
While tolerance of inequality reflects
the acceptance of an unequal
distribution of resources and
opportunities within society.
You don't want to,
so there's the sort of the idea that the
bash rise to the top and the best is
moral judgment and the top is the right
place for the best people to be.
And then you might ask,
well,
why is the top the best?
I mean,
why did we assume that the,
the,
the top of a dominance hierarchy is the
right place to be?
Well,
part of it is of course,
that the closer you are to the top of
the dominance hierarchy,
especially if you're a male,
the more likely it is that you're going
to,
you know,
um,
be attractive to people of the opposite
sex.
So there's,
that's partly it,
but then this other thing seems to be,
well,
it's actually a bit,
it is a better place to be at the top
because it's,
it's cleaner and safer and there are
more resources there.
And so that accounts,
at least in part for the judgment of the
people who were at the bottom of the
hierarchy.
So these two dimensions of you're
roughly aligned with social and economic
conservatism as expressed in the
constructs of right wing
authoritarianism and social dominance
orientation respectable,
which you,
which you could measure hypothetically
with questionnaires.
So
these core facets of conservatism are
also closely related to to higher order
value dimensions described in moral
foundations theory,
which reflect preferences for order and
tradition on the one hand and
preferences for egalitarianism on the
other.
Okay,
so we'll,
we'll leave that part.
Political conservatives conservatism
confess be thought of as a social immune
system reflecting the extension of
pathogen avoidance mechanisms to the
integrity of the social system.
Just as the behavioral immune system has
been conceptualized as helping to
maintain the purity and integrity of an
individual body.
So to May the same pathogen avoidance
system help to maintain the abstract
integrity of the social order.
In particular,
the social immune system would help to
maintain order by suppressing any
actions or individuals to deviate from a
group's accepted social traditions.
So it has been reported,
for instance,
that regions with higher levels of
disease preference prevalence tend to be
associated higher levels of social
conformity and autocratic rule.
Individuals who feel more vulnerable to
disease likewise report higher levels of
ethnocentrism,
xenophobia.
Such basic concerns about pathogen
avoidance be does contribute to the
desire for order and tradition among
conservatives along with the harsh moral
judgements associated with violations of
the social order.
In particular,
severe moral judgements may be a key
mechanism by which the social immune
system instantiated in conservative
practices and policies aims to eliminate
exposure to deviate social elements that
may increase the risk pathogen exposure.
Okay,
now we wrote that about two years ago
now.
There was a paper published about three
months ago in plause one which you can
look up online.
I've got the reference for it here.
Now.
This paper is absolutely mind boggling,
so I told you guys what effect sizes are
big,
right?
Like 0.2 that's pretty good 0.3 that's
larger than about two thirds of social
science studies published 0.5 it's like,
well,
you're dancing on moon because you just
don't get a correlation.
To a 0.5 between two things.
Unless you're extraordinarily lucky.
It's like 95th percentile effect size.
Okay,
so this paper was published about three
months ago.
Now I'm going to read you the abstract.
Okay,
and then I'm going to show you briefly
show you the data.
According to the parasite stress
hypothesis,
authoritarian governments are more
likely to emerge in regions
characterized by high prevalence of
disease causing pathogens.
Recent cross national evidence is
consistent with this hypothesis,
but there are inferential limitations
associated with the evidence because
salad,
you don't know what direction that
direction relationship is.
We report to studies that address some
of those limitations and provide further
tests of the hypothesis.
Study one revealed that parasite
prevalence,
and so that's parasites or infectious
diseases predicted strongly predicted
cross national differences on measures
assessing individual's authoritarian
personalities and this effect
statistically mediated the relationship
between parasite prevalence and
authoritarian governance.
So what does that mean?
More infectious diseases in the area.
The more likely the individuals in that
area are to have authoritarian political
beliefs and it's the authoritarian,
authoritarian political beliefs of the
people,
the individuals in the area that
produces the authoritarian government.
So it isn't pathogen prevalence,
authoritarian government,
authoritarianism.
It's not a top down thing.
It's a bottom up thing and it's driven
by individuals and that seems to be
driven by just how likely they are to
catch something that's nasty and
infectious.
So then you think,
well in the west,
well what's the probability you're going
to catch something nasty and infectious?
It's like,
well,
very low.
So you're liberal.
Now.
Wouldn't that be something if that was
actually the case,
you know,
is that the west is liberal because it
has plumbing or could easily be,
I mean plumbing is no trivial thing,
right?
That mean you think of all the things
you don't want to do without.
It's like in Canada,
plumbing would be number one and then
maybe he would be number two more.
Maybe you would reverse those,
but it's way the hell up their
study to have tested the parasite stress
hypothesis on a sample of traditional
small scale studies,
results revealed that parasite
prevalence predicted measures of
authoritarian governance and did so even
when statistically controlling for other
threats to human welfare.
So it was,
it was pathogen prevalence,
particularly one additional threat
famine also uniquely predicted
authoritarianism.
Okay,
so it's famine and disease.
Together these results further
substantiate the parasite stress
hypothesis of authoritarianism and
suggested societal differences in the
authoritarian governance result in part
from cultural differences in
individual's authoritarian
personalities.
There's the data.
Now you look,
this is just,
it's just unbelievable.
So look at this.
So one is authoritarian governance,
right?
There's the correlation with pathogen
prevalence 0.42.
So there's another,
um,
failure that I didn't show here that
chosen either,
this is from study to study one.
The correlation was 0.65.
It's like,
Huh,
isn't that interesting?
Maybe the reason that there are
authoritarian countries in the world is
because there's too many infectious
diseases.
And so the waiting to get rid of
authoritarianism is to get rid of
infectious diseases.
So God,
who would have ever guessed that,
you know,
and look at the it warfare was negative
0.11,
right?
Do you think that might be associated
with authoritarian?
Melik?
Malnutrition wasn't even very big
predictor.
You know,
famine,
actually men hit the hit the hit the
equation.
So Feminine,
the probability of disease.
So now let's look at this from a
sociocultural perspective.
So I spend a lot of time studying Hitler
because I'm interested in the
ideological possession.
You know,
tinder is a great example of that
because,
well,
because his ideology was so harsh,
but it was also so attractive to people,
it was so unbelievably attractive.
You know,
when you're going to ask how the hell
you account for something like that.
So,
um,
I'm going to dim the lights a little bit
here because you guys have to be able to
see this.
So,
all right,
so you look on the right theory.
That's the Nuremberg parade ground.
So I hope you can see this a little bit,
that the left,
and that's all people,
right?
So the Nazis built this parade ground
and Nuremberg that was like the biggest
parade ground ever built on the planet.
And they'd have hundreds of thousands of
people at these rallies,
right?
And so you look at the order,
if there's a line down the middle there
where the leaders walk,
and that's at Nuremberg,
and then it's just surrounded by these
masses and masses and masses of people
in lines and all these orderly displays
of power.
And then there's Hitler there like this.
And one of the things Hitler was really
proud of was the fact that he could
stand like that for like eight hours.
And that was willpower as far as he was
concerned.
And he was a worshiper of willpower and
he bathed four times a day.
So he's also somebody who was very much
obsessed with cleanliness,
cleanliness,
and willpower and order.
So that's Hitler.
So now we'll look at that.
That's something that's Nurburg again,
so this is called the cathedral of
lights.
And so that,
that's the parade ground Darragh at the
bottom that I just showed you,
that was full of people.
So you get some idea of how big that is.
Now all those lights around that which
they called the cathedral of likes was
the Luftwaffe,
gave the Nazis all their antiaircraft
lights and then they arranged them
around the parade grounds.
So the whole thing was enclosed by this
perfectly orderly cathedral of lights.
And that was part of the spectacle that
went along with the Nazi with the Nazi
[inaudible] Nazi party rallies at
Nuremberg.
And then so you know,
you look at the top left when they are,
those are,
those are soldiers,
I can't remember at the Nuremberg
rallies,
they had all sorts of people there.
They had like the shovel brigade and
they were all standing there with their
shovels ready to go.
Shovel for Germany and and athletes and
all sorts of people arrayed.
So that you know,
there,
there's this massive display of order in
power.
So you look at the top left hand corner,
you see all those people are lined up,
it's absolutely perfect.
And then you see the same thing when the
right here.
And Look,
you look at the organization of that,
everything's square and perfect and
everybody's in line and you know,
they're all in uniforms and they're all
going like this the same way.
And then when they,
when they marched the soldiers,
they were in perfect lines,
perfect squares,
and they're all going like this.
You know,
it's,
it's absolutely rigid,
orderly perfection.
And so the Germans,
what Germans tend to be conscientious,
you know,
which is part of the reason why they
have excellent engineers and part of the
reason why their economies so damn
powerful.
But one of the downsides of
conscientiousness is orderliness,
right?
And so well,
you know,
people think the Nazis were uncivilized,
but the new evidence seems to suggest
that they weren't down civilized at all.
They were really,
really,
really civilized.
And that if you get too civilized to
orderly,
to conscientious,
then things go to hell in a handbasket
very,
very rapidly.
So
now this,
some of this stuff is awful,
but I'm going to read it to you anyways
because you need to know how this sort
of things work now.
No Hitler emerged into power in the
1930s when,
when Germany was in a real state of
chaos,
right?
Cause it was after the second world war
or the first world war.
You have to remember what happened at
the end of the first world war,
the Spanish flu,
the Spanish flu epidemic,
which was generated in the trenches
because you can generate really intense,
intentionally deadly,
um,
illnesses if the owners can be
transmitted from one person to another
very quickly,
right?
Because the,
it's okay for the organism to kill you
as long as you last long enough to get
the eldest to the next person.
And so if you're all crammed together,
it filthy conditions.
The illness can just hop from person to
person.
And so it can breed particularly deadly
forms.
That's what happened with Spanish flu.
And then the Spanish flu went all around
the world and it killed more people than
World War One did.
Okay.
So that was world war one.
Then there was the Spanish flu,
then the Germany economy fell completely
apart and there was hyper inflation.
And so there was complete chaos.
And then the Germans were worried that
the communists were going to take over
and it was like,
it was like a little bit of hell on
earth and so long came Hitler.
Now Hector was one of these orderly
types.
And so here's the kind of language he
used.
This is from a pamphlet from 1936 the
Jew as world parasite,
the people in the world will recognize
the Jew as world parasite and there will
be a time when there will be one united
front of all people against the Jewish
world parasite.
And it depends with vans and humanity
will be freed from the most severe
illness for much it's suffered through
thousands of years.
Now you can think about this as metaphor
and of course it is metaphor,
but it's a weird because it's not
precisely conscious metaphor.
What seems to be happening is because
Hitler's one of these people who's
hypersensitive to discussed an extremely
orderly,
it's,
it's natural for his mind to conceive of
categories in this way.
Hidden there was always talking about
the area and people as like pure and
perfect,
but also as a body.
So the area in race was a body.
And the problem that the area in Ray's
faced was that there was all these
parasites that were attacking it and it
was the moral obligation of the Germans
to push back against those parasitical
forces.
So,
so here's what happened in Germany.
So Hitler,
when he came to power,
some of the things that happened to
Germany,
he's first started a public health
campaign.
And so he had these vans that had
doctors in the Max ray machines and so
on.
And they went all over Germany screening
people for tuberculosis,
which you know,
was infectious disease and also a
particularly terrible one.
They actually knocked down the rates of
tuberculosis in Germany quite a lot.
So it was like,
well,
let's,
let's embark on a public health and
cleanliness campaigns.
Like,
well,
okay,
you can get rid of tuberculosis that
way.
So then,
then the next thing that he did,
or one of the next things that he did
was he was kind of irritated about how
messy and ugly the German factories
were.
So,
you know,
cause they're kind of dirty and they've
got rats in them and mice and bugs and
so on.
And so the next thing that they decided
to do was to clean up the factory.
So they had people,
you know,
a sweeping them all up and fixing the
grounds in front and planting flowers
and that kind of thing.
And they were fumigating them to get rid
of the parasites.
And the fumigation agent they used,
was it insecticide called Zyklon B and
[inaudible] was the gas that was
eventually used in the concentration
camps.
And so,
so you can see the connection there,
right?
It's like a logical progression of
ideas.
So the next thing that happened was
that,
uh,
they decided their clean up the mental
asylums,
right?
Because well,
you know,
do you really want those sorted
defective people being parasites on
everyone else and should they really be
allowed to reproduce?
If Navy,
it'd be just better to,
you know,
euthanize them because they are useless
and they're suffering anyways.
And so that seemed to go pretty well.
And then,
well then you know,
what happened next,
you know,
then the,
the extension,
the next extension was well to anything
that was foreign,
like a foreign body.
And then this showed up in all sorts of
weird ways.
So,
um,
not see as the most who grew to some
degree out of like nature worship.
I don't know how else to describe it.
There were kind of nature cults in
Germany in the 1930s and they went way
back and one of the things the nature
coats were concerned about in Germany
with the presence of invasive species in
the German,
uh,
you know,
in,
in the German ecological system.
You know,
when we complained about that now too,
because,
you know,
you get plants coming over from China
and places like that,
that,
you know,
spread through ecosystems and
hypothetically disrupt them.
But you know,
and that seems like a reasonable thing
to be concerned about.
But,
but the reason I'm pointing out the
connection is because you never know
where these systems of ideas are going
to lead.
Right?
It's like,
oh,
contamination.
Okay,
fair enough.
You know what contaminations real well,
who's responsible for the contamination?
Hot.
That's where things start to get tricky.
You know,
when the Nazis just kept pushing them,
pushing the limit.
And so I'll show you some of the things
that come from Hitler speeches or right,
it's,
this is from my end comp.
So since the state did not possess the
power to master the disease,
the menacing decay of the right was
manifest.
It's,
that's all disgust,
sensitivity,
contamination.
The masses feel that the mere fact of
the Jews existence is as bad as the
plague.
Politicians tinkering around on the
German national body saw it.
Most of the forms of our general
disease,
but blindly ignored the virus at the
time of the unification.
The inner decay was already in full
swing and the general situation was
deteriorating from year to year.
So it's all,
you know,
decay and disgust and contamination
metaphor.
The symptoms of decay of the prewar
period can be reduced to racial causes.
The Nation did not grow inwardly
healthier,
but obviously language more and more.
Anyone who wants to cure this era,
which is inwardly sick and rotten,
must first of all summon up the courage
to make clear the causes of the disease.
Um,
they think that they must demonstrate
that they are ready for appeasement so
as to stay the deadly cancerous ulcer
through a policy of moderation.
The Jew must take care that the plague
does not die.
If this battle should not come,
Germany would decay and at best would
sync to ruin like a rotting corpse.
You can see in the right today an
example of mortal decay.
The 1st of May can only be the
liberation of the nation spirit from the
infection of internationalism,
the restoration to health of peoples
against the infection of materialism
against the Jewish pestilence,
we must hold a loft,
a flaming ideal.
Now that's interesting because hidden,
they're reading light.
The use of fire.
Fire was a really primary element.
Fire and light.
We're real primary elements in the
Nuremberg rallies and you know,
fire has this purification element,
right?
That's partly why they used to burn
heretics at the state.
It was like that's how you,
you purify things with fire.
And of course you do purify things with
fire.
Part of the reason that we cook things
is because if you cook them,
then the pathogens die and then that's
purification.
So it's not illogical.
I gave orders to burn out,
burn out,
down to the raw flesh,
the ulcers of this poisoning of the
wealth.
Really unbelievably harsh,
harsh language.
The only permanent way to cure disease
conditions is to disclose their causes.
Uh,
let's see.
This is the battle against a veritable
world sickness which threatens to infect
the peoples of plague,
which devastates whole peoples and
international pestilence.
The international carrier of the
bacillus must be fought if within this
community,
one state is infected,
that infection is decisive for all
alike.
And then so,
and he doesn't know,
he also doesn't just address this sort
of language towards the sorts of people
that he ended up eradicating or trying
to eradicate in the camps.
He also used that with regards to
communists.
So we have very real interest in seeing
to it that this bullshit is plague shall
not spread over Europe.
National Socialism has made our people
and therefore the right immune from a
Bolshevik infection.
Um,
it's Saturday.
You get the point
and here's some more language from this
metaphor from a book.
And I'll tell you the book in a minute.
This is the man who wrote this book,
analyzed Hitler's writings and his
speeches looking for metaphorical
foundations.
Um,
the spider was slowly beginning to suck
the blood out of the people's pores.
Um,
here are we face,
we'll have the list eating like
poisonous abscesses into the nation.
It's all this like you can hardly read
these things without being disgusted by
them.
You know,
it's all language that's associated with
disgust at not with fear.
And so that seemed to be very,
very appealing to the Germans have the
time.
Horrible language.
I'm going to show you a bit of a film
now.
Um,
no,
we don't have a lot of time for it
unfortunately,
but I'll,
I'll show you a little bit of it
anyways.
Um,
don't we use this?
It kind kinda shows you how this,
how this,
how these ideas were portrayed in,
in like
call
propaganda and effective propaganda
means might affect the prompt.
Again,
[inaudible]
the political route
shovel.
So you get the picture.
I mean,
you could hardly get a more compelling
representation of perfect orders and
that,
you know,
how many thousands of people do you
think there are?
They're all nicely arranged into perfect
squares,
all moving at exactly the same way.
It's like war against pestilence.
It's a very strange way of looking at
the Second World War,
but the evidence is increasingly strong
that that's the right way to look at.
All right,
so we'll see you guys on Tuesday.