Okay.
So today we're going to talk about
Oh,
openness.
Now
you might say in some sense that
openness is the last discovered that the
big five traits,
and it's also the one I would say that
comes up most weekly in the factor
analysis.
Um,
when hands ising formulated his trait
representation,
which was extroversion,
neuroticism and psychotic system,
he,
he felt that he encapsulated all of the
fundamental variation in human
personality and he was loath to include
intelligence as a personality trait.
Now the relationship between
psychologists,
ISM and openness is rather complex.
Isaac basically felt that people could
be extroverted and that would be the
positive dimension.
It could be,
you know,
high in negative emotion.
That'd be the negative emotion
dimension.
And that they also could have a
predisposition to psychosis.
And I guess that would be,
he was thinking about the brain systems
that underlie schizophrenia and that
that tendency to,
to dissociate and develop
hallucinations,
but also maybe the system in human
beings that are affected by
hallucinogenic drugs,
which seem to affect human beings
differently than they have other
creatures.
So,
but Isaac psychotic cism.
Eventually it was broken down into low
agreeableness and low conscientiousness.
It didn't predict the predisposition to
psychosis at all.
And later factor analysis found that you
could load out
intelligence and creativity as a
personality dimension separately.
Now it's a bit tricky because you have
Iq measures.
Iq measures are much more direct
measures of intelligence than the
personality measures.
I mean the personality measure is
something like,
do you think you're smart?
You know,
I mean I'm being a bit flip about that
because it's more sophisticated than
that.
But when you talk about someone as a
smart person,
you're generally referring to the trait
that we would describe as openness.
You also are doing that when you refer
to the,
to creativity as a,
as a predisposition and you could
measure the smart part a lot better with
Iq and Iq is also a pretty good
predictor of creativity.
So
well,
so let's see how they're associated.
So he remember that
you have your big two traits,
stability of plasticity and stability
breaks down into conscientiousness,
emotional stability and agreeableness.
And then you can see how each of the
aspects are correlated,
how highly they're correlated.
So industriousness and orderliness at
about 0.4,
volatility,
withdrawal and emotional stability or
neuroticism actually,
um,
about 0.6 and agreeableness and
politeness at about 0.4.
And then the next trade is extroversion
and openness that makes plasticity and
people who were high in plasticity tend
to be good entrepreneurs by the way.
And extroversion rates into
assertiveness and enthusiasm correlated
at about 0.5 and then openness and
intelligence and the correlation there
is lower.
It's 0.35.
The average correlation between the big
five is 0.2 and the correlation between
the big two is about 0.2 and so you have
to remember,
you might ask yourself,
well,
is it correlation of point for twice as
large as a correlation of point to
announce to that is no,
because you have to square them to
compare the marath medically.
So correlation of point to give you
0.044% squared,
right?
And of correlation port four gives you
16% squared.
So there's actually a difference of a
factor of four.
And so you need to remember that when
you're considering effects sizes so that
you can understand exactly what they
mean.
Now you know if you're accounting for
16% of the variants,
which would be a correlation of 0.4 then
that leaves 84% left unexplained.
But that's a bit of an overstatement
most of the time in psychology because
our measures are are rather imperfect.
And so for example,
if you give someone a personality test
and let's say that the validity of their
self report is about 0.6 and 0.7 which
is probably what it is,
maybe it might be a little bit higher
than that.
So that's,
that means that they're self reporting
is only picking up 50% of the variation
in their personality.
And if you pick up,
you know if,
if your are,
if an are derived from that measure
accounts for 16% of the variance.
In some sense it's twice as powerful as
it appears to be because the measure is
so error retinal and a lot of the things
that we measure in psychology,
our error ridden.
And what that means is that the
correlations are generally what it
means.
Although not in variable,
he isn't.
The correlations are bigger than they
look.
In any case,
the correlations that come up in
personality research are certainly big
enough to be meaningful.
And I would say meaningful in terms of
predicting major life outcomes and
predicting important economic outcomes
and that sort of thing.
So all right,
so
one of the things you might ask yourself
is exactly what does intelligence
measure.
So we'll start with intelligence from,
from the,
and that would be equivalent to
intellect,
roughly speaking.
So intellect in the big five,
the aspect seems to be associated with
interest in
whereas the openness proper aspect seems
to be associated with aesthetic
sensibility and creativity.
That's the best way to think about it as
far as we've been able to figure out.
And the biggest relationship is between
the intellect and intelligence as
measured psychometrically.
Now intelligence is an interesting
concept.
It's very controversial.
In fact,
if you,
one of the things that continually
happens over and over again in
psychology is that psychologists
discover all sorts of new kinds of
intelligence and you know,
the biggest two proponents of that sort
of thing.
I suppose we're Bob Sternberg who came
up with this thing he called practical
intelligence and then Howard Gardner who
came up with the theory of multiple
intelligences,
which had a very large effect on
educational psychology.
Um,
when the theory was first proposed.
And that's not saying much because
generally speaking it's very difficult
to find a discipline that's more
susceptible to fads than educational
psychology.
And as far as I can tell,
generally speaking,
each fat is worse than the previous one.
So you know,
Gardner positive that I think there were
seven,
oh there they are,
seven or eight different intelligence as
linguistic,
musical,
logical,
mathematical,
spacial body,
kinesthetic,
interpersonal and interpersonal.
And people talk about emotional
intelligence and they talk about
practical intelligence.
And as far as I'm concerned,
all of that's complete rubbish.
And there's technical reasons for that.
I mean there's technical and
philosophical reasons for that.
The first thing is you can't just mess
up a word.
You know,
the whole point of having a word is so
that it defined some things at described
some things and doesn't describe other
things,
right?
And so you can,
you can make the word intelligence a
comment for whatever you want.
So you can say that the ability to dance
as a form of intelligence.
But the problem with that is you blur
out the word so bad that you can't tell
what it means anymore.
And so,
and I would also point out we had
perfectly good words for those major
intelligence as we called them talents.
And so it's perfectly reasonable to make
a distinction between the talent and
intelligence.
Now you might say,
well,
how the hell do you know the difference?
Like if,
if things look similar to some degree,
then how do you know if they're the same
or different?
Well that's exactly what you do when you
do the construct validity process.
So let's say you rated a number of
people on their dancing ability and then
you rated the number of people on their
ability to multiply two digit,
two,
two digit numbers in their head quick
while then you see,
technically if both of those were
intelligences,
then the people who could dance better
could multiply two digit numbers faster
in their head and they would be slightly
positive.
Sorry.
See,
that's what happens when I don't have
any diet coke.
So anyways,
if intelligence was the right word to
subsume both of those,
then what you'd see is that would be a
high correlation with people who are
good dancers would also be the ones who
could multiply most rapidly.
And I mean multiply in their head.
Um,
but that,
but you're not going to be able to
extract out a single factor like that.
It's just not,
it's just not the case that those things
associated like that.
So for something to be one phenomena,
the things that it,
hmm,
obviously I've talked too much this
semester.
All the things that are subsumed under
that definition has to be correlated and
highly correlated because otherwise
they're not the same thing.
It's the definition of the same thing.
Now,
Rq is a very peculiar construct,
a very unique construct from a
psychological perspective,
but also more generally from a social
science perspective because Iq has the
most predictive validity of anything
ever discovered in the social sciences
period.
Now the other thing that is interesting
about our Iq is that a lot of the people
who were interested early in the
measurement of intelligence,
we're engineers turned psychologists and
the engineers have actually had quite a
whopping effect on psychology.
Part of the reason that psychology has
an advanced methodology and advanced
statistical techniques is because we got
invaded by engineers in the early part
of the 20th century.
And so the engineer has made our
measurements much more rigorous than
they would've otherwise been.
And it's been a huge advantage.
I mean,
one of the things that's happening to
psychology is that starting to eat other
disciplines,
so it's had a massive effect on
economics and it's going to have a
massive effect on political science.
And the reason for that is because we
know how to measure things and it
actually turns out to matter that you
know how to measure things.
Obviously.
I mean if you're going to be talking
about something that's specific and well
defined,
first of all,
if you can't make it specific and well
defined,
all you can really do is argue about it.
And you know there are better and worse
arguments.
But the problem is is that just because
an argument is good doesn't mean it's
right and that's a big problem.
So also something to remember when
you're arguing about people that you
have relationship with because you know,
if you happen to be better at
structuring your arguments and your more
verbally fluent man,
perhaps more assertive and maybe less
agreeable,
you're going to win the arguments.
But that doesn't mean you're right.
It's unfortunately,
it's not that simple.
And so as far as I can tell me,
empirical process is the only way of
getting rid of that is restricting or
eliminating the catastrophic,
the detrimental effects of pure theory.
No and
well,
and our measurement techniques have been
pretty good about that.
Okay.
So now what happens with Iq here?
I can define Iq for use,
just so you know what it is.
So
imagine that you had a library of
questions.
So here's some questions.
So there's millions of questions in this
data bank.
What's two times 68 what's the capitol
of Georgia?
What's the definition of hyper tricks?
Anemia?
What comes after in this sequence?
Two four eight 16
yeah,
remember these numbers?
So I'd tell you the numbers and then
you'd have to tell me the back.
Two (413) 576-1215 1418 2022 and then I
might ask you in fact to remember them
backwards.
And that's a working memory task.
So,
okay,
so those are all questions that require,
they require abstraction and mental
operations.
That's the key as far as I can tell.
So you might say,
well,
exactly what constitutes and
abstraction.
And it looks to me like what an
abstraction is.
There's the capacity to formulate an
abstraction and there's the capacity to
manipulate them to formulate an
abstraction.
I think what you do is you take a
phenomena and you represent it with
something that's low resolution,
that's more or less what an abstraction
is.
So for example,
if I imagine this classroom later,
um,
my,
my imagined representation is going to
be a much lower resolution than the
actual classroom,
but it's sufficient for certain
purposes,
just like a thumbnail on a computer is
sufficient for certain purposes.
And then once I simplify the,
the,
the phenomena in question,
then I can also perform certain
operations on it,
say in imagination or semantically and
the capacity degenerate.
That abstraction and the trends and make
the ability to manipulate those seems to
be the core element of intelligence.
And I think part of the reason why
intelligence,
roughly speaking as a human dimension,
although you know,
obviously you can,
you can,
you can to some degree rank order
animals in terms of their capacity to
learn.
But there's this whopping
differentiation between human beings and
animals in this area,
particularly is because we can use
abstractions.
Now,
I heard a woman named Temple grandin
speak once and it was very interesting
talk.
She's very autistic.
And,
uh,
but very,
very,
very brilliant,
which is not very common for people who
are artistic because usually it's
associated with it,
a substantial amount of intellectual
impairment.
But she also had an extraordinarily
devoted parent who spent almost all of
her time trying to pull her daughter out
of her autistic isolation.
Now,
grandon has gone on to become a
University of Chicago professor,
and she works in the,
in the agricultural area,
and she has redesigned the mission,
the chutes walkways basically that take
cattle to the slaughterhouse.
And she's done that to make them less,
much less stressful for the animals.
And part of the reason that she can do
that as far as she's concerned,
is because she thinks like an animal.
And what that means as far as she can
tell is that she cannot generate an
abstraction,
not easily.
Now she could speak.
So obviously she learned to do it to
some degree,
but she talked more about inner talk,
more about deficits and imagination or
concrete [inaudible] of imagination.
So one of the weird things that you see
with autistic kids,
not frequently,
but now and then it's actually a famous
example of this on the web.
There's a guy,
I think he's from Britain and you can
take them in a helicopter and fly him
over a city and then he can stand in
front of a paid piece of paper,
like 12 by eight start anywhere and draw
the entire city,
you know,
and now,
and then you see autistic savant who are
children who can draw perfectly
realistically.
And so maybe they'll draw a horse and
they don't even start the horse.
Like a kid would,
like a normal kid would,
would sketch the outline of the horse
and put some eyes in,
you know,
they start anywhere and make the horse
perfectly detailed.
And,
and what Clarendon claimed was that,
so she said,
okay,
you think of,
think of house or think of church.
And she says,
what comes to mind if you think of
church?
And maybe she'd say,
well,
you'd get this little image of something
that's sort of shaped like this with a,
you know,
a steeple on top or across or something
like that.
And that's the church.
And so maybe you think of house and it's
like a little kid's house,
you know,
it's gonna,
it's got a rectangle and a parallel and
Graham and that's not a Parallelogram,
whatever the hell you call that thing on
the top.
And then it's got a chimney with smoke
coming out of it,
right?
Two windows and a door house.
Yeah.
But there,
there are no houses like that.
Like each individual house looks a lot
different than that.
And so in order to have that conception
of house,
what essentially what you have to do is
you have to take the class of all
possible houses and extract out the
features that are in common across all
of them.
And that's an abstraction.
And so as far as Grandin's concerned,
she doesn't have obstructions like that,
which when you ask her to remember to
think of church,
she remembers at Church it's always
singular instances.
Now,
the thing about human beings is that,
you know,
we perceive singular instances to some
degree,
although I think our abstraction
capacity all often interferes with our
ability to do that.
But we also perceive abstractions.
And you can kind of tell this,
if you're ever trying to learn to draw,
like if I say draw a hound,
you guys,
most of you,
unless you have artistic training,
you're going to draw up what's
essentially a hero glyphic hand.
And I,
I think the drawings the children come
up with aren't drawings.
I think their hero glyphs,
they're abstracted representations that
are quasi linguistic.
They're not artwork there.
They're pro prodo language.
Right?
And so,
and here are glyphs,
of course,
we're one of the earliest forms of
written language.
It makes sense.
Cause if you want to communicate about
something,
why not draw an image?
You know?
And then the eventually the image turns
into a word.
But I actually think that's,
I think that's the developmental
progression of language among human
beings.
It's the abstract,
that image first and then it's the word.
Um,
anyways,
you know,
if you drew a hand,
you'd like to draw a hieroglyphic hand,
five fingers or maybe even four,
right?
Because that's what they do.
That's what animators do.
You can't fit all those sausages on one
circle,
you know,
so they just simplify it down to four
and no one even cares.
You Watch an animation automated
program,
which is highly abstracted,
right?
I mean,
homer Simpson looks nothing like an
actual person,
like really tremendously unlike an
actual person that's completely
irrelevant,
you know,
after two or three seconds,
it doesn't matter at all.
Which is also why I think three d movies
never really,
it's never a technology that's ever
caught on.
It's after the first four seconds.
Who the hell cares?
It's irrelevant whether you see it in
three dimensions because you don't need
much information to actually structure
your perception.
Now,
if you want to see your hand,
weirdly enough so that you can draw it,
you have to snap out of your normal mode
of perception.
I find it's often a lot easier to do
that with one eye closed because it
flattens it out and then you have to
stop looking at your hand as if it's a
hand.
You have to look at it again like it's
an object.
And as soon as you do that it's actually
rather shocking cause it's such a
strange looking thing.
Like if you,
if you put your hand in a non-canonical
position that's a canonical position,
I would say you put your hand in the non
canonical position and then look at it.
It's,
it's the weirdest shape thing.
It's quite shocking to see it.
And then you can draw it once you can
actually see it like that.
But before that you're pretty much stuck
in hand.
So,
so anyways,
I think what happens with intelligence
is that people are capable of
abstracting and then they can manipulate
abstractions.
And so let's take another look at,
at what abstractions might be.
So
now part of the reason I think that
abstraction is so useful is because
things are really,
really complicated and it's going to be
a lot more difficult to manipulate.
The actual thing that to manipulate some
represent to div,
abstraction of it.
So if you could get an abstraction that
that captures the gist of the entity.
Now how would we do that is not exactly
obvious,
but if you can then you can expand a lot
more resources,
concentrating on the relevant parts of
the,
of the entity and a lot last time
concentrating on the irrelevant parts.
So you know,
so for example,
if you ask a child to draw a house,
what color the house is is irrelevant.
Now why it's irrelevant.
It's not exactly obvious.
I guess it's because color can vary
across houses and color varies across
all sorts of other things.
And so color turns out to be a non
canonical element of house so you can
just dispense with it.
When you're thinking about a house,
you'd say,
well it doesn't matter what the into
houses,
it's still a house.
So what exactly defines those features
that make something a house rather than
something else or are not that easy to
figure out?
You know,
you could say,
well,
how's has four walls and a roof?
And those are the external walls.
And I guess you could identify the
minimal necessary components,
but even that's not so,
so simple.
And you could say a house is also
something that someone lives in which
allows you to put caves as houses
because caves obviously share very
little in common with you know,
a standard house.
So my,
my point is is that it's difficult
exactly to figure out what set of
features we do use to determine whether
something is a member of a class.
There's this guy named,
uh,
gigger answer,
who's thought about this a lot and he
thinks that we,
that there are a combination of
objective and functional basically.
And that enables us to do things like
come up with the category of things you
would take from your apartment if it was
on fire.
It was really interesting category,
right?
Because most of the things that you're
going to take bear very little
resentment.
It's hard to see why they make a
category.
Pets,
family members probably in that order.
Um,
photo albums,
identification.
What else might you take if you were
your phone,
I suppose,
what else would you take out of an
apartment during the fire?
Well,
you guys would be out on the street
stark naked obviously,
so well you get,
the point is that,
you know,
those things that are just mentioned
seem to share very little in terms of
objective features in common.
But there's some reason that they still
cohere as a category.
All right,
so anyways,
why do you need to abstract?
Well,
because you can handle the complexity of
the world better.
Even your perception is a form of
abstraction.
You know,
because when you look at someone,
a lot of the abstraction has done for
you because you just can't perceive very
well.
But when you look at someone,
first of all,
you only see the surface of them that's
facing you would not the other surface.
So that's a big limitation.
You only see them now in this,
you know,
split second rather than extended across
time.
You don't see any of their micro
structure right beyond the,
beyond the,
you know,
general pattern of the physiology at
this level of resolution.
You don't see anything below that.
I can't see yourselves or your organs or
anything like that,
which is actually a real problem often
for us.
And I can't see the systems that you're
part of.
So right off the bat just to proceed,
gives you a low resolution
representation.
And a lot of that's limitations of your
processing.
Your eyes just can't zoom in that far.
You don't have the cortical capacity to
improve your vision,
you know,
plus how much do you really want to see
at one time,
no more than necessary,
whatever that means.
And evolution seems to take care of that
problem.
So your perception abstracts for you
right away.
But then I would say maybe you make a
leap from perception to conception or
something like that.
And so that would be the leap from the
perception of the actual object to the
image of the object and then a leak from
the image of the object to the word.
So it looks to be like a word is a
representation of an image,
which is a representation of an object
or situation.
It's something like that.
So and you need those because you have
to deal with the complex world.
So here's,
here's one way of thinking about it.
So look at the top left corner of that
diagram.
So I called that the thing in itself and
what it is,
is,
is an array of dots,
roughly speaking.
And I think there's 360 dots there.
And you might say,
well,
and then if it was a real world object,
you could imagine that would be in three
dimensions.
Not to cause that's too,
and it would be transforming because it
would be also extended across time.
So,
and it would have micro structures that
were far smaller than that and macro
structures that were far bigger.
But so even that is an abstraction.
But it's,
I'm,
I'm using a fairly complex abstraction
to rip represent the thing in itself.
That's the thing.
You cannot proceed,
right?
What something actually is,
you just get an image and then the next
five things are ways you could look at
that.
So you could say,
well,
it's a rectangle.
You could say it's four rectangles and
forget about the dots.
You could say that it's,
I think that's 16 lines or what is it?
32 lines,
a 24 lines.
So if you are going to,
if that thing in itself was an orchard
and you are going to walk north,
south to north through it,
that would be a good representation.
You know those would be corridors
roughly speaking.
And then object for is a combination of
object one and object to,
and then object five is well all of it's
blurred out are the little groups of six
dots.
And so you might say well what is that
thing?
And then answer is well it's any of
those five things.
And so that's an interesting way of
thinking about it too because one of the
things that shows you is that you can
disagree about what something is right
at the level of perception.
And then you might say,
well which of those is the best
representation?
And the first answer might be well the
most complex one,
the top,
the one on the left hand corner.
But that's not necessarily the case.
It might depend on what you want the
representation for.
Like,
imagine.
It's weird.
It's weird because imagine you have a
map.
Okay.
And so you think,
well,
I'm going to make the best map in the
world.
And so you make a map that's exactly the
same size as the territory that it
represents and has all the detail.
Well that's not any use at all.
That thing because you could just use
the territory.
Right?
So you know the,
just because as a map gets increasingly
detailed to some degree,
it's increasingly useless as a map.
And so what you need is this weird
combination between accuracy and
simplicity.
And so you want your map to be no more
complicated than is necessary to take
you from point a to point b.
That's it.
So because otherwise it wouldn't be
simple to use and the additional
complexity would eliminate the utility
of the,
of the map.
So,
so you might say that what we're trying
to do with our intelligence is to get
what we need with the least amount of
effort possible.
And,
and you know,
there's a sort of a Piagetian idea
that's lurking behind that,
which is,
well you don't want,
you have limited resources,
you don't want to expend any more energy
than is necessary and you want to build
representations of the world that
suffice to keep you going now and then
next week and next month,
and then you know alone and then in
groups.
And so you build a representation of the
world that has some concordance with the
thing in itself,
but has this functional simplicity so
that you could actually use it in the
real world.
All right,
so back to this diagram.
So I've got the object and five
representations and then there are ways
of representing it linguistically at the
bottom.
So
what that is,
the words are basically a simplification
of something that's already simplified.
So okay,
so intelligence seems to have something
to do with the process of functional
simplification.
Now back to the library of questions.
So you have this database of questions
and so then what you do is pull out a
hundred questions randomly.
All right?
And you want to pick out a hundred
because if you just pick out one,
like if I asked you what the capital of
Georgia was and I asked you what the
capital of Georgia was and you got it
wrong and you got it right,
I couldn't really say with any degree of
certainty that that means that you have
more intelligence because the
probability that I get an accurate
measure with one question is quite low.
But if I use three questions while then,
you know,
I would,
I would start to become,
my measurement would start to become
less error written and if I use 10 would
even be better.
And if I use 20 for a personality
questionnaire,
the rule of thumb,
and this is just a rule of thumb,
is that if you don't have 20 questions
in the questionnaire,
then you don't have enough questions to
really generate a reliable measure.
So you'll still,
you'll still see single item measures
used in psychology,
but um,
you can add additional accuracy by,
by increasing the number of items.
I designed an Iq test a while back and
we got a pretty good,
we've got pretty good reliability and
pretty good validity.
Reliability as you know,
you the same set of people twice and the
rank order of their performance stays
the same.
So if you've got 90 on the previous
test,
you'd get 90.
And if you go up 95 because you're more
intelligent in this example,
if you've got 95 and the last one you'd
get 95 on this one.
So that's reliability.
You can get a pretty,
we could get a pretty reliable Iq test
with nine items,
but it was substantially improved with
17 and with increments,
you know,
you get uh,
uh,
what would you call it?
Diminishing returns.
So a hundreds,
plenty.
Okay.
So you pull out a hundred questions and
then you take a hundred people and you
give them those questions and then you
score them right and wrong.
That's all there is.
And then you sum the scores.
Okay.
So basically that,
that miss some behaves like the average.
Let's say you average the scores just to
make the argument a little bit more
straight forward.
You average the scores.
And so each of you gets the average of,
you know,
uh,
calculated across the Times that you
were right and wrong.
So it's an approximation of the
frequency of your,
of how right you were.
And then we rank order you one to a
hundred.
That's Iq,
that's all there is to it.
So now people say Iq doesn't exist.
Well that's annoying because all they're
doing is gerrymandering.
The definition of the word exist,
you know,
cause you can do that if you ask if a is
equivalent to be,
the answer is it depends on what you
mean by a and what you mean by be,
it's almost always a foolish question
because you can take b and a and bend
them and twist them in such a way that
you could make one thing and other thing
without too much problem.
People usually get around that by only
using a word in a context,
right?
In a sentence or a phrase or a paragraph
that defines the word so that you can't
weasel around like that.
But,
but more specifically in psychology,
we have methods to tell if something is
real.
You know,
and psych,
if Iq doesn't pass the test of reality
for a psychological measure,
then no other psychological measures
passed the test because they're
validated exactly the same way Iq is and
they don't work as well.
So you can say,
well no that's not real.
But then you have to throw out,
you probably have to throw out the
social sciences completely insofar as
they're actually sinuses because the
same statistics are used to generate
their findings.
So you can't just say,
well this really powerful thing doesn't
exist.
Well a bunch of these weak things exist
and they're measured the same way.
You don't get to play that game.
So,
okay,
so does it exist?
Well you could measure it,
you can measure it reliably.
So that's definitely something you know,
cause you might say,
well does your shadow exist?
Well generally speaking,
under normal conditions you could
envision your shout a relatively
reliable,
you know,
does it exist?
Well it passes one test of existence.
You know,
you can't be detected with a number of
senses.
You can't touch it for example.
But you know,
whether or not something exist is
actually a rather tricky question,
but
you can measure it and it's useful and
that's not a bad definition of,
of exist.
So what's it good for?
Well,
it predicts major life outcomes and
importantly,
so,
and we can talk about the power of
intelligence momentarily.
If you were actually going to calculate
an Iq score per se,
you would take the rank order that I
just described and you would correct it
for age because you know,
you can't really expect a seven year old
to know as much as it,
if the year old or a 20 year old.
So generally speaking,
if you take a technical Iq test,
it will rank order you,
but it'll only rank order you with
people of the same age as you.
So that's just another,
you know,
it's an additional correction.
Whether or not that actually gives you a
more accurate estimate of Iq is depends
on what you mean by accurate.
Uh,
very bright seven year old
generally doesn't know enough to do much
useful in the way of work,
but they can learn extremely quickly.
And so,
mmm.
If you compared seven year olds to
people of other ages purely in terms of
their score on an Iq test,
there's a high probability that you
would underestimate their speed of
learning.
By the same token though,
by the time you were 40 you have a lot
of accumulated knowledge and so if,
if you only measure learning speed,
then you would underestimate,
you would overestimate that seven year
olds advantage over the 40 year old
Iq is basically a unitary phenomenon,
but you can fractionated into,
it's very,
very complicated
for reasons that I'll tell you about in
a minute.
If you had to divide Iq into to the way
you would divide,
it would be into crystallized and fluid
intelligence and fluid intelligence
would be roughly the ability to learn
and crystallized intelligence would be
roughly a measure of how much you've
learned.
Now those are separate to some degree
and here's why.
They're separate.
As you age,
your capacity to learn decreases.
It's quite ugly.
So by the time you're about 24 you're
starting to get stupider from the
perspective of being able to learn.
And that's just pretty much a linear
trip downhill until you depart the
world.
So it's,
it's,
it's nasty to see cause it's quite a
steep degeneration.
You can stave that off by the way with
the cardiovascular and cardiovascular
exercise and weightlifting.
So that's the best way to keep your
learning capacity intact.
It's not to do cognitive exercises and
stood in physical exercise and then as
you age,
then the amount you know goes up.
And what happens is those two things
actually tend to average out.
So now you might say,
well if I'm claiming that Iq,
is this a unitary thing,
how can I make the claim that you can
divide it into two elements and that
those elements are in some sense
separate.
And I think the reason is for this,
so your,
your prefrontal Cortex,
roughly speaking.
So that's the part of your brain here
forward.
You can think about,
in part it's the part that does the
programming of motor activity,
voluntary motor activity.
But it also seems to be,
so let's say you're doing something new
and you're pretty clunky and awkward at
it and then you do it more and more and
you get smoother and smoother and
smoother at it and you know what you
have taught,
monetize it.
What happens is you're using your
prefrontal cortex and to some degree
your whole right hemisphere when you're
first doing it.
And then as you get better and better at
it,
the ability shifts to the left and then
it goes backwards.
Um,
so what's happening to some degree is
your prefrontal cortex is programming
the rest of your brain and you could
think of fluid intelligence as a measure
of the ability of your,
of your brain to program itself and
crystallized ability as a measure of how
much programming is there.
And then so are separate in that manner
because they perform separate functions.
But then you can also understand that
the better your program or is the better
the programming is going to be.
So that inflates the correlation.
And so you can have two separate things
functional functionally that are even
dissociable in terms of age.
But because they worked so tightly
together,
it's like how fast can you dig a hole
and how big is the pile of dirt?
Well,
obviously those two things are different
in some important sense,
but they're going to be highly
correlated because the faster you can
take a whole,
the bigger the pile of dirt and so,
so anyways,
crystallized intelligence is often also
often measured as verbal intelligence,
but the better measure s fundamentally
is crystallized intelligence.
Now you know how we looked at the I the
personality hierarchy,
right?
That was this
and what you see is three strata,
roughly speaking aspect,
trait super factor and it looks like the
super factors.
I would say
the validity of those super factors is
not yet clear.
You can get a lot of useful prediction
by looking at the traits and there's
more and more evidence.
There's about 400 studies now using the
aspect.
There's more and more evidence that you
can also derive additional useful
predictive validity from differentiating
the personality down to the,
to the,
to the aspect level.
That's the highest resolution
personality model we have.
There are people who claim that there's
something at the apex which you might
call good personality,
but I don't think so.
I think it's,
I don't think so.
You'd have to read the literature to
understand the,
okay.
The dispute.
It's a statistical dispute roughly
speaking.
But um,
we've found in our research that
stability and plasticity early
correlated that 0.2 they're pretty
separate.
So I'm going to stick with that for now
even though it might be wrong.
What?
Okay.
So
see how I would explain this problem.
If you read the cognitive literature and
the neuropsychological literature,
you will find that neuropsychologists
tend to assume that,
okay,
there are forms of cognitive ability
that you cannot describe as Iq.
Okay.
And they make that claim because they'll
take a test and they'll,
they'll use the test to measure
something and then they'll correlate
that with Iq and the correlation will
only be about 0.2 or 0.3.
And so they'll say,
well that's not a high enough
correlation.
Okay.
To justify saying that those things are
identical because the correlation should
be more like 0.8 for them to be
identical.
But the problem is,
let's say I had a measure of your Iq and
your Iq and your Iq,
your Iq,
and then I asked you two questions and
you and you and you and I summed your
answers whether they were correct or
incorrect.
Now what would happen is there'd be some
correlation between your total score on
those two questions and your overall Iq.
Maybe it would be 0.3 but that wouldn't
justify me in claiming that the two
question Iq test is different than the
full scale Iq test.
It's just worse.
Okay?
You're going to run into this problem
when you read psychological literature
and if you ever do it,
do any research because it's very
difficult to determine whether you get
what's called discriminant validity,
which is this thing measures this,
this thing measures this thing and
they're actually different,
or whether you just have a lousy measure
of this and the lousy measure this and
so the correlation is low.
Now here's a neuropsychological test
and you could make the case that this is
measuring something different than Iq.
So imagine you see an array of 12
pictures.
They're just drawings,
drawings of a telephone and a boot and a
chair.
Just calm and objects.
Okay,
so you see 12 of them and then you have
to click one and then when you do that
they move and then the next time you
have to click one you haven't already
clipped and then they move again and you
click and they move again and you click
and you'll see by the time you get to
about eight of them,
you're starting to run into trouble
because it's,
it's difficult to remember more than
eight abstractions simultaneously.
Seven actually in some people claim it's
as low as four.
That's the capacity of working memory,
which is why we kind of like phone
numbers to be seven digits long.
A lot of the things we want to just
remember r s r seven units long and if
we want to remember more than that,
we chunk.
Although you know,
if I show you some dots,
okay,
say,
well how many doors?
Three.
You don't have to count them.
You can see three dots.
You can see four dogs.
It's not obvious that you can see five
dogs at that point.
You start to go three and two and then
if there's six dots,
well that's how they would be arranged
on a dice dice,
right?
The reason they'd be reached on a dice
that way is because you could see two
sets of three and for six,
you know,
if they're sort of randomly dispersed
like that,
I say,
well how many dots is that?
One?
You have character.
And what that shows you is that your
working memory,
which is really a function of fluid
intelligence,
is a very,
very narrow thing.
And it's like your vision,
you know,
remember we saw the gorilla video,
right?
Then you can only pick up the thing that
you're attending to.
Well,
working memory is like that.
It's this narrow,
narrow form of attention and it's sort
of specifies unitary phenomenon.
I mean that's not coining unitary,
but it's close enough.
And I think the reason that it does
that,
it's like why is your attention so
narrow is because often what you're
trying to do as you work in the world,
just to make binary choices,
you know,
you don't want to choose between 20
things you want to read.
You want to choose between two things
because then when you choose between two
things,
you can actually act.
If it's still two things,
you can't act.
If it's one thing you could act.
So imagine you go into Chinese
restaurant is a good example because
Chinese restaurants virtually always
have like 400 items on the menu.
And you might ask yourself,
well how the hell do you figure out what
you want?
And what you don't do is go through
every single menu item and contemplate
it because you'd be there for a week.
So what you seem to do is eradicate
chunks.
So you might say,
well I'm not in the mood for anything
but fish.
Okay Bang,
three quarters of the menu disappears,
you know,
and then you might go,
well I,
I don't want it branded whack.
And then another half is gone.
And now you're down to maybe eight
choices and you know,
you reduce that to four and then to to
perhaps,
well I'd like this or I'd like that,
but the waiter doesn't care about that.
The waiter wants to know which one you
want because until it's reduced to one
you don't get to act.
And so the reduction,
the reduced narrow strip that we use to
perceive the world and partly as a
consequence of processing inadequacy,
but it's also partly because we really
are trying to reduce things all the time
to zero in one,
right?
Yes or no.
So okay,
so back to the,
this three stratum theory of cognitive
abilities.
Now
you've got this array of 12 items and it
keeps shifting.
And what I would do is score you by the
number of duplications you if you pick
the same item more than once,
you lose a point.
So the maximum points you can get is 12
and you know,
people usually make three or four
mistakes.
And so I could take your score on that
test.
Maybe I'd give it to you two or three
times just to make sure.
I have a reasonably stable indicator and
then I can correlate it with your full
scale fluid Iq and I get a correlation,
but both put two five or 0.3 now if you
don't know anything about psychometrics,
you'd say,
oh well that's obviously measuring
something different than full scale Iq
because it only correlates that 0.25 or
0.3 but what it turns out is no,
it's more analogous to the problem that
we were just talking about where I asked
you three questions and tried to derive
your entire icu from that.
It's just a bad measurement.
Now what happens is if you take the
neuropsychological tests that people
have developed that theoretically assess
the function of different parts of the
brain,
so and you factor analyze them and you
extract out a single factor,
the single factor it looks exactly like
fluid intelligence now is exactly the
same as fluid intelligence.
It would be the onus would be on the
person who claims it's not to
demonstrate the difference.
We did give university students have a
very extensive battery of prefrontal
cortical tests and measured their Iq.
And then we use the prefrontal cortical
test average and the Iq to predict
grades.
And what we did find was the prefrontal
tests predicted over and above the eye
Iq,
but we thought maybe
if you don't,
the prefrontal average and the Iq and
you added them to to predict grade,
say that's a regression analysis they
both added in so they predict,
they predicted different parts of the
variation.
It added additional youth necessary
information.
However,
if you took all the neuropsychological
tests and all the individual Iq tests
and you put them in one data set and
then extracted out a single factor is
that will be fluid intelligence,
roughly speaking,
that predicted grades very well.
And then what was leftover didn't
predict it all.
So what we concluded was that
neuropsychological tests,
prefrontal cortical tests,
test intelligence,
and they test a slightly different thing
than fluid intelligence tests do.
But that isn't because they're testing
something different.
It's because fluid intelligence tests
the way they're currently constituted.
Don't sample the universe of potential
questions as well as they should.
So it wasn't that we discovered
something different.
We discovered a measurement error
roughly speaking that only took five
years.
By the way,
it took five years to figure that out.
It was very annoying because when we
started,
I was trying to predict grades,
you know,
and I didn't know the ICU literature
very well at that point because
psychologist don't usually teach it very
much because Iq bothers the hell out of
everybody.
And so,
and the neuropsychologist who have their
own field are,
you know,
they are motivated to make the claim
that they've discovered something new.
And I just took that on face value.
But then we tried to predict like,
okay,
if I'm going to predict how well you do
at your job,
well I want to get a good cognitive
measure because if it's a complex job,
because if it's a complex job that keeps
changing and you have to learn to keep
up and if you can't do that,
you're not going to do very well.
So that would be bad for you and it
would be bad for everyone around you.
And so we were trying to pick up
additional information that would enable
that,
the accuracy of that prediction to be
increased and looked at the neuroscience
literature.
But at most it was an ambivalent
success.
Okay.
So how does that relate to this?
Well,
at the bottom tier where it's the most
differentiated,
you have single tests and there are only
correlated with each other at about
point to maybe 0.3.
So you might say,
well,
they're all measuring different things.
It's,
they're not,
they're all measuring the same thing
badly.
And then you might clump them.
So let's say I ask you,
Oh God,
maybe I give you a test that,
uh,
asks you,
tested your vocabulary with six letter
words and then I gave you another test
that tested you vocabulary with seven
letter words and another one that tested
you vocabulary with eight letter words.
And I said,
well,
those are all different tests.
Well,
they would correlate quite high,
not perfectly,
but I could clump them together and make
one sort of super test out of them.
And then I could take super test a and
super testy and super test B C and look
at the correlations between those.
Those would climb to about 0.5 or 0.6
and then if I clump the super tests
together,
which would be happening by the time we
got destroyed him to there,
then the correlation between the tests
would start to rise to about 0.7 and
then if I collapsed all the super tasks
into a single measure,
then the correlation between any of
those stratum to tests and g cause that
would be the highest level thing.
G is general intelligence.
That's roughly speaking fluid
intelligence.
The correlation between any of the super
tests and gene would be about 0.8 so the
point of all this,
there's no way of discussing this sort
of thing without doing it statistically
and technically because there's
statistical and technical processes.
So what happens is is that now let's say
now you have a measure of fluid
intelligence.
Okay,
you've got this measure and you take one
of the stratum two sets of tasks and you
use both to predict academic
achievement.
What happens is that the super factor g
kills the rest of them.
You're just not going to be able to find
any of the tests in the bottom strata
that are going to add to the prediction
of what the general factor can give you.
Now with with with personality,
that's just not the case.
You can't pull out a single factor that
predicts how personality is going to
influence jobs.
You know,
performance across your life.
If you add neuroticism,
if you take the single factor and you
add neuroticism,
neuroticism is going to kick the single
factor out.
Conscientiousness is going to kick the
single factor out and so forth because
there isn't a single factor.
It's not,
the tests aren't highly correlated
enough to say that they're all measuring
the same thing to some degree.
The personality traits really are
different.
You know,
you can clump them into plasticity and
stability,
but even there,
your loot you,
you're maintaining a lot of validity.
So if I took stability and then he and
used conscientiousness to predict job
performance,
conscientiousness would wipe out
stability.
It'd be a better measure.
But you never get that virtually.
Never get that with the lower tests in
the EICU stratum.
Okay.
Now,
yeah.
Well,
I just talked to you about that.
So that's,
that's a,
that's a good representation of how
these things are associated.
So at the bottom you have the single
tests and then they,
they chunk into say sequential
reasoning,
quantitative reasoning,
and induction on the fluid intelligence
size side in general,
knowledge and language development.
On the crystallized intelligence side,
that's the red.
And then they're all subsumed underneath
fluid intelligence,
which is the measure that you really
want to have.
Okay.
So what good is that?
Well,
it basically correlates 0.5 with major
life outcomes,
and that's 25% of the variance.
And maybe you can get it a bit higher
than that,
but we'll just stick with 0.5 as a,
as a representation.
And so let's say,
let's say you take a bunch of students,
a hundred of them,
and you want to sort them into those who
will pass a class with a 50% failure
rate.
Okay?
So you just pick the brandable,
you're going to pass,
you're going to fail,
you're gonna fail.
So that's no knowledge.
I have no predictive dominant you
whatsoever.
So my validity,
the validity of my classification is
basically going to be equivalent chats,
zero,
right?
I'm only going to have a 50% chance of
picking who passes and who fails.
If I used Iq,
if I had all your Iq scores and I did
the prediction,
I'd get right 75% of the time.
So it's a huge difference.
It cuts the failure rate in half by
using Iq.
Iq is a very good predictor of health
and it's a predictor of longevity.
It's a predictor of resistance to post
traumatic stress disorder.
It's a predictor of obviously
occupational status.
It's a predictor of educational success.
That's a predictor of income.
It's very powerful predictor.
And here's another way of
conceptualizing its effect.
So imagine that you could choose how you
were going to be when you were born.
This is in North America because it's
going to vary by society,
at least to some degree.
You get to be born into a family that's
at the 95th percentile for wealth or you
get to be born at the 95th percentile
for intelligence,
who's better off at the age of 40.
And that answer is the person who picks
being born with an Iq in the 95th
percentile at birth.
It's more powerful predictor of longterm
life outcome then familiar wealth.
So,
and it shows up everywhere.
Like one of the things we did recently
was looking at disgust,
sensitivity.
We're going to talk a little bit about
that when we talk about
conscientiousness because orderly people
seem to be more sensitive to discuss the
disorderly people.
That seems to be why they're orderly.
But the higher you are in Icu,
the less disgust sensitive you are.
Now,
we don't know exactly why that is.
Maybe it's because,
you know,
maybe you could make the inference that
Iq is,
is in related in some way to the
physiological integrity of the cortex.
You know,
rather than the limbic system,
which you know,
is the source of say,
emotions and motivations.
Um,
and the,
the more powerful it is,
the more inhibitory capacity.
It has over the more fundamental
motivations and emotions you could make
that case.
The problem is is that intelligent
people don't necessarily seem to be any
less impulsive.
So,
and you can have pretty vicious
personality disorder that's
characterized by extremely disorganized
behavior and a complete inability to put
longterm plans into operation and still
have a high Iq.
So what are the things we really can't
figure out?
It's just a hell of a thing to try to
figure out is like the relationship
between Iq and industriousness.
Zero.
And that just makes no sense to me
because most of the brain models are
predicated on the idea that your ability
to engage in longterm planning is a
factor that's associated with
intelligence.
But then industrious people seem to not
only engage in longterm planning,
they seem to do it right so that if
they're more industrious,
they put their plans into operation,
then the plan is actually work.
But it's not correlated with Iq.
So then I can't figure out,
well obviously the industrious person in
some ways able to regulate their own
behavior,
you know,
well they're not procrastinating,
for example.
And you'd think that that the ability to
not procrastinate would be a cognitive
feature,
but it doesn't seem to be and we have no
idea what makes people industrious and
we can't figure it out.
So it's this incredibly potent
predictor.
It's just about as powerful as Iq and we
have no idea what it is.
So,
so if you,
you know,
if you think,
if you have a smart idea about that and
you want to pursue it like feel free
because there's a big mystery there that
no one's been able to crack and we'd
been added for a long time and have had
almost no success.
You know,
we had people do things like give them
sentences of ends am's and use sort of
randomly distributed and then we'd have
them count the use,
you know,
like a whole page of sentences.
They're not sentences,
they're just strings of letter count the
use,
how useless.
You know,
you'd think that someone industrious
would do that better.
It's like they don't,
that's an Iq test.
And people who co can count the used
faster have hierarchy,
almost everything that you would do that
would,
where it has to do with manipulation of
abstractions of any sort.
Even something that basic seems to be
fundamentally associated with Iq.
People with hierarchies have slightly
bigger heads.
If you control for body size,
they have slightly bigger brains.
the axons on their neurons are a bit
thicker so that the electrical messages
seem to travel a little bit more
efficiency efficiently.
They are slightly faster in simple
reflex tests.
So it goes right down to the level of
cause are simple reflex light goes on,
pushing buttons.
There's not many neurons mediating that
response.
You know,
chains of neurons.
There's only a few neurons communicating
so that you can do that.
But even at that relatively simple
processing level,
Iq is associated with speed.
So there's a physiological component.
You're less likely to develop
Alzheimer's disease if you have a high
Iq.
And maybe that's because your brain is
just more robust,
you know,
so you could sustain damage,
say of up to 50% of your brain and you
wouldn't even show it if you're,
if you have a sufficiently high Iq.
Whereas if you're,
you know,
if you're on the bottom end of the Eicu
distribution,
you're much more,
you seem to be much more susceptible to,
to physiological damage.
Um,
nutrition is a big predictor of Iq
variation.
So,
and a lot of that's been hammered out of
modern,
you know,
so 150 years ago,
people's Iq was pretty tightly
associated with their nutritional
status.
But now,
you know,
there are very few people in North
America who don't have enough to eat
even though there's some variation in
quality of diet and that's flattened out
a lot of the,
uh,
cultural variability and an
intelligence.
Okay.
So this is a,
um,
this guy named him.
He'll did this paper to American
psychologist a while back and one of the
things he was interested in doing,
remember we talked about effect sizes,
right?
How big is an effect in psychology or
the social sciences in general.
And people have used rules of thumb that
0.5 was a moderate effect and 0.3 was a,
you know,
a minimal effect.
And 0.2 was uh,
you know,
starting to diminish to the point of non
utility,
but what hand pld had instead of
guessing,
because that was just a gas,
was actually go and look at papers that
were published in psychology to see what
effects sizes are we're being reported.
So it's an empirical analysis of how big
the effects that psychologists and other
social scientists report.
And so what he found was that
mmm,
the highest third of papers.
So that the third of papers that had the
biggest effects reported effects from
0.35 to 0.78.
Um,
the middle third from 0.2,
one to 0.33 and the lower third from 0.2
to point to one.
So then was there another,
yeah,
if you look on the left side here,
you see that and are of less than 0.15
characterizes the first quarter of
published studies and R of 0.15 to 0.35
the next core tile.
So 50% of psychological studies report
and are of less than 0.35
90% report and are of less than 0.5 and
only seven to 8% reported in our 0.5 or
above.
So what that means is that the
relationship between Iq and say academic
performance or longterm life income is
higher than that reported in all but
about 5% of psychology studies.
Okay.
So here's an interesting,
you might say
again,
in order to determine whether something
exists,
you have to be able to measure it and
then it has to be good for something.
So it has to be
grippable and it has to be usable as a
tool.
We'll save for it.
For the sake of argument,
what sort of Iq do you need for what
kind of job?
Um,
this was derived from a company called
wonderlic and wonderlic does employment
testing.
Psychologists usually don't use the
wonderlic test.
It's a relatively short Iq test and it's
a good test,
I think don't use it because it was
developed commercially,
but we tested the the wonderlic code lot
and it has excellent psychometric
properties.
It's a very good Iq testing,
probably errors a little bit in testing
crystallized Iq rather than fluid Iq,
but we won't argue about that for the
time being.
All right,
so if you have an Iq from 130 116 to 130
that puts you in the 86 to 95th
percentile,
right?
So that means you're minimally,
if there were eight people in a room on
average,
you'd be the smartest person.
Okay.
I should tell you,
just so you know that
if you're a state college student,
we use the u s as an example because
there's more differentiation between the
American universities in terms of
quality.
Then there is the Canadian universities.
If you're in an a,
if a,
if you're in an average American
postsecondary institution,
your Iq is 115 and so you know,
you think that's not all that bright,
but that's brighter than seven out of
eight people in the general population.
And so there are as many people,
if you look at the North American
distribution,
so we have the 50th percentile in the
middle of the normal distribution.
You have the 85th percentile here and
you have the 15th percentile here.
It's about 70% of people fall between
the 15th and the 85th percentile.
All right?
At the 50th percentile,
you're,
you're not really very literate.
And so what that means is that in the
United States there's just as many
people who aren't literate as there are
people who are in college.
And what I would mean by literate is not
so much like here's a bare bones
definition of literate.
You could follow written instructions.
And so what that means is it's kind of a
twofold issue,
right?
You can,
you can make out the words and the
phrases and the sentences,
but then you can translate them into
actual action.
You can use the information and an 85
you're going to have not a very good
time doing that.
And so when you're wondering things
about the way society is structured and
white people you know are not,
don't necessarily make the most
intellectually sophisticated choices.
One thing that's very much worth
remembering is that there's just as many
people who are functionally illiterate
in North America as there are people who
are in,
you know,
tier one colleges.
It's quite shocking.
Anyways,
okay,
so you want to be an attorney,
a research analyst and editor and
advertising manager,
a chemist,
an engineer and executive assistance
analyst and auditor.
So you're up in the profession levels
there.
You need an Iq of at least 116 and so
130 would be better.
My suspicions are that the average Iq of
people in this room is about one 20 to
one 25 it might be a little higher than
that.
It's hard to measure Iq in the ot
population because a lot of people have
English as a second language.
And so that,
that makes it harder to,
you know,
it's harder to measure crystallized
intelligence,
obviously using an English language
test.
But that's,
we found when we've done our studies at
the uft that the average exceeds one 20
so you know,
so you guys have the cognitive power to
basically pursue professional level
careers.
Um,
from one 10 to one 15 manager,
supervisor,
programmer,
teacher,
general manager,
person,
purchasing agent,
registered nurse sales account
executive.
These are actually empirically derived
by the way.
So the wonderlic company has tested a
very large number of people.
And so these are the,
the actual averages of the professions
that they are describing.
It's not hypothetical.
Okay.
108 to 103 two,
108 so that's the 60 to the 70th
percentile clerk,
customer service Rep,
computer operator,
medical debt collectors,
secretary accounting,
clear general sales,
telephone sales,
assistant manager,
credit clerk,
drafter,
designer,
bookkeeper.
There's a lot of white color,
like low level entry level white color
jobs in that particular category.
So that would be the brighter people
among the high school students who
didn't go to college and university Iq.
This is dead average 50th to the 55th
percentile.
Police officer,
receptionist,
cashier,
general clerical staff inside sales
clerk meter reader,
printer teller,
data entry,
electrical helper,
dispatcher in general office.
So that's right at 195 to 98 so that's
the 42nd to the 45th percentile.
Quality Control Checker,
claims clerk,
security gardner,
unskilled labor.
So look,
the unskilled laborers are up at 95th to
98 right?
So that's,
you're still at unt,
the unskilled labor level,
you're still have an Iq that's higher
than 40% of the population.
Arc,
welder,
diasend or mechanic medical,
dental assistant Iq,
87 to 93 messenger factory production
worker Assembler,
food service worker,
nurses aid,
warehouseman,
custodian,
janitor,
material handler and packer.
Okay,
so now what you see happening,
the difference,
it looks to me like you can do job,
you can count conceptualize jobs most
simply with a two by two matrix.
Okay,
so there's managerial administrative
jobs and creative jobs.
That's the first one.
And then there's low complexity.
High complexity.
And so what you're starting to fall into
at the 21st to the 30 percentile.
So that's still one person in three are
low complexity,
managerial jobs.
And so what I mean by that is that if
you're in a low complexity job,
imagine you're responsible for 30
things,
but roughly speaking,
it's the same 30 things all the time.
And roughly speaking,
they have to be taken care of the same
way each time.
So you have a finite domain of
responsibility and you can master it and
Iq will predict how fast you master it.
But once you master it will predict how
well you do.
What happens then in all likelihood is
that conscientiousness starts to
predict,
or maybe emotional stability starts to
predict or some of the other personality
factors start to become more important.
So,
but at 87 to 93 you're down at the level
of custodian and janitor.
And then that's that.
And that's not so good because you have
the bottom 15 to 20% of the population
who aren't quite,
who haven't,
who don't have the cognitive ability at
that level.
And so one of the things that you're
going to hear a lot about as you get
older is reasons for unemployment.
And one of the prime reasons for an
employment in the future is increasingly
going to be that there is just nothing
for someone of that level of
intelligence to do.
And this is partly why people hate Iq
because you think that is a nasty,
nasty thing to conclude.
I'd be telling you a story.
So I had a client at one point who I
suspect he had a verbal Iq of about 85
and a nonverbal Iq that was lower.
Um,
he had other psychological issues,
but,
but we'll just concentrate on that one
for the time being.
And you know,
he had a hard time finding a job.
He was socially anxious and that didn't
help.
But you know,
even if he could overcome that,
it was very difficult for him to master
the basic skills that were involved in
what you would consider even relatively
straightforward tasks.
So I spent a lot of time trying to find
him a job,
which is insanely difficult.
He went to the government first to get
help and they told him to,
you know,
type up his resume on a computer and
distributed.
It's like,
well,
that wasn't very helpful because he
didn't know how to use a computer and he
wasn't going to type up his damn resume.
And you know,
it was,
if you want to get a job,
go out and do the things that it would
take to get a job while yeah,
if you can do that,
then you don't have a problem.
And so the government agencies were
completely useless,
you know,
and they were staffed by people who
would assume that if you didn't do what
you were advised to,
that you just didn't want to have a job
instead of ever thinking that maybe you
couldn't do it.
It's not that easy to use a computer.
You know?
So I,
and then I tried to get him a volunteer
job.
Well,
you bloody well forget about that
because it's harder to get a volunteer
job than it is to get a real job.
And the reason for that is that you have
to step through a number of complex
bureaucratic hoops,
including having police check.
And you know,
first of all,
that's intimidating as hell for people,
even if they haven't done anything
wrong.
And second,
it's not that straight forward.
You know,
it involves maneuvering through a
complicated bureaucracy.
And that's not the only step.
There's all sorts of other steps.
So volunteer work,
that's how it man,
that's,
that's just not gonna happen.
Not generally speaking.
And then I found him a job helping a guy
out who had a,
a bicycle shop.
Slash.
Bookstore.
It was kind of a strange combination,
but it was a government subsidized
temporary position.
And then he did a good job at it.
He could,
he,
he was reshelving books and that sort of
thing.
And so he was reliable and he could do
that.
But you know,
the subsidy program ended.
And of course if you run a bike shop,
slash,
bookstore,
it's not like you have additional money
to hire someone because you know,
those are,
that's a store that's just not going to
be generating maybe any income.
But certainly not enough to hire
someone.
So that fell apart.
Then I did a bunch of con,
I did,
made a bunch of personal contacts with
charity organizations to see if I can
get them a volunteer position.
I finally got him a volunteer position.
So,
and uh,
then I went with him to train him at the
volunteer position and that was so
enlightening.
So what he had to do was he had a stack
of pieces of paper here and then a stack
of envelopes here.
And in principle,
the pieces of paper,
which were letters were in the same
order as the envelopes were.
And so what he had to do was fold the
pieces of paper three times and stuff,
the folded piece of paper into the
envelope and then seal the envelope and
then put it here.
But it was a bit more complicated than
that because sometimes the letters were
in French and sometimes they were an
English.
So what that meant was that he had to
watch and see that the French envelopes
went into this stack and the English and
envelopes went into that stock.
So that's one degree of complexity,
right?
But then it also turned out that those
damn envelopes had to be run through an
automatic letter sorting machine.
Now you might think,
well that doesn't matter,
but it does matter because those things
have very tightly defined tolerances.
And if you
make a mistake,
imagine you fold a piece of paper and
the first time you fold it,
you made a mistake of an eighth of an
inch.
And then the next time you fold it,
you make another eighth of an inch
mistake.
That means your piece of papers now one
quarter inch out of true
and then you stuff it in the envelope
and folded,
but you crinkle the envelope.
And so then the envelope gets stuck in
the automatic processing machine.
So I taught him probably 20 hours how to
fold this piece of paper into three,
you know,
and he was a bit shaky and he just
didn't have the motor fine motor ability
or the cognitive ability to do that.
And then I'll end with this,
we need finally couldn't do it anymore.
What happened was the letters came with
photographs attached to them.
And then he had the full,
the pieces of paper around the
photographs in a way that different
crumpled the photographs so that they
could still fit into the envelopes.
And each photo was,
you know,
stapled maybe half an inch different per
piece of paper.
So then he had to fold them properly
with a different folding technique for
every piece of paper.
And he had to sort them into French and
English and then also with the envelopes
and the papers ever gone out of sync,
which they did now.
And then he had to figure out how to
sort the envelopes and the pieces of
paper to make sure that they were
matched with the proper,
you know,
who they were matched with the proper
envelope.
It's like no,
that was the end of it.
And so I'm telling you the rest of his
story later.
So anyways,
you know,
there,
there is,
the moral of the story is if you're
smart,
you're privileged and it's thank God,
make use of it.
And if you're on the low end of the Iq
of distribution,
man,
you've got one tough life ahead of you.
It has nothing to do with willingness to
work or virtually nothing.
So,
and it's a good thing to know,
even though it's horrible.
Yeah.
Entrepreneurial.
Yup.
No problem.
I just want.