The Bible is a series of books written,
edited,
and assembled over thousands of years.
It contains the most influential stories
of mankind.
Knowledge of these stories is essential
to a deep understanding of western
culture,
which is in turn,
vital to proper psychological health as
human beings,
our cultural animals,
and to societal stability.
These stories are neither history as we
commonly conceived that nor empirical
science.
Instead their investigations into the
structure of being itself and calls to
action.
Within that being,
they have deep psychological
significance.
Hi everyone.
I just wanted to make a quick video to
remind everyone or let everybody who's
watching know that I'm starting my
series on the stories of the Bible,
the psychological significance of the
stories on the Bible.
On Tuesday,
May 16th at the Isabel Bader theater in
downtown Toronto.
I'll put the address and everything at
the bottom of the video.
In the description.
I want to delve into the biblical
stories from a psychological perspective
and I've wanted to do it for a long time
and have done it in part in my maps of
meaning series,
but the biblical stories are are what
their canonical in relationship to the
rest of our culture.
It's very difficult to understand
Western civilization itself,
unless you're grounded in the biblical
stories there.
There are like a precondition for
knowledge of the humanities and and
knowledge of history for that matter and
so I want to improve my understanding of
them and share what I'm able to figure
out with everybody that I can and so I
wanted to just make a quick video to let
everyone know that I'm going to run a 12
week series about two hours lecture per
week,
starting May 16th and running until
approximately mid August pretty much
every week except a couple where I
couldn't get the theater.
It's really nice theater,
so that would be good.
I'd also like to let everybody know that
the videos will be a taped a thanks to
my patron subscribers and put on youtube
probably within a week or two after I
initially showed them as soon as we can
get them edited and all of that.
So anyways,
there's still season tickets left.
That's the tickets that will allow you
entrance to all of the lectures and
their individual tickets left for each
lecture as well and you can get those at
Jordan b Peterson Dotcom.
But as I said,
I'll put all the instructions and the
details in the description of the video
below.
So I'm tuned in on Youtube if you're
inclined to and if you're in Toronto and
you'd like to see them live,
then come down and see them live.
It should be really interesting.
I hope that's the plan anyway,
so thanks a lot and uh,
hopefully we'll see you there.
Otherwise.
Well you'll see them on youtube and
that's good too.
Thanks a lot.
Bye.