So there's,
there's a paper you're supposed to read
this week was gray marble of the limbic
system and Basal Ganglia.
It's a hard paper,
but it's easy compared to the optional
paper,
which was Swanson.
And I had everybody read that last year,
but you know,
people were basically having
convulsions.
And so I decided that it wasn't really
fair to get you to read it.
However,
I would very much recommend that you
read it and because it's a bloody
brilliant paper and you'll,
you'll learn so much from it that it'll
be worth,
especially if you're interested in the
scientific element of psychology at
Swanson.
He's a smart guy and that's a great
paper.
And one of the things I really liked
about it,
and this is what I'm going to an end
about grey's papers as well as be there,
they're there,
they're describing brain physiology and
the relationship between that physiology
and behavior in a way that's
sufficiently sophisticated so that I
actually think it's psychologically
revealing.
It's,
it's so,
it's,
it's useful and important to know these
things.
And I think what's happening,
you know,
I've been thinking more and more that
that hierarchy that I've showed you guys
over and over,
I really think that that's basically a
map of the unconscious.
It's something like that.
And it's not that hierarchy I showed you
isn't obviously a fully worked out
representation of the unconscious,
but it's,
it's not a bad schemata.
And I think what it's missing is that,
you know,
the at near the bottom where you have
the actual actions,
those actions are actually sequenced
into what you might call motor melodies
that have a perceptual frame associated
with them.
And then those are nested inside
fundamental motivational systems.
And Swanson's paper does a lovely job of
detailing the,
the physiological substrate for that,
you know?
So basically what he shows is that the
nervous system is built up of
hierarchical models that started in the
body that basically start with spinal
reflexes.
You know,
the sort of quick and dirty spinal
reflexes that cause your,
your,
your people think of their brain is in
their head.
It's like,
no,
there's a big part of your brain in your
head,
but a huge part of it's distributed
through your body.
So I re I re,
I remember reading and I hope this is
correct,
that there are more neurons in your
autonomic nervous system,
then there are in your central nervous
system and the autonomic nervous system
is distributed throughout the body and
it's the part of the nervous system that
governs all the things.
You're too stupid to take care of,
like how your liver works and how your
heart should stay beating and how you
digest food and it's,
you know,
complicated things that consciousness
isn't capable of dealing with and you
don't want to,
you know,
you don't want to downplay the
complexity of those sorts of functions.
There are so important that evolution
does let you mess around with them.
So,
and then,
um,
you know,
the,
the voluntary motor system and the
sensory system.
So the central nervous system,
well,
you know,
your spine is fairly hefty bit of neural
tissue and then of course the neurons
themselves distributed through your
body.
So really your brain is distributed
through your body.
And there's also a tremendous number of
neurons in your gut as well.
And some of those seem to actually
produce information that might actually
even acquire consciousness.
Now,
I don't necessarily mean at the gut
level,
but it certainly informs you.
So,
so Swanson's basic proposition is that
it's a piagetian proposition.
You know,
that you lay out these initial reflex of
behaviors and then they're sequenced
into more complex melodies.
The,
the,
uh,
you know,
the lowest level,
highest resolution behaviors you
practice and practice until you're an
expert at them.
Like,
you know how to graph,
you don't have to figure that out.
So you've got these elements of behavior
that you can basically parcel off to
automated systems.
And some of those automated systems are
so automated that they're handled by
very low brain areas,
like spinal level.
So for example,
if you take out paraplegic person and
you and you,
uh,
have you take a paraplegic person and
you suspend them under the arms,
over a treadmill and tilt them forward,
they'll walk has pretty remarkable a
cause.
You wouldn't think that.
But walking isn't that complicated.
I shouldn't say that.
Walking could be,
can be handled by the spine.
Figuring out where you want to walk.
That's more complicated.
So higher order brain systems are
involved in that,
but so you think about it as a
hierarchy.
Now one of the things that that,
ah,
that Swanson really concentrates on is
this is the function of the
hypothalamus.
And uh,
she would tell you some things about the
hypothalamus.
It sorta sits at the top of the,
of the spinal cord and it's,
it's not that big.
It's a little bitty brain area,
although it's,
it's also not,
you know,
you gotta remember that when you hear a
word like hypothalamus or word like
emotion or word like brain,
those are low resolution words,
right?
The phenomena itself isn't homogenous.
And so if you look at the hypothalamus,
it's composed of modules.
And then those modules are composed of
modules.
And those modules modules are composed
of modules and all the way down to the
cellular level.
And then there's some modules there and
that goes all the way down to the
molecular level.
And then there's sub modules at the
So it's really,
really complicated.
And to think about it as a homogenous
system is just a low resolution
representation.
So the hypothalamus isn't an entity,
it's a group of functionally related
entities that are composed of groups of
functionally related entities.
But you know,
you can't start at the highest level of
detail and progress forward.
So we're going to use shortcuts.
So anyways,
the hypothalamus isn't a very big brain
area,
but it's an important one and it's
sufficiently sophisticated so that if
you take a female cat and there's an
important reason that it's female and
you take out basically it's whole brain,
the limbic system that's responsible for
emotions and the whole critical cap.
So it basically has no brain except for
his cord,
the hypothalamus.
And if you keep it in a relatively
closed environment,
you don't like a like a cage,
it pretty much acts like a normal cat.
It can do all the normal cat things.
It can,
it can engage in defensive aggression,
it can eat,
it can drink,
it can sleep.
It's Co,
it's conscious as you know in so far as
you can tell whether or not an animal is
conscious,
it's hyper exploratory,
which is extraordinarily peculiar
because the last thing you'd expect of a
cap with no brain would be to be hyper
exploratory.
Right?
It seems to be insanely curious about
everything and that's what that seems to
indicate is that it's psychomotor
exploratory system,
which is in fact grounded in the
hypothalamus is still active but it
can't build up the memory
representations that would inhibit the
exploratory activity because basically
what you're doing when you explore is
you're taking something something
complex and then your mapping.
It's responses in relationship to the
transformations of your body and in so
far as the set of transformations of
your body that you're likely to
manifest,
say in this place have zero motivational
relevance,
which is really what you're hoping for
most of the time.
Then you build up a representation of
the place that's,
that's part of that for septual motor
hierarchy and it shuts off your
curiosity about it.
And then what you perceived from then on
in really is your representation of the
thing rather than the thing itself.
And you're kind of happy about that
because it's easier to see what you've
already learned that it is to see the
thing itself.
Now things can get re novelized you know
if someone acts very peculiarly right
beside you,
you're like the whole space around you,
it's going to get renormalize very
rapidly and your body will go on alert
because of that.
But Mick,
basically what you're doing is learning
in order to ignore,
right?
Because you want and you want to play
attention to everything all the time.
It's like that's,
that's a short path to exhaustion
because if everything's relevant than
your body goes on hyper alert and you
produce cortisol and you know you're
ready for anything and there's,
that's kind of exciting.
But as a longterm survival strategy,
it's bad.
What,
you just don't have the energy to
maintain that for any length of time.
So part of the reason the cat is hyper
exploratory is because the systems that
mediate exploration are still intact as
long as it has a hypothalamus and some
of the rough underlying circuitry that
associates that with the motor output
system.
Um,
but it can't remember what it's
explored.
So just stays hyper exploratory.
It's also hyperreactive safety accuse of
aggression.
I would say like a hypothalamic cat is a
lot like a two year old,
you know,
and I mean that in the best possible
way.
Um,
two year olds that are extremely
curious,
they're hyper exploratory,
they're very,
very reactive to stimuli.
You know,
they cry easily,
they laugh easily,
they run around easily.
They,
they get scared easily.
you know,
experience pain easily.
So,
and it isn't until they built the higher
order structures in the,
in the,
you know,
perceptual motor hierarchy that that all
gets integrated and they're not so
reactive then they're nowhere near as
much fun at that point either,
you know,
but uh,
and so the female cat can,
can regulate it.
It's water intake and it can also engage
in sexual activity.
No male cat can't do that.
It needs more brain than just the
hypothalamus because it's more
complicated to sequence male sexual
behavior.
So you can tell the difference between a
male cat with no court tax,
let's say a no limbic system and a
female cat,
but pretty much only in that,
in that particularities.
So,
so,
you know,
so that's very interesting because if
you,
if you study neuropsychology and you're
taught by clinical neuropsychologist
say,
or even neuropsychologists that have a
clinical background,
they're very cortical centric.
You know,
and I think it's,
it's part of your hangover.
We're,
we're,
you know,
since we got unseated from our position
at the center of the universe,
we've been,
you know,
rat rat radically running around trying
to figure out what it is that makes us
special in relationship to animals.
And we kind of cottoned onto the idea
that,
you know,
we have this big cortical cap and
especially the prefrontal Cortex,
and it's very large in relationship to
our body,
which,
which it is.
And that,
you know,
somehow that distinguishes us from other
animals,
which it does.
But,
but that's also led us into thinking
that the most recently evolved parts of
the brain are the most important.
It's like,
and,
and in some sense the smartest,
you know,
but there's a real error of presumption
there because you might also,
you might think instead that it's those
parts of the brain that evolution has
had the longest time to work on that are
in fact the smartest,
you know?
And they do take care of all the heavy
lifting.
You know,
your,
your consciousness isn't entrusted with
any of the heavy lifting.
You can fiddle around the edges with it,
but you're not going to be allowed to do
anything that's really pr,
you know,
that's really physiologically profound
and it's a good thing because you just
don't have the intellectual capacity to
manage that kind of ongoing
physiological monitoring in all of us.
Like you don't understand your body if
you're lucky,
the thing works and you can ignore it
roughly speaking,
you know?
But if it ever goes wrong,
good luck trying to figure it out
consciously,
you know?
I mean,
we're getting somewhere with that,
but it's very,
very difficult to do so.
So we should think about the
hypothalamus for a bit because it seems
to be pretty damn important.
And so I would say,
you know,
people have wondered sometimes and
they've asked me,
you know,
where's the Super Ego and the ego and
the ID located in the brain.
And you know,
it's a stupid question and it's not a
stupid question at the same time,
um,
it's actually a useful question at one
level of analysis because you could say,
well,
the end from the Freudian is sort of
the,
the natural force that propels
motivation.
You know,
and,
and when we say motivation,
we're not saying much different than
saying in,
by the way,
you know,
it's the same kind of low resolution
word.
And it's clearly the case that we have
fundamental motivational systems and
that we do share them with animals and
that they do drive our behavior in it.
But they also drive our perceptions in
all the ways that Freud thought about,
you know,
and one of the things I really like
about the psychoanalysts is that they,
they never make the mistake of assuming
that a motivational system or an
emotional system is a mechanical system
that reacts to deterministically.
They say no,
those things are like personalities.
And that's,
that's much more sophisticated viewpoint
than the typical behaviorist or the
typical cognitive psychologist,
you know,
because they tend to think of the
computer in either stimulus response
terms.
So it's basically deterministic chains
or as if the,
the,
the information processing system is a
computational apparatus,
which it is.
But it's not only that,
you know,
it's an embodied computational apparatus
and the body is a very sophisticated
thing.
You know,
it's,
it's been very difficult for us to build
embodied robots.
And it's also the case that until you
build embodied robots,
the things don't really get smart.
You know,
you have to have a body for the thing to
actually have any intelligence.
And that was actually figured out by a
robotics engineer named Rodney Brooks
back in the 1990s 92 93 published a
couple of papers on that saying,
you know,
that if we were going to build
artificial intelligence,
we shouldn't start from the top down.
We shouldn't build a world modeling
machine.
And then embedded in something that
moves around,
we should build something that sort of
moves around semi autonomously,
like a stupid insect.
Insects aren't stupid.
So I do mean as stupid insect and if we
could manage that,
we'd really be doing something,
you know,
and I think we've,
you might've gotten beyond the stupid
insect level of,
of robots so far.
Um,
and you know,
it starting to ramp up really fast,
but it's in large part because the
things are embodied.
And so because it is the case as,
as we've discussed that your,
your perceptual,
your cognitive perceptual motor systems
have to be embedded in an output system
that can interact with the world in
order for them to be doing anything
that's actual or real.
So.
So anyways,
back to the hypothalamus.
Um,
roughly speaking and I'm no expert on
hypothalamic function and I had to pound
by way through Swanson's paper because
it's quite complex,
you know,
but the hypothalamus is sort of the
nexus between the brain,
the mind and the body.
That's one way of thinking about it.
And it's very good at monitoring your
body,
the states of your body and it can
figure out basically when your blood
sugar's too low and when you need water.
And when you,
I don't exactly remember how it's,
uh,
associated with the regulation of
breathing because I suspect that that's
a different system and I don't remember
that being a sub component of the
hypothalamus,
but it does also regulate things like
sexual behavior and sex,
sexual attraction and temperature
regulation and excretion and,
and you know,
all the things that you would associate
with the basic biological functions that
come along with being a complex animal.
And,
you know,
we share those functions way down the
evolutionary chain.
You know,
we share a lot of the functions with
everything that moves,
approach and avoidance.
We share with pretty much everything
that moves.
And by the time you get to the higher
mammalian functions,
you know,
we share those with pretty much all
mammals.
That's partly why we can understand
mammals pretty well.
You know,
it's,
you can kind of have a lizard as a pet
and some of them are more social than
others.
But you know,
to really have a pad,
it has to be a mammal.
And it's even better if it's a social
mammal,
like a,
like a dog because you know,
you can understand dogs and they can
understand you cause they're
hierarchical animals and they have the
same roughly the same set of biological
functions that you do.
You know,
their brains are organized around smell
and not around vision.
And almost all animals are like that
except for people and maybe hunting
birds,
you know.
So that's one thing that really
distinguishes us from dogs,
but we're similar enough in or embodied
behavior so that we can directly relate
to dogs and you know,
they can even play and plays a circuit.
So there's a guy named Jaak Panksepp,
j a k Panksepp,
p a n k,
s,
e p.
P who I would roundly recommend that you
read if you're interested in in
behavioral neuroscience.
I think he's a genius.
He's sort of on par with gray as far as
I'm concerned.
And on par with Swanson and Panksepp I
believe discovered the play circuit in
mammals.
And so you know,
two thumbs up for him.
That's a big deal.
That's kind of like discovering a
continent from the psychological
perspective.
And it's a search.
It's a circuit that's separate from
exploration,
which is kind of interesting cause you
think about play as a form of
exploratory behavior,
but it's sufficiently different from,
from standard exploratory behavior that
it has a circuit that's devoted to it
and there's a lot of primary circuits,
you know,
and they're networked in with the rest
of the brain.
And obviously circuit is a,
you know,
a metaphor.
So I could say there's a lot of primary
subpersonalities.
They're like one eyed monster.
There's only one thing thereafter,
you know,
and there's a whole bunch of them.
And so roughly speaking,
they regulate the things.
I already mentioned that the
hypothalamus regulates defensive
aggression,
sexual behavior,
temperature,
regulation,
food and water intake,
excretion,
while then there's one for breathing,
then there's another for pain,
then there's another for anxiety.
Um,
and there's another for exploration and
there's others.
There's sensory modules as well.
You know,
there's a visual circuit and an auditory
circuit to know olfactory circuit and
the circuit gets devoted to taste and,
and there's a circuit that keeps track
of how your body is localized in space.
That's a parietal circuit.
And um,
what else is important?
Oh yeah.
There's a circuit that you can use to
abstractly model perceptual structures
and patterns of behavior before you
implement them in the world.
And that seems to be a higher cortical
function fundamentally.
And you associate that with the contents
of your consciousness.
There's a language circuit,
um,
though.
Oh yeah.
There's an empathy circuit that mediates
maternal behavior.
There's a hunting circuit that mediates
predatory behavior.
Um,
there's a circuit to check dominance and
subordinate subordination.
MMM.
There's a circuit that mediates
creativity and human beings.
There's a circuit that mediates social
activity.
So,
and,
and the,
the positive reinforcing nature of
social activity and that's quite tightly
expo associated with the exploratory
circuit.
Um,
let's see.
Well that's,
you know,
that's not too bad for beginning.
I'm sure I've missed some and I'll
remember them.
But,
and each of those subsystems is
important enough so that there's a neuro
architecture devoted to it.
Now some of those neural architectures
are flexible enough so that if they
don't develop in one brain area,
they'll develop in another.
So it's,
it's not exactly as if the location of
these functions is specifically
determined in advance before
development.
So for example,
if you have a baby and it has,
you know,
epilepsy and the epilepsy is really bad,
sometimes they'll take out the whole
left or right hemisphere.
And if they do that early enough doesn't
really seem to have much consequence for
the baby,
you know,
which is pretty weird.
You think?
Well,
half of the brain that problem fairly
useful.
But in some sense it's as if the
cortical elements of the brain are
territory that can be inhabited in
colonized by the lower levels of the
brain.
And so you could say that the lower
levels of the brain,
including the visual input systems,
would just as soon call a nice,
what we call the visual cortex.
But if there's no visual cortex because
it's been removed,
then they'll just go call tonight as
part of the auditory cortex.
You know,
and what you see in other situations
sometimes is that people have high,
high hydrocephaly.
And what that means is that their
cerebral spinal fluid builds up in their
brain.
And so the ventricles get very enlarged.
And so if you take an x ray or an MRI or
other sort of scan,
if these people,
you'll find that their entire skull is
full of water except for like a half
inch thin slice of court at old tissue
around the water,
like a balloon.
And one of the guys who was like that
had a phd in mathematics from Cambridge,
you know,
5% of his brain tissue was intact.
Now it was pretty active that 5% and you
could also be sure that it would not
have been very resilient to damage.
You know?
So part of the reason that we have an
excess of cortical tissue,
so to speak is because you know,
we need to be resilient to assaults and
trouble.
And it does appear,
perhaps this is,
this is,
this is the sort of discussion that got
Larry Summers kicked out of Harvard.
Um,
it looks like men are,
are somewhat more differentiated in
their cortical function than women.
And what that means is that there is a
very small subset of spatial skills that
men seem to have an advantage in.
But the price they pay for that is that
they're much more susceptible to a brain
malfunction and also to brain damage
because they don't have redundancy built
in to the same degree women do.
So,
and that's part of the reason why there
were far more boys who have learning
disabilities for example,
than there are women.
So
now people debate about that because
it's contaminated with concerns about
gender.
But,
um,
so,
okay,
so the brain's gone all these like
specialized sub circuits and they're
variable in their expression.
And what,
what that basically means is that on
average across people,
they're likely to be located in the same
place.
Now there's,
there's,
there's some discrepancies,
cause lefthanders are different than
right handers and people also have mixed
dominance.
And so their brains can be organized in
ways that are not exactly cononical.
So we're saying roughly speaking,
and it extends,
it extends in some weird ways to
phenomena that you wouldn't necessarily
think could possibly be organized in
that manner.
So for example,
the part of the brain that you use for
silent reading and the visual Cortex is
back here and then the auditory cortex
is about here.
And then the part of the brain that you
use for silent reading is where the
auditory and the visual cortex overlap.
So that's pretty cool.
So what it means is that you look at
words and you hear them because your
eyes are using the auditory cortex as a
representational structures.
So that's pretty cool.
And so it turns out that people who
silent read pretty much used the same
brain area to do that.
And so you might think about that as
biological preparedness in some sense.
But of course people didn't learn to
read silently til 500 years ago,
roughly speaking.
You know,
even the earliest literate people,
most of them read out loud,
silent reading was a very,
very rare phenomenon.
Julius Caesar could read silently and
people thought that that was part of his
magical power because it's,
well it's pretty damn weird.
You know that you can use your eyes to
here,
you know,
cause you can all do it.
You think,
yeah,
anybody can do that.
But you know,
it's a pretty new thing on the
evolutionary horizon and to be able to
hear with your eyes,
it's like good work guys.
That's,
that's not an easy thing to manage.
So,
so anyways,
the brain is,
has specialized subsystem,
but it's a dynamic biological systems so
you can muck about with it quite a bit
and it'll set itself up in slightly
different ways.
So the systems aren't necessarily
localized exactly the same place in
every one.
But roughly speaking,
everyone has those systems and roughly
speaking,
they're in the same place across people.
Now.
There's a lot of variability and it's
one of the things that makes you know,
Mri studies in the light.
Very difficult to interpret because if
you average across a lot of people,
what it means is you blur things out,
you know,
cause you can only extract out the
commonalities and although you know
they're getting better and better at
dealing with that.
So
okay.
there's other ways that you can think
about the brain too.
These are all approaches to
understanding it.
You know,
there,
I would,
I would say it's a very,
very complex thing.
In fact it's the most complex thing
there is.
You know,
there are more patterns of combinations
of neuro connections in your brain than
there are subatomic particles in the
universe.
So you are,
I know you,
you won't believe that because it
doesn't seem possible.
But you can do the math and you'll
figure out that it's actually right it.
So you're the most complicated thing
there is and by a lot.
And so in some sense there's more space
inside your head then there is space
outside your head.
It depends on how you conceptualize
space,
you know,
because you can conceptualize space as
the number of ways that something can be
configured and that state space,
and that's a,
that's a a magnitude measurement,
you know,
and the distance between things,
well that's another way of
conceptualizing space.
But if you're wanting,
if you want to think about big,
what's inside you is,
I think that it's bigger than what's
outside you.
It's certainly that way in terms of
complexity,
unless you factor in the other brains,
you know,
so.
So that's very much we're thinking about
means that,
you know,
what we don't understand about the brain
is going to fill many,
many books.
And one of the things we really don't
understand his consciousness,
people just don't get that.
And it doesn't really look,
you know,
you might think that consciousness is an
emergent late evolutionary function,
you know?
But it doesn't really look like that,
I mean,
even when people become demented and,
and they,
you lose almost all of their higher
cortical function.
There's no doubt there's still
conscious.
And so consciousness might be way,
way,
way older than we think.
And in fact,
I think it's highly probable.
I don't think a hypothalamic cat is
unconscious.
It's certainly a wake,
you know,
and distinguishing between awake and
conscious is no easy thing.
You might say,
well,
animals aren't conscious.
It's like,
well,
you know,
here's the thing.
You know what people norm normally think
is that humans are different than other
animals.
And so before you anthropomorphize an
animal,
you should be careful.
But I think that's complete rubbish.
I think it's exactly the opposite.
Before you assume that humans have
attributes that animals don't,
you have to prove it because there's
continuity,
tremendous,
tremendous continuity.
And so it's right to anthropomorphize
animals.
What's wrong is to presume a priority
that humans are qualitatively different.
Now there are some very bizarre things
about this.
Obviously,
you know these,
we have opposable thumbs,
that's a big deal.
We can grip things.
That's a massive deal,
you know,
and it turns out that there's another,
your,
your brain maps your body onto its
surface onto its motor strip and it's
sensory strip,
which are roughly here on the brain.
And if you take the motor strip or the
sensory strip and you make a
representation of how it represents the
body,
which is called a Homerun,
keyless wilder,
penfield wilder penfield still did this
first at mcgill university.
He,
I don't know if you know this and
perhaps you'll be fortunate enough to
experience it,
but people who have brain surgery are
conscious when it happens.
And that's so that the surgeons can
figure out whether this little part is
doing anything important before they
take it out.
You know,
it's getting very horrific thought.
But Penn field when he was,
he did some of the early psychosurgery
for epilepsy because in tractable
epilepsy,
sometimes the only thing to do is
radical surgery,
like a corpus.
You caught the Corpus callosum for
example.
So that the,
you know,
the electrical storm so to speak,
can't transmit across the hemispheres
and the whole brain won't be affected.
So,
but while he was doing that,
he used the little electrode to map out
the surface of the brain and he mapped
out the motor strip,
which is just behind the prefrontal
cortex.
And then the sensory strip,
which is just behind that to find out
how the body representatives or the
brain represents the body.
And basically what he showed was that on
the motor strip,
you know,
you're,
the thumb has as much representation as
your whole trunk.
So basically your thumb is as smart from
a motoric perspective,
smarter than you from here to here,
you know,
well try picking up something with your
back,
you know,
and you'll figure out exactly why that
is.
And the thumb basically has almost as
much representation as the rest of the
hand.
But the hands are like gigantic
balloons,
you know.
And the arms are a little skinny sticks
here,
theater fairly highly
represented,
especially in the sensory cortex because
you know,
you gotta be careful about what you,
what you step on.
And one of the things that's very
interesting about the representation of
the feet on the sensory strip is that
it's right beside the representation of
the Genitalia.
And so there's crosstalk.
And so some of you are pretty into foot
massages and that's why,
you know,
so it's,
it's,
it's a consequence of the overlap.
Now why that overlap is there,
I don't know exactly,
you know,
maybe,
maybe the brain had organized itself.
So particularly sensitive surfaces.
We're taking advantage of the same
tissue,
something like that.
But you know,
it's an interesting case of it's like
synesthesia and sent in a sense,
it's like sensory synesthesia.
So,
um,
as far as your brain's concerned,
your all hands and your hands are almost
all thumb and you're quite a bit of feet
and your lips are massive and so is your
tongue and your face is very highly
represented too.
So basically as far as your brain is
concerned with regards to sensory input
and motor output,
you're this huge face with great big
lips and tongue and you have massive
balloon like hands and your feet are
pretty big too.
And there's a fair bit of sensory
representation for the Genitalia as
well.
And then the body's hardly there at all.
So,
so that's kind of what a human being is
like,
right?
We're all thumbs in hands and we talk
about what we do with our thumbs and
hands all the time and we take things
apart with them.
And we put them together and then we
tell everybody else how we're doing
that.
And that's basically a human being.
And when you're thinking about the
difference between human beings and
highly encephalitis mammals like
dolphins and whales,
because people have claimed that
dolphins and whales are extraordinarily
intelligent and you know,
dolphins don't seem particularly simple
minded,
but look at the things they're in.
Like if they're in these test tube
shaped bodies,
what are they going to do?
Flip sand up into buildings?
It's like they can't manage that.
And so the embodied the,
the manner in which their nervous system
is embodied turns out to be
extraordinarily important when you're
trying to understand something like the
relationship between cortical tissue
mass and intelligence,
you can't just think about mind as
something that's floating like a soul in
space if it isn't stuck in something
that you can use,
it's not particularly good for anything
or anything that human beings would
regard as particularly intelligence.
Okay,
so that's kind of a,
Oh,
here's another way that you can think
about the brain and you can also think
about it as divided.
This is sort of a Schema that there was
more popular with the Russian
neuropsychologist,
but it's pretty good.
One,
you can think about the front part of
the brain is being concerned with motor
output.
And so there's the motor strip that
allows you to sequence activities and
then you know,
to make these kinetic melodies that are
chains of things that you know how to
do.
Um,
and then in front of that is the
prefrontal cortex and the prefrontal
cortex grew out of the motor cortex.
And that's pretty interesting because if
you think about that from an
evolutionary perspective,
what that implies is that thought is
abstracted action,
right?
Because that's where it came from.
And so basically what you're doing when
you're thinking is you're figuring out
action sequences that you could
implement and modeling their
consequences and evaluating them before
you implement them in behavior.
And that's why I think it was Alfred
North Whitehead though I should might be
getting that wrong.
He said,
uh,
we think so that our thoughts can die
instead of us.
It's a lovely way of thinking about a
day.
So it's sort of like we generate
abstract avatars of ourselves acting in
the world.
And if the Avatar does something stupid,
Bang,
we,
we kill it often and we don't implement
it in our own bodies.
That's smart.
So basically we're thrown off abstract
representations of ourselves so they can
perish instead of us.
It's pretty cool.
So also what you do when you're playing
video games.
So does anybody know where the word
Avatar came from?
Anybody?
Uh,
uh,
directly.
Yeah,
that's exactly right.
So an Avatar is the embodiment of the
daddy on earth.
He's such a cool idea.
It's so interesting that that would word
was,
was used to represent your fictional
self insight in a video game.
You know,
it's one of the mysteries about words.
You never know how those things get
generated or catch on,
you know,
but it's such a,
it's such an interesting idea that you,
you know,
you,
you limit yourself in some interesting
way and toss yourself into an abstract
world and you think that's really fun,
you know?
And then that thing dies and gets reborn
or does whatever the hell it wants to
do.
And you think that's very entertaining,
but the real you is behind that,
you know,
so you can toss off all,
uh,
what do you call,
pseudo selves in a sense and play about
with them without any real costs.
Few and maybe with some benefit.
And that the term for that is your
avatar.
That's very cool.
That,
so anyways,
it is an extension of what you do with
your capacity to abstract,
right?
Cause you're,
you're producing simulated worlds and
you act in a simulated way.
And,
and that's what you do when you were
imagining things,
you know?
So that's what you do when you write
books of fiction.
That's what you do when you go to a
movie.
And so all avatars,
one thing,
one form or another.
So some of those are archetipal avatars.
Okay.
So the way the Russians,
the Russians had a very,
very long and illustrious history of
producing psychologists.
And so,
and I'm hoping I'm getting this right to
Pavlov.
You know,
about Pavlov and Pavlov's dog.
Pavlov was Leery as instructor.
And luria was the instructor of Vinegar
Dova and socal off who discovered the
orienting response,
which we're going to talk about it a lot
because I think it's the most important
discovery that was ever made in
neuroscience.
Um,
they should have gotten a Nobel prize
for that for sure.
Um,
and then soak law of in vinegar,
dover were precursors to gray and great
wrote,
developed the most well thought through
theory of anxiety and incentive
motivation.
And so,
um,
you,
it's useful to kind of know that
developmental history luria was also
influenced by Piaget by the way.
And he was also influenced by a thinker
from mit called Norbert Wiener,
which is like the perfect name for
someone who goes to mit.
But anyways,
he was a real,
he was a real genius.
This guy,
what are the pioneers of artificial
intelligence research?
And he developed cybernetic of embodied
cognition and the cybernetic models are
the models that gray uses in his
neuropsychology of anxiety.
And so it's,
it's nice to know the history of the
development of these ideas because you
see how things connect behind the scenes
in ways that you wouldn't really think
possible took me years to figure out
those,
those intellectual connections by the
way.
So,
so if you remember them,
then you won't have to spend years
figuring them up yourself.
So anyways,
one of the ways that luria
conceptualized the brain was as motor
versus sensory.
And so the motor was the motor circuit
and then the prefrontal cortex.
And so that determined the range of
potentials that you could manifest in
time and space and also helped you
implement them.
And then the back of the brain basically
that rough,
roughly speaking,
the back half was the sensory half and
the sensory half is a lot of it's
auditory.
And again,
that's about here.
And a huge chunk of it is visual.
And then there's,
uh,
there's,
there's areas that are more central to
the brain that are much,
much older that are associated with
olfaction and taste.
Cause those are the,
has been around for a very,
very long period of time.
And the smell circuits in and taste
circuits are extraordinarily archaic.
So they're not part of the,
roughly speaking the sensory cortex.
So you can think of motor versus
sensory,
that sort of front versus back
distinction.
And then you can also think about a left
versus right distinction.
So,
and people often think of the left as
the linguistic hemisphere and the right
as the non-linguistic hemisphere.
And that's roughly accurate if you're
talking about lefthanded males.
And,
and it's roughly accurate for everyone
else too,
but,
but it's mostly accurate for them cause
there's more complications in brain
lateralization in people.
It's not a simple thing.
One of Leary,
a student's guide named El Conan
Goldberg,
came up with an alternative theory of
hemispheric function,
which I think is better.
Um,
he thought that the right hemisphere was
specialized for the initial stages of
novelty analysis and detection and that
the left hemisphere was specialized for,
um,
creation of the detailed responses to
those things and the storage of those
detailed responses,
particularly in the back of the,
in the back of the brain.
So he thought of the right hemisphere is
an anomaly detection.
And first stage modeling system that was
primarily under limbic control and he
thought that the linguistic capacities
of the left hemisphere,
we're merely a reflection of its
capacity to generate detailed
representations.
So,
and I,
I'm telling you that for a specific
reason because it's relevant to graze
model.
Okay.
Oh,
okay.
So I'm going to describe to you an
integration,
roughly speaking between Swanson's
mortal and graze model and the orienting
reflex mod models of soul,
clove and vote Victor Cordova.
Now
people started to get interested in the
lower levels of the brain.
Really I would say,
well the animal psychologists got there
first,
but there was a flurry of activity
around the hippocampus,
particularly in the 1960s and that was
begun first by the Russians who are
playing around with electrical,
um,
eeg analysis of brain function.
So I know your brain produces a lot of
electrical activity,
but a 100 watt light bulbs where
something like that,
when it's busily buzzing away on all of
the things that it does and you could
get some low resolution insight into
brain function by analyzing the
different patterns of electrical
activity it produces.
It's been likened to listening to a
symphony with a stethoscope stethoscope
through a six foot concrete shell,
which is approximately correct,
but it's an investigative technique that
has some utility.
Now.
It turns out that,
so imagine that I,
I did this to you,
I put you in a chair and I strapped eeg
electrodes to you.
And then now and then I have you
listened to a beep,
beep,
and then there'd be a little fraction of
time and I'd play a louder beep beep.
And then that was allowed to beat by the
way.
And then there'd be some beeps after
that.
And then if I did that to you a hundred
times and then I averaged the manner in
which your brain waves were manifesting
themselves across all those hundred
times,
I could extract out a particular pattern
of brainwave that was locked to that
stimulus.
And so then I could infer I couldn't,
I would first of all have the wave form,
which would have a temporal element and
I could actually do some calculations if
my instrumentation was sophisticated
enough about exactly where that wave
form was emanating.
So keep that in the back of your mind.
What soak glove and vinegar Dova started
investigating was.
So that was,
that's an electrophysiological
investigation.
What they started investigating with
something a bit simpler,
which was skin conductance response.
So it turns out that if I take you and I
put you,
this is what the scientologists used to
read in grounds.
By the way,
in case you're wondering,
um,
in grams or memory traces that are
theoretically left from the time that we
inhabited Venus,
I think that's their theories.
Um,
it's something like that.
So if I put you in a chair and I hook up
electrodes to your hands,
I can pass a current through the
electrodes through your skin.
And how well that current is transmitted
is going to depend on how much you're
sweating and how much you're sweating is
going to depend on how much your body is
preparing to act.
Because one of the things that happens
if it starts to prepare to do something
is that sweats a little bit.
And that's,
I presume,
because if you start acting,
you're going to get hot.
And so he might as well prepare to cool
yourself.
Now it happens very,
very fast.
So if I play a tone to you,
you're sitting there and all of a sudden
the tone goes off.
What will happen is that your skin
conductance will increase.
And then if I play the tone again,
it,
it'll increase again,
but less.
And then it'll increase again.
But last and then soon I can play the
tone to you and it's flat.
Now then if I take the tone and I
increased the volume,
or if I change the pitch,
or if I even changed the timing of it,
any little tiny change whatsoever,
and I play the tone to you,
bang,
the original response will be
reinstated.
So the Russians were thinking about
this,
they were thinking,
okay,
well what?
What does that imply?
And they thought,
well,
it has,
it's analogous to an earlier phenomenon
that was known as habituation.
So if you take a snail,
it'll come out of its shell and you tap
it,
then it'll go into a shell and then it
will slowly come out of its shell.
You can tap it again.
And if you're into teasing snails and
um,
if you do that enough,
the stale,
we'll just start to ignore you.
Now you could call that fatigue because
it might be fatigue or you could call it
habituation is what happens is the
sensory nerves are no longer sending a
signal to the motor nerves to make the
thing contract.
And so that's habituation.
It's a form of learning.
It's a form of learned irrelevance.
Now Soak love and vinegar Dova weren't
satisfied with the sort of odd
hermiticity that was implied by the
habituation models.
And so they came up with a slightly
different suggestion for what was
happening when the orienting response
yeah.
Was he was declining across time.
They suggested that what you did when
you were listening to a tone was to
build an interior model of the tone.
And that was,
it was a representation of the tone in
all of it's important dimensions in so
far as you were capable of doing that,
you know,
with your particular level of hearing
acuity and that you had inferred that
the tone was irrelevant.
So you've mapped it in the map says this
is safe territory,
and then when the tone occurs,
the map inhibits your response.
If something like that,
the model inhibits your response.
And so the idea would be you're always
carrying a model of the world around in
your head that you've learned and as
long as the world is behaving in
accordance with that model,
then you stay calm.
A very,
very smart idea.
And so the orienting reflects is that
initial response when something happens
that your map does not cover.
Okay.
And they localize that to the
hippocampus,
which is very good at them with their
primitive equipment.
Back in the 1960s these were very,
very smart people.
The Russians got there way before the
North Americans and they western
Europeans because who are the only ones
doing investigations into this sort of
thing at that time,
because the Russians had figured out
very early that the brain was stuck
inside the body and so that bodily
responses and emotional responses and
motivational responses were were valid
indexes of of brain activity.
It took the western neuropsychologists
till the 1990s really to start figuring
this out.
And it was Antonio Damasio who,
who led the way he,
uh,
he had generated this hypothesis called
the somatic marker hypothesis would be
that part of the way that you evaluate
things when they occur is by reading off
the report of your body.
You know,
cause it's going to react in various
different ways.
And that's going to tell you what the
thing is.
And the way reason he figured that out
was because he was reading abstracts
from Russian neuropsychologists and he
was the only one doing it in the late
eighties.
As far as I can tell though,
I was doing it too.
But that was because I read gray and
gray had done it.
So,
so anyways,
the Russians got there very early and it
was so clove and vinegar Dova that
basically is basically identified the
orienting response.
And the reason I think that deserves a
Nobel prize is because it's the bloody
thing that piaget was talking about.
You know how Piaget would say that a
child will run through its Schemas,
right?
And if the Schema produces something
novel,
you know,
so the kid is moving its arms and bang
it wax into a little immobile and the
child Sorta startles but says do it
again.
You know,
and so then it tries to do it again.
So it tries to replicate the emergence
of the phenomena by modeling it's
interactions with it and constructing a
psycho motor perceptual schema.
But the initial like burst of awareness,
that's an orienting reflects.
And so what soak love and vinegar Nova
discovered was how people reacted to the
unknown.
And that's a major thing man.
Because everything you learn is a
consequence of you interacting with the
unknown.
So,
you know,
it's a huge discovery and you know,
it's psychology is a funny science
because we never,
we've never really figured out when
we've discovered something that's really
worth discovering.
And,
but uh,
like the discovery,
the orienting reflects that was like a
home run milner olds and milner
discovered the reward system,
the incentive reward system.
When was that?
I think that was in the take.
That was in the early seventies it was
like that.
It was Nobel prize winning stuff too.
It's like it's the whole circuit for
positive emotion and exploration.
It's like that's a big deal to discover
that,
you know,
and then Panksepp discovered the play
circuit and that's another whopping
discovery.
Like I really do think these things are
equivalent to discovery continents.
It's a big deal.
But you know,
for some reason
I don't know what it is.
It's not modesty I don't think,
but let's,
psychologists don't seem to be that good
at figuring out when what they've
discovered is like a major league
discovery.
So.
All right.
Hmm.
So what happened with regards to Soak
Lovan Vinegar Dover?
There,
there was a whole flurry of,
of,
of ideas that their research generated.
A lot of that was among artificial
intelligence,
um,
investigators.
And what they basically concluded was
that the way that creatures work in the
world was that they produced expectancy
maps
of how the world would lay itself out
when they acted in a particular way and
then they would transform the mortal
internally.
This is probably how you think.
You think they transformed the model
internally and make a prediction about
what the outcome of their behavior would
be
and then that would manifest that
behavior.
So the idea is stimulus.
First of all,
the idea was stimulus response.
And that's actually true if you don't go
much above the spine.
So at the behaviors were,
we're right about that.
There are deterministic levels at which
the nervous system operates or or
roughly deterministic.
But as the amount of brain tissue
increases,
as the number of processing interfaces
the number of neuro connections between
stimulus and response increase.
The idea that it's deterministic starts
to fall apart because it's chained
complex chain networks of activity
between the,
you know,
the action or the stimulus and the
action.
But there are circuits that are really
simple.
It's just one neuron or two neurons and
those things are super fast and you need
them.
You know,
if you're going to jump out of the way
of the snake,
for example,
you're going to be sitting there
thinking about snakes.
It's like you want your eyes to activate
your spinal cord.
So you jumped to the side that's not
conscious.
It's like it's way too fast to be
So when we've,
we've conserved all those,
you know,
archaic systems because we need to be
fast and you can model the way those
archaic systems work by using the
standard tendance of behaviorism.
And you can get quite long way doing
that,
but you can't get everywhere.
So the mapping idea that I'm describing
is,
um,
mean in part it's,
it's the entrance of,
of cognition into the,
into,
into behaviorism.
It's part of it.
It was,
it was more complicated than that,
but that was part of it.
So,
you know,
and that kind of makes sense.
I suspect that's the way you think.
You think,
you know,
you see something,
you think about what it is,
you figure out what you're going to do
and then you do it.
And then it either works,
in which case that's great for everyone
or it doesn't work.
And then you have an orienting reflex
that was their basic idea,
you know,
and it's,
it's pretty smart idea.
It turns out to be wrong in many
complicated,
and I can't even tell you exactly why
it's wrong,
although I do know that part of the
reason that it's wrong is that it turns
out that it's way more complicated to
produce these damn models than anybody
thought because the behavior is to at
that point and Soak Lovan vinod grid
over we're behaviors.
They kind of had this implicit idea.
You think stimulus response.
Now in between that there's a black box,
right?
That's whatever the brain is doing.
They didn't care about that because they
didn't think you had to take it into
consideration.
But there's still two other elements of
that theory.
One element is there is a stimulus.
Another element is there is a response.
Well,
we won't go into the response part yet,
but we will go into the stimulus part.
It's like,
let's say that you look at someone
attractive and your heart rate
increases.
Okay,
what's the stimulus
exactly?
The person,
you know,
the person's eyes,
the way their eyes are configured in
relationship to the rest of their face.
Um,
older shape,
um,
context.
What's the stimulus?
And the answer is,
well,
who the hell knows?
Because figuring out what the stimulus
is turns out to be hard and the behavior
is they just pretended that no,
no.
Everything was made out of homogenous
blocks.
And when you looked at them,
there they were,
and that was the stimulus,
roughly speaking.
So they pretended,
they got rid of having to consider the
complexity of the brain.
Remember half year damn cortex is
devoted to seeing it turns out that
seeing is very difficult.
The behavior's just the funnest.
That by by just pretending it wasn't a
problem,
they just assumed the stimulus was
given.
So it was like,
there's the box,
there's a picture of the box on your
retina.
That picture is translated into the
little guy inside your hand.
And then he figures out how to move your
arms.
It's like,
well,
that's not right.
It's not right.
Because it's very difficult to specify
the stimulus.
It's extraordinarily difficult.
And that's part of the reason why it's
been,
it's taken so long to develop artificial
intelligence and you can't teach the
damn things to see.
And that's because there's no edges.
There's no lines.
There's no primary objects.
All of that is something that our brain
constructs for us on the fly
instantaneously.
So we think it's just there.
But some of you have probably played
with photoshop trying to adjust an image
chain.
It's like,
are there lines in that image or there
are,
there are edges.
It's like not at all.
You increase the resolution,
it just turns into a massive pixels that
are fundamentally indistinguishable from
one another.
Like if you,
if you take a photograph of someone and
you try to cut them out and put them
against a different background,
what you find right away is that you end
up with this cutout looking thing
because you're,
you're trying to make something into it.
A manipulable object that's segregated
from the world that actually isn't
represented that way in the photograph
at all.
You might see it that way and in fact
you do.
But if you start to play with the
representation,
you find that just like,
it's like,
it's pixels all the way down.
And so it's very hard and photoshop is
pretty damn sophisticated.
It'll do edge detection for you,
you know?
But it's,
it's Kinda rough.
It's,
it's,
it's not enough to fool your eyes.
So it's hard to see things.
So that was one of the,
that's actually one of the places where
behavior is,
which we will talk more about,
started to fall apart.
It was like,
oh,
it turns out the problem is a problem of
the stimulus is like way more
complicated than we thought.
And then it also turned out that the
problem of the behavior was way more
complicated.
So the basic,
so let's say you train a wrap to run
down the runway,
and the way you do that is you take the
rap and he make sure he's hungry.
Skinner's rats,
bf,
skinner,
he was like the dean of behaviorism.
His rats were starved to 75% of their
body weight.
So a Skinnerian rack was a weird rap.
It was really lonesome and isolated and
it was starving and so,
and so you could kind of treat it like a
one dimensional entity,
right?
Cause it would do anything for food.
So it was an extraordinarily hungry rat.
And then it was also an isolated frat.
So it was a simplified model of an
actual rat.
And that's a simplified model of a human
being.
And you know,
you might think that I'm not very fond
of the idea that you can model human
beings with rats,
but I'm actually extremely fond of it
because,
uh,
a rack is a way,
Barrett better model of who you are.
Then your model of who you are is a
model of who you are.
You know,
so a rat is a lot more like you then
you're thought of you is like you and
rats,
like give the guy some credit man.
Those things are smart,
you know,
and they are like us in many,
many,
many ways,
many important ways.
So you can get along way with a rat.
And I think I told you at the beginning
of this class is like part of the
pharmacology that a lobster uses to
determine its position in a dominance
hierarchy is the same pharmacology that
you use.
So you know,
you're quite a bit like a lobster,
but you're even more like Iraq.
So that's enough compliments for one
day.
So,
okay,
so so the behavior is modeled as simple
behaviors model didn't work out so well
and neither did the idea that in some
way you were generating a,
an accurate model of the world and then
you were comparing the actual world to
that model and that that's how you
planned your behavior.
There's lots about that.
That's true,
but but there's lots of boat.
If it isn't,
so anyways,
I'm going to treat it like it's true for
the time being because we can get quite
a long ways with low resolution theories
even if they're not completely right.
They may still have tremendous benefits
and behaviorism had tremendous benefits
because we learned all sorts of things
about behavior in the brain from the
behaviors.
Almost everything we know from a
scientific perspective about psychology,
it's behaviorists.
I've learned way more from the animal
researchers than from anyone else except
for the clinicians way more there,
there,
there.
They're so careful in their terminology
and their scientific approach.
Okay.
Yeah.
You remember that little oval.
Then I keep showing you point B,
point a you're trying to get from point
a to point b.
And point B is a representation and
point a is a representation
fundamentally.
And then you,
you know,
you invoke actions or perceptual schemes
that are necessary to translate one
state into the other.
Okay?
Now imagine for a moment what the
primary biological brain systems do is
grab hold of that oval and they say,
point a,
you're hungry.
Point B,
you need food.
Here's the behaviors and the perceptions
that of you that you've used in the past
to solve that problem.
Let's prime them and implement them.
And so that's what's happening during
your day is like you get hungry,
the hypothalamus grabs that little oval
and now you're,
you're under the control of the
hypothalamic perceptual and motor
functions.
Now it's connected to the rest of the
brain.
So it's going to do this in a pretty
sophisticated way,
but it's going to call on procedures and
routines that you already know in order
to solve the problem.
Like,
you know where the fridge is,
you know how to open the peanut butter,
whatever it is you're going to eat.
You know how to hold a knife,
you know,
so all those things are going to be
primed.
The,
the behaviorists thought of that.
They thought of the action of the
fundamental biological systems as
drives.
And there's a deterministic element to
drive,
you know,
so you're hungry.
The hunger makes you move your foot down
the stairs in a sort of stereotype
manner.
Uh,
chaining of behavioral outputs,
simple reflexes,
and it drives you to the fridge.
And that drives you to unscrew the
peanut butter and to take out the knife.
And these are all chained reflexes.
It turns out that's wrong,
but,
but it's an entry.
It's a useful and interesting model.
What
the way it was demonstrated that that
was wrong.
Okay,
so now we're going to go back to rats
for a minute.
You've got a rat and you put them in
the,
in a,
in a maze and you want to teach them how
to get through the maze.
So you put the rat there and then you
put a little food pellet in front of the
rack.
And so then the rack reddens down in the
maze and eats the food palate.
Maybe it's only this far.
And so then you put the rat back,
can you put a foot pet food pellet there
again?
And it runs down the runway and it gets
the food pellet.
And maybe you do three or four times and
you put the right back in the other cage
and they leave him for a day.
And then the next day you take the same
route and you put it back in and you put
the food pellet about three inches
farther.
And so it runs down there,
grabs the food pellet,
et cetera.
And then you put another three inches
in,
another three inches,
and soon the rack is zipping through
that through the maze.
And you can see how you could
conceptualize that as the simple
chaining of reflex behaviors,
right?
Cause it's,
it's not that complicated.
The rat has to walk reflexive and then
just has to change in the reflexes
together.
And you want to have a simple model if
you're a scientist.
And so that was the model.
But then some wise guy took a rat,
I can't remember his name unfortunately,
but he was extraordinarily funny as far
as I'm concerned.
He took the rat and he caught up its
back legs and then he put its back late
on a little cart and then he put the rat
in the maze and sure enough the rap go
like this through the maze to get to the
end.
And he said,
well obviously that's not reflex
chaining because like rats don't have
wheels,
but if you stick wheels on a rack it can
figure it out pretty damn quick.
And so it was experiments like that that
blew apart the simple reflex chaining
hypothesis of behaviorism.
It's a very,
that's a such a funny experiment to,
I mean they must've just cackled away
when they come in a talk that went up.
It's like,
talk about your ultimate nerd
experiment,
right.
Let's put wheels on this rat and see
what happens.
Anyways,
so soulful love and vinegar dove and a
variety of other people started
believing that,
you know,
animals weren't simple chains of
reflexes from sensation to behavioral
output,
but that they generated models of the
world.
And the basic model would be,
and this is a cybernetic model,
this comes from Norbert Wiener from back
in the 1940s when he was studying
simple,
intelligent machines.
And one of the things wiener worked on
was anti missile systems.
So cause you imagine,
so you get a muscle and it's zooming
along and you want to shoot another
missile added to it.
Now that's a complicated problem.
It's trying to hit a moving target and
he construed that.
What the antimissile missiles should do
is track its trajectory towards the,
like the ideal trajectory towards the
missile and then correct for deviations
from that.
So you know,
so if it got a little too far to the
left then it would move to the right.
And then if it got a little too far to
the right,
it would move to the left.
It's like a Thermostat,
you know,
it's basically the same system that's in
a thermostat.
It's the simplest form of intelligent
behavior.
And that's actually the model that gray
used was quite funny because when I was
teaching about this in Boston,
I had an engineer in one of my classes
and I went through the gray model,
which is the cybernetic model.
And I,
and he said,
you know,
that's,
that's weird.
That's exactly the same system that we
use to design and he missile missiles on
Jesus.
That's,
that's really weird.
That's a of a coincidence.
And then the engineer went off to
England where he met Jeffrey Gray and
jet and he said that like,
isn't this an interesting coincidence?
And Grace said,
well,
it's not a coincidence because it was
the anti missile missile researchers
work that or at least a branch of that
work that had the same intellectual
history as this particular theory.
So,
you know,
that was quite cool.
And that's all stemming from this guy at
mit.
So imagine what happens is your
hypothalamus says,
ah,
you don't have enough sugar in your
blood.
And so like it pops up this perceptual,
I call them motivation action maps.
What is it?
No,
I can't even remember.
But I called them,
um,
motivation,
oh,
it doesn't matter.
Um,
there,
those little,
those little ovals and they contain a
way of looking at the world.
So a way of focusing in on the things
that are relevant and they contain that.
The,
the branching sequence of ready made
actions and perceptions that you would
use to solve the problem.
And they sort of prime those so they're
at hand.
And I think that's what you basically
experienced when you get hungry.
You know,
and hunger isn't just the feeling in
your stomach,
the empty feeling.
It's also this impulse to act right in
a,
in a particular direction.
And it's a heightened particular taste.
Um,
and maybe even for a particular
substance.
So it turns out this is quite cool.
You know,
there's five or six or seven primary
tastes and part of your brain tells you
what it is that you're tasting.
And then another part of your brain says
whether or not that is a good taste or a
bad taste.
And if it's a good taste,
then you'll pursue it.
And if it's a bad taste or even a
neutral taste,
you won't pursue it.
And so what happens is that as you get
hungry,
the goodness of the taste increases.
And then when you eat it decreases.
It tastes the same though.
Right.
Which is kind of interesting cause you
might think that,
you know,
if you were eating something salty,
the way he would stop is it just
wouldn't taste salty anymore.
But that isn't,
what happens is you have a goodness
adjuster and it works independently for
the different tastes.
So that's why when you eat,
you still have room for dessert because
that part is unsatiated that taste isn't
satiated yet.
So,
okay.
Anyways,
the Hypothalamus,
let's say pops up this little sub
personality and it's the eating
subpersonality.
And if it's like a really desperate
eating subpersonality,
you better not get in its way.
You know,
you're,
you never experienced that to speak of
because you know,
North Americans are never hungry.
Hungry is what happens after you haven't
eaten for 30 days,
you know,
that's hungry.
So,
and you will,
you don't want to get in the way of
someone like that.
They're going to be occupying the
hunger,
motivation,
action and perception module all the
time and in a very,
very motivated way.
And the hypothalamus is no hiker.
It's got massive projections reaching up
into the parts of the brain that you
would associate more particularly with
you.
And if it wants to subordinate you to
it,
it will.
And you'll see this all the time.
And Binge eaters,
you know,
because a binge eater will starve
usually herself and starve herself and
starve herself and starve herself.
And then the hypothalamus will say,
especially if she gets a little upset
because the,
the negative emotion will suppress her
preferred in frontal cortical function.
And then the hypothalamus ago,
and then the little eating bark module
pops up and you know,
she's in the fridge eating two ports of
ice cream in 15 seconds.
And then she says,
it was like,
it wasn't even me.
It's like,
yeah,
it wasn't,
it was,
it was a fundamental biological
subcircuit that is devoted to not
letting you starve yourself to death,
you know?
And so you don't want to get into war
with one of those things.
And that's really what happens in
bulemia in particular.
It's a war between higher cortical
centers and lower subcortical centers.
And that's not good,
you know,
so.
So anyways,
off pops the Little Lod,
you all,
it says state a,
you're,
you don't have enough food.
Your blood sugar's too low.
State be solved that by having a peanut
butter sandwich,
you know,
it's context,
it's context specific.
Solve it by eating.
Okay?
Now what that has done is set up the
framework for satiation.
Okay?
Now,
satiation is a kind of reward.
Now you might think that satiation is
the kind of reward that everyone wants
because that's actually what people
think,
you know,
they think that what you want is to give
to your goal.
And generally we presume that getting to
your goal is rewarding.
But it's a funny kind of reward because
actually,
because it's a consumer Tory reward,
which is a particular kind of reward,
it has its own circuitry.
The consumer Tory reward just shuts off
the system that was pursuing it.
That's the consequence.
So the drive goes away.
It's a funny reward,
right?
Because you stopped being impelled by
the drive.
You're kind of happy about that.
But all that happens is that system
sinks and Poof,
up pops another one.
So Conservatory reward does this strange
kind of reward because it's never really
final and all it does is shut down the
part of you that wanted it.
So,
okay,
so that's consumer Tory reward.
And that's important to remember.
You'll see why after awhile.
Now imagine what could happen as you
move towards the consumer Tory reward.
So here's,
here's some rough things that could
happen.
The things that you're doing could work
in the way you want them to work.
Okay?
And so that's kind of the no hassle
situation.
You know,
you go downstairs,
you opened the cupboard,
the peanut butters there,
you make a sandwich,
you eat it,
and then you go back to study.
Pretty
no,
I'm excited.
You know,
it's like it's a boring story and that's
the kind of story you want and inhabit.
Habit.
Most of the time you want the things
that you know how to do to produce the
results that you want to produce to
work.
And that basically keeps your emotions
regulated.
So now that we understand this a to be
movement and we understand how the
underlying biological subsystems
modulate that,
now we can start to think about emotion.
All right?
So
as you're walking towards your goal,
you're evaluating what happens as you
walk and as long as the things that you
want to have happen are happening while
you walk,
then you're dopaminergic system,
which is the source of incentive reward,
which is the second kind of reward.
You're dopamine system is going,
good job,
good job.
And you kind of liked that.
It keeps you alert,
you know when you're on the right track
and it reinforces that behavior because
your body assumes that if the thing is
that you're doing is working,
then the circuit that does that should
get a little stronger and a little more
well developed because it's producing
the desired outcome.
And I think you feel good about that.
And I think the reason you feel good
about that is because your brain is
actually like,
it's in a state of growth.
It's producing chemicals that help your
brain grow.
And I think it's the feeling of that,
that you have as a positive feeling.
Now how you feel that I don't know.
But why wouldn't you feel that?
It's like the thing you're doing is
working,
it should thrive.
And so you're pretty happy about that.
And that's like mild level positive
emotions.
I know what I'm doing,
you know?
So that's one thing that can happen.
Things that you expect or predict.
It's expect if you use a pure cognitive
warrant,
it's desire.
If you use a model that incorporates
motivation,
cause socolow lovin vinegar Dova and to
some degree gray kind of thinks about
the brain as something that predicts and
expects,
you know?
So as long as what you expect to happen
is happening,
then you stay calm.
But there's a,
there's an error in that in the error is
well you don't just expect things,
you want them,
right.
And you're always aiming at something
specific.
And it's the biological systems that
underlying motivation that they're
specifying that.
So you can't think of yourself as a cold
calculating expectancy machine,
cognitive expectancy machine.
Cause you're not like that.
You want things,
okay,
so you're moving along towards you
target and the things that you want to
have happen are happening and the cues
that you're approaching the target are
appearing as they should be.
And your dopamine system,
which is grounded by the way,
in half of the hypothalamus,
so half of the hypothalamus is devoted
towards popping up these little bubbles
that tell you what you should want and
how to get them.
And the other half is devoted to
exploring and to mostly to exploring
into paying attention.
Okay?
So,
and it will be ticking along just quite
nicely as long as what you're doing is
working.
But then we'll say,
well,
what if what you're doing isn't working?
What if,
uh,
what if you get to the cupboard and you
open it and your little brother has
eaten all the peanut butter?
Well,
what you get,
Dan,
is a mismatch.
It's like instead of the presence of the
peanut butter,
you get the absence of the peanut
butter.
And that's actually a stimulus.
So cool.
The absence of a desired entity is,
it is a punishment.
It's a punishment.
So that's pretty abstract,
right?
I mean it's pretty abstract punishment.
It's like a hole where there shouldn't
be a whole,
will produce an orienting response and
frustrate you and make you aggressive
and irritated and all those sorts of
things.
And so,
and you're going to feel that negatively
now.
That's interesting.
That's a punishment.
Now,
if you had suspicions that the peanut
butter might be missing when you were
opening the door,
that would make you anxious.
Cause anxiety,
fear more particularly fear is the
expectation that a punishment might
occur.
And you have a separate interesting
though,
even though it's,
it's in relationship to a punishment
which you might think of as a primary,
um,
unconditioned stimulus,
right?
It's an unconditioned stimulus cause he,
you naturally,
you're naturally respond to it.
Fear which could be considered a
condition.
Stimulus actually has its own circuit.
It's so common that what we want might
not be there.
That we've evolved the whole circuit
just to deal with things that are
threatening as well as things that are
punishing.
Punishment,
pain,
threat,
anxiety.
Threat is threat of punishment.
So it's an abstract form of,
but it's an abstract representation of
punishment.
You're anxious so that you don't get
hurt.
Now you might say,
I'm so damn anxious,
I don't,
I'd rather have to hurt.
But no you wouldn't.
It's like it's a lesser price to pay.
It's a law.
It's a lesser pain to avoid a greater
pain.
That's really what anxiety is.
So the next time you're anxious,
you should be happy about that because
at least you're not pain,
which is what the anxiety trying to
protect you from it.
Okay,
so you're going towards your goal and
one thing that could happen is that
things that you want to have happen are
happening and things that you want to
have appear are appearing.
And so you get a little dopamine kick
from the hypothalamus and that makes you
feel like you're,
you know,
on the right track,
which is exactly how it makes you feel.
Because we're trajectory oriented
animals and just like an anti missile
missile,
we're always trying to hit a moving
target.
And so if you're on the right
trajectory,
then everything,
everything about the way you organized
your brain at that moment is functional.
And so your brain pumps up a little bit
of neuro chemical to make those areas of
the brain that are involved in that
productive activity grow a little bit
and you think,
Hey,
are going pretty good for me.
So that's pretty cool.
Now here's another thing that could
happen.
So we could say,
well,
the peanut butter isn't there.
Well first you're going to be surprised
about that.
Hypothetically,
if to the degree that you thought it
would be there.
And so that's gonna make you anxious
because one of the things that can
happen when you're on the way to get
something you want is that something you
don't expect will happen.
That's novelty,
that's novelty or a normally and
normally is the mismatch between the
structures that you're using to
represent the world and your actions in
it and the actual world.
It's the detection of a gap between the
state of reality and your representation
of the state of reality.
Now,
the bigger that gap,
the more anxious you get.
Now then you might say,
well,
how do you calculate how anxious you
should be?
And Gray.
Actually it doesn't talk about that,
but if you,
but there's a paper in there by carver
and Scheier that you'll have to read
that's related to this.
So remember the hierarchy,
right?
You got little bitty things at the
bottom and you've got great big things
at the top.
And so you might say
you open the cupboard and the peanut
butter isn't there and you think this
stupid family,
I should go hang myself.
You know,
which I I would say is not a
particularly adaptive response,
although it does solve the problem.
What's happening there is that you're
calibrating the threat as a threat to
the integrity of the top levels of the
hierarchy that you use to orient
yourself in the world.
And I would say that's pretty,
that's fuzzy thinking.
You know,
before you hang yourself about it,
you might think if there's some simpler
things you could do that were lower in
the hierarchy and higher resolution that
would solve the problem.
Like,
well you could go to the corner store
and get a jar of peanut butter and then
that problem would be solved.
Right?
Or maybe you could just have something
that wasn't peanut butter.
And you know what I mean?
You want,
you want to do a shift at the low levels
of the hierarchy at high resolution
because it's less anxiety provoking.
It's less effort and it doesn't take you
apart.
And so there's a rule and I don't know
how your brain figures it out.
The rule is make the least modification
necessary to solve the emergent problem.
It's a really,
really,
really important rule.
And if you use it when you're talking to
other people,
they will like you a lot better because
maybe you know,
the person that's working for you
doesn't do something that they said they
would do.
And that puts you in trouble.
I mean,
one responses,
you know,
you're a useless creek,
get the hell out of here so you're,
you fire them.
And the other is,
okay,
tell me exactly what happened during the
time that you were supposed to be,
you know,
outputting this,
this resource.
So he listened to the person detail out
there,
psychomotor schemes and you see where
you can tweak one or two so that the
next time that happens,
the next time a situation like that
arises,
you don't get the same undesired output
as much better.
But it takes acuity,
right?
Cause you gotta turn it low resolution
situation,
which is I'm irritated and anxious and
frustrated and hurt by your foolishness.
You're a parent foolishness,
which is really easy thing to
conceptualize because it doesn't take
any effort.
It's just an expression of my automatic
response.
Or I can think,
okay,
let's let's constrain this
differentiated,
sequence it and try to figure out where
the problem actually lies.
Now if it happens 50 times,
well maybe it's time not to have a
relationship with that person anymore.
But to begin with,
at least you want to start with the
smallest possible correction.
And you can really remember this when
you're arguing with people,
you know,
especially with people that you have a
relationship with.
It's like save the,
we should get a divorce statements for
the serious occasions and if there's
violations,
like assume that they're high
resolution,
low level violations,
investigate that.
And if that doesn't work well then jump
up one level but start low.
And most of the time your brain is
trying to figure out how to do that.
For you,
it would like to assume that your
stupidity is of the rectifiable kind.
And I want to talk to you a little bit
about how it makes that calculation
because it's a very hard calculation to
make,
right?
It's like if you wake up and you know
you,
there's something about you that's
aching.
It's like what the hell are you supposed
to think about that?
Because the ranges from nothing,
it'll go away in five minutes to hey,
you know you're dead in three months and
there's no real way of telling what
level of catastrophic response you
should have to the emergence of that
anomaly.
It's a real big problem.
And so your brain has to estimate it and
all sorts of different ways.
And as we differentiate it,
differentiate out the personality traits
will start to talk about that.
So for now,
just remember that your your built in
biological systems are specifying the
goal and the framework within which you
construe that goal.
Perceptions and actions as little
personality.
And it wants some,
okay.
As that little personality is going on
long towards its goal,
three things can happen.
It can make progress,
it can get stopped in a way that's
easily rectifiable.
You know,
like maybe there's a toy on the stairs
and you have to step around it.
Obviously that's not going to bother you
very much because it just requires a
tiny transformation of your,
of your Schema,
right?
So little things you can rectify might
help.
So those are little punishments or
middle threats or you can hit an
anomaly.
Okay.
And if things are going right,
that's positive emotion.
That's extroversion.
By the way.
It's the same system.
So extroverts,
they're positive,
they're positive reward system.
The incentive reward system is quite
active and extroverts not active and
interests.
And then in terms of neuroticism,
people that are high in neuroticism tend
to react with more anxiety and pain to
the same amount of disruption.
And those are two of the first
fundamental personality traits.
So we'll see you Tuesday.