Okay.
So I'm going to tell you today about a
way of looking at the world that I think
is substantially different from the way
that most people look at the world.
And the way I want to tell you about
looking at the world today is I think
more inclusive than a standard sort of
materialist view.
Like the standard scientific view of the
world,
of course,
is that it's made up of familiar objects
and that the world is in essence a
material place.
But there's some very potent limitations
of that viewpoint despite the fact that
it's given us tremendous power and the
limitations are essentially as follows,
the essential materialist view can't
tell us anything about consciousness,
which is probably the primary fact of
experience.
Neuroscientists in recent years,
mostly in the last decade of being
trying to crack the problem of
consciousness,
and they have absolutely made no
progress.
They've tried to associate consciousness
with neuronal activity,
but that seems to be an incomplete
answer because there's many forms of
neuronal activity in the brain that
aren't accompanied by consciousness at
all.
Not only do neuroscientists understand
virtually nothing about consciousness
and they can't even really figure out
what it's function is and they can't
understand why our brains would go to so
much effort to make us aware of things
when it isn't clear at all,
that awareness is necessary for life.
Especially given that there are many
life forms on the planet that don't seem
to be aware at all.
The standard materialist view is also
insufficient.
Many other ways it's insufficient.
Philosophically,
I think as you probably all know,
because our conception that portrays the
world is made up of objects is in some
really fundamental way dead.
I had,
it doesn't seem to have a place in it
for human beings or a place in it for
meaning or a mode whereby you might be
able to conceptualize the real existence
of something like an emotion or a dream
or a motivation.
All phenomena which are just as
mysterious to neuroscientists send to
scientists in general has consciousness.
Now,
the problem with this seems to be mostly
experiential.
If you have to ask people what they know
more than anything else,
they know,
number one,
that they're conscious.
They know.
Number two,
that their internal experiential life is
composed of emotions and motivational
states,
which although not rational in essential
structure are so real and relevant that
virtually everything that people do is
predicated on them.
So our current viewpoint,
despite its ability to give us
tremendous technological power,
seems to eradicate from formal
consideration many,
many essential experiences that are
vital to life.
In fact,
even perhaps primary.
Now,
I'm going to suggest to you today that
there's an alternative viewpoint.
And I think also it's one that although
you may be hearing about it formally for
the first time,
is also something that you know
unbelievably deeply how thousands of
years ago playdough propose that all
knowledge was remembering.
And of course we don't believe that
today because we believe we gathered
knowledge as a consequence of contact
with the world.
But you'll see today that the knowledge
that I'm going to share with you,
we'll strike a deep chord of
remembering.
And it's because everything that you've
done throughout your life is in one way
or another predicated on what I'm going
to tell you today.
I'm going to demonstrate this in a
peculiar way,
I think because I'm going to start by
telling you a story,
and the reason I'm going to do that is
because models of the world that include
phenomena,
light,
consciousness,
and emotions and motivations and actions
and interactions are generally portrayed
formally in stories and not in
scientific theories.
And it does turn out to be that stories
themselves have an identifiable
structure,
even a grammar that makes them
comprehensible.
Furthermore,
it turns out that even the simplest
stories,
especially if they're elegantly
constructed,
have an unbelievably profound underlying
meaning,
and you can frequently see this most
particularly in children's stories.
So I remember I showed my son when he
was four years old,
the Disney movie,
Pinocchio,
which on the surface of it is a very
strange tale,
right?
It's a wooden puppet who wants to become
real,
so he has to rescue his father from the
belly of a whale.
A structured that could by no means be
considered rational.
That is in fact so surprising and
unexpected that it's remarkable to
imagine that grown men and women,
including children,
can sit in a movie theater and watch a
story like that unfold without ever
thinking for a second.
That it's absolutely peculiar that they
can be taken in by such a tail and
regard it experientially as real.
Pinocchio is a deep,
deep story.
It has echoes that go back three or
4,000 years to the earliest stories that
we know and it's so rich with
information that a child can watch it
over and over and over and over.
I think my son Watched Pinocchio 30
Times a why?
Well,
it's either because a child can't tell
the difference between fantasy and
reality or it's because there's
something to those stories that's much
more potent than we actually consciously
understand.
And it's kind of interesting too,
you know,
if you go to a,
if you go to a video rental
establishment,
you'll find that in the top 10 highest
grossing movies of all time are for
Disney movies that are animated
fairytales,
essentially retelling of mythological
stories.
They strike a deep chord.
Why?
Well,
Shakespeare was of course a great
literary figure,
said it perhaps better than anyone else
has,
which is not surprising cause he said
many things better than anyone else has.
He said all the world's a stage and all
the men and women,
merely players,
they have their exits and their
entrances and one man in his time plays
many parts.
And so following from that,
you can imagine that a story is know
more about the props in the world than a
play that you go see as about the props
on the stage,
uh,
dramas about the manner in which people
actually exist,
the emotions that they feel,
the motivational states they encounter,
the problems they have to solve when
they interact with each other.
And the play's the thing from that
particular perspective in which we can
capture those aspects of our experience
that are not only real but essentially
human.
I'm going to tell you a little story to
begin this off with.
It's a kid story written for children of
about four years of age,
but it's very,
very elegant.
I tried to cut it down for this talk,
but I found I couldn't because it was so
well edited that every single piece of
it had to fit in to make the story
complete and I'm going to show you first
the structure of the story.
Now,
this is a very useful diagram in many
ways.
It's very simple.
Basically it says this,
whenever you're doing anything,
you inhabit a bounded world.
Now you know like for example,
you're sitting here in this lecture,
there's things you are paying attention
to and things you're not.
If I took most of you out of this room
right now and asked you definitively
what color the rug was,
you would know or what color your chair
was,
for example,
or what the person next to you was
wearing,
and bless that person happens to be your
husband or your wife.
You wouldn't remember any of those
things.
And the reason for that is when you're
in a situation like this and you're
attending to a speaker,
most of the occurrences that are
unfolding around you are irrelevant.
You don't store them.
You only focus on certain things.
Well,
how do you decide what to focus on given
that there's,
this is virtually unlimited number of
things to pay attention to.
Well,
you have to conceive of yourself as
being somewhere always and you have to
conceive of yourself as going somewhere.
So you could say,
and in a real sense,
the world you inhabit is a journey.
It's a journey from point a to point b,
a journey from what is to what should be
a journey from the place you are,
which is insufficient in some important
manner to a place that in some important
manner is going to be better.
A standard story has exactly that
structure.
Child comes home and you say,
well,
what happened to you today on the way to
school,
setting up the little narrative
structure and the child will unfold the
sequence of events that he encountered.
If the stories more interesting than
just a recount of exactly what happened
to him.
It usually involves the encounter with
something unexpected on the way to point
b and a description of the manner in
which that encounter with the unexpected
was resolved.
Typical story.
Now.
Why would you want to know that?
Why would you want to listen to it?
Well,
it's because on your journey from point
a to point b,
all sorts of unexpected things always
happen,
and if someone else has encountered
something unexpected and conjured up a
decent solution to it,
it could well be worth your time to
listen
well.
Maybe there's a pattern to encountering
unexpected things.
Maybe there's a proper way to encounter
the unexpected.
Maybe it's the case that in our
collective wisdom,
as human beings,
we've gathered up representations of
ways to encounter the unexpected that we
put forth in our stories.
How should you face what you don't
understand?
Well,
now I'm going to tell you this story.
It's written for four year old kids,
but I want you to take a look at it for
a moment,
from a different perspective and see if
you can imagine exactly what it is that
it's saying.
Okay?
There's no such thing as a dragon.
Well,
we all know that,
right?
A dragon is a fictitious creature,
reptilian,
terrible lives forever,
breathes fire hordes,
Gould,
strange combination of attributes.
Why would something terrible and ancient
hold a treasure.
Billy bixby was rather surprised when he
woke up one morning and found a dragon
in his room.
It was a small dragon about the size of
a kitten.
The dragon wagged it's tail happily when
billy patted his head.
Okay.
It's interesting,
you know,
in Chinese mythology,
dragon is a positive figure in European
mythology.
The dragon is something to face in
combat and destroy or something to face
in combat and build something out of the
pieces left over from the Dragon.
Billy went downstairs to tell his
mother,
yeah,
there's no such thing as a dragon.
Said Billy's mother.
And she said it like she meant it.
I remember once my daughter had a
nightmare.
She was about four.
This was at the time when she first
started to notice graffiti and litter
and both graffiti and her bothered her.
She couldn't understand the motivations
behind the graffiti artists and she
didn't like the fact that there was
litter cluttering up the world's order.
And the reason she got sensitive to that
as a child was because children are
really,
really dependent on order.
Right.
I mean,
and the reason for that is that their
realm of competence is rather
restricted.
So they'd like to see things.
Mac mass stops a little kids for
example.
They're not happy with you if you play a
game with them and then mess around with
the rules of the game.
They don't like that at all.
They think that that's immoral activity
to shake up the structure of the game.
Well anyways,
while she was pondering all this,
she uh,
came into our bedroom one night and
said,
Dad,
I had a nightmare.
Now we all know,
right?
Nightmares aren't real.
Just like dragons.
Dreams aren't real.
Of course.
Which raises the question of why in the
world you'd bother having them six or
seven hours a night every single day of
your life and why they're a recognized
feature of animal behavior all the way
down to the amphibian level.
She said,
I dreamt that was a clear flowing
stream,
but in the stream there was all sorts of
garbage and it scared me and bothered me
so much.
I woke up.
So I told her,
look,
close your eyes and imagine the stream.
It's full of garbage.
What should you do about it?
She said,
well,
I should take the garbage out of the
street.
And I said,
all right,
so picture this dream,
picture yourself,
cleaning the garbage out of it.
She calmed down and went back to sleep.
Why?
Well,
because dreams concentrate on threat.
We know that they present threats to
you,
threats you haven't been able to deal
with.
Well,
there's a part of your brain that tracks
threats and it's not really all that
smart.
In some ways,
all it does is say,
look,
here's the problem and it's waiting for
the rest of your brain to conjure up
some solution to that problem.
And if it doesn't conjure up a solution
and it just presents the problem over
and over and over and over and over.
So people who have posttraumatic stress
disorder,
for example,
who've been really upset by their
contact with something unexpected,
dream about the same tragedy forever
until they solve it and they solve it by
facing it and living it over and over
voluntarily.
So you might think right off the bat
from listening to that little story that
suggesting to your four year old
daughter who's just had a nightmare,
that her fears aren't real and that the
dream representation of them isn't real
because it's not tangible.
Like a table might not really be the
best approach to the problem.
So you see billy,
he's pretty much got it right right off
the bat,
right?
The dragon wagged his tail happily.
When billy padded it's head.
Bailey went downstairs to tell his
mother there's no such thing as a dragon
said billy's mother,
and she said it like she meant it
till there's a dragon in this house.
Now the next thing he might wonder is
how often have you actually gone into a
house where there's a dragon?
My guess is if you don't take this
particularly specifically and allow
yourself to use your imagination and to
think metaphorically for a moment,
you've all encountered dozens of houses
that were filled right to the rafters
with various dragons,
all of which were being studiously
ignored by the people who inhabited the
house.
Billy went back to his room and began to
dress the dragon,
came close to billy in a friendly manner
and wagged his tail,
but billy didn't pat it.
If there's no such thing as something,
it's silly to pat it on the head.
Billy washed his face and hands and went
down to breakfast.
The dragon went along.
It was bigger.
Now almost the size of a dog
belly sat down at the table.
The dragon sat down on the table.
This sort of thing was not usually
permitted,
but there wasn't much billy's mother
could do about it.
She'd already said there was no such
thing as a dragon and if there's no such
thing,
you can't tell it to get down off the
table.
Sometimes I sit with friends of mine who
have very young children to eat saint
and the children two or three years old
don't sit out the table.
They sit on the table or they run around
the table or they run around the table
and pull things off the table or they
run around the house and pull things off
all the shelves in the house and keep
their parents so busy chasing them
around that they have no time
whatsoever.
Do we interact as adults?
Well,
you have to wonder under those
circumstances whether you're dealing
with a child or a dragon,
so to speak.
And you also might wonder whether or not
the dragon is large and unruly.
Precisely because the parents are
completely unwilling to admit that it
actually exists.
Mother made some pancakes for billy,
brought the dragon,
ate the mall,
mother made some more,
but to drag an eight those two mother
kept making pancakes until she ran out
of batter.
Billy only got one of them,
but he said that's all he really wanted.
Anyway,
one time,
ah,
an acquaintance of ours in Boston
brought their son over to be Babysat at
our house and his nanny had just been in
a car accident so he was being shunted
from house to house.
Well,
his parents went off to work and uh,
he didn't have very good reputation.
This kid,
he was about four and a,
he came over to our house and with his
mother in the morning and she dropped
him off and she said,
well,
he probably won't eat all day,
but that's all right.
Oh and I thought,
no,
he's four.
If he doesn't eat all day,
ah,
that's not all right.
Right.
Cause kids,
if they don't eat their basically
horrible,
right.
If they don't sleep,
they don't eat.
They're horrible.
So it isn't all right that he doesn't
eat.
So then you think,
well maybe there's some sort of dragon
associated with this child that happens
to be interviewing perhaps with his
ability to eat.
So I came back at noon,
my wife had taken care of the children
that day and I walked in the house and
the other four or five kids that we had
in house were off playing.
And this little kid was standing in the
corner,
like really isolated and looking,
you know,
upset fundamentally.
So I went over and I poked him a bunch
because generally if you poke a kid a
little bit,
you know,
well they'll go like this,
the sort of back off.
But sooner or later you can crack them
and they'll smile and then they'll play.
Not this kid,
boy,
there's no bloody way who's going to
play with me?
And that was like he'd already learned
that adults should either be ignored or
that they were trouble and he wasn't
gonna let any adult into his little
world.
So there was absolutely a dragon
associated with that little boy and it
was eating all his pancakes.
Billy went upstairs to brush his teeth.
Mother started clearing the table.
The dragon who was quite as big as
mother by this time,
made himself comfortable on the whole
rug and went to sleep.
I really like this one.
By the time billy came back downstairs,
the dragon had grown so much.
He filled the hall.
Billy had to go around by way of the
living room to get to where his mother
was.
I didn't know dragon's group's who fast
said billy,
there's no such thing as a dragon.
Said mother firmly
cleaning the downstairs took mother all
morning.
Well with the dragon in the way and
having to climb in and out of windows to
get from room to room.
So you know,
you think back in your own experience
when you've gone to a house where
there's a dragon hiding underneath the
living room rug and nobody's saying
anything about it.
And then you think,
how long does it take to get something
absolutely simple done in a house that's
absolutely jammed to the rafters with
unfinished business forever,
right?
Organizing people in a household like
that to even do something as simple as
go out for breakfast in the morning or
even perhaps to make a meal is virtually
impossible.
Why?
Well,
because there's something going on in
the household that has been studiously
ignored for a very long time and has
grown so large as a consequence that it
occupies the whole domain.
By noon,
the dragon filled the house.
It's head hung out the front door.
It's tail hung out the back door and
there wasn't a room in the house that
didn't have some part of the dragon in
it.
When the dragon awoke from his nap,
he was hungry.
You Bake for truck went by.
The smell of fresh bread was more than
the dragon could resist.
He ran down the street after the bakery
truck.
The house went along.
Of course,
like the shell on a snail.
The mailman was just coming up the path
with some mail for the big speeds.
When their house rushed past him and
headed down the street,
he chased the big space.
How has for a few blocks,
but he,
but he couldn't catch it.
When mister bixby came home for lunch,
the first thing he noticed was that his
house was gone.
Luckily one of the neighbors was able to
tell them which way it went.
You know,
that sort of thing happens to people not
infrequently to write,
hey,
they're not really looking around much
at what's going on and they come home
from work one day and their house is
gone.
And what does that mean?
Well,
maybe their children have become
completely alienated from them or maybe
their wife has decided suddenly,
but of course not.
So suddenly to leave.
Why?
Well,
according to this story,
it's because something ignored was
growing in the house.
Mr Bixby in his car and went looking for
the house.
He studied all the houses as he drove
along.
Finally he saw one that looked familiar.
Billy and Mrs Bixby,
we're waving from an upstairs window.
Okay.
You know when in the 1890s in India when
a house was being built,
the local priest equivalent to the
priest would come by to set the
foundation stone.
And when he set the foundation stone,
he take a big spike and drove it into
the ground.
And the reason he drove it into the
ground at the place where the foundation
was going to be laid was to keep the
great dragon that is underneath the
earth.
Firmly pinned down by its head so it
couldn't move and shake the house to
bits.
And what does that mean?
Well,
it means the same thing that's meant in
the new testament when you're told not
to build your house on a foundation of
sand,
right?
It doesn't matter how good the house is
or how well constructed it is or how
rich it is.
If the foundation has made out of sand
or if it rests on top of a dragon,
there's nothing in that household that's
ever going to be accomplished.
That's positive.
And the wealth,
the display that the house might consist
of is nothing but a sham.
Mr Bixby climbed over the dragon's head
onto the porch roof and through the
upstairs window.
How did this happen?
Mr Bixby asked.
It was the dragon said,
billy,
there's no such thing.
Mother started to say,
there is a dragon.
Billy insisted a very big dragon and
billy patted the dragon on the head.
The dragon wagged his tail happily then
even faster than it had grown.
The dragon started getting smaller.
Soon it was kitten size again.
I don't mind dragons this side said,
mother,
why did it have to grow so big?
I'm not sure I said billy,
but I think it just want it to be
noticed.
So the first thing you might think about
is just what happens if you don't pay a
bill?
Like really don't pay it.
Right?
I mean when it first comes in,
it's only the size of a kitten.
But if you leave it alone for two or
three years,
it's pretty much grows into a full
fledge dragon.
Well,
why?
because things that you ignore have a
life of their own complex life,
like a bill bills attached to a whole
industrial complex,
right?
One of whose major functions is to make
sure that you pay the bill and if you
don't pay the bill,
then you immediately find out what it's
connected to.
It's connected to something,
a Manson,
very troublesome.
And if you allow all the full force of
that thing to manifest itself,
it's not pretty.
So one lesson from this story is that if
something's nagging at you just a bit,
it's probably better to deal with it
before it turns into a full fledge
dragon.
And then you might think,
well,
what if it's already full fledge dragon,
right?
I mean,
then what's your option?
And this is there is nothing left but to
run away.
And so then I can tell you what we know
from 50 years of studying the outcome of
clinical psychological interventions.
So let's take an extreme case,
right?
Let's say something truly terrible has
happened to you.
And as a consequence of that,
you're in shock post traumatic shock,
which is a condition that's sufficiently
serious to damage your brain over time.
It's not only a psychological disorder,
it's a physical disorder.
If you're really stressed,
your cortisol levels shoot up.
And if your cortisol level shoot up that
cortisol and high dose,
this is a neurotoxin,
it starts to damage your brain.
So let's take a very extreme case and
imagine that you've been violently
sexually assaulted.
And as a consequence of that,
you're in post traumatic shock.
How do you get cured?
So that means you can't really go
outside.
You certainly can't encounter anything
that's associated with the event.
Your sense of integrity and personal
safety of being completely destroyed.
Is there any way you can get back on
your feet and all?
There's a woman named Edna Foa in New
York,
I think one of the world's top clinical
psychologist and she's been dealing with
women who have post traumatic stress
disorder for decades and she's found a
treatment that works and the treatment
is this.
She has the women relive the event in as
much detail as possible over and over in
their imagination with the accompanying
emotion and she's found because she's
done physiological measurements on her
clients,
that those women that allow themselves
to get the most fully upset as a
consequence of the reliving get better,
faster and stay better longer.
The clinical evidence is absolutely
clear.
When you take someone to therapy,
you're basically doing two things to
them.
Well,
three,
you allow them to confess what's wrong
with them because it's really useful to
actually say what it is that's bothering
you.
It makes it clear and distinct.
You help the person get their story
straight because you have to have your
story straight,
right?
You have to know where you're coming
from and you have to know where you're
going because otherwise there's no
structure for your life.
Then the third thing is if your path
from point a to b is being blocked by
something that you're afraid of,
you better learn to confront it because
if you don't,
it will grow and expand until it turns
into the kind of dragon that occupies
your whole house.
This is another representation of a
story that's a simple story.
I think it's one that's really most
applicable to children at.
There are aspects of it that are most
applicable to children.
Sexual desire.
One obviously isn't.
It's a map of motivation.
It basically says this and it's easy to
understand.
If you think go to a movie,
it doesn't matter what country it's
made.
There's certain things that always
happen,
right?
Like two broad classes of fiction,
adventure and romance.
What's an adventure to go to new lands
and discover something new and become
transformed a consequence.
What's a romance to meet another person
who's certainly as complicated as
anything you could meet on an adventure.
And again,
to be transformed as a consequence of
the contact to fundamental plots.
Why?
Why are there fundamental plots and why
can we understand them without them
being explained to us what it's,
because fundamentally we're all very,
very similar.
We have a finite set of basic needs.
So for example,
hot people would rather be cool,
thirsty people would rather have water
hungry,
people would rather eat.
And these motivations color what we
conceive of as our ultimate destiny.
So in the Old Testament,
for example,
an agrarian community,
often hungry paradise was construed as
the land of milk and honey.
Well,
why?
milk is high in fat and honey is high in
glucose.
And if you're hungry,
really hungry,
there's nothing you want more than fat
and sugar.
Affiliative desire,
we like to be around other people,
sexual desire,
a fundamental sub element of a romantic
plot.
These underlying motivational systems
have ours set us up.
Bounded world within which we live.
So for example,
if you fall in love with someone and you
construe your destiny as being with
them,
any indication that they're pleased with
you is going to produce a rash of
positive emotion.
Why?
Because our emotional systems are set up
so that any sign that we're moving
towards our goal is responded to with a
rush of positive emotion and conversely,
a frown from the person that you love,
especially in the initial ages of an
initial stages of a romance is met with
a flood of negative effect.
Why?
Because anything that stops us on the
path that we've chosen produces negative
emotion.
That's how we're set up and our
emotional systems are actually quite
straight forward.
We pause it.
A goal.
The thing about people is that we can
pause it virtually anything as a goal.
That's one of the things that
distinguishes us from animals,
so we can all be thrilled to death when
our favorite soccer team scores a goal
because we participate in what they're
doing.
The same way we participate in watching
a protagonist on a movie or in a book,
we can feel it.
We embody it.
We even know now that the neural systems
that I utilize to watch a movie involve
the same neural systems that the actor
is utilizing,
acting out the part.
So when you say you understand someone
else,
what you mean is your body is set to do
exactly the same thing.
Their body is and your emotional systems
are locked on exactly the same way
there's are.
So when they experience something and
you're watching it,
you experienced an echo of it.
And that's what understanding means.
And it turns out as well that those
neural systems that allow us to embody
someone else and to imitate them are
right underneath the structures that
we've evolved to use for language.
And what that indicates is that mostly
what we use language for is to tell
stories,
to tell about the way that people act so
that we can derive information not about
what the world's made of.
Cause we don't really care about that
some fundamental way,
but instead,
how should we act?
That's the fundamental question.
How should we act now?
If you go see a movie about a thug,
the message there is given that the thug
generally comes to not so good and don't
act like a thug.
Right?
Interesting.
Though it might be compelling as a
lifestyle,
at least sufficiently compelling,
so you'll watch it.
It's not a good longterm strategy.
What is a good long term strategy?
You know,
we've been collecting stories as people
we don't know how long really,
we don't know,
a hundred thousand years maybe.
There's being creatures like us,
indistinguishable from us for 100,000
years and we know that society's that
appear to be more or less as archaic as
those old societies tell stories,
have rituals,
have mythology.
We have ancient written stories like the
Enuma Elish,
which is a Sumerian story,
the oldest written story.
We have 4,000 years old based on a oral
tradition that's probably 20,000 years
older than that.
We've been collecting stories for a
long,
long time.
What do they mean?
What are they good for?
Well,
imagine this,
you know,
you tell a story to your husband or your
wife,
Hey,
but something interesting that you saw,
right?
Well then imagine that you could collect
a thousand of the most interesting
stories and then imagine that you were
some kind of literary genius like,
like Shakespeare.
And you could take those thousand
interesting stories and boil them down
to a hundred really interesting stories.
And then imagine that you had 10,000
years to gather up those hundred most
interesting stories and average them.
And you could come out with one perfect
story,
the best story,
the most interesting story that you
could possibly tell.
Well,
that's what a myth is.
It's the most interesting story you can
possibly tell.
And just as this little story that I
just told you,
how to an underlying mythological
structure,
virtually every story you ever see has
such a structure.
That's why it's compelling to you.
And when you meet someone who's
charismatic or who holds your attention
or who you're interested in,
the probability that they're acting out
a mythological fragment is very,
very high.
And that's why it is that your attention
is captivated by them.
What's the world like from this
perspective?
Well,
look,
you know,
you're all sitting in this room.
You think if I took out of here,
how would you describe it?
Well,
you'd say it was full of chairs.
There was a table lights.
Well,
why would you pick that level of
resolution?
They like,
why wouldn't you say,
well,
you know,
the average ceiling tile had about
15,000 dots on it.
It doesn't seem like a relevant data
point,
right?
You say the same thing about the rug.
There's no nothing stopping you from
counting the number of stains or the
number of red spots or the way the light
plays off your partner's shirt or the
shine on your shoes and if you are an
artist say,
and to make a representation of this
room,
you'd concentrate on aspects of it were
completely different from those that
you're concentrating on.
Now you talk about chairs,
TV cameras,
cabinets,
tables,
why they're functional.
They're objects,
right?
Their tools,
they're tools there.
Things you can use.
Normally when you're going from point a
to point B,
you divide up the world into things you
can use.
Those are things you see your perceptual
systems do,
this things you can use and things that
might get in the way.
And as you move from motivated world to
motivated world,
the little stories that you inhabit,
he chopped the world up in different
paces.
So a piano for a concert pianist is
different as a different phenomenon than
a piano for someone who has no musical
education,
but you're always passing up the world
in terms of what it's good for,
how it can serve your purposes,
and you even see it that way.
Now the question is,
the complicated question isn't so much,
how do you parse up the world into
things that are useful to you?
Like chairs.
The complicated question is what do you
do when something that you don't expect
happens?
So imagine you've had a 15 year long
marriage
and you find lipstick on your husband's
color.
Not once but three times and then you
think,
well,
I thought I had a map,
right?
I thought we were both in the same game.
I thought we were both going from point
a to the same point B.
I thought we had established a shared
structure of interpretation,
but I find that there's some aspect of
his apparent behavior that's completely
outside my scope of interpretation.
What do you do while you can choose to
ignore that,
right?
It's easy to do that.
Why would you not?
Why would you ignore it?
Because if you don't ignore it,
you have to think he's not who I thought
he was.
And that's really not a good thing to
think because people are really,
really,
really complicated.
And if they're not who you think they
are,
you have no idea who they might be.
And you also might think,
well,
maybe I'm not who I think I am because
after all I got sucked into this
situation.
I thought I had pretty much understood
the world.
And it turns out that I certainly don't
understand the opposite gender.
And there's some indication that I
really don't even understand myself
because fundamentally I'm so clueless.
And then you might think,
well,
when did this start?
This cluelessness how long have I been
blind?
Well,
do you really want to ask that question
will not generally.
Right.
It's easier to keep the dragon in the
closet,
which is where it tends to live.
What happens when you encounter
something you don't?
For a long time psychologist thought
that people learned fear,
right?
So your typical person,
your typical lab rat was a common
creature.
Now it's a funny thing and because if
you take a lab rat out of his cage and
you put them in a new cage where you
want to teach him,
say to be afraid of something,
to be afraid of a light paired with a
shock,
which is a typical psychological
experiment.
The funny thing about the rat is you got
to let him calm down before he's normal.
Well,
except that you might think that the not
comrade is also the normal route,
right?
You take the rat out of this cage and
you put them in the new cage and what
does he do?
He goes like this.
Well,
why?
he's a rat,
right?
Someone might eat him.
So he's a bit nervous about being in
this new situation.
Rats do not like being in new
situations.
They don't like bright light.
If you put them in a new situation
that's brightly lit,
they go right over to the corner because
they think maybe cats won't find them.
Rats are so afraid of cats that they
never even have to meet a cat to be
afraid of them.
So you can take a rat that's never seen
a cat in his life.
And if you let him smell some cat odor
or show him a cat,
he'll,
well,
I'll tell you,
if you show a route,
a cat somewhere,
he doesn't expect it.
He will run back to his burrow and
scream for 24 hours.
Now you imagine how scared you'd have to
be to screen for 24 hours,
especially given rattle.
He lives about a year.
So that would be for you,
like screaming,
that'd be like screaming for three
months.
Right?
So the rat runs back to his burrow and
he screams and every other rat who hears
him scream,
freezes.
And they all stay like that for 24 hours
until they sort of calm down.
And then the first thing they do is they
go back to the place where they saw the
cat and they start to map it out so they
do these things called corner runs,
which is so the rat and wants to go back
to this territory.
He knows the territory.
It might be a place where he gets food
is the cat's still there while you might
think stay in the borough,
right,
but then maybe you don't get something
to eat so the rat goes back to the place
where the cap was carefully and then he
hunches down and he runs over part of it
and if nothing kills him then he goes
back and does the same thing with a
little more of the territory until
finally the rats of running all over the
territory again.
Then they go back to eating,
making love,
paying attention to their families
because rats are quite social despite
the fact that they're rat
the rat smart enough to go back to the
scene of the crime,
so to speak.
Right.
It's not going to let the dragon,
that might be their grow.
The rat knows that if something is
terrifying,
it should be investigated,
not run away from.
The question is what do you encounter
when you encounter something you don't
expect and so you say,
well,
you've got your spouse mapped out,
right?
But then they do something you don't
expect,
which hopefully happens fairly
regularly,
right?
Because otherwise you get bored with
them.
They do something you don't expect and
you think,
Aha,
who is that person?
Precisely.
And what that means is that what,
what that means is that when you
encounter something unexpected,
you actually can't see what's there.
Why?
Because it's too complicated.
You might have to spend a month talking
to your spouse to figure out just
exactly why they have that particular
peculiar opinion.
You have to explore and dig to find out
how they map the world.
If you encounter something unexpected,
the first thing you see is not the
world.
The first thing you see is just a sense
of discomfort and fear combined with
some late and curiosity that the world
is not the way you thought it was.
Now,
how do you find out what the world is
actually like?
We have to investigate it.
You have to investigate.
It means you have to take a risk.
You have to move forward.
The same way that people do in
psychotherapy,
you have to find the thing that you're
bordering on avoiding and going and map
it.
Now,
it's a curious thing.
You know,
common anxiety disorders,
agora phobia,
Agora phobia is a generalized anxiety
disorder,
and people who suffer severely from
Agora Phobia often get to the point
where because of their panics,
they're housebound.
They can't go outside their room or
their house.
Now,
they'd run away from their room or their
house too if they could,
but there's nowhere to run.
So they're pretty much stuck being
somewhere.
So
an agoraphobic comes in for therapy,
I think,
well,
what do you do with them?
And you say,
well,
then I agoraphobic says I can't go on
elevators.
And you say,
okay,
well let's go try.
And you say,
all right,
well
relax.
It's teach the person to breathe.
It's really,
it doesn't help that much,
but it makes them feel better.
You can do this without teaching them to
relax.
It doesn't matter a bit,
but it does help them feel better.
You say,
okay,
well there's the elevator saying,
how close can you get to the elevator?
They say,
well,
I,
you know,
I can't really get more than like 20
feet.
That's maximum.
I said,
well,
okay,
let's just go up to 20 feet there and I
may do that.
And then you let them stand there and
stand there and stand there and stand
there and stand there.
And sooner or later they get bored of
being 20 feet from the elevator.
And then you say,
well look,
you know,
let,
let's,
couldn't you go 10 feet?
And I didn't know I couldn't go 10 feet.
That's too close.
How about,
could you go three more feet?
Yeah,
I think I could do that.
So they go three more feet and then he
let them stand there and they find out
nothing terrible is happening sooner or
later.
And then they go another three feet and
then they go another three feet and then
they're,
they're like confronting the elevator
and then they're inside the elevator.
But they're going like this because they
don't want to look at the elevator.
Right?
So you say,
well,
you've got to look at the elevator.
You can look at the numbers.
You got to look at the buttons.
Um,
so they do that.
Then you think,
well,
could we go up a floor?
No,
we couldn't go up and floor.
Okay,
well I'll tell you what,
we'll just close the door.
I'll put my hand and it'll open again.
Could you do that?
Yeah,
I could do that step by step sooner
later.
And usually sooner.
Bang.
They've gone up a floor.
Right?
So then what happens?
They go home and have a fight with her
husband that's been brewing for like 15
years.
Why?
Well,
it's not because the elevators
symbolically related to the fight has
nothing to do with it.
It's because what the person learns in
the combat with the unknown,
which just happens to be taking the
guise of an elevator,
is that they can confront things that
frightened them without being destroyed
by the confrontation.
And so what you see immediately,
and this was contrary to in the original
psychoanalytic prediction,
is that man,
you know,
you take that person out and you teach
them,
they can go on the elevator and right
off the bat they're going to shopping
malls,
they're in taxis,
they're back in the subway and they're
standing up for themselves at home.
Generalization.
Why?
Because they didn't learn that the
elevator wasn't frightening.
How doesn't let they learned,
they learned that despite the fact that
the elevator was this terrifying as
anything they've ever encountered,
they were actually up to the challenge.
And now that's a really useful thing to
teach someone,
right?
Because have you have an obsessive
compulsive patient?
Now?
I had one who actually used to work with
radiation or he was Tara.
He worked in some kind of bio lab in
Montreal.
People with obsessive compulsive
disorder often fairly frightened if
they'll contaminate someone else.
So like typical obsessive compulsive
obsession would be all go to a shopping
market.
I'll touch some fruit from,
you know,
some third world country.
I'll get some nasty bacterial disease.
I'll bring it home and I'll give it to
my kids while you tell them,
look,
you know the chances of that are like
one in 150,000 when they look at you and
they think,
I don't care if the chances are only
150,000 what if my kids die?
And you think,
well,
yeah,
that does pose a problem,
doesn't it?
Because it isn't exactly clear from a
logical perspective where you should
draw the risk line.
Well,
with the obsessive compulsive,
you do exactly the same thing.
You say,
look,
yeah,
your fears real.
No kidding.
Because lurking at the bottom of their
fear is the same fear that everybody
else has.
Right?
Same fear.
I might die,
I might get sick,
I might lose the people that I love.
Not only might that happen,
it's going to happen.
Why aren't people afraid of that all the
time?
We don't really know.
Obsessive person becomes aware of it.
What do you tell them?
You say do it anyway,
do it anyways.
And they learned quickly that if they
don't run away from the thing they
afraid of,
there's something in them that responds
to it.
They learned that the fear is not larger
than they are now.
I like getting the phone,
his case in particular,
because you've always might wonder with
this,
like what's the limit?
Right?
Okay.
Yeah.
That sounds good in theory,
but what if something really terrible
happened to you?
Well,
what's happened,
dad?
The forest patient starts up there with
terrible,
right?
I mean,
that's up there with terrible,
right stripped of social dignity,
violated physically that combines two of
people's most specific fears.
Well,
then there's other kinds of
confrontation to it.
I liked the story of Solzhenitsyn.
I think it's really a good one because
there's different kinds of dragons,
right?
There's natural dragons like death and
disease,
and then there's social dragons like
bureaucracies and tyrannies.
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn,
you may or may not know as a prisoner in
the salt Soviet ghoulag concentration
camp system,
that by his report at least killed 60
million people between 1919 to 1959
right?
60 million.
That's 10 times as many as Hitler
killed,
at least with regards to the genocide.
60 million people soldier knits,
and he had a pretty nasty life.
I mean,
first of all,
he's on the Russian front,
which was a nasty place to be.
Then he was captured by the Germans,
so they didn't like Russians.
So they put them in separate prisoners
of war camp,
partly because Stella and who was the
consummate paranoid wouldn't sign the
Geneva Convention on the treatment of
prisoners of war.
So the German set up extra pow camps for
the Russians,
and they starve generally so badly that
if other POW is we're in the vicinity,
they throw food packages over the wire,
even though they themselves weren't
particularly well fed.
So then,
so the war ends and the Russians,
we ended solution gets up and goes back
to Russia.
Right.
And what happens?
He's thinking,
you know,
wow,
this is over.
We help defend the father land we're
going to get,
if not a hero's welcome,
at least some welcome.
But stellan figured,
no,
no.
These Russians had been to the west.
They were contaminated by their exposure
to the Western economic system.
And as a consequence of that,
they posed a threat to the integrity,
the Soviet state.
So he just threw them all in
concentration camps.
So fine.
So Solzhenitsyn sitting there in this
concentration camp on a coal pile,
a coal pile,
which contain this kind of clay that his
compatriots would eat because they were
so damn hungry that it was better to
have the clay in their stomach,
that nothing at all.
And he thought,
all right,
what the hell did I do to get here?
Which is really a remarkable thing to
think,
right?
Because like there was the second world
war and that probably couldn't been
pinned directly on him.
And then there's Stellan who was,
you know,
really one of the world's worst
monsters.
And then there's the concentration camp
and the POW camp.
And like a lot of things happened to
soldier Knutsen,
but he said he had nothing but time to
think in this concentration camp.
And he wasn't really that happy with the
way things turned out.
So he made a vow in the camp and the vow
was this.
He said he is going to go back over his
whole life,
right from day one and try to remember
every time he ever did something he
thought was wrong.
He thought,
right,
not someone else,
but that that gave his conscience a
Pang.
How'd he said?
Well,
since I don't have anything better to
do,
I'm going to spend like the next 10
years seeing if I can undo all those
little knots in my soul that I tied.
And the consequence of that was that he
wrote a book called the Gulag
Archipelago,
right?
Three volume book,
1900 pages long.
He memorized it because there wasn't any
paper and pencil available for him in
prison.
And then it circulated in the
underground and the Soviet Union for
years before it got published in the
last published in 1975 definitely one of
the literary events that brought down
the Soviet Union.
So I think that's kind of interesting,
isn't it?
To think this one guy,
right?
He's got numbers tattooed on his arm.
He's a skinny as a rail.
He's three quarters dead.
He's been beat to death in 15 different
ways.
He decides under completely unreasonable
circumstances that he's going to take
personal responsibility for the position
that he happens to find himself in.
The consequence of that 25 years later
is that Solzhenitsyn's still around but
the Soviet Union isn't and you think,
well that can't be the way the world
works now Canon,
but then you think this too,
like do we really know how the world
works?
Right?
We've had a pretty nasty century in the
last hundred years,
right?
We had the Nazis,
we had mt say tongue.
We had the recent tragedies in Africa.
We don't seem to learn anything about
genocide.
Someone like Solzhenitsyn says,
wow,
you know,
might be your fault.
Why?
What are you ignoring?
Good question.
Can you make peace with your own family?
It's not so easy,
right?
It's probably no easier than making
peace between the Israelis and the
Palestinians.
What are we encounter when we
encountered something we don't
understand?
We don't know.
It's not the simple world of objects.
The simple world of objects is something
we've learned to see.
The real world is way more complicated
than what we just see.
Let me give you an example.
When I was in Montreal in 1985 my
computer crashed.
So what do you do when your computer
crashes?
While we're not,
we're not computer encounter something
unexpected.
It crashes.
It can't do a damn thing about it.
You have to fix it.
So I checked the monitoring.
It was okay.
I wouldn't go on.
It seemed all right.
Then I noticed my labs weren't working,
so I went to the fuse box.
So all the fuses seemed okay.
So then I went outside to go down to the
corner store to get a cigarette and I
saw that outside.
All the lights were off,
the traffic lights were off,
right?
The whole city was in darkness.
Then I found out the next day that there
was a solar wind,
big solar flare,
put out a big cloud of electrons zipped
along to Earth at the speed of light,
put an electrical pulse through the
Hydro Electric Grid.
And Quebec crashed my computer.
Well,
I hadn't thought until that point that
the integrity of my computer was
dependent on the stability of the sun.
Everything is way more complicated than
it looks,
and when you just look at something,
you see a very simple representation of
what's actually there.
What do you encounter when you encounter
something unexpected?
Well,
when you first encounter it,
you don't know.
All you know is that frightens you,
but it makes you curious.
Think dragons,
right?
Every primates afraid of lizards,
including us.
Chimpanzees don't like snakes.
If you take a champ,
it's never seen a snake.
You throw it us to show it a snake,
it will hit the roof of its cage.
Then it'll look at the snake.
Why would a drag and hoard gold?
Because a dragon represents everything
that you're afraid of.
What's embedded in everything that
you're afraid of.
Absolutely everything that you need to
find run from what you're afraid of,
run from exactly what you need to find.
One of the oldest dramatic
representations we know of,
not this specific painting.
This is Saint George and the dragon
dragon lives in the ground
chase,
thereby heroes of a previous generation
now and then re-emerging kills people,
right?
These are skulls around it's
layer.
It threatens the integrity of the
community.
Like everything unexpected does.
Hero comes out,
slays the dragon,
freeze the treasure.
This case it's a virgin,
a woman
dragon's hoard gold because the thing
you most need is always to be found
where you least want to look.
I'm going to close this with another
dream.
This is dream my five year old nephew
had,
now he got to get the context of this
stream right here.
After this dream,
parents were divorced
so there were dragons in the house.
He was about four at this time is
running around the house with this
little plastic night helmet on and its
sword is zipping around,
killing things with it,
doing this all at the time and even when
he went to sleep at night,
he'd put this,
the a sword by his pillow and the night
helmet on his pillow.
Now,
every night or every second night or
every third night for six months,
he'd been waking up screaming.
Now why?
While he was about to go to
kindergarten,
right?
So that's,
that's a real threshold for kid,
way from maternal dependence
fundamentally into the real world.
That's,
that's a new thing.
But also there was upset in his house.
So I was there one night when he woke up
screaming next morning,
I said,
well,
did you dream anything?
And so he launched into this story,
he said,
dwarf.
He was in this field and these little
creatures like dwarves were coming up to
him and they didn't have any arms.
They just had legs and they were bad,
big beaks.
And they were covered with hair and
Greece and on top of their head was
across,
shaved into this hair and there's lots
and lots of these doors.
And they were jumping on him with their
beaks,
biting him.
And we all looked at him thought,
well,
it's no wonder you're waking up
screaming,
right?
I mean,
you know,
that doesn't sound so good.
And then he said,
well,
wait,
there's more right back in the distance.
There's a dragon and the dragon is
puffing out fire and smoke and every
time he pops out foreign smoke,
it turns into these dwarfs.
Big problem,
right?
Just like the problem with the Hydra in
Greek mythology,
cut off one head,
seven more appear.
Right?
So are you going to do about these kill
one big deal,
10 more common.
I said,
what can you do about that now in
illegal trial,
that would have been an inadmissible
question,
right?
That's called leading the witness
because what I told him was despite the
horror of this situation,
you maybe could do something about it
and he said,
hi,
I'd take my sword.
I get my dad.
That's a good idea,
right?
Dad,
here's the real dad and then there's the
tradition dad,
right?
You might as well have your father by
your side if you're going to go into
battle.
I'd take my sword,
I get my dad,
I go to where the dragon was.
I jumped up on his head.
I put both of his eyes out with this
sword.
I'd go down his throat to the place with
the fire comes out.
I can cut a piece of that box out and
I'd use it as a shield and I thought,
wow,
that's unbelievable.
Unbelievable that he could do that.
It's perfect,
right?
There's no sense going after the dwarves
because thousands of them,
you might as well go after the dragon.
What happens if you go after the Dragon?
You get a piece of it,
right?
A piece of its center nature,
a piece that can defend you against
anything including other dragons.
So what if this was the case you think
evolutionarily speaking or religiously
speaking,
what if we were adapted to the world?
And what if it's not the simple place of
dead objects that we think it is?
What if it's something a lot more alive?
Lot more like a story?
What if the story is something like
this?
You have absolutely everything you need,
but you have to use all of it.
If you run away from any of it,
and in particular the parts of it that
frighten you,
which you know there's endless reasons
to run away from.
If you run away from any of it,
you don't get that piece of the Dragon.
If you miss even one piece,
there's a chink in your armor.
There's a place where you're vulnerable.
If you make even one mistake,
you lessen yourself.
If you less than yourself,
you're going to run away more.
Not only that,
when someone wants to lean on you,
they're not going to be able to lean on
you because you'll just fall over.
What if it was the case that we were
adapted to the world really adapted to
it so that if we made full use of all
the talents we had,
we'd be okay.
What if it was the case that if we set
out consciously to never run away from
something,
we know we shouldn't run away from that?
Everything would be all right.
Well,
you can think whatever you want to
think,
but this is what I think.
I think it's bloody amazing that that
Little Kid's book that I read you at the
beginning of this lecture had all that
information in it,
and so you might ask yourself when you
leave,
if that information isn't true,
how the hell did it get there?
That's it.
Thanks.
[inaudible]
support Ontario's public television.
Donate at [inaudible] dot org.