Hi everyone,
I thought I would take three minutes to
let you know where I'm going to be
speaking publicly in Canada,
the United States and Europe now until
the end of 2018.
I've been touring for about three months
discussing the issues of meaning and
responsibility raised in my books,
12 rules for life and maps of meaning.
My wife,
Tammy and I have already been in 60
cities and I've spoken to about 200,000
people.
Here are the Canadian,
American,
and European cities.
I will be traveling to over the next
five months.
Calgary,
Friday,
July 27th,
Edmonton.
Saturday,
July 28.
Winnipeg Sunday,
July 29th,
Regina.
Tuesday,
August 14th,
Saskatoon,
Wednesday,
August 15th,
row chest,
Wednesday,
September fifth,
Westbury.
Thursday,
September sixth,
Wallingford.
Friday,
September seventh,
Baltimore.
Sunday,
September ninth,
Durham.
Monday,
September 10th,
Miami.
Thursday,
September 13th,
Orlando,
Friday,
September 14th,
St Petersburg,
Saturday,
September 15th,
Jacksonville.
Sunday,
September 16th,
Cincinnati.
Tuesday,
September 18th,
cleveland.
Wednesday,
September 19th,
grand rapids.
Thursday,
September Twentieth des Moines,
Tuesday,
October second St Louis,
Wednesday,
October third,
Kansas City.
Thursday,
October fourth,
Denver,
Sunday,
October seventh,
Colorado Springs,
Monday,
October eight,
San Antonio,
Wednesday,
October 10th,
Irving,
Thursday,
October 11th,
Honolulu,
Wednesday,
November 21st Los Angeles,
Saturday,
December first back in Canada,
Calgary,
Thursday,
December fourth,
Vancouver,
Wednesday,
December fifth.
Then it's off to Europe.
Dublin,
Sunday,
October 21st Oslo Tuesday,
October 23rd,
Manchester,
Thursday,
October 25th Oxford.
Friday,
October 26th,
Glasgow,
Saturday,
October 27th,
Edinburgh Sunday,
October 28th,
Amsterdam,
Tuesday,
October 30th,
Cambridge,
Thursday,
November first,
Helsinki Sunday,
November fourth,
Stockholm Monday,
November fifth and Birmingham.
Wednesday November seventh.
We'll be adding some more cities to the
European leg of this tour.
There'll be announced soon and also
we're going to Australia in February and
then back to Europe in April of 2019.
Those dates will be announced in the
relatively near future.
It's been really something to to around
like this and these events have been
extremely positive,
so if you're inclined to come out and
hear me lecture,
you'd be more than welcome.
Thank you very much.
Bye Bye.