Hi everyone.
Thanks for tuning in to the April,
2019 Q and a probably won't
do another one until June.
I'm traveling almost
completely through May,
although it's getting easier
to do these on the road.
Camera quality usually isn't as good,
so we'll see what happens.
I like doing both, but be nice to do
it with the right equipment. So look,
before we get started, I've got a bunch
of things I'd like to tell you about.
I hope that you're interested in the
first one and the oddest one I suppose is
the fact that I'm going to be debating
the renowned Marxist philosopher Slavoj
[inaudible],
who's a very well,
well known continental academic tomorrow
at the Sony Center in Toronto at seven
30 on the topic happiness
capitalism versus Marxism.
We've decided we'll live streaming this
event for those who might be interested
in marching the events as they unfold.
Tickets for the livestream
are available on my website,
Jordan peterson.com but I'll
put all the proper links below.
So if you pick up a livestream ticket,
you can view the debate at any
time up to 30 days afterwards.
We're also going to put the
debate eventually up on Youtube,
probably within a month.
So if you don't want to watch it live
well then you can always wait and watch it
later. But if you want to participate
in it in so far as you can do that
electronically,
then I guess the livestream
idea is the right one.
We thought we'd run it
as an experiment anyways.
Maybe you can have a Peterson versus
Dziedzic party if that's the sort of party
you're interested in on a Friday night.
I'd also like to know,
let you know that season two of the
Jordan would be Peterson podcasts has now
started with the first three episodes up.
Two of them are 12 rules for life
lectures taken from my tour last year.
Uh, one of them from Seattle and one from
Portland as well as an interview with
General Stanley McChrystal,
retired four star general and former
commander US forces Afghanistan.
We partnered this year with Westwood one
largest audio network in the u s and my
daughter Mckayla is
going to serve as cohost.
So hopefully that allowed a little
bit of lightness and warmth.
And a little bit of humor
to the podcast and um,
we're hoping as a consequence
of partnering with Westwood One,
which also means by the way that the
podcast will now be ad supported. Um,
that that would help incentivize me to
make sure that I got a podcast out every
week.
It was a bit haphazard over the last year.
The broadcast was generally
a lower priority item and
we've decided this year to
make it,
well a top priority or perhaps at
least in the top five. Let's see.
So,
um,
and we hope we'll get higher production
quality out of it and be able to find a
larger audience.
And so I guess we'll see how that goes.
The initial feedback has been pretty
good with about 600,000 or so views per
episode, so that seems to be performing
quite nicely. So thank you all for that.
Jordan B. Peterson videos
on youtube, which will,
we'll also feature most of the podcast
content like it has in the past will
remain unmarried monetized as previously.
Now next we will get to the questions,
I promise.
I'm going to London in May to celebrate.
And promote the release of the May 2nd
standard paperback of 12 rules for life
into the UK, Australia,
New Zealand Indian,
and other international English markets,
not including US and Canada.
Yet preorders of that paper back can
be obtained at the penguin website.
I'll leave the links below.
I'm extremely excited.
One of the things I was really
excited about this year, you know,
I wrote the foreword to Alexander
Solzhenitsyn's abridged good Uyghur
archipelago. So that was, that
was, uh, I was a pretty good honor.
That was, uh, last week,
by the way, in New York.
I talked to his son
[inaudible] and we, we, uh,
spend about an hour discussing historical
material related to the Gulag and
that'll be released
with the audio version,
which I've read the forward because as
I said, I wrote the foreword and ignite,
I believe,
read the rest of the audio,
but that'll be released in audio book form
fairly soon along with that interview.
So that was extremely interesting.
He's a very accomplished man in his
own right as a pianist and conductor,
and it has a very successful
international career. So, um,
he has his father's intellect,
that's for sure.
So it's really exciting for me,
was very exciting for me to
do that forward. But it's,
I would say equally exciting to have
a paper back in the great tradition of
Penguin paperbacks,
which I've loved ever since I was old
enough to know the difference between
let's, no, let's rephrase that old enough
to start to read serious literature.
And so to have,
uh,
a paper come out on the Penguin label is,
well,
I just saw the first copy of it this
week. They sent it to me. It's, um,
hard to believe, man. It's,
uh, it's, uh, I think,
I don't even how you think I even had
that as a dream. You know, I didn't,
I didn't think that was,
was there ever any likelihood of that?
So it's better than a dream come true in
some sense because it's a dream that I
never even suspected might occur.
That came true.
So that's good.
Anyways,
you can preorder that if
you're inclined to, uh,
it's discounted in price, of course, to
the, in comparison to the hardcover. Um,
maybe it'd bank a good gift for someone
you like suming you liked the book.
So
finally,
most of the time when I do a Q and,
a,
I also talk a little bit about two
programs that my colleagues and I have
developed.
One called self authoring Dotcom and
the other called understand myself.com.
And the first one is a set of writing
programs that help you write an
autobiography and a description of your
present personality and a plan for the
future and they're all laid out.
So that doing that is what guided and
scaffold and simplified so that you don't
have to answer the terribly
difficult question.
Who was I when I grew up till now?
All as one question.
Anyway,
a lot of people have used the programs,
there's tens of thousands of them now
and we have good evidence for the future
authoring program in particular,
which helps people make a plan and
develop a vision and make a plan for the
future. That, for example,
among college students,
it decreases their dropout rate by
about 25%. It seems to have, um,
about the same effect on their
grade point average. So anyways,
these writing exercises, if there's
anything bothering you about your past,
you know, you can tell that because
you have negative memories. Um,
let's say of anything that happened
to you 18 months or previous,
shouldn't really mess around with
traumatic memories before they're about 18
months old. But if your past
still haunts you, you know,
if you can't stop thinking about it,
then there's,
there's things that have happened
to you that you don't understand.
You don't understand the causal pathways
that lead you down the path that you
are now afraid of or regret.
And they alarm systems that make up your,
the,
the parts of your brain that control
anxiety will never let you free of that
because their job is to alert you to
danger and past or present perhaps in case
you encountered the same situation again.
And unless you've come up
with an elaborated causal
account of what put you at
risk,
then you're likely to suffer from
those anxiety related or trauma related
memories for your whole life.
So you can write the autobiography part
of self authoring dark come and asks you
to break your life into 70 parks and
write about the important positive and
negative experiences in each and analyze
them. And I've had plenty of people,
I'm not making a formal
scientific claim here by the way,
but there is good evidence that this
kind of riding does help people, um,
uh, come to terms with their past and
increase their psychological health.
We haven't done those studies specifically
on our program so I don't want to
claim that we have,
but I have had many people mentioned
that after completing the past authoring
program,
a lot of the things that they had bothered
them chronically had begin to recede
into the past they belonged.
So anyways,
we're offering those programs.
The self authoring program,
you can buy two for one,
there's a special on,
it's rather permanent special because
it seems to be very popular anyways.
That means you can buy one for you and
a friend and it's 20% off and so is
understand myself.com.
That's a personality test that
I developed with my colleagues.
That gives you a big five readout,
extroversion, neuroticism, agreeableness,
conscientiousness and openness.
I think I go to all five there and
10 of the aspects that make them up.
So it's very high resolution personality
test and it's been on the horse side is
not designed to make you feel good.
It's designed to actually tell you about
your strengths and weaknesses and look,
man, everybody has strengths
and weaknesses. So you know,
if there's a bit that's harsh in the,
in the test results, don't feel too bad.
It's not like you're
alone in that anyways.
The code for the 20% discount is may
and it's valid until the end of May.
And so look these, these
programs, you know,
let's think about the future
authoring program. It's,
it's really a good thing to have
a plan for your life. You know,
you're not going to get what you need
and you want less the aim at it and you
know,
and aim at it unless he knew what it is
and you're not going to know what it is
unless you think about what it
is that you need and you want.
And it's hard for people to do that
and we're not trained to do that.
It doesn't happen to us in school.
It doesn't happen to us in university.
We liked the future authoring program
and this and the past authoring program
and the present authoring program.
They all the clinical evidence about
programs like this suggests that they work
very well and they're there
and you can do them badly.
That's the other thing that's kind
of cool is you don't have to get all
perfectionistic about it.
You don't have to write a perfect account
of your past and you don't have to
come up with the right plan for the future
because you're not going to anyways.
Cause what do you know about
what the future's going to bring?
It's still worthwhile to chart
a course though, you know,
because it increases the probability
that you'll get what you want.
So you know, my, my
colleagues, Daniel Higgins,
he's at Harvard and, or
was it Harvard? He's a PA,
has a phd from Harvard and Bob Bob Peele
who just resigned or just retired from
McGill.
We built these programs over a couple
of years along with some of my graduate
students, particularly
Raymond Mar. And uh,
we think they've been really
useful for people. So, um,
and you know what,
we were trying to figure out low costs,
psychological interventions
that could be scaled,
that would not do people any harm that
they could do on their own with minimal
administrative overhead and cost.
And so that's the philosophy
that underlies them. So, um,
well that's enough of that.
I should also mention finally,
for those of you who might be interested,
I was in New York this week, um,
on Monday for example, um, I
taped 16 interviews with Dr Oz.
Now there's a man with energy.
I'll tell you we did that.
I was pretty much fried by the
end of that. His wife Lisa,
who's very bright person and who
knows my work very well asked, uh,
wrote out all the questions that Dr
Oz used to interview me. And, uh,
they were killer questions.
I had to think about every one of them.
And so we seem to have a good time.
There was a bit of a studio audience there
and they seem to like the discussion.
And so these will appear as 10 to 15
minute video clips either on Dr Oz's
broadcast show or on youtube or both.
And you know,
it never know. They might show up
on my channel as well. Um, but um,
before Warren they're coming and
hopefully, what did he call them?
He thought it would be useful if there
were good 10 minute clips of some of the
things that I've talked
about for people to access.
And so he's got a nice professional
studio and I like working with them. Um,
so,
well that was New York House did a talk
last night at the beacon theater, um,
which was sold out. So that's the
third time the beacon is sold out.
So I don't know what it
is about New Yorkers,
but they seem to like to talk about
sorrow and suffering and malevolence and
Russian communist camps and well,
maybe also the possibility of having a
reasonable and productive and meaningful
life. And that's really why people are
there. So it was a good, a good event.
And my daughter Mckayla,
um, opened the show.
So that was kind of fun.
And she also did the Q and a because
there's a Q and a portion of its that was
different and it was cute warm as far as
I was concerned and she's kind of funny
and so that was helpful as
well. So anyways, um, uh,
as a lot of news,
hopefully it wasn't too much.
And so now I'll do my best
to answer your questions.
Um, I'm a little, no, I guess
I'm not quite ready yet.
Little nervous about the
debate was Dziedzic tomorrow.
I'm not a political philosopher,
you know,
and it's been a long time since I read
Mark's re-read the communist manifesto
over the last couple of weeks
and tried to think it through.
And so I'm going to talk tomorrow about
the essence of the capitalist flow or
the communist philosophy. Um,
I don't think I've read a book.
Well,
we'll leave it at that.
I'm going to take it apart tomorrow at
the lecture and, uh, I hope I'm ready.
I've got 25 minutes to
make my case pretty short.
Shouldn't take a lot of
prep time if I'm careful,
but I can't waste any of
the time. And, and uh,
I'd really like to do a good job cause
I think it's an important debate.
No,
it's an important subject.
I don't know if it's going
to be an important debate.
I know a lot of people in
Europe will be watching it, so.
All right everyone, let's see,
um, what we've got here to,
to address,
have you had been allotted the
opportunity asked Michael Mix?
What would you have discussed with nature?
Well,
I think I would have discussed with them
what the psychoanalysts discovered in
the 20th century or what they
claimed to have discovered, who,
which I believe was a genuine discovery.
See when nature announced the
death of God, which by the way,
as you may know from listening
to my lectures was not
precisely a triumphal, um,
wasn't an announcement of triumph.
It was announced.
It was a warning and the tolling
of bells of Sorrell. That's a,
that's a good way of, of thinking
about it. Even though Nisha was a
at styled himself as a vicious,
an intellectually vicious critic
of institutionalized Christianity,
which he certainly was.
He was also a strange friend to the faith.
I think in the most fundamental sense,
that's the truth.
He wrote some things about Christ, for
example, which were very positive. Um,
and I think the reason he,
I,
he understood as well how important
the narrative substructure of the Judeo
Christian tradition was to the
maintenance of Western civilization.
He understood. He, here's one of the
people I learned that from, you know, um,
so
see,
so when Nietzsche announced the
death that God, he did it softly and,
and then he tried to think about what we
might be able to do about that because
it was going to lead us down to bad
pathways. You'd the towards nihilism
and the belief or what would you call the
direct experience that because God was
dead, everything might be permitted
as, as Dostoyevsky pointed out,
or totalitarianism,
which would arise as irrational
substitute for them dogmas of religion.
And he knew that, that both of those
would be catastrophic occurrences.
And so he was trying to figure
out what we could do too.
Heal ourselves I suppose as a consequence
of this great loss cause neat.
You also believed, well I mentioned
this, that you know, the belief in God,
just not something so simple as belief
and you know, a bearded man in the sky.
It's sad to even have to say that
and maybe it's not necessary but,
but at least you know more,
more profoundly that the death of the
idea that a universe ordered by something
that's akin to the living and
conscience and conscious and,
and intelligent.
Um,
it's rough to replace that with
pure random meaninglessness.
And of course that's the pathway
denialism. Anyways, neat.
You thought we would have to create our
own values to replace those that would
fall because of the death of
Christianity and the psychoanalysts,
Freud and young, particularly
young. But Freud began at,
I think,
and you've made this explicit,
I think found a fatal flaw
and niches theorizing.
And maybe it's a fatal flaw in
relationship to modernism per se.
Even to the idea of rational thought
itself as master of its own house.
You're not,
you can't make your own
values and you can aim,
you can direct your life.
You can,
you can cooperate in determining
the values that you pursue,
but you cooperate with forces in yourself
that aren't you and can't be made you,
not, not in any straight forward way.
And it's easy to understand this.
If you think about,
for example,
the fact that if you do something that
you shouldn't do or if you don't do
something that you should do,
that you'll lay awake in bed at night
and torment yourself about it and worry
about it and consider yourself
an unworthy person. You know,
as if you believed in the idea of sin.
It's a very strange thing that there's
an ethic that calls to you from within
that you can't control that, that
holds you responsible for your actions.
Now it's just one of many
sub personalities in some
sense that are operative
within people in it.
It depends,
I suppose on how integrated
the personality is.
The less integrated people
are more different depending
on what emotional state
they're in.
But you know with the,
the you that's overwhelmed with grief
or the you that's overwhelmed with,
with love or lust or,
or the you that's overwhelmed with anger
possessed by those things is really
often by no means the same you that you
like to think of yourself as when you're
under full conscious control and,
and in your normal state of mind.
I mean even the idea of of
drunkenness intoxication,
that's possession by a spirit, right?
That's why whiskey is a spirit.
It's the spirit of Dionysius and you
drink and you become something that you
normally aren't. You know,
they say in Vino Veritas,
but it's not necessarily reasonable to
believe that everything you do and say,
well you're intoxicated
by alcohol is true.
The point is that there are
multiple personalities that
work within you and they
have a fair bit of autonomy,
like a strange autonomy.
If you could just create your own values,
you can imagine when some sense you'd
be doing what Ruskell Nicole tried to do
in crime and punishment,
which is a book I'd really recommend.
He believed that Nietzsche, an idea
that you could create your own values.
And as a consequence, he decided
to murder a terrible old woman, um,
who was oppressing many of the people in
our neighborhood and seemed loved by no
one and hated by everyone.
And who is a vicious slave master to her,
not very bright,
nice and risk.
Melnikov thought that he could
do away with her, that would,
that would get him out of
some financial trouble.
And then he would do good
things with the money.
And that if he was a real superman in
some sense in the Nietzschean manner of
thinking that he could just dispense with
all the guilt that might logically be
associated with murder. Because
after all, if there's no god,
everything is permitted and
we can create our own values.
And crime and punishment is
an unbelievably deep study
of what happens when you
cross a line that you shouldn't have
crossed because of your own arrogance.
And so it was gone. The cough, this is
a thriller, this, this book, you know,
a real detective story. Well, he, uh,
I hate, I'm not going to blow the plot,
but he,
he sort of successful in the murder.
It gets away with it,
although it doesn't exactly turn out
the way he expects even the act itself.
And,
but what he discovers in the aftermath
of what he did is that he was no where
near as in control of himself and his
personality and his emotional reactions.
And he's as he thought,
and he tortures himself for a very long
time with very interesting psychological
and social consequences as well as
driving the plot ahead very rapidly with
what's what he's done. Absolute start
traumatized disbelief at what he's done.
And so what I'd like to ask Nisha,
because that's the question that I'm
supposed to be answering is given the
mutability of man,
the fact that we are composed of multiple
sub personalities, which by the way,
it was something that needs you actually
mentioned and that I believe that both
Freud and noon relied on when they
were formulating their psychoanalytic
theories, given the fact that we
aren't masters of our own houses.
And given the fact that we're
divided amongst ourselves.
How in the world is it possible for
us to develop our own values when,
when we're a massive internal
contradictions and were,
and each of those contradictions is a
consequence of something live trying to
make its case made. You know, like
if you were your own creation,
whatever that might mean,
if you are in full control of your
own consciousness and emotions and
motivations,
well then you certainly wouldn't be guilty
about things you didn't do or did do
because you could just revamp your
value structure at will to optimize,
let's say your emotional
state and you know,
it's good to some degree
to be able to do that,
to cheer yourself up and to
dampen your grief. But man,
you're not as in control of
yourself as you'd like to think.
And you're haunted by many things that
you could be in many things that you are.
One of the things that
really terrified me,
I think enough to change when I was to
change the way I was living when I was
studying psychology was that encounter
with that psychoanalytic idea that you're
not alone in your psyche.
You know,
you can even tell that
if you're a student,
if you're trying to read
something that you have to read,
you know there's difference between
reading something you have to read and
something that you want to read. If you
want to read it, you can just read it.
If you have to read it,
you might not read it at all.
You might just procrastinate endlessly.
Uh,
even even if there's an important outcome,
like an exam,
even if the consequence of that exam
might be failing a course and destroying
your academic record,
you'll still find yourself very resistant
to read the paper unless you happen to
be personally interested in it.
And that's so interesting too,
because even at that level,
you're not the sort of person that
can create their own values. Man.
You can't even convince yourself to read
a piece of complex writing if you're a
university student enrolled
in a course that you chose,
that that assignment is part of.
And so that's a pretty good indication
of just how many directions you're pulled
in simultaneously. So I would really
like to discuss that with Nietzsche.
I would like to know what he thinks
thought about that. You know,
maybe he thought that despite
our dissociate ability and
the multiplicity of our
personality,
that the possibility or the necessity
of creating our own value as soon as the
only chance we had, but, but,
but what you see,
what I learned from Yom,
and this is the probably the most
profound thing I learned, I think
of all the things that I know perhaps
is that values aren't created.
They're discovered and they're discovered
through a consultation with the parts
of yourself that you're not conscious of,
that you're not fully conscious of,
that aren't articulated,
that aren't fully articulated
elements of your primary personality.
You have to discover what your values
are and you're informed about that.
Well, partly by other people who will
object. If your values aren't appropriate,
but certainly by a dialogue with
yourself and with your conscience,
that's,
that's an a very important thing to know.
It's a part of the reason why I think
that you need to tell the truth because
you're forced to negotiate with yourself
to operate properly in the world.
And if you've worked yourself,
let's say,
or some elements of yourself by
engaging in self deception and lies,
and you're not now because of that,
you're not who you could be and you don't
live in the world as you should live
in it. Then when you discuss with
yourself what your value should be,
it will be as if you're discussing it
with someone that you can't trust and
that's, that's not good. Like you.
You can't afford that.
Life is difficult and it contains many
pitfalls and unless you're careful and
you sort yourself out properly and you
aim high and walk on the straight and
narrow path,
you don't have a hope of understanding
where you should be and at what time,
when the crisis hits
and the crisis will hit.
So you want to get all those little sub
personalities in a line. If you can't,
it's part of the reason, for example,
why you thought you had an integrate.
Your shout at which is the
dark part of your character.
He thought that was necessary or where
it would go and have a little autonomous
life of its own may be manifesting itself,
for example,
when you're angry or drunk instead
of integrated into the rest of your
personality,
like a properly disciplined player
in a complex and sophisticated game.
So,
hmm.
How lots of tough questions today.
Here's one from Basil.
I live in constant worry. My children
are going to be hit by a car, kidnapped,
murdered, beaten up. It's
a torture. How can I stop?
Well,
I guess the first thing I
would say is that you should
reassure yourself, and I know that's
a paradoxical to think about it,
that these things could
happen. You know, look,
I've never been surprised as a
clinician that people were anxious.
So what you say, it doesn't surprise me
except that the constancy part of it,
perhaps it's surprising because
children can get hit by cars, kidnapped,
murdered and beaten up. Um, and it
is a torture to contemplate that.
And so you might ask yourself,
not Bazell not why so much you're
living in constant worry that that could
happen to your children.
But why everyone else isn't always
living in constant worry that that could
happen. You know, because tragedy
can strike and it strikes children.
Apparently you're quite attached to
your children and so aren't very,
what would you say,
Suze by the realization
that something terrible could happen
to them now, you know, first of all,
I might say you might want to go talk
to somebody professional about this,
you know,
because maybe you're depressed more
than you should be and maybe you have an
anxiety disorder.
Um,
I'm not saying that that
is not a diagnosis and I
certainly couldn't derive that
from what you said,
but it's one of the possible things that
could contribute to this constant worry.
You know,
or,
or maybe you're physiologically ill
and less resilient than you should be,
maybe you're not eating enough.
Um,
one thing I would recommend to begin with
is to make sure that you just try this.
I know it's surprising advice,
but try to eat a big breakfast for
like two weeks. See what happens,
see if that drives the worry doubt.
Now.
Then the next thing I would ask is
when does it happen? Like is it,
are these dreams or these
thoughts before you go to bed,
you wake up in the middle of the night
with these visions running through your
head. Um, and again,
this has to do with food.
Is it more likely to
happen if you're hungry?
That's what something worth checking out
because the next time you get worried
in the middle of the day,
you might try eating something.
I would recommend something high protein,
high fat rather than high carbohydrate.
And just see if that helps.
Because that might indicate that some
of your worry is a consequence of
hyperglycemia. And that's a lot
more common than people think.
So if it's dreams and visions at night,
you know,
one of the things you can do that's
counterproductive is you take one of those
fantasies that's torturing you,
you know, and that you're Oprah,
you're suppressing because you will be
suppressing it and let it play itself out.
You see what's happening is
that the parts of your mind,
the parts of your brain,
the parts of your psyche,
that our alarm system,
so that's the anxiety systems are they're
trying to think something through and
they're using fantasy to think it through,
right?
And so this is actually a form of thought.
It's torturing you because it's reasonable
for the parts of your brain that are
on the outlook for negative occurrences
to think, well, what if, what if?
What if?
That's what thinking is.
And sometimes you think positively what
f and sometimes you think negatively and
well you're
in all likelihood doing everything you
can to escape from these thoughts when
they make themselves manifest.
But all that does is make the systems
that are producing those thoughts even
more likely to produce them. Because
now they think the alarm system thinks,
oh, well here's the danger, which is
basically the vulnerability of children.
And I'm trying to present,
um, the active agent,
the person who I inhabit with evidence
of this potential threat as a good alarm
system.
And it turns out that they're so afraid
of the message that I'm delivering that
they won't even listen to it.
Therefore,
that situation must be much
more dire than I suppose.
And I'm going to amp the APP.
I'm going to have to amplify and increase
the emotion of my statement and the
repetitiveness of the thought.
And so that's just not helpful at all,
right?
Because what you've done is you've taken
a worry and you've now recategorized it
as a worry that so terrible that
you won't even think about it.
And so now the alarm systems think that
you're being chased by he who can't be
named.
That's a good way of thinking about it
and a good allusion to something popular
in culture. And so they're just
going to be screaming nonstop.
So what do you have to do? Well,
man, this is counterproductive,
but I'll tell you it
works next time you have,
there's a couple of things you could do.
You could start by bringing
to mind those fantasies.
Sit down somewhere,
take some deep breaths,
try to calm yourself
down a little bit and let
those thoughts come forward.
You know what they are and then watch
them like you're watching a movie.
Even if it's a horror movie,
watched them.
Let the whole fantasy play out and see
what what comes out at the end now at at
even if it's, it's going to be
frightening to do this. Now look,
even if the vision is quite horrific,
right?
The entire thought is quite horrific.
You have now indicated to your anxiety
systems that you have enough courage to
face the worrisome event and just
that alone should be helpful.
Now,
you may have to do this multiple times
and you might have to do it with all the
thoughts and you'll know that you're,
you know that you will have done it.
You'll know that you've done it enough
when doing it starts to become mundane
when all the emotion goes out of it.
And if you're particularly frightened,
that might take a long time. Now the other
thing that you might really consider,
this is something you
can do as an adjunct,
is you should think about what
you would do if this would happen,
if this happened, you know, as
if it happened in real life.
And to take even the worst case
situation, you know? So let's say,
let's say that you received the news
that your child would was hit by a car.
Well, you know, you could receive news
like that. And then the question is, well,
what would you do and what you should,
what should you do?
And the answer is you don't know.
You think that that would kill you.
You think that that
would be unbearable and,
and the end of the world, and it's
not surprising that you think that,
but it's not helpful.
You know,
because people have to live
through catastrophe and you
have more than one child
apparently.
And I would presume as well that you
have a spouse and other people that love
you and need you.
And so it isn't good that you would fall
apart and die in an apocalyptic dread
if something happened to one of the people
that you love because then you would
leave all the other people
bereft of you as well.
And that's not helpful.
And so if your child was hit by a car,
well what would you do? We have to think
it through. You know, you'd grieve,
you'd go to the hospital,
you'd have a terrible time,
you'd have a terrible year,
you know,
and that would be that.
And you'd have the funeral and you'd have
the loss of the child and all of that
would be
awful.
But people live through that.
You know?
And maybe you could have an aim and
aim would be that if that happened,
your determination would be to live
through it so that you could be there for
the rest of your people and so that you
wouldn't fall apart and collapse because
the death of someone and the subsequent
utter collapse of a person closely
associated with them, that that second
event does not improve the first one.
It makes it worse.
And it's incumbent upon you to develop
the psychological strength to be able to
tolerate what it is that your anxiety
alarm systems are tormenting you with.
And you know, you might think, well
that's impossible, but you know,
it's not impossible because people live
through catastrophe and they do that in
large part are no small part by
by discovering that there are darker
and stronger forces within them,
then they might be willing to appreciate.
And that one of the consequences of
integrating those forces is that you have
the strengths and the cruelty
in some strange sense to endure,
right,
to dare continue to live,
even if the unthinkable happens.
And it's no simple matter to think
of that as a moral step forward.
But you know,
people are called upon to be strong
and strong in the face of the worst
catastrophe. And your psyche is
tormenting you with precisely that.
You know, it won't let you go. It'll
shake you like a dog shakes a ride.
It won't let you go
until you deal with it.
Deal with mortality,
even the mortality of your children and
you find within you what would allow you
to withstand that damaged
you're not to with stand up.
And you do that by letting yourself
go where your thoughts take you,
even though you don't want to.
That's a trip into the abyss.
You know,
that's a trip into the underworld
and those are best taken voluntarily.
You're being dragged down there by
forces that are beyond your control.
And the mythological motif is that those
who are pulled into the underworld by
forces beyond their control do
not come out, not come out easily.
It can be the end.
You know?
So you go there courageously.
And so if you're a parent,
one of the places you have to go
courageously is to that place where your
children are ill or dying or deceased.
You have to do that.
You haven't grown up
until you have done that,
even though it's a terrible thing.
So
that's how you could deal with that.
It's a rough man, but I'll tell you,
it's a lot better than living in constant
worry that your children are going to
be hit by a car, kidnapped, murdered,
or beaten up. So you know, you're like,
you're in a situation that
characterizes the situation.
Many people in life,
you don't have a good choice.
You've got to rough choices.
You could go left and that's rough
and you can go right and that's rough.
And that's all you've got.
And I would say you have the freedom to
choose which of the two difficult paths
you're going to choose.
And the one that involves voluntary
confrontation with what tortures and
torments you.
It's a terrible Predator of death.
That's the pathway that's going to lead.
Okay
back to the stability that not only you
need but that your family requires you
to have.
So that's that.
And you guys,
you're asking tough questions tonight.
News of real atrocities committed
by humans, especially torture.
Leave me physically shell shocked
and paralyzed as if I had PTSD.
Is there something wrong with me?
Well,
you're, you're more sensitive
than the typical person.
Perhaps you're more imaginative,
you know, maybe you're more open.
You could take a personality test and
find out what your personality traits are
that probably be the best. That would
really be the best way of figuring it out.
My guess is that you're extremely
high and compassion, which is a,
an aspect of agreeableness and it's
the maternal aspect fundamentally.
And so you're, you're probably
very high and compassion. Um,
I have a personality test at a site called
understand myself. You could go there,
understand.com
you can go there and you could do the
personality test and that will help tell
you.
I would say that you're very high in
compassion and I would guess the are also
very high in trait neuroticism,
which is the trait that measures
sensitivity to negative emotion,
anxiety say and emotional pain and the
combination of high compassionate and
high negative emotion
sensitivity would produce,
would increase the probability of someone
suffering from the consequences that
you described. If that was also
allied by Hio with high openness,
which is the creative
creativity dimension,
it would mean that you're someone who
can get really lost in the stories of
other people. So high people are high
in openness like fiction for example.
And the reason for that is that they,
they,
they're imitative in some
sense cognitively they
can really take on another
character and they can take that on to
the exclusion of everything else so that
they're deeply engrossed in
the, in the story. You know,
someone who's high in openness,
you can kind of tell a person like
that because if they're reading a book,
Fiction Book and you call
their name even multiple times,
they may not respond because they're
so deeply embedded in the narrative and
have become the characters to such a
degree that they've shut off the outside
world and they're living in their
mediated imagination, you know?
And so that'd be my guess with regards
to your personality traits, um,
if it's really affecting you,
like your statement is quite
extreme as if I had PTSD,
um,
to develop PTSD,
generally exposure to
malevolence is necessary.
And so that element of your experience
is in keeping with that statement.
But PTSD is,
is relatively rare and generally requires
a very intensely traumatic personal
experience.
Now,
one of the predictors of the development
of PTSD after exposure to trauma is
something called depersonalization.
And some of you may have experienced this.
The personalization tends to occur when
something happens to you that's so far
outside the manner that
you conceptualize reality,
that you cannot believe
that it's happening.
And so the d realization is that all of
a sudden you're in a world that doesn't
seem real because something
that isn't possible by your,
as a consequence of your philosophy,
let's say your perceptual structure,
your value structure has just occurred
and posed a unspecified threat to the
integrity of your entire belief system,
which is really what,
what happens when you develop post
traumatic stress disorder is the value
hierarchy that regulates your neck.
Negative emotion gets destroyed at some
fundamental level by your encounter with
something that you didn't
believe could possibly
exist.
Um,
I doubt that your response is
sufficient to produce PTSD.
Um,
if that is the case,
then you're sensitive to anxiety at a
level that far exceeds the normal and it
might be worth going to
talk to someone about that.
It's possible that like,
I don't know because you haven't
provided me with any information.
I don't know what your mood is like.
Like, are you, are you, are you depressed?
Are you anxious all the time? Right? Um,
you wake up in the middle of the night
and worry about things, you know,
because maybe there's something that's
broader that characterizes dysfunctions
in your negative emotion systems
that, um, might be addressed.
Maybe you're going through a
particularly rough time in your life,
and so you're hypersensitive.
It's impossible to tell from the context.
But at least now you know a little
bit more about what might be,
what might be a resulting
in your responses.
Okay.
Cod Boone Ham.
Dr. Peterson,
I recently found out that my
father was a former Kamir Rouge.
Now the Khmer Rouge exiled and kill
millions of people in Cambodia.
So this is a rough discovery.
I feel hurt that he was part of the horror
in Cambodia. How do I deal with this?
Yeah.
Oh,
you know,
the first thing I'd recommend is that
you read a book and the book's called
ordinary men,
and it's a story about how
ordinary men in Germany,
policemen were
trained and encouraged to become cold
blooded murderers of naked pregnant women
in Poland during World War II. And
it's a, it's a horrifying book.
Um, and so you might think, well,
why in the world would you read
a horrifying book of that nature?
And I would say because it will help
you understand that people who did such
things were in niches,
phrase human all too
human and might help you
bridge the gap between
the father that you thought you
knew and the father that once was.
And to bridge the gap between you and
those two if you understand that the sorts
of things that your father may have been
involved or in or the organization at
least that he was involved with.
If you understand that people,
including yourself,
have the propensity to behave in that
manner and that it's not something unique
to your father, terrible though
it may be. If it's part of the,
what would you say?
The eternal proclivity
for malevolence and evil,
that's part and parcel of
the human spirit. You know,
as the Catholics have always insisted
with their doctrine of original sin,
then that may allow you
to understand the situation
of your father better.
So that's the first thing is that you
have to learn something about evil and you
have to learn something about
how it possesses people.
And you have to learn something about
how it possesses ordinary people.
And that will mean you'll have to learn
something about how it might possess you.
And that's rough learning.
So you've got rough learning to do.
And then the next thing I would say is,
look,
it was a long time ago.
Um,
and what's your father been like for you?
You don't like maybe he's changed.
You know,
people can repent and,
and rejoin the world
that the Christian idea,
which is remarkable.
One is that there's no sin that you can
commit that so terrible that you can't
be redeemed. Now people laugh at
that idea because they think, well,
that means that you can,
they think cynically that that means
that you can be the worst and most
impulsive center possible
throughout your entire life.
And then conveniently in the moments
before death, repent and you know,
enter the everlasting kingdom of God.
And unfortunately it's not that simple
because to repent and to be redeemed is
to truly understand what you did to allow
the parts of yourself that did that to
wither away and die or burn away,
which I think is a better metaphor
because there's plenty of pain involved to
chart a new course and just swear by
everything that's wholly that you're going
to stay on it.
And maybe your dad did that.
And so in which case your job is to
find out how even now knowing something
about the evil that can possess
people and even people that you love,
even yourself,
you'll have to find it
within you to forgive.
If you determined that this man with all
the hidden complexity that you've now
discovered is someone you love and so
good luck. Cause that's
a, that's a tough road.
You've got to walk there.
So I'd like I said,
I would say read ordinary men that'll
teach you something that you need to know.
The Greeks is by anonymous.
The Greeks had the maxim know thyself.
How did we come to know ourselves in
terms of our personalities and more
importantly potential?
Well,
you know,
one of the things I often told my
students and my clinical clients as well,
I guess I probably told my
family members this as well.
Some of the many ways that one of the
first ways to come to know yourself is to
understand that you don't,
and that y'all still know the
people you love very well.
But we'll get to that.
You know,
you can learn to kind of watch yourself
like you're watching a stranger,
but you have to adopt a position
is a position of radical humility.
I would say both.
Both humility in two senses.
So one sense would be the humility
of recognizing your ignorance.
So you have to understand that you don't
know who you are and that's not easy to
understand because you think you know,
but then you know,
you remember you can't control yourself
very well. You're not very disciplined,
you're full of flaws. Maybe you don't
know yourself as well as you think,
but it's hard to get low
enough to understand how
deeply it is the case that you
are ignorant about who you are.
Now there's an upside to that too,
which also is that you're also
ignorant about who you could be.
And so the discovery of that,
you know,
is some reward for the horror of
determining who you actually are.
Then I would say, well, well then
he watched yourself, you know, and,
and you attend to your
conscience and you see,
you watch yourself like
you're watching a stranger.
You watch what you say and you
listen and you think, well, what,
what sort of person would say that?
And how am I reacting emotionally
when I'm communicating in that manner?
You know, is that making me feel
stronger or weaker? Is it, is it,
is filling me with shame? Is it
helping my confidence? Um, am I,
am I laying out a lie?
Am I deceiving myself and other people?
Am I adopting this personality at
parties that is designed to impress,
into amuse? And that comes across as
nothing but like self centered narcissism.
Um, what are my dark fantasies?
What are my aggressive fantasies?
Um,
what is it that I'm willing to do?
What am I interested in so that
all spontaneously pursue it?
What do I procrastinate about and why?
What am I unwilling to do?
What do I think is good?
What do I congratulate myself
for accomplishing and what
do I be rate myself for?
Failing to confront and to implement?
Those are all incredibly
complicated questions and
you don't know the answers to
them. So that's, that's a start.
And then in terms of potential,
well,
he'll discover a little bit more about
your potential as you discover who you
are, especially the darker parts of
yourself because then you'd discover your
potential for mayhem. There's some
real utility in that, you know,
discovery that you're dangerous.
It's such a useful discovery.
It's actually something that
strengthens you. Because the first thing
that a realization like that
can in fact produce is the,
the ambition to incorporate that danger
into a higher order personality that
dangerousness into a higher
order personality. And that
can make you implacable.
I can make you someone who can say
no when you need to say no. You know,
that can make you someone who
won't avoid necessary conflict.
And so that's unbelievably useful.
And so that's one of the potentials
that you might discover. Um,
the other thing you do to
discover your potential is to,
while you challenge
yourself, you know, it's like
rule four in my book,
12 rules for life is comparing yourself
to who you were yesterday and not to who
someone else's today. And that's kind of
a good way to start this. It's like, well,
okay,
take a bit of a look at yourself and
think about what's not so good that you
could improve,
that you should improve by your own
standards and that you would improve.
You know, and say yourself
a little goal. Um, you know,
maybe you're not studying at all
at your university or maybe you're,
maybe you're at work and you've got
this stack of paper there, you know,
and you haven't looked at that damn stack
for like a month and you know that you
should be and your boy bothering yourself
at night because you're avoiding that.
It's like maybe they go,
I've avoided that stack of
paper completely for one month.
I'm quite a coward when it comes to
whatever snakes might be hidden in that
stack of paper.
How about tomorrow?
I just like put that stack of paper
in front of me on my desk and I like a
glance through it for 15 seconds.
See if I can do that. It's like, well,
you set yourself a goal of improvement.
You know, it's a humble goal because
okay,
really are you such a coward that the
best that you can bloody well managed
after a month of avoidance is 15
seconds of exposure to a stack of paper.
You know, it could easily be
you've avoiding it, you're
obviously afraid of it.
And so the situation could be that
dismal and dire and you might think,
well Geez,
it's no bombed my ego.
It's no, it's no, it's not fostering the,
the strength of my ego
to recognize myself.
Someone who could only
withstand 15 seconds of exposure
to that thing I'm afraid
of.
And so that's a form of humility too.
It's like there's things you could do to
improve and you know what they are and
there's small steps that you could take
that you might take that would put you
in that direction.
And then the question is,
are you big enough to take
those small steps? You know,
are you capable of grappling with the
fact that you're fundamentally flawed to
the point where you have to break things
down into almost child like steps in
order to manage them and answer to that
is yeah, you are. And that's the lot of,
I don't know if it's a lot of everyone,
most people have things they avoid,
you know, and they're afraid of.
So I would say to some degree,
it's the lot of everyone,
people vary in the degree to
which they've conquered that.
Then you do meet people from time to time
who were extraordinarily disciplined,
but most of the time they've got
disciplined in exactly this manner.
It's through slow incremental improvement
and then you challenge yourself.
It's like, well, could I do
this? That would be better.
Then you find out and then you think,
well,
is there something slightly larger and
more challenging that I could do that
would be better?
And,
and you try it and you find out and as
you try it and you find out generally you
get better at it and you can take
on larger and larger challenges.
That's why I suggested again at 12 rules
for life and also in maps of meaning is
that you know,
you take responsibility for yourself.
That was part of standing up
straight with your shoulders back.
It's like take on the world man,
but only in the,
in the, in the, what would you say?
Only at the level that you
can manage. You know, when,
when you're deeply,
when you were ignorant and biased
and deeply flawed and immature,
it's where everyone starts.
You don't want to take,
you don't want to bite off
more than you can chew,
but it doesn't mean that you can't
wrestle was if part of reality,
you know,
some part that's small enough so that
you have a good shot at victory and then
you attain victory over some
small part of the chaos.
And then you're the person
who is victorious over chaos.
You're just a beginner,
but that's who you are.
And then maybe you can get unbelievably
good at that and maybe you can ally to
that.
The ability to recast tyrannical
order into chaos and restructured into
something
deeper,
more profound and more
suitable for human habitation.
That's the other half of the hero myth,
right?
Half is to overcome chaos itself and half
is to confront tyranny where it needs
to be confronted to allow the
chaotic di Di di degeneration.
No
can allow the chaos to emerge
in place of the tyranny.
And then two can recast that
into the order that's proper.
And
you do that by challenging yourself
humbly at the level that you're able to
function. That's right. And
you can think of it, you know,
it's easier to understand if you think
about a child that you're trying to rear
properly and you want to make that
child help that child reveal their,
their highest potential, whatever
that is, whatever that means.
And what you do is you don't set them a
series of impossible tasks and the hope
of undermining their self confidence,
you form a relationship with them that
is predicated on your interest in their
highest mode of being.
And then you offer them challenges that
are precisely optimize to durability,
right? So they can do them,
but they have to stretch.
The two elements of their ability would
be what they can do and what and how
much they're capable of and
transforming what they can do.
And an optimal challenge is stretches you
to the end of what you can do and then
into the domain of what you have,
how you can transform.
And so if you love a child,
then you set them tasks of that nature
and maybe they have a reasonable chance
of success.
A 70% chance of success or an 80%
chance of success might depend on how
sensitive your child is.
You do the same thing for yourself,
but you have to be humble and wise enough
to understand that you might have to
aim pretty damn low,
especially in those places where
you're not functioning well.
And it might be so embarrassing
that you can't even,
that you can't bring yourself to fathom
that that's actually who you are.
But you know,
young describe the fool archetipal figure
the of the trickster and the fool as
the precursor to the savior,
to the redeemer.
And that's unbelievable bit of wisdom
because what you meant was that to put
yourself together,
which is to follow the path of redemption,
the fall of the redeemer,
if the Redeemer is a type of personality
that you could in fact be inhabited by
our manifest,
then this first step towards that
is to allow yourself to be a fool,
right? It's because you
don't know what you're doing.
You have to admit that,
and there's going to be a loss
of ego or destruction of ego,
arrogant ego that
necessarily accompanies that,
but you need the laws of that arrogant
ego because it's precisely interfering
with your movement forward.
You know,
it's part of the adversarial process
mythologically speak and it stops moral
progress.
You're too proud of who you think you are
to notice what you're like so that you
could change properly. You don't want
to sacrifice that part of yourself,
it's probably associated with some
delusion that helps you maintain,
uh, what would you say? A positive,
although very fragile self image, you
know, in the absence of genuine effort,
um,
it's not to be recommended.
So,
okay.
Do you know yourself by
watching and paying attention?
That's why the Egyptians worshiped Horace.
The eye as a god,
they knew that attention was important.
And the Ms Damien's did the
same thing with their God.
Marduk it's not thinking exactly,
it's not imagination,
it's just, it's watching. Like
you're like you're a snake.
A snake,
you know,
is a symbol of wisdom in part because
a steak is a symbol of many things.
But wisdom is one of them.
I suppose it's because encounters with
snakes that can I, if they're not fatal,
they make you wise.
Because snake watches like cold bloodedly
with no emotional reaction just to see
what's there, doesn't allow,
symbolically speaking,
doesn't allow what is wanting or desire
to interfere with what is observed.
So you watch yourself like that
as if you don't know who you are.
Well,
that's the beginning.
And then you challenge
yourself continually
to see how far past yesterday you
could push today and tomorrow,
and to continually experiment with
expanding the domains not only of your
competence, but of your ability
to increase that competence.
And it's not obvious to me the upper
limit to that is proportional to the moral
effort that you put into it.
The more that's guided by,
by the highest of all possible visions,
right?
The alliance with the highest of
all possible conceivable good.
And the more it's motivated by the more
it's accompanied by truth in speech and
action,
the more you will develop your potential.
And I believe that potential to be as
an unlimited in the upward direction,
more unlimited in the upward direction,
then it is unlimited in the
direction that brings people to,
to the political and social hell's that
so often characterize the world that we
inhabit. And so you also, I suppose,
have to be willing to undertake
that as an adventure because
okay,
it's a hell of a thing to bear. That
kind of responsibility. You know,
it, it takes, it takes a
person out of the ordinary.
It takes them out of themselves and
yeah,
and there's an innate,
there's an alienation and isolation that
goes along with that NSA and a great
sorrow,
all of that together.
But there's deep meaning
to be had in it and it's,
and there isn't anything
better that you can do. So
that's the answer to that question.
Okay.
Anonymous asks,
how do you reconcile the fact that Nisha
is often taken to be a precursor to
postmodern philosophers such as food
co do the postmodernists misuse Nicha.
Okay.
Well, Nietzsche is a precursor to
the postmodernists. Okay. I mean,
he's a precursor to
virtually every strand
of serious literary,
philosophical and psychological thought
since Nicha.
So for the entirety of the 20th and
the 21st centuries. And to say that he,
the only way nature could not influence
the postmodernist would be if he wasn't
a great philosopher,
which he was.
Or if they didn't know his writings,
which they do to some
greater or lesser extent.
The postmodernist read Nietzsche,
I would say as someone who was
essentially triumphal about the death of
Christianity and about the rise of,
okay,
the individual human, let's say
as the locus of values, but,
but first of all,
I don't think that's true.
I don't think Nietzsche was
triumphant about that at all. I,
I think that he was wise
enough to understand that
catastrophic price we would
pay for the breakdown of our
Meta narrative.
See that the postmodernists
disbelieve above all,
perhaps mean if you needed
one phrase to define them.
It is that they don't
believe in Metta narrative.
So stories that that bring
communities together.
Now you know there's a problem with
disbelief and Mehta narratives because I
don't know where you stopped.
Like how big does a narrative have to
be before it's a Meta narrative and
therefore no longer worthy of belief?
Do you end up not believing
in any narrative whatsoever,
all the way down to the bottom, which
means your entire value arc is destroyed,
which means technically that you would
be unable to act because you act within a
narrative framework that posits that
one thing is more important than another
and therefore worth
moving actively toward.
So you lose that whole structure
and while you can't lose it,
you're, you're done. It's, it's
not even technically possible.
You might be able to fragment it badly.
That happens in schizophrenia.
You might be able to subvert the positive
elements of it or have it subverted as
happens.
In the case of depression,
you might lose faith in it as
happens with the nihilists,
but there's no demolishing your
faith in narratives all the way down.
So they,
they misuse knee chip in that manner
because they take his criticism of,
okay,
his criticism of Christianity and his
statement about the death of God damn
indicate that all narrative has now
become invalidated
and they offer nothing as an alternative.
Now need you at least offer the idea
that you could create your own values.
It's not obvious to me that
the postmodernists have
incorporated that element
of Nietzschean thought.
I don't think they misused nature.
That's the funny thing.
It's not based on a
misunderstanding of nature.
His pronouncement of the death of God was
his conviction that the Meta narrative
had disintegrated and that
the consequences of that
would be disintegration all
the way down the structure and the
postmodernists believed that that
disintegration,
this is maybe
see it isn't obvious that
needs to thought that that was,
he thought it was inevitable.
I don't know if you thought it was right.
It's not always obvious reading Nietzsche,
if he believed that the reason that God
had died was as he put it because we had
killed him. You know there's a, there's a,
there's an idea of criminality
there that are carelessness.
You see the same thing echoed in the
old Mesopotamian myth Enuma Elish where
that younger gods get careless and kill
the father upon whom the rest that's
Appsu and because of that chaos comes
back in the form of Tiamat to destroy all
of them. That's the same story
Nisha told with the death of God,
and he does treat
the fact that God is dead as a murder
that was undertaken by careless human
beings and seems to hold us
morally responsible for that.
And I don't believe the
postmodernists or sensitive
or
I don't believe that there,
I can't,
I can't get the word right.
I don't believe they've
adopted that element of,
of niches Sorrell let's say the postmodern
description of the demolition of
the narrative is triumphalist.
It means that the old,
this is where it gets oddly mixed
up with Marxism in my estimation,
it means that the old power structure,
which was by definition,
tyrannical and oppressive,
no longer has any justification,
and those who were alienated and isolated
by that set of presuppositions can now
compete and take their rightful place.
And so they replace,
it's a funny thing,
they replaced the overarching narrative
with a landscape of warring smaller
narratives that are tribal.
And they disguise that to some degree by
associating them with ethnic and racial
and sexual characteristics. Right.
Which seem immutable in some sense.
And therefore not.
So,
obviously tribal is a very tricky game.
They don't seem too as they
should extend their skepticism,
even if they were avid
followers of nature,
to the narratives that make up the notion
that there's something coherent and
useful and super ordinate,
let's say about group identity
predicated on race, ethnicity,
and sexuality.
And so that's not precisely a misuse
of that is a misuse of nature.
I suppose it's,
it's the arbitrary determination
of where his prognosis of narrative
degeneration would stop.
The postmodernists say it stops at ethnic,
sexual and racial identity and
I don't see a justification for that. So
they're, they're misusing of that way.
Um, I think the people who
use Nicha properly, we're,
I think that was young predict
it only Freud to some degree.
But Freud solution,
although useful,
was not as deep as niche as your lungs,
you know,
young solution to get to the problem that
needs your post was that we had to go
into the abyss to rescue the
father who had collapsed and died.
And that meant to go to the darkest
possible places to find the brightest
possible light.
And I believe that was correct.
I think he can we go,
Paleo has said the same thing about Eric
Noi moments works, especially two books.
One called the origins and
history of consciousness,
which is a great book. And so on my
list of great books on my website,
which you could go take a look at it,
it's a hard book.
It's quite a bit like
my book maps of meaning,
like they're really the
same book in a funny way.
There's three books that are the same
that were published in the 20th century.
Um,
there's young symbols of transformation.
There's Eric Norman's,
um,
origins and history of consciousness.
There's my book maps of meaning.
I'm not stating that they're all
have the same quality by the way.
That would be a bit on the
presumption was side or,
and I guess you could also
include Joseph Campbell's book,
the hero with a thousand faces.
They're all trying to tell the same story.
And that story is precisely the
reclamation of the fractured and mortally
wounded father.
So that's gone in the final analysis,
although it can also be your own
father or the father within you,
or the four that you could
be from the, from the,
from the abyss into which he's fallen,
and then incent ancient mom archetypical
motif that that's required of each
individual.
It's an existential requirement for each
of us to rescue our fallen society from
the abyss into which it's
eternally plunging that
requires our attention and our
sovereignty and our citizenship and
their ability to adopt responsibility and
our willingness to work,
to envision and work
towards a better future.
One that's better for better
in the Piagetian sense,
better in an integrated sense, right?
Better for you, better for your family,
better for the community,
and to think that through carefully
and to understand that that's,
that the world is structured so that
you're either doing that or you're
wasting your potential in a manner that
allows terrible things to enter the
world.
And for me,
it was really the second realization
rather than the first that was
transformative.
It wasn't so much that I believed
that I could do good, that
motivated me to begin to be
a conscientious person and,
and dedicated to,
to something.
It was the realization that in
the absence of that I would be
a conduit through which things that
should not be allowed into the world would
pour, would inevitably
poor, even by mere inaction,
even by merely not being
who I could have bee.
And that after I had read literature
on totalitarian atrocity and on general
criminal psychopathology so deeply,
I couldn't allow that to be
something I would partake in.
It. It, it,
it was wrong enough in my estimation.
It appeared wrong enough in
my estimation so that I was
properly cowed into the sort of submission
that might possibly make you attempt
to be a decent person.
And whether or not I'm a decent person
seems to be subject to a substantial
amount of debate, some of which
I take part in myself. Um,
but I would say that
like there's been some
effort put in that direction.
How have I prepared for my debate was yet,
what are your goals for the
conversation? To be productive. Well,
I haven't prepared enough,
but I've got tomorrow,
you know,
and you can do a lot with one day I
want to review some more of ZX youtube
videos. I want to go through
a couple of his books. Um,
I've got some good lists
of what seems central,
but what I've done so far, I really have
25 minutes to make my case, you know,
the rest of it's discussion and Q and a.
And I'm not too worried about that because
it's easier for me to answer on the
fly than to deliver a prepared argument.
Um,
there's something more
involuntary about it, you know,
something more habitual anyways,
I don't know the reasons precisely,
but it's definitely easier.
We've got 25 minutes to make my case.
And,
uh,
the way I prepared for that was that
I reread the communist manifesto and
thought it through.
And I've identified what
I think the fundamental,
every philosophical tree ties or
every tree dies that purports to be
philosophical is predicated on a set of
assumptions or axioms that make up the
undeclared articles of
faith of the statement.
And so I've tried to identify what
those are. Some of them anyways,
I won't have time to cover all of them.
So I've identified let's say five,
it's going to be somewhere between five
and 10 and then I've thought through
whether or not they were
credible as axioms and I,
yeah,
I don't,
I don't believe that.
I don't think I discovered a single
axiom in the communist manifesto that was
credible.
Okay.
I,
I discovered what I discovered instead,
I think is that that tract was written
by two people who could think but who
couldn't think about what
they were thinking because
the propositions that they
put forward are so uncritically accepted
by the writers of the track that it's
actually a kind of miracle.
You know,
I'll just give you one example and I will
bring this up tomorrow in the debate,
Marx and Engels cause angles also help
write the communist manifesto appeared to
presume that and also to hope for and to
wish for and to work in a revolutionary
manner towards ensuring that
private property would be abolished
and that that means of production.
So the entire economy in some sense
would be held by the dictatorship,
dictatorship of the proletariat and that
would be a consequence of the working
class seizing control. But there's no
real development of that as an idea.
It's like, well, seizing control,
how and and who like and just because
is it really the case that just because
it's members of the working class that
have now seized control of the means of
production,
that they're going to be benevolent in
a way that the capitalists weren't mean.
That seems to be psychologically naive
beyond even the capacity of marks.
Um,
and I,
I have to watch the sarcasm because
I'm going to try to keep that and any
potential anger at a minimum tomorrow,
but to not think that through. It's like,
and then well really you're going to
centralize all the production and,
and,
and that's going to result
in better decision making
in a distributed market who
are going to be these geniuses that will
run the centralized decision making of
the dictatorship of the proletariat,
assuming that it isn't the most malevolent
of the proletariat that's risen up to
take control,
which is the most likely outcome if
you're not absolutely naive about human
nature.
And so the fact that,
and then they both presume that somehow,
and this is not specified either either
the dictatorship of the proletariat,
I suppose perhaps because it would free
the working class from the in slave
shackles of their labor and motivate the
more effectively that although they do
not elaborate on that,
you're left to guess that an
era of super abundance material,
super abundance would manifest itself
in which everyone would have what they
needed so that they could pursue their
creative endeavors in freedom and that
would constitute the communist utopia.
It's like,
okay,
there's so many unexamined assumptions
in that set of propositions that it's
almost impossible to
know even where to start.
It's like I don't understand how this
hyper abundance was supposed to manifest
itself.
Um,
it certainly didn't manifest itself
in any actual communist countries. Um,
it's especially peculiar because Mark's,
even in the communist manifesto admits
that one of the things that communism is
really good at doing is producing
a surplus of commodities,
but,
and these are material commodities and
because and and so that seems to me and
paradox of cold contradiction
with the whole communist,
what would you call it?
Ambition.
Because if it's hyper abundance that's
going to bring about the Marxist Utopia
and eventual classless snus and
capitalism is good at
producing hyper abundance,
why wouldn't you just let the capitalist
system run out until it produced
universal hyper abundance
and we'd have the utopia.
Now the Marxist answer to that would
because would be that it would be because
the selfish capitalists for structural
and and class based reasons would keep
all the excess production to themselves.
But God,
that's a lot of pessimism with regards
to those on the capitalist side and a lot
of optimism with regards to
those on the working class side.
No real understanding whatsoever of
their common humanity and common flaws.
And then the idea that the best
way to read history is as the
struggle between the
proletariat and the bourgeoisie.
That strikes me as almost
impossibly one sided and naive.
Um, I won't get into that tonight
because I'm going to discuss that quite
substantially tomorrow. But, um,
first of all there's lots of reasons
for conflict and class position might be
one of them, but it is by no means
the only one. And even it was,
there's no reason to assume that that's
a natural and unique consequence of
capitalism.
And so the other thing that's
staggering about Marx's
communist manifesto is it's absolute
the absolute absence of any form of
biological conceptualization.
You know,
and maybe that's not surprising
given when it was written. You know,
it was pre Darwinian biology has
really exploded in the 20th century.
But I read that track now and I think,
well you just didn't,
you just don't know
anything about human nature.
And I don't mean the human nature
that's on the surface, you know,
that we only share it with
other human beings. For example.
I mean nature itself and the nature of,
of social interactions in the structure
of social hierarchies and the nature of
implicit motivation. You knew none
of that. And like that's actually,
that's actually a big problem 160 years
later when we do know something about
human psychology and so,
well,
and then the other thing I hope to do,
see I've probably taken 15 minutes up
just to answer that and I've only got 25
minutes in total.
The other thing that I want to do is
just lay out some of the statistics that
have been gathered over the last 10 years
by people like Steven pinker and Hans
Rosling and Marion Tupe,
yet human progress and just point out
the magnitude of the absolute economic
miracle that's occurring all around the
world as millions of poverty stricken
people are lifted out of abject and
horrible privation at a rate that's an
that's incomprehensible
and that was unforeseen.
And so I don't know what a
Marxists does with that. Deny it,
I suppose.
Um,
certainly the working class in the U
S and perhaps elsewhere in the western
world has taken us a certain relative
hit as a consequence of opening up
competition to the rest of the world
and then being exposed to competition by
third world working class
people who could, you know,
work for lower wages.
But the net consequence of that,
as far as I can tell is that it's not a
mere opinion on my part that things are
so much better economically now
than they were like when I was born.
That
you can only describe it as miraculous.
I mean one example, just one
example is the child mortality rate.
Now Africa is now the same as it was in
Europe in 1952 like that's within the
span of a single life taught and that's
in the poorest place in the poorest area
of the world. It's absolutely
miraculous and so you know,
know 10 statistics of
that magnitude and well,
I'm going to review them and
make sure I get this correct.
10 to just make the case that while all
the dismal consequences of capitalism
have fundamentally failed
to manifest themselves,
especially in comparison to the sins of
other forms of communal organization.
And so then after that,
well he'll have a chance to make his case
and we're going to ask each other some
questions. And then the moderator and
the audience, Oh, participated questions.
And I hope I can have a good conversation
with Jesus yet because he's an
interesting thinker and it isn't even
clear to me why he identifies as a Marxist
because he's creative enough in his own
right in some sense to be his own man,
you know, to be his own
thinker. And so anyways,
that's how I've,
okay,
that's how I've prepared well that,
you know,
whatever preparation,
40 years of thinking and
argumentation might also constitute.
So, okay, so look,
it's nine 30 and I've got a big day
tomorrow because I have to prepare for a
debate with [inaudible] and I have to
do a good job because it's an important
topic and
it could have,
yeah.
Repercussions that are of sufficient
magnitude so that it should be taken with
the utmost seriousness.
I hope I can keep my sense of humor
and I can keep my anger under control.
I hope I can listen to him as if
he is someone who knows something.
I don't, I hope we can have a productive
discussion. I hope I'm prepared properly.
I let you all know that you can pick
up livestream tickets for that event.
That's at seven 30 tomorrow night,
eastern standard time.
If you go to my website, you can find
it under talks, you can find the link,
but I think I've already put it
in the description of this video.
So if you want to
participate in this live,
then you can electronically anyways.
Otherwise we will put the lecture,
the discussion or the debate up on
youtube within approximately four weeks.
And so
that's that.
I guess. Thank you all for tuning in. Um,
those were good questions.
We didn't get too many of them,
but they were deep and uh,
okay.
And well worth answering and, and well
worth contemplating. And hopefully,
so that mutual act of con participative
contemplation that we all just engaged
in,
we'll have salutary effects on each of us.
That would be the hope. So best
of luck to all of you and, uh,
good luck moving upwards.
We'll see you in June.