I'm in the UK at Penguin,
which I'm thrilled about because I think
penguin is the greatest book publisher
in the world and and England is the
center of the English language and
that's really something because England
has brought a tradition of truth and
clarity to the world that has
illuminated it in many ways and I'm
hoping that this book extends that great
English tradition one step farther,
like a good colonial should.
So that's.
And I hope you read it and I hope that
it helps you sort out your life.
I think people have found the things
that I've said helpful in that regard
and I've tried to distill them and
extend them in this book and deepen
them.
So hopefully that's what you will find
when you read it.