Hi everyone.
Happy New Year.
I've got some things to say to junior
high and high school students and their
parents about the politicization that is
occurring in the public school system
and what should be done about that.
I have some very radical suggestions,
I would say,
which I am not putting forth lightly.
I think that it is time for public
school students and their parents to
actively rebel against the
indoctrination that is being offered in
the guise of education.
But before such a recommendation can be
reasonably offered or considered by its
recipients.
Some careful argumentation and review of
recent events is in order,
so please bear with me while I walk
through that process.
It's important to get these things right
and not to rush.
About a year ago,
actually on September 27th,
2016 I made a series of videos.
One of them criticized a new piece of
federal legislation.
Bill see 16 bill [inaudible] is,
and I'm reading this directly from the
government website and act to amend the
Canadian Human Rights Act and the
criminal code.
Here's the summary.
This enactment amends the Canadian Human
Rights Act.
To add gender identity and gender
expression to the list of prohibited
grounds of discrimination.
The enactment also amends the criminal
code to extend the protection against
hate propaganda set out in that act to
any section of the public that is
distinguished by gender identity or
expression and to clearly set out that
evidence that an offense was motivated
by bias,
prejudice or hate based on gender
identity or expression constitutes an
aggravating circumstance that a court
must take into consideration when it
imposes a sentence.
Now you may notice on careful reading
that the act modifies the criminal code
to clearly set out that evidence that an
old fence was motivated by bias.
Prejudice or hate extends the purview of
what might constitute hate to a degree.
That's I think completely unacceptable,
but that's the least of the problems
with this bill.
You can't really tell what the other
problems are though,
unless you go read the policy guidelines
that were established by the Ontario
Human Rights Commission,
which already guide interpretation of
similar legislation in Ontario and would
be used by the federal government's own
admission to guide the interpretation of
Bill [inaudible].
Now.
When I made the videos,
I said as much,
I said that there were two fundamental
dangers to this bill.
One was that because of the Ontario
Human Rights Commission is a radical and
dangerous organization bent on producing
the most punitive possible policies in
the pursuit of its radical neo Marxist
postmodern agenda,
that the legislation would introduce the
possibility of persecution or let's say
prosecution for so-called offenses that
should never be considered within the
proper domain of legal prosecution.
Now,
I also objected to the manner in which
the relationship between biological sex,
gender identity,
gender expression,
and sexual orientation was written into
the Ontario Human Rights Commission's
policies and therefore essentially into
the law pointing out that the law now
demands that we consider those four
different phenomena as essentially
independent when they are in fact very
tightly causally linked and as well that
the claim that's being made both
implicit and explicit,
that those four sets of phenomena differ
within each strata as a consequence of
socialization,
in fact is also wrong,
but also undermines the primary
arguments that transsexual people and
gay people used to buttress the reality
of the our identity.
Namely that they have a biological
proclivity that directs them towards
such identities,
expressions,
and orientations.
I pointed all of those things out and
that we were in danger of legislating
compelled speech in relationship to
preferred pronouns,
which are the pronouns that people who
vary in their gender identity
hypothetically want to use to be
referred to.
I pointed out that we were in danger of
making compelled speech,
something required in Canada so that for
the first time in our history and in the
history of the British common law,
the government would be able to
legislate the content of your speech,
which is quite different than
legislating what you can't say,
which is already something that's very
dangerous.
There were a variety of consequences of
making this video,
which were much more dramatic than I
presume they might be.
Although I did know that bill
[inaudible] posed to genuine threat to
the integrity of our state.
Now,
the first consequence was that a very
large number of faculty members at the
University of Toronto decided that I had
made the campus an unsafe place by my
statements and petitioned the university
to do something about that.
And then there were a number of
demonstrations and then the University
of Toronto sent me two letters telling
me that I was violating their policies
and probably the law in Ontario,
which was something I had warned about
by the way,
because the law was written in such a
dismal manner and over inclusive manner
to ensure that even criticizing it could
be prosecuted under its guidelines let's
say,
and then there was a debate that the
university held were defenders of bill
see 16 insisted that I was all the
terrible things that I had been called
and that I was misinterpreting the bill
and that the dangers that I forced saw
as a consequence of its implementation
would never manifest themselves,
sorry,
rather than to address himself to the
scientific evidence concerning gender
identity and expression and by adopting
rhetorical strategies more common to
Breitbart news.com then a university
professors lecture,
Dr. Peterson goes on to discredit the
very construct on political grounds
instead of on grounds provided by
scholarly evidence that these constructs
are in no particular order leftist
radical and politically correct on the
subject of pronouns and gender
expression.
Dr. Peterson is emphatic.
That quote,
I don't recognize another person's right
to determine what pronouns I use to
address them.
I won't do it for the vast majority of
people.
He goes on to say gender identity and
sexual orientation and I guess he means
sex are the same thing.
And quote as for the definition of
transgender,
Dr. Peterson claims that,
and I quote,
I don't believe that they,
these people,
these terms stand for good things.
I think that these people use these
terms as a pretense that they stand for
good things as a pretext for them to
continue their nefarious activities and
quote,
well this is hardly the stuff of
academic scholarship
now and I should say to the university's
credit by the way,
that once they got on their feet after
sending me the original two letters,
they seem to have come down quite
strongly on the side of free speech in
the last year.
And so that's something positive that's
come out of all this.
But the truth of the matter was that I
am none of those things and that I had
read the bill and it's surrounding
policies extremely carefully and what's
worse actually understood them and that
what I had done was merely communicate
my understanding and I would say my
proper and accurate understanding of the
bill to a public that was actually quite
willing to take the time to investigate
the issue and follow it carefully.
The press initially was very ambivalent
towards me,
but as some of the leading journalists
in Canada,
including Christie Blatchford and aunt
anella are too so and eventually conrad
black and also Margaret Winter early
listened to the videos that I had made
it and then actually read the policies
in question.
They understood that the bill did it in
fact pose a threat to free speech in the
manner that I had described and came out
very strongly on my side.
Now I have some sympathy for the fact
that I was tarred with a variety of
epithets immediately after having made
the video because I was warning that
there was something not good going on in
Canada and whenever anybody warrants
that you should be skeptical of them
because Canada has been a very stable
and well functioning state for a very
long period of time.
So when someone pops out of his rabbit
hole or it comes out of the swamp,
let's say,
and says there's something rotten in the
state of Denmark,
the proper response is,
no,
there's probably something wrong with
you.
And the next investigative strategy is
to say,
well,
here's a bunch of things that are
typically wrong with people that have
something wrong with them,
bigoted,
transphobic,
racist,
et Cetera.
Maybe you're one of those things.
And so we'll throw those at you and see
if they stick.
Because if they stick,
then we don't have to pay any attention
to the problem and maybe it will go
away.
But the truth of the matter is that I
was and am none of those things.
I was fortunate because there was
evidence that that was the case.
I have videotaped virtually everything
I've said to students in the entire 25
years of my university tenure.
And so everything that I thought was a
matter of public record and I had posted
it on youtube in the form of hundreds of
lectures.
Not only is there nothing scurrilous and
self damning in those videos is quite
the contrary.
People have found the content extremely
useful from a psychological perspective
and,
and that's now up into the millions of
people.
And so it turns out that I'm not the bad
guy of the supporters of this bill's
imagination.
Now the other tactic employed by the
people who have been unhappy about what
I have been saying is to assume that I'm
an alt right or even a far right figure,
which is an accusation that has been
leveled at me many times in the last
year.
And there's also a reason for that.
The reason for that is that the group of
people to the right of the radical left
is a very large group and it includes
everyone from socialists say of the
classic 1970s type all the way to the
most far right Nazis imaginable who are
all united in their opposition to the
radical left agenda and thus form what
you might describe as a group by
default.
Now the fact that some of the members of
a group by default are unsavory
characters,
does not demonstrate that all of the
members of that group are of that type.
Now it's very convenient for the radical
left and much more straight forward than
actually formulating arguments to assume
that everyone who doesn't think exactly
what they think is some sort of
monstrous figure,
but it happens to not be the case.
There are many reasonable people,
in fact a vast majority of reasonable
people who are firmly opposed to the
agenda of the radical left and it's
completely unreasonable to lump them in
with outright far right and not see type
figures.
Part of the reason that the postmodern
neo Marxist find themselves compelled to
do so is because they believe that they
are correct and that they have right on
their side.
And if it turns out that anyone
reasonable is objecting,
then the fact of that reasonable
opposition would make it necessary for
some things to be rethought.
And so it's much easier.
And I would also say much more
gratifying to an inner sense of
resentment and vengefulness to merely
tar everyone who doesn't agree with the
same brush.
And the argument be damned.
This brings us to the most fundamental
reason why there has been such
vociferous opposition generated in
relationship to what I've been saying.
And that's because I got the
interpretation of bill see 16 and its
surrounding policies and the pernicious
postmodern Neil Marxist doctrine that
gave rise to it essentially correct.
And it's in the best interest of those
who are pushing this pernicious doctrine
and its legislative consequences to do
everything possible to discredit me so
that the facts of the matter remain
hidden from the general public and
perhaps even from those who have
formulated the doctrine themselves.
So I read bill [inaudible] and the
surrounding policies that would guide
it's interpretation as formulated by the
Ontario Human Rights Commission.
And then I informed the public to the
best of my ability about the content of
that legislation and policies and its
intent.
And we've outlined the consequences.
Two major questions remain is what I had
to say to be trusted.
And if I was correct in my analysis and
diagnosis,
what steps should be taken now,
if any,
to rectify the situation.
So let's begin with the question of
whether or not my interpretation is to
be trusted.
And we'll start that with a brief
overview.
And then an analysis of the recent
events at Wilfrid laurier university.
As you may know or may not know,
but should know at Wilfrid laurier
university.
Recently,
a teaching assistant named Lindsay
Shepherd found herself in hot water
because she had the temerity to play a
video clip from TV shows the agenda in
the class that she was charged with
conducting as a consequence of playing
the video clip,
she was brought in front of a
disciplinary panel consisting of three
individuals,
Nathan Ramboo,
Canna Herbert Pimlott and Adriana Joel
ramboo counter and Pimlott our
professors in the communications
department at Wilfrid Laurier University
and Andrea Joel is an administrator who
was hired as a consequence of
legislation introduced by Kathleen Wynne
to conduct exactly the sort of
disciplinary investigation that she sat
in on.
Now Lindsay Shepherd had the presence of
mind and the fear to tape the
disciplinary hearing and after the story
about what had happened was released,
Lindsey released the entire audio tape
and caused a national and international
scandal and would be interested to see
the original complaint or complaints
because I don't really have any context.
What exactly that problem ones.
Sorry,
can I,
sorry.
Can I just ask anything to maybe just
provide us with full frame?
Sorry,
one.
Yeah,
I just like to hear the whole like your
what,
what took place.
So if you could just give us the whole
story and then,
and then,
sorry,
I just feel that because I'm just
sitting in the night.
Yeah.
Okay.
So,
um,
we,
we have to teach about grammar.
And in the Pearson book there was a
section about pronouns and using like
gendered language.
So I wanted to make it more engaging.
So what I did is we were talking about,
um,
in paper is using,
say as,
as like a singular,
and then we're also talking about like
his and hers and like how to construct
sentences with that.
And then to contextualize it,
I brought up like a youtube debate,
so debate with both sides during
Peterson sides.
And this,
this fellow named Nicolas Matt,
who was also a prophet.
Uft.
Okay.
And they,
you don't have the name of the video.
Um,
it was from the agenda with Steve Pagan,
what's in a name,
potentially a great deal.
University of Toronto,
psychology professor Jordan Peterson has
a fight on his hands after objecting to
proposed legislation that he says would
violate his freedom of speech by forcing
him to address transgendered people
using the pronouns of their choosing.
Joining us now to better understand the
issue and debate what's at stake in
Vancouver,
British Columbia,
Sarah and Meyer transgender pundit and
Utuber in the nation's capitol.
Kyle Kirkup,
professor of law at the University of
Ottawa and here in studio,
the aforementioned Jordan Peterson
professors,
psychology,
University of Toronto,
Nicolas,
Matt,
lecturer,
transgender studies,
a u of t and Mary Rogan,
who's article entitled growing up trends
is featured in the October issue of the
Walrus magazine.
Good to have you three here and our two
friends and points beyond.
We appreciate everybody being on the
program for what is I think one of the
hottest topics in the country today.
Professor Peterson,
and it's all because of you.
And I think before we go any further
with our conversation here,
I want to give people a sense of how hot
this has got.
A starting on the downtown campus or the
University of Toronto.
Well as you can see that you're honored.
Some free speech are capable of making
the lords the brine articulately noise
free speech mechanism by which we keep
our society functioning.
By doing this,
I'm going to post this online that you
would like people to not to be,
to be more accommodating of trans people
and people of color at your events.
In future.
I would a person of color.
I'm a person of color and I felt very
accommodating here.
There had been multiple,
multiple recorded instances.
I'm trans people killing themselves,
right?
Because,
because they are,
because they are not being integrated
into society.
If it wasn't for this long,
I asked you to refer to me.
What'd you do?
Why do you have the authority to
determine whether or not an individual
is worthy of you using their pronouns?
Like if I asked you,
would you please use they them pronouns
for me?
What?
What do you want us to jump through?
Those are my pronouns.
Okay.
With um,
indulgence of everybody else on the
program.
I'm going to start with Professor
Peterson off the top here for a while
because as I suggested you thought long
and hard about this,
you posted a few things up to youtube,
uh,
because you had been thinking long and
hard about it.
One and a half million hits later,
Jordan,
one and a half million,
it's later.
This has become a huge issue.
So let's start there.
Why did you post those views to youtube
in the first place?
Well,
there's proximate and distal reasons.
The proximate reasons was because I
received some correspondence from,
from,
uh,
from clients of mine who had been,
um,
I would say persecuted in a variety of
ways by people who were politically
correct.
And they sent me some documentation
about bill [inaudible] 16 and the
associated policy statements on the
Ontario Human Rights Commission,
which I read and was not very happy
about.
Um,
and also because the University of
Toronto decided to make anti racism and
anti bias training,
so called anti racism and anti bias
training mandatory,
which are regarded as an inappropriate
incursion into the domain of political
opinion by the university
administration.
Have you taken that training yet?
No,
and I don't have to.
Yeah,
it's,
it's the HR department personnel that
have to take it if they decide that you
have to,
will you?
No Way.
Not a chance.
And what's the other,
you referred to persecution that friends
are clients of yours had experienced,
so yeah.
Yeah.
Well,
um,
there are lots of places now where the
workplace has become,
I would say excessively politicized.
And so people who have viewpoints,
and this also involves,
includes,
I would say fairly radical leftist view
points.
People don't feel comfortable at all in,
in,
in being able to use the language of
their choice or to have even no opinions
about a variety of different things
essentially.
I guess what I'm asking you is to lay
the case out.
What is it you find offensive about this
legislation?
Well,
fundamentally the,
there were two things that really
bothered me,
although there have been other things
I've thought about since.
One was that I was being asked as
everyone is to use a certain set of
words that I think are the constructions
of people who have a political ideology
that I don't believe in,
that I also regard is as dangerous.
What are those words?
Those are the made up words to read
that,
that people now describe as um,
as gender neutral.
And so to me,
they're there.
They're there an attempt to control
language and,
and in a direction that isn't happening
organically.
It's not happening naturally.
People aren't picking up these words in
the typical way that new words are
picked up,
but by force and by FIA 10,
I would say by force,
because there's legislative power behind
them.
Like these made up words,
xe and Zer and that sort of thing.
What about,
they're not all made up where it,
quote unquote made up words for example,
they is one of them.
Yeah.
But we speak to an individual as they,
right.
But we can't dispense with the
distinction between singular and plural.
I mean,
I know that the advocates of that
particular approach say that they has
been used forever as a singular and
that's actually not correct.
It's used as a singular in very
exceptional circumstances.
So we understand your views and where
you're coming from.
Uh,
you decided to lay these views out in
some youtube discourses.
Yes.
You put them up,
the response has been overwhelming.
Did you anticipate that you would get
this kind of feedback?
No,
there was no way of anticipating this
and I think you mentioned in the Intro,
you know,
that this is a consequence of what I've
done and I don't think that's true.
It's a,
it's a consequence of the fact I thought
about it then.
I think the right metaphor is that,
you know,
there's a large forest and it's been a
hot,
dry summer or maybe a drought and
there's plenty of deadwood gathered and
I lit a spark and you can't blame the
forest fire on the spark.
There is out there an appetite against
political correctness,
which is what you have described.
This says in fact your youtube videos
called professor against political
correctness.
But let's make sure we're all speaking
the same language here.
You would define that,
how political correctness,
well,
I think it's a particular kind of
ideological game and I think the outcome
is two fold.
It's to make the player feel morally
superior and also to take rather serious
acts swings at the foundation of
society.
And so the game is identify a domain of
human endeavor.
Note that there's a distribution of
success.
Some people are doing comparatively
better and some people are doing
comparatively worse.
Define those doing worse as victims.
Define those doing better as
perpetrators.
Identify with the victims,
have yourself a set of enemies handy to
vent your resentment on.
Feel good about it even though it didn't
really require any work on your part.
And then endlessly repeat.
And let's do one more question here and
then we'll get everybody else into the
conversation.
You know,
of course that since this story broke,
you've been called a lot of things.
Yeah.
Um,
one of which is a trans phobe.
Yeah.
Some people have accused you of um,
using the free speech issue to mask
what's really going on here,
which is an attempt to deprive other
people of what they believe are their
legitimate rights.
Well I know when to give you the
opportunity to speak to whether or not
you are a trans phobe well I can tell
you that I've received more letters from
transsexual people supporting me then
opposing me and I never said anything
really about transsexual people about
their existence.
Although that was the first thing that I
was accused of doing.
I didn't say that transsexual people
didn't exist.
I said that gender identity,
gender expression and biological sex do
not vary independently,
which they don't.
And so this issue is in some sense only
peripherally about about transsexual
issues.
It's more centrally about gender issues.
And then on top of it's the biggest
issue is is that it's a free speech
issue.
Okay.
Let us continue to explore all of those
issues that you have just raised.
And um,
what do we do this,
let's take a moment.
We're going to explain a few basic
things here.
The issue of so called non traditional
pronouns goes together with non
traditional gender identities.
New York City for example,
recognizes 31 such gender expressions.
In other words besides man and woman,
there are 29 other gender expressions.
For example,
Penn Gender Queer,
gender,
gender fluid,
crossdresser by gendered gender blender
and the list goes on.
And Nicholas,
this is where I want to bring you in the
discussion because you teach this,
you teach trans studies.
So if you would give us a brief primer
on so many gender identities that in
your view require non traditional
pronouns.
Basically
not correct that there is such a thing
as biological sex and I'm a historian of
medicine,
I can unpack that for you at great
length if you want,
but in the interest of time I won't.
So that's a very popular misconceptions.
It was like a youtube debate.
It was one hour long but I showed about
five minutes and then some,
I mean the students were,
were very interested.
I could tell they're all of their eyes
were on the screen.
And after when we had a debate,
there were people of all opinions.
And like from,
from what I could see,
it was a very friendly debate.
Um,
obviously this person who had an issue
did not express it to me.
They just went straight to whoever.
I don't,
I don't really know what happened.
So,
um,
just for some additional context.
So you come,
you came from uft,
is that right?
No,
no.
You,
oh,
you mess up.
You,
okay.
So you weren't,
um,
like one of Jordan Peterson,
the students know.
Um,
so just to give you some context though,
Jordan Peterson is,
he is a,
a figure that's uh,
basically highly involved with the,
with the alt right.
He lectures about,
um,
basically like critiquing of feminism,
critiquing,
um,
trans rights.
I mean,
I'm familiar.
Like I,
I don't see,
I follow up on,
on critique.
You okay.
So yeah,
nothing is,
can you share people from those ideas?
Am I supposed to comfort them and make
sure that they are insulated away from
this?
Like is that what the point of visits?
Because to me that is so against what a
university is about.
So against it I was not taking sides.
I was presenting both arguments.
Okay.
So the thing of it is about this is if
you're presenting something like this,
it,
uh,
you have to think about the kind of
teaching climate that you're creating.
And this is actually,
these arguments are counter to the
Canadian human rights code.
Uh,
ever since I know that you talked about,
um,
see 16 ever since this past,
it is discriminatory to be targeting
someone,
um,
due their gender identity or gender
expression.
So bringing something like that up in
class,
not critically.
And I understand that you're trying to
like,
it was critical.
I introduced it critically.
How so?
Like I said,
like I said,
I,
it was in the spirit of debate.
Okay.
In the spirit of the debate is slightly
different than being like,
okay,
this is,
this is like a problematic idea that we
want to meet when we want to unpack.
But that's taking sides.
Yes.
Like it's taking sides for me to be
like,
oh look at this guy.
Like everything that comes out,
his mouth is bs,
but we're going to watch anyway.
Okay.
So I understand the position that you
coming from and your positionality,
but the reality is that it has created a
toxic climate for some of the students.
You know,
it,
it's great.
Like how many one,
yes.
May I speak?
I have no,
I had no concept of,
of like how many people complained,
like what their complaint was.
You haven't showed me the complaint.
Yes,
I understand that this is upsetting,
but there's also a confidential,
at the end,
confidentiality matters.
The number of people is confidential.
Yes.
It is one or multiple students who have
come forward saying that this is
something that they were concerned about
it and that it made them uncomfortable.
If this is,
for example,
a trans student,
this is basically debating whether or
not a trans student should have rights
within one of their classes.
Um,
and that's not something that is really
acceptable in the context of the kind of
learning environment that we're trying
to create.
It would be the equivalent of debating
whether or not,
uh,
you know,
a student of color should have rights
or,
or should be allowed to be married.
Do you see where you'd like how this is
not,
this is not something that's
intellectually neutral that is kind of
up for debate.
This,
I mean,
this is the charter of rights and
debate,
but I mean,
you're perfectly welcome to your own
opinions,
but when you're bringing it into the
context of the classroom,
that can become problematic.
I'm not going to become something that
is the,
creates an unsafe learning environment
for students,
but when they leave the university,
they're going to be exposed to these
ideas.
So I don't see how I'm doing a
disservice to the class by exposing them
to ideas that are really out there.
And I'm sorry,
I'm crying.
I'm stressed out because this to me is
so wrong.
Can I mention the gender violence,
um,
generating actual violence?
Yeah,
so I agree that,
um,
it does gender balance,
I think just include sexual violence,
but it also includes,
um,
targeting folks based on gender.
Um,
so that includes transphobia,
Bi phobia,
homophobia.
All those sorts of things I protected
under the policy.
And so those are things that Laurie has,
um,
upheld as values,
as well as the Ontario Human Rights
Code.
Um,
and so those are things that we're
responsible for,
uh,
not,
um,
impacting our students in that way and
not,
um,
not spreading transphobia.
Okay.
So what I have a problem with is I
didn't target anybody who did.
I Target Trans folks how by telling my
ideas that are really out there by
telling them that.
But
really it's,
it's not just telling them in
legitimizing this as a valid perspective
as this is another valid perspective and
university,
all perspectives are valid.
That's not necessarily true.
Well,
this,
this is something that's being debated
in current society and I don't feel the
need to shield people from what's going
on in society.
Like to imagine that this is happening
in university.
It's just a bad.
Okay.
So just to give you a context also
within all of this is happening.
Um,
Laurie a's being blanketed with white
supremacist,
um,
posters currently.
Um,
there's another debate in society,
which is whether or not North America
should be a set of white nationalist
states and that it should be ethnically
cleanse of other people.
That is also a current debate society.
Would you show something in your
tutorial that,
you know,
had,
white supremacists and non white
supremacists debating whether or not
other people should live in North
America.
Is that something that you would show,
um,
if that was related to the content of
the week and we were talking about right
wing speech bubbles?
Maybe
it depends on the content.
Like,
I mean,
if there's really ideas that are
existing out there like that,
then I mean,
look,
the thing is like,
I don't see what's transphobic about
showing a video of Jordan Peterson.
He's a real person.
He is that he's out there,
he's a real person,
but he's a real person who has engaged
in targeted behavior that,
uh,
or,
or targeting of,
of Trans Students,
um,
in particular,
like,
like basically doxing them,
uh,
if you know the term,
like giving out their personal
information so that they will be
attacked,
uh,
harassed.
So that death threats will find them.
Um,
this is something that he has done to
his own students,
he has done to other students.
Um,
and this is also something that the
students are aware of.
So this is,
this is basically like playing,
not to kind of do the thing where
everything is kind of compared to
Hitler,
but this is like neutrally playing uh,
a speech by,
by Hitler or Milo Yiannopoulos from
Gamer gate.
This is the kind of thing that
departmentally in terms of like critical
communication studies and in terms of
the course of what we're trying to do is
diametrically opposed to everything that
we've been talking about in the lectures
faculty and administration at Wilfrid
laurier university reacted in a number
of different matters to the release of
this tape information.
I'm going to first read you some
excerpts from the independent fact
finding report commissioned by Wilfrid
Laurier University President Deborah
mcclachi.
She said,
I believe it is time for some clarity
around the events of the past few weeks
here at Wilfrid laurier university
stemming from the very regrettable
meeting that followed the showing of a
TV show clip by a teaching assistant
during a tutorial.
There were numerous errors in judgment
made in the handling of the meeting with
Ms. Lindsay Shepherd the ta of the
tutorial and question.
In fact,
the meeting never should have happened
at all.
No formal complaint nor informal concern
relative to a lorry.
A policy was registered about the
screening of the video.
This was confirmed in the fact finding
report.
There was no wrongdoing on the part of
Ms. Shepherd in showing the clip from TV
in her tutorial showing a TV oh clip for
the purposes of an academic discussion
is a reasonable classroom teaching tool.
Any instructional material needs to be
grounded in the appropriate academic
underpinnings.
To put it in context for the relevance
of the learning outcomes of the course,
the ensuing discussion also needs to be
handled properly.
We have no reason to believe this
discussion was not handled well in the
tutorial in question.
So after Debra mcclachi commissioned an
independent fact finder,
Lindsay Shepherd was completely
exonerated.
I'll put a link to where you can read
the university presidents entire
response to the disciplinary meeting in
question.
Now,
this is how Debra mcclachi sums the
situation up.
For those who have chosen to use this
incident as an indictment of Wilfrid
laurier university or the plight of
Canadian universities in general,
I say your assertion is unreasonable and
unfounded.
While that really is the question,
isn't it,
was this a unique occurrence,
a consequence of the misbehavior,
shall we say,
of two ill informed professors and an
administrator,
or was this actually diagnostic of the
genuine state of Canadian universities,
perhaps universities in the Western
world?
We have to review the evidence at hand
first.
We have what happened at Wilfrid laurier
itself.
I would like to point out that the
events there were more serious and less
predictable.
Even then what I had warned about when I
made my original video,
I assumed that people would be,
could be prosecuted,
failure to use
preferred pronouns,
and I was objecting to that as a example
of compelled speech,
but I never imagined that a teaching
assistant would be accused of breaking
provincial and federal laws.
Bill see 16 specifically for daring to
show a video about people discussing
such issues on a public television
station and then also accused of being a
transform,
which is let it be noted now a crime
under the criminal code provisions of
Bill See 16 furthermore,
in the aftermath of her release of this
discussion,
shepherd was accused of all of the right
wing attributes that had been leveled at
me,
all of which are also arguably
prosecutable under the ages of bill see
16 now we don't want to underemphasize
the importance of this.
Remember that these were two faculty
members and as well and administrator
Andrea Joel,
who is hired precisely for this purpose.
So that's the first piece of evidence.
Next we might consider the response from
others at Wilfrid laurier university
itself as well as professors and pundits
outside that university in other
departments and institutions.
I'm going to start with a letter that
was written by 20 members of the
Department of communication studies at
Wilfrid Laurier,
which is the same department that houses
Ramboo,
Kana and Pimlott.
Here's what they had to say about the
matter.
I'm going to paraphrase.
A meeting with shepard was secretly
recorded and sent to the media by that
ta,
this act,
spark columns and op eds that rushed to
assess the meeting.
Generalizing from this single event,
a diagnosis of our program,
the university and the state of higher
education in Canada.
We welcome the widening range of
perspectives on this situation that are
beginning to emerge in the public
sphere.
We recognize that the meeting was
mishandled.
We specifically acknowledge the power
imbalance in the meeting.
As doctor Ramboo.
Kenna acknowledged in his open letter to
his ta in future meetings were serious
matters pertaining to the conduct of Tas
are under discussion.
We acknowledged that students should be
encouraged to bring someone representing
them and their interests.
We would support a graduate student
initiative to unionize ta's which could
provide student employees with a
grievance process and other forms of
support in cases such as this one as we
understand it,
doctor ramboo counted,
did not operate unilaterally when he
called a meeting with his ta.
Rather,
we believe he acted in response to a
disclosure made by one or more students
to university offices set up to provide
confidential support.
Upon being notified of this disclosure,
Dr Ramboo,
Kenna as course instructor,
understood that he had a responsibility
to act in line with university policies
including those laid out in the gendered
and sexual violence policy.
Now I'm going to interject here for a
minute.
That's a very interesting because
president mcclachi has basically
complained that Rambo counter and
Pimlott and Joel herself acted outside
the policies that the university has
established.
However,
the faculty members writing and
supportive their callings claim that the
reason that Rambo County and Pimlott and
Joel as well acted in the manner they
did was because they were following
those policies.
So which is it?
Now,
here's my 2 cents for what it's worth.
My suspicions are that the policies are
written so badly like bill see 16 itself
and the surrounding policies at the
Ontario Human Rights Commission that
either of those interpretations are
possible.
It's convenient for the university to
disavow responsibility for the actions
of its faculty member and it's
administrators and it's convenient for
the faculty members and administrators
to say that they were just following
policy and it's not clear at all that
the independent fact finding council has
settled that to anyone's satisfaction.
Either way,
it's serious business back to the
letter,
while the free speech of a single
individual has dominated discussion
surrounding this situation,
academic freedom is also a decisive term
in this context.
Dr Rambo,
Kenna exercises academic freedom as a
core supervisor by setting parameters
for the multiple tutorials that
supplement his lecture.
It is within the scope of a supervising
professors academic freedom to have
workplace meetings with Tas regarding
how course material is taught.
All right,
so I have to interject again.
It isn't obvious to me that this meeting
with shepard constituted a normative
workplace meeting with a ta regarding
how course material is taught and the
fundamental reason for that is the
appearance at the meeting of the
administrator,
Andrea Joel,
as well as the numerous accusations that
were leveled at Shepherd.
So I think that that sentence is
disingenuous.
At best.
We maintain that the use of materials
that invite controversy into the
classroom need to be approached with
pedagogical care and forethought.
Public debates about freedom of
expression,
while valuable can have a silencing
effect on the free speech of other
members of the public.
We uphold the rights of Trans nonbinary
and queer folk to be addressed in our
classrooms in ways that they define
those in positions of authority in the
classroom.
Faculty,
instructors,
teaching assistants are not sitting
equally around the table with students.
Instead,
they have a responsibility to foster an
environment of mutual respect and
critical thinking.
One wherein students should never feel
that either their grades or their
wellbeing could be impacted because of
their gender,
sexuality,
race,
class,
or any other facet of their identity.
We appreciate that our university has
mechanisms through which students who
feel unsafe,
unfairly treated or have experienced
intolerance in the classroom or
otherwise in the role of students can
make appeals and find support and
resources to help them.
We also acknowledge that we can do a
better job of making students aware of
these mechanisms.
We are always so grateful when students
do approach campus offices designed for
reporting problematic classroom
situations as their courage makes us do
our jobs better.
We thank you for coming forward.
You are such valued members of our
community.
Charges that are program shelter
students from real world issues or
fosters classrooms.
Inhospitable to discussing contentious
issues from different vantage points
seem to us simply preposterous.
We reject efforts of those who have
seized this episode as a strategic
opportunity to disparage disciplines and
scholars with commitments to improving
social and economic inequality within
universities and in society.
At Large.
Commentary on this event in the press.
And social media has emboldened
individuals who see themselves as noble
defenders of free speech to intimidate
our faculty and students to the point
that protective measures have been taken
in an attempt to secure their safety.
Okay.
So another bit of commentary is
necessary there.
So there was a concerted effort made by
the Neo Marxists,
postmodern radical leftist types to
paint lindsay shepherd as the
perpetrator and the faculty members and
administrators who were involved in this
issue as the true victims.
And that's where this bit of
conceptualization is coming from.
Perhaps the most remarkable of such
comments about shepherd was broadcast on
our national broadcaster,
CBC,
TV Sunday,
scrum where a number of journalists,
Vicky,
Moshe,
Shama John Edmondson,
and Susan Riley.
We're discussing people of the year.
It was Vicky Mashama that made the
comments that I've clipped.
John,
who would your pick be?
Uh,
another young woman,
um,
Lindsay Shepherd who have heard a lot
about,
uh,
she was the young teaching assistant
that Laurier University,
uh,
who was called on the carpet for showing
a video of Jordan Peterson.
And it was the,
the recording of that disciplinary
hearing that went viral and that really
exploded the whole issue of the debate
that's occurring within the social
sciences and humanities od the right of
freedom of expression,
the right of freedom of research versus
the right of protection,
the right to safe spaces.
Uh,
the right not to be a subject to
regression.
This is a virulent debate that's
happening on university campuses across
the country.
Um,
some of us have written about it in the
past,
but it has to be said,
uh,
well,
no matter where you are on this debate,
it was Ms. Sheppard and that and that
tape that,
uh,
blue this entire issue open and made it
a part of the national discourse.
And for that she deserves great credit.
I disagree.
I think that she is someone that exists
and I think a lot of people responded to
her for the same reasons.
They tend to respond to things,
which is that she's a young crying white
girl.
But there are lots of moments in which
the academic freedom conversation could
have been had.
And guts has been skipped over serially.
And I don't think that choosing
appropriate person to have launched this
conversation because as it turned out,
she leans hard,
right,
and some of her choices,
well,
whether you like when she needs or not,
we're having this debate here on this
show now and we're having it because of
Ms. Sheppard
back to the,
against this politics of revenge.
We acknowledged the moral imperative to
support and protect our colleagues and
students.
We urge our colleagues at Lori and
beyond to monitor carefully how this
event has been framed and taken up.
Another bit of commentary for me.
I would also encourage colleagues at
Lori and beyond to monitor carefully how
this event has been framed and taken up.
I guess that's exactly what I'm doing
now.
We agree with Lorius president that we
live in an increasingly polarized world.
Understanding the forces and discontent
driving this polarization,
including how they are at play in this
situation and with what consequences is
a collective task in which we all have a
stake and 20 undersigned,
faculty and affiliate members of the
Department of Communication Studies
signed this.
Although the signatories of this letter
admit that the meeting was mishandled.
They do not say much about how with the
exception that shepherd was not provided
with independent or support.
To the contrary,
they state that Ramboo Kana at all.
We're simply following university
policies put in place as quote mechanism
through which students who feel unsafe,
unfairly treated or have experienced
intolerance in the classroom or
otherwise in the role as a student can
make appeals and find support and
resources to help them.
Thus,
although mcclachi and these letter
writers both claim in their way that
this incident is not diagnostic of the
state of the program,
the university and the state of higher
education in Canada,
both the statement from mcclatchy and
the Department of Communications
indicate in fact that something has gone
deeply and profoundly wrong.
Ramboo Canada's colleagues state that
Ramboo Canna Pimlott at all did nothing
wrong except shepherds lack of
independent representation.
And if they did do something wrong,
it was merely because they were
following policy which was laudatory and
admirable in its intent,
if not in its implementation.
Now the Wilfred Laurier a faculty
association also weighed in on this
issue,
and here's the gist of what they had to
say.
I'll put a link to the entire letter in
the description of this video,
but this is what they considered most
worthy of note
to be clear.
W L Ufa condemns the violent speech and
actions that have unfortunately become a
daily occurrence on our campuses.
In particular,
the harm that has been leveled at our
trans community and its supporters is
unacceptable.
W L UFA stands in solidarity with our
Lgbtq t community as they continue to
battle their way through walls of
ignorance and oppression.
Walls that seem to have been
disproportionately fortified in the last
few weeks.
So that's commentary on then Lindsay
Shepherd affair from the faculty
association,
representing all of the professors at
Wilfrid laurier university.
No comment whatsoever of substance on
the nature of the meeting itself.
Only an expression of concern for the
hypothetically and very poorly
documented by the way,
unsafe conditions for faculty and
students that have arisen at Wilfrid
laurier university in the aftermath of
the release of shepherds tape of the
meeting.
Now I said that I was speaking to junior
high and high school students at the
beginning of this video and so far I've
only talked about the state of our
universities,
but I'm doing this and providing this
extensive background because
universities provide the teachers for
our public schools as well as the
destination place for the most
academically able of the students who
come through the school system.
Thus,
before making my recommendations,
which I will do with all seriousness,
I have to document my discontent
thoroughly.
I'm therefore going to talk about the
response to the shepherd if they're
outside of Wilfrid laurier university
before returning to the point at hand.
I'm doing that to demonstrate that the
state of affairs indicated by Lindsay
shepherds tape is by no means unique to
Wilford Lori a itself.
I'm going to start with a few video
clips featuring professor Rinaldo,
a wall caught of the women and Gender
Studies Institute at the Ontario
Institute for the studies of Education.
These clips are taken once again,
interestingly enough from TV shows the
agenda with Steve Pakan.
Walcott recently appeared on the agenda
to discuss the events.
I'm speaking with you about today.
I chose to highlight Walcott because
he's director of the women and Gender
Studies Institute at the Ontario
Institute for the studies of Education
and oil.
Z as it's known is perhaps the most
influential educational institute
concerned with Public School curriculum
in all of Canada and therefore an
organization whose decisions are of
critical importance for determining the
nature of what's taught from
kindergarten all the way through high
school,
not only in Ontario,
but because of its influence all across
Canada and perhaps beyond.
I firmly believe that Walcott's attitude
is indicative of the ideological stance
that characterizes the philosophy that
is taught to those who will be the
teachers of young people in the public
school system in Canada from
kindergarten through high school.
The incidents at Wilfrid laurier
university have certainly provoked a
debate within academia and beyond on
finding that sweet spot between freedom
of expression and respecting the
diversity of the student body.
Is it possible to satisfy both of those
legitimate aims?
Let's find out.
Can we welcome in alphabetical order?
Shannon Day professor of philosophy at
University of Waterloo and Mcfarland,
professor of political science,
University of Waterloo,
Thomas Merit Canada research chair in
genomics,
bioinformatics
at Laurentian University in Sudbury,
Janice Stein,
founding director of the Munk School of
global affairs at the University of
Toronto and Rinaldo Walcott,
associate professor in social justice
education at Oise,
the Ontario Institute for Studies in
education.
Okay,
so a couple of things we want to answer
that I'd take the loan lung for you on a
desk.
So what do we are actually fan today in
2017 it's a long cultural award.
I had new wage in a university in the
60s when women studies and I happened to
be the director of lemming studies at
the same university as Janice when
women's studies and black studies broke
into the North American University.
That's been a consistent push against
them from the 60s on until the present.
And part of this debate around free
speech around academic freedom are ways
to diminish the fundamental impact of
women's studies and black studies and
other ethnic studies has had on the
university all the way up to having
women as presidents.
And Bim and that's vice presidents in
writing institutions.
I teach difficult material all the time.
My students,
I don't have to give trigger warnings,
I don't have to do any of that.
It's not about what's in our books
that's at stake here.
It's about a reframing of the university
where people like myself,
indigenous people,
Queer people are making a demand on an
institution that had headed to a
previously locked us out and we're
seeing that our voices matter too and
we're saying that the ways in which the
languages of academic freedom and free
and free speech have been framed within
the context of the university has often
provided pathways in particular for
straight white men to say really cruel,
harmful,
hurtful things and words do hurt and now
we're responding to that and we're
saying,
no,
this can't happen.
This kind of happened in our workplaces
where we come to,
where we are,
where we come to study and so on.
This is a cultural war that's being
waged within a particular institution
and we should be extremely clear about
that.
This is a pushback against the way in
which academic scholarship as actually
revealed on the opinions of the
university as a kind of white
supremacists logic or senior
administrators jump into pr mode.
Not to address what's happening inside
in Firstie but to quell the Shelton
voiseys largely of the right way.
Outside university.
I see this everyday at my university at
University of Toronto.
We have the ongoing Jordan Peterson
matter,
right?
Their response is not been to say
women's studies,
Black Studies,
African studies.
These kinds of studies have been
tremendous contributions to the
university.
Instead,
there's been a profound silence as
though the work that folks who work in
those areas do does not matter that
overwatch,
all wealth and generative intellectual
spirit serve the university and that
that is their fundamental flaw.
That where we've seen our senior
administrators become managers in favor
of the donors in favor of a secured
right wing mom,
you'll never see the soul call laugh.
Actually getting that kind of response
from university administrators don't
agree with you and another one that I
think it's much more subtle and it's
much more complex.
Actually the role of your receipt
administrators is not get into those
debates.
Um,
what really matters is that all the
programs you talked about,
which are very important,
and from my perspective,
a core part of the university,
um,
thrive if and faculty members and
students feel free to come into the
classroom and have these debates,
the role of university administrators
fundamentally beyond everything else.
And many of them are scars in their own
right,
but their role in their current jobs is
to protect those rights.
But what I'll say to there,
there's silence is an abrogation of
those rights by their very silence,
by the very silence.
What they're saying is that some of the
voices matter more than others within
the context of the institution.
Think that's true.
I,
well,
we fundamentally disagree.
Let's look what the University of
Toronto,
one concrete example did.
And when Jordan Peterson's work became
very controversial,
they did what he versus she do.
They organize the debate
that was fundamentally flawed.
And Jordan Peterson,
it was not even the question of Jordan
Peterson his work,
because he doesn't work in the areas
that he's claiming to criticize.
He does.
He has no expertise in them.
If I as a black faculty,
University of Toronto had engage in the
kinds of things that Jordan Peterson
engaged and I am sure I would have been
drummed out of the university.
I think we're sidestepping the issue.
The issue is really one about the,
the role that university has played in
helping to purchase the very kinds of
oppressions that many of us teach them
research.
Right now the university is deeply
implicated and producing certain kinds
of logics of white supremacy and if we
don't grapple with that,
then we can actually begin to grapple
with the claims that people who have
been tradition,
who have been consistently oppressed and
Chateaux now entering into the
university are making claims on that
institution to better respond to them.
This is what this is fundamentally
about,
but also I would say to you Steve,
that what happens is it's not from
women's studies and black studies that
these,
that these kinds of things emerge from
if neutrally from white male scholars by
the majority often making claims about
things for which they have no expertise
in.
And then we find the entire institution
coming into place to support their right
to speech.
Fundamentally a prosthetic you argued in
seriously,
um,
and engage and say if there are scholars
in the university who have no expertise
as you claim who are speaking and
writing about things which they are not
really qualified to speak about,
is precisely when there's free debate
and academic freedom at that kind of
shotty work is exposed and that's where
I want to agree with what it is.
A marketplace of free ideas has not
consistently worked for nonwhite people.
You should be honest about that.
I think that,
I think we're,
we're,
again,
there's a confusion here,
I think having,
you call it marketplace and I don't,
I call an an a Gora,
which is a different thing,
but an open public square,
not a marketplace and open public square
of free debate,
not only for faculty members where
academic freedom has me,
but for students.
Students also have to be,
feel free to say things that maybe
unpopular,
maybe unconventional,
maybe risky.
Not Illegal.
No,
of course not.
A Waco,
right.
We have marketplaces and a gorgeous
where people didn't debate other
people's humanity as well.
Right now what we do is in classrooms we
have people debate whether or not trans
identities are are,
are,
but that's how universities evolve and
that's how they improve.
Second evolve,
but also saying that some things are
intolerable.
What?
What is the fear of saying that some
forms of speech and tolerable in a world
where we already have limits on speech,
we've seen it happening in the first
year.
BDS,
we've seen it happen.
Israeli apartheid week.
We've seen the university and many
skillful kinds of ways limit speech.
Clearly it's morally and ethically
bankrupt.
The petitions in has harsh terms as I
can to debate other people's humanity.
If we can't begin there,
then there's something fundamentally
wrong with the university as an
institution.
This seemed to be one of the confusing
aspects of the situation at Aa in so far
as one of the professors who was
upgrading the teaching assistant for the
way she conducted the class didn't seem
to understand what the Canadian human
rights code prevented or didn't prevent,
covered or didn't cover.
Do you,
do you wonder whether faculty need a bit
of a refresher on what's legal or
illegal in their classrooms?
And let's say his name,
Professor Rambo Cooker found himself in
a very difficult situation.
He's also an untenured man of color and
we know I've been a professor for over
two decades.
I know that as a,
yeah,
on tenured black professor,
but I'm,
I had white ta's that often felt that
they could do the course better than I
could too.
And they often overstretched their own
responsibilities as tas.
I am sure that in the context of this
one particular instance that there's
much more surrounding that professors
all experience with this young white
woman that share race isn't parliaments
peaks to this longer deeper histories
again,
that the best academic and scholarly
work in women's studies,
black studies and and otherwise I'm
going to have to use this term sub all
disciplines raising,
which is that,
you know,
we see that kind of response when it's a
young white woman.
We see that kind of response when it's a
white woman in parliament.
Right?
And it's not just about hypocrisy.
It's about a log embedded history of
home matters who counts.
This is about a culture war where we're,
we're representative.
Democracies have had to yield more space
that people who've been normally shut
out and as we come into these
institutions and we asked for their
transformation,
things are beginning to fray.
Much of this is about the Christ of
Whiteness taking place in the context of
the university is the crisis of
Whiteness.
The crisis of whiteness is that white
people are no longer
allowed to simply say and behave in ways
that they could.
For instance,
in the 50s in the context of the
university,
we not push back on it.
We now call the illegitimate.
We now call it intolerable.
Now that we've talked about universities
and those who teach the teachers and the
ideology that possesses them say,
we're going to move a little bit closer
to the school system itself.
I want to focus on the elementary
teachers,
Federation of Ontario and the Toronto
District School Board.
These are institutions that are unique
in some senses to Ontario,
but I believe they are reflective or
perhaps even lead the way in the
development of the kind of curricula
that are or soon will be used to cross
Canada and the rest of the Western
world.
Given how fast information now travels.
The first question we might ask is what
should children and young adults be
taught and not taught from kindergarten
through high school?
My answer to that is quite straight
forward.
They should be taught to read and write
and speak skillfully and gracefully and
that should be done with a minimum of
political bias.
If you agree with that sentiment,
however imperfect you might find it,
then you need to realize that it is not
in the least the guiding principle of
the current public education system.
The people who are teaching your
children no longer believe,
for example,
that children can be taught without
political bias.
They also believe that there are
particular political viewpoints are so
self evidently and finally correct that
it is proper and just to concentrate on
inculcating them into children as early
as kindergarten regardless of what their
parents or anyone else might want.
I do not believe that this is a goal
shared by even a majority of teachers
and many have written to me indicating
their dissatisfaction,
but a small noisy domineering victim
hood claiming coterie of radically left
wing thinkers have commandeered the
controls and they're steering the ship
where they want it to go.
Screaming bloody murder if anyone dares
to question or worse oppose.
Both the Elementary Teachers Federation
of Ontario,
which operates at the provincial slash
state level and the Toronto District
School board which operates at the level
of the city have explicitly adopted a
social justice program and if
implemented curriculum based on its
principles from kindergarten through
grade eight was similar programs
operating in the remainder of junior
high and high school.
The ETF oh elementary teachers remember
is equity oriented.
This means equality of outcome,
not equality of opportunity,
and that is a radical left wing even
marxists goal.
They described their own organization as
a quote,
Social Justice Union end quote and have
produced educational material aimed in
their own words at fostering a climate
of social justice in Ontario.
This material is part of the social
justice begins with me initiative,
the ETF,
oh elementary teachers,
Federation of Ontario claims.
Furthermore,
that the education system is a key means
of delivering messages around inclusion,
diversity and welcoming environments.
They have developed a curriculum of
children's literature aimed at
delivering precisely this message,
thus bending art as ideologues always
due to the purposes of propaganda
justified by their belief that their and
justify their means.
The Social Justice and equity project
encompasses all elements of the
curriculum including language arts,
mathematics,
science and technology,
and the arts.
Even the very act of reading is taught
from a neo Marxist slash postmodernist
radical left perspective as students are
encouraged after finishing a given book
to identify the power claims of the
author and to know which groups have
been excluded from consideration by that
author.
The Toronto District School Board for
its part has its own social justice
action plan committed as it is to
fairness,
equity,
human rights,
and economic egalitarianism.
That is the slogan of a political
manifesto,
not a proper statement for an
administrative board whose proper role
is the local governance of the education
system.
No matter the t d s be unabashedly
announces its progressive agenda with no
consideration whatsoever given to the
fact that indoctrination and education
exist at precyse cross-purposes to one
another.
Their policies continue.
The TDSB has a shared responsibility to
contribute to positive social change
both locally and globally.
Learning about and engaging in social
justice issues such as equity,
diversity,
abuse against women,
poverty reduction and Environmental Ism
will make school a more relevant and
meaningful for all students.
Okay.
And will also ensure as much as this can
be done by fee,
yet it's students within the system
adopt the political stance deemed
appropriate by their administrators and
teachers.
Now make no mistake about it.
I know perfectly well that there is a
need for right and left wing viewpoints,
the right as a proclivity towards
counterproductive stacy's and sameness
and has to be balanced by the more
innovative thinking.
That is part and parcel of the
psychological processes that also drive
left wing political belief.
So my objection to the indoctrination of
children by the state and city has
nothing specifically to do with a
dislike of the opinions of those who
occupy what is after all half of the
political spectrum.
Yeah,
but the fact that it's such views are a
necessary part of Bellin's public debate
by no means justifies transforming
public education into a system of
indoctrination.
And that is exactly what has happened.
It has to stop.
Now,
many people have already discussed with
me their intent to pull their children
out of the public education system
because of this transformation,
but that is not the proper solution
assistant belongs after all to the
parents and children who use it and it
does not.
Right that any faction bends its
function to their own use.
So I'm going to recommend something
radical.
I have no idea how to set the
universities right in any simple manner.
Some of you know I've started working on
an online humanities university,
but that is a major project,
unlikely to bear fruit until years in
the future.
Yeah,
the humanities as they stand broadly
speaking,
geography,
history,
languages and literature,
Gender Studies,
cultural studies as well as many of the
social and applied sciences,
anthropology,
sociology,
social work as well as law and the
faculties of education most specifically
are occupied by radical left neo
marxists who will stay in their
positions for decades into the future.
The corruption that characterizes their
academic practices has spread widely
into the general culture,
political and corporate as well as
educational.
Although it is only the latter that
concerns us at the moment.
I think the only real hope of
forestalling further deterioration of
this sort that would require,
for example,
large scale exodus from the public
school system,
which I think is inevitable if present
trends continue is for the users of such
systems,
school children and young adults and
their parents to put a stop to its
politicization.
We have now reviewed evidence indicating
widespread ideological corruption at the
level of the professoriate
administration,
university department,
University and higher education systems
in general as well as a refusal to admit
to that corruption and a proclivity to
name,
call deride shame and protest when such
issues are brought to light.
Okay.
Such corruption particularly although
not uniquely typifies the faculties of
education where those who teach your
children are in turn taught.
Because of this,
the public education system has become
politicized and that politicization is
broadening and deepening,
presenting social danger in the form of
the involuntary indoctrination of
children and compromising the proper
function of public education itself,
which is the creation,
autonomous self governing free thinking
individuals.
So I am recommending the following
concrete actions affected and concern
families should first discuss the issues
and formulate a plan.
I think the following two books are
invaluable.
One more proximately locally and one
more distally.
There's a book called understanding
postmodernism by Steven our hex.
The whole book provides a good
introduction to the problem,
but the first chapter in particular
provides a solid overview.
I think the Gulag archipelago by
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn is also required
reading for many reasons,
not the least of which is his masterful
analysis of the relationship between
radical left wing thinking and the
absolute collapse into tyranny and
catastrophe that characterized all such
experiments in the course of the last
125 years.
More directly,
I think students should with the backing
of their parents if possible,
leave their junior high and high school
classes.
If any of the following topics arise,
this means they should stand up notre
objections to the content.
This sounds like indoctrination to me
rather than education,
so I'm leaving and then leave.
Perhaps they could encourage a classmate
slash friend to videotape their actions
and posted on Youtube.
It wouldn't take very many students
performing such an act to produce a very
powerful effect and it is certain that
many who won't have the courage to do
so.
We'll agree secretly that such action
was necessary.
Here are the topics I regard as
indicative of indoctrination rather than
education.
Diversity.
Okay.
Inclusivity,
equity.
Conveniently,
these form the acronym die,
which is exactly what the philosophy
underpinning their grouping and use
should be encouraged to do.
White privilege,
systemic racism,
gender.
I'm not claiming that there is nothing
to be learned about such topics or even
that they shouldn't be discussed.
What I am saying is if they are brought
up in an elementary,
junior high or high school classroom,
the odds are very high that the lesson
to be learned will be one driven by
ideological slash propagandistic
concerns rather than one aimed at the
inculcation of knowledge,
wisdom or skill.
Okay,
here are the words again,
diversity,
inclusivity,
equity,
white privilege,
systemic racism and gender.
Okay.
There will be mistakes made with such an
approach.
Some who discussed issues such as
inclusivity and equity are going to be
more reasonable than others,
but that does not change the fact that
the philosophy driving the pushing
forward of such topics is essentially
ideological and propaganda stick.
So I think such active resistance will
get the point across very effectively.
It is too bad and to just come to this,
but in my opinion,
it has think long and hard about it.
My feeling is this,
if effective action is not taken now to
counteract the politicization of the
public school curriculum,
the need for such action will merely
increase and it will take much more to
forestall the process later.
Pick your poison.
Okay.
Good luck the best you and your family
and happy new year.