I thought I'd let you know where I'm
going to be speaking publicly now until
the end of 2018 I'd been touring for
about three months discussing the issues
of meaning and responsibility raised in
my books.
12 rules for life and maps of meaning.
Here are the Canadian,
American and European cities.
I will be traveling to over the next
five months.
Cincinnati,
Tuesday,
September 18th Cleveland,
Wednesday,
September 19th grand rapids,
Thursday,
September 20th demoine.
Tuesday,
October 2nd St Louis,
Wednesday,
October 3rd Kansas City.
Thursday,
October 4th Denver Sunday,
October 7th Colorado Springs,
Monday,
October 8th San Antonio.
Wednesday,
October 10th irving,
Thursday,
October 11th Honolulu,
Wednesday,
November 21st Los Angeles,
Saturday,
December 1st back in Canada,
Calgary,
Thursday,
December 4th Vancouver Wednesday,
December 5th then it's off to Europe.
Dublin,
Sunday,
October 21st Oslo Tuesday,
October 23rd Manchester.
Thursday,
October 25th Oxford.
Friday,
October 26th Glasgow.
Saturday,
October 27th Edinburgh Sunday,
October 28th Amsterdam.
Tuesday,
October 30th Cambridge.
Thursday,
November 1st Helsinki Sunday,
November 4th Stockholm Monday,
November 5th and Birmingham.
Wednesday,
November 7th we'll be adding some more
cities to the European leg.
Of this tour.
There'll be announced soon,
and also we're going to Australia in
February and then back to Europe in
April of 2019 those dates will be
announced in the relatively near future.
It's been really something to tour
around like this,
and these events have been extremely
positive,
so if you're inclined to come out and
hear me lecture,
you'd be more than welcome.
Thank you very much.
Bye.