It's on me.
There we go.
All right.
We're live.
Holy Cow.
Hello,
Youtube.
We are live in Phoenix.
We're at Comerica theater.
I've got this Jordan Peterson guy.
I'm Simon.
I'm somehow hosting on his channel,
but that doesn't see right.
We're about to do what are maybe 13th,
14th,
15th.
They're all starting to blend.
Yeah.
In a good way for this one.
You really stepped up in the wardrobe
department.
I feel very sharp.
Sharp.
This thing has been unbelievable.
Huh?
It's pretty remarkable.
And this theater in Phoenix is one of
the most interesting ones yet.
It's very big.
It's about eight stories.
High side.
Yeah.
So about about 4,000 people waiting in
there.
It's about 105 and Phoenix today.
They're actually only here to purchase
the arch and
pretty much I,
I literally went to the gym twice today
to sweat indoors because it was so hot
outdoors.
Um,
but we've been bouncing around.
We just did three stops and tenses that
night.
Everything has been great.
Like,
and what I say to you every night,
I say it before we started and then at
the end it's like,
man,
everything that they say about this man,
about this tour,
about everything going on here,
it's completely the reverse of the
truth.
Yeah,
it's pretty interesting.
Yeah.
Well,
I spent a fair bit of time after the
lectures talking to people.
It's usually about 150 people that I get
to say hello to and,
and everybody has 15 seconds or so to
tell me a story,
but they don't
really low.
Audio is low.
All right,
we're going to talk louder.
Okay.
All right.
We're going to talk louder.
Let's see if we can pick it up.
So yeah.
Energy,
peanuts in men.
So I talked to about 150 people
afterwards and um,
they,
they all have a story to tell me,
but most of the stories are variants on
a theme,
which is that they're happy to listen to
the lectures because it's helping them
clarify their thinking or providing them
with words that they haven't had before.
Describe things they know to be true or
they tell me that they're doing better
as a couple or the father and son
they're or or father and the daughter or
mother and the daughter and they're
getting along better or it's a couple of
just decided to get engaged and their
relationship is better.
Or a father who's he was doing better
with his kids are,
but none of it's political.
It's political.
It's maybe it's maybe 10 percent
political and I'll.
I'll talk to the camera for a second for
this because everyday when they tell you
that Jordan's got angry white men,
right?
That's first off,
I would guess it's about 60 slash 40,
usually a male to female.
There are gay people.
There are black people,
white people,
Asian people.
There were Muslims last night and Jews.
I mean the whole thing.
All of that diversity.
That actually doesn't matter.
It's all there and they just.
They just consistently lie about it.
I think that it seems to me that the,
let's say the mainstream media types
that have been pillaring me in various
ways don't have a lexicon for dealing
with a phenomena that's primarily
psychological.
They have to make this fundamentally
political,
the political aspects of it,
you know,
and so far as I'm not a fan of the
radical leftists for example.
And,
but by the way,
you had been slamming the radical right
to.
I mean your whole thing.
I mean this is the irony of the
situation is you talk about the identity
politics,
right?
And the danger of that as much almost
onstage.
I don't like collecting this.
Yeah,
I think it's a bad route.
I think it takes us down a path and I
think that in destiny of a tribal path
is bloodshed and I don't care whether
it's the west wing or the right.
I'm more perturbed about the left lane
because of their dominance in the
universities in particular and that's
why,
you know,
the lots were lower this came from,
but it,
it's the collectivist issue that's the,
that's.
It has an almost everything that we've
been talking about that I'm talking
about with the audience is about the
western tradition of individual
responsibility essentially also not
individual rights,
although they're part of the discussion.
It's funny to be,
but I would also say that in the
collectivist lexical and there's no such
thing as free speech and there's really
no such thing as individual
responsibility and so in so far as I'm
able to make a case for that,
that makes me an enemy,
but even more importantly,
it takes the dialogue outside of their.
The way they frame the world.
They don't know what to do about it.
I don't know how to handle it,
so they invent an enemy essentially.
Right.
They don't really do the work
intellectually to counter the arguments,
so they just do the same old thing we
were saying right before we started how,
what a year and a half ago.
We didn't even know each other.
You.
The first time we ever did anything
together was,
I think it was November,
second of 2016,
which was a day or two before the
American election.
It feels like a lifetime ago when we
did,
I just moved into my house,
I didn't know my studio yet and we did a
little google hangout thing and the
audio was terrible and the video is bad
and you were telling me that the
Pinocchio Story,
which now most of your audience knows
about and you were getting teary eyed
and it and it ended and I thought,
I truly,
I mean I've said this to you,
I was like,
I don't know exactly what to make of
this guy.
And then subsequently you came on my
show many times and we've done a couple
of hours together and we did the sit
down with Shapiro and it's like every
month or two months this thing just
levels up,
levels up and it feels more real.
It feels more concrete.
And uh,
and we're all kind of growing together.
But I gotta tell you man,
we crossed 600,000 youtube subscribers.
I think on the same day you got to like
one point two.
Right now I'm,
I'm almost at $800.
So it stopped me a good sense.
I like competition.
I do like competition,
we do like that,
but it's just so cool watching this
whole thing growing.
Luckily as as hundreds of millions of
people come online,
we're not gonna run out of audience
because there's another 2 billion people
to join,
to join the electronic web with enough
bandwidth to start streaming videos.
So it looks to me like this whole online
video and audio and podcasts world is
just getting its legs underneath it.
God only knows where it's gonna go.
Alright.
Well since we're a behind the scenes in
the green room here,
let's just do a couple of behind the
scenes things here.
First off,
just how you feel while doing this whole
thing on my health is improving very
much.
I'm much,
much better than I was a month ago and
in comparatively better than I was a
year ago.
So yeah.
So that's really working out well.
I'm having a very nice time with the
audiences.
They're unbelievably,
isn't it incredible.
I mean,
meeting these people like just literally
every.
We haven't had one protest or no,
uh,
just everywhere they're planning
something in Portland.
Yeah.
Well,
we'll see about port credit or if it's
gonna happen,
it's gonna happen,
it's gonna happen in Portland,
but being really,
you know,
every night after the show,
uh,
you meet a certain amount of people
afterwards and I usually go out into the
crowd.
Yeah,
there's hundreds,
sometimes thousands of people wait.
And it's like,
man,
they just want to hug you.
And a lot of hugs.
It's pretty vicious people.
Yeah.
It's a good thing.
You're not a Germaphobe.
Yeah.
Well the other thing too is if,
if I'm protested enrichment or,
or Portland to any degree,
I'm going to videotape the lecture elite
and put it,
put it online and then people can see
what's being protested.
Yeah,
I think so.
I think that's the plan when we do
these,
they've pretty much been different every
single night.
I mean we've done about 15 shows and I
mix it up a little bit every night,
you know,
and then a couple of jokes in there that
are the mainstays,
some lobsters stuff and the rest.
But you can dispatch the logs have to be
in there,
but.
But you pretty much,
I mean the hour and a half that you do
and then especially when we do the q and
a after,
which is totally off the cuff,
you're kind of just going in and out and
sometimes you do three rules,
sometimes you do eight rules,
sometimes you know rules.
It's kind of amazing.
Yeah,
well I'm trying to develop a very large
corpus of stories around each of the
chapters and then I can mix and match
them and I'm also trying to push the
ideas that I've been developing in the
book farther ahead with each talk.
And so I spent a lot of time talking
about the relationship between
hierarchies and goals and and and
difference in status.
That's been a,
that's been a main theme and the
relationship between Truth and quality
of existence.
That's another one that there's a very
powerful positive relationship.
They're necessary and so on.
All of those themes,
you know,
there's no end to the amount you can
develop them.
And each venue gives me an opportunity
to push it a little bit farther and
clarify what I'm thinking and get the
story a little bit tighter and see how
the audience see how the individuals in
the audience are reacting.
And so I liked the fact that you opened
with some with a humorous intro and then
the q and a has an element of lightness
and comedy in it because one of the
things I learned a long time ago was
that even if you're dealing with
something that's extremely serious,
if you can't do it with a comedic touch,
then you haven't got the balance right.
Even if it's deadly serious stuff.
They love it when you make them laugh
sometimes accidentally.
Then like they're like,
they love that.
They really love it.
Yeah.
That's pretty cool.
Well,
you got to show today.
I do.
I guess I got to show to do.
To show you.
All right guys.
That's Jordan Peterson.
I'm Deborah.
Would you tell these people to subscribe
to my channel?
Subscribe to Dave's damn channel.
Needs the subscribers falling far behind
it.
Not The bottom lobster.
Don't.
Don't make me the bottom line guys.
I guess he's the top lobster,
but can we look at second level lobster
or something?
All right,
well it's good.
It's going to be fun tonight and we look
forward to seeing you guys were doing
this through through July and then
you're continuing into August.
Maybe September going to jump back in
and September.
I'll job.
Good.
All right.
Awesome.
Great.
You Bet.
Thanks Johnny.