Yeah,
so last week I told you I offered you an
interpretation of foundational stories,
right?
More than two,
but roughly speaking to,
um,
the creation stories because there's two
of them in genesis and then also the
story of the Buddha and I was presenting
you with a proposition and it's a multi
layered proposition.
The proposition is that the archetypal
story structure that we've already been
discussing is reflected in detail in
those stories and the archetypal story
structure is something like the
existence of a preexisting state where
things are roughly functional so that
you might think of that as the state of
things going well and that's the state
where your perceptions and your plans
are sufficiently developed so that when
you act them out in the world,
not only do you get what you desire,
but the story itself validates itself
through your actions.
Right?
Because what happens when you act
something out and you get what you
intend.
Just like when you use a map and get
where you're going.
Not only does that get you to where
you're going,
but it also validates the plan or the
map.
And so that's,
that's,
that's a definition of truth.
That's a pragmatic definition of truth.
This is the sort of thing that I was
trying to have a discussion with about
Sam Harris,
because the idea is that we have to
orient ourselves in a world where our
knowledge has always insufficient.
We never know everything about anything.
And so the question then is how can you
ever make a judgment about whether or
not you're correct and the answer to
that is something like,
well,
you lay out a plan and you can think
about it this way.
If this is actually an answer to the
postmodernist problem of how is it that
you determined whether or not your
interpretation of the world is.
We won't say correct because that's not
exactly right,
but no,
the postmodernists subject say with
regards to the interpretation of a text
that there's a very large number of
variations of ways in which that texts
can be interpreted and that's actually
true and need.
It's the same.
It's actually a reflection of a deeper
claim,
which they always often sometimes also
make.
Which is,
well,
if that's true for a text which isn't as
complex as everything,
although it's complex,
then it's even more true for everything,
which is to say the world lays itself
out in a very complex manner and you can
interpret that in a very large number of
ways.
So who's to say which interpretation is
correct?
Okay,
fair enough.
Which a reasonable objection and it's,
it's tied in with even a deeper problem,
which is the problem of perception
itself because if the world is laid out
in a manner that's exceptionally
complex,
then how is it that you can even
perceive it?
Well,
that's,
that's partly the question that we're
trying to answer and the answer to that
is what you have evolved perceptual
structures and they're actually oriented
towards specific goals and your
embodied.
So the,
your embodiment as a goal directed
entity is part of the solution to the
problem of perception.
But it's more complicated than that.
So we could say,
well,
you come equipped and this was constant
objection to pure reason essentially,
um,
that the,
the,
the problem is,
is the facts don't speak for themselves.
There's too many facts for them to speak
for themselves,
so you have to overlay on top of them
and interpretive framework.
Well,
where does the interpretive framework
come from?
Well,
the right answer to that is something
like it evolves,
right?
It's taken three and a half billion
years for your perceptual structure.
You're a body perceptual structure to
evolve and it's done that.
I roughly in a trial and error process.
I don't think that exhausts what's
happened over the course of evolution,
but it's a good enough shorthand for the
time being so,
so there's the constraints imposed on
your perceptual structures by the
necessity of survival and reproduction,
but there's other constraints imposed to
that.
You might regard to subsets of that.
One is that because you exist in a
cooperative and competitive landscape,
the perceptual structures and plans that
you lay out,
we'll say the maps that you lay out have
to be negotiated with other people and
so that put stringent constraints on the
number of interpretations that you're
allowed to apply.
So you can think about this in a pig and
sense.
That is if there are children in a
playground and they're trying to
organize themselves to play,
they have to agree on a game and the
game is of course a perceptual structure
and a goal directed structure and a
structure that delimits action and
interactions and so they at least have
to settle on a game and so that
constrains the set of possible actions
and perceptions in the environment to
those that are deemed socially
acceptable.
And then you say,
well,
what are there further constraints?
And the constraints might be,
well,
let's play the game and see if it's any
fun.
And that means that you have to take the
plan that you've organized consensually
and then lay it out in the actual world
and see if when you lay it out in the
world,
it does what it's supposed to do.
In some sense,
what you're doing is testing a tool.
So the idea that the range of
interpretations is infinite and
unconstrained turns out to be incorrect
and now it's that.
That is.
That doesn't mean it's easy to figure
out how they're constrained,
but the technical suggested that,
well,
there's an infinite number of equally
valid interpretations is just not
correct.
It's not correct and it's not correct on
biological evolutionary grounds and it's
not.
It's also not correct on sociocultural
grounds because it has to be negotiated
and then you know,
piaget put a further constraint on that
essentially by saying,
well,
not only does it have to be a game and a
game that attains its hands,
but it has to be a game that people want
to play.
So it also has to satisfy some element
of subjective desire as well.
So that's three levels of constraint,
right?
It has to be a game you want to play.
It has to be a game that you can play
with other people and it has to be a
game that if you play with other people,
actually works in the world.
Okay,
well so much for an infinite array of,
of options.
It's a very constrained array of
options.
Now,
and I think that the idea that I've been
proposing to you is that what evolved
mythology does these representations
that we've been dealing with these
archetypal representations is sketch out
that landscape.
What is the landscape of playable games?
That's a good way of thinking about it
and so it's.
It sets out a landscape.
It sends out a description of the
landscape in which the game is going to
be played as well as a description of
the lens of of the game itself,
and so the landscape is roughly that.
The core,
the core archetype seems to be something
like it's it's.
It's something like the interplay
between chaos and order and chaos is
represented by the Serpentine Predator
because we use our Predator detection
circuits to conceptualize the unknown
because what else would we do it that,
that that seems,
given that we're prey animals and given
our evolutionary history,
it's very difficult to understand what
else we could possibly do because the
critical issue about venturing into the
unknown is that you might die or perhaps
a slight variant of that is something
might kill you,
but whatever.
Those are close enough.
To the same thing,
so chaos is what causes your
deterioration and death and there's lots
of ways to conceptualize that,
but but a reptilian Predator
fire-breathing reptilian Predator isn't
a bad way to start.
And so the question is,
well,
what do you do in the face of that?
And one answer is you build
circumscribed enclosures that's order
and then also you act as the builder of
circumscribed enclosure.
So that's partly the hero.
Now the hero is also though that's not
good enough because the circumscribed
enclosure isn't impermeable.
It can be invaded,
it will inevitably be invaded either
from outside or from within.
Right?
And so we've been conceptualizing the
Predator,
the malevolent Predator at multiple
levels of analysis throughout our
evolutionary history say,
but also in our symbolic history,
trying to understand the nature of that
which invades the enclosure,
right?
And we can say,
well,
it's partly external threat,
it's partly social threat,
but it's also partly the threat that
each individual brings to bear on the
social structure because of our,
let's say our intrinsic malevolence.
And so that would be the snakes within.
And so that accounts for the analogy
that the Christian analogy between the
serpent in the garden of Eden and Satan,
which is a very,
very strange analogy.
It's not obvious at all why those two
things would stack on top of one
another,
especially given that when the creation
story originally emerged in,
in the forum I talked to you about last
week,
the story of Adam and Eve,
the idea that the serpent in the garden
was also something that was associated
with the adversary,
wasn't an implicit part of the story
that God laid on afterwards.
Like,
well,
what's the worst possible snake?
Well,
that's a reasonable question.
And then a better question is what do
you do about the worst possible snake?
And one answer is you face it,
but there's other answers to like you
make sacrifices,
right?
And that's how you stave off the dragon
of temporal chaos.
Roughly speaking,
is that you learn to conceptualize the
future.
You see the future as a realm of
potential threat,
and then you learn to give things up in
the present and somehow that satisfies
the future.
Now,
so maybe you're offering sacrifices to
God and you think,
well,
why does that will take?
You've got to think about that
psychologically.
Why does that work?
Well,
you could think about the spirit of God,
the father as an image istick
representation of the collective spirit
of the group.
We'll call it the patriarchy if you
want.
It doesn't matter.
It's the thing that's common across the
group as a spirit,
as a psychological force across time.
Why do you make sacrifices to that?
That is what you do all the time.
You're right now.
You're sacrificing your time to the
spirit of the great father because your
assumption is is that if you do what's
diligent so you're not chasing impulsive
pleasure at the moment,
unless you're pathologically interested
in this class or something like that,
you're not chasing impulsive interest.
You're sacrificing your impulsive
interest to satisfy the spirit of social
requirement and so you're offering a
sacrifice to that spirit in the hope
that you can make a bargain with it so
that it will reward you in the future
and that reward will be part of partly
the staving off of insecurity,
which is no more than to say that part
of the reason that you're getting your
degree is because you believe that it
will aid you in finding employment and
status and all the other things that
will stave off the dragon of chaos.
So now those things were as as we've
been at pains to point out is those
things were acted out and then
represented an image and story long
before they could be fully articulated
because we're building our knowledge of
ourselves and also our social structures
and also the world from the bottom up as
well as from the top down.
There's an interplay between the two
levels of analysis.
Okay.
And so,
so that's partly,
that's partly the archetipal
underpinning and then with regards to
the stories themselves,
you're,
you're in a map,
so to speak.
You're using a map and with any luck
it's detailed enough so that you can use
it to get to the place that you want to
go and sometimes you don't,
and that means that you have to
recalibrate your,
your journey along the map,
which by the way is exactly what gps
systems do when you go off the pathway,
right?
They stop.
That's an anxiety response from the GPS
system.
They stop,
they recalibrate,
and they readjust the map now and then
if you're unfortunate,
this very rarely happens anymore.
You'll be on a road that isn't mapped
and then the GPS system doesn't know
what to do.
While that happens in real life too,
I mean those are.
I'm using gps for a very specific
reason.
Those are intelligent systems as far as
I'm concerned.
Those are the closest things we ever
designed to intelligence systems because
they can actually orient,
right,
they oriented in real time and they're
unbelievably sophisticated systems,
right?
Because they required a huge satellite
network and and so on,
and they're cybernetic systems.
Technically speaking,
they,
they respond very much like the way that
we respond.
So,
so anyways,
you know you're in,
you inhabit a map,
you try to adjust the resolution of the
map so that it's more complex than it
needs to be to get you from point a to
point b.
that's it.
You want minimal resolution because that
enables efficient cognitive processing.
It doesn't overload you too much.
Like when I'm looking at this room,
if I look,
say I want to walk down this pathway,
basically what my mind does,
my perceptual field,
and you can detect this,
if I look straight ahead,
I could barely see you.
People on the periphery,
you're more like,
you're kind of like blurs you too.
I can tell that you have heads,
but that's about it.
When you move,
I can see your hand,
I can probably see your eyes,
but barely.
So you're all very low resolution and
even though I can't detect it at the
very periphery of my vision,
you guys are black and white.
So my color vision disappears at the
periphery even though I can,
I can't actually perceived that.
So what happens is if I want to walk
down here,
this pathway becomes high resolution.
It becomes marked with positive emotion.
All of this turns into low resolution
back here.
It's not even represented and then I
find out,
well,
am I doing this properly?
And the answer is while I walk forward
and if I get to the goal,
then I've done it properly enough and if
one of you stand up and get in my way,
then I'm going to focus on you and
assume instantly that I haven't mapped
you properly,
right?
I,
I put you in the category of irrelevant
entity when in fact you have to be in
the category of strange object,
the thing that object and so well.
So then we inhabit those structures all
the time.
We're in a structure like that,
a perceptual structure,
and if it's working,
then it's got the archetipal quality of
paradise,
so to speak,
because it's axioms are correct and it's
functional and then now and then
something comes along and that's what
the snake is.
The eternal snake in the garden that
pops up inside a structure and it turns
out that the things that you weren't
attending to are the most important
things rather than the least important
things and that what does that do?
It blows the map into pieces and that
can happen at different levels of
severity,
but at the ultimate level of severity,
it's apocalyptic,
right?
Everything goes and that's a.
that's a traumatic intrusion and
essentially the story of the Garden of
Eden is the story of a traumatic
intrusion.
That's exactly what it is,
and so what happens is that Adam Eve are
living in unconscious blasts,
roughly speaking,
everything's fine.
They're in their walled garden,
there in a paradise will state.
They're not aware of their own
vulnerability or nakedness,
so they they,
they,
they're not suffering from negative
emotion.
Something pops up that radically expands
their vision and all of a sudden now
they can apprehend all sorts of things
that exist as threats,
so that's their own nakedness and
vulnerability and temporality itself
because they become aware of the future
and bang that state of being in that
paradise is forever gone.
That's the strange thing about human
beings is this is what happened to us,
I think,
is that our perceptions developed to
such a degree that we could no longer
ignore what was irrelevant.
We couldn't do it because we discovered
roughly speaking,
once we discovered our finite
limitations in time and space,
we discovered that we were surrounded by
infinite threat always,
and maybe that's why people are so hyper
awake because threat wakes you up while
we're in a constant state of existential
threat.
Now the advantage to that is that we
take,
we take arms up against a sea of
troubles constantly.
That's the advantage,
right?
And We build enclosures and we take
precautions for the future and we live a
very long time and we generally live
quite safe lives compared to the lives
we could live.
And so we've traded pain for anxiety.
That's another way of thinking about it.
Now.
It's still a pretty rough trade,
right?
Because who wants to be nervous all the
time,
but you're alive and awake when you're
nervous and it is a form of
consciousness elevating activation.
That's another way of thinking about it.
So the story of Adam and Eve is the
story of the eternal fall that that's
what it is.
It says,
look,
you exist in these walled enclosures,
but there's something that lurks that
will always knock you off your feet.
And then the question is what is that?
And the answer to that is being
formulated over very long periods of
time.
Partly it's the probability of predation
itself.
That's the snake,
the thing that can come in subtly and
undermine you.
Okay,
but then that's,
that's what would you call it,
expanded upward to include the abstract
snake,
which is that thing that can undermine
your conceptual schemes.
So you have your actual territory and
then you have your abstract to our
territory and in your actual territory
there are actual snakes and in your
abstract territory there are abstract
snakes,
right?
And then the worst snake of all his
malevolence.
And that's.
I think that's technically correct
because one of the things that you view,
for example,
when you're looking at posttraumatic
stress disorder,
is that it's almost always the case that
someone who suffers from post traumatic
stress disorder,
which you might think of as a real real
life re incarnation of the fall,
is that people encounter something
malevolent and it breaks them because
it's the worst thing to understand.
It's like suffering is one thing,
man,
that's,
that's bad enough.
Vulnerability and suffering that's bad
enough,
but to encounter someone who wishes that
upon you and will work to bring it
about.
That's a whole different category of
horrible,
especially when it also reflect
something back to you about yourself.
Because if someone else can do that to
you and they are human,
that means that you partake of the same
essence.
Strangely enough.
That's actually the cure to some degree
to posttraumatic stress disorder is like
if you've been victimized,
you're naive and you've been victimized.
The way out of that is to no longer be
naive and to no longer be victimized,
and that means that you see this
reflected in the Harry Potter idea.
For example,
that the reason that Harry Potter can
withstand voldemort is because he's got
a piece of a is being touched by it and
the way that you.
The way that you keep the psychopaths at
bay is to develop the inner psychopaths
so that you know when,
when you see what right and then,
but that's a voluntary thing.
It's,
it's,
it's so.
It's like a.
it's like a,
a set of tools that you have at your
disposal which has full knowledge of
evil and that does.
Nisha said if you look into an abyss for
too long,
you risk having the abyss gaze back into
you.
Right?
The idea is that if you look at
something monstrous,
you have a tendency to turn into a
monster and people are often very afraid
of looking at monsters.
Things exactly for that reason,
and then the question is,
well,
should you turn into a monster?
And the answer to that is yes,
you should,
but you should do it voluntarily and not
accidentally,
and you should do it with good in mind
rather than falling prey to it by
possession essentially.
Because that's the alternative.
And how does it possess you?
That's easy.
You're suffering makes you better,
your bitterness makes you resentful,
you're resentful,
means meat,
makes you vengeful.
And once you're on that road,
you go down that a little bit farther,
man.
Well you end up fantasizing in your
basement about shooting up the local
high school and then killing yourself,
right?
Because that's sort of the ultimate end
of that line of pathological reasoning
being should be eradicated because of
its intrinsic evil and I'm exactly the
person to do it and I'll cap it off with
an indication of my own lack of worth
just to hammer the point home.
Right?
And if I can garner a little post post
you fame along the way,
well that'll satisfy my primordial
primate dominance hierarchy,
a imaginings to at least in fantasy.
So you know,
it's the full package.
If you want to go down that route and of
course people don't like to think about
that sort of thing and it's no bloody
wonder.
But without the capability for mayhem,
Europe,
you're,
you're a,
you're a potential victim to mayhem.
So you need your sword.
It should be sheath,
but you need to have it and it's very
frequently the case.
If you treat someone with posttraumatic
stress disorder,
there's two things you have to do.
You have to help them develop a very
articulated philosophy of evil because
otherwise their brain bothers him over
and over and over.
Why?
Why were you so deal with naive?
How did you become victimized?
Why were you such as soccer?
These are good questions.
You don't want to have that happen to
you again.
You don't want to be exploited twice.
Okay,
so your eyes have to open up.
We know the price of that from the
Egyptian myth,
right?
You come into contact with seth.
What happens?
Even if you're a god,
you lose it.
I.
It's no joke,
man.
and then the cure for that is the
movement down into the underworld and
the revitalization of the father.
That's the identification with the force
that created culture,
right?
And that then there's you and that
together.
Then you can withstand malevolence.
Maybe you could withstand tragedy and
malevolence and then that's the whole
secret,
right?
Because that's what you want in life,
you need to be able to withstand tragedy
and you need to be able to withstand
malevolence because those are the
forces.
They're always working against you,
and so it's.
This is associated with the union idea
of incorporation of the shadow,
right?
You have to be.
We know this God,
we know how predators work with regards
to children.
Even if you're a pedophilic Predator and
you're looking at a landscape of
children,
the child that you're going to go after
is the one that's timid and won't fight
back.
You've picked your victim and predatory
people in general are exactly like that
man there because they're predators.
They're not going to attack someone
who's who's going to fight back.
In fact,
the issue is likely not to even come up.
They're going to be looking for someone
one way or another that cannot
conceptualize what they are and then
perfect.
It's open season and it's open season,
and so if you're treating someone with
posttraumatic stress disorder,
first they need an introduction to the
philosophy of malevolence and second,
they have to learn to become dangerous
because that's the only way out.
What's the alternative?
To get these recurrent thoughts about
their vulnerability in the face of
malevolence and their own naivety
because by definition,
if someone's psychopathic has exploited
you,
you're too naive.
It's.
It's a definitional issue.
You can say,
well,
that's no fault of mine.
How the hell could I be prepared?
Fair enough,
man.
Perfectly reasonable objection doesn't
solve your problem because it's an.
It's an eternal problem,
right?
The internal problem is how do you deal
with tragedy and malevolence and you can
say,
well,
I'm not prepared.
It's like,
yeah,
fair enough.
Unsurprising.
Especially if you were over protected as
a child.
It's not a good idea to overprotect your
kids because the snakes are going to
come into the garden no matter what you
do,
and so then you,
instead of trying to keep the damn
snakes away,
what you do is you are a mere child with
something that can help them chop them
into pieces and make the world out of
them so that the trick for human
thriving in the face of suffering and
malevolence is strength,
not protection.
It's a completely different idea.
We also know this clinically.
We know for example,
that if you treat people with exposure
therapy for agora phobia,
which is roughly speaking,
the fear of chaos,
I would say the fear of everything.
You don't make them less afraid.
You make them braver.
It's not the same thing because with an
agoraphobic,
see what happens to them is is the fault
they never conceptualized death and
suffering.
They're naive,
right?
It never enters their theater of their
imagination and it's because they're
protected from it,
but then something happens.
This,
this often happens to women in their
forties because they're.
They're the people most likely to
develop egret phobia.
Something happens there,
they've been protected from chaos by
authority their entire life,
so maybe they had an overprotective
father and then they went to an
overprotective boyfriend and then they
went to an over protective husband and
maybe they were willing to be subjugated
to all three of those because of the
project protection,
right,
so so that's the bargain.
They stay weak and dependent and maybe
they have to because that's the only way
they can appeal to the person who's
hyper protective,
but the price they pay for that is that
they're not sufficiently competent and
then something happens in their life.
Often in their forties,
they develop heart palpitations.
Maybe as a consequence of menopause.
Their heart starts to beat a radically
and they think,
oh,
no,
death.
It's like,
well,
who are you going to talk to about that?
Right?
There's no protection from authority for
that,
or maybe their friend gets divorced or
maybe their sister dies or something
like that.
It brings up the specter of mortality
and maybe the specter of malevolence and
mortality and it brings it up in a way
that authority recourse to authority
cannot solve,
and so then they have panic attacks.
What happens?
They go out,
they get afraid,
they feel their heart beating.
Then they get afraid of their heart
beating because they think,
oh no,
I'm going to die,
and they think,
oh no,
I'm going to die and I'm going to make a
fool of myself while I'm doing it and
attract a lot of attention.
So the two big fears come up,
mortality and social judgment,
and then they have a panic attack.
It's like fight or flights going out of
control.
Very,
very unpleasant.
Then they start to avoid the places
they've had a panic attack.
Then they end up not being able to go
anywhere.
So then tie A.
Matt has come back,
write a huge monster,
a little victim,
and so what do you do with them?
Well,
there no saying no.
There's no tire map that's done right
there.
Naivety is over.
They've had a direct contact with the
threat of mortality and social judgment.
They've met the terrible mother and
they've met the terrible father and
there's no going back.
There's no saying,
oh,
the world is safe.
It's not safe.
Not at all.
The fact that you think it's safe means
that you were living in an unconscious
bubble that was sort of provided to you
by your culture.
It's a gift and now that's been
shattered and so now what do you do?
Well,
the answer is you retreat until you're
in your house and there's nowhere you
can go.
You're the ultimate frozen rabbit,
right?
And your life is hell because you can't
function.
The alternative is let's take apart the
things you're afraid of.
Let's expose you to them carefully and
programmatically,
and then you'll learn that you can.
You're actually tougher than you think.
You never knew that and maybe you didn't
want to take on the responsibility
because you know people play a role in
their own demise,
so to speak.
When you had opportunity to go out and
explore or withdraw because you were
afraid,
you chose to withdraw because you were
afraid.
So it's not only that you were over
protected.
Often it's that you were willing to take
advantage of the fact that you are
overprotected and run back there
whenever you had the opportunity,
you know,
so maybe you're a kid in the playground,
right?
And you're having some trouble with
other kids and you know,
in the back of your mind,
I should deal with deal with this
myself,
but you go and tell your mom and get her
to intervene and you know that that's
not right.
You know that you're breaking the social
contract,
but it's easier.
And so that's what you do.
You run off to an authority figure and
hide behind the great father,
right?
Roughly speaking,
while the problem with that is you don't
learn how to do it yourself.
So then you have to relearn it painfully
when you're 40.
So then you take people out,
you say,
well,
what are you afraid of?
Rank it from one to 10.
So 10 is make a list of 10 things.
You're afraid of the least.
The thing that we're least afraid of.
We'll call number 10.
So we'll start with that.
Okay,
well,
I'm afraid of elevators.
Okay,
well let's,
let's look at a picture of an elevator.
Let's have you imagine being in an
elevator.
Let's go out to an elevator and let you
watch the terrible jaws of death open
because that's how you're responding to
it symbolically,
right,
and you're going to do that at it.
At the closest proximity you can manage.
You find out,
you go do that.
It works.
You're nervous as hell,
especially from an anticipatory
perspective,
shaking.
You go out,
you stop,
you watch it happen,
and he actually calmed down.
You do that 10 times and it no longer
bothers you.
Well,
what you've learned that you didn't die,
but more importantly than that,
you've learned that you could withstand
the threat of death.
That's what you've learned and then you
move a little closer and then you move a
little closer and then you move a little
closer and finally you're back in.
What's no longer the elevator from a
symbolic perspective.
It's a tomb,
right?
It's,
it's,
it's a place of enclosure and isolation
and you learn,
hmm,
turns out I can withstand that,
and then you're much more together,
much more confident,
and that's often one of the things that
often happens in situations like that.
I've seen this multiple times,
is that if you run someone through an
exposure training process like that and
toughen them up,
they'll often start standing up to
people around them in a way they never
did before because they wouldn't stand
up for themselves before because they
weren't willing to undermine the
protection.
See,
if you're protecting me,
I can't bother you because I can't
afford to forsake your protection,
so if I'm going to play that game,
I'm going to be high hide behind you,
then I can't challenge you.
So that's no good because that's
sometimes why people.
You see this with guys very frequently.
They're still deathly afraid of their
fathers judgment when they're in their
thirties or forties.
It's like,
well,
why not?
Because they still want to believe that
there's someone out there that knows,
and so they're willing to accept the
subjugation because it doesn't force
them to challenge.
The idea that there's someone out there
that knows because that's the advantage
of having your father as a judge,
right?
Because he knows,
well,
what if he doesn't?
What if no one knows any better than
you?
Well,
that's a rough thing.
You don't until you realize that you're
not an adult,
right?
That's really technically the point of
realization of adulthood is that no one
actually knows what you should do more
than you do.
I mean,
it's a horrible realization because what
the hell do you know?
It's a terrible realization and people
will often pick slavery,
permanent slavery to the spirit of the
great father,
let's say over that realization and it's
completely understandable,
but the problem with it is that there's
more to you than you think,
and so if you continue to hide behind
that figure,
then you never have a chance to
understand that there's more to you than
you think far more time than you think.
Maybe there's enough to you so that you
can actually withstand the threat of
mortality without collapsing.
Maybe even withstand the threat of
malevolence without collapsing.
Who knows?
It's certainly possible,
and it's not an abstract question,
it's exactly the sort of question that
you address in the psychotherapeutic
process.
It's always the question that you
address and the answer is often in the
affirmative because people can get
unbelievably tough and you know that
because people work in emergency wards
in hospitals,
right?
Or they work in,
in palliative care wards or they work as
mortuary assistance.
I mean these people have bloody rough
jobs,
you know,
are there on the front line of police
investigation into,
you know,
highness child abuse crimes and so
they're confronting malevolence on a
regular basis and you know,
those are very stressful jobs,
but people do them and some people do
them without even being damaged by them.
Although that's a harder thing because
you can see horrible things,
you know,
things you will never forget.
So,
so I would say the story in the story of
Adam and Eve is a Meta story and it's a
metta story for two reasons.
One is it's about how stories transform
because Adam and Eve are in this
unconscious paradise and then it
collapses.
And that happens to every potential
story.
Right,
that's niches realization.
He said,
look,
imagine that you live within a belief
system and then something arises to
challenge the belief system.
Not only does the belief system
collapse,
but something worse happens.
Your belief in belief systems collapses,
and that's the road tonight.
Now it doesn't have to because you can
jump from one belief system to another,
but sometimes that doesn't work is that
you do a medic critique and you say,
oh,
I was living in this protective
structure and it turned out to be
flawed.
Okay?
One alternative is jumped to another
protective structure.
Find another alternative is protective
structures themselves are not to be
trusted.
Bang,
you're in chaos.
How the hell are you going to get out of
that?
That's the pathway denialism.
While you can,
you can.
You can work your way through that.
That's difficult,
or you can do what young would regard as
a soul damaging move and you can
sacrifice your new knowledge and re
identify with something real rigid and
restricted,
which is what I would say is happening
to some degree with the people in Europe
who are turning to a regressive
nationalism.
As an alternative to the current state
of chaos,
it's like I know that that people need
to identify with local groups.
I understand that,
but the risk,
the danger of making the state the
ultimate God and that's order,
but that's not a good replacement for
chaos.
It's just another kind of catastrophe,
right?
Too much order,
too much chaos,
both.
Catastrophes.
You want to stand in the middle somehow
and mediate between the two and that's
where you have your real strength
because then it isn't that you've
discovered a safe place because even the
bloody right wingers or after a safe
place,
right?
They just want it to be the state.
Yeah,
exactly.
Well,
there's no safe places and the next
issue is do you really want a safe
place?
Is that what you want?
You want to be so weak that you want to
be protected from threat.
What the hell kind of life is that?
You're a paralyzed rabbit in a hole
that's no life for a human being.
You should be confronting danger and the
unknown and mlevel.
It's because and the reason for that to
his pit.
This is the weird paradox.
This is,
and I believe this is the paradox,
first of all,
that was discovered in part by a Buddha,
but also laid forth very clearly and
Christianity,
which is that the p,
the solution to the problem of tragedy
and malevolence is the willingness to
face the who the hell would ever guessed
that.
It's completely paradoxical.
It's a completely paradoxical
suggestion,
is that,
well,
why does it work well?
Because the more you confront the two of
them,
the more you grow and maybe you can grow
so that you're actually larger than the
chaos and malevolence itself and you
think,
well,
what's the evidence for that?
And that's easy.
That's what people do.
That is how we learn.
Like every time you expose your child to
something new,
a playground,
what are they exposed to?
Chaos and malevolence.
Now there's more to it than that
obviously because kids play and they,
you know,
they promote each other and they form
friendships and all of that,
but in the playground itself,
there is the complexity of the social
structure and the malevolence of the
bully.
It's right there and you throw your kid
in there and you say adapt,
and they do.
Okay,
so they can do it at a small scale.
It's not trivial,
but the playground is a complicated
place.
The kid can adapt.
Well,
how much can you scale that up?
Can you scale that up to from the chaos
and order and malevolence of the
playground to chaos in order and
malevolence itself?
Well,
that's the question.
I don't think there's any reason to
answer that in the negative,
so because we don't know the full extent
of a human being and it is the problem
that's worked out.
So in the Buddhist story,
for example,
what happens after,
so Buddha's world collapses in the same
way that Adam and Eve's world collapses,
it's a consequence of repetitive
exposure to mortality and death.
What happens to Buddha as he realizes
that the little protected city that his
father made for him,
the walled garden,
it's exactly the same motif that's in
this Adam and Eve story is,
is it's,
it's what it's.
It's fatally flawed.
That kind of protection cannot exist and
he discovered that in pieces,
right?
Which is exactly what happens to
children is that they go out,
they discover a limit,
they run back and the parents can help
them with the limit.
They run out,
they discover limit.
They run back,
but some at some point they run out,
they discover a limit.
They run back and the parents have
nothing to say to them because they've
hit the same limit that the parents hit.
Just like,
well,
what are you gonna do with your life?
How are you going to.
How are you going to operate in this
architectural universe?
While your parents can only say,
well,
they can say you identify with the
proper archetipal figures they do that.
They at least act that out for you,
but at some point it's a problem that
they cannot solve for you without making
you weaker.
That's the thing you know.
So it's an interesting thing that I've
learned in therapy because one of the
things you have to learn as a therapist
is how do you not take your client's
problems home with you?
It's very common existential problem
that beginning therapists face because
they're afraid.
It's like while you're dealing with
people all the time who have serious
problems,
sometimes it's mental illness,
although less frequently than you think,
and sometimes it's just that they're
having a good catastrophe right there.
Their parents have cancer or something
like that,
or their father has Alzheimer's and
they're unemployed.
They have a drug problem or they have an
schizophrenia son or like these aren't
mental illness problems,
right?
Those are just catastrophes,
and so people are discussing those with
you all the time.
How do you avoid being crushed by that
or avoid taking it home?
And the answer to that is you don't
steal the problem,
that that's the answer.
It's like you have some problems.
If you come and talk to me,
I'll help you figure out how to solve
them.
I will not tell you how to solve.
I won't steal your problems because what
we're trying to do in therapy is number
one,
solve your problem.
Number two,
turn you into a great solver of
problems,
and the second one is way more important
than the first one,
and so you never solve someone's problem
by removing from them the opportunity to
solve their problem.
That's theft.
That's the eatables situation.
That's the over protective mother.
No father can play that role too.
We're talking about architectural
representations.
It's like all protect you at the cost of
your ability to protect yourself.
No wrong.
That's the,
that's a sin.
That's a good way of thinking about it.
That is not what you do with people,
not with your children,
not with your partner,
not with yourself.
You don't do that.
That destroys people's adaptive
competence and it and it disarms them in
the face of chaos and malevolence and
that's a terrible,
you know,
send someone out are unarmed in a world
like that,
it's a terrible thing to do so.
And if people aren't strong enough to
manage it,
then they get resentful and then when
you get the downhill spiral that goes
along with that.
Okay,
so the Med is story is partly you're in
your,
you have a map,
but it's insufficient and things will
come up to disrupt it and sometimes the
disruption is catastrophic.
Everything falls apart.
That's what happens to the Buddha and
that's what happens to Adam and eve and
the rest of the biblical stories are
actually an attempt to put that back
together.
Now that that's been assembled,
as I said,
it's been assembled over centuries,
right?
Okay.
We've got the problem.
The problem is the apocalypse,
the ever present reality of the
apocalyptic fall,
that's the problem,
and so you could say,
well,
what is that?
It's the insufficiency of all potential
conceptual schemes,
right?
Your conceptual schemes are insufficient
to deal with the complexity of the
world.
It's a permanent problem.
So what do you do?
You stop relying on your conceptual
schemes.
That's part of the answer.
You start relying on your instead on
your ability to actively generate
conceptual schemes in the face of chaos
and malevolence and so that makes you
someone that identifies with your
creative capacity,
your creative,
courageous capacity for articulation and
action in the face of the unknown rather
than some formulaic approach to the
territory and that is not and that the
idea is that that elevates your
character to the point where you can
withstand tragedy and malevolence
without becoming corrupt and that
provides a permanent solution to the
problem.
Well then you might say,
cynically,
what's your evidence that that's a
permanent solution and answer that is
while the evidence isn't all in yet,
first of all,
because people only live that way
partially and so we haven't put the
hypothesis to the full test and second,
we don't know what our limitations are.
We have no idea what our limitations are
and they're.
They're both greater and lesser than we
imagined because you know,
you have to ask yourself like if people
stopped adding voluntarily to the misery
of the world and devoted themselves to
setting things straight,
setting themselves straight and setting
the things around them straight,
what would happen and the answer to that
is,
well,
there'd be a hell of a lot less
unnecessary misery in the world.
So that might not be a bad place to
start.
But apart from that,
there's very little that we can say,
could we overcome the catastrophe of
mortality?
Why not?
You think that's beyond our capacity?
Could we make the world a place where no
one was suffering anymore than necessary
and still allow the world to exist?
Well,
possibly because we don't know the
limitations of our capacity.
We're only running it 40 percent if
that.
I would say if we don't make full use of
all the people that are in the world,
we don't have our situation set up so
that the gifts that they could offer to
everyone are fully realized.
We haven't set the systems up for that
yet,
so we waste people like mad and then we
waste ourselves like mad and so I would
say this is something also.
That's one of the things that's really
interesting about the Old Testament
Jews.
This is,
I think one of the reasons that their
book has become so central is because
what happens in the old testament after
the fall is that Israel produces a
series of states,
right?
Rise of state and then a fall and then a
rise of another state and then a fall.
So it's the same thing except it's
happening at a political level.
The political state rises,
it gets corrupt,
it falls,
it rises out of the ashes again,
gets corrupt and falls.
I think that happened six times in the
old testament and one of the things
that's very interesting is the reaction
of the Jews.
They always say it was our fault.
Instead of taking the Cain and Abel
route,
so we're not going to tell you that
Kayden enabled story right away.
Instead of taking the Cain and Abel
route,
they always say,
if the state collapsed,
it was because we did something wrong.
That's very different than saying,
you know,
it's arbitrary fate.
It's the nature of arbitrary fate or the
structure of reality that we're doomed
to collapse into chaos and that's an
indication of the corruption of being.
While you can take that route if you
want,
it's the corruption of being well,
good luck with that.
So what are you going to do about that?
That's easy start.
You'll start to work for the destruction
of being.
That's what you will do.
The alternative is to say,
this terrible thing happened and somehow
it's my fault.
Well,
at least that really opens you up to the
pathway to doing something about it and
maybe it's actually the case may be
terrible things happen because you're
just not who you should be.
At least it's a night,
you know?
That's true to some degree,
right?
You'd know it because things happen to
you all the time and you think,
well,
you know,
if I just would've played that game
straight,
if I were to put this thing in order,
that wouldn't have happened.
It's like,
okay,
fine.
What's the ultimate extent of that?
Dostoyevsky said at one point that every
human being was not only responsible for
everything that happened to him or her,
but also simultaneously responsible for
everything that happened to everyone
else.
Now it's a very,
it's A.
I would say it's almost a hallucinogenic
idea,
right?
It's a,
it's a transcendent idea and it can go
very wrong.
Sometimes depressed people,
for example,
get hyper responsible for what's
happened and just crushes them.
And so it's,
it's a,
it's a mode of thinking that can produce
its attendant pathologies,
but there's something about it that's,
there's something about it that's
metaphysically true.
So.
Alright,
so I'm going to tell you the story of
Cain and Abel.
Now I really liked this story.
It's,
it's,
it's very short.
It's only about a paragraph long,
which is very interesting because it.
It's one of these examples where it's
like a genie.
That story,
there's so much condensed into it that
it's almost unbelievable and there's
even ambiguity condensed into it,
which is,
which is very,
very interesting because it actually
makes the story more complex and
sophisticated.
So let me tell you the story now.
The first thing I want to tell you some
things about the story first,
so we've got the original paradisical
state and then the collapse and so now
metaphysically speaking,
we're in,
we're in the collapse.
We're in when we're in the post fall
condition were still occupying a
mythological landscape,
right?
This isn't history as we normally
understand it.
It's at history,
so when we talk about Cain and Abel,
Cain and Abel were actually talking
about the first two real human beings
because Adam and eve,
they were created by God and being we're
in paradise,
and so that's not the normative
condition of human beings,
right?
That's a.
that's a special time.
That's outside of normal time and space.
Cane enabled by contrast there in
history because in some sense,
history actually starts a couple of
times in the Old Testament,
right?
It starts with the creation of being.
It starts with the formation of the
garden.
It starts with the fall.
It starts with Cain and Abel.
It starts over again with Noah,
and then it starts with Abraham,
which is really where what we would
recognize more as conventional history
begins,
so there's a number of starts of
history,
but this is one of the Cain and Abel are
the first two human beings.
Who are they?
They're the adversarial brothers,
hero and adversary there types of Christ
and Satan,
so well known supposition.
You see that hostile brother Motif,
while it's an architectural motif and
the hostile brothers are the part of you
that's striving for the light,
that's one half and the part of you
that's embracing the darkness,
and so that's part of you.
It's part of the social structure.
That's seth and Cyrus.
It's part of the natural order in some
sense.
That's the benevolent and destructive
elements of nature,
right?
You see that negativity running through
all the architectural representations,
but cain and Abel are the hostile
brothers and the Kay Kane is roughly
that part of you that says,
Oh,
to hell with it and means it right,
and that means you will work for your
own pain and destruction at the same
time that you're working for the pain
and destruction,
not only of your brother,
but all but more particularly of the
brother that you admire because that's
actually a lot more entertaining,
right?
If you're gonna become destructive and
you go destroy something bad that hardly
qualifies as destruction.
What you want to do is find something
great and destroyed that.
That's destruction,
that's revanche.
None of this putting punishment where it
deserves to be.
What you want to do,
and this is partly why the story of
Christ is archetipal and archetipal
stories.
When you cannot push beyond what's the
worst possible punishment,
what's the worst possible punishment
meted out for the least the least,
the most innocent person.
You hit an archetypical and there so you
define most innocent person.
You can do that anyway.
You want to find most innocent person.
Define worst possible punishment,
conjoin the two things.
You get an archetypal story and the
reason for that is you can't push beyond
it,
and so if you want to destroy something,
you want to destroy an ideal,
not something that's flawed,
and so cain and Abel are set up exactly
that way.
So I'll read you the story and I'll
interleave some interpretations along
with it.
So,
and Adam knew eve,
his wife,
and she conceived and bore Cain and
said,
I have gotten demand from the Lord,
and she again bare his brother Abel and
Abel was a keeper of sheep,
but Cain was a tiller of the ground.
Okay,
so April's a shepherd and Cain is a
farmer.
The shepherd is a archetypal symbol
because the shepherd is the leader of a
flock and the shepherd is the heroic
leader of a flock.
And the reason this is Middle Eastern
mythology,
let's say,
well,
if you were a shepherd,
what did you do?
You took your slingshot in your stick
and you defended your nice,
juicy,
plump,
delicious sheep against Lions,
right?
So it was no joke,
man,
you,
you were a tough cookie if you were a
shepherd because while you were acting
as the guardian of of that,
you're acting as the Guardian against
predation,
roughly speaking,
and you aren't armed very well.
I mean,
well you can just think about it for a
minute.
It's time to think about fighting off a
lion with a,
with a slingshot or with a bow and Arrow
or with a spear.
I mean you have to have a lot of courage
to manage that,
especially successfully.
So Abel was a keeper of sheep and Cain
was a tiller of the ground,
which isn't as heroic role.
And so right off the bat,
you get this dichotomy between the two
roles.
It's also of great interest that Cain is
the older brother and Abel is the
younger brother.
And you see that very frequently in
mythology because the older brother is
the one that's privileged by status,
right?
So he's got.
He's got privilege,
Kate,
because he's the elder brother.
That also means that if there are
possessions to be handed down to
generations,
the older brother gets them.
Now,
interestingly enough,
pain has privileged,
but he's not the one that's favored by
God.
That and I think that's absolutely it's
absolutely brilliant that it's set up
that way because it's actually able.
Who doesn't have the right that the
first board has who actually turns into
the person who's the proper
manifestation of the ideal?
It's because cane has things given to
them.
You might think,
well that's great.
He's privileged.
What a wonderful thing for cane.
It's like,
don't be so sure about that and partly
because one of the things that you'll
find because of many of you will be well
off when you have children is one of the
problems with being reasonably wealthy
when you have children,
is that you deprive them of privation
because a lot of what makes people
mature is necessity and if you have,
for example,
if you have more money than you know
what to do with roughly speaking,
it's very difficult to say no to your
children when they want something
because why are you going to say no?
You can just provide it.
Well,
what makes you think that that's what
you should do,
but you can have anything you want.
Well,
what happens?
You devalue what you want and your
desires continued to grow.
Well,
that's not very helpful,
so it's not obvious at all that
providing people with an excess,
let's say a privilege is something
that's good for them from a
psychological perspective.
They need to hit the proper limitations
and if you're a fortunate,
it becomes very difficult to deprive
your children properly,
so you'll,
you'll fight with that.
It's a big problem and that's what
happens when you get spoiled children
roughly speaking,
right?
They get every.
They get everything by doing nothing.
Well,
that's not a good lesson because that
won't work in the world.
It'll work very counterproductive.
Lee,
and in process of time,
it came to pass that cain brought of the
fruit of the ground and offering unto
the Lord and Abel.
He also brought of the firstlings of his
flock and of the fat thereof,
and the Lord had respect unto Abel and
his offering,
but unto Cain and his offering,
he had no respect and Cain was very
wroth angry and his countenance fell.
Okay,
so again,
there's a tremendous amount packed into
that.
This is the first time that we see the
motif of sacrifice.
Right?
And so I mentioned to you before how
these archaic people conceptualize the
world,
right?
It's a dome with a disk of land and
underneath that a disc of water fresh
and underneath that a disc of salt
water.
So that's the world.
And then up in the heavens,
that's where God is.
And so God's up in the sky.
And we talked about why that might be
and part of that is,
well,
when you look at the night sky,
you look at what transcends your current
reality and you look at what inspires
our.
So there's a,
God exists where all is experienced,
fine.
That's a perfectly reasonable.
That's a perfectly reasonable hypothesis
when you think that what you're trying
to do is formulate what constitutes the
transcendent.
Because if you exist within a conceptual
structure and you encountered that which
is outside the conceptual structure,
you will feel all and that's a
combination of fear paralysis,
right?
And the combination of overwhelming
possibility and you can experience that.
For example,
if you listen to a great piece of music,
what happens?
The hair on the back of your neck stands
up.
Why?
Because you're a prey animal and you
just puffed up to look bigger.
That's why you have that experience is
pilot erection and it's part of all.
So when you see a cat puff up,
because a big dog is in front of it,
that's what the cats feeling.
It's like,
oh my God,
puff.
Right?
So when you encountered that,
which transcends your,
your limited sphere of apprehension than
you experienced,
or you look at the night sky,
that's what happened.
Music can do that.
And all sorts of things that we do can
evoke that sense.
And so they located the transcendent
value in that which inspired off fight
reasonable.
Now you can argue about the utility of
the personification,
right?
Because God,
the father was personified in human
form,
but that's a very sophisticated idea too
because as we already found in the Old
Testament,
there is an association between whatever
God is Yahuah or below him and and
creating order out of chaos and
something about each individual human
being and so I don't believe that the
personification of God,
the father in the Old Testament is
archaic and primitive at all.
I think it's one of the most
sophisticated things that people ever
developed.
The idea is that the ultimate
transcendent value is the capacity to
generate order out of chaos using
linguistic ability,
let's say,
and that each person has that as an
essential element of their being.
It's like argue with fat far you get
that is one hell of a vicious
conceptualization and I would also say
it's the bedrock upon which our legal
system rests so you don't move that
easily.
You move that and many things fall and
there are things that you may say you
don't believe,
but you act them out all the time.
In fact,
if you didn't act them out,
people would set you straight very,
very rapidly because basically what
other people want from you,
even though they don't conceptualize it
in this terms,
is that you accord them the respect due
the the incarnation of the logos.
That's exactly what it means to interact
with someone properly.
So it's you can say what you want about
what you believe.
It doesn't matter what matters is what
you act out.
All right,
so,
oh,
so now we have this conceptualization of
what's transcendent that's emerged as a
part partially perhaps as emotional
contagion,
that which inspires awe is that which is
transcendent and it's associated with
these underlying ideas about the
creation of order out of chaos and the
instantiation of that spirit in human
beings.
That's all lurking in the background,
and then we have this other idea which
we already talked about,
which is that there is a patriarchal or
paternal spirit that represents the
community at large,
stretched across time.
You can think about that as the spirit
of the ancestors,
so it's the past.
It's the president,
but that's also projected into the
future.
That's the thing,
you bargain with four year life in the
future,
I'm going to sacrifice myself to get a
degree.
Why is that?
Because the spirit of my culture will
reward me in the future.
That's the sacrifice.
Okay?
Well,
it doesn't people.
We were chimpanzees for God's sake.
It took us a long time to figure this
out.
Chimpanzees,
don't sacrifice the present for the
future.
You know,
you gotta ask yourself,
how long did it take human beings to
figure out that there was a future and
then what to do about it?
I mean,
this isn't something we didn't go from
chimpanzees to fully articulated human
being in one,
in one step.
It was created knowledge in that was
extraordinarily painful.
What did we learn from observation?
Something like storing up goods for the
future helps us live.
Imagine how difficult that is.
You know,
marriage and that you're a,
you're a farmer.
Back when it was an extraordinarily,
you are barely scraping out a living
doing that.
It was hand to mouth at best.
All right,
so now it's winter and you've got your
damn seeds in your cellar,
right?
What are you going to do?
You're starving,
you can eat them,
or are you going to wait and plant them
again in the spring because that's your
damn choice,
and so the people who decided to eat
them while some of the people who
decided to save them died,
well,
let's say more of the people who decided
to eat them died and so this sort of
knowledge was was gathered in
unbelievable agony.
You don't get what what you have what
you want right now for you.
That's nothing because you're very much
accustomed to getting what you want all
the time right now,
roughly speaking,
compared to people who live from hand to
mouth,
but back when things were much rougher,
the idea that you had to sacrifice
something of value now to be paid off in
the future.
Man,
that was a rough thing to accept.
Okay,
so what happened?
So people figured this out.
Somehow they figured out that you could
make an offering of something you valued
and that might help set the world
straight.
How do they conceptualize that?
While they conceptualized it ritually,
they were acting it out to begin with.
It's like the Piagetian idea,
you know when I,
when I look at that top part of the
looking is this right?
It's the adjustment of my body to the
shape of the Cup as part of my
understanding.
Well,
Piaget's PA,
one IMPINJ's great observations is that
we use our bodies to represent things
long before we understand what it is
that we're representing,
which is to say no more than we act
things out were dramatic creatures,
right?
We use drama and the the sacrificial
ritual is a drama that points to a
higher psychological truth and the
higher psychological truth is let go of
what's him let go of what you value now
and perhaps that will pay off multi
manifold in the future.
You're making a bargain and then you
might say,
well,
who are you making a bargain with?
And you could say,
well nature,
but that's not exactly right.
It's not exactly right because let's say
I have something of value in the social,
in the social organization and I'm going
to.
I'm going to let it go because I'm.
I'm relying on a corresponding reward or
a greater reward in the future.
It's a contractual relationship with
other people.
It's not a relationship with nature,
it's that we've organized ourselves into
a social structure and we're willing to
maintain the integrity of the social
structure across time so that if I give
up something now,
I can be paid for it in the future,
and the rule of the deal is that we're
going to try to keep the future the same
as the president so that those contracts
can be,
can be met in the future.
That's money.
That's what money is,
right?
Here's some money.
You've made a sacrifice.
That's why you get the money.
What is the money signify?
It's a promise from the community that
the Labor that you invested,
we can be stored and then brought
forward for your own purposes in the
future.
So it's actually part of the social
contract.
So the thing you're sacrificing to is
the spirit of society that produces the
social contract,
and so that's conceptualized as God the
father.
Well,
how else would you conceptualize it?
It's,
it's the spirit of the dominance
hierarchy.
That's the right way to think about it.
So it's the.
It's what's common across all the
members of the dominance hierarchy
across time.
Well,
it's something you can negotiate with
true or not,
but what the hell do you think you're
doing when you make a contract?
What's the law?
It's all of this.
It's the manifestation of that
patriarchal spirit across time and space
and what do you do?
You sacrifice to it.
Well,
so back 40,000
years ago,
5,000
however old the story as it's probably
older than that,
this is the best people could do with
regards to realization and they go to
quite right because they also noted that
God was happier if you actually
sacrificed something of value and so
there's a tremendous complexity and not
idea because one of the things I could
say,
and this is something you've pointed
out,
let's say you're miserable and unhappy.
Okay,
here's a cure.
Find what's valuable and let it go.
So we could say,
well,
maybe it's a relationship that you have.
Maybe it's relationship with your
parents,
right?
And the relationship is pathological,
but you're locked into it.
You value it and no wonder because it's
a relationship with your parents and
your suffering terribly because of it.
Well,
what do you do?
Maybe you let it go.
It's a sacrifice and the idea is that,
well,
that'll clear the future for you.
Well,
very frequently when people are
suffering terribly,
not always because sometimes you just
suffer stupidly,
blindly and without recourse,
you know you get cancer and then you
die,
so we have no idea how to deal with
that,
but sometimes the reason that you're
suffering is because you just won't let
go of the thing that's biting you and
you think,
well,
I can't let go of on and I've had
clients like this.
I can't stop communicating with my
mother who phones me three times a day
everyday of my life and never says
anything that isn't unbelievably
critical and demeaning.
I can't let that go.
It's like,
wow,
that's not such a good idea.
The funny thing too,
often when people let something like
that go,
it goes away,
sorts itself out and then comes back so
they don't even end up losing it,
but unless they're willing to let it go
to sacrifice that they make no headway
whatsoever.
And so one of the rules is if people are
impeding your development,
you sacrifice your relationship with
them,
right?
It's a very,
very rough rule.
So
in process of time it came to pass that
cain brought of the fruit of the ground
and offering unto the Lord and Abel.
He also brought of the firstlings of his
flock and of the fat thereof.
Now that's interesting.
This is,
this is where a close reading matters,
so we don't know what Kane's offering
is.
It's not much described,
but we do know something about ables
offering and what we know is that by the
standards of the time,
it's a high quality offering.
So it's the firstborn and it's the fat
high calorie,
right?
I mean,
you know,
we think of fat as a dietary danger,
but if you're hungry,
that's really wrong,
right?
Because fat is unbelievably high
calorie,
and so what's happening is the story
points out quite clearly that what able
decides to offer to God is of high
quality.
So it's the real thing.
It's the real thing.
He,
he's,
he's paying a price.
Okay.
And so then it's burned.
While why is it burned?
Well,
you know,
this is back again thinking from an
archaic perspective.
Well,
gods in the sky,
you can't throw your lamb up into the
sky,
it'll just fall back down and so,
but people knew because they've mastered
fire that smoke and savor rose and so
you can detect the quality of an
offering as a consequence of burning.
And then that would go up in the spirit
of the fire would go up to the sky and
God could detect whether or not you're
offering was of reasonable quality.
You know,
it's concretized obviously,
but you don't want to make the
assumption that the people who were our
forebears were stupid just because they
thought using metaphors that aren't the
same as our metaphors.
They were still mapping out the damn
territory.
You know,
and,
and you look,
you can read a book like you're above
the authors of the book or you can read
a book as if it might have something to
teach you.
And I would say,
well sometimes the book isn't worth
reading,
but if a book has been around for a very
long period of time and a very large
number of people have thought that
perhaps there's something in it.
Sometimes they're right.
So,
and it's a tricky thing and it might
also depend on how you read it,
but I've found that this sort of
investigation was a lot more useful if I
started from the presupposition that
maybe there was something I didn't know.
Instead of,
you know,
so funny.
For example,
I taught a first year course about 10
years ago on the psychology of religion
and it was so interesting dealing with
the 18 year old students because they
are completely dismissive of religious
ideas.
And I thought,
God,
you guys,
you don't know anything yet.
You have this specific kind of blindness
that a set of very intelligent social
psychologists also identified,
which was blindness blindness.
Because it actually turns out that the
least,
the less you know about a topic,
the more you'll overestimate the quality
of your knowledge.
And so I thought,
well,
we're,
we're in this situation where kids who,
who don't even know how to act in the
world,
they don't know anything,
will come to university and start off
with a proposition that they're astute
critics of Judeo Christian culture,
which of which they know nothing.
They know nothing about it.
They knew nothing about history.
They know nothing about philosophy,
nothing about literature,
but they're absolutely certain that
they're correct there in the criticisms
that they're bringing forth.
It's absolutely unbelievable.
So anyways,
and it's not helpful because then you
don't,
you don't get to learn and you want.
Well she,
you know what happens if you don't
learn.
Okay.
So anyway,
so it looks like ables doing a good job.
That's the implication.
The story doesn't say Abel is doing a
really good job with his sacrifices.
It just hints at it.
And I liked that because.
Because it leaves that ambiguity.
It's like maybe you're working really
hard and your brother's working really
hard and you really can't tell the
difference between your quality of work
and his quality of work,
but for some reason he succeeding like
map that happens,
right?
Because there's an arbitrary element to
life.
And so the story he says,
well the Lord has respect unto Abel and
his offering and there's an implication
that maybe the reason for that is that,
you know,
canes offerings are a little second
rate,
but the story doesn't come over and out
and club you over the head with that
idea.
It just leaves it as a,
as an ambiguous possibility.
And the reason for that is sometimes you
make sacrifices and maybe they're even
real ones and they don't pay off or they
pay off for someone better.
And so there is this arbitrary nature of
that the transcendent that you're
attempting to deal with it rewards and
doesn't reward more or less of its own
accord or there's an element of that.
And so it's ambiguous in the text even
though there's a hint that perhaps Abel
is doing a better job than kate.
So I like that.
I think it's very sophisticated.
So what happens?
Well,
Kane makes his offerings and God isn't
happy with them.
Now we don't know how cain figures out
that God isn't happy with his offerings.
We get some hints of that too.
But the story does tell us that's what
happens.
And so then we get the psychological
response on the part of cane.
Now one response could be,
Jesus,
I must be doing something wrong.
I better straighten myself out,
you know,
I better come up with a better quality
offering and try that again.
That isn't what happens.
What happens instead is that cane
becomes angry wroth and his countenance
fault.
And so what does that mean?
It means this,
right?
It means he is not happy.
He's angry and out for revenge.
And so one of the,
I've been thinking about this a lot
lately with regards to the literature on
inequality because there's a very good
literature that shows,
for example,
that there's,
there's a,
there's a measure called the Gini
Coefficient and the Gini Coefficient is
a numerical index of the relative
inequality of a geographical locale.
So for example,
if you went to Newfoundland where
everyone is roughly not very rich or
North Dakota,
say almost everyone there is say lower
middle class,
something like that,
or upper working class,
something like that.
Very little variability,
low Gini Coefficient,
okay?
And if you go to Miami Beach,
say where everyone's rich,
low gini coefficient,
because it isn't an index of absolute
wealth or absolute poverty,
it's an index of relative poverty.
And so if everyone's rich,
the relative poverty is low,
and if everyone's poor,
the relative poverty is low.
Now one question is where's the crime?
And you might think,
well,
the crime is where the absolute poverty
is high,
right?
Or the absolute wealth is low.
That's where the crime is.
That's wrong.
If it's.
If things are relatively distributed in
an egalitarian manner,
the male on male crime,
especially homicide is low and it's also
the case where everyone is rich.
But if you go into places where there
some rich people but not very many,
and there's a lot of people who are
comparatively poor than the male
homicide rates,
rates and violent crime rates amp up
substantially.
And it's a consequence of male on male
competition,
and so what you could derive from that
and maybe even reasonably is that you
should flatten out the damn income into
distribution because you're
destabilizing the society by
facilitating male criminal aggression.
You can make a good case for that.
You know,
in,
in places like Columbia where the Gini
Coefficient got unbelievably extreme,
society got so violent that it could
barely hold itself together.
So,
so you,
you can make a conservative argument for
redistribution of income using the
observation that if the income
distribution gets too extreme,
the whole bloody thing starts to
destabilize.
It might fall,
but,
but then you also might say,
well wait a minute,
is it any quality that's driving the
violence or is it resentment of the
inequality that's driving the violence?
Now,
that's a tough question because you
might say,
well,
what if the game is rigged and there's
no way of moving up the power hierarchy?
Well then maybe anger and,
and the desire for revolution is the
appropriate response.
But that doesn't really mean to me that
the response should be that sort of
thing that you see in hygienic
coefficient neighborhoods,
which is interracial,
intra racial violence between men.
So for example,
in neighborhoods where there's high
murder rates,
the murders are always between young men
and they're always within race.
And so that doesn't seem to me to be
exactly a politically revolutionary
move,
right?
It's more like it's more like a violent
competition for the sake of,
of,
of attaining status.
And you might say,
well that's reasonable,
but because the inequality is there and
men need to find status because it's
part of what drives them forward.
It's part of what makes them attractive
to women.
It's a necessity.
Well,
the question is,
do you attain status through destruction
or do you start making your offerings,
putting your offerings in order?
And that's something we really need to
figure out because that's a fundamental
political question.
It's a fundamental political question.
Anyways.
What happens in this story is that cane
decides that the fact that God isn't
accepting his offerings means that he's
entitled to become angry and,
and,
and negative.
It's those two things or both put
together,
right.
He's raw,
he's angry,
and he's also depressed and so he's in a
state of mind that,
well,
I think the best characterization for
that is hostile resentment because it's
unfair.
It's like,
yeah,
it's unfair,
so what going to do about it?
Can you get destructive about it?
Are going to change your approach?
Well,
Kane,
he does the ultimate thing and this is
what people do when they do the ultimate
thing because that kind of hostile
resentment has an architectural end
point and the architectural end point is
the point that you get when you're
hostile and resentful because you
haven't been successful and then you go
sit in your mother's basement for about
10 years and then you start imagining
just how nice it would be if you shut up
the local high school so that everybody
knew your name and what happens is you
go from I'm irritated because things
aren't working out for me very well too.
I'm irritated.
Nine and a hate.
Those people for whom things are working
out well too.
I'm irritated and I hate the fact that
the world is set up so that this has
happened to me and then you go to well
because I'm irritated and hate the
world.
I'm going to do whatever I can that will
destroy most rapidly and with the,
with the highest possible amount of pain
and suffering conceivable and at that
point then you don't just go shoot up
the high school.
You go up and shoot up the elementary
school and so if you're wondering what
kind of pathway people walk down to get
to that point,
that's the pathway and the ultimate cap
of that as well.
I'll,
I'll get,
I'll kill the kids because.
Well we already know that killing the
innocent,
there's a lot more effective than
killing the guilty and then just to cap
it off,
I'll blow my head off at the end just to
show you just how God damn pointless it
all is.
And so that's the logical extension of
keynes attitude and you might think,
well that's a bit of an overriding and I
will say it's not an overriding and all.
It's exactly what happens in the text.
So it's exactly what follows it so far.
So Kane is not happy.
And so who was he not happy with?
Well,
he's not happy with God.
And so what does that mean?
Well,
we've already unpacked this.
He's not happy with the social contract
because that's part of the spirit,
the patriarchal spirit,
let's say.
Then there's more to it than that
because we already,
we've already analyzed what God,
the idea of God might represent in the
background of this story.
He's not happy with the transcendent.
He's not happy with the idea of the
logos,
all of that.
No faith in the transcendent,
nothing but he does nothing but despise
the social contract.
And he's got no faith whatsoever in the
logo.
So let's say the word that brings chaos
out of order,
he's all got nothing but contempt for
all of that.
And you know,
certainly,
you know,
people like that and if you don't know
them,
you just go on youtube and read the
comments and you'll see all sorts of
people like that.
So.
So anyways,
so God has a little chat with him and he
says,
well,
W W,
why are you angry and and why?
Why are you upset?
And cain says,
and God says,
if you do well,
won't you be accepted?
And if you don't do well,
sin lies at your door and unto thee
shall be his desire and thou shalt rule
over him.
Okay?
That's a very mangled translation I
would say.
So I'm going to take it apart.
So what God says is while you're angry
and you're upset,
it's like,
well,
what's your problem?
And then God tells kate if you did
things properly,
they would work out for you.
Well,
it's the last thing he wants to hear it
because what cain wants to believe is
that the reason he's not doing very well
is because there's no sense having any
faith in the logos.
The transcendent is,
is evil and aimed exactly against him.
And the entire social contract is
faulty.
That's what he wants to hear,
but that isn't what God says.
God says,
well,
wait a minute,
maybe you're doing something wrong.
Well,
that's maybe a worse message than
everything else is corrupt.
It's like you're having a problem
because you're just not everything you
could be.
Well,
and then God says something really nasty
and you can't tell from this lines.
I read a bunch of translations to try to
figure out exactly what it meant.
So this is what God tells kate.
He says,
you're in a room in a house and there's
something at the door,
and he uses a metaphor.
God uses metaphor.
It's a sexually aroused predatory cat
and you invited in even invited.
Did you know that it has evil intent.
You invited in to mate with you,
right?
And you're.
It's,
it's union with you.
This,
this malevolent force,
this sexual union with you has produced
an offspring and that offspring is what
possesses you.
And so not only have you done something
wrong,
you've,
you've invited the spirit of wrong doing
into your life and you creatively
intermingled it with it voluntarily to
bring forth a monster of your own
creation.
So that's what God tells Kane.
So like,
look,
it's bad enough that God says,
you know,
you should get your act together because
maybe that's why things aren't going so
well for you before you criticize the
transcendent and the world and the
structure of being.
Maybe you're doing something wrong,
but it's worse than that.
He says,
not only are you doing something wrong,
you bloody well know you're doing
something wrong and you and you're doing
it creatively and with intent,
so not only are things not going well
for you,
but you've played a creative role in
producing that situation and so god
basically says,
I am taking zero responsibility for
rejecting your sacrifice.
It's all on you.
And so kane leaves and he's like,
seriously?
Not Happy with that response because he
wanted to hear Pat,
pat,
you're a victim of circumstance and
everything's conspiring against you.
And really being God,
I should get my act together and just
give you what you want.
Because obviously being God I'm wrong
and you're right.
Well that isn't what happens.
It's exactly the opposite of that.
It's completely on you.
That's the,
that's the judgment.
And so kane leaves and believe me,
he's,
he was wroth before it.
His countenance had fallen before,
but it's nothing like it is now.
And so he's hits the next stage and he
thinks,
okay,
I'm going to take my revenge.
What am I going to do?
I'm going to find the most innocent and
worthwhile thing that's favored of God
and I'm going to kill it.
And that's what he does.
And it doesn't matter.
That's his brother and able.
We know we're drawing the inference.
Ables done the right things.
Everyone likes him.
Everything's flourishing for Abel.
He's a good guy.
He's one of those people that you meet
that has everything,
and then you meet them and you wish you
could hate them,
but you can't because they're really
good people.
And then you're really hate them because
not only do they have everything,
but it appears that they deserve it.
And there's nothing that sort of sits in
your soul and rots it more than that
realization.
And so that's the situation with Cain.
And cain thinks Cain talked with Abel,
his brother,
and it came to pass when they were in
the field that Cain rose up against
Abel,
his brother,
and slew him.
So that's so interesting because look,
look what happens to cane here.
So he's not doing well.
He's separated from the transcendent and
from society.
He's bitterly resentful and now he goes
out and kills the very thing that he
most wants to be.
So he destroys his own ideal,
right?
He just demolishes his own ideal.
That's how far his resentment has pushed
him.
And so he's,
he's done right?
But it doesn't matter because it enables
them to take revenge.
So he doesn't care.
It's like,
it's like the suicidal school shooter
that blows off his head at the end of
his mayhem.
It's like it doesn't matter to him.
It's part of the same art form.
And the Lord says unto Cain,
where is Abel lie brother?
And cain said,
I know.
I don't know.
Am I my brother's keeper?
While that's a good question,
and that's why it's posed in the story,
because they answered that it's supposed
to be yes.
And God says,
what have you done?
The Voice of your brother's blood cries
unto me from the ground.
That's actually the Motif that
Dostoevsky explorers,
I would say in crime and punishment,
because what happens is that was calling
the coffee's cane for all intents and
purposes,
and he commits a murder,
but he gets away with it well,
so he thinks so.
He thinks no one suspected.
He buries the money.
He can't stand to touch the body.
He buries it in a in an abandoned lot,
and he's drawn there now and then to
look at where it is,
but he can't touch it because the money.
It's so funny because the money before
he kills the pawnbroker is not the same
as the money after he kills the pawn
broker.
And the risk only cough before he kills
the pawnbroker is not the same as the
risk and cost after he kills the pole
broker.
In fact,
they're not the same at all.
And so the scarlet macaw is tormented by
God,
you could say,
but not from the external world.
He sets the crime up quite nicely.
It's that this,
this spirit against which he
transgressed,
tortures him from within and there's no
escape from it,
and so eventually what happens in crime
and punishment is was called Nicole.
Cough continues to manifest himself as
guilty in every possible way until he
receives the punishment that he desires
because it's the only way that he can
set things right.
He actually,
he actually,
he essentially turns himself in
eventually because he can't tolerate
what he's done so well.
So that's the idea.
The Voice of your brother's blood cries.
I'm to me from the ground.
It's guilt and now you're cursed from
the earth which has opened her mouth to
receive your brother's blood from thy
hand.
When you till the ground,
it will not henceforth yield to you its
strength,
a fugitive and a vagabond,
shall thou be in the earth,
you know?
And you might say,
well why does God not just strike caden
dead?
And answer to that perhaps is that
wouldn't be sufficient punishment.
That's what it looks like to me.
It's like what's the punishment?
You live with what you did.
Right?
And I don't want anybody taking you out
either because then you won't have to
live with what you did.
So that's the punishment.
And cain says unto the Lord,
my punishment is greater than I can
bear.
It's like,
yeah,
behold you have driven me out this day
from the face of the earth and from thy
face shall I be here.
That's the same as what happens to Adam
in the garden of Eden.
Remember,
Adam hides from God and he has his
reasons.
And now cain is alienated from God.
There's no real,
there's no reconstructing that
relationship he's put himself by
violating his contract,
but say with the transcendent and also
with society and also with his own
spirit,
he's put himself outside the possibility
of redemption.
And that's why he says the punishment is
greater than I can bear.
There's no hope left,
right?
So he's in hell for all intents and
purposes,
behold,
that has driven me out to stay from the
face of the earth and from thy face
shall I be hidden.
I shall be a fugitive and a vagabond in
the earth.
And it shall come to pass that everyone
who finds me will kill me,
and God says,
therefore whoever slayeth Cain,
vengeance shall be taken on him.
Seven fold.
And the Lord set a mark onto Cain,
lest any finding him should kill him.
Now,
that's interesting.
And you think,
why in the world would God protect cane?
Well,
the next part of the story actually
tells you that you have a family.
I have a family.
Your brother kills my son.
So what do I do?
I come and I kill your father and your
cousin and then you think,
well,
I killed your father and your cousin.
I'm going to come back and I'm going to
kill four of your people.
And then I come back and say,
yeah,
no problem.
It's 16 to you this time.
And then you come back and you say,
16 a,
let's try for 32.
And so this is what happens.
This is actually why justice systems are
set up by the way you go.
There's a bunch of reasons justice
systems are set up and one is to punish
the guilty.
That's one.
The other is to have the guilty repent
that's to to maintain social order.
That's three.
Here's another one that no one ever
thinks about.
Back 30 years ago,
the governor of Massachusetts,
whose name I forget was running for
president,
and while he was governor,
Massachusetts,
he
had released a number of prisoners,
one of whom his name was,
I think Willie Horton.
It doesn't really matter.
And when Willy was released on this
program,
he went out and raped someone and
perhaps killed them.
I can't remember,
but it doesn't matter.
The rape is good enough.
And the governor was asked during a
debate what he would do if a release
prisoner had raped his daughter or his
wife,
and he gave a very weak answer.
Uh,
what was his name?
He gave a very weak answer.
Something about,
you know,
letting the law take its due course.
And that's the wrong answer,
right?
The right answer is I would be compelled
with every fiber of my being to hunt
that person down and to tear them into
bits,
but I won't do it.
Now,
what's,
uh,
what's the purpose of the justice system
is to alleviate you from the
responsibility of revenge.
That's what it's for,
because otherwise what happens,
you kill one.
I killed two.
You kill for kill eight,
you kill 16 and soon everyone's at war.
And so God protects cane to stop that
from happening,
to stop the feud from emerging because
those things can go forever and then
from transforming the entire society
into a state of war.
And so what's also.
So I'll tell you the rest of the story.
And Kane went out from the presence of
the Lord and dwelt in the land of nod on
the east of Eden and Cain knew his wife
and she conceived and bare enoch,
et cetera.
So now you have a genealogy,
right?
So came starts to have a family,
you have a genealogy.
And so a number of people are named in
the lineage.
And so,
and it tells you what,
this is sort of an attempt to describe
how things came about.
So this is like the naming of the heroes
of old.
And so you have a enoch who builds a
city.
You have a gal who is the father of
those who dwell intense,
and of those who have cattle,
you have juvenile who was the father of
of musicians and Zillah who bore
tubilcain.
Tubilcain is a very interesting person
by tradition.
Tubal cocaine is the first artificer of
weapons of war,
so keynes,
descendant after multiple generations is
the person who produces weapons of war.
All right,
and so,
so there's another bit of the story
within which that needs to be placed in
context.
And lamech,
who's one of the grandchildren of Cain
says unto his wife at Wives Adah and
Zillah hear my voice.
You wives of Lamech Hearken unto my
speech for I have slain a man to my
wounding and the young man to my hurt.
Okay,
so what he's saying is he,
he's been involved in a murder if can be
avenged.
Sevenfold truly Lamaq 70 and seven.
And
so there's the implication there that
the tit for tat process has begun.
Cain killed Abel.
Abel Caine's children killed seven
canes,
grandchildren kill 70 fold,
and then tubal cane pops up on the
horizon and he's the person who makes
artifices of war.
And so the story in its fragmentary
manner ties the individual's
psychopathology that's resentful and
revenge seeking to the proclivity for
broad scale warfare.
And this really hit me because I was
interested particularly in what was
happening in the Nazi camps with the
guards because the guards were
gratuitously cruel and I was very
curious about that.
And so here's an interesting story.
This was in a book called a ordinary
Germans,
Hitler's willing executioners.
And it was a book that was written about
30 years ago.
The challenge,
the idea that the Nazi phenomenon was
topped down order following,
which I don't believe,
by the way I think that that's a very
weak,
weak hypothesis.
Fascistic societies are fascistic at
every single level of organization
spiritually within the family,
within the local community.
It's like a holograph.
It's the same,
absolutely everywhere.
It's not top down.
I mean,
there are leaders who get produced and
maybe they catalyze it,
but to blame it on the leaders is to
forget about the process by which the
leaders come to be.
So No,
you don't get a pass that way.
So here's one of the things that
happened,
um,
as the Nazis started to lose the war.
So here's what you should have done.
If you are a Nazi and he wanted to win
the war,
you should have enslaved the Jews and
the Gypsies and had them work right?
You should have had them work for the
benefit of the victory and then if you
wanted to liquidate them afterwards,
that's the logical thing to do.
If you want to win and we assume that
Hitler wanted to win,
but that's not a very intelligent
assumption.
Why would you assume that he wasn't
exactly a good guy?
So why should we assume that he was
aiming at the good that he was
promoting,
even in his own terms,
right?
The glorious everlasting for Third
Reich,
right?
That'll rule for a thousand years and be
a bastion of civilization and music
because that's the sort of thing he
purported to be interested in.
Well,
so what do you do with the Jews and the
Gypsies?
Well,
round them up,
fine.
Enslave them,
You don't kill them.
You certainly don't devote a substantial
proportion of your war resources well,
you're losing to accelerate the rate at
which the extermination is taking place
because that's a bit counterproductive
unless what you're aiming at is the
maximum possible mayhem in the shortest
period of time.
Well,
so what happened as the Germans started
to lose the war,
get Hitler lose faith in his own
ability.
No,
he believed that the Germans had to be
traded with weakness and so he's
perfectly willing to accelerate the rate
at which Germany was losing the war,
and so when Hitler and his minions have
the choice,
here's the choice.
You can suspend your unnecessary
demolition
of people when the damn war and then
pick it up afterwards or while you're
losing.
You can just accelerate the mayhem even
though it's counterproductive.
It's like what'd they pick while they
pick to accelerate the mayhem,
and so to me,
there's an old psychoanalytic idea.
I think this was derived by young.
If you can't figure out what someone is
doing or why,
look at the outcome and infer the
motivation.
If it produces may him.
Perhaps it was aiming at me hip.
Now,
you know,
you have to use that dictum carefully.
If someone's irritating,
you know,
maybe it's because you're irritable,
had you should sort yourself out,
but maybe it's because they're actually
aiming at irritating you and that's the
actual motivation.
So perhaps not,
but it's another tool in your analytical
armament.
So and so you see,
well,
this is the thing about warfare that's
so interesting about,
about,
because you can,
you can attribute it to territoriality.
You can attribute it to a war for
resources.
That's what the,
I would say wretchedly,
simple minded economists presume people
fight over scarce resources.
It's like,
hey,
we're a little bit more sophisticated
than that.
And first of all,
what resources are you talking about?
The bloody anyway,
it had nothing.
They live perfectly well.
What did they have?
Snow and seal,
blubber,
you know,
people can live and unbelievably
deprived conditions,
and so the idea that there are natural
resources that we fight over because
there's a shortage of them is a pretty
oversimplified view of human beings.
It's like,
well,
why do people fight?
Well,
maybe they fight sometimes for good
reasons,
but very,
very frequently they fight for bad
reasons and those bad reasons are our
personal as well as sociocultural and
economic.
You know,
if you were announced a prison guard,
for example,
whatever pathologies you were carrying
around in your destructive little soul,
whatever element of Cain was deeply
embedded in you had the opportunity to
be manifest fully at every moment of
your waking existence.
Right?
You had these people who were completely
beholden to you with no rights
whatsoever,
to whom you could do whatever you're
evil little heart determined think,
well,
maybe that was a motivation for putting
them there to begin with and all the
cover story about,
well,
we're trying to build the Third Reich
and we're trying to stabilize the state
and we're trying to do all these good
things.
Maybe that's just a cover story for the
real motivation,
which is nothing but but what the
construction of death camps had killed 6
million people.
How about that?
And the obliteration of 120 million
people on the planet and the and the and
the and the leaving of European runes.
Maybe that was the motivation or are we
going to attribute to Hitler the highest
possible motives?
Say No,
it's an archetype of manifestation of
cane.
Now he's going to put up a front that
says,
well,
I'm your savior.
It's like,
well,
disruptive people think that Kayden is
their savior.
Let's take a break for 15 minutes.
So okay,
so
the next thing that happens,
these stories were so together,
right?
To make something that resembles a
coherent text and there's this literary
analytic.
No,
there's a literary technique known as
autonomy and autonomy is the
juxtaposition of two things beside one
another with the implication that
because they're juxtaposed,
they are causally,
they're related in some important matter
to one another,
and so the stories are sequenced and the
there's an implicit.
The stories are sequenced in a
particular manner and you might operate
under the assumption that that
sequencing occurred because the
sequencer who was an editor or a group
of editors,
they call that person the redactor,
but they have no idea if it was one
person or many people who organized
these texts into something resembling a
coherent story.
So imagine the story's evolved somewhat
independently and then they were
organized so that they produced what
approximated the coherent narrative.
It's not entirely coherent because there
are paradoxical claims,
say at the level of the sentence.
So for example,
the creation order in the first story of
genesis isn't exactly the same as the
creation order in the second story and
you know people who insist upon the
literal truth of the Bible,
whatever that means is are bothered by
those contradictions and turn themselves
into knots trying to iron them out and
fair enough,
right?
Because you want the story to be
coherent,
but you know that sort of.
It's important,
but it's also beside the point.
You don't want to focus on one level of
analysis at the exclusion of all the
other levels of analysis.
That's probably the right way to think
about it.
Now.
The fact that these stories are
sequenced in a particular manner and
that that kind of makes sense,
implies that there's some sort of
narrative coherence underneath driving
forward.
Otherwise they would be nothing but a
random assemblage of stories and they're
by no means random.
That's for sure.
They're selected and edited and put
together in a particular manner by and
then stored that way and dealt with in a
particular manner by thousands of people
over many,
many years.
What happens after Cain and Abel is
while there's an interlude,
which is this interlude and it's kind of
a bridge and there's a lot packed into
it too,
although I'm not going to take it apart,
very much so,
so this is after after Cain and Abel
Story and it came to pass when men began
to multiply on the face of the earth and
daughters were born unto them,
that the sons of God saw the daughters
of men,
that they were fair and then took them
wives of all which they chose,
and there were giants in the earth in
those days.
And also after that,
when the sons of God came into the
daughters of men and they bare children
to them,
the same became mighty men which are of
old men of renown.
Okay,
so I already pointed out that if you go
back just a little bit,
you see that the descendants of cain are
represented as founders of of
institutions.
Right there are
in our norco builds the city and a and
add a or Jibo who was the father of
those who dwell in tents and of those
who own cattle.
And then there's Jubal who's the father
of all that are musicians and so on.
So one of the things that you see in,
in myths very frequently is that if
there's a pattern of behavior that's
characteristic of the culture,
that pattern of behavior is attributed
to a hero.
Who was in the past who was the first
person who did that?
And so you might say,
well what does that mean?
Well,
it means in part that there was a first
person who did that,
although more likely there was an
assemblage of people who aggregated that
particular ability say the ability to
play music across a very large amount of
time.
But these are preliterate people,
right?
And they're trying to remember the past.
And so what happens,
Mircea Eliade documented this quite
well,
is that that aggregation of people gets
collapsed into a single Meta person.
And that's the hero of old.
And so,
and we already talked about how this
works is that you know there are
admirable people and then you can tell a
story about an admirable person and then
you can extract a story out of the set
of admirable people and you keep
building higher and higher order
admirable people until you extract out
at the top what's ultimately admirable,
and this is actually an indication of
that process.
So curry,
the giants that are being referred to in
this particular phrase,
are they heroes of the past who
established the traditions on which the
society exists.
And so that's all compacted into this
little paragraph.
So this little paragraph here,
there were giants in the earth in those
days and after that,
when the sons of God came into the
daughters of men and they bare children
to them,
the same became mighty men which were of
old men of renown.
While you could hardly say,
I think there's very little difference
between what I just told you and what
this story says mean.
It says it as if it was something that
literally occurred.
But in some sense it doesn't exactly say
that.
It says,
well,
the ancient landscape was the landscape
of heroic adventures.
It's like,
well,
we do that to our own history,
right?
I mean even when we consider it literal
history,
we don't pick people at random to
historicize.
We picked people who had some
substantive impact and tell stories
about them and they're emblematic in
some sense of the spirit of striving
that characterize this humanity.
And so you can't have history without
something pathologization because the
mythologized occurs at the level of the
selection of the entities about which
you're going to weave the historical
tale.
So.
Okay.
So anyway,
so there's little,
there's a little interlude there that,
that talks about the appearance of
heroes in the past,
but then it's just,
that's just done with very,
very rapidly.
And then we move into another story.
This is the story of Noah.
So the way it looks to me is that
the part of genesis that I'm going to
talk to you about ends with the flood
myth and also with the Tower of Babel.
And so the flood myth is the desert
demolition of everything that came
before and the Tower of Babel.
In some sense is exactly the same thing,
so there's too chaotic.
I mean it's like the fall occurs in
stages.
There's paradise and then Adam and eve
fall into culture and then Cain and
Abel.
Cain falls into chaos and then the
entire society falls into chaos and the
flood comes in,
the Tower of Babel is produced,
and then that's the end of the truly
archaic parts of the Bible,
and so what that seems to me,
what's happening,
it's very sophisticated,
is that there's an implicit causal
narrative being warrant woven about the
manner in which Kane responds and the
probability that human beings are going
to deteriorate and the flood is going to
come so and God saw that the wickedness
of man was great in the earth and that
every imagination of the thoughts of his
heart was only evil continually and it
repented the Lord that he had made man
on earth and it grieved him at his heart
while we already encountered a story
like that once already,
right?
That happened in the Marta story where
timeout and ab sue give rise to the
elder gods and they kill app suit,
which was not very smart idea,
right?
They demolished the substructure of
their stable society and of course chaos
comes flooding back.
Well,
what does it mean to say that human
beings,
let's see,
to say that
the wickedness of man was great in the
earth and that every imagination of the
hearts of his thoughts of his heart was
only evil continually is not much
different than to say that people are
acting in a manner that demolishes the
cultural structure.
Now,
we've already even pointed out that the
cultural structure that happens in this
story was produced by the heroic giants
of the past.
Right,
and we've also noted that what Cain is
objecting to in this came like manner is
the social structure which isn't
rewarding and properly and the
transcendence that's above that and the
spirit of logos itself.
He's rejecting all that.
Okay,
so the issue here is that when that sort
of evil is produced exactly as when
Appsu is slade,
slade,
I guess that's right by the,
by the elder.
Gods then all hell breaks loose.
All chaos comes back now.
Tie Matt,
if you remember correctly,
is the god of the salt water goddess of
the salt water,
and so the return of Tire Matt and the
flood,
our mythologically similar ideas.
Now Elliot has taken apart flood myths
from all over the world and he two
brilliant comments about them and
they're also akin to some degree to what
you can see in the Egyptian story about
seth and the corruption of the state.
So because the Egyptians figured out
that there's always a power working
within this state,
let's say that corrupted it.
Now that was set and that was always
working for its overthrow.
It's an idea like Satan and I said that
the word Seth becomes the word Satan
through Coptic Christianity.
So,
so the iliads idea was this,
that things fall apart of their own
accord merely because they age that
that's the first motif in the flood
story.
And that's only to say that if you build
something,
it indicates if you build something and
you just leave it the hell alone,
it will assume not work.
Right?
And that's entropy.
So one of the reasons that the flood
always threatens is merely because of
entropy and you see that reflected in
the Egyptian story because one of the
reasons that,
oh,
cyrus falls prey to seth is because he's
old.
He was a great hero when he was young
and created the Egyptian state,
like the men of renown.
But now he's old and it's worse.
He's willfully blind,
but that's the next thing.
But the fact that he's old is just to
start things fall apart of their own
accord.
So once something is given to you,
you have to maintain it just to ensure
its continued existence.
And so you actually,
you actually have a contract with most
of the things that you own.
It's like a,
it's like a moral contract.
Let's say you have a car or you've
decided that you're going to sacrifice
to have the car and so you've.
You've performed an ethical calculation,
but the car was only worth the sacrifice
as long as it functions as a car.
And so what that means is that to
justify the sacrifice you've made,
to have the car,
you have to maintain the car.
Because otherwise you're acting out the
proposition that the thing that you
sacrificed for actually didn't have any
value and so your obliterating that as a
useful contract and you run into the
situation where the car will just
deteriorate of its own accord and then
you won't have a car at all.
Well,
so let's say,
how do you speed the process by which
your car deteriorates?
Well,
that's easy.
You're driving it along the road and it
starts to make a ticking noise,
tick,
and you think I should go have that
ticking noise checked because you've
heard it and then you think,
no,
it won't matter.
It's like,
yeah,
probably it'll matter.
And what does matter mean while it
matter his mother,
that's chaos to you,
no matter,
but what it means is that that little
ticking noise is the birthplace of tie a
mat in your car.
That's a good way of thinking about it
is that it's your first indication that
the dragon of chaos is going to manifest
itself in your car.
That happens when you.
I've got a funny story about that,
so I had a friend in in graduate school,
someone I really liked,
but I wouldn't call her Mcelliott and
mechanically inclined let's put it that
way and she had an old Honda and those
things were notorious for rusting out.
This is 30 years ago when they were
first produced.
They weren't adapted well to Canadian
winters and we used to go into her car
and her Honda and it got a little on the
scary side because it was so rusty
underneath that you can actually see
through the floorboards and that
actually made me nervous because if you
can see through the floorboards,
that means that they're not really
floorboards.
What they are is like rust and so I
mentioned the fact that that might be a
problem to her a couple of times,
but she was sort of blind about it.
And one day she was driving down St
Lawrence Street in Montreal,
which is the main street running roughly
north and south.
And her hood popped up.
It bent and popped up spontaneously and
so she was really curious about that.
And so she was with this friend of hers
who was just as clueless mechanically as
she was,
which is really quite remarkably
clueless.
And so they pulled off into a service
station and had the guy come out and
look at it and well,
he,
he opened the hood obviously.
And what had happened was the body had
fallen off the frame.
So.
And what had happened was the shock,
which is like supposed to be attached to
the car,
had pushed up through the,
through the,
the hood.
So literally the car body had fallen
onto the ground and.
But she was,
she managed to drive the cart.
Okay.
So look,
that's,
I wouldn't exactly call that willful
blindness because perhaps there is an
element of willful blindness.
She didn't know anything about
mechanics,
but you get the point,
right?
It's like,
let's say she would have been in a fatal
accident.
You might say,
well you can shake your fist at God for
producing the circumstances,
but you know,
the fact that you could see through the
floorboards,
that's probably something that you might
have paid attention to.
And so it's always the question is,
if things fall apart around you,
to what degree is it the mere tendency
of things to degenerate entropically
because they do that of their own accord
or have you sped the probability of
decay by failing to pay attention when a
little snake manifests itself inside
your paradise.
And it's always.
It's always a question.
So here's a.
here's an example,
an interesting example.
I think.
So I thought about the actual floods,
like the New Orleans flood.
Okay.
So New Orleans is built where there are
floods,
everyone knows that and it's a major
port in the United States.
A huge part of American trade goes down
the river to New Orleans.
So there was a reason it was built where
it was,
even though it was a dangerous place to
build it.
And in order to maintain New Orleans,
they had to build these levees that kept
the water back.
Now the American,
what is it?
American Army Corps of Engineers,
if I remember correctly,
it was responsible for building and
maintaining the levies and the dikes.
Okay.
Holland is also built underwater.
As you may or may not know,
and they built huge dykes to keep the
ocean back so they can reclaim the land
and that's basically Holland.
Holland is an unbelievably organized
society and part of the reason is is it
isn't land.
It's underwater and so if you're not
bloody well awake in Holland,
then the ocean comes in and you all
drowned and so the Dutch are very,
very careful about such things and they
build their dikes so that they
calculate storm intensity and then they
calculate the intensity of the worst
storm in 10,000
years and then they build the dikes to
withstand that storm.
The Army Corps of Engineers built the
dikes in New Orleans to withstand the
worst storm in 100 years and they knew
that was insufficient and New Orleans,
Louisiana is an unbelievably corrupt
state and you can't dump money in there
to fix things because people just steal
the money.
So and then nothing gets fixed.
And so then what happens?
There's a hurricane and then what
happens?
There's a flood and everybody says,
why would God send the flood?
And the answer to that is,
well,
was there a flood or where the dikes not
high enough?
And that's what's so interesting is that
it's always,
this is a great father versus great
mother conundrum.
If the system fails,
is it because of the surround
overwhelming the system or is it because
the system was insufficiently awake and
doomed itself?
Okay,
so elliot is take on the flood myth is
this,
God comes along and floods the world
periodically.
Why?
And that that's the catastrophic influx
of chaos,
right?
Chaos will wipe you out from time to
time.
Why?
Well,
entropy does in your conceptual schemes
and your willful blindness speeds the
process.
And remember that's what the Egyptians
said about.
Oh,
Cyrus,
right?
They said he was,
oh,
he was a great king,
a man of renowned,
but he was old,
but he was also willfully blind and it
was the combination of his agent is
willful blindness that allowed seth to
chop them up into pieces and depose him.
And so with that,
fair enough,
it's brilliant,
right?
It's like why does states fall apart?
Because the structures get old and no
one's taken care of them,
and people have their eyes closed and so
it's the same situation.
It's the same situation in the flood
myths.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
things fall apart.
They're going to flood,
but if you were awake enough and you
were on top of it,
then you could continually stave that
off and actually partly what you're
doing because you're alive,
is staving off entropy like you're an
anti and tropic process.
It's a really good definition of life.
There's a great physicist named Erwin
Schrodinger who wrote a book called what
is life,
and that's the fundamental thesis of the
book.
You're always trying to stave off
entropy.
What's the best way to stave off
entropy?
Decay,
chaos.
Keep your eyes open.
That's the rule.
Shut your eyes especially to things you
know.
You should see the flood comes and
that's the evil of man that's laid out
in this story because that's the worst
sort of perhaps it's not the worst.
It's one of the primary sin,
so to speak,
that will bring about the flood.
We already talked about the other things
that characterized canes,
attitude,
so cool,
so God's upset because he had made man
on earth and it grieved him at his
heart,
and God says,
I will destroy man,
whom I've created from the face of the
earth,
both man and beast and the creeping
thing and the fowls of the air for I
repent.
I've made them.
But Noah found grace in the eyes of the
Lord.
Okay,
so that's an interesting thing.
So here what we have is the.
The question is the whole world's in
chaos at this point,
right in this point in the story.
And the chaos is a multiple sorts.
It arose from the fall.
It rose from the emergence of self
consciousness.
It emerged safe.
It rose from the sins of cane,
like things are not going well.
It's multiple levels of collapse and
it's got to the point where God saying
this is a mess,
like it's such a mess that the whole
thing has to be washed away.
The first fall wasn't enough.
Even canes collapse wasn't enough.
We're going to just scrub the whole
bloody thing clean.
So it's,
it's the ultimate in traumatic
collapses.
The question is,
well,
what do you do in the face of the
ultimate in traumatic collapses and the
answers in the story.
So Noah is someone who finds fate,
who finds favor in the eyes of God.
So he's like,
Abel,
there's something that Noah is doing
right.
It's going to enable him to ride out the
storm.
And so the question here,
it's the same question.
Do you want to have a life where there's
newell storms
or do you want to have a life where you
can ride out the storms?
That's the issue,
right?
Are you behind the dikes or do you build
a boat?
Do you captain the boat?
That's the same idea.
So the idea here is that the thing that
rides out the chaos is the thing that
builds and captains the boat.
It's another dominance hierarchy idea.
What should be at the top?
Well,
it's,
it's the top of something that doesn't
get flooded out as well.
What should be at the top?
Well,
it's to be the boat builder and to be
the captain of the boat,
it's not to be hidden from the flood.
Precisely.
And so,
I mean,
here's,
uh,
here's something to think about.
Identity,
identity politics,
because that's what we're up to our neck
in.
Okay?
Are you who you are?
Can I box you it?
Will you accept that as an identity?
So I could do that lots of ways.
You're male,
you're Asia,
you're young,
right?
There's things about you that I can
derive because of your putative
membership in a set of different groups.
The problem with doing that is that the
number of groups that I can assign
youtube is without end.
So I have to pick arbitrary groups to
assign you to and you can accept that if
you want,
but there's no evidence that those are
the proper canonical groups.
But maybe you're happy about that
because now you've been assigned
membership in a group and that's your
identity.
Okay?
So the question is,
well,
fine,
what happens when that identity is flown
into pieces?
Then what?
Well,
here's,
here's the answer to some degree and
this is the answer that's embedded in
the story of Noah.
If you want it withstand chaos.
Do you want to be who you are or do you
want to be the thing that changes who
you are constantly.
That's the question and that's the
difference.
That's the difference.
There's a categorical difference in are
you who you are or are you the thing
that could continually be more than you
are and that's the thing that isn't the
stable identity.
It's not the initial state.
It's also not the state of being in
chaos that nihilistic state,
let's say,
and it's not even the state of
reformulation that occurs after you've
gone through the process.
It's the state of continually going
through the process so you can identify
with the thing that trends you could
identify,
identify with the thing that you are or
you can identify with the thing that
transforms who you are.
Right,
and that's the same as the state
subjugating itself to the individual
because the individual is the thing that
transforms the state and what the state
should do.
The states necessary because obviously
it organizes all of us into peaceful
cooperation and competition,
the states necessary.
Then the question is,
is the state the highest good?
And the answer to that is,
well,
it can't be because it's old and dead
and blind,
and so if the state becomes the highest
good,
then you're occupied by the spirit of
something that's old and dead and blind.
Well,
that's not only not good for you because
then you're old and dead and blind,
but it's also bad for the state because
as soon as the state gets old and dead
and blind,
God gets unhappy with it and the chaos
comes in and washes it away.
So it seems like a bad solution.
So what's the proper solution?
You subordinate your group identity to
the identity that transforms your
identity,
right?
And this state subordinates.
It's power to the vision and
articulation of the individual because
that's what revives the state.
And so that's what these stories are
trying to stumble towards.
Roughly speaking.
So Noah found grace in the eyes of the
Lord.
Why?
While Noah was a just man and perfect in
his generations and Noah walked with
God,
now you remember in the Adam and Eve
story,
Adam was walking with God to begin with,
but then he got all self conscious and
hid behind a bush and when God came to
walk with him,
he blamed his wife for his
insufficiencies,
which I still think that's such an
unbelievably comic story.
I just can't believe it.
It's so absolutely ridiculous,
but that's exactly what happened.
While you have no adhere and Noah.
Noah is like a counter,
another counterpart to some degree to
kate as adjustment and he walks with God
and so he's oriented properly and
because he is oriented properly,
when the flood comes,
not only does he managed to get through
it as an individual,
he manages to get through it with his
family and he saves and while he saves,
he roughly saves the world.
That's how the story puts it forward.
I mean,
it's an arc and it's full of animals and
you know,
it's,
it's got a child's story element to it.
In fact,
I suspect it probably was the story that
was primarily told to children.
You know,
it's like a fable,
but it's a fable with punch,
like the Pinocchio Story,
a fable with punch.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
there's gonna be a flood.
There's always a flood.
So who are you?
If you want to get through the flood,
well then you're noah.
You're the that builds the boat.
You're the thing that acts justly.
You're the thing that walks with God.
We already know what that means.
You identify with the transcendent.
That's Japan.
Oh,
pointing to the star before the
transformation process that occurs with
Pinocchio.
It's you're identifying with a
benevolent spirit of the state,
so you have a relationship with the
transcendent and the benevolent spirit
of the state,
and you're also identified with the
capacity to generate chaos out of order
and the reverse.
That's what it means to walk with God.
Roughly speaking,
it's across all of those dimensions.
So what does that do?
It gives you the power to withstand the
flood and to bring people and and being
itself and civilization along with you.
And that's the story of Noah.
So it's a precursor,
it's,
it's another.
Abel is a precursor to the idea of the
Redeeming Messiah,
right?
Noah is a precursor to the idea of the
redeeming messiah.
You could think about the best pro tow,
Messiah's or pro tow Meta heroes,
something like that.
And they manifest themselves.
They're part of the giants that walked
in the past and they're embodied their
attempts embodied in story to elucidate
this triangle that's at the top of the
pyramid,
right?
The eye that's at the top of the
pyramid.
So,
so I won't tell you the rest of the Noah
story because I don't think it's
necessary for us to,
to,
to delve into the more narrative
details,
um,
but I do want to.
So it's a pretty rough.
I can point it out in some pretty rough
story.
Every living substance was destroyed,
which was upon the face of the ground,
both men and cattle and creeping things
and the follow the heaven and they were
destroyed from the earth.
And Noah only remained alive and they
that were with him in the Ark.
It's very terrifying story,
you know,
and,
uh,
it's worth attending to because we are
currently in a period of extreme chaos.
So,
okay,
so anyways,
works out God's had enough.
He's killed,
he's killed enough of everything.
It's a,
it's a traumatic occurrence.
We can put it that way.
The waters recede and God,
a God has done for the time being.
And so then this is what happens at the
end.
So the arc settle down there,
unloading it and creation is reborn.
And so then you think,
well,
what sets things right?
Again,
between man and God,
and the story says that Noah built an
altar unto the Lord and took of every
clean beast and of every clean foul and
offered burnt offerings on the altar.
So it's the same idea here.
It's that same idea that you started to
see emerging in the Cain and Abel Story.
What is it that sets things right
between man and God?
Sacrifice.
So the flood comes,
then no,
it makes the proper sacrifices,
right?
It's part of reestablishing the proper
order.
He makes the proper sacrifices and so
god is happy with the sacrifices,
which is a good thing,
given that he's pretty ordinary
and,
um,
and the Lord smelled a sweet savor.
So remember I told you before that the
reason people thought that this would
work for us because the smoke would rise
up and God would be able to detect
whether or not the,
the sacrifice was of high quality.
While you have it written right there,
you know,
very,
uh,
concretized image of,
of,
of the archetypal spirit,
right?
The Lord smelled a sweet savor and said
in his heart,
I will not curse the ground anymore for
man's sake,
for the imagination of Man's heart is
evil from his youth.
Neither will I against smite anymore
every living thing as I have done.
So that's pretty nice is noah sacrifice
actually calms down God down to the
point where he says,
well,
I'm not going to wipe everything out
again.
It's like,
well,
fair enough,
you know,
but I would consider it somewhat of a
tenuous contract because we've seen more
than one example in the recent century
where we came bloody close to wiping
everything out again,
while the earth remains,
seed time and harvest and cold and heat
in summer and winter,
day and night shall not cease neither.
Again,
will I be any more every living thing as
I have done.
So.
All right,
so that's that.
He basically tells noah the same thing
again,
that he told Adam at the beginning of,
of the,
of the genesis story.
So fine.
And then he,
he tells them a bunch of rules which I
could go into,
but at the moment I won't,
but I want to show you that
basically what God,
I guess I should do this to some degree.
God lays out a bunch of rules so you
could think about it as a precursor to
what happens in the story of exodus
where the 10 commandments are revealed.
So this is like a foreshadowing of that
story.
No.
What makes the proper sacrifices?
And God says,
okay,
fine.
Here's the rules.
Follow these rules and then they're laid
out and things will go okay with you.
That's the covenant.
That's the agreement between the end.
You could say that's the agreement
between the individual and the spirit of
the state.
That's one way of looking at it,
but it's not enough because it isn't
merely the spirit of the state that's
being negotiated with.
It's the spirit of the state.
It's the spirit of that which transcends
the state and it's the spirit of the
moral order that's within the
individual.
All three of those things are being
negotiated simultaneously.
The proper sacrifices are made,
the proper rules are laid out,
and the.
And the idea is that there'll be a good
balance between order and chaos as a
consequence,
as long as people continue to play by
the rules.
So that's the awkward fundamentally so
far that seems to work out.
And then
this one I think is extremely
interesting.
It's also very short.
It took me a very,
very long time to,
to understand this.
Alright,
so this is after
the story of Noah.
So what happens is you get this
situation where things descend into
chaos and there's a great flood.
So that's sort of like the ultimate
chaos story.
And I think of it as a if there's.
So you mentioned when things fall apart,
one possibility is that they fall into
chaos.
The other possibility is something like
they become hyper
conceptualized in hyper orderly and so
then the state itself,
which would be the antidote to chaos
actually becomes a source of pathology.
And I think that that's what's being
hinted at in the story of the Tower of
Babel.
So here's what happens is that human
beings,
I'll read it to you,
this is,
this has to do with Noah's descendants.
It's a flip into another story.
And it came to pass as they journeyed
from the east.
Oh yes.
And all the days of Noah were 950 years
and he died.
New Story and the whole earth was of one
language and one speech.
Everybody is getting along fine in their
tribal organization.
Let's say it's homogenous.
They can all speak to one another and
they all speak the same language.
And it came to pass as they journeyed
from the east,
that they found a plain in the land of
Shinar and they dwelt there and they
said to one another,
Goto let us make brick and burn them
thoroughly,
and they had brick for stone and slime
had they for mortar and they said,
go to go to let us build a city and a
tower whose top may reach unto heaven
and let us make a name lest we be
scattered abroad upon the face of the
whole earth.
Okay,
so what's happening here?
Only the bare.
This is this.
What this story means is very deeply
implicit in the story.
It's hinting at it and I think it's
because it was really beyond the power
of the conceptualization of the people
who generated this story.
To elaborate it to any great detail,
but I think what it means is this,
is that
there's a guy named Robin,
I think Robin Dunbar,
and one of the things that Dunbar has
done is do a very detailed correlation
analysis of cortical expansion and group
size.
And what he showed is that if you,
if you plot primates bicortical size,
let's say you correct it for body size,
you plot primates by critical size,
and then you plot the size of their
social groups.
You see a very tight relationship
between the size of the social group and
the size of the cortex.
The optimal human social group is like
200 individuals.
It's something like that,
which is maybe roughly the number of
people that you can reasonably track on
facebook.
After that.
It's like,
well,
there's names,
but you don't know those people.
You're not capable of tracking social
dynamics there any more complex than
that,
partly because you have other problems
to solve.
And so one of the things that has been
observed is that human groups tend to
fraction eight if they start to exceed
200.
And maybe that's partly because you
can't keep track of the complexity,
but there's another
constraint which is you want your group
to be big enough so that it protects
you,
but you want it to be small enough so
that you can climb to the top.
Because when the group gets really,
really,
really big,
well maybe it can protect you,
although it also doesn't give a damn
about you,
like once your won $60,000
of the group,
like you are at the University of
Toronto where one 30 million of the
country or maybe one slash 300 million
of Europe,
which is partly why Europe is going to
fragment because that's just not enough,
right?
You're just not enough there that this
group is too big.
What happens?
You keep aggregating the group.
It gets more and more powerful and you
can think of that as something that has
the capacity to replace the
transcendent.
Right?
We'll make a society that's perfect.
It's like a Utopian vision.
That's what I see happening in this
story.
It's like,
well,
make something so great on the part of
human beings that it will reach up to
heaven itself,
which means it will take the place of
God.
That's what it means.
That's exactly what the Communists did
in Soviet Russia,
and that's what they tried to do in in
China too,
and so that's why you ended up with
people like Stalin as the God,
so you talk about getting what you
deserve.
So anyways,
so you build these monolithic
enterprises that we,
let's call them state enterprises and
the idea there is that the state,
the hyper organized and all inclusive
state can bring about utopia.
That's what it means to reach to heaven.
So what happens?
So God gets wind of that and he says,
the Lord says the Lord came down to see
the city and the tower which the
children of men built,
and the Lord said,
behold the people is one and now they
all have one language and this they
begin to do and now nothing will be
restrained from them,
which they have imagined to do.
Go to let us go down and therefore
confound their language that they may
not understand one another's speech.
Well,
it's interesting because it sort of the
story kind of portrays it as jealousy on
God's part,
right?
It's like,
oh,
these,
these human beings there,
they're building so magnificently that
they're starting to challenge my
dominion while while I'm going to go
down there and play a trick or two on
them,
and that'll,
that'll take care of that.
So what happens?
The people within the group gets bigger
and bigger and bigger and bigger and
bigger,
and what happens?
It starts to fragment.
That is what happens.
That's exactly what happens.
That's part of the reason why the
totalitarian state enterprise to replace
the transcendent with structure.
That's one of the reasons it's doomed.
As you pull more and more people in,
what happens is you start to pull in
chaos itself and that starts to fragment
the order.
Here's an interesting thing.
I think that's happening with the.
So the lgbt power groups are exclusion
excluded groups,
right?
And so it started out with gay rights
and then one of the things that's
happened that's so interesting,
so you could think of,
there was a normative group and there
was excluded people.
Okay.
And so one section of the excluded
people stood up and said,
hey,
you know,
enough of this exclusion,
so we're gonna categorize ourselves and
we're gonna fight for recognition as the
excluded,
we're going to fight to be included.
But what happens is,
well it's l and then it's lb and then
it's lbg and then it's lgbt.
And the last thing I saw which was
actually handed to the medical students
at the University of Toronto,
there's 20 letters.
Why?
Well,
because
you can't.
This is tangentially related to this
story only.
You can't come up with a category of the
things that don't fit inside categories
because there's an infinite number of
things that don't fit inside categories.
And so when you try to build a category
out of all and categorical entities,
all that happens is it starts to
fragment because there's actually no
unity there.
And one of the things you are starting
to see is that there's power battles
emerging on the part of the excluded on
the left.
And it's inevitable because I think
that's what this story is trying to
represent is that you can't build the
state up beyond a certain size if you
do,
it will fragment and fall apart.
The people within it will no longer
speak the same language and they'll,
they'll,
they'll disperse themselves to different
corners of the earth.
And so I think we're actually in real
danger of forgetting this.
And one of the things that I saw read a
couple of ominous things.
So if you plot the size of economic
catastrophes over the last 30 years,
they're getting bigger each time.
So that's scary.
Now,
part of that is because the world
economy is getting bigger and so maybe
you have to control for that.
But the magnitude of the chaos has been
increasing with each collapse.
Okay.
I,
one of the things that came out of the
last collapsed 2008 was the government
rescuing collapsed companies like Aig
and the Royal Bank of Scotland,
which by the way was the biggest company
in the world.
No one knows that.
But Royal Bank of Scotland collapsed.
It was the biggest company in the world.
And Aig was the insurer of insurers and
so it collapsed too.
They were rescued by the government and
maybe fair enough.
But one of the motifs that came out of
that was the idea of too big to fail.
Well,
this story says,
wait a second,
it says two big means definite failure.
It means inevitable failure.
And that strikes me as highly probable
is there's a warning in this story,
although it's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a bear story,
right?
It's only four or five lines.
It's just the outlines,
but it's placed in a very particular
place.
It's placed right after the flood,
right?
It's like,
well,
there's the nihilistic chaos of the
flood.
And then there's the temp totalitarian
temptation to build hyper structures
that can theoretically replace the
transcendent.
But what happens,
you build the hyper structure and it
fragments from within,
and then people don't speak the same
language and they and they distribute
themselves,
sort of chaotically on the surface of
the earth.
So
therefore is the name of it called
Babel.
Because the Lord did there confound the
language of all the earth.
And from thence,
did the Lord scatter them abroad upon
the face of all the earth?
I think the other issue too is that
what's the problem with the
homogenization of a group?
It's like you bring everyone into the
group and then they're all the same
uniformity.
Well,
the advantages,
you can understand everyone,
the disadvantages,
there's no variability left,
right?
There's no variability.
Everyone is a clone of everyone else and
that's great if you know where you're
going and you know how to get there,
but it's really,
really bad if the underlying structure
shifts on you because the fact that
you're adapted to one situation,
hyper adapted to one situation might
mean that your content completely not
adapted to the next situation.
You build groups that are too big and
too homogenous.
They're effective,
but only within the limited range of
their map.
And if the map no longer functions,
then the whole thing sinks.
And that's I think what happens in this
particular story.
And then okay,
at the end of that,
then what happens is that soon
afterwards,
I think perhaps immediately afterwards,
the story of Abraham,
he merges and that's really.
I would say that's when the the prime
myths,
the prime,
oh,
myths take on a more historical element
and history,
you know,
roughly speaking history as we know it
begins something like 6,000
years ago,
so and then.
Then the rest of the biblical stories
proceed at pace.
From there,
what basically happens is that as
something that was well mapped out by
northrop Frye and you think at the
University of Toronto that you all would
have been encouraged to read northrop
frye because he was perhaps the greatest
literary scholar that the University of
Toronto ever produced and what He.
He outlined the old testament very
interestingly,
he said that what happens after these
initial stories is that the state
arises,
so it's like the Tower of Babel is
continually rebuild over and over and
it's the state of Israel's.
The Israelis Israelites get their act
together,
build a state.
What happens?
They get corrupt.
A prophet comes up and says,
you better watch out because what you're
doing is not making God happy and the
profits are very brave because they come
forward that the kings are authoritarian
and they can kill them.
At an instant,
but the profits are moved by walking
with God,
let's say,
for lack of a better argument.
They come to the king and say,
look,
you're not caring for the widows and the
children.
Right?
And you think that's okay because
they're weak.
It's not okay.
You're breaking the covenant.
You're breaking the rules and the price
for that is what we really saw.
The price for that is a flood.
It's like get your act together or
you're going to be sorry.
Now sometimes the kings to whom the
prophets speak,
listen,
but often they don't and then the whole
bloody state is demolished and then
isn't real.
Lights are back.
Like they're enslaved or they get wiped
out by their enemies are like,
it's a complete bloody catastrophe that
lasts for centuries and then they kind
of struggled back up and make another
state and then they get arrogant and
then it gets corrupt and then a profit
comes along and says,
you know what happened last time?
It's like,
well,
that was 600 years ago,
right?
And I knew everything now so I don't
have to pay any attention to you.
It's they ignore it and then because the
and the prophet say,
you are violating a fundamental moral
order,
you're supposed to as king,
you're supposed to be subject to
something higher than yourself.
Right?
It's like the idea that the
Mesopotamians had that the emperor was
supposed to be an emissary of Marduk.
That's why he was the emperor because he
was a good Marduk.
He could confront chaos and make order.
That was what gave him his sovereignty
or the Egyptian Pharaoh was a
combination of Osiris and horus.
That's what gave him sovereignty and so
the idea was you get to be king,
but you have to act out the spirit of
being king and if you don't do that,
then well king or not all hell's gonna
break loose for you.
And that's what the profit is
continually say,
but the Israel lights,
you know,
they don't pay enough attention and they
continued to get absolutely demolished.
And so the Old Testament can be read at
least in part as the description of a
sequence of the rise and fall of states
and their descent into corruption and
chaos.
And so we'll leave it at that because I
want to tell you the next part of the
story,
the last part of the story,
roughly speaking in our next lecture,
which is also the last lecture.
So we've got about 12 minutes if we want
it.
So if anybody has any questions you can
ask them are we can and if you don't
then we could call it a day.
So does any.
Well,
it's a lot of information.
So.
And it's a lot of strange inflammation.
So I'm curious,
you know,
if,
if what you make of it,
you were talking about your why is why
is it a similar size,
which is American.
You think the right and left can talk to
each other.
You think they speak the same language,
right?
You see it that fragmenting occurring
and they really are.
Not only are they speaking different
languages there,
they really are speaking different
languages.
It's the right way of thinking about it.
Yes,
it's very,
very dangerous.
You know,
I think the US worked for a long time,
first of all because it didn't always
have 300 million people.
It's a lot of people to put under one
umbrella.
Now the utility of the American system
is that it is a hierarchy,
right?
There's individuals,
families,
towns,
states underneath a somewhat loose
federal structure and that sort of.
So it's not a.
it's not a monolith where everyone has
to speak precisely the same language.
It's got some flexibility built into its
structure because it's,
it's,
it's formulated into components which
have a certain amount of autonomy and so
far that's worked sufficiently well.
Whether it will and it will probably
continue to work.
I mean the are a very,
very robust people and they've gone
through things that are analogous to
what they're going through now.
Many times God only knows,
right,
but,
but it's very dangerous thing to presume
that the Americans are down for the
count because they have an uncanny
ability to rise from the ashes even
stronger than they were before.
But you can certainly see the danger
lurking in Europe.
That's,
that's a different thing.
Like I think the European state is dude,
because I think it grew too fast and
it's severed that connection between
like there's not the proper hierarchy
of,
of identification.
So,
and people are saying,
wait,
I Brussels,
like,
who the hell are you guys?
Why are you making decisions for us?
And we don't agree with your decisions
and like are you sure that Greece and
Germany can be in the same place because
that's by no means self evident,
right?
The Germans aren't very happy about it
and the Greeks aren't very happy about
it and one of the rules for making an
organization is that it's a lot easier
to make a functional organization worse
than it is to make a dysfunctional
organization better.
And so you might say,
well you've got Germany and France and
England,
well let's say Germany and France
powerhouses,
especially Germany,
they can afford to bring Greece in.
Well
maybe,
but
there's no evidence that they can afford
it.
So I mean Greece is unbelievably
corrupt.
No one pays her income tax.
That's a big problem.
Right?
And bringing them in to a union at a
high order has no effect whatsoever on
the micro behaviors.
And the thing is the micro behaviors
have to be rectified and no one really
knows how to do that.
How do you stop a country where people
don't pay their taxes from?
How do you stop the people from not
paying their taxes?
Why do we pay our taxes?
Who knows?
We could just all of a sudden decide not
to,
you know,
and the government wouldn't have the
resources to run around gathering them
all up for one reason or another.
It's become customary for people in
functional Western democracies to pay
their taxes.
But why,
who knows?
It would have been way easier for us
just to do what the Greeks did and
pretend to pay them,
you know,
so there are too big I think.
And so the people on the right is saying
back to the nation and like I understand
why they're doing that,
but,
but
the danger is the nation will
subordinate the individual.
And I do see it as another example of
safe spaces.
It's just scales different.
So.
And that's why I think that the proper
antidote to that,
to both the chaos on the left and the
order on the right,
roughly speaking,
is to walk the proper line in the
middle.
And we better do that because things are
not.
Things are too chaotic at the moment.
So it's not good.
Maybe it's really good that's possible.
But we're in a state where I really
believe we're in a state where things
could go any number of ways and there's
no,
there's no predicting it.
So.
And never felt that,
you know,
I mean I lived in the eighties and you
know,
political correctness rose up in the
nineties as well and I can remember a
lot of what happened in the early
seventies with the oil crisis and all
that.
So there were times when things were
shaky but they weren't shaky the way
they are now.
They're an internal shakiness rather
than something that was a threat that
was,
seemed to be imposed from the outside.
And that's different.
And,
and it's,
it's,
it is associated with,
with this intellectual war that's going
on with postmodernism in new Marxism.
And all of that as well.
So
dealing with,
and you mentioned that the effects are
much more pronounced than men,
especially given the agenda.
It's a lot of questions.
They're good questions.
Um,
I'll tell you a couple of strange things
that it takes that I don't really
understand.
The first is when we've done the
analysis of the effects of the future
authoring program,
it has had a different differential
impact on men and it's had a
particularly differential impact on what
I would call it excluded men.
And so that would be non western ethic
minority men or,
or what majority men who aren't doing
very well.
So for example,
at Mohawk College,
the future authoring program had a
particularly robust effect on Mohawk
college students who are men who hadn't
done very well in high school and knew,
hadn't picked a major that had a
destination,
a career destination at it's amp.
So you can imagine those people are,
they have an ambiguous relationship with
the idea of education and they're not
oriented specifically towards a goal.
They're not very motivated.
Now why did it have a differential
effect on man?
That's a good question.
Well,
first of all,
the women are doing better,
so it might just be a matter of the fact
that it does better for people who
aren't doing as well and at the moment
most of them are men,
I don't believe.
I think that might be part of it,
but I don't believe that's all of it.
I think that part of the reason that
women are doing better is because
they're agreeable and so if a system
sets out a structure and says,
here's a pathway to attainment,
the women won't rebel against that.
They'll go along with it and that's
working very well for them at the
moment.
The man,
especially the men on the disagreeable
end of the distribution and there's way
more men on the district disagreeable
end of the distribution.
Then there are women,
right?
That's what you get from.
If you look at overlapping normal
distributions.
So there's the male district,
female distribution for agreeableness,
mail distribution for agreeableness.
Tremendous overlap.
Okay.
Women are higher.
All the really agreeable people are
women.
All the really disagreeable people are
meant and maybe the real differences
occur at the extremes.
Right?
So,
so,
and it's a very interesting side effect
of overlapping distributions so people
can be mostly the same,
but that can still produce radical
differences.
Disagreeable men won't do anything they
don't want to do.
They just say up yours,
I'll go home and play video games with
you.
I'm not listening to your stupid classes
and why should I work for you?
I'll just go have fun.
I'll do my own thing.
I don't think they're motivated.
And so then if you take the men who are
like that and you say,
okay,
what do you want?
You can have what you want,
but you have figured out what it is.
So then they write down what they want.
They think,
Oh hey,
well that might be worth having.
So maybe I'll put some effort into it.
That's what it looks like to me.
Now,
you know,
that's weak evidence and this is a weak
argument,
but I'm trying to stretch out my
understanding to account for this.
But I'll tell you something else that's
really weird.
I don't understand this either.
So more than 90 percent of the people
who watch my videos on youtube are men
now that's weird because now about 80
percent of psychology students are
women.
So that is not what you would expect,
right?
You would expect that the majority of
them would be women and you might say,
well it's because of the political
stance I've taken.
And I thought,
well that's possible.
So I went and looked at the demographic
data because I have that.
Well before I did any of the political
videos,
85 percent of my viewers were men.
So it's actually increased a bit.
It's increased by six percent and that's
not trivial,
but it was still overwhelmingly men.
So that was interesting.
I thought,
what the hell,
why is that?
Exactly.
And then now I've been watching crowds
when I've been talking to them and the
crowds that have come to see me in
person.
This happened at the University of
Toronto Free Speech Debate and I
actually noticed it and commented on it
before the debate took place because I
was talking about intrinsic differences
between men and women.
And I looked around the room and I
thought,
hmm,
hey,
80 percent of the people in this room
are men.
So I had all the men stay windham and
women stand up and then all the men
stand up.
They said,
look,
here's a natural experiment.
For some reason,
80 percent of the people who showed up
to this sermon,
now everybody thought I was kinda
cracked to to do that.
And it was a risk,
you know?
But I thought,
no,
there's something going on here.
And then what's interesting now is that
every public appearance that I've made
that's related to the sort of topics
that we're discussing is overwhelmingly
men.
It's like it's like 85 to 90 percent.
And so I thought,
wow,
that's weird.
Like what the Hell's going on here?
Exactly.
And then the other thing I've noticed is
that I've been talking a lot to the
crowds that I've been talking to,
not about rights but about
responsibility,
right?
Because he can't have the bloody
converse.
What are you doing?
You can't have the conversation about
rights without the conversation about
responsibility because your rights are
my responsibility.
That's what they are technically,
so you just can't have only half of that
discussion and we're only having half
that discussion.
The question is,
well,
what the hell are you leaving out?
If you only have that half of the
discussion and the answer is,
well,
you're leaving out responsibility and
then the question is,
well,
what are you leaving out?
If you're leaving out responsibility and
that answer might be,
well maybe you're leaving out the
meaning of life.
That's what it looks like to me.
It's like here you are suffering away.
What makes it worthwhile,
right?
You know you're completely out.
You're completely.
You have no idea what you're you.
It's almost impossible to describe how
bad an idea that is.
Responsibility.
That's what gives life meaning.
It's like lift a load.
Then you can tolerate yourself,
right?
Because look at your useless,
easily hurt,
easily killed.
Why should you have any self respect?
That's the story of the fall.
Pick something up and carry it.
Pick.
Make it heavy enough so that you can
think,
yeah,
well useless as I am.
At least I could move that from there to
there.
Well,
what's really cool about that is that
when I talk to these crowds about this,
the man's eyes light up and that's very
like I've seen that phenomena because
I've been talking about this
mythological material for a long time
and I can see what I'm watching.
Crowds people,
you know,
their eyebrows lift,
their eyes light up because I put
something together for them,
not sweat,
mythological stories do.
So I'm not taking responsibility for
that.
That's what the stories due.
So I say this story to people,
go click,
click,
you know when their eyes light up,
but this responsibility thing that's a
whole new order of this is that young
men are so hungry for that.
It is unbelievable.
And one of the things I've been talking
to some of the people who've been
running for the conservative leadership
in Canada and I've been talking to them
about,
well the difficulties they have
communicating with young people because
conservatives,
what?
What the hell are they going to sell to
young people,
right?
Because being conservative is something
that happens when you're older.
They can sell responsibility.
No one's selling it.
And the thing is,
for men,
there's nothing but responsibility.
No,
I was watching the simpsons the other
day.
I watched the simpsons episode and I
deconstructed it.
And so it's really interesting.
So what happens in the first Simpson
episode is that it's Christmas and homer
and marge,
you're going to buy some Christmas
presents,
but homer doesn't get his Christmas
bonus.
And so he's absolutely crushed by that.
And that actually is a recurring theme
in the simpsons where homer loses his
job or something like that or can't make
enough money.
He's completely crushed even though he's
kind of useless,
bumbling,
laughing,
fool of a guy,
you know?
The thing that gives that show its soul
is that he still oriented towards his
family.
That's what makes them honorable,
is that foolish as he is.
He's decided to adopt responsibility for
his family and to try to bear that.
And so he's not.
He's a holy fool.
He's not a complete fool.
And so interesting watching the story
because he suffers dreadfully as a
consequence of not being able to fulfill
his responsibility.
Well,
that's for men.
Women have their sets of
responsibilities.
They're not the same,
right,
because they're complicated because
women of course have to take primary
responsibility for,
for having infants at least,
but then also for caring for them,
they're.
They're structured differently than men
for biological necessity,
even if it's not a psychological issue
and it's also partly a psychological
issue.
Women know what they have to do.
Men have to figure out what they have to
do and if they have nothing worth living
for them,
they stay Peter Pan and why the hell not
because the alternative to valued
responsibility is impulsive,
low class pleasure,
and you saw that in the Pinocchio Story,
right?
That's pleasure island.
It's like,
well,
why lift the load if there's nothing in
it for you?
That's another thing that we're doing to
men.
That's a very bad idea and two boys,
it's like your pathological and
oppressive.
It's like,
fine.
Then why the hell am I going to play if
that's the.
If that's the situation.
If I get no credit for bearing
responsibility,
you can bloody well be sure I'm not
going to bear it,
but then you know your life is useless
and meaningless and you have your full
of self contempt,
denialism and,
and that's not good.
And so that's why I think that's what I
think is going on at a deeper level with
regards to men needing this direction.
A man has to decide that he's going to
do something.
He has to decide that
image.
Yeah.
Well,
you know partly what you're trying to do
in the future authoring process to say,
okay,
well what's your highest value?
Right?
It's the star.
It's like,
okay,
what are you aiming for?
You can decide man,
but you know,
there's some criteria.
It should be good for you.
It should be good for you in a way that
facilitates your moving forward.
Maybe it should be good for you in a way
that's also good for the family and the
community.
It should cover the,
the domain of life mean there's
constraints on what you should regard as
a value,
but you.
But within those constraints,
you have the choice.
You have choice.
Well,
the thing is is that people will carry a
heavy load if they get to pick the god
damn load so and they think,
well,
I won't carry any load.
It's like,
okay,
fine,
but then you're like the sled dog that
doesn't have a sled pole,
you're just gonna.
You're going to tear a piece is out of
your own legs because you're bored.
You know you need.
People are pack animals.
They need,
they need to pull against a weight and
and that's not true for everyone.
It's not true.
Particularly say for low conscientious
people.
I mean maybe they're open and creative
are extroverted and some other things,
but for the,
for the typical person,
they,
they'll eat themselves,
they'll eat themselves up unless they
have a load.
This is why there's such an opiate
epidemic among a dispossessed white,
middle aged guys who were unemployed in
the US.
It's like they lose their job.
They're done,
right?
They despise themselves.
They develop chronic pain syndromes and
depression
and the chronic pain is treated with
opiates.
So that's what we're doing.
So yeah,
that's what it looks like to me is you
have to.
And it's so interesting to watch the
young men when you talk to them about
responsibility.
There is a God damn thrilled about it.
It just blows me away.
It's like,
really?
That's what's.
That's the counterculture.
Grow the hell up and do something
useful.
Really.
I could do that.
Oh,
I'm so excited by that idea.
No one ever mentioned that before.
It's like rights,
rights,
Jesus.
It's,
it's,
it's appalling.
It's,
it's,
and I feel that that's deeply felt by
the people who are,
who are coming out to to listen to these
sorts of things,
to there.
They've had enough of that so.
And they better have because it's,
it's a nonproductive motive being
responsibility,
man.
That's where the meaning in life is.
So.
All right,
good.
One more class.
Hey,
we'll see you next week.