Yeah,
please join me in welcoming the
disciplines.
[inaudible]
hey,
so I know everybody's really eager to
get into the question resolution at hand
and to hear from our speakers.
So I will just introduce the resolution
and the format people have the legal
right to decide.
He resolved that people up the legal
right to decide the pronouns by which
they will be addressed and you'll notice
that we've dropped him disrobe
resolutions that we can discuss the law
as it is,
as it ought to be and various levels of
law,
provincial offices,
rollers,
federal laws.
Um,
and we will,
each speaker will speak for 15 minutes
and openings and then they'll have 10
minutes each for bottles.
And then we'll have ample amount of time
for questions and answers,
which I'm sure many of you have a for
both of our participants,
especially Dr. Peterson.
Um,
just one quick note about the spirit and
is going to proceed.
Um,
we are here gathered as jurists,
as officers of the court or future
offers through as of the court in a
spirit of openness and inquiry,
um,
about the laws that we subject ourselves
to.
And the laws that we govern and how they
shape our interactions as society.
Um,
so we are proceeding fearlessly and
openly and respectfully.
Um,
so professor party,
okay,
start.
Okay,
let's have happening
daily ready
be Queens full for inviting me to this
and putting it on.
You know,
this is exactly the kind of thing that
running mead was conceived before.
So,
uh,
you know,
Nice,
nice job and a hope.
We have a good evening.
Don't hesitate when we get on to the
later stages,
the speak up and say your peace.
We're here to talk.
All right,
so don't be shy.
I'm sure you will.
The resolution as stated really as
Joanna mentioned,
raises two questions.
One,
what the law actually is as of today and
secondly what the law ought to be.
And I suspect that Professor Peterson
and I might actually agree on the first
one,
what the law is.
I think it's pretty clear that the law
as it exists right now as reflected in
the Ontario human rights code is that
this is true.
When you're read to you,
this is section one of the Ontario Human
Rights Code.
And I know you've probably heard this
before.
Every person has a right to equal
treatment with respect to services,
goods at facilities,
and that's been included to include
education at the post secondary level
without discrimination because of an a
whole bunch of numerated items including
gender identity and gender expression.
Now it doesn't talk about pronouns per
se in the statute,
but according to the Human Rights
Commission of Ontario,
that's one thing it should include and
there are decisions of tribunals
especially I haven't BC,
again,
not directly on the point in the
classroom about the pronouns,
but enough to suggest that that's a
logical extension of the proposition.
In section one,
the more interesting question is not
what the law is but what it ought to be.
Whether or not that state of the law is
good,
something that we should approve them
and I'm here to argue in the affirmative
that that's exactly the way it's
supposed to be.
I'm going to go with these through these
essential five points to make my cases.
They're talking about free speech first
and then about free speech in
classrooms,
the nature of gender privacy questions
and then the nature of language itself.
All right.
First,
let's talk about free speech because
this question is often framed in the
context of two opposing forces,
one being free speech and liberty on the
one hand and on the other sort of a,
a tyrannical government,
a social justice warriors trying to shut
down the ability of individuals to speak
for themselves,
and I want to suggest to you that that's
actually an artificial dichotomy.
Let me put it to you this way.
There actually is no such thing as free
speech.
What I mean by that is that the law is
full of limits on speech.
I mean,
let us count the ways.
Speech is limited by the law of
defamation.
You can't go off and talk about your
neighbor in the repertory terms.
If it's not true,
you'll be sued.
Speech is limited by the law of
negligence.
You can't yell fire in a crowded theater
if there isn't one,
you'll be held liable for injuries.
We even have a tort called the
intentional infliction of emotional
harm.
That harm being afflicted most of the
time by speech.
Speech is regulated and limited by the
criminal law.
We have laws that prohibit counseling a
crime suggesting to somebody or
arranging for somebody to go off and
commit a crime.
Even if all you've done is speak words.
We have laws that prohibit hate speech,
which is nothing more than speech.
We even have restrictions of speech in
the area as minor as consumer law
restrictions on advertising where and
when and what it can say.
The proposition is this.
It is not a general rule that speech is
free.
What we have is a starting point of
freedom of expression in the charter and
then we have reasonable limits as
defined by societal needs.
And the question is not whether or not
this speech is free,
it's whether or not those limits are
reasonable and the reasonableness of the
limits can be defined by whether or not
they achieve a common good.
All right,
so let's get off this black and white
and go.
This is a matter of gray and in the gray
I think,
I hope you'll agree with me that the
gray favors this kind of outcome.
So on the point number two,
we're talking here about the ability of
somebody to decide the programs by which
they will be addressed.
Now that's a general proposition,
but our particular focus is of course
the classroom.
So there's a student of the boss and the
teacher and the teacher refers to that
person that's came over her and that
person says,
well,
I don't want to be thought of,
I don't want to be referred to as a him
or her.
I want something to be gender neutral.
A third thing,
if you like
question,
is speech more free or less free in
classrooms than it is on the street.
I've suggested those various
restrictions that exist in the law in
general in the classroom.
I'd like to suggest that speech is even
more restraint because there are
obligations,
there are relationships between teacher
and students and between students and
institution.
So for example,
this doesn't speak to this question
specifically,
but just by way of example to show you
to illustrate that there are more
restrictions on speech.
How would you feel if you're in your
classroom,
you started off the semester and the
professor in question would refused to
refer to you by anything other than you
slimy weasel.
Now don't you think you would have a
complaint?
Maybe not even based on kind of the
human rights code,
but just on pure administrative law
principles.
Those principles suggest that a teacher
in a classroom has at least a minimum of
the responsibility to be unbiased,
to apply an even hand.
And if through language that even hand
is clearly not being addressed,
uh,
express,
then I would have saw it.
There is some kind of legal remedy
insight.
There are lots of other examples both in
the classroom and outside.
Let's say you have earned a phd
and a person in authority.
Perhaps it's the teacher.
Perhaps it's a,
an official,
it doesn't really matter who it is,
but in some kind of official capacity
refuses will not call you.
Doctor wants to call you,
Mr,
which is actually not the title that
you've earned.
What if you're a woman and you are not
married and the teacher insists upon
calling you miss and you want to be
called Ms,
which is the neutral form.
Now,
once upon a time we were having the same
debate about myth
woman wanting to be called ms and the
powers that be back at that time said,
look,
there's only two.
There's Mrs or miss.
Choose one.
Here we are again.
We have to choose one.
Actually there is a third choice.
I want to suggest that there are also
examples.
You will here to object to this idea.
Would you raise a false equivalency?
This does not say anybody has the right
to insist upon being called anything
because you can think of examples where
that just don't do so.
If I had a student in my classroom,
he said,
professor,
I would like you here for and from now
on to police to refer to me as Your
Majesty.
Well,
I'm not going to do that.
I'm sorry because objectively speaking
you are not wealthy unless you can show
me your crown.
All right,
so the question is not as broad as that.
The question is actually very narrow and
limited.
It's limited to the question of the
proper pronoun to be used for a person
who is gender neutral,
which brings me to point number three
and that is the nature of gender.
I want to distinguish between two
related but different ideas and those
two ideas are gender and sex.
Now,
I'm not a biologist,
I'm not a psychologist,
I'm just a lawyer.
Emphasis on being the word justice,
but I'm going to suggest to you that the
two ideas can be distinguished this way.
Sex being the bio,
biological idea and gender being the
cultural idea,
you might be able to determine
somebody's sex by looking at objective
factors.
Maybe not,
I don't know,
but I'm going to,
I'm going to entertain that possibility.
I'm not sure you can do the same thing
for gender because gender is an
inherently subjective thing.
Unlike whether or not somebody qualifies
for the title,
Your Majesty.
I would have thought that whether or not
you are a male or a female or a neither
in gender terms is something only you
can tell us.
Okay.
So I think that distinguishes the
subjective questions from the object of
one.
As soon as you had a subjective
question,
that the choice has to be determined by
the person who was being addressed.
So on to privacy,
our insistence upon a binary choice that
he or she in a sense reflects our need
to categorize.
But the strange thing about that need is
that it is based upon information that
really is very personal.
Now,
much of the time you can tell through
outward appearance,
but if you look at the bottom line,
what you're,
what you actually need,
I think to insist upon that choice.
Aren't you really asking after all at
the bottom of it all,
you're insisting to know what that
person's junk looks like
and really nobody else's business.
But Yours,
if you refuse to indicate with the junk
is life.
And if you,
and it's not clear on the,
on the face of things,
and I use that word on purpose,
which way you're going to go,
why should the world care?
It's really all about you.
I don't know.
They're just trying to categorize.
I want to see if your one thing or the
other thing,
it doesn't matter what you are and in
fact it doesn't matter so much that you
might be a third thing or somewhere in
between.
In other words,
nobody has the right to pry to obtain
the information necessary to make the
choice between he or she.
Okay,
and so finally,
let's talk about language because this
after all is about like we may in fact
be talking about a peculiar
characteristic of the English language
because as of right now the English
language has just two personal pronouns
but can be used for human beings.
We have a third one.
It's called yet,
but this doesn't fit very well when
you're trying to talk about it.
He moved there.
The English language is not unique in
this,
but not,
nor is it universal.
There are other languages that do have
either a neutral third choice or are not
gendered in the first place.
One might be inclined to resolve this
debate by looking through the dictionary
and say,
well I'm sorry,
there's only two in there.
There is no third,
the third that you want me to use,
I can't find.
And therefore it's not part of the
language and therefore I'm not going to
do that.
But the thing about language,
both English and all the others is that
essentially evolutionary changes over
time.
And if you look in the dictionary today
and don't find that third thing,
look again in a year and two years,
in five years,
it will be there.
So the fact of its absence at the moment
is really not determinative of anything.
It's coming.
We might as well be ahead of the curve
then behind
and with that I'll give it the song.
Yeah.
So one of the things that I don't like
to do in the discussion,
and I suppose this is part of the whole
problem,
is I don't like to see linguistic
territory to the people with whom I
disagree.
And that's actually part of the reason
why I have refused,
let's say,
to use a set of pronouns
that I believe are every believe the use
of them is irrelevant in some sense to
this particular issue because I actually
think the issue is quite a bit deeper.
Um,
just
and so part of my objection to using
those particular pronouns was the lack
of my desire to seed linguistic ground
to people whose political,
philosophical,
and even deeper moral stances I do not
agree with in the slightest.
And as soon as you see linguistic ground
to your last call them adversaries,
you have decided that you're going to
play a game within the rules that they
have established and therefore you lose.
So that's why I'm taking the objection
to some degree to the way that this is
formulated.
Because it isn't really about the right
to decide.
It's about the right to insist upon by
force.
And you might say,
well,
what constitutes force?
Well,
I debated Brenda Cossman a lawyer and
she said,
because I had made the claim,
let's say that you can be jailed for not
using this particular category of
pronouns,
which we've already agreed is enshrined
the necessity for doing so.
It was already in tried within the
current legislation.
So I'm glad that you agreed upon that.
And she basically insisted that
according to the surrounding policies,
you couldn't be jailed for that they
could just take away everything you
owned.
And,
and I thought that was extremely
interesting first of all because she
seemed to think that that was all right,
but also because she didn't actually
notice that that was kind of the point
that I was making.
Plus if you don't agree or act out the,
uh,
what would you call it?
The judgement of the human rights
tribunal,
then they can take you to,
I believe it's Ontario Superior Court
where they can nail you for captain then
and they can put you in jail.
So yeah.
Okay,
fine.
You know,
it's a nuance,
but um,
it's a non,
it's a nontrivial direct route and
people have in fact been jailed for such
thing.
So,
so let's get to the insist upon by force
issue here because that's where the the
issue and that's the way that this
should be formulated.
And so well we could also,
there's another problem here too.
And the problem is,
well which pronouns exactly and you
might say,
well I'm transsexual male to female to
be addressed as she and the reverse as
he and in fact most transsexuals,
in fact,
the overwhelming majority of them,
there are about maybe 0.3% of the
population to begin with.
And I would estimate,
although I don't know for sure that it's
99% of them,
but no one really knows actually want to
be addressed by he or she.
They just want to be addressed by the
other one.
Okay.
So there's a tiny minority the size of
which no one knows who insists that that
particular categorizing categorization
scheme,
it doesn't apply to them.
So the question then is,
which one does,
and the problem with that is that you
cannot actually answer that question.
And I can,
I can,
I can give you a hint about that.
With regards to the ever lengthening,
uh,
acronym used by the lgbt community to
describe those who are marginalized,
you may notice that every year there's
an additional initial in that acronym.
And the reason for that is that the
potential number of identities will
multiply until it fraction down to the
level of the individual itself.
It has to because you're not a group,
you're not a member of a group.
You're the simultaneous member of
multiple groups.
In fact,
so many groups that they can't even be a
numerated.
And if my linguistic usage is predicated
on recognizing all of those identities
while we might as well just go home now
because I don't have time to come up
with a million different descriptive
pronouns,
that property going or less evolved the
free market.
Because one of the things the free
market does is enable you to recognize
your multi-dimensional exist and say and
mind simultaneously using mutually
agreed upon price as the determinant
that takes all of those factors
simultaneously into account.
And actually on a pure computational
level,
there isn't any other solution to that
problem because it's actually in
computable.
So the Pronoun problem becomes very,
very problematic,
very,
very rapidly.
You can see that with the acronym growth
in the lgbt community,
which will,
which has to fractioning.
We'll continue the fractured because
none of those groups are homogenous in,
in any but the most trivial of senses.
So that's a big problem.
Which pronouns?
Okay,
so what sort of problem is that?
Well,
in New York state for example,
they've already more or less passed into
law the proposition that there are
pretty much as many pronoun descriptors
as there are people claiming identities.
And so on facebook for example,
which is a good example of saint common
parlance,
it's about 71 different gender
identities already recognize and no
agreed upon lexicon to represent any of
them.
And so the issue there is,
well what stops the infinite
multiplication?
And the answer to that is wim.
And that's actually written into the law
because the law already states that your
identity is predicated on your
subjective and I would say whim and
that's also wrong.
It isn't.
So I was watching Louis C k and the
other night and you know he's a great
philosopher and he said if you,
I'm sorry I don't normally use profanity
but Louis C K does and I am quoting him,
you said,
well if you call someone an asshole they
can't actually object because it's not
up to them.
It's up to someone else to determine if
that's the case because that that
identity classification is actually a so
socially negotiated process.
And that's the thing about your
identity,
the idea that your identity is this
subjective construct.
It's like I am being literally truthful
about that.
That's what two year olds think and
that's why they can't play with others.
So two year olds are egocentric and they
cannot expand their conception of the
world to include the minds of others.
They don't really learn to do that until
between two and four.
And by the way,
if they don't learn that by four,
they never learn it.
And so by the time they're for what they
learn is that your identity is actually
a negotiation.
It's a negotiation from moment to moment
and also throughout the course of your
life.
So for example,
even a child who was pretending knows
that you be the mom all be the dad will
play house.
You can take on that identity at all
take on this one.
But we both have to agree on what the
identity is or we can't play.
So your identity is actually part of the
Public Commons and the idea that it's
your subjective determination is it's so
primordially wrong psychologically that
doesn't even register.
So,
and the notion that's already written
into the law and that's an absolute
catastrophe because in every possible
way,
developmentally,
psychologically,
um,
philosophically,
biologically it's a completely untenable
proposition.
But it doesn't matter because it's
already written into the law.
It's like your identity.
It's like your reputation.
You think you get to have the reputation
you want.
Well,
good luck with that one.
We're so good at tracking reputation
that if we haven't evolved module for
remembering reputation,
you cheat once.
I'll never forget it and you don't get
to object to that,
you know?
I mean you can,
but that isn't going to change the
outcome and it doesn't change the fact
that your reputation,
which is certainly a major part of your
identity,
is something that's dependent on the
interactions that you have with other
people.
Do that to revert to the notion that
that's a purely subjective construct is
it's just,
I just can't even believe that we're
seriously considering that at much less
writing it into the law.
And then there's something even more
appalling going on underneath the law
then that which is we have actually
written into the law now a social
constructivist view of identity.
And so the social constructivists
roughly believe that all elements of
human identity are socially constructed,
which is very peculiar because at the
same time they also insist that all of
your identity is subjective whim.
And those two propositions aren't
logically commensurate,
but you know the people who are
generating this sort of thing and don't
really care about logical
commensurability.
But in any case,
the proposition that your identity is
somehow unmoored from a reality outside
of your subjective saying linguistic
space.
It's also,
it's,
it's wrong.
There's no other way of putting it.
So like,
and this is written into the law
already.
So the proposition is that biological
sex,
which many of the holders of,
of saying what admiration for this law
don't even believe exists,
which I,
I don't even know what to say about
that.
But the proposition is that biological
sex,
gender identity,
gender expression and sexual preference
vary independently.
That's the law.
And it's wrong.
It isn't even close to right.
He doesn't mean they don't very but very
independently as a whole different
propositions,
playfully,
completely different proposition.
So looking at this way,
okay,
so here's biological sex will say
there's some amount of overlap.
I don't care,
like make me overlap this much.
It's not because the only 0.3% of people
are miscategorized by their biological
sex.
Okay.
So then you think,
well,
in terms of gender identity,
it's 99.7% of people have the same
gender identity as their biological sex.
So much for independent variation,
there's some variation,
but it's not independent.
Then you add gender expression on top of
that.
You say,
well,
the vast majority of people who are have
one biological sex and the same vial on
the same gender express that the same
way.
And almost all of those,
we could say 97% it's probably more like
98% but maybe it's 95 I don't care.
Have the sexual orientation that you
would expect if you knew their
biological sex,
their gender identity and their gender
expression.
So the idea that those are very
independently,
it's like,
okay,
fine.
But what that means is that you either
don't know what the word independently
means or you don't care or you've
defined it,
you've redefined it completely.
Well,
he can't just muck about with the law.
That way,
you know,
you can't instantiate a philosophical
viewpoint into the law without noting
what you're doing,
especially if it's palpably false.
And this entire,
uh,
and this is partly the reason that I
objected to the thing to begin with.
It's like
apart from these logical and tenability,
given the infinite multiple
multiplication of potential identities,
apart from the fact that there's no
consensus whatsoever on what set of
pronouns you should even hypothetically
use apart from the fact that,
um,
your identity is as socially negotiated
phenomena at its core.
Well,
there's the ultimate foolishness of the
proposition that there's no relationship
between these four levels of the manner
in which human beings conceptualize
themselves.
And that's all tangled up in this one
piece of legislation,
which is why
the idea that people should have the
right legal right to force other people
to recognize the particular game that
they're playing at that moment is it's
multidimensionally observed and worse
than that,
it's dangerous.
And now we'll complete with that.
The reason that it's dangerous as far as
I can tell is because it's also the
expression of an underlying all call it
ideology.
You could call it a philosophy,
but I don't think it actually qualifies.
Although,
and it's mostly postmodern and the
postmodernist are very smart people.
But you know the smart ones,
but their uh,
their,
their notion of what truth and reality
is debatable at best and pathological at
worst and that that's a problem because
this kind of legislation,
he emerges immediately out of that
philosophical context and philosophy
matters.
It's the axioms by which you Orient
Yourself in the world.
Those things mattered.
And if you write a whole new set of
axioms into the law,
which we've already done by the way,
they're going to unfold the unfold
according to their inner logic and you
don't have any choice about that.
They unfold in some sense all by
themselves.
Just like if a virus invades your body,
it unfolds all by itself.
You think little bitty virus,
great big body.
Well don't be thinking that the law has
a virus.
Laws are viruses.
There's something alive.
You add them to an ecosystem.
That's what we are.
They're going to do whatever their
internal logic demands and we're going
to see how that turns out over time.
And I've seen this sort of thing
happened before when when people walk
down this particular philosophical path,
and I suppose this is the point where
people accuse me of scaremongering,
but I have watched that sort of thing.
It's like the axiomatic presuppositions
nested inside this legislation assume
that human beings have no intrinsic
nature.
And what that means is that they can be
remolded in any manner whatsoever by the
state.
While we've watched that happen,
I wouldn't recommend it.
And so it's for all those reasons that I
think that the proposition is false,
the law is observed to the point of
incoherent error.
It's actually wrong.
It's not just bad law,
it's actually wrong.
And to boot,
it's,
it's dangerous and it's not least
dangerous because
it actually constitutes forced speech.
And that's a difference.
That's a very different thing from just
saying that there are things you
shouldn't say because you'll upset the
polity,
you know?
Fair enough.
But that's not the same thing at all.
It's saying there are things you have to
say because you have to act and speak in
accordance with this particular
philosophical view of human beings.
Good enough.
[inaudible].
All right,
three points I wanted to respond to.
Number one,
the,
the force question.
Number two is the matter of the infinite
number of pronouns,
you know,
one per person.
And the third one
is the question of whether identity is,
uh,
is a negotiated matter.
All right,
so on the,
on the force question,
we agreed on this.
We are talking about forced speech.
No question.
This is not a question about what you,
you know,
really ought to do in polite society.
No,
we're talking about what the law says
and what the love will make you do.
And if you don't do it,
maybe not immediately,
but eventually the cops will come.
So no bones about it.
We're talking about serious stuff here.
It's not just preferences,
it's what the state requires you to do.
So the stakes are high,
no doubt about it.
Oh,
on the infinite number of pronouns
matter.
However,
I mean you,
you can see that that would be
problematic if in fact we took the
proposition to its logical extension
without pulling it back a little bit.
Then yeah,
if everybody is allowed to pick their
own pronoun,
then it obviously becomes unworkable
because you can't,
they can't make sense of it if you're
the teacher.
I mean you can't keep track.
I can't,
can't keep track of people's first
names,
much less their pronouns.
So yeah,
if you get to the stage where there are,
you know,
13 different,
some classifications for the kinds of
gender identity that you want,
then I think the law is going to say,
well actually no.
What enabled us to do is in the first
place was reasonable limits on free
speech and now the requirements are
unreasonable.
What we're talking about here is really
the ability to insist upon a gender
neutral pronoun.
If we got so far as to say that you can
pick our own pronoun,
then I don't think the arguments that I
made before really apply like he's now
you're into real absurdity.
Right?
So this is not a limitless thing.
It is not suggested.
Everybody has their limits.
Limitless ability to insist upon the
language to be used by other people.
All we're saying is that there is a
logical and reasonable case to be made
that there needs to be something that is
neutral.
Maybe one,
maybe a couple,
I'm not going to give a number to it,
but granted if we get to a situation
where there is an unlimited number,
then fair enough.
That seems out of hand to me.
Number three,
identity as a socially negotiated
matter.
Well,
there's some truth to this.
Yes.
In the outside world as you are
interacting with people,
forming relationships with people,
uh,
of whatever kind,
maybe friendship,
maybe intimate,
maybe you're starting a family.
I mean your,
your gender identity is important to
those people too and so yes,
there is certainly an of social
negotiation in your gender.
What
that negotiation's not taking place with
your teacher.
It's not taking place in the classroom.
The teacher doesn't have to know what
that negotiations about.
It doesn't have to know its outcome.
Okay.
As far as the teacher is concerned,
all he or she or it needs to know is
what you want to be called in the sense
of one or the other or neither.
That's all.
Let's try this analogy.
The
the point is that gender should be
irrelevant in the classroom.
Just like race should be irrelevant in
the classroom.
So if we had a situation in the English
language were different races were being
referred to by different pronouns,
we might find that a little bit of Horn
because it doesn't matter.
Why would you distinguish between
someone who was white and someone who
was dark?
Same question with gender.
Why do you need to distinguish between
someone who was he and someone who was
chic?
It can if you want to and it's okay with
them,
but the point is you don't need to in
order to carry on the task you're
supposed to be performing.
So if that person doesn't want to fit
into that binary,
well then what's the big deal?
I think I'll leave it there.
[inaudible]
well,
you know,
it's hard to argue with the
reasonableness of the vast majority of
that statement set of statements,
but it's the,
the acceptability of the argument is
predicated on whether or not that degree
of reasonableness is actually already
built into the law or will be.
And my suspicions are actually that at
some point it will be,
but I can tell you that there's going to
be a lot of carnage before them because
my worthy opponent basically pointed out
as I did previously,
that the idea that we can evolve into a
near infinite set of pronouns by the
way,
which the Ontario Human Rights
Commission policies already essentially
recognize.
So they've already admitted that
although I'm certain server Julie
certain that the people who formulated
the policies really have no idea when
they formulated that this was going to
go beyond he,
she and they,
they had no idea that like within five
years that'd be 71 different gender
identities and a set of pronouns
associated with each.
So I think this multiple kid
multiplicative explosion that's
occurred,
caught them by surprise.
They wouldn't have formulated the
legislation that way to begin with.
I think if they would've had the
foresight to see what happened,
but you never know,
but all right,
so,
but back to the idea of these reasonable
limits.
Well,
I think that as these matters are forced
through the courts,
up to the Canadian Supreme Court,
that these sorts of limits will in fact
be imposed that we'll find that it
isn't,
people don't have the legal right to be
addressed by whatever pronouns they
choose because we run into precisely the
problems that we've been discussing.
But the problem is is that as the
legislation is currently constituted,
which is more or less what we're
discussing,
we'll perhaps it should be constituted
in a manner that would sustain a supreme
court challenge.
If we're going to talk about should,
and I don't think there's a hope in hell
of it,
the way it's constituted right now would
withstand a supreme court challenge.
It'll depend on how they select the
Supreme Court justices and we'll see how
that turns out in the future.
Because already,
I don't know if you know this,
but the law has been put in place so
that the people who select our judges
are going to have to undergo mandatory
unconscious bias retraining before
they're allowed to sit on the
committees.
And so while you can think about that,
and if you want to,
I recommend looking into the validity of
the tests that are used to diagnose,
so to speak,
unconscious bias,
because they don't even,
they don't even come close to meeting
the necessary requirements for a
clinical diagnostic instrument.
And there's absolutely no evidence
whatsoever that unconscious bias
retraining produces the intended results
and a fair bit that it actually produces
the opposite.
So we could easily be in a position
where the supreme court itself becomes
pathologized by this process to the
point where they won't invalidate the
law.
But under the current circumstances,
I would say it is inevitable that they
would,
but people are going to pay a fish's
price for that.
It's no,
it's no simple matter to fight a vicious
piece of vicious ill written
pathological piece of legislation all
the way up through the court system to
the Supreme Court and the number of
people who have the emotional
wherewithal to manage that.
The strategic resources,
the intelligence,
the team and the finances are there.
They're just nonexistent.
There might be like two people like that
in Canada,
you know,
I mean as her Levant did something like
that with the Alberta,
the Alberta human rights tribunals into,
you know,
just about did him in financially he's a
tough guy.
I'm pretty emotionally stable but it's
no joke.
So you know,
my proposition is that the law is kermit
currently formulated,
is observed,
it's a dirt multidimensionally it's bad
law.
And my opponents stated,
well essentially it will have to be made
reasonable.
It's like yeah,
okay,
no problem.
If it's made reasonable then it's made
reasonable.
But that isn't what we have now.
You might think of I,
I idea of ms cause that's actually not a
bad comparison,
you know.
But I'd like to point out that there
were never any legal penalties for not
using miss ever.
And language just doesn't change that
way.
It never changes by legislative fee up.
That isn't how it works.
It changes,
especially in English,
it's bottom up process because the word
is a tool actually.
It's not a description for a thing.
And what happens is that if you invent a
good tool,
any of you can do that.
If you invent a word that fix and and on
all the linguistic monkeys,
I was there waiting for that tool,
they'll pick it up just like that.
And the truth of the matter is is that
no one's come up with that particular
linguistic pro tool to solve this
particular problem.
And that's an indication that there
actually isn't a solution to it yet.
And that's partly because it's an
exceptionally complicated problem.
And so the idea that that should be
solved in some sense by ill conceived,
ill written,
philosophically untenable legislation
that has a,
I would say pathological impunitive
philosophy at its face is it's not a
tenable proposition.
And it's certainly not the law as it
currently stands.
So I guess that stopped for my,
my rebuttal.
Thank you.
Okay.
We'll start taking questions.
Sure.
Okay.
I have a question for a doctor.
Keiter said that I think doctor,
any sort of already great and I was just
wondering it to speak to it a bit more
directly when we're talking about
whether you can or someone to refer you
or refrain from referring to you in
different ways.
I guess one issue that I'm having
difficulty,
one of up thrown down is I think we all
acknowledge that you have a right to
force people to refer to you in certain
ways.
If a professor was at a class and they
had a student who insisted on calling
them a girl,
then they were male or you know,
calling them clear or something,
or I can think of way worse words,
it would say,
well that's,
that's not a pronoun and that's a
derogatory label.
That's just meant to degrade me.
Um,
but if you know who's to say what is a
pronoun and I'm not sure that it
necessarily would change.
Um,
if 95 or 97 friends all insisted on sort
of,
um,
degrading or you know,
using that pejorative label,
uh,
to the person.
And I think that people who are
transgendered or whatever do experience
when people use the wrong gender labels,
do they,
they've experienced real predators.
They experienced that as kind of
oppressive in that way.
So I don't know if identity is a subject
or an object,
but,
um,
but I do know that we placed important
demands on one another.
I don't,
I don't know that nature,
but I know that fundamentally like our
society is going to work better if we
respect each other.
And I think history bears bears that out
and that,
that self respect and allowing people
self identification to play a role in
that,
that public aspect.
Um,
we do already have limits on how people
can refer to each other and they're
informed by how people want themselves
to be referred to.
Okay.
Well that's a of questions.
So I'm not trying to be a smart Alec
both.
It's just not going to have to sort that
out for a minute.
He could up.
The first thing I would say is,
you know,
pro pronouns,
and I'm not a linguist to,
I'm not going to be able to whip this
off the top of my head,
although I do know that,
um,
there is a psychologist named James
Pennebaker who's written a whole book on
pronouns,
which she might be interested in
referring to.
And pronouns turned out to be
extraordinarily important as signifiers,
but they're also part of what's called a
closed linguistic category and they
don't change.
And so that's something that's useful to
know,
but you also bring up the distinction or
the lack of distinction or made a lack
of distinction between adjectives and
pronouns.
And that's pretty interesting because
there's no real reason why if you can't
insist upon which Pronoun I used to
address you,
you can also assist on which adjective I
use to address you.
And there's a lot more adjectives and,
and so that's cause I don't see like,
if you can choose your Damn Pronoun,
why can't you choose your adjective?
You know,
I mean adjectives are you the list of
words you listed as pejorative.
We're actually not pronouns.
They were adjectives.
And so you can,
you can object to them.
And there's no shortage of times when
you use a pejorative adjective to
describe someone,
especially if you believe that they've
misbehaved.
It's like if the person can insist upon
their pronoun,
why can't they insist upon your
adjective?
And that's another part of this problem
with this multiplicative complexity that
it isn't addressed properly within the
law.
With regards to respect,
you know,
you said,
well,
human civilization progress is a lot
better if we respect one another.
And I actually don't believe that at
all.
I believe that human civilization,
pr progress's and maintains itself.
When we respect people who've earned
respect,
you don't just respect everybody
randomly.
Well,
what the hell uses respect?
If you just respect people randomly,
it's like inflating the currency.
You know,
it's like the simpsons episode where you
know,
Bart gets a trophy because it's every
child gets a trophy day.
All you do is inflate the currency.
Respect is actually limited to that
category of people who've earned respect
in some manners.
So whatever you're talking about with
regards to say common decency between
people,
it's not respect and did definitions
actually matter.
They matter a law.
And so I hear the respect argument all
the time,
but you also can't force me to respect
you.
I mean you might be able to force me to
act like I respect you,
but you can't force me to respect you.
It's just not possible.
And you could break me I suppose in and
then perhaps I would do it,
although I can't see exactly how we
precisely.
But um,
so,
so there's a number of,
I mean I,
I get your point and I'm not trying to
denigrate it in any sense.
There's a complex issue here,
which is to what degree do you allow
individuals to,
to govern the conversation that's had
about them in their presence or
otherwise.
But I would just back to my original
argument,
which is that's a negotiation.
It's either in negotiation,
you got three states can negotiate with
someone,
you can be their slave or you can be,
they're tired and I would pick
negotiation.
But as far as I'm concerned,
the law right now as it's currently
instantiated,
is a tyrant and it makes people into its
slave and we're going to pay for that.
And it's paid predicated on
hypothetically on respect and
compassionate.
I don't buy that for a second.
I don't think that's true in the least.
And there's a huge literature on
compassion.
Here's a problem with compassion.
Mother grizzly bears are very,
very compassionate towards their cubs.
But if you get near those cubs,
they'll tear you to pieces.
And that's the flip side of compassion.
And I'm speaking not as a lawyer here,
but as a psychologist that's already
well documented.
Compassion is by no means an emotion
that produces the desired social
outcome.
Quite the contrary.
Life is very much more complicated than
then.
Well,
if you were just empathic,
everything would work out.
It's like you can't meet William Pathic
to everyone and that's a big problem.
So,
so I've answered some of your questions,
you know,
we'll address it,
some of them,
but that's about the best I can do it at
the moment.
Your take on,
it seems like every time on every step
of the quality rates,
this slippery slope argument comes up
and the courts and society solve that
issue that you think that those are air
path.
It's a tough one because you know,
I think it was yoga.
You'll be there if he said something
about things are hard to predict,
especially the future.
Just kind of Nice line actually.
But that's the problem with slippery
slope arguments,
you know?
But I don't think I'm making a slippery
slope argument because I think I'm
objecting to the law as it's currently
instantiated,
not as how it will be.
It's all,
we have already written his social
constructionist philosophy into the law
that's already there.
Now what the consequences of that will
be.
I can't tell,
but one of the problems is it's wrong.
It's factually wrong.
It's,
it's statistic.
Sorry.
Actually it's statistically wrong.
That's the problem because the
insistence is that those factors that I
described independently very,
which is a,
it's a predicative social
constructionist and postmodern is
thinking,
but it's incorrect.
There's no evidence whatsoever for it
unless you gerrymander the notion of
independence.
And you know,
once you start doing that,
that's a big problem.
So,
so I s you know,
so I stand by my initial documentation
of the errors in the law.
And I do think by the way that,
assuming the things continue on their
current jurisprudential course,
which is debatable,
you know,
the Ontario Human Rights Commission and
it's in the powers that it's abrogated.
It's being given by the,
by,
uh,
by the legislative.
It
has the right to suspend normal tier of
jurors,
prudential procedure and also precedent.
So you might want to look that up cause
that's a real fun thing to read.
So if society continues on its current
course and the courts operate under
their current presuppositions,
then this law will be subject to the
limits that you described and so could
be,
but like I said,
there's going to be carnage along the
way
are there.
So I just want to bring you a little bit
of facts into this cause I know you're
talking to those get carried away,
but box unfortunately along both sides.
So I don't have it.
Mr. Peterson suggested,
uh,
the,
the key distinction here,
and this is,
this is me talking now,
not that the advocate,
the key distinction is that this
legislation doesn't prevent you from
doing something.
It requires you to do something that is
now outrageous proposition.
Outrageous
it speaks is bad enough because it is a
significant step away from California
crime.
Now,
there are some restrictions on free
speech and Mike and which are
appropriate counseling a crime,
just watching defamation might be,
although that has some problems,
but Kelsey and crime is the best
situation where you shouldn't be allowed
to say that,
but,
but hate speech is an expression of an
opinion about nobody in particular
about,
it's about a group.
Now,
if you have an individual who believes
those things about a group,
you know,
lots of people including me,
would say that's unfortunate.
But if you're living in a free society,
you're supposed to be allowed to say
what you think,
even if other people don't like it.
And RFN is the essence of free speech is
to be able to offense,
not to Burns back offense or were you
well,
I'm going to answer that more or less as
a psychologist.
So what are the tenants of clinical
therapy including psychiatry and it's
say nonmedical forms is that
dialogue is curative.
That's actually the fundamental
proposition.
Um,
uh,
the thing about having someone in
therapy is,
you know,
and they're often like everyone bent
over shape quite badly.
Sometimes homicidal,
sometimes homicidal is good enough and
her 10 and vengeful and you know,
and for good reason often,
no,
no joe,
good reason.
If you were in their shoes,
you'd feel the same way in all
probability.
You have to let those people talk.
You have to let them talk.
They don't even know what they think
until they talk.
You know,
you think,
you
think and then you talk.
It's like,
no,
you don't.
You know,
most people can't think at all.
And I don't mean that in a pejorative
sense.
It's very,
very difficult to learn to think because
to think you have to hold an argument
between two opposing positions in your
own head.
Do you have to delineate both positions?
And you have to make like,
no,
not a straw man out of either.
You want to make and Sam Harris
Tournament an iron man or both and then
you have to do that alone.
It's like,
yeah,
maybe you can do that if you're
Dostoyevsky,
but because he's the only person I've
seen who's really managed that
consistently,
but to expect anything other than an
unbelievably well trained mind to even
even step into that territory is naive
beyond belief.
Almost everyone thinks by talking,
they don't even know what they think
until they speak.
And so often if you let people speak,
they'll think they'll speak and they'll
say,
you know,
and then they become aware of some
internal contradictions or maybe they
shock themselves.
That happens a lot.
It's like,
Whoa,
I can't believe I said that.
And they hear what they have to say.
It's being revealed themselves to
themselves.
Geez,
that just enough,
right?
There is often enough to change them.
But,
but even if it isn't,
let's say they're particularly
intransigent and we're not debating
about whether hate speech exists because
bloody well,
right?
It exists and it can be unbelievably
pathological and I think I'm actually
quite familiar with that sort of thing,
but you want that out in the air so that
people can hear it.
You want to drive the people who hate
underground.
We know what happens psychologically
when you do that,
it's a very bad idea.
Anything you drive underground thrives.
It thrives and it partly thrives because
it isn't even allowed to express itself
and then it festers and turned into,
it turns into hatred that far exceeds
the original and the idea that you make
society safe by not letting horrible
people say terrible things.
It's like it's,
it's not a good crop position.
You want those people out in the open
where they can say what they have to say
first of all so they can see what
they're like,
second of all,
so that they can see how people respond
because you don't even know what you
should think in some sense until you
watch how people respond.
You know at some,
well I won't go on and on about that,
but it's,
it's,
and then the question,
if there's other questions,
who defines ate cheese?
That's a deadly one.
It's like it's great if you're on the
left and the left is in power because
the left defined statement there are
going to be in power forever,
man.
And as soon as the people who were on
the opposite side come into power,
they're gonna use whatever arguments you
had and their own and whatever you think
is going to be hate speech like right
now.
So you should always,
and this is what the founders of the
American constitution get,
you know,
they always thought,
okay,
how could a absolute mlevel malevolent
full screw this up?
They never thought,
well how can we establish the Utopia?
So that's what you're always thinking
when you're putting a limit on something
including someone else's speech.
It's like,
okay,
how could the most malevolent fool
imaginable screw this up the worst
possible way and then presume that will
happen and then take steps so that that
isn't how it turns out.
So you are let the people who have,
who have horrifying viewpoints express
them,
you know,
subject to these limitations because you
want to make them into martyrs.
That's what happened with Gif.
I can't say it properly cared wheel
dues.
He's right.
Yeah.
The Dutch ship who's leading the polls
by the way,
and who has a pretty decent chance of
winning the election.
They nailed him for hate speech and his
popularity went up like 4%.
It's like,
it doesn't seem like very smart move to
me,
but I'm sure he's not too unhappy about
it,
you know?
And it might be that the fate of the
rest on his shoulders,
maybe not.
Maybe it's marine Le Pen
in the center.
Then you both mentioned the difference
between different degrees,
uh,
laws that are telling you not to say
something,
which is a lot of people.
I wonder if you could talk more about
that or why you think one is more
extreme in the other way.
Both seem to be imposing some
dishonesty.
Well,
I don't think that laws that restrict
your speech in the ways that we've been
describing are any good either.
I think they're both,
um,
tyrannical.
Uh,
but the,
the requiring you to use a word that is
not actually in the dictionary yet.
I mean,
I said,
I suggested that language was
evolutionary and it is,
language does change and it may well be
that we get this kind of a pronoun
sooner or later.
I'm not objecting to that at all.
I think that kind of a problem from that
would be kind of cool.
Probably very appropriate.
And civilized society.
It's not the word I'm talking about when
I,
when I'm criticizing it.
It's the idea that we should be changing
language by statute.
That is the problem.
That means that language is now
considered to be in the purview of the
state.
No,
not,
not a free country.
Um,
so,
um,
that's what I'm asking,
answering your question,
but I just think,
I mean they're both bad.
Just one's more extreme than the other
one is.
So.
So let,
let me tell you about an experiment.
So you know,
people think,
they think,
which we've already gone through and
they do that only to a limited degree
because thinking is hard.
And most of you do that by talking.
Um,
but people also think they know what
they're talking about when they say
something in general and if they don't,
and I'm not being cruel about this,
like imagine I asked one of you to come
up and draw a helicopter on the board.
It's like,
you know,
you're going to draw it like a
helicopter,
a five year old draws.
It's going to be like a box with a
beanie on top of it that the stick out
the aspect helicopters like no,
that's going to help you.
Like you don't,
what you don't know about helicopters
would still many volumes.
You're knowledge is sufficient to
communicate kind of an abstracted
representation and a lot of your thought
is actually like that.
You don't know as much as you think you
know.
And so,
and that means you're more vulnerable in
many ways than you think.
And so here's an example.
Let's say I bring you into the lab and I
get you to fill out a political
attitudes questionnaire and I localize
you say pathway beacon center and
radical,
something like that.
Maybe an NDP territory or something like
that.
And then I ask you to write a 500 word
essay about why corporations are a
blessing.
Okay,
now so you don't agree with it.
Yeah,
yeah.
I know you don't agree with it,
but like try to write a decent essay.
If you'd run a good one,
I'll give you like an extra 10 bucks or
something,
whatever,
50 bucks,
whatever.
So you write out this essay and it's
contrary view point and I'll bring you
back the next week and I give you the
same political attitudes questionnaire.
What do you think happens?
You've moved substantially towards the
right.
And so if I regulate what you have to
save,
I regulate what you think.
And you might think no,
but you're wrong.
Because what you think,
what you say,
especially if you do it eventually
determines what you think.
And,
and I am not willing to cede that to the
state,
but also,
but not only because I object,
especially to this particular
philosophical in banding of this
particular statute to say,
but also because you see your stupid
opinion is the corrective for the
states.
Stupid opinions,
like we've all just swamped in ignorance
and stupidity.
It's just,
it's a human condition and states are
horrible.
Tyrannosaur tyrannical messes and
individuals are like corrupt and blind.
And so it's amazing.
We can stumble around in the world at
all.
But what you hope is that now and then
some Dingbat Otter is something vaguely
sensible that helps curb the tyranny of
the state.
And you're going to have to let a lot of
stupidity be aired before any pearls of
wisdom emerge to the surface.
So you have to let people stumble around
like prejudice morons because that's
what they are.
But hopefully as they stumble and
listen,
they can become a little less appalling.
And so can this state,
and that's,
no,
you told me envision.
I can tell you that's for sure,
but,
but I've never seen a utopian state and
I'm certainly never seen a perfect
person.
So it seems pretty perfectly reasonable
to me to three of them be exactly that
matter.
Don't let people inside your head.
It isn't a lot of obvious that they know
what they're doing.
So,
yeah.
Yeah.
Um,
so I,
I had a thought while you both were
talking.
Um,
and it seems like the sort of genesis of
this debate comes from people who they
feel as though the current words don't
describe them accurately.
No,
there are men who feel like women and
vice versa.
Then there's people who don't feel like
either applied.
And I think you're Mr. Peterson.
I think you're right to point out that
there's a kind of weird flip that occurs
where it's no longer that the language
doesn't describe them.
It's that the language has to sort of
point out their exact identity and
uniqueness.
And I think maybe a way to sort of
reframe the idea is not to have a
language that has to cater to every
single person,
but sort of a singular term that can,
didn't know whether or not someone wants
to partake in the current structure of
language.
So he or she,
and then if you had a third term that
didn't have to have any connotations of
gender but rather stood for the
proposition that they know they don't
associate with you or sheet.
And that way you can leave it sort of
facially neutral to any particular
person.
Well,
maybe not.
Maybe reasonable legislation would mean
set up in that manner,
you know?
But I would say let's democratize the
problem.
As soon as someone comes up with a
solution that people find usable,
it's like,
it's like ms,
it's like I use ms,
you know?
I think it's kind of,
that's useful.
You know,
I'm actually more comfortable using it,
I would say.
And I,
you know,
I kinda gone point people didn't want to
have their marital status advertise
publicly didn't seem necessary.
Well,
women aren't the same as they were a
hundred years ago.
Right.
And they're not even close to the same
pill was a biological revolution.
Everything's flipped upside down.
So we needed a new word.
Okay.
We came up with one wasn't,
it wasn't implemented by force,
was implemented by public opinion and
that's,
that's how it English in particular,
like the French French is a bit
different because they actually have
committees to decide what constitutes an
acceptable word,
especially in France,
but also in Quebec.
But in English it's like,
it's the Commons man.
Throw a word out there.
If you,
if you've,
if you've nailed the problem,
people will pick that up so fast.
You can't even believe it.
They will just spread virally.
Well,
we don't have that solution.
And why is that?
Well,
because we don't know how to solve this
problem.
And so the law legislators come along
and say,
well you,
so by asking each person to tell you
what to say,
it's like,
no,
sorry,
wrong plus dangerous plus motivated and
a variety of other things.
So,
so sure fine could work,
you know,
but I can't decide if that work because
there's a strange idea now for some
reason that in some sense the world is
obligated to validate your identity and
that ain't that.
So it's just,
and so you deal with the world as it is,
as we all do.
And if a word comes along with it works,
it will be used by people because people
are interacting in negotiating.
It doesn't happen because there is a
legal idea that the world has to respond
to your needs.
It's just not the case.
If the world is required to,
to validate your identity,
you are done for,
and the reason for that is that every
single one of you have a pathological
direction in which you are likely to go.
And that's because every temperamental
virtue comes with a temperamental bites.
And so the only,
you know,
you think you were saying,
it's like you're not,
you're not even close.
If I put you alone in a cave for two
weeks,
you'd be done.
Oh,
he can't.
You can't be saying on your own.
And so what happens is that your
parents,
if they have any sense,
train you roughly speaking to be vaguely
acceptable to other people and they keep
nudging and winking at you every time
you're a moron so that you,
you get nudged into something
approximating acceptable and you're
clued in enough to pay attention.
So when someone raises an eyebrow or
does it find your job funny or something
rather subtle like that,
you immediately revise your identity.
And we're always nudging and tapping
each other nonstop,
exchanging information about how to stay
sane.
And if I'm forced into a position where
I have to validate your identity,
it's like,
what if your identity is wrong?
What if it's pathological?
What if it doesn't serve you well?
And I start validating.
You think I'm your friend.
I'm not your friend at all.
I'm a mirror for your narcissism and you
will disappear and drown.
And I see this happening all the time
with people.
Like if you're fortunate,
you're surrounded by people who like you
now and wish you'd be a little better
and they'll let you know when you're
failing on that and then you think you
don't even have to think that much.
All you have to use watch.
It's like,
is this person like rolling their eyes?
It that's a bad one that predicts
divorce by the way.
And you get to Ireland and stage,
that's not good.
But basically,
you know you're,
you're fortunate that people don't
validate your damn identity.
It's like what makes you think you've
caught your identity?
Figure note,
you're really complicated and you're
clueless as hell about it because he
can't represent yourself entirely.
You're the most complicated thing that
exists.
How are you going to come up with an
accurate definition of your identity?
You got a hundred people out there
helping you out.
If you've got any sense,
if you're vaguely tolerable and you know
they're kind of hinting at you what not
only what you are but what you might
become.
Man,
you should welcome invalidation,
validation of your identity.
Now malicious,
well that's a different story but it's,
it's not that easy to separate out
accurate criticism,
especially if it hits you right where it
hurts,
which is where you're wrong.
You can't separating that out
maliciousness or hate speech.
It's like good luck,
good luck.
You never learned anything without pain.
And often when you receive a piece of
corrective information from someone,
so like if you could throw that person
in jail,
you would,
that doesn't mean they're wrong.
So do you have a question?
Yeah,
the question.
So looking at the past three years,
cause we do have that benefit,
but we have the human race Rev.
You know there has been case law but it
hasn't just been pronoun use,
right?
It's attached to other forms of
harassment.
So I would kind of pause it that that's
what we're going to see,
that it's going to be usually cases of
employers or uh,
you know,
hockey Canada and not allowing a mentor,
someone who identifies as a man took to
change in the locker room,
that kind of thing.
So does,
does that change your opinion knowing
that,
you know,
so far with the case all we do have,
has it been a freedom of speech,
isolated incident?
It doesn't,
it doesn't,
although I'm not disagreeing with what
you said.
The problem is as far as I'm concerned,
that,
and this isn't something I addressed
earlier,
is that bad legislation will be cooptive
by people you just cast and despise.
And so even if these people are
reasonable,
as soon as problem is,
as soon as you put bad law in place,
bad people rushing to enforce it.
And so you're basically stating while
there's a human rights organization,
say it's so,
so societal organization,
it's been reasonable and it's,
it's,
it's a decision so far,
which are not completely convinced the
wait,
but you know,
so they made some mistakes that happens.
But the idea that under the current
legal conditions with this particular
legislation in place,
those are the same people that are going
to be running it in the near future is
wrong,
is that people who want this kind of
power will rush in to take it.
That's exactly,
it always happens.
So it certainly happened in this
situation.
It's like imagine an insurance company.
So you're,
you worked for an insurance company and
you have to decide if grandma gets her
cancer treatment.
Well,
if you're the least bit compassionate,
your last,
call it 15 minutes and not yours because
every day you're making absolutely
brutal,
brutal decisions and you have to,
because the insurance company doesn't
have an infinite amount of money.
Well,
so what happens to people in those
positions while either quit or they get
hard hearted as hell or people who can
do just that with no problem occupy the
positions?
Well,
it's the same situation here.
Bad legislation makes bad rulers and I
think this legislation is,
it's,
it's so bad.
It's almost unbelievable.
You know that if you're an employer,
you're basically responsible for all the
inaction or action of your employees.
If they offend someone,
whether or not that offense is
documented or not,
whether or not it was intended,
it's like who would write a piece of
legislation like that?
Well you can read the Ontario Human
Rights Commission's policies.
It's like it's their quick plain as day.
So no,
I don't trust the legislation at all and
I don't believe that it would be
reasonably enforced.
I think the courts will take it apart
over time,
but
it will cost some one and it could have
been me and still might be a lot,
a lot so
and other people will suffer while
that's happening.
That's how I,
that's how I see you.
Yeah.
So you've had your hand up for a long
time.
First of all,
even though I disagree with you,
thank you very much for coming to speak
with us.
Um,
I had sort of two quick points.
One of them like be more planning
question.
I thought it was interesting in response
to an earlier question.
You said something about pronouns being
a linguistically closed category.
I thought that was an interesting
concept because we've all been using the
singular you all night,
even though that historically didn't
exist in English.
So clearly things do change for announce
do change.
But my question for you is,
your concern was that pronouns could be
a sort of eliminate this category,
or at least that was my understanding.
We have limitless categories all over
the place.
Uh,
the charter recognizes that individual
people's conceptions of religion can
differ.
Names are limitless category.
Um,
so why prone,
why pronouns in particular concern.
And if you don't accept the front and
someone else tells you,
where should you get the pronoun to
refer to them as if they are not the
source of it.
What it's,
well,
I don't well
care what pronouns people want to be
addressed by.
And of course they have different names,
but I'm not required by forced to use
them.
So that's the fundamental
characteristic.
It's like it isn't whether or not you
can decide to use whatever pronouns you
want,
but you're,
that isn't what we're discussing.
We're discussing whether or not I should
be required by force.
Do you use the same pronouns?
And there's no such thing as a limitless
category,
by the way,
that's an impossibility because a
category,
you read your post modernists,
they figured this out.
Categories,
you acquire limits and limits,
exclude and marginalize.
It's the central doctrine of
postmodernism,
and so they're the critics of
categorization and that's why I'm
bringing them up.
If you know they're not friends of
categorization,
I'm making the argument for the enemies
of categorization.
And so there's no such thing as a
limitless category,
which is also actually by the way,
why the lgbt acronym universe keeps
multiplying is because they're actually,
what's actually happening is that there
is a category which you might consider
normative sexual behavior,
traditional sexual behavior,
and there's those who do not fit into
that category as well.
No one fits into that category.
So the category,
it's a category without limits.
That excluded is a category without
limits.
It's not a category.
It falls apart of the total in court.
It tends towards infinite multiplicity.
It has to because it contains an
infinite multiplicity and that will
manifest itself across time.
So,
um,
and then with regards to,
you know,
why we use the pronouns we used,
it's like,
well who knows?
I don't know.
It's,
it's partly I don't buy the youth thing
by the way,
cause it was valid before that.
And you know,
so there was still a marker in the same
linguistic category,
but,
and technically they are close to
linguistic categories.
So if they change,
they change very slowly.
But whatever,
you know,
I'm going to seed that.
But technically I think it's erroneous.
Can they transform much slower than
other categories for?
So let's put it that way.
So where do these come from?
It's common to use the comments,
man.
It's like everyone decided that over
some extended period of time and it
seems to work.
So people use it to,
and it's certainly not because of
subjective decision.
I mean that's an element yet obviously,
but it's only one who knows how many
elements we don't know.
Manny.
So,
all right,
well we're out of time.
Thank you very much for our participants
with Jack
[inaudible].
Herr Professor Party.
Argue devil's advocate because no other
law professor was willing to argue
because I think we all three agreed that
this was a very important conversation
and it was very satisfying.
Um,
so if you'd like to see more provocative
debates or get involved with us worth
thriving newsroom,
they're writing needs society.
We will be hosting our student
leadership conference in the summer in
the country in Ontario.
Do we have a lot of things around?
So thank you very much for coming.
And things.