There are coffees that have the drawings
as well.
Okay,
so you should have 343 pages and how,
how many drones are there?
Susan,
you have the many of drawings at the
back of your book
for four drawings
living in the middle.
Oh,
oh yeah,
those,
that's different,
right.
We'll do the origin the way
you might want to put those into the
backs of your book because that's what
you're supposed to be.
Well that's good.
That looks like everybody.
So at 14 people,
so that's a good stuff.
Okay,
so I'm going to lecture for awhile and
then what you should have read today was
the preface of the thing that you picked
up from noman coffee and the first
chapter which is called maps of
experience.
In terms of this book,
you should be reading it now and also
for the next class.
We'll go over this in some detail too,
so,
so I'll start,
if you have any questions,
feel free to ask them.
I'll try to leave at least half an hour
up to hand open for general discussion
and really like,
you know,
feel free to stop me at any point if
what I'm saying doesn't make any sense
or if you have some relevant associated
issue.
Okay.
Now the first thing we have to figure
out basically is what it is that we're
talking about in this course.
And uh,
that's so we have to establish the
domain of inquiry.
That's basically the purpose of today's
lecture.
Um,
the reason I got interested in this sort
of thing as I mentioned to you last week
was because I am interested in figuring
out why people are motivated to commit
acts of aggression.
Really atrocious acts of aggression
because that's the kind of I'm really
interested in in defense of their,
of their belief systems.
Probably mast if you can pull in
somewhere over there because they needed
a closer with you.
So if you guys could just cram together
a bit,
if you would,
maybe we
get a few more people in here.
Okay.
Now,
once again,
does everybody here have,
is some of us
okay?
And does everybody have this book?
Okay.
Is there anybody that wants this book?
All right.
Hi
Noman
coffee.
If you talked to the people that have a
clue,
they're binding it.
People have been getting bound copies
and if you don't get a phone call,
tell them it's supposed to be filed.
Okay.
Cause you don't want to pack that thing
around them about,
yeah,
I know they're doing the Mona order only
basis now.
Yeah.
Although I ordered eight for the
copies.
Yeah.
Well I didn't expect to get rid of 45
coffee.
So did you get one that didn't have any
high order?
That's what they're doing now.
No,
I also teach it at the extension school.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
So we're done with procedural issues
theoretically.
Okay.
Well reverse myself here again.
So what we're going to talk about today,
let's start the story again.
I got interested in what I'm going to
teach you about cause I was interested
in looking at motivation for social
conflict.
Maybe I can get you to shut the door so
disturb the whole smaller
Illinois
with regards to the videotape.
If you can ignore it,
that would be best.
There's no real purpose to it.
I want the videotape.
So it's not like you're going to be,
your comments are going to be one of the
children.
Anyone tried to just know to worry about
it.
Right
when I started giving some consideration
to the problem of motivation for social
conflict.
So I was interested in why people become
rigid in their ideological
identifications and their cultural
identities.
And I was interested in really why
individuals do that.
So I started to get interested in what
role social identity plays in
information processing,
which is hence the title of this course,
which is kind of wording and useless.
But the thing is everyone knows that we
have social identities and ideological
identities.
They're religious,
their cultural,
their intellectual,
whatever.
But nobody's really paid much attention
to study how the representations of that
cultural identity,
uh,
alter the manner in which we,
we feel emotion,
which perceive and by which we act.
I'm interested in how our internal
representations of our culture modulator
or emotional expression,
that's the best way to point and say you
know,
your brain basically is programmed as
you're socialized.
That's what socialization is for and
obviously it's socialization that
instills cultural identity and equally
obviously the process of socialization
that leads to cultural identity must
have some impact on the way you think
and obviously leave that on the way that
your mind functions and the way that
your brain functions and see North
American neuropsychologists have been
loath to give any consideration to this
sort of notion to think that cultural
transformations might have some direct
impact on physiological function by the
time the Russians.
By contrast,
this has been a central tenant of their
nurses neuropsychological theories
basically since since day one.
This is particularly true with regards
to Alexander Luria and uh,
uh,
what's his name,
the gods scheme.
Now you can think about this,
it's quite obvious if you think about it
for a second with regards to something
like the,
the capacity to read silently.
Now here's the case that,
well this is a relatively new talent.
I mean literacy is a new talent,
right?
Most people weren't able to read 500
years ago.
It's only been 500 years and only for a
little bit of that,
that the capacity to read has been
widespread and the capacity to read
silently is a relatively new development
in human history.
Now.
It's a cute your thing if you think
about it,
that nonetheless,
the capacity to read silently localizes
to a specific part of the brain,
which is to say it's as if you have a
part of the brain that's evolved for
that purpose.
It's the same place and everybody more
or less their individual variations.
There are differences when people are
lateralized differently,
but all that aside,
if you learn to read,
there's a part of your brain that
specializes for that and it's pretty
much the same place in every way and it
wasn't there or wasn't doing that sort
of activity 2000 years ago.
In fact,
I read at one point,
I don't know where the reference to this
is like so many things that I make
reference to,
but I've had at one point that people
thought Julius Caesar was a magician in
part.
I mean he was obviously a remarkable
person,
but in part because he can read
silently,
he didn't have to read a loud,
so it wasn't just reading.
That was remarkable.
It was being able to read without
talking.
Anyways,
the point of all of this is that
your brain,
this is [inaudible] view of the brain
fundamentally is your brain is an organ
that produces sub organs,
culturally specific subordinates,
not it's that's it's remarkable capacity
is that it can generate new molecules
that are specialized for certain tasks
as a consequence of environmental
programming.
This is an interesting sort of notion,
which is to say that at some level of
physiological there analysis,
at least your culture determines how
your brain works.
Now it's very classic.
You know,
your brain is very plastic.
When you were a child.
You can sustain immense amount of
cortical damage in childhood and still
grow up normally.
For example,
if you're a very,
very epileptic as a child,
sometimes what surgeons will do is take
out a whole hemisphere,
the whole right hemisphere gone.
And children who have hemisphere
activities,
if they're done young enough,
still grow up to be relatively normal,
quite normal.
In fact.
And there are other cases too where
people are hydrocephalic,
which basically means that they're
ventricles don't vamped properly.
Um,
and cerebral spinal fluid builds up in
the sculpt.
So these people often have stalls that
are slightly larger than normal,
not necessarily obvious,
but what steel case.
And they end up with a skull.
It's essentially full of liquid with a
very,
very thin layer of brain tissue around
this,
this all of liquid.
And,
uh,
there are a number of case reports of
people who have like 5% of the aquatic
and tissue intact who have high
functioning intelligence,
his normal personality.
So the point is,
you're,
especially the higher cortical levels of
your writing are very,
very functionally flexible.
We can childhood now by the time you're
an adult,
you know,
the pattern changes a little bit done,
kind of looks like your brain dies into
it's adult configuration.
That's an interesting we look at,
which is to say you have way more
neurons that you need,
especially right before you're born.
And a environment prunes your brain down
to its adult configuration.
So although of course you develop
connections as well,
but you lose a lot of neurons.
So,
uh,
and by the time you're an adult,
you're brain is nowhere near as flexible
as it was when you were a child.
And if you sustain damage to certain
parts of your brain that are already
specialized,
well and you know,
then you have the damage and you can
work around all that,
but it can still be really prominent
question.
So that's sort of the market and it's,
yeah,
that's right.
That's the department because it is the
rent adapts,
whereas the body,
yeah,
that's a great comment.
You know,
and if you start thinking about that,
it has really revolutionary implication.
So you can say,
for example,
if I have an idea that's really radical
and saying in a sense that changes the
configuration of my Cortex,
I can transmit that maybe not to you.
Maybe your brain is already fixed,
so to speak,
put down the generations and alter the
structure of brains,
hand spores.
So you could say,
well,
ideas can spread through a population
that way.
That's a lamarche and sprint.
But even more interestingly,
I think this is speculative of course,
but let's say that Tom,
there are certain types of revolutions
in thought that are actually the
consequences of biological mutations.
So you could see that,
well,
you're a particularly odd sort of person
from the genetic perspective and as a
consequence you think in a very,
very unique manner.
But the thing that's so interesting is
that if you can still communicate those
thoughts,
then the effect of that genetic mutation
can be transmitted throughout the
population without any biological
alteration at the genetic level at all.
So that's,
that's really something,
something that's interesting because it
means that the consequences of genetic
mutations on combination can spread
through a population as fast as
communication can move.
So that's,
yeah,
the Lamarckian does it,
everybody know what Lamar can
transmission is?
Well,
Lamarck was the character who thought
that the reason that that you could,
you could transmit acquired
characteristics.
So the reason drafts that long the x is
because it kept trying to stretch their
net is basically,
uh,
so,
and they transmitted the capacity to do
the stretching to their offspring.
So you can transmit acquired
characteristics down the genetic line
and there's no,
you can't do that,
that's wrong.
But that's what Lamar thought.
But he wasn't completely wrong because
there is,
that is how this sort of transmission
works.
It's non genetically mediated cumulation
of biological resources.
So that's very interesting.
So,
you know,
that's a good comment.
Okay.
Anyways,
so,
uh,
that's kind of,
that's,
that's some of the background of why I'm
interested in,
in the neuropsychology of culture.
And if you're interested in that sort of
thing,
you want to read the golf ski and you
want to read Luria.
Um,
because the Russians are really
interested in the effect of culture on
cognition and the regulation of emotion
on as far as I'm concerned,
like for a long time they were five
decades of hand of North American Europe
in terms of exploring this sort of
thing.
I'm not exactly sure why that is,
but that is the case.
So,
okay.
Well the first thing that I started to
started to realize I guess,
and this,
this is sort of an emergent realization.
It wasn't something that happened early
on when I was trying to develop these
ideas.
It became a way of making them clearer.
I started giving some consideration,
I guess to the old philosophical
distinction between facts and values,
no
values,
and you could say value.
That's kind of it in the domain of what
should be and uh,
or ethics and a fat.
Well that's kind of in the domain of
what actually is or what,
or what was more,
what could be,
you know,
taking the past,
present and future consideration as long
be known in philosophical circles that
you can make any,
you can't draw any conclusions about
what should be,
what ought to be from an analysis of
what is,
which is to say you can't derive an
ought from an nice,
and there's some sort of divide there
and you can sort of think of have this.
Um,
just knowing the particulars of the
situation doesn't mean that you know how
to act there.
And I think that's really where the
division takes place,
which is to say that come out with a
description of the characteristics of a
place.
Like let's say you were from a lower
working class family and you buy some
Miss Fortune.
You have to go to La,
a Tuxedo ball where there'll be nothing
but rich people.
You don't really know how to act.
You know,
you can describe the circumstances,
you basically know what it is that
you're going to encounter.
But that doesn't tell you anything at
all about how it is that you should
conduct yourself.
And the other thing that's kind of
interesting about that is that how you
should conduct yourself.
And this ties in directly to what we're
going to talk about today's game.
You want to or what goal you want to
pursue.
You know,
so you have to decide that a priority.
If you're going to go to this party,
you can say,
well I don't like people like that
anyways.
They're all capitalists exploiters and
they deserve my contempt.
And so I'll go there and act miserably
and make everyone just like,
and that would be perfectly fine.
And that's an,
that's an odd as far as you're
concerned,
that's some moral injunction and if you
accept that line of reasoning,
you're going to act one way.
And if your other line of reasoning as
well,
maybe I have something to learn in this
situation,
I'll just shut up and watch.
Then what towards the tubes,
the Ot under those circumstances to
something completely different.
So you know you can switch around.
What the should be is by determining
where it is that you want to go.
That's obviously not something you could
do with Fox,
like whether you want to be liked or
whether you want to be hostile.
It's nothing to do with like be the
objective aspects of the situation.
So yeah,
there's a real,
so that's a,
that's a problem.
So
that's sort of the background.
So let's go into this.
No,
we all know that people have belief
systems,
but we don't really know as far as I can
tell what that means.
It's like
Kevin belief system.
This analysis sort of suggest that there
isn't such thing is there,
there's no such thing as they belief
system is at the very minimum,
my belief system is composed of two
elements,
which is your description of how the
world is from the factual perspective
and also your description of how the
world should be.
Or You could say your interpretation of
the reality of phenomena.
It also your interpretation of how you
should act with regards to those
phenomena.
So at the very least when you're talking
about beliefs,
you're talking about something that has
to constituent elements
always be known for a long time.
Now it strikes me that there's a real,
there's an analogous division in human
cognition between fact and value that
you wait,
describe that as the division between
science.
Math.
Okay.
We don't really fight with people over
what things are from the scientific
perspective.
I think in part because
unless you're,
I emotionally identified with your
particular,
which basically means unless you're,
you imbued your theory with dreams of
career for example,
or dreams of prestige or whatever,
why don't you scientific theories pretty
much as good as the next,
which is to say that from the scientific
perspective,
all facts are equivalent.
They don't have any intrinsic emotional
significance.
You're supposed to be objective with
regards to your description of the
world.
We don't really have to fight about what
the world is.
From a scientific perspective.
It's partly because there's not so much
emotion involved in it.
All that happens sometimes that's more
of a contamination.
Then something central to the scientific
enterprise.
People are always trying to get rid of
that.
You don't mess around with your data to
make it turn out the way you want it to
because the way you want things to turn
out has nothing to do with the
scientific enterprise,
at least in part.
The other thing is from the scientific
perspective is we have a method of
solving arguments in the scientific
world.
Sorry,
you can put whatever you're competing.
Hypotheses are about the nature of
things to a task and in a sense if you
can't do that,
what you're talking about is probably
not scientific at all or that's what
funding at the very least.
So first of all,
there's not a lot of emotion and tangled
into scientific viewpoint.
You,
second of all,
if there is a problem,
a dispute,
we have a very,
very formalized mechanism for working it
out and people are usually willing to
abide by that because well,
it works.
It's,
it's demonstrated its utility from the
pragmatic perspective.
Plus it's comprehensible.
You can outline all the rules.
I mean,
we really have a strategy for that.
You don't even have to be very bright to
scientists.
All you have to do is be very thorough
and follow the rules.
This is a making explicit,
the scientific procedure that happened
about 500 years ago there boats,
we know how to,
we know how to come up with a
description of the world from the
sensory perspective that everyone can
agree with them.
We're less okay.
That isn't what we fight with people.
Yeah.
What's important to us is not what
things are so much as what they mean and
so then the question is,
well in a sense what does meaning me?
And that's much the same as asking what
is an emotion or what is a motivational
state or what does it drive state.
These things of what we have proved very
difficult to nail down in the past.
What's the meaning of meaning but well
aren't going to give you a provisional
definition.
And that is the meeting of something has
its implication for behavior.
And I mean that literally and behavior
is the act of propelling your body
through space.
That's at least one dimension of
meeting.
There are more profound levels of
meaning.
You could also say that something is
meaningful.
If it has implications for the Schema
that you use to generate behaviors,
that's a more profound piece of
information.
Something that's more profoundly
meaningful cause then a phenomenon and
event that occurs can change your
reaction to hold classes of the fans.
That's a really been phenomenal,
but we are not going to discuss that so
much today.
We'll just stick with the simple
definition meeting,
which is implication for behavior and,
well,
I'll give an example in the chapter that
you were to read today about a girl
little girl,
three years old or whatever she is
exploring her environment.
We tend to think that when someone's
exploring their environment,
what they're trying to do is map the
sensory properties of that which
surrounds them and that's how we think.
So the girl in the example I use,
well what she's wandering around
touching things and poking about using
all the exploratory tools that she
hasn't heard disposal,
some of which she thinks up and some of
what she coffees and she approaches a an
antique table and on top of the table
and there was a very fragile green glass
antique vase and she reaches up to touch
it in the course of her exploratory
activity and your mother immediately
shrieked no,
don't touch that.
Comes over and grabs her hand,
pulls it back six zero nine and it says
that's not something for you to touch.
Why don't you see
the girl has just discovered something
about what that thing is from the
motivational perspective,
which is to say,
well you can view that object is
something that has sensory properties,
but you can also view it as something
that has motivational significance.
Then the motivational significance in
this case for that child is ambivalent
because the thing is interesting,
it's green and it's shining.
The draws,
the explorer Tory candidates candidacy
out of the,
that she wants to approach it,
but it's also something that's linked
with punishment.
So that's an ambivalent phenomenon.
Much of what we do when we map our
environments is map them for
motivational significance.
No,
because we're so good at being
scientists or we have become so good at
being scientist for the last 500 years
or so.
We tend to think that when we mapped the
environment,
what we're mapping it,
four is it sensory properties,
but as far as I can,
first of all,
you think about it,
animals are not scientists,
so whatever they're doing is not a can
decide.
It's accepted,
it's more primitive and it's more
permanent form.
Whenever animals are doing is more like
whenever it was that we were doing
before we became sides.
So you could say,
well,
what was that we were doing whenever
that was 150,000 years ago or 250,000
years ago,
we still managed to Mac the environments
because we can live in,
I mean obviously we're all still here,
so our relatives were pretty good at our
ancestors were pretty good at doing
that.
We weren't doing it from the scientific
perspective.
We are doing something else.
What we were doing is mapping the
environment for implications for
behavior.
You see it when you really want to think
about this good and heart because if you
think about it,
it's,
it'll start changing the way you view
the world because it answers some
strange questions that are otherwise
difficult answers.
Like
why do you stop asking questions about,
you know,
from the scientific perspective that
you're surrounded by a certified of
mysteries.
There's nothing you comprehend.
Absolutely.
In your field of experience,
there's more questions about the factual
nature of things wherever you look,
but sometimes you ask questions and
sometimes you don't know what is it that
stops us in any given circumstance.
You can't answer that.
If you start thinking about how it is
that people think scientifically,
you can only answer it if you start
thinking about how does that people
think from the motivational perspective
because I can tell you that you'll stop
asking questions.
Say about like I don't know any of you
very well,
at least at the moment.
The fact that I don't know what you're
very well isn't compelling me to do a
tremendous amount of exploration because
I know you well enough so that I can
predict your behavior in this
circumstance,
which is to say that I have a very
detailed vision in my mind of where this
next two hours is going to go in terms
of the whole two hour period in every
sort of sub temporal aspect of that down
to the immediate present.
And as long as none of you violate my
preset positions,
I don't have to ask any questions about
you cause I've taught you math and
likewise for me,
as long as things go according to your
predictions,
you know the world and the thing you're
trying to predict is the,
the effect that your behavior has on
phenomena.
In terms of motivation.
So anyways,
so you can just sort of keep that in
mind.
So look,
as far as I'm concerned,
we think two different ways.
One way is being formalized and that's
the scientific way,
but the scientific enterprise is,
is the attempt to come up with an
accurate description of the sensory
properties of phenomena in so far as
those are collectively apprehensible.
But just to say that we want to know
what things are from the sensory
perspective and we engage in a
communicate an exercise to determine
that.
Because if I want to figure out what
this is from the scientific perspective
is much more effective.
If I could have a thousand people
working on it all at once and we're all
communicating our knowledge and we can
build out a very detailed picture of the
thing.
But the only reason we want to do that
so that we can track the motivational
significance of things more accurate to
say once again,
why does an animal care if something is
green rather than red?
Well,
it may be because being able to
discriminate colors.
Finally we're finally means more
accurate mapping of the motivational,
motivational relevance.
Just to say that if you can only see in
black and white for example,
if something that's the same hue red is
poisoning as something edible green,
well you've had it cause you can't
distinguish them.
If you can want to see black and white
know if you can see color,
which means you can make a finer level
of sensory discrimination.
You can keep better track of where the
good things are,
where the bad things are and as far as
I'm concerned,
that's really why we do science.
In the final analysis when you get like,
cause you've got to ask what's the
motivation for doing all these kinds of
things and looking at the fruit flies,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
We want to keep track of where the
motivational significance is up.
Things are and we can do that better by
making finer and finer discriminations
between things because then we could
say,
well this thing is that and this thing
is that and it's useful to be able to do
that.
What I don't understand the difference
between interest and value.
When a cat made me value the food days
batty,
that is not necessarily interested it.
Um,
but still he places value on it.
So I don't understand the word how that
works out.
Well things we are interested in,
things that have value.
So I don't think that I value having
interests.
So is normally don't think about food is
that it's interesting if you're a food
deprived and it's not if you're not.
So it depends on your,
it depends on your current state of
interpretation.
So you can never identify anything is
having interest as an,
an intrinsic aspect of that thing.
That's something we'll cover in more
detail too.
But if something is valuable to you,
your interest in the weather,
the valence is positive or negative so
that interests can fluctuate.
I mean you,
and when you ask a question like that
too,
you want to make sure that you
discriminated in your own mind.
The difference between the two terms
that you're using.
So there's obviously some overlap
between interest and value.
It strikes me that probably what you're
referring to is that um,
the things that have no specify
biological significance but that are
unpredictable are interesting.
Something like food is valuable.
So you might be able to say that the
interest is the more general phenomena
of value before it's being discriminated
into its sub components.
Okay.
Cause if something unexpected happens,
it attracts your interest,
which means that you value it but you
have no determination of the value of
yet.
You can only say here is something that
I didn't predict and then the purpose of
exploration is to is to put it into the
appropriate boxes or something that you
want to,
you want to give some consideration to
cause that's like in a sense that's one
of the most fundamental things that I
want you to to to learn is that when we
classify things using exploration,
we're not attributing meaning to
something that has a neutral background.
We're taking something that has a very
broad range of nonspecific meaning and
restricting it to something specific.
So,
for example,
we'll make it more cooperative and take
a wrap by the tail and you drop them
into a new cage.
Interest is everywhere.
It's not one specific.
The racks going to sit there like this.
First of all it's going to be paralyzed
because it doesn't move like it's motor
systems are inhibited by its anxiety
system.
It is not moving.
And the reason it's not moving,
well the rab doesn't know this but this
is what we would presume the reason it's
not moving is because
in novel territory there may be a
Predator and if you don't move and
predators can't see it,
so the route of sits there like this and
maybe it'll sniff a little bit cause
that doesn't draw any attention to
itself.
And if nothing happens that kills it
slowly it starts to unwind a little bit.
And then it's the systems,
the bda curiosity,
which are the incentive reward systems
technically start driving the route
around and the rattle explorer and what
it's trying to do is reduce the
nonspecific value of the novel
environment to something specified,
which,
which you could say in a sense.
Is there anything here that will hurt
me?
So it's looking for punishment.
It's actually looking to avoid them.
But once they know where the hell they
are,
is there anything here that will make me
anxious,
which is to say is there anything here
that signifies that the punishment is
likely?
Is there anything here that I can eat or
they will otherwise satisfy?
What am I consuming Tory requirements or
is there anything here that will signify
the presence of something that will
satisfy by conservatory reprivatise
those are four categories.
Punishment,
satisfaction,
right.
And hope basically.
And what the route is trying to do is to
restrict the indeterminate significance
of the normal circumstance to a
discriminant category.
Which is to say it wants to know exactly
where all the things that have
determined value are located.
Mostly it's going to map nothing cause
that's the alternative.
Calculates no relevance.
And most of the things around you,
our map into that box.
Like you'd think,
well your reactions in this room,
most of the phenomena in this room or
not attracting your attention.
And I mean you can,
you can divert your attention to them.
But you like those things,
those are irrelevant.
You know how had I not pointed them out?
Perhaps you'd remember they were there
and perhaps what they signify.
Nothing from the motivational
perspective so you've mapped them is
irrelevant in most of the things you map
are mapped as irrelevant.
That is now they start with no started
out as novel.
That's the fundamental,
that's the old position and
does the historical progression guess
say for the sake of argument,
the scientific method was establish more
last 500 years ago.
Say,
well it was at that point where are our
mythological models of reality and our
scientific split.
Now
I'm going to ask you to swallow a
presupposition for the time being and
that presupposition is that town.
It'll take me a while to explain the
logic behind it.
Look,
you know how you get scientific
information.
It's basically talk to you explicitly
and you can read experiments and you
read theories and so on are the explicit
education,
but how you pick up knowledge of how to
act well,
that's not quite as explicit.
It's not as easy to figure out.
I mean,
obviously you model,
we know that children pick up a lot of
inflammation by modeling behavior,
which is basic English is a big coffee
adults,
and that basically means they watch
adults act,
move their bodies who space and they
duplicate those patterns of action any
generalized from,
so that's one way behavioral wisdom
transmitting.
Some of it's explicit as well,
at least in terms of the receipt of
rewards and punishments,
because parents will modulate their
children's behavior by engaging in
motivationally significant interactions
with them.
At least that's what you should do if
you're a parent.
That's your primary responsibility in a
sense.
So that's what we mean when we say that
you're paying attention to someone.
It basically means that you're
modulating their behavior with your
behavior,
with your emotions.
So fuck a child will monitor,
our parent will monitor his child and
react positively when something that the
parent wants to happen happens and
native glee.
When something happens that the parent
doesn't want to happen.
So the child's behaviors,
well that's just the classical
reinforcement theory.
Basically you exchange rewards and
punishments and threats and promises and
more human behavior.
We do that all the time.
And your interpersonal interactions,
that's part of the reason why people
with personality disorders can sort of
have an uncanny effect on which is to
say if your personality disorder,
do you have a really potent expectation
about how someone else will behave?
Usually like a son of a bitch?
Fundamentally.
And if someone with a personality
disorder encounter someone who doesn't
back like that and they're a challenge
to their belief system and even with
personality disorders are extremely good
at turning.
Everyone may meet into the same person
that they already met and they do that I
think by exchanging very,
very subtle and covert reinforcements,
which is to say,
you're engaged with me.
I have a personality disorder.
Every time you act properly I'll ignore
you or say something contemptuous or
look away or do something quite saddled.
And every time you act like a miserable
bastard,
which is what I expect all,
at least pay some attention and possibly
even reinforce you covertly.
And you'll find if you get close to me,
that you,
it's almost like you've been distorted
by a gravitational field.
As your behavior starts getting pulled
in strange directions.
We do that to each other all the time,
and one of the things you might consider
it as well,
our societies are very large.
We're all engaged in these patterns of
mutually modifying interactions and
something emerges from that.
The stable,
and I guess I would say that the things
I'm going to teach you about mythologies
are the things that I do as stable,
emergent properties from risk,
from centuries of reciprocal
interaction.
So if we're engaged in some pursuit,
you're going to modify me and I'm going
to modify you,
and neither of us really know precisely
what that means because we're not
conscious of all the reasons that we do
everything and have to spend.
I mean,
it's bad enough if there's only two of
us,
but if there's like 50 of us,
well then you can imagine that
calculating all the permutations of the
interactions becomes virtually
impossible.
The point is we will settle into some
sort of stable configuration or
important or will disappear.
Those are the options and a human
societies do so settle into stable
configurations and we don't really
understand how that happens,
but we,
we have developed the ability to
describe those configurations without
understanding and,
and I think that makes up a big part of
mythology.
So miss are the stories we tell
ourselves how we behave when we don't
know how it is that we behave or even
why.
So when a file that when you know things
to consider in the future,
let's go back.
Good.
Was there some connection between what
you,
the distinction you were just making him
the declarative declarative memory that
just talks about yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
We'll discuss.
We'll discuss that in some detail.
I think the is,
so you have these three separate memory
systems.
One of them's knowing non declarative,
which basically it's nonrepresentational
ducks,
the procedural system,
procedural memory governance,
your motor output.
If it's habitual under an employee.
That's right.
You use your procedural memory to walk
with because walking is way too
complicated to do as a consequence of
representation.
It's like it's such a complex.
While you can't think about how to walk.
It's a habit.
It's a skill.
It's like if you play the piano,
if you know a piece off by heart,
as soon as you think about it while your
fingers stumble over themselves because
it's too complicated to think about.
You can't handle all that information in
your interactive conscious.
Anyways.
We've coded a lot of behavioral
information in our procedural systems.
It's not,
it's not declarative.
It's not representation.
It's there.
Well,
I think part of what a story is is it is
the representation of the patterns of
behavior that are coded in a procedural
systems.
So you see when we're engaged in any
sort of interaction,
you and I are both modifying the
contents of our procedural memory
systems by exchanging to put it very
harshly by exchanging reinforcements.
We do not understand the nature of the
pattern.
That's the outcome of that exchange.
But we can watch it and that's what the
story is.
It's our,
I think,
I think that's our,
our episodic memory system that kicks up
images basically cause we'll get it
back.
Your right hemisphere is good at
recognizing patterns,
you know,
and your behaviors.
Behaviors have patterns obviously.
That's why you can predict behaviors.
One of the ways that we make those
patens explicit is by making images of
them and then describing,
and that's basically my story and we,
you get a story.
Basically what you're doing is you're
using words,
activate images of behaviors.
You're trying to,
you're trying to instill behavioral
patterns by doing that anyways.
You don't understand the story.
That's all BS.
There's lots of stories we tell our kids
that we have a little foggy snowstorms.
Fairy Tales would like that.
Very peculiar stories,
but the kids are interested in them and
they'll listen to them over and over and
over.
And that's because there's a lot of
information in those stories like that
or than you can possibly imagine all
embedded in those stories.
And the person who's listening to it
doesn't understand it and the person was
telling it doesn't understand it,
but the inflammation is still
transmitted.
So,
which is very peculiar.
It's very strange.
So I started thinking about that because
was very,
well when I started understanding that
religious systems of thought actually
had some meaning,
that they,
that the stories they were telling were
accurate.
Then I couldn't figure out,
well,
if they are accurate,
how the hell did they develop?
If no one understands what they mean,
if which is impossible,
right?
It's like how do you develop a system of
thought in the absence of any
understanding of what the system means?
Well,
that seems like a complete with insulin
and with our problem,
it's like,
well,
you,
it's,
you don't point about something similar
with dream to set up a dream will
sometimes give you a premonition of a
future state and he didn't mean that you
could interpret the future by reading
your dreams.
He meant that the thing that you will
become is in,
in a sense,
operative now it's in its nascent form
and on that nascent form has more to do
with dream structure and imagination.
And it does with anything explicit.
If you can interpret your dream,
sometimes you can see where it is that
you're headed.
And again,
it was the same mystery.
How is it that your brain can know where
you're going to be when you can't even
understand what that means?
But that's why there's multiple memory
systems.
Theory is really useful because you can
say,
well,
look at social animals,
for example.
Like a wolf obviously does not have a
declarative representation of the nature
of its social structure.
You know,
it knows who's white on the dominance
hierarchy and knows how to behave,
but it can't describe it's patterns of
behavior.
They're not conscious,
meaning they're not representational,
they're not declared,
but they're still there and they're
there because they've been selected for,
from the Darwinian perspective.
It's like these patterns of interaction.
There's certain patterns of social
interaction.
They're stable over time.
They emerge as a consequence of a social
interactions.
And they emerge way before the groups
that have the patterns,
understand what the patterns are and
are.
Our attempts to spin stories are
descriptions of those patterns of action
before we understand what they are
giving.
Another example of that same,
uh,
people have said that everything in
Freud is in Shakespeare.
But the thing about about Shakespeare is
that nothing in Shakespeare's explicit,
it's still all story,
right?
He was great spinner of drama,
all Shakespeare's plays,
plays,
which was a reference to behavior.
All Shakespeare's plays are
images of patterns of action.
You can say what Freud did in so far as
you grant,
he's theorizing Craig's is make an image
of a pattern of behavior,
explicit representation from the
perspective of some manner from
perspective of words.
Well,
same with maths.
I mean we miss her full of wisdom about
behavior,
but it hasn't yet been made explicit.
And now the problem with us of course,
is that we think we know our hands are
full of a lot of bizarre nonsense and
that makes it very difficult for us to
figure out what it me.
And that brings me back to this.
This is where I'm telling you this whole
story.
It's 500 years ago,
the scientific methodology was four
formalized when we found out very
rapidly.
Let me read you something from you.
He's talking about the typical attitude
that commit evil individuals.
So this is the Orthodox Christian media
evil individual.
And you have to realize that hundred
years ago,
the in Europe site,
although there might've been sectarian
differences within the Christian
community,
in most cases you are Christian.
Not because that's what you believe,
but because the world that you lived in,
was it Christian world?
It wasn't like you had 15 different
belief systems,
all of which were equally coherent to
sort of choose between.
It was that the world you inhabit,
it was Christian.
That was the explanation of the
universe.
So anyways,
young said,
you know,
it isn't till culture start mixing.
For example,
you can't take like a Muslim if you're a
Christian,
unless you've met one.
And if they're not around,
well the issue doesn't even come up.
So anyways,
you can see how totally different than
the world appear to medieval man.
For him,
the Earth was eternally fixed and that
rest in the center of the universe and
circled by the course of a son.
That's statistically,
there's stone,
it's more men.
We're all children of God under the
loving care of the most high,
who prepared them for an eternal
blessedness,
and they all knew exactly what they
should do and how they should conduct
themselves in order to rise from a
corruptible world.
Do an incorruptible and joyous
existence,
such a life no longer seems real to us.
Even in our dreams.
Natural sciences long ago torn this
lovely veil to shreds.
Well,
at least you know at the,
from a fundamental perspective,
we know perfectly well that the earth
was not the center of the cosmos,
at least not in the way that it was
procedure from the medieval perspective,
and it was very,
very rapidly after the scientific
methodology became formulated.
Scientists,
we're generating observations like mad
that seemed to exist in direct conflict
with the most fundamental statements of
religious systems.
That's fine.
For example,
the fact that the sun was at the center
of the will of the universe originally,
but I mean,
we don't even believe that anymore.
It's just some,
you know,
semio obscure star,
not all that particularly powerful,
often some backwater corner of one
galaxy among hundreds of billions of
galaxies in the universe that's so big
that you can't even comprehend.
So I mean that's a different picture.
And of course the logical conclusion to
Joe,
the to say the so same sort of thing
happened to Galileo.
The heavens were supposed to be perfect
from the medieval perspective and we
never plan.
It was supposed to,
supposed to have a perfectly circular
orbit even because of the circle was the
most perfect of figures and the moon was
supposed to be something that was
completely without blemish.
Since it was part of the heavenly order.
Galileo with his telescope showed that
there were mountains on the moon and
praise that he attempted to demonstrate
this to.
We need to look through the telescope
because for there,
for reasons that we're going to discuss
that this course continues.
But the point is,
is that very rapidly after the
formalization of the scientific
methodology,
our ability to regard mythic
descriptions of the world as valid was
essentially destroyed.
Well,
I think this is,
I mean,
I would like you to think about this and
see if there's anything wrong with the
explanation because it seems so simple
that it's observed.
But I think we made a big mistake of
logic somewhere along way because we
made the presupposition that what we
were doing when we were doing science
with the same thing that we were doing
when we were doing religion,
which is to say that what religion was,
was an attempt to describe the world in
the same terms or are,
are,
uh,
tending to the same phenomenon that we
attend to when we're doing science.
So then we have the general attitude
that,
well,
what religion was at bask was sort of a,
uh,
a science with an abysmally poor
methodology based on,
you know,
erratic and unpredictable and biased
stuff.
Uh,
observations.
There were all designed to produce a
given an all the religious people seem,
you seem to have a sort of swollen that
more or less whole as far as I can tell
too,
because
obviously these are generalizations and
neurosurgeon exceptions,
but people still seem to believe that
whatever it was that religious religion
is doing is the same thing that science
is doing.
It's just,
it's like a different viewpoint in the
same plane.
So you get these weird arguments say
between fundamentalist Christians and
evolutionary biologists,
they're talking about different worlds
and they don't know on either side,
you know,
so that
I want to tell you at least in part what
the nature of the world that the miss
described is and how it differs from the
scientific world.
And the basic premise of this is that
why medstar concerned about is the world
that you act the act.
That's what he's trying to describes.
So miffed tells you,
well,
here's how human experience is
structured with regards to how you
should act.
It's not that big a surprise.
And you know,
religion is concerned with morality and
morality is the study of how the APP,
so it doesn't seem like such a major
leap in some regards,
but it seems peculiar that people
couldn't have figured out
on a general like in a general sense
that what religions were doing and what
science we're doing where we're not
really convince her they weren't in the
same domain.
Science is concerned with facts and
religion.
Stories are concerned to value and you
know a story has a moral right.
That's what you're supposed to derive
from the story.
You take primitive stories like aesop's
fables,
the is made explicit at the end here,
here's the characters and acting out
their roles and here's the behavioral
information you're supposed to derive
from that.
Analyze the story for the moral.
The moral is in the light of the
behavior which you just received.
How it is that,
how is it that you should adjust your
ongoing behavior?
That's the kind of information that
stories have.
Stories provide you with information
about how to act,
which is the information about the
motivational significance of things and
situations.
And when you have a story,
a good story about a given situation,
you know how to ask and knowing how to
act inhibits your anxiety because
knowing how to act means that we need to
do something.
You can predict outcome and as long as
there are predictable outcomes all
around you,
then you know,
anxious.
It's knowing how to act and inhibits
your anxiety.
So I would say,
well then it's not much of the
presupposition that it's stories that
inhibits your anxiety.
The fact that none of us are made
anxious by any of the other people in
this room is fundamentally because you
share the same stories.
So we act in a predictable way.
So when you mess with someone's story,
you're messing up the structure they use
to attribute determinant significance to
objects and situations.
And
you can mess with someone's story nearly
by behaving in your own peculiarly,
culturally determined way.
If you haven't to be among foreigners,
you don't have to say anything.
Oh,
the words sufficient are perhaps even
more potent than behaviors,
but just your mere existence poses a
certain amount of threat.
Okay.
Anyways,
Nietzsche,
he observes something similar to what
I'm telling you.
About a hundred years ago we said,
you know what,
I'm [inaudible],
if you think about it,
that we've worked,
we've like pouring the intellectual
foundations out of Christianity using
science,
but we all run around acting like
Christians more or less.
This is his employment.
He started about Europeans here a
hundred years.
So this is peculiar.
No,
you might debate,
can think to yourself,
well,
I don't act like a Christian or whatever
it is that your particular religious
background has to me.
But of course that's really quite
ridiculous because you did not advance
all your behaviors.
In fact,
you probably imagined almost none of
them,
most of them are copied their coffee
from your parents or from other people
that you matter,
you know,
from significant others throughout your
whole life,
from,
from books he read,
from movies you've watched and so on and
so forth.
In so far as you are inculturated,
your behaviors are not your only
advantage.
And that's the whole purpose of college.
He had to invent every one of your
behaviors.
Well,
you'd never get anywhere.
So you coffee behaviors that have been
accumulated by humanity over large
periods of time.
So whether you think you have a
religious based morality,
you're not.
It's really knowing the issue because
what you do,
okay.
Human human society as being religious
for like
veering or nearing the hundred percent
of its entire developmental history.
You don't shake that in 500 years.
I mean really
religions to boldly be explicitly
tumbling down the cents
per hundred years with the rise of big
ideological systems to replace.
All right?
As far as I'm concerned,
the system like communism or any
authoritarian system mass just get
replaced with religion.
Anyways,
Nisha said when one gives up Christian
belief,
for example,
one thereby deprives oneself with the
right to Christian morality.
Christianity's the system consistently
thought out and complete view of things.
If one breaks out of been a fundamental
idea like the belief in God,
for example,
on their by breaks the whole thing to
pieces.
What is nothing of any consequence left
in one's hands.
Christianity presupposes the man does
not know and cannot know what is good
for him,
what evil he believes in God.
God alone knows Christian morality is a
command.
It's the region is transcendental.
Beyond all criticism at all,
right to criticize or possess as truth
or we have got is truth.
It stands or falls with the belief in
God.
If modern westerners really do believe
they know of their own accord,
intuitively what is good and evil
if they consequently take,
they no longer have need of Christianity
has a guarantee morality.
That is merely the consequence of the
ascendancy of Christian evaluation
and an expression of the strength and
depth of this ascendancy so that the
origin of modern morality has been
forgotten and the highly conditional
nature of its way to exist,
no longer felt on Nietzsche is basically
saying is that
the fact that you might think that you
can have a morality without a,
that we're talking about crystal
morality in this particular
circumstance,
but it can be any morality is derive
from a system that was predicated on the
notion that there was some
transcendental Va.
The fact that you can think that you
have a morality that will last without
that belief is proof of how potent that
belief system is actually means.
It has worked so well and protects you
still so well
that you can be incarcerate Lee
convinced of its lack of necessity.
Uh,
I noticed in your footnote on that and
hear that you said you had originally
said been English.
Yeah.
Um,
what's he,
I mean I know this,
I know this applies for up to a
character of belief systems in general,
but if he was referring to wasn't or,
or what's he to the sort of moral
realist philosophers.
Yeah.
To beat that English tradition,
which I think was about the same time.
Yeah.
He was irritated by attempts to,
to argue that we're already have a
rational basis and it was in fact
derived as a consequences of rational
thought and you're going to see it.
It's right there.
And then normally that normally that you
can see it and that it's right there.
But that's how it was originally
derived,
which is to say that reasonable people
got together and rationally decided that
this is how they should conduct their
affairs.
Oh,
neat.
You said,
look,
don't look at the historical record.
You behave first,
then you figure it out.
And there's huge gaps of,
of,
of tens of centuries between figuring
out how to behave or between acting and
then later being able to say how it is
that you have.
So,
uh,
he thought that the English,
we're putting the cart before the horse
in the man's man having no vision for
the,
for the length of historical development
so I can not happens.
And then you make declarative
representations of it.
Then for instance,
when a new person and you teach them,
declared what you teach them verbal
stories about the religion for example,
does that get into their behavior?
I need,
so that then by listening to the stories
about that they actually learn the
behavior of the procedural level of how
to ask and without believing.
Yeah.
Well that's a good question to me.
Um,
I don't know exactly what impact,
watching stories that has on behavior.
And I think,
I think really what watch the stories
probably does too is reconfigure your
conceptions of the present and the
future so that the motivation,
the significance of things shifts and
that has a consequence on your behavior.
Although,
so you also have to realize that,
you know,
movies and books and so on portray
heroes and heroes are more wireless for
emulation.
And a model for emulation is essentially
someone to be annotated.
So I don't think that you can write off
the direct impact of the story on
behavior.
And when kids play,
for example,
when they,
when they pretend that they're
something,
what they're basically doing is
embodying and imaginative representation
of a pattern of action.
And that's what that is,
what their play does,
at least in part.
So there is,
there's some direct effect,
I think
getting this neat,
you said,
look,
you know,
we have no rational reason for having a,
for continuing to behave in the way that
we behaved in the past,
which is essentially a dog,
Judeo Christian presuppositions in
European society because we don't
believe in the funds miracle.
You don't believe in the fundamental
premises of the system by which those
moral rules we're generating.
So you can say,
well,
Christianity Judeo Christianity is a
tree,
a tree of recent positions.
Then the most,
and we live out here in the branches and
the most fundamental presupposition is
that there is a god.
And if you,
if you break the tree at that point,
then the whole tree is dead.
You just don't know it.
It might take a long time to die.
And she would say,
and this was basically his theory,
for example,
that's why people in the 20th century
were so unbelievably susceptible to
rationally ideologies like fascism and
communism rationally described
ideologists because well,
well,
because their foundation can be made
very unstable by destruction at this
point in their presumption hierarchy
state.
Well,
this isn't an inhibitory network in a
sense.
You can think of it as a methodology for
keeping anxiety under control.
When this goes well,
that whole thing is cast into doubt.
The the grand inquisitor,
the trunk of the tree was not god,
but then it had been captured.
The grand inquisitor is planning
foundation of the society.
Had been captured by the RG,
religious and spiritual aspect that
became be potentiated just undermine.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's fair enough.
Well,
that's something that we'll have to talk
about.
Talk about.
Yeah,
I don't,
I don't want to answer that right now.
I
will just answer briefly.
You can say,
well,
the belief in God is the belief in two
things.
One is authority,
and the other is process of adaptation
is simply and the priests,
to the degree that the priest and
Dostoevsky story encapsulate this,
this was theoretically made unnecessary
say,
well,
we'll tell you what the world is like.
That's all you need.
But you remember Dostoevsky story to the
Grand Inquisitor,
he met Christ out the back door because
that's why that's brilliant.
Story means standing,
but does it as well,
even though the grand inquisitor is a
fascist,
fundamentally,
it's representative,
I think,
in that story of the Catholic church,
tremendously potent authoritarian
structure with sufficient flexibility to
allow them the active process,
some small measure of freedom in which
to operate.
What'd you say?
Well,
and it goes to ask you a story that the
process is Christ in the grand
inquisitor.
He's the act of spiritual.
Wow.
Yeah.
He's the act of spiritual process as
opposed to the static structure of the
church,
which is basically once in government
sense,
it's trying to make things or disorders.
Awesome.
Okay.
So
many ways.
As far as I'm concerned,
we have a split in the recognizance
consciousness and the split is between
what we assume to be true from the
scientific perspective and how we're
willing to govern our actions because
their actions are still governed by
mythological presuppositions that we no
longer presumed to be valid.
We're still learning to accept them and
we also know that they're useful.
I mean,
for example,
Western democracy is predicated on the
notion of the natural right,
and the natural writers a transcendental
idea.
Nobody's been able to pin the damn thing
down.
I mean,
what we found is we can't do without it.
I know at the basis of natural,
right,
is the idea that you know,
there's something about you that's more
or less incomprehensible that I have to
have respect for.
Although I can't categorize it,
I can't describe it rationally.
If I act like it's not there,
things immediately go very badly astray.
The notion of natural,
I mean people have tried to come up with
rational explanations for the natural,
right?
But that's foolish.
That's foolish because like every system
at the base of every system is a
presupposition.
That's because say well,
that's because you don't know everything
and because you don't know everything
that means,
but whatever you do has to be predicated
on some preset positions,
right?
I mean,
you have to take a leap of faith at some
point that the presupposition of the
national right tree is that there's
something valuable about the individual
and it's once you accept that,
that's like a rule of the game,
we'll just play that game.
You're valuable and I'm valuable.
We don't want to why?
Given that premise,
there's a whole bunch of necessary
conclusions.
Those are our main goal of the whole
body of our natural rights.
And you might say,
well,
once you've accepted this,
you can rationally derive those,
but you can't provide rational
underpinnings for that because that's
just in the sense it's in a sense it's
just an arbitrary decision.
It's just a game rule.
It's like you want to play the game.
If you want to play this particular
game,
you have to accept that rule.
I don't think it's arbitrary now
actually.
I think there's a real reason why that
particular phenomenon emerged.
Like it's fundamental.
That's another thing I want to do in
this course.
Sorry I jump all over.
You know what that's like.
I want to show you that this precept
position is not arbitrary,
that it's a necessary emergent property
of successful patterns of social
interaction and then even if you wipe it
out,
he would pop back up.
I you say say that emphasis on
individual work is the hallmark of any
society bedside,
properly functioning and stable,
stable in the long term and also capable
of updating itself when it's necessary
and then it'll just pop up over and over
and over again of its own accord.
So that'll help us get away from the
idea that morality is arbitrary in some
sense.
You know,
the old argument system,
no matter what moral rule you can think
of,
there's some society somewhere on the
planet who does exactly the opposite
thing
equal have used that sort of
argumentation to too.
But that sort of evidence to argue that
there's no such thing as as
transcendental morality that that's a
useless pursuit.
Nature's point was people say that,
you know,
they're willing also to undermine their
own belief systems by pointing out
obvious things.
Like you know,
if you shoot a rocket far enough open
space,
you open going to find having,
so God's not out there.
We still act like our moral systems have
value in their useful and it really does
appear that acting that way.
It works.
So then you have to wonder,
well it works.
You know what's at the basis of it.
And it's really interesting,
like when I first started thinking about
these ideas,
there was still a lot of debate on the
world scene in the sense of how it is
that we should conduct two affairs.
You know,
at the very least,
there's two major sources of,
or two major bodies of ideas that were
in,
in like deadlocked competition and one
was authoritarian,
more or less the communists,
the communist bloc.
They had the way of their head,
their notions of how to configure the
world.
And then there was our side and you
know,
we were basically at each other's
throats and that,
that was very disturbing to me at the
time that have sort of all fallen apart
now with any luck.
And uh,
it does seem that whatever it is that
we're doing in the West seems to work at
least better than anything else anybody
can come up with.
So Nietzsche was already in this
morality has tried sitting there
origins,
you can't have it if you don't accept
the transcendental origins,
you might think you have it past that
just proves that you don't understand
it.
Uh,
it's also the case that
this morality,
which has transcended dental origins
works
and it also seems to be the case that
it's preset positions.
Okay.
I wanted to borrow some time for
discussion.
So I just want to
covered too
slow.
Is Concerned with morality is how to act
neat.
You pointed out a hundred years ago that
Tom,
the fact that there was morality was a
much more difficult problem to solve
then which,
and he was right.
I guess in a sense the fact that there
is morality is the question.
One of the questions that we're going to
give us facts.
Why is there a morality?
What does it mean that there is morality
and given that there is morality,
is there anything that can be said about
if that's universal across morality?
He's like,
see,
that's another thing is we know that
within a different moral systems there
are differences of opinion about what
should be done.
I'm sorry,
across moral system there are
differences of opinions,
if any,
about what should be done,
but the fact that there are moral system
seems to be a universal of human
culture.
So there's something universal in the
domain of morality at the level of
analysis that says that every human
culture has a morality on.
I'm kind of interested in looking at the
metal structure of the morality is to
see if there's anything that we could
pull out that is common to the ball
because that would give us some idea
about what morality is and if we want to
come to agreement in the long term about
how it is that we should conduct our
affairs.
And so in part lesson or propensity to
engage the social conflict,
it seems to me to be reasonable,
to be useful,
to be able to apprehend rationally what
the basis for the fact of morality yet.
And so the methodology here is Bob,
we're going to look at some neuro
psychology because I'm interested in,
in what modern research has to say about
the way we regulate our emotions.
So that's one domain of evidence that
we're going to cover.
The other domain is comparative
mythologies strap.
We're going to look at
mythologies from different cultures and
see if we can extract from them what
their essential structure is to see if
there are any commonalities and that
structure.
So that's basically,
that was basically the notion.
Say the basic issue here is how can the
current state of experience be
conceptualized in abstraction regards to
its meeting?
It's just the same.
Well,
that's what,
knowing how to act meet.
What are the significance of the
phenomena that you currently apprehend?
Say meaning means implication for
behavioral output logically.
Therefore,
myth presents information relevant to
the most fundamental moral problems,
which is what should be done.
So that's the question that stories are
trying to answer how you should,
how is it that you should act but
desirable future,
which is the object of what should be,
can only be conceptualized,
sorry
can only be conceptualized in
relationship to the present,
which serves at least as a necessary
point of contrast and comparison,
which is to say,
well,
if you think that things should be a
particular way,
you're always conceiving that in
relationship to the way that you
conceive of them being now and those two
things.
What's this kind of a peculiar aspect of
this form of cognition,
isn't it?
You evaluate your presence state in
terms of your ideal future,
but you also evaluate your ideal future
in terms of your presence state.
So there's a constant interaction going
between the two.
That's why poverty for example is
relative and I think it's relative in
terms of its socioeconomic effects.
It's where you are in the dominance
hierarchy to determines the effect of
socioeconomic status rather than your
absolute level of material.
Wellbeing is something that's what
really worth considering for a
psychologist when they talk about ses
because,
well to give you one example,
like the black community in the u s
which is a population that's frequently
studied with regards to the consequences
of low socioeconomic status as a
population group constitutes the 13th
most wealthy nation on the planet.
You can also sign,
so that's kind of interesting when
you're thinking about things in absolute
terms.
It's also the case that even the poorest
people in North American society,
you know with exception of people who've
fallen completely out of the world have
access to two technologies.
The 200 years ago were non existence.
And I'm not talking about computers,
I'm talking about like heat and running
water.
So poverty,
that's just one example.
Poverty is where are,
you are construe with respect to where
you could be.
And there's some,
obviously there's some level of absolute
poverty too.
I mean if you don't get enough to eat
well that brings everything to a halt.
But point is is that you can't conceive
of where you are from the effect of
perspective without also conceiving of
where you could be in vice versa.
Uh,
mass to answer the following stories.
What is,
which is,
what is the nature of the current state
of experience from the motivational
perspective,
what should be to what Angie,
we'd be moving and how can we get there?
Well,
and I,
I showed you last week is faith.
Well that's a story as far as I can
tell.
Now you want to use your imagination for
a minute saying his dad snores.
Just the story.
It's also a kingdom.
What a ridiculous thing to say.
You could imagine that there's a castle
wall around that and that what surrounds
it is hostile territory.
So that can be viewed as sometimes in
mythologies.
It's viewed as a notion might be one way
of looking at it might be viewed as
barbarian lands are dark forces.
The point is is the out heres where
things that you can't predict take place
and everybody who shares your story is
predictable.
They live inside your kingdom,
everybody outside is contaminated with
chaos basically.
But you see why that is is even in this
class is we have a vision of where the
class is going to go both over the
course of the whole semester.
And just today,
you know,
we have a vision of how it's going to
progress and how we can,
how we can save ourselves in
relationship to all the others in this
class and exactly what's going to happen
and what the plan is.
And so as far as we're concerned,
we compose a unit and we're a unit
because we can predict all each other's
behaviors and we can predict each
other's behaviors cause we all have the
same story.
That's what the story is.
How does this tie in with mythology?
But one thing,
I haven't said anything about this.
Why do I think this all has anything to
do with mythology?
It's kind of a glaring question.
That's why you look at the Christian
viewpoint.
For example,
I say map it onto the structure.
Well,
Christianity gives you a picture of
Matt.
That's what miss dew and Christianity
says,
well,
what is man
contaminated by original sin?
That's a hereditary retained.
You'd have it whether you deserve it or
not.
It's they're
in desperate need of redemption and
living in a sea of
chaos and misery.
Basically.
I mean this is a pretty negative.
This is a pretty negative summary,
but it'll do for the,
for the present purposes,
that's our presence state like,
and we don't want to trivialize this,
that the Christian perspective basically
is,
look,
there's something fundamentally screwed
up with the world.
Human beings do not fit here really
well.
We're,
we're,
we pose a constant question to
ourselves.
We don't understand our place in the
nature of things.
We're always doing things that we don't
understand.
There's a central mystery here that we
haven't solved.
It's not,
this is not a trivial conception and
people laugh about original sin.
What sort of weird consent concept of
that,
but this says,
well,
there's something about human beings
that we don't understand.
It makes them evil.
Well
isn't just lack of socioeconomic goods
mass best.
Well then there's also some image of the
ideal future and that's paradise
or heaven
or even the Kingdom of Heaven on earth.
It doesn't have to be something that's
purely spiritual,
spiritual.
That means in a sense
that means my domain of the imagination
and you could say,
well,
paradise is the archetype of the ideal
future,
which is to say that whenever you're
committing an action of any sort to act
means to have a prayer,
which means to say that you are here and
you're going to go here and you have
behavioral routines to bring that
transformation about whatever act you
undertake has that structure.
So you could say,
well,
the collection of acts as a whole has
that structure to act is to adopt the
structure.
You could say,
well,
you could
abstract out from all of the particular
notions of your ideal future.
Some abstract that met a notion of the
ideal.
And that would be paradox.
So that's why you can see how these
myths sorts in fills the notion that
there is some sort of ideal,
let something that's inherent to people
and you can build your ideal well just
by imagining what the best of all
possible situations could be.
And Christian morality,
by the way,
is the acceptable procedures by which
the unbearable present can be
transformed into the ideal future.
And if you share that well,
then you're part of a community.
And a community means that you're walled
in with all these other people who think
like you and all the barbarian hordes
and the discord and a male companion.
The unpredictability that's outside.
Perfect.
So that's a story.
And while that was,
that was a religious story,
you say,
well,
the communist stories like that,
I mean it's pretty outdated story.
Kindness in many ways.
The current situation is characterized
by a socioeconomic inequality.
That's a consequence of class.
The class struggle that we,
uh,
we can erect to heaven on earth by
distributing income and opportunity
equitably.
We have to undergo a period of
intermediate and chaos,
which we'll get to later to bring that
about,
etc. Etc.
So,
you know,
in one of the things that's happened to
many,
many European communities,
and this is an appalling thing,
is that when their religious structures
collapsed,
the first thing they do is replace them
with like far more idiotic political
utopias.
And as far as,
I mean this has happened in many places,
happened in Russia.
How in Germany,
I think it happened to China,
I think it's happening pullback as a,
as a matter of fact as well.
Anyways,
that's what I think when it came to
quality last Roman Catholicism and you
know,
the late fifties and now we think that
if the political situation was just
transformed,
that the world would turn into a
utopian.
That's what happens when people lose
their religious beliefs.
So that's the first thing.
They do use these cause there's a big
hole there.
But okay.
So that's the,
that's the simple story.
And you can say,
well there's more to the story in a
sense.
There's also transformational grammar
and that kind of looks like this.
Say,
well,
it's w go ahead.
I just wanted to ask you why,
why you chose to call the president
unbearable.
I mean that seems to have such a
striking implies a really strong effect
instead of letting it be imperfect or,
yeah,
well it's just,
uh,
what do you say?
It's kind of satirical I guess.
I mean,
you're always trying to change it no
matter what it is.
Look,
I'll give you an example.
Okay.
Really quickly.
I read this really funny story in the
Atlantic magazine needs a weaken.
I hated liking it because,
but anyways,
I did like,
it was kind of funny.
But um,
so this guy,
he's a travel writer and he goes on one
of these cruises and everything's done
for absolutely everything.
It's like if he goes and goes swimming
in the morning,
in the morning and he sits down on his
beach chair,
he gets a towel.
There's a guy there that's higher just
to make sure he has a tell and if he
gets up to walk around the pool,
the same guy's job is to go and get his
talent and replace it with another one.
I mean he doesn't have to do anything.
He said he could eat at the restaurant
18 times a day and if he didn't feel
like walking up to the restaurant and he
could call room service and get whatever
you wanted and it would be there in 10
minutes.
As he said for the first three or four
days,
he was really guilty about this.
Like he couldn't stand the fact that,
well it's often uh,
people from the third world,
often man.
And he ships by the way,
because they weren't cheap.
But anyways,
he was real guilty about having,
being waited on hand and foot basically.
And so for the first two or three days
he was sort of racked by guilt.
But by the end he said,
and this is quick funny,
he said,
by the end of the trip having adjusted
to his new circumstances,
he was finding himself increasingly
irritated by the fact that when he
called for room service and they brought
him a sandwich,
they always put it too close to the
little decorative orange slice and the
edge of the guts.
Soggy.
So anyways,
sorry.
See,
this is very funny.
You don't,
that's when people are like,
cause you know,
he would just to sort of your,
your expectations of just to bounce the
situation and then you construe the
motivational significance of events with
regards to that that can
conceptualization.
Well,
so that's kind of why I put that as like
for him,
the unbearable president was the fact
that,
you know,
of the corner of his sandwich was soggy.
He was ready Urinetown of himself for,
for reacting in this manner.
But he said,
well,
that's just what people are like when we
are,
when you're set of expectations alters
the valence of phenomena instantly
changes.
And that's why the Buddhists in part
thing,
the world is my ass,
right?
You just generate a story about what
should happen.
You can switch the valence of phenomena
virtually,
virtually at will,
but not entirely.
I mean,
there's still certain constraints.
So
you're always trying to run from this
incense to get to this.
It doesn't matter what your situation is
and this is permanent.
Like that thing just moves more or less
with you wherever you move.
So,
uh,
that's the simple story.
And then there's the more complex story,
which we'll talk about it in detail.
So when you have this,
that's the known,
you know,
that's an ideology,
for example.
Well,
if something interferes with 20 year
plans,
something unexpected happens,
you just switch to another plan.
All right?
But I started again interferes with a
more fundamental precept position like
who you are,
where you're going,
then this whole thing can come crumbling
down.
That's represented here.
And this is transformation,
transformation,
grammar in since I guess it's how
conception a can turn it to conception
be,
which is to say that,
oh,
people's belief systems will shift
radically.
So you also need a structure for
mmm,
you have a belief system,
that's one thing and you need one.
But you also need a process by which
your belief system is outdated because
your belief system is supposed to map
the environment and the environment
keeps changing and now and then you have
to undergo a fundamental revolution in
your beliefs.
And that's basically what this is.
When you have a,
well,
you know the example I gave you will
read about it in detail.
It's like,
first of all,
there's a little story in that,
in this,
in the book about this guy who was going
to a meeting and he's going to be a real
start.
This meeting is elevators late,
so he thinks he's going to be right in
the fact that the elevators late three
of distressing because he's construing
the significance of that with
relationship to his meeting.
So that makes them mad.
Nays down,
it goes up in front of the building and
now he's kind of late to his meeting.
It's a few blocks away.
Like anybody who gets in his way,
it makes a massive little old ladies are
lovers out for a stroll or whatever.
He construes their existence with
regards to his plants.
So if you had lots of time while they
wouldn't bother him at all,
but the fact that he's late makes them a
bowl of irritation.
So anyways,
when the elevator doesn't show up,
yes to shift plan,
he goes down the stairs and said,
well that's a minor league irritation.
Well say when he gets back,
he's done with his meeting and his boss
calls me into the office and set aside,
you're fired,
you're incompetent,
you're the worst employee we've ever
had.
Well,
he had visions of being a star in his
hand,
was evaluating everything with regards
to that.
It's still being quite irritated about
the fact,
say the elevator wouldn't show up like
now something's really make it happen to
them.
That's a major league discrepancy.
You know,
it's,
it's blown out.
A few fundamental precept positions.
It's knocked out his version of the,
of who he is and what he's doing,
where he's going.
It's blown in.
The whole structure uses to interpret
the motivational significance of
phenomenon and that means that it's an
event that's not be emotionally neutral,
has taken place.
It's a,
it's an event that has a tremendous
amount of emotional significance.
He's very anxious,
he's very depressed.
It's like you could say in a sense,
and we'll try to outline this more
details because motivational systems are
no longer regulated.
He doesn't know what anything means
anymore and when you don't know what
anything means,
everything makes you anxious.
That's a problem.
Actually this represents,
so he's down here,
everything's gone chaotic.
You said,
I don't know who I am anymore,
and that happens to people you know.
Then you have to reevaluate your whole
past and your present and your future,
your whole story shifts,
everything changes and maybe you can do
that or maybe you cut your throat
because that happens to people too and
everything falls down.
It just can't handle it.
They're overwhelmed by their negative
emotions and that kills them.
That's the end of the,
well,
let's say he pops back out of it.
He's a little bit more humbled as time.
Figure it out.
Maybe he didn't like his God damn job
anyways.
You should have done something he wanted
to do a long time ago.
Maybe it wouldn't be in such a bastard
and got fired in the first place.
His conceptions of who he is and why he
wants to be have changed because my
emotions are reregulated.
He interprets the world from a slightly
different perspective,
but the metal structure of the
perspective is still the safe.
Right.
He was here in this kind of structure
when he was there.
He's still in this kind of structure
here.
It's just what the contents of the
structure and difficult,
so there's a stability,
there's a stability and structure as
well as flexibility for change within
the structure.
This is the big mythological story by
the way.
Set us up.
You can look at this all sorts of ways.
I'll try to diagram this out later.
These are castles.
Kingdoms.
Say this is a dominance hierarchy.
That's,
and then we'll discuss that in some
detail later.
It's like if you're in a corporation,
for example,
you share a dream with everybody in the
corporation and you arrange yourself and
a power hierarchy to attain the goals of
the corporation to get from here to
here.
You move up the dominance hierarchy and
it's in your best interest under those
circumstances to keep the corporation
going and also to prop yourself up the
levels of the dominance hierarchy.
So there's a dominance hierarchy here
and the king of the dominance hierarchy.
Maybe it's the CEO or whatever,
Hayes.
He's the active representative of the
ideal future,
which makes him the king basically from
the mythological perspective.
Anyways,
so that's a community.
This is a dragon.
That's one way of looking at a dragon is
something that there's in a cave and
it's very dangerous,
but it sits on something very promising.
Cord of treasure.
Dragons are the places that an almost
events emerged from say their
representations of the chaos that
surrounds predictable territory.
The thing about chaos is that it's
threatening and policies at the same
time.
Yeah,
and it seems that the majority of our
behavior is not able to be planned or
formulated.
Declaratively.
Yeah,
adaptive behavior
inside the little circles.
All I meant really my plan is that like
you draw on in your reservoir of
habitual behaviors and put them into
play to retain certain and so it's like
even the guy rushing to the meeting,
he doesn't have to think about how to
walk like that's a hope.
Those sequences of behaviors are already
habitual.
He just says,
well,
the plan is I will walk there.
So that that's all I meant by that is
that you just have like your
conceptualization of your present state
is somewhat general and so as your
conceptualization of your ideal future,
but do you have specific plans to move
you from one state to another and you
can shift between the felt,
like I said,
this is a simplistic viewpoint.
It that structure.
We'll look at the real structure of that
much later in the court stuff.
That's all I mean by it's just those are
sub routines that will enable you to
pursue your goal.
That's all.
So what if you're doing something that
isn't adapted behavior,
it's not something like walking,
it's something like trying to make a
good impression.
But what if,
what if you're taking some sort of
mythical knowledge that you've gotten
about how to make things work out,
but you can't formulate that the plan
and you have this goal and this is how
you're getting there,
but you have a plan together that way.
You're just trying to get their hope on
a psychoanalysis,
but you can have plants that you don't
have a representation now,
right?
I mean isn't that,
no,
it only plans but even representations
of the ideal,
right?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Well it depends on your left,
their level of representation.
So you can have fantasies that could
haven't made explicit like this.
By the way,
I think this,
this,
this is a fantasy and so is this,
it's the fantasies.
That guy here,
the guy,
you're a motivational fit guide,
your motivational,
motivational judgments,
your dreams about the future.
If you don't know what you're doing,
then you engage in exploratory behavior,
you know?
So it can say,
well,
I have this idea of future in mind,
but I don't know how to get there.
Then you try out different patterns and
just that's something we'll discuss next
week.
So that's a,
that's a default positions.
I know where I want to go on,
but I don't know how to get there.
So since I don't know how it,
since I don't know what to do,
what can I do?
That's a of a question,
but the answer is,
you know,
the answer to that is you start engaging
in exploratory behaviors of various
sorts to make what you want to happen,
start happening.
That syncs the things that you do know
how to do that.
You don't know,
you know how to do.
They just fall inside that little tickle
on top like things that you're doing
without being aware of planning to do
then that way.
But you're doing them
well.
They would form sub routines of this
basically.
So you,
you,
you like,
you use what you know how to do
automatically in your attempt to do
what,
what it is that you want to accomplish,
like walking or moving your hands,
whatever you sequence those behaviors
that you already know how to do.
So I'm in describing the first circle,
you,
you basically described a kingdom,
right?
With an authoritarian rule and whatever.
Yeah.
Are you going to go into and during the
class what,
what kind of works best?
Because,
uh,
you've also described elsewhere,
I don't remember how democracy works and
how it's not,
there isn't a general generalized
hierarchy,
but,
but people have a,
a hierarchy and there are certain
specializations.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
we're still doing really introductory
introductory work can we will go into
that?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
Cause what I want to do is find out,
well this is the myth of the way,
by the way,
this is the sit up there with it.
It's this story that myths referred to
most,
particularly as the structure of
adaptive structures and how they
transformed and when the myth is when
math is describing the world,
that's what it's describing said.
Well this is from the mythological
perspective.
The world is constructed of the
distinction between chaos and order.
It's like before chaos,
in order divided,
you don't have anything and you could
send them all,
this is chaos and this is order by order
is also something that has to transform
because anything orderly that doesn't
change dies because it's hard to say
exactly why that is.
Because things change and you have to
keep up with them is the simple answer.
I have no idea why that is.
And just the as the case.
So the mythical world is the world.
It's always stable,
which is to say there's an unknown.
That's chaos.
It has a certain effect of Valence,
which is frightening and promising.
That's always there,
the unknown.
And then there's the no and that's your
culture.
That's the story you shared with
everyone.
That's your procedures to bring about
what you want to bring about.
That's your kingdom.
That's always there.
And then there's a process that mediates
between the two.
That's you.
That's always there.
Those are the three constituent elements
of the world,
chaos order and,
and the hero actually hold on those,
those all out.
They're split into positive and negative
representations and mythologies as well.
So that's the mythological world.
So,
and it's as far as I can tell,
it's a per ticket,
I said completely code internally,
coherent representation of experience.
And it includes,
it's concentrates on if effect of
Valence and motivational significance
rather than on sensor structure.
So what sort of things would affect your
content is the new adaptive structure.
Okay.
What,
what do you mean by what sorts of
things?
Well,
w what would influence a particular
shape that it takes a particular story
that it tells hopefully past experience.
I mean these are like these are
fantasies,
but to the degree that someone's
healthy,
their fantasies that are constructed on
knowledge that's generated as a
consequence of past endeavors.
So let's say like you're doing something
and you have to fail in a major way,
in an unexpected way.
Well hopefully what happens,
but that basically means that there's a
bunch of information about your
circumstance that you failed to either
notice or to adapt to.
That's what it means.
If a failure comes as a big surprise,
as a general rule,
you're not paying attention.
So hopefully what happens when this is
reconstructed,
that's what sort of on a higher plane is
that all of the anomalous information
that you didn't take into account?
Probably because it was threatening is
now incorporated in here.
So hopefully that sounds like koons.
That is not exactly that.
What Kuhn,
what Kuhn was describing.
Look,
that's normal science,
right?
Yeah.
Max Revolutionary Side.
Let's see.
What Kuhn found basically was this
structure in science,
but what Kuhn found was only a
substructure of a much broader process
of adaptation.
So it's like a mythic structure of
science then.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean what,
what tune was describing is how
cognitive systems stabilize and
restructure,
but in the scientific domain.
But you could just say,
well,
cognitive systems stabilize and
restructure no matter what we're
applying to.
So cool.
I now this is a very strange quirk of
history because you sadness,
like in 19 both 1930 said,
ah,
this is not a religious systems progress
and I can't,
first reasons I cannot understand.
No one seemed to notice that.
And then coon said at 1962 or 61 this is
how scientific systems transforming it
was like what was the revelation?
But anyways,
who knows?
Maybe it's easier for people to accept
and understand probably in the
scientific domain because we feel that
we understand that type of knowledge and
we do because the rules are,
or explicit.
It's harder to understand how this works
when you're talking about they elance.
Hmm.
But the thing you have to remember,
it's like I'm trying to,
I'm trying to make this argument is as
concrete as possible.
You have to,
Matt Damon says you have to because you
have to know how to behave and you have
to get what you need out of the world.
And uh,
we have a structure for doing that.
It's,
it's of primary importance.
That's why we do,
while we're alive,
everything else is just an adjunct to
that.
So when you're looking at this sort of
thing,
you're looking at the most fundamental
aspects of cognition as far as I can
tell.
And you're,
you're basically the purpose of
cognition as far as I can tell,
it's to regulate emotion.
That's why we have,
that's what it's good for.
We want to not be in pain.
We want to not be anxious.
We want to have a future that's full of
hope and and satisfaction and we're
always trying to adjust our models of
the world,
hopefully to ensure that battle curves
when we do more specific cognitive
exercises like sites,
well that's a subspecialty
specialization.
It's very useful.
Hopefully it's very useful.
It's dangerous too.
Other questions?
You may just say that the second is more
adaptive than the fall.
Hopefully it doesn't happen.
It doesn't have to be,
you don't describe something that he
called retro regressive reestablishment
of the Persona,
which is you're trying to do something
and you fail and when you reorganize
yourself sphere of the taxes,
much more constricted.
So like you can get worse as a
consequence of this if you just cause
all that anomalous information that you
haven't processed.
You can't just let that in.
It doesn't change you by letting it in.
You have to adjust your behavior to the
anomalous territory and that takes a lot
of,
well,
a lot of ingenuity and a lot of hard
work and that's why fried,
you know,
fried found by the end of his life.
He said,
well,
Mira consciousness doesn't entail cure.
Well that's because just knowing that
something,
there isn't the trick.
The trick is if there's a threat that
the environment,
wait,
let's say people find you obnoxious,
generally flow,
and that isn't what you want.
It's interfering with your,
your future as well.
The problem,
just knowing that people will find you
have nauseous,
that's normal.
That useful to assimilate that
information is to take it in and move
differently and respond differently so
that other people are no longer that
category of things that's hostile
towards you.
So it's not,
it's not just heightened consciousness,
it's like total reconstruction of your
behavioral outputs.
You have to learn to pay attention and
to listen to and to have some respect
for somebody else's story.
And so
the new system also depends on what's
available.
Right.
And that's why you can repress me.
Is Your path available to talk to you
about double the ideologies around?
I mean,
yeah,
because that's true.
It's easy to about what's there is what
you're proud of.
A lot of it.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's true.
Well,
that's why.
And how brainwashing institutes
basically work.
Will they toss the nautilus information
on you until you crack and then they
just throw a new system out to you.
When she grabbed onto immediately it,
Koreans did that during effectively two
American prisoners of war in the fifties
so now I'm going,
I mean,
it's not just,
that's how the army works.
It's how fraternities work in a,
in a more minimal sands.
That's how initiation ceremony
ceremonies.
So it's not always negative that that
will curse.
I mean it's,
it's only negative if what your hand is
less useful than what you had
or less useful than what you could have
constructed yourself.
Okay.
I know that was sort of randomly.
Any other questions?
What's the process of coming up with the
whole system like that?
Does that imply that you should have
power over it or that it's exploration?
What
are you,
where are you in?
Can you talk about you're here,
you're the thing that moves from here to
here,
but I mean,
if you're the person who comes up with
this system,
yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
That's why the way is the proper path of
life from a mythological perspective.
And who identify with the way is instead
of identifying with this,
where are with this,
knowing that they're temporary is to
identify with this because it's the only
thing that's constant across the
constant spans.
You say,
well,
there was no one territory and there's
unknown territory and there's the
process by which what is generated out
of the other.
And you said,
well where does the individual fit?
Basically,
where are you?
Well if you're doing this voluntarily,
then you're identifying with the process
by which cultural information is
generated rather than with the
information itself.
So that makes you always on the always
in the proper locale,
so to speak,
to construct the world.
That's where it will be less wear will
be interesting.
Occurrence is taking place.
That's a proper place to live.
I'll give,
I'll close with that as an example of
that.
Say,
well here's another symbol that you're
all familiar with
that that's dao and down means two
things.
It either means the way,
depending on the translation,
the way which is that or it means
meaning.
So to live in Dallas,
to live in meaning.
And this symbol is a symbol of the
totality of the world.
And why is that?
Plus,
because this is chaos and there's
usually give it the feminine connotation
for reasons that we'll discuss later.
And this is ordered
and it's chaos and it's the split
between chaos and order and the mutual
coexistence that makes the world.
And this dog is black because anything
orderly can immediately be turned into
chaos,
more or less unpredictably.
And sometimes by your own efforts and
chaos can also be turned in order.
That's why this little dog is white.
Also by your own efforts.
Exploration does that.
And Dow,
the man who lives in down lives on
deadline with one foot in order and one
foot in chaos and the reason for that.
So that's where all the interesting
things are happening.
That's where the information is flowing.
If you're all here,
you predict everything,
well that's secure,
but it's boring and it's not just
boring.
Symbolic,
it defines boring.
There's no new information happening
here.
And if you're here,
well there are so overwhelmed with new
information that that you can't do
anything with it and you want to be
here.
And if you're here and you're doing
this,
you're paying attention to anomalous
information always.
You're allowing that to destabilize this
structure when it's necessary,
they have to do this.
That's the hero in the belly of the
beast,
by the way,
are the sun would packs it's way out of
the dragon at night and back up.
So that's the path of the hero.
And in terms of systems that are stable
over time and an authoritarian system
says this is not necessary.
So if the case as things change,
a system that's property,
government said,
well we need this but we also need this
and therefore we're going to have to
allow a certain amount of disorder into
the system so that flexibility can be
maintained.
And the,
the,
the trick is belts.
It's like too much novelty.
Everything degenerates too much,
order,
everything.
Petrifies.
You wore the right on the proper edge
and the way that you can tell you're on
the edge when you were interested in
something that's,
that's the sign that says you say,
well,
there's an effect of sign post that
tells you when you're here.
If you're here,
you're interested.
you're terrified.
You're here,
your board,
it would be right in the middle of that
and then that means your brain is on and
it's optimal in an optimal manner
because your sensory systems are
probably heightened because you're a
little bit anxious.
You're doing a lot of exploration.
We find it that pleasurable,
like last left frontal activation.
People like that.
That's incentive reward pleasure.
That's what cocaine does to you is this.
When you're here you're on.
It's analgesic too,
which is kind of interesting.
There's no work flow.
Yeah.
It's not quite though because the
problem with things like flow,
and this is Joseph Campbell's thing too,
is they're always talking about
following your happiness.
This is not right to get here.
What you have to do is look at things
that you hate from is no one would buy a
book that tells them that it's a flow,
but no,
but this is amazing.
This is a major problem.
Um,
problem with new age philosophy in
general.
It's the normally that you have to face
and the a priori motivational
significance of an anomaly is terror
because otherwise people would be in
flow all the time and they're not,
it
looks expensive.