Well after all that.
So welcome to psychology to 30
nice to see you all here.
So what I'm gonna do today,
oh I'm going to start is I'm going to
give you an overview of the content of
the course and then I'll give you an
overview of the plas requirements rate
at the end of,
I think we might as well jump right into
the content to begin with.
So
there's a website,
I don't really like blackboard,
so I have my own website.
You can go to Jordan Peterson,
Jordan B.
Peterson,
dark palm,
and underneath there there's a menu that
lists all the courses and the full
syllabus is listed there.
So all the information that you're going
to need about the course can be found
there,
including most of the readings,
although there was also a textbook,
which I presume a majority of you who
have already purchased.
So it also lists the other things that
you need to know,
like what days the tests are going to be
and what the assignments are.
And I'll go over that anyways at the end
of the class.
So,
but to begin with,
I'm going to tell you what the course is
about so you can decide whether you're
in the right class or not.
So
okay.
Personality is a somewhat peculiar field
of study in psychology because
it spans a number of sub disciplines
that aren't particularly well suited to
one another.
So for example,
it spans
clinical psychology and experimental
psychology
and it also spans
and approach that is associated
fundamentally with single individuals
with an approach that analyzes
individual characteristics in large
groups,
which is generally what you have to do
in experimental psychology.
It's also a relatively strange ad
mixture of philosophy and I would say
engineering and medicine as well as
science,
and you might think of medicine as a
but it's not.
And the reason that it's not as,
because it's concerned with the
promotion of health and health is not a
scientific category.
It's a category that can't help but be
value laden because you have to decide
what constitutes health health and what
constitutes illness or what constitutes
wellness and what constitutes pathology.
And there's no way you can do that
without bringing value judgments into
the equation.
It's particularly true in psychology
because when you're thinking about what
a healthy might be,
you generally don't merely think in
terms of the absence of pathology.
You think in terms of the presence of
positive traits,
right?
And someone who's fully healthy mentally
and physically.
While the psychologists,
especially the humanistic psychologists
from the 60s might consider someone
who's truly psychologically healthy,
self actualized,
which would mean in some sense that
they've been able to develop the
entirety of their positive potential,
whatever that is.
So because of these peculiarities,
personality psychology,
the course of course in personality
psychology has to be pretty wide
ranging.
And so this course is in fact wide
It,
it,
it uh,
brings in elements of cultural history,
um,
elements of moral philosophy and then
elements that I would consider almost
completely biological.
And it does that in order to provide you
with a multidimensional view of what it
means to be a human being.
I have some other principles that I
abide by while I'm teaching this course
as well.
And one of those is that I don't really
want to tell you about anything that I
don't think you will find useful and
useful.
Like there's a difference between a fact
and a useful fact,
right?
There's lots of facts.
You can go on Google and you can drown
yourself in facts.
I'm sure you do that every day.
But a useful fact to me is one that
transforms the way that you look at the
world or the way that you act in the
world in some manner that you find
beneficial.
And so another way of of describing
useful from that perspective is
relevant.
And so one of the principles I abide by
is that I don't really want to teach you
anything that isn't relevant.
And my criteria for relevant is first,
is it going to make a difference to you
personally?
So are the things that you learn
immediately meaningful to how you
interact with the world?
And then the second is,
is there some evidence that the facts
that you're going to be,
that you're going to be presented with
actually have some social utility or
some political utility or it's an
economic utility so that the fact that
you know them makes a difference to the
way that you act in a way that also
affects the people around you.
And so
it's for those multiple reasons that I
brought together the material that I
have brought together.
Now that means that there's some factors
that you have to take into account
before you take this course.
And there's another personality course
being given at exactly the same time.
Well,
I don't this semester anyways.
And so it may be that that one's more
suitable for you than this one.
I don't know.
But I can tell you what this one's going
to be like.
And so if that isn't what you want or if
that's not what you're interested in,
then you probably shouldn't take this
course.
So the first issue is that there's a lot
of reading.
There isn't as much reading as there
used to be in this course.
By the way.
Um,
but there's still a lot of reading and a
lot of that
original source material,
both from the personality theorists
themselves and then also original source
material from empirical papers.
So I would say that not only is there a
lot of reading,
but the readings actually quite
difficult.
Um,
I think it's useful given the way I
already defined utility to you.
And so I believe that reading what I
present to you is going to be good for
you,
but if you don't have time to do a lot
of reading,
then you're going to find this course
frustrating.
So there's also because of the emphasis
on clinical theoreticians,
which is a major part of it's
personality theory,
especially the more classical
which by the way is generally the
elements of personality theory that most
students are most interested in.
Um,
there's a lot of what I would consider a
philosophical material.
And the reason it's philosophical is
because it's concerned with how a person
should live.
And that's a much different question
than what a person is.
So it's how a person should live or
perhaps how a person might transform
themselves or act in order to transform
themselves so that their personality is,
well,
for lack of a better word,
better now you can substitute healthier
for better,
but in a context like the one we're
discussing,
the difference is trivial really.
So then the last thing that I would
caution you against is that I don't
lecture from the reading material so
often.
I'm not exactly sure even what I'm going
to tell you when I come to class,
I know the material,
but I don't want to stick to a
prescribed outline.
I want to talk to you about the things
that I think are important and so with
luck,
that'll make the lectures worth
attending and worth listening to.
But if you were more inclined from a
temperamental perspective,
do you want it?
Of course,
where things are laid out in a very
orderly fashion and they progress in a
linear fashion and it's predictable,
and the lectures reflect the reading
material,
then this is not a good course for you.
And so I would presume that would be the
case.
If you're orderly.
And by the way,
that's one of the subdivisions of the
big five personality trait model.
And orderly people tend to be
conscientious,
but they like things cut and dried and
laid out in a linear fashion.
Um,
I'm not that orderly.
I'm higher in openness and openness is a
creative,
uh,
dementia.
Um,
and open people tend to use relatively
loose,
loose associations when they speak and
to cover a wide amount of territory.
And so some people will like that.
Um,
if you like reading literature for
example,
you probably liked this course.
If you don't,
then you probably won't.
So
anyways,
that's pretty much enough for the
warnings.
So,
uh,
now I will tell you what we're going to
talk about it.
One of the things that makes human
beings unique
has,
is the fact that were self conscious.
Now you'll see ethologists are people
who study animal behavior do relatively
elementary tests of self consciousness
on animals.
So one of the most famous demonstrations
of such self consciousness is the mirror
test.
And so in the mirror test,
what you essentially do is you take an
animal,
maybe a chimp or maybe a three year old
child,
um,
and you put a lipstick mark on their
forehead or on their nose,
and then you show them a reflection of
themselves in the mirror.
And if they wipe off,
or Jeff,
you're towards the lipstick mark,
then you can make the presumption that
they understand that it's them that's
being reflected in the mirror.
Or at least they understand that well
enough so that they can use the mirror
as a guide to action with their,
with their hand or,
or whatever it is that they happen to be
pointing with.
And the reflection.
Now,
dolphins seemed to be able to manage
that there some members of the core of
family.
So those are basically crows and ravens.
Those things are really smart and they
seem to possess rudimentary self
consciousness.
I said dolphins,
Cetaceans and general.
So whales,
although I don't know if all whales are
self conscious because it's,
for example,
difficult to get a mirror and big enough
to show a blue whale,
um,
human beings,
that's about it.
No,
I don't think that's a very good
definition of self consciousness really
because the mere fact that you can
recognize yourself and it's also not
fair to some animals like dogs,
right?
Because dog would need a smell and
mirror really because and most animals
are very,
very smell predicated.
Most of the brain is,
is structured with the olfactory system
has its core and like us really because
our brains are structured with the
visual system at the core and that makes
us rather peculiar but so it's a little
unfair to animals like dogs are ready to
rats that relied primarily on olfaction
to orient themselves and world.
But the thing is I don't think that's
really a very good definition of self
consciousness.
It's very rudimentary.
You might say,
well that's the first sort of step to
being self conscious because if you're
fully self conscious,
I think you need two more things.
You need the capacity to imitate,
which is a much more important capacity
than people generally realize it.
In fact,
I would say it's a equivalent
importance.
It's of equivalent importance to
language.
In fact,
I'm not even sure that you could use
language if you can't imitate,
first of all,
obviously all the words you used are
also the words that other people use.
Otherwise you're not going to be very
comprehensible.
So even the mere fact that you do speak
means that you're relying on invitation
to get your point across.
So you need imitation.
And the reason you need the invitation
is because once you can imitate,
you can use your body as a
representational structure to represent
the world and other people.
You can even use your body as a
representational structure to represent
yourself,
which you might do.
For example,
if you're telling a joke at a dinner
party and then you,
you know,
act out of self parody and everyone
laughs.
So,
and then with regards to language,
while language obviously enables you to
build sophisticated models of the world
that are well articulated,
to exchange those with other people and
to think,
okay,
so in order to be self conscious,
you have to be able to recognize that
you exist in this physical envelope,
at least here and now.
You need to be able to imitate because
that's partly how you come to understand
yourself and other creatures like you,
which is a very important part of being
self conscious,
right?
I mean everything I learned about any of
you is also going to help me understand
the sort of creature that I am,
whether that's for good or for evil.
And then with language,
well not only can we articulate our
representations about each other in the
world,
but we can also store those articulated
representations over very,
very,
very long spans of time.
And we do that partly in ritual,
which is the acting out of a
representation.
And we do that partly with regards to
stories which are in some sense an
articulated representation of an acting
out,
right?
Because you can think of a story as a
drama.
So drama is behavior representing
behavior.
And then a story is an articulated
representation of a drama.
Now we have very old rituals and we have
very,
very old stories.
And so part of what we do in this course
is we go back to as close to the
beginning as we can possibly manage to
start to understand how people have
understood themselves and represented
themselves across the span of human
history.
And we're doing that because we want to
be able to put our current knowledge in
some kind of historical context.
And part of the reason for that is,
well,
one of the things that characterizes the
human personality is that it's a
historical phenomenon.
You know,
I'm sure you've heard in many classes
that much of what makes up your
personality is a cultural construct.
Well,
whether or not much of it is or not
isn't really the issue.
Certainly some of it is.
And an important part,
you're a cultural creature.
And that means that you have emerged
within a tradition that's been shaped
and in any number of ways by an
extraordinarily lengthy historical past
or historical and biological.
And so what that means in part is that
if you don't understand
your history and that's your history as
it matters,
not necessarily some collection of fats,
then you don't understand yourself.
So,
you know,
human beings in their self conscious for
we don't really know how old we are.
Um,
more or less biologically or genetically
identical creatures to us existed at
least 150,000 years ago.
But we seem to have discovered fire and
were able to master it maybe 2 million
years ago,
you know,
and that required a fair bit of
intelligence.
Um,
and there are,
there are artifacts that indicate a
fairly high level of,
of cultural capacity that are at least
50,000 years old.
So we can't really say when,
when we got fully self conscious and
perhaps we might also say that we're not
even fully self conscious yet because
you know,
really what the hell do you know about
yourself?
You know,
you're really,
really,
really complicated.
And at best you have a partial model of
who you are and that thing fails all the
time,
which as you can tell,
because you're always doing things that
surprise you and often not in a
particularly positive way.
So there's no end of mystery.
Anyways,
the upshot of all of this is that we're
going to establish the context first.
That's a historical context and I want
to do that two ways that the first thing
I want to do is to talk to you about
mythological representations of
personality.
And that's more important than you might
think.
In fact,
it's probably more important than you do
think.
Um,
by myth what I mean is the
representations of human beings in
extremely long lasting and persistent
stories.
And so some of those are the stories
that are found in various religious
traditions,
but there's oral traditions that
surround those religious traditions.
You know,
it's assuming that their religious
traditions are written down and there's
fairy tales and that sort of thing and
standard narratives that,
that people use to guide themselves as
they move through the world.
And most of the clinical theories that
we're going to discuss,
so Freud's theory and young's theory and
the theory of the existentialists and
the phenomenologists in the humanists
and so forth are variants of those
mythological stories.
Now,
part of the reason for that is that
neat.
You said once that a philosopher was
seldom anything other than the
unconscious advocate of their cultural
worldview.
So what he meant by that was you already
come to the scene with a set of
presuppositions.
Now,
some of those are embedded in your
behavior.
So for example,
when you walk,
when you attend a funeral and you know
how to behave,
he generally,
you're quiet and solemn.
You might not be able to explicate the
rules that a person should follow at a
funeral,
but you can do it.
Now.
You could perhaps articulate them if
pressed,
but it's not like you're following those
rules.
When you go to a funeral,
you just know what to do.
If someone pressed you,
you could turn it into a list of rules,
but it's really more encoded in your
actual behavior.
You just automatically know what to do.
You can tell,
you know,
when you ever,
you interact with someone who's really
socially fluent,
you can tell that they're not
consciously processing the way that
they're acting,
otherwise,
they're,
they're self conscious and awkward.
They're just very fluid.
It's automatize behavior and it's coded
right into them.
So if you're a great philosopher,
then according to Nietzsche,
at least what you do is you take a look
at how you act and what you think,
and then you say,
well this is what it's like.
It's not so much that you're inventing
new ideas,
it's that you're articulating the nature
of structures that are already there.
So you can imagine,
for example,
imagine that you're particularly
interested in wolves.
And so you wrote,
you studied some wolves and one of the
things you see is that the wolves have a
dominance hierarchy.
So there's,
there's a leader and then there is
struggle in the pack to see who's going
to be the dominant leader.
Now there's a couple of problems with
that,
which is that,
you know,
if we'll stay and wolf be fight and
they're pretty evenly matched and they
tear each other to shreds,
then we'll see is going to come in and
pound both of them.
And that's not a particularly useful
strategy for welfare,
for Wolf B.
Plus then the pack loses the power of
Wolf and wolf be in.
So that's hardly useful at all.
So what's happened is that wolves have
evolved dominance and submission
strategies so that they can figure out
who is going to leave and who is going
to follow without having to engage in
the kind of physical combat that's going
to result in damage.
And so usually what happens is that the
two wolves face off,
you've probably seen cats do this when
they encounter each other,
you know,
out on the street,
the first thing they do is sort of
turned sideways and they puff themselves
up and they dance back and forth.
It's quite comical.
But what the is trying to do is look bay
and exposed to try and make the other
cat nervous enough to leave.
And so what wolves do is roughly the
same thing they puff out.
So they look big and they make all sorts
of ferocious noises and they threaten
each other.
And usually what happens is one wolf
will lose his nerve,
flopped down,
roll over,
show his throat.
And that basically means something like
I'm useless and,
and,
and you know,
and pathetic and you can tear out my
throat if you want because of that.
And the other wolf.
Thanks.
Yeah,
you are a pretty useful and pathetic,
but you know,
we're gonna need you to morrow to hunt
down a deer so you know you can get up
and protect your miserable self and
that'll be okay.
Now if you were watching that,
you might say,
well,
just follow rules,
but of course they don't.
That's just how we'll Zack,
when you describe what the wills are
doing,
then you turn it into a rule.
But it wasn't a rule to begin with.
It was just a pattern of behavior.
Now human beings are like that were
chalked full of patterns of behavior and
they're there.
They're the consequences of our biology,
which is something we'll talk about in
depth in the last half of the course.
And there are a consequence of our
culture and they're built into our
boardings.
Like every,
every time you interact with another
person,
they're telling you how to behave right.
Don't be too obtuse.
Try to be a little bit witty,
have something interesting to say.
Don't be too annoying.
If you're going to say something funny,
make sure it's funny.
Take turns while you talk.
Play nicely,
take your turn,
don't eat all the bread,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
You know?
And so if you don't abide by those
rules,
then people lift their eyebrow at you or
they don't smile at your jokes are they
don't look at you or they roll their
eyes when you come in,
which is really not a good sign by the
way.
And you get punished severely for it.
And then if you do act like they would
like you to act,
you know,
then people smile at you and there they
invite you to their place for dinner.
And you know,
maybe you have an intimate relationship
and some people that like you.
And so we're exchanging information
about how we should manifest ourselves
in our bodies with every possible
interaction.
And what that means is that shapes the
way that we are.
Now.
The problem is,
or partly is that you don't really
understand the consequences of that.
Like you,
you can act it out more or less
depending on your social skill and,
and the degree to which you've been
exposed to other people.
But that doesn't mean you're a conscious
that you have that you can consciously
articulate all the rules that underlie
that.
And if you think that maybe you can,
well fine.
You know,
imagine a well behaved four year old,
you know by four you've got a lot of the
social rules down because by four you
can play with others if you're ever
going to be able to,
you can already do it by the time you're
four.
If you can't,
by the time you're four you are in
serious trouble because other kids won't
play with you and then they won't teach
you how to act.
And then you stay immature and isolated
and you know,
off in your little corner dejected and
bitter for the rest of your life.
Now you know,
you might think that's a little rough,
but it's not.
That's what the,
that's what the data indicate.
So,
so anyways,
what this means in part is,
well we've been shaping how all of us
behave as long as we've been social.
Now you might say,
well,
how long have we been social?
Well,
crustaceans are social.
So lobsters for example,
organize themselves into dominance
hierarchies and they modify each other's
behavior.
And that's 400 million years.
So we've been social and living in
groups since our ancestors
departed on the evolutionary timescale
from the ancestors of lobsters.
So that's very,
very,
very long time.
There weren't any trees around back
then.
So social life is older than trees,
so you can be sure that you're adapted
to it in a major way.
So it's built into your biology.
But then there's the historical element
of it too.
And it's quite,
we're quite flexible from a cultural
perspective.
So there,
there's an example,
this guy named Robert Sapolsky who,
who I really like,
he's a great scientist.
He went off to Africa to study baboons.
Baboons are not pleasant.
Generally speaking,
there may fight a lot.
They're bullies.
They bite,
they can really bite at bamboo and like,
uh,
a predatory cat will think twice about
taking on I baboons.
They've got major teeth and their,
their temperament is not particularly
positive.
So polsky went and studied a group of
baboons and they were engaged in typical
baboon,
gang behavior,
harassing each other.
All the time and bullying each other.
And they're all stressed out because
it's the Polsky knew that because he
measured their levels of stress and,
and testosterone and so forth.
And so it was pretty miserable baboons
existence.
But then what happened was that
the baboons went to feed somewhere that
I don't remember,
and they,
a lot of them contracted tuberculosis
and it turned out that almost all the
hyper aggressive male,
it's got tuberculosis and died and all
that was left was the Beta males roughly
speaking.
And then the whole book bundle and
culture transformed so that it became
much more agreeable in much more
cooperative.
And then when aggressive baboons would
move into that territory,
you know,
singly or their own,
then they'd get all placid and calm too.
So it's interesting gate because
obviously baboons aren't social to the
degree that we are,
but it does indicate that even at the
advanced primate level,
you know,
their brains are pretty big,
but not as big as ours.
That cultural transmission of behavior
expectation can be quite powerful and it
can transform quite rapidly.
So anyways,
we've been shaping each other's behavior
for a very,
very,
very long time and a lot of that in
encoded deeply in biology,
Andean culture.
Now biologically,
when we'll talk about this a lot,
when we get to the biological section,
one of the ways that you can know how
social you are is by noting how hurt and
ashamed you get if you make a serious
social error.
You know?
So if you're at a party and you make a
fool of yourself,
you know,
depending on your level of neuroticism,
which is also a big five trade,
that index is how sensitive you are to
negative emotion.
You might obsess about what an idiot you
are for the next three or four months or
maybe even for the next five years.
You know,
people do not like social exclusion.
You know when you have a little counter
that's more or less built into the back
of your brain that roughly first of all
estimates how successful you are.
There's an estimation that actually
seems to occur right at birth,
where when part of your neuroticism
levels are set,
and then that can be modified to some
degree by learning.
You know,
and if you're a talk baboons while
you're going to experience less negative
emotion and more satisfaction than you
are if you're a bottom baboons.
And it's exactly the same with people.
So you know,
we liked to be climbing up dominance
hierarchies,
we like to be near the top of dominance
hierarchies.
And if the little counter out the back
of your brain notices that you know
you're doing a good job of climbing
towards the top of irrelevant dominance
hierarchy,
then it's going to produce more
serotonin and you're not going to be as
in as much pain,
you're not going to be as depressed,
you're not going to be as anxious,
you're not going to be stressed and so
forth.
So,
so there's a biological basis for our
social being and it's extraordinarily
important to us how we fit into social
groups.
Okay.
So we've also been trying to figure out
what the hell we are,
who we are for thousands and thousands
of years.
Partly as a consequence of imitation,
you know,
cause I can act you out and that'll sort
of help me understand what you're like.
And partly as a consequence of
articulated communication,
Lord of that storytelling.
Now people have been telling stories
for,
we have no idea how long.
I mean if you go and visit peoples that
have no written language and who've been
isolated from the rest of human society
for say tens of thousands of years and
such people still exist,
you find that they tell stories,
they dance,
they act each other out,
you know?
So we know certainly that the propensity
to tell stories and to engage in ritual
behavior is far older than our ability
to write.
I suspect you could push it back at
least 50,000 years.
Although I suspect it's a lot older than
that.
And so what's happened is that across
those sorts of timescales,
we've started to tell stories about one
another that represent how we act.
And then you might think,
well,
some of those stories are interesting
and memorable and some of them aren't.
And then we tend to remember the
interesting and memorable ones and pass
them on.
And so you can also imagine human beings
aggregating together in groups of
thousands and thousands of people over
thousands and thousands of years telling
their stories to one another and
hammering those stories into some sort
of mutually acceptable and
comprehensible for.
And so for example,
one example of that is that if you look
at the creation stories,
the creation story that say occurs in
Genesis in the Old Testament,
it's a member of a class of creation
stories that characterized Middle
Eastern mythology.
And it seems to have arisen out of the
Organization of separate Middle Eastern
tribes thousands and thousands of years
ago,
each with their own traditions into a
relatively homogenous story that
characterized a large group of people,
central beliefs.
So we have information about how we act
from the representations that we've made
of those actions that we passed forward.
And a lot of those take the form of
myths,
religious stories.
And so part of what we're going to do is
we're going to begin the course with two
foundation establishing themes.
One has to do with the structure of
mythological representations,
and the second has to do with a set of
rituals and processes and beliefs that
have been identified more or less
worldwide that have to do with shamonic
transformation.
Now,
the title of this course is personality
and its transformations.
And the reason it's titled that way is
because you aren't just who you are.
Okay?
You're also something that changes all
the time.
You're more like a river then like a
rock,
you're constantly transforming.
Yeah.
Physicist Erwin Schrodinger thought that
people were dissipative structures.
It's a very interesting idea.
So a dissipative structure is a
structure that maintains its structural
integrity while its elements transformed
completely.
So you know,
when you let the water out of the sake,
you get a whirlpool,
right?
And the whirlpool is a fairly stable
entity,
but the water that the whirlpool is made
of,
it's constantly changing.
That's a dissipative structure.
Well,
that's what you're like.
You maintain your form across time,
but your elements are constantly
transforming.
And people are very,
very transformative creatures.
You know,
we can,
okay.
Unlike animals really because animals
are sort of what they are and that's it.
I mean they have some capacity learned
but not very much.
Your typical beaver is acting more like
more or less today.
Like you know,
his great,
great,
great grandfather was acting 5,000 years
ago.
There's no real accretion of culture.
Whereas with human beings we transformed
like Mac.
I mean we do that culturally things
aren't much.
There's so many things for example,
that are different now than there were
20 years ago that it's almost impossible
to manage it.
And then so we transform on a cultural
scale quite rapidly.
But we also do that individually.
I mean you guys have all just made the
transition to university.
Just roughly speaking,
you know,
I'm sure that your,
like you were in some ways when you were
in high school,
but well hopefully you're better than
you were in high school a whole bunch of
ways as well.
You shouldn't be more mature,
but your personality may have
transformed substantially.
You know?
And with any luck,
you're not done with your sequences of
transformations,
you know that's going to be something
that characterizes you for the rest of
your life in so far as you're a dynamic
person,
your eyes are open,
you pay attention,
you and you can learn.
And so one of the things you might say
is that the most stable thing there is
about the human personality is its
capacity to transform.
And that's really something that's worth
knowing.
You know,
because one of the things I can tell you
about the great myths of mankind,
there's lots of them and they have
different themes.
But one of the most powerful themes is
the way you get yourself out of trouble
is to transform your personality.
Now you think you kind of do that every
time you learn something,
right?
Because you learn something in your
little different than you were before,
hopefully different in a significant way
and hopefully different in a way that
helps you solve some problems that you
couldn't solve before.
So you could say one of the late motifs
of being human is,
well,
if I were encountering an obstacle I can
just transform it and I can figure out
some way of getting around it and that's
something that makes us quite
remarkable.
No one,
one of the things that I could suggest
to you,
and I think this is one of the largest
ideas that exist,
especially communicable in this short a
time,
is that it's much better to identify
with your capacity to transform then it
is to identify with who you are now and
that can get you out of an awful lot of
trouble.
I mean one of the things that
characterizes the logs for example,
or people who are trapped in fixed
belief systems is that they worship who
they are now and that'd be all fine if
everything was going 100% for them,
but it's seldom the case.
And so unless your life is perfect and
that seems highly improbable,
maybe if you were someone else it would
be better.
And you know that's all you've got.
And some sense because changing the
world in some way that's going to make
you feel better about it.
Well,
you know,
you might be able to do that in some
small way,
but the probability that you could or
should try to do that on large scale is
it's pretty low.
So,
so in the mythological representation
section,
I'm going to talk to you about the
fundamental elements of narrative.
And the reason that I think that that's
necessary is because there's,
there's sort of two things that you have
to consider when you're talking about
people.
And one is objectively what is a person
light?
They'll same way you might think about
what Iraq is like or maybe even what a
rock is like.
So that's a,
so that's a scientific question in some
sense.
But then there's another question which
is,
or maybe two questions,
how do people act and how should they
act?
And maybe the first one is a scientific
question,
but the second one certainly isn't.
And the way that we explore how people
do act and how they should act has a lot
more with to do with narrative then it
has to do with science.
And you know,
you know this,
oh you have to do is think about it.
You know,
you think about where do you get most of
your information about what people are
like when you're not actually just the
interacting with some people.
And the answer to that is quite
straightforward.
You read novels,
he read literature,
you go see movies,
you watch a game of thrones,
you binge on game of thrones,
you know,
you go watch star wars.
You know,
maybe you line up for three days if
you're completely insane to go see star
wars,
you know?
And you might ask,
well what in the world are you doing?
Well,
people are hungry for information about
how people do act and how they should
act.
And we're absolutely compelled by
narratives and there's reason for that.
Well and you kind of know what a
narrative is and one isn't right,
go to a movie and you think,
ah,
the character development is pretty
good.
But um,
you know,
as a story it was terrible.
And then maybe you talk with your
friends about why it a terrible story.
But the funny thing is you kind of know,
right?
It's like some things are stories and
some things aren't.
And laying out what actually makes
something a story that's very difficult
but you still know it and you can come
to some consensus even,
you know,
if you look on I mdb or rotten tomatoes,
people form large group consensus about
what constitutes an acceptable narrative
pretty damn quickly and there seems to
be at least a certain amount of
agreement,
you know,
barring individual differences.
So
the mythological and the shamonic
discussions that were going to undertake
have a couple of purposes.
One is to provide you with the
foundations of a language that you can
use to understand narrative.
And that's going to prove very,
very useful because most of the clinical
theories that we're going to talk about
are really narrative based and once you
understand their mythological
substructure so to speak,
it gives you a framework within which
you can slot the theories.
You know,
because one of the things that's
complicated about personality theory is
that there are a lot of personality
theories and you might think,
well how the hell can that be?
Because if it's a theory,
theoretically there could only be one.
Like there's only one theory of
relativity rough,
roughly speaking,
it's a little fuzzy around the edges,
but people agree on the core elements.
Well with personality theory there's,
there's many,
many different personality theories and
so then you might think,
well how are you supposed to make any
sense out of that?
Well there's two ways.
One is to put all of them into a more
fundamental underlying structure and
that's something that I'm really going
to strive to have you guys do while
you're taking this course.
And the other is to actually adopt a
slightly different set of
presuppositions about personality
theories.
And so you could say,
well,
there's only one theory of relativity.
But then you might say,
well yeah,
there's only one theory of relativity,
but then consider a toolbox.
So maybe some of you are relatively
handy and you have a toolbox.
What's in the toolbox hammers or a
hammer saws,
ranches,
pliers,
vice grips,
et cetera.
You know,
when you might say,
well,
there tools,
why do you need all those tools?
And the answer is,
well,
you can hammer a nail in with a ranch,
but it'd be a lot better if you could
use a hammer and you can probably bang a
bolt off with a hammer.
But it would be a lot better if you had
a ranch.
And so then you might think,
well,
if you're trying to do something
complicated and sophisticated,
why not have a bunch of tools?
Now we don't generally think of
scientific theories as tools,
although that is what they are.
Above all else,
there are tools.
And then when we're dealing with
something as complicated as a human
being,
while you know,
we may need more than one tool to get to
the bottom of it.
And it's also the case,
you know that to say understand a human
being.
Well that's a complicated thing.
It's cause he might say,
well I understand to what end you don't
mean comprehensive universal on
omniscient and understanding.
Obviously you mean I want to know x
about someone because I have some desire
in relationship to my interactions with
them.
And so there's all sorts of tools that
can facilitate that.
So what I would say is that you know,
Freud to microscope and human is a
telescope.
That's one way of thinking about it.
I mean there's no particular reason I
associated either of those with those
two tools.
But the point is is that if you pay
careful attention to personality
theories,
they can expand your capacity to
represent yourself in ways that's
extremely useful because you know,
you should understand who you are and
why and what implications that has for
you because you're a transformable
creature,
but you also have a fairly stable
underlying substructure,
right?
Otherwise you just melt like an octopus.
So you're this weird dynamic combination
of relatively permanent structure and
then embedded capacity to transform.
You have a nature.
And so understanding your nature is
extraordinarily youth worthwhile.
And so hopefully what we're going to do
during this course is give you a whole
bunch of tools to understand yourself
and other people with tools that will
really be useful,
things you can use day to day to
understand yourselves and your families
and so on,
and to improve your future with any
luck.
And then also cover
the elements of you that are stable,
most of which I would say have been
discovered,
at least in the more objective sense by
biological psychologists.
So mostly animal research is peculiarly
enough.
Okay,
so mythological representations,
we're going to take a trip back through
time.
We're going to look at archaic and
ancient stories of mankind told by
members of our species to each other.
And I'm going to concentrate on stories
that have lasted.
We don't know how long,
you know we have stories that in the
written form or 4,000 years old,
but all the evidence suggests that those
stories are based on traditions that go
back far,
far beyond that,
at least 50,000 years and maybe way
before that.
So it will take a look at those and
that'll give us a foundation that we can
use to build on.
And then we're going to look at shamonic
rituals and descriptions to get some
sense of the archetype of
transformation,
which sort of means,
well,
what is it that you have to undergo when
you're changing and what are you likely
to experience when that happens?
Now I can give you a bit of a preview.
It's not always the case.
Maybe it's seldom the case that if
you'll learn something important that
it's,
you know,
this happens to people all the time.
So maybe,
I dunno,
maybe you had a recent relationship that
went seriously sour and you know,
maybe it was because you were going out
with a jerk or maybe it's because you're
just not very sophisticated and no doubt
you're trying to figure out which of
those happens to be true.
Well,
you're,
you know,
considering the relationship.
But generally what happens to people
when they're moving towards something
and the bottom falls out because
something occurs that they didn't
understand and couldn't predict maybe in
their own behavior.
Maybe you had an affair while you were
in your relationship and you didn't
expect that.
Well,
what happens is that your current model
of yourself and perhaps even of the
world is demonstrated as insufficient,
not rattles you up badly.
And then you're rattled up for some good
length of time,
not very motivated,
somewhat depressed,
fairly anxious.
You sort of fell apart.
You don't know which way is up.
And then maybe if you're lucky you think
about it and talk about it and put
yourself back together.
And when you come out the other side,
you're a little smarter and a little
more together,
then you work to begin with.
Now if you're unlucky,
you just stay in the little pit for
people can stay in the little pit for a
very,
very long time.
And that's not so good.
And so,
you know,
the process of transformation is
actually quite dangerous because it
doesn't necessarily have to be completed
in a successful manner,
but it does have a pattern.
And the pattern usually is you think you
know what you're doing and then
something happens to demonstrate that
you actually don't know what you're
doing.
And that puts you in a spin.
And then through careful analysis and
support and discussion and other
processes that we don't really
understand very well,
you come to incorporate the anomalous
knowledge that knocked you on your back.
You reconstruct your personality and
your representations of the world,
and then you move ahead,
hopefully more than you were before.
But it's an interesting thing to know.
You know,
one of the things nick just said again
was that you could,
you could tell the character of a human
being by how much truth there willing to
tolerate.
Now that's an interesting phrase because
you generally think of people because
they're optimistic.
They generally think of truth as
something positive.
Obviously it's better to know the truth.
It's like no if you pulled the wool over
your eyes as a general rule,
learning the truth is not a pleasant
experience.
That doesn't necessarily mean that it's
not something you should do.
But the idea that the path to
enlightenment is blissful,
uh,
that's not a very smart idea.
In fact,
it's quite the opposite.
So the Shamana rituals basically
manifest that's in an architectural way.
So one of the things you see happening
with the typical,
the Sharman,
by the way,
shamanism is a worldwide phenomenon.
It seems to be associated with a
primordial or archaic psychology of
transformation.
It's often drug Aden and generally what
happens is that a shamonic
transformation is accompanied by a
descent into something approximating
psychological death and then a
rebuilding and a rebirth that puts the
person out on the other side.
It's like an initiation ritual and
that's another way of thinking about it.
Or you might think about it as the
depression that possessed you have
during your first semester of
university,
which either
okay,
do you out of the university altogether
because that happens to a lot of people
are which you recovered from and finally
became a university student.
Although perhaps that wasn't a
particularly pleasant transition.
You know,
we've done some testing with u of t
students and it's interesting to note
that about a third of you meet criteria
for clinical depression your first year
here.
Now,
what that indicates to me is that the
criteria for clinical depression are a
little on the sensitive side,
but,
but regardless,
because if a third of people meet the
criteria,
thank yeah,
well that's a little sensitive,
but by the same token,
you know,
it's not an easy adjustment and the old
you has to die.
And generally that's not very pleasant.
So,
and it's a good way to think about the
impediments to learn it because you'll
hardly ever learned something without
having part of you dies first.
And that's part of the reason that
people are rather resistant to learning
anything new.
That's important.
Okay,
well,
so you've got that.
Now after that we're going to talk about
piaget and piaget isn't necessarily
known as a personality psychologist,
but that's okay.
Piaget published a v,
he was a developmental psychologist,
maybe the greatest developmental
psychologist.
He published a very large number of,
of books,
many of which haven't even been
translated yet,
some of which haven't even been
published yet.
So Piaget thought a lot of things about
a lot of things.
And he's generally known for his stage
theory of development.
But he really wasn't all that into that
stage theory.
It just seemed to be the part of his
theory that
I would say rather dimwitted western
intellectuals could grasp onto most
easily.
And so that's generally what you hear
about.
But Piaget was a very,
very sophisticated thinker and one of
the things he was interested in was,
well he was interested in how the child
in some sense boots itself up.
That's a reasonable way of thinking
about it.
Cause you know when you turn on a
computer,
what happens is a certain number of
primitive functions,
primitive fundamental functions come
online first.
And then those functions enable more
complex functions to emerge.
And then Noah's functions may enable
more complex functions to emerge and
soon they're,
your computer is waiting for you.
And human beings are kind of like that.
So when we're first born were very
primitive when we're first born were
very immature.
That's a better way of thinking about
it.
We're not precisely primitive.
We still have very large brains and
they're more connections in those brains
at birth.
And there are any that there will be for
the rest of your life,
which is quite interesting.
You actually dye into your personality
because what happens isn't so much that
you make new connections,
it's that a whole bunch of the ones you
already have that you don't use
disappeared.
So that's pretty peculiar anyways.
When you first born,
there's not a lot to you in terms of
capacity to engage with the world.
Your mouth is pretty wired up,
your lips and your tongue,
which is a good thing because you have
to breastfeed and that's actually not
very simple.
You have to have a clue to do that and
it's the first complex social
interaction you're likely to engage in.
So you,
you're born with a fair bit of a
priority,
sophisticated wiring already in place,
but the rest of you,
man,
it's not there much at all.
You can't control your arms.
You know,
if you watch a baby in a crib,
a young baby and it's not swaddled up,
you know,
their arm sort of float around in space
and so to their legs and now and then
they might hit themselves and January,
that seems to come as quite a shock to
the baby.
It's not it's peripheral nervous system.
The peripheral elements of its central
nervous system are not well developed at
birth.
And so it's almost as if the baby has to
discover its limbs.
It sort of expands from the middle
outwards.
It has to discover its limbs and then
start to figure out what to do with
them.
And so what piaget attempted to do was
to lay out the processes by which a
child unfolded into the world.
Now some,
there's a biological basis to that
because you come into the world at birth
with a set of reflexes at hand,
and those reflexes are enough to get you
started.
And so piaget it,
here's one way of trying to understand
piaget.
I like it quite a bit.
It's a bit of an oversimplification,
but it'll do,
there's lots of different ways of
thinking about what the world is made
up.
Now.
You know,
if you're a classically,
if you're a classical scientist,
you tend to think that the world is made
out of matter,
you know,
and then matter is made out of atoms and
atoms are made out of God only knows
what atoms are made out of,
right?
Because by the time you get under Adams,
you just have no idea what's going on
down there.
But you know,
we generally don't think about that too
much and we sort of assume newtonian
reality and that everything is made out
of hard little particles like dust.
And that's the scientific model.
But there's other ways of looking at the
world that are not only equally valid,
but equally necessary and equally
powerful.
And one of them is that you can look at
the world as a matrix of information,
you know?
And so information generally has
significance and meaning,
or at least in so far as information is
conceptualized by human beings.
And so for example,
if you're two years old and you're
crawling around on the floor and the dog
has a bone and you grab it and the dog
nips you,
that's informative.
And so what piaget claims is that
children come into the world with an
information seeking structure and then
as they interact with the world,
phenomena emerge that they can model
with their bodies.
So for example,
if I'm going to drink this,
then I'd have to model it with my hand
before I can do so.
And so it turns out,
for example,
that wouldn't,
if this thing sitting here,
especially if I'm thirsty and I look at
it,
my eyes tell my hands to get ready to
grab it.
And so when you say you understand
something,
what you mean is that at least part of
what you mean is that when you perceive
it,
it maps itself onto your body.
And so this happens at pretty low levels
of your nervous system.
So for example,
there are people who are blind.
They say they're blind,
they can't see anything.
But if you move your hands up like this
and you asked them to guess which hand
you're lifting,
they can do it with almost a hundred
percent accuracy and you think,
well how the hell can that possibly be?
They were blind.
Well the reason that happens is because
your eyes are detecting patterns in the
world.
Some of those patterns you perceive as
conscious reality,
but other patterns you just mapped right
onto your spine or or onto your
emotional system doesn't,
you don't need the perception of the
object in order to have that activated.
Cause you know,
you probably think there's the world,
you see it,
you think about it,
you evaluate it and then you act.
It's like that isn't how it works.
It's very seldomly how it works part
because it's just too damn slow.
You know?
If you had to think about everything,
you'd be running over pedestrians,
no Onstar,
right.
You have to be able to react very,
very quickly.
And part of the way you do that is by
having your sensory systems map right
onto your motor output systems.
So,
so piaget,
well
for Pha,
part of the way that the personality
emerges out of the,
out of the doldrums of infancy is that
the child encounters the world and
incorporates the information that they
gather as a consequence of bumping up
against it.
And then they build themselves in some
sense from their bodies and the ability,
the abilities that they're practicing
with their bodies,
like the gripping mechanism and the
pointing mechanism and does scratching
mechanism and all those things that they
can build.
They build those up to the point where
they can start to use abstractions.
And so the baby sort of spirals out of
nowhere using it's exploratory capacity,
absorbing information from the world and
creates its personality that way.
It's a lovely marvel and we'll cover
that in some detail.
The depths,
psychologists,
I concentrate primarily on young and
Freud.
And you know,
if you take a personality course,
generally you'll,
you'll be introduced to Freud first and
then you'll be introduced to young.
And maybe I've learned some of the Neil
Friday ideas more or less as after
thoughts to Freud,
but I,
I don't really think that's appropriate.
First of all,
I think you can make a strong case that
ewm was,
that the utility of [inaudible] theory
is particularly evident when you're
talking about radical similarities
between people.
So young was very biologically oriented
in some ways.
He was way ahead of biological
psychiatrists and psychologists because
when young was beginning to formulate
his theories in the west,
in,
in North America anyways,
in the United States,
most of the people who were studying
human beings where behaviorists and
behavior is basically presumed that you
are a blank slate at birth and that you
learned how to do everything that you
know how to do.
Well,
that's not true at all.
Um,
first of all,
you can't learn everything that you know
how to do because you have to know
something to start the whole process
off.
And second,
you know,
you don't have to learn really to
understand what a dog's grown means.
You know,
it's kind of wired into you and you
already don't have to learn to be afraid
of the dark man.
You've got that down by the time you
were about three,
you know?
So there's lots of things that are built
right into people and and what exactly
that means we are not sure about,
I mean it does look,
for example like snake phobia is,
is innate.
And even if the actual phobia isn't an
eight and it probably is,
you can learn to be phobic of snakes and
no time flat.
Whereas like trying to become phobic of
pistols is very,
very difficult.
Now young was very interested in the,
I think what the best way to think about
it is the substrata of human cognition.
You know,
because human beings are a particular
type of thing.
It's not like our,
our souls are disconnected from our
bodies and that our knowledge is somehow
appropriate or,
or universal in some way that would make
sense if we didn't have bodies.
We're not like that at all.
We're in our bodies,
our brains are adapted to our bodies,
our minds are adapted to our bodies.
It's so as our knowledge.
And that means that our cognitive
abilities are theories of the world have
biological substructures and those are
presuppositions in some sense for our
dollars that we don't have to learn.
So,
for example,
you don't really have to learn that
being punched hers.
You just discover that you don't really
have to learn what a smile means.
You don't really have to learn what
anger means,
you know,
you'll experience it.
So it's right in you.
It's you,
aren't you like little kids,
little babies.
When they're crying,
they're often angry.
So for example,
by nine months of age or baby can more
or less
identify its mother.
So someone walks into the baby's room
and it takes a look at the baby and it's
not the baby's mother.
And the baby starts crying and you
think,
oh baby.
It's like,
fair enough.
That baby is not sad.
That baby is angry.
And you can tell if you look at the baby
because it's turning all red.
And that's what people do when they cry,
when they're angry.
And so it's a good thing to know when
you're arguing with someone and they get
upset,
maybe they start to cry.
You think,
Whoa,
the poor person.
But then if you look,
you'll see that they're all red and that
means they'd like to strangle you,
but they're,
you know,
they're social niceties is hopefully
preventing them.
So that can certainly change your
attitude towards whether or not you
should be feeling sorry for them when
you hurt their feelings.
So,
so there's all sorts of things that are
universal about human beings and what
human was very,
very interested in what those universals
are and how they played out in patterns
of behavior.
So you can imagine,
you can imagine that you have an
instinct,
say like anger and thinking about that
way,
it's like a cross section that person's
angry,
you know?
And you can imagine the facial
configuration that would go along with
that.
But in a more sophisticated way,
if you want it to represent anger,
maybe you've represented like a drama,
like a story you know began.
That's actually what you want to know.
If someone gets angry,
what happened?
Well,
imagine that you took a thousand stories
about angry people and you boiled them
all into one story.
So that everything that was common about
all the stories about anger when it
capsulated in a single story,
well that would be the architectural
story of anger and everyone would
recognize it because it's like anger
represented like a movie in some sense
in its purest form.
Well that's an archetype and that's the
sort of thing that human was
extraordinarily interested in
understanding and document.
And it's a tremendous amount of fun.
So one of the things we'll do is I'm
going to show you some movies,
probably the lion king,
at least parts of it.
And I'm going to show you how the
archetypal structure manifest itself.
And that's really worth knowing.
It's kind of a pain because then from
now on you go to movies and you'll
think,
oh well no,
that's that architectural structure and
that's what that symbol means and you'll
really be annoying to your friends.
But it's very entertaining and it's very
illuminating.
And partly because what's really cool
about these archetypal story structures
is that not only they do,
they tell you who you are,
but they tell you in some sense who you
should be.
Now that's cool because one of the
things that modern people have a real
problem with is trying to understand
whether or not life has any meaning.
You know,
we look at the world from the scientific
perspective and we say,
well,
it appears that all of this is,
you know,
without meaning,
it doesn't mean anything in any cosmic
sense.
It's,
it's a pretty dope,
dopey conclusion as far as I'm concerned
because the originators of the
scientific method excluded subjective
meaning from the doctrine and at the
outset.
So,
you know,
if you look at the world scientifically
and you say,
well,
it's without subjective meaning,
it's like,
well,
yeah,
obviously because science was set up so
that all of the subjected meeting would
be stripped away from the phenomenon.
So,
you know,
it's not something to be really shocked
about afterwards.
And it also doesn't mean that there's no
such thing as subjective.
Meaning it just means that it's very
difficult to get a grip on it from a
purely scientific perspective.
And one of the lovely things about
architectural stories is they tell you
in a way that's universally believable
who you are.
And,
and that's very cool.
And you know,
because you think you could learn this
in university too,
and it just tears me up.
You know,
you learn implicitly or explicitly and
almost all of the fields of study that
you're going to undertake,
especially on the humanities.
And that moral gravity is relative and
that there's no ultimate meaning,
which is a really rotten thing to be
teaching people of your age,
you know,
because you're,
you're too damn young to be nihilistic.
You know,
you can be nihilistic when you're 85
you're all done by them.
But to be nihilistic now that's a bloody
catastrophe.
You know?
And it's completely pointless because
the notion of the notion that things are
meaningless in some ultimate sense,
it's a,
it's an extraordinarily primitive
philosophical theory.
And it does not serve people well.
It makes them sick.
And so one of the things that you might
consider that is that if you're stupid
theory makes you sick,
maybe there's something wrong with it.
It might be a criteria for the utility
or perhaps even the truth of the theory,
you know,
it depends on how you think about these
things.
You know,
you might say,
well,
if a truth makes you sick,
that doesn't mean it's any less than the
truth.
Well maybe,
maybe it really does mean that it's
much,
much less of a truth.
It depends to some degree on what you
mean by truth.
So anyways,
Young's very,
very,
very useful for that.
He's a terrifying thinker really.
Like
I read when I was about 23 or 24 I spent
two years and I read pretty much
everything.
You wrote about 23 volumes and it just
blew me into bits.
I had no idea what the hell was going on
in my dreams changed really.
It was really,
really rough.
I was reading each at the same time and
he's just about as bad,
like Nicha Sedi philosophize with a
hammer,
you know?
And that's great.
Unless he's taking a hammer to your
skull and that's not nearly so pleasant.
So you know,
young,
he's,
he's a completely different sort of
creature.
And I think that's part of the reason
you never really learned about them in
university.
You know,
if you don't understand and he looks
weird and if you do understand them a
little bit,
he's terrifying and you're bloody well
going to stop.
You'll thank God.
No,
that's okay.
I don't,
I don't really need to know that.
So
Freud,
Freud tonight,
nice whipping boy for a psychologist's,
um,
which I also think is pretty pathetic
because it's in gray,
ungrateful could begin with,
you know,
Freud was really the person who
formalized the idea of the unconscious,
you know,
now everyone takes that for granted that
there's a cognitive unconscious.
That's what the psychologist discovered
in what the 1980s.
There's a cognitive unconscious.
It's like,
yeah,
good work guys.
They'd figured that out back in 1910.
You know,
but you don't see credit being given to
Freud for making that sort of discovery.
If you look at experimental psychology,
which I think,
like I said,
I think that's really ungrateful.
Freud's a strange guy and you know,
you can take issue with especially the
details of his theory.
And I don't like the eatable complex for
example,
or penis envy,
those sorts of things.
It's like it all in some ways they seem
laughably anachronistic,
but you know,
sometimes someone can be wrong in the
details and right in the overall
conception,
you know,
because theories are multilayered
things,
right?
So sometimes I read a student essay,
you know,
and uh,
the pear,
the sentences are just awful.
This person like on God only knows where
they learn to write probably in a high
school somewhere and you know,
it's,
it's incomprehensible.
But if you read the whole thing,
you think,
man,
there's an idea in here,
you know,
the person is smarter than their ability
to write.
And so then you can write,
you can say,
look,
you can't write worth a damn.
But you know,
you're pretty smart and you've got some
ideas here that if you could articulate,
might be a really high quality so you
can be wrong in the details and right in
the overall picture.
And Freud was like that all the time.
And Freud is also unbeatable.
Wow.
In relationship to familial pathology.
So from Freud's perspective,
okay,
a fundamental task of the emerging human
being was to extricate themselves from
their family.
Now you might think,
well,
why is that such a problem?
Well,
here's a couple of reasons.
First,
your parents take care of you.
So it was like maybe you don't want to
dispense with that too early,
especially if they really,
really take care of you.
And that's the double situation from the
Friday of perspective.
It's like the atypical situation arises
when you have a parent or two parents
who do so much for you that you're no
longer able to do anything for yourself.
And that is not a good situation.
It's extraordinarily pathological.
And there is nobody like Freud who lays
out the details of that pathology.
And we're going to watch your movie
crumb.
It's called,
which is very disturbing movie,
which I suppose is a trigger warning for
those of you who think you need trigger
warnings.
Um,
it's a very,
very distressing documentary,
but it will show you freddy and
psychopathology that like,
you've never seen it unless you happen
to live in a thoroughly eatable family.
All right,
so look,
I didn't get through the whole outline.
I'll tell you very briefly what you're
going to be required to do and then
we'll continue this,
that in the next lecture.
So there's three exams,
two midterms and a final.
They're multiple choice.
Okay.
I'll post some of the questions before
the exam so that you know what you're
getting into.
I don't think they're particularly
difficult.
Some of you will beg to differ.
Um,
there's pressure on us this year to
curve the grade,
so beware.
I may have to do that.
Okay.
Just in,
you need to know that,
um,
you have to write an essay,
750 words.
That's not a very long essay,
but that makes it actually more
difficult.
The signup for the topics,
for the essay or on the website,
you can just go there and sign up.
There's 20 different topics and there's
15 slots for each topic.
So I would recommend that you do that
quite quickly.
You have to do a personality,
self analysis,
7.5% of your grade.
The link to that is online too.
You can get started on that whenever you
want.
Um,
your ta,
one of them,
that's Christine brophy.
She's over there in the corner
patiently waiting for me to introduce
her.
She has office hours there.
They're posted online.
You can sign up for her office hours all
in line.
You can also sign up for my office hours
online.
So,
well,
that's halfway through what the course
is going to be about.
So we'll see you on Thursday.