Okay,
so the last time,
so the last time we talked,
I talked to you about how the knowledge
structures that we inhabit might be
built from the bottom up and so I'm
showing you this diagram because it
might help clarify that a little bit,
so what you see at the top of this
hierarchy partially built hierarchy and
so one way of thinking of an attribute
like good when you apply it to a person
or bad or evil or or wonderful or
whatever is to think about it as a
description of an object,
but it's not really.
It's a shorthand for a set of.
While I think of them as micro
personalities,
but you could also think about them as
behavioral patterns.
Now one of the things I mentioned to you
about,
I talked to you a little bit about words
at one point and what words signify and
this is a very complicated problem and
so most of you are probably Augustinians
without really knowing it because St
Augustine originally proposed that a
word was a label for a thing.
And of course that's how people
naturally think.
I mean,
I'm sure most of you would regard that
definition as perfectly suitable,
but it's not.
It's by no means the only definition and
it's by no means necessarily the correct
definition,
so there's a famous philosopher named
Viv Goldstein who proposed instead that
a word was like a piece in a chess game
which meant that it was something that
it was.
It was something that you did something
with or you might think about it
actually as a tool and when you think
about how you use words,
then you can see that you're using them
often as tools to interact with other
people so that for a purpose,
right?
The words have a purpose and so the word
is a tool.
And what I like about the tool idea that
dual ideas,
very,
very evolutionarily sophisticated
concept,
partly because we're tool using
creatures probably beyond our other
capacities except for possibly
invitation and language set.
A set is so far apart from other
animals,
but the thing about a tool is that the
difference between dual in an object as
an object doesn't have a user.
The word object doesn't imply user,
but the word tool implies user and it's
not obvious that we ever interact with
anything in the world without
interacting with it in some motivated
way.
And so what we're doing is using words
to get through the world to interact
properly within the world and to move to
where we want to go.
And so,
okay,
so that's the second way of thinking
about where it.
Here's another way of thinking about a
word.
A word is like a box of things and so
imagine that you,
you've cleaned out your basement and
there's a bunch of boxes downstairs and
you know,
one box is labeled books while inside
that box there can be any manner of
books.
You know,
books is a very,
very diverse,
very,
very diverse set of phenomena.
If you're moving,
books are kind of condensed into one
thing,
which is heavy objects that are made out
of paper.
No,
but you can also imagine another box
that says things and in the thing box,
I'm sure you have a thing drawer at home
where you put all the things that you
don't know what to do.
And,
and so it's like,
it's like the category of old things
that you don't know what to do with
things.
Okay.
So a word can also represent a
relatively heterogenic heterogeneous set
of tools or entities.
And that's very much,
that's very,
very,
very useful to know because one of the
things that happens often when people
are arguing is that they use the same
word,
but each word contains a set of
different objects,
you know.
So you might say for example,
um,
is fear real questions like that are
very strange.
They're not really answerable in some
sense because it depends on exactly what
you mean by fear.
Because fear can contain a lot of
heterogeneous entities roughly speaking.
And then it also means it also depends
on what you mean by real.
And so you can define fear and you can
define real.
So that fear is a subcategory of real.
Or you can define fear and you can
define real.
So that fear isn't a subset of real.
So,
so like the idea that fear is a box that
only contains a certain set of entities
or a certain set of tools.
And that reality is the same as wrong,
and people argue about those sorts of
things all the time and you know,
they make these binary questions like,
is x a y?
Well x and y are generally not well
enough defined so that you can easily
come up with an answer to a binary
question like that.
Okay.
So words can also represent a relatively
heterogeneous set of attributes or
objects or tools.
When you say that someone's a good
person,
for example,
you don't mean that they're a good
person all the time or that everything
they've ever done in their entire life
is good because they wouldn't be a good
person and they'd be a saint or some
other fictional character like that.
So when you're applying the label,
we're calling label for the purposes of
this argument.
It's a descriptive.
It's descriptive tool.
Actually,
when you're applying a,
a term like that to someone,
it's a shorthand for a variety of states
that this person could exist in the
majority of which you would regard as
positive.
You know?
And you might say,
well he's a better person than she is.
And then you'd say,
well,
the proportion of attributes that she
has,
I think I said she,
whatever it exceeds the proportion of
positive attributes that this other
person has.
So the other way that you can think
about a word is Mrs. More complicated
and involve a little bit of
visualization.
So imagine that you have a child's train
on a track.
It's going round and round the track and
it's got cars on it that you can put
things in and all the cars are full of
things.
And then on the track there's a box with
cutouts.
Say That so that the train can pass
through and on top of the blocks is a
word and the word is things and the
train is going through the box.
And in some sense what that would mean.
Imagine the train was long enough is
that at any given second,
the box of things would contain
different things,
but it would still be a box of things.
And a lot of words we use are like that.
Not only are they do,
they represent a heterogeneous set of
entities,
but the set changes depending on the
context that we use the word yet,
so all right,
so the reason I'm telling you that is
because a word.
Here's another way of thinking about a
word.
This will be good for you computer while
you're all computer people.
Now of course
a word is a low resolution image,
so you know what you think about it.
I'm worried isn't good enough
approximation of the thing that it's
representing.
Sort of like a thumbnail.
Now obviously one of the differences
between the thumbnail and the real thing
is that the real thing exists at a much
more,
a much higher level of resolution that
exists at many,
many more layers,
but you can use the thumbnail to
represent it and the advantage to doing
that is that it doesn't take up much
processing time and it doesn't take up
much memory.
So lots of times you want to use the
shorthand for the thing rather than the
thing because it's just too complicated.
Otherwise and often.
Then you might say,
well,
how do you know that your shorthand
representation is a good representation
of the thing that you're trying to
represent?
And the pragmatist would say,
well it depends on what you want to do
with it.
That that's the tool.
Like aspect say it's like if you're
using word x to represent potentially
heterogeneous class,
why?
And when you use it,
you get to where you want or you get
close enough to where you want,
then it's good enough.
So it's like it's how you know a joke is
good enough.
Well someone labs,
it's like okay,
the joke is good enough and so.
So one of the things that's quite
interesting about the way that you
interact with the world,
and this is something that pragmatists
really discovered in some sense,
was that you're always aiming out some
bounded set of events that's somewhat
different from the current set of events
because otherwise you could just sit
there and then you put your conceptions
to work and your actions to work to
manage the transformation.
And if you manage the transformation
then it's good enough.
And that's.
You don't have to go any farther than
that.
So that explains partly how you can
maneuver in the world with limited
knowledge,
use low resolution representations to
partially hit vague goals and that
generally gets you there.
Uh,
that process was called satisficing by
now.
What's his name?
Just extraordinarily famous economists
and psychologists.
Anybody remember who coined the word
satisficing?
Economists,
psychologists or assignment.
That's right.
Sorry,
but thank you.
That's exactly right.
It was herb assignment,
so you know,
and he said,
well,
you're often not out to optimize,
let's say in a search for a partner.
Well,
to optimize it,
you'd have to search through several
billion people.
It's,
you're not going to do that because you
don't have the time.
And so then you might say,
well,
you don't know exactly how you do it,
but it's something like this.
You have five attributes that you're
looking for and maybe to that you don't
know you're looking for,
but you are looking for.
And the first person that comes along
that matches those well enough you pick.
And so it's not an optimization issue,
but you know,
given that you have a limited amount of
time,
you can't wait around for optimized
solutions,
you have to go ahead with sufficient and
then move to the next issue.
Okay.
So all that's a conceptual precursor for
taking a look at this diagram.
So we're calling someone a good person
and so what does it mean while we're
going to do a bit of a micro analysis,
we'll assume that it's a shorthand,
low resolution representation of the
person and that you can decompose it.
So if someone says x is that Henry is a
good person and maybe he's 45,
he might say,
does he have children?
And then you say yes,
and then you might say,
well he is he a good parent because you
might assume that if he's a good person,
he would be a good parent.
Now it's conceivable that he could be a
good parent,
a good person without being a good
parent.
If he was good at like five other report
and things.
But let's assume that as a good person,
he's also a good parent.
I think it's reasonable to assume that
good parent would be a subset of good
person,
right?
Because it's more specific,
more specific means it covers less time
and space in some sense because good
person is a description of a person that
covers how the person interacts with the
world across the broadest possible
amount of time and location and then
good parents as well.
That's.
You find that out when they're
interacting with children.
Let's say for the sake of argument,
there's other issues and then you might
say,
well,
if he's good parent,
what is he?
What does he have to do to be a good
parent?
You might say,
well,
yes,
to feed his children so he probably
needs a job and it would be better if it
was a good job.
So he's got a good job and that's part
of being a good person.
Um,
and then maybe he can care for his
family.
And so care might be regarded as a more
specific subset of good parent.
And so you can decompose care into,
let's say play with baby and then you
can decompose,
play into while I decomposed it into
peak tickle and clean.
And then what's interesting about this
is that those are all abstractions,
but once you get down to a high enough
level of resolution,
they're no longer abstractions in that
there are actually options that you
undertake in the world.
Moving your hand is not an abstraction.
So at some point,
and this is a nice elegant solution to
the mind body problem to some degree at
some level of resolution,
high resolution,
it stops being conceptual and starts
being action and that's where the mind
hits the world.
And then I'm like,
if you go into an even higher level of
resolution than that,
like what do you have to do in order to
move your hand?
The answer to that is you don't know.
You just do it.
And so your consciousness bottoms out in
some sense at the level of voluntary
motor activity.
So there's a level above which you
cannot perceive which are the networks
that you're involved in.
And there's a level below which you
can't perceive,
which is under normal circumstances,
perceive our control,
which is whatever it enables you to
actually move.
So all right,
so then you might say,
well what are all of these things?
These like how would you conceptualize?
I decomposed good person,
but then you might say,
well what are all these things made out
of?
In a sense,
what are their constituent elements?
Good person,
good parent family care,
play with baby.
They're sort of like games.
They're sort of like stories.
They're sort of like rituals.
I think about them in these terms.
So if you look at,
that's where we get to this particular
diagram,
which we're going to concentrate on
quite a bit.
So let me shift to it and then we'll,
we'll,
we'll talk about that.
No,
I don't exactly know how to.
What to call this thing.
I think the best way of thinking about
it is that it's a subpersonality and
that the reason I call it a sub
personalities,
because only a personality has all the
attributes that this thing has.
And so the attributes are.
It's something I talked to you last week
about the fact that the Russian
neuropsychologist,
for example,
felt that people had to build models of
the world and and so you could call this
a model of the world,
but and so the reason they suspected
that was because if you brought someone
in,
I think I ran through this.
If you bring someone into a laboratory
and you play them a tone when they first
hear the tone and they manifest and
orienting reflex,
which is a change,
a change in skin conductance,
and that's actually a consequence of
neurological activity,
and then if you play the tone of bunch,
they stop having that reaction and then
if you vary the tone on any perceptible
dimension,
the orienting reflex returns,
and so the inference from that was all
obviously the the person must be
constructing a model of the tone because
otherwise how would they know if
something deviated from it?
Especially on all those dimensions.
So not only is it,
not only is it a model,
it's a multidimensional model.
Okay.
Now,
the upshot of that was that for a long
time people tried to figure out how in
the world we modeled the world and then
they also tried to make smart machines
that modeled the world,
that could then plan their actions in
the world and then could act in the
world as a consequence and they got
nowhere with that because it turned out
that the world is so damn complex that
if you're going to model it,
you're going to spend all your time
modeling.
You're not going to spend anytime acting
in and you're not going to get anywhere,
and it's partly because the world is
almost infinitely complex.
And so if you're trying to get a
computer to look at the world,
you might say,
well,
what is the computer supposed to look
at?
Everything?
Well,
no,
I mean you look at a lot in some ways
and not very much in others and half
your brain is dedicated roughly speaking
to visual process.
You know,
and then you've got your other senses to
help you figure out what's going on.
But you don't build a model of the whole
world.
You don't build any model alone at all
of the parts of the world that aren't
relevant to you.
So for example,
you're a model of this floor is very low
resolution.
If I took you guys out in the hallway,
assuming the hallway floor isn't the
same color,
and I said,
what was the color of this floor?
You would not be able to tell me.
And the reason for that is who cares?
It could be shifting color all the time
while you're sitting here,
you know,
suddenly and you're not going to care.
And the reason for that is you're not
falling through it and it isn't moving.
And so it's like an invisible
presupposition of your,
of your current knowledge structure.
And there's all sorts of things going on
around you that are like,
that.
You don't pay attention to the walls,
you really don't pay attention to the
people that are around you.
You know,
they could start themselves in a
different way.
You wouldn't notice unless you know the
person.
Um,
there's all sorts of things that you
don't model.
Now you've all seen the invisible
gorilla video,
I presume everyone seen that hasn't?
No.
Is there anyone here who hasn't seen
that video?
Okay,
good.
So that's something a.
I mean it's really something that.
There's this psychology experiment
that's so well known.
You can talk to a crowd now and almost
everyone's seen it.
It's so shocking.
It's like,
of course I would see a gorilla if one
was dancing around on the basketball
court.
It's like,
Huh?
No,
you wouldn't.
Or there's a 50 percent chance you
wouldn't.
Now,
the reason for that is fundamentally
speaking is that your given a task when
when you watch that video and the task
is to count the number of times the ball
was thrown by the team in black and so
all of a sudden your perceptual systems
reorient themselves and you're actually
not really looking at people.
You're looking at something that might
be like animated stick figures who are,
who are engaged momentarily and moving
the object of of perceptual importance
around and so you can blur them out,
which you do because obviously you can't
tell the difference between a gorilla
and the person dressed in black and the
reason you can't is you don't need to in
order to fulfill the task.
You can treat all the people like
vaguely moving black objects and as long
as that doesn't interfere with your
counting,
then it's irrelevant and so actually you
don't build a model of the whole world
and you build a model of only the parts
of the world that are irrelevant to your
ongoing microaction.
Now the problem that brings up is how do
you know what's relevant and.
Well,
that's a much.
That's a tough question and I would say
the reason that you know what's relevant
is because some things don't change over
time and you've been evolving through
three and a half billion years,
so you've built yourself.
If we go back to that other diagram,
you imagine the levels there from the
micro activities to the abstractions.
You think about how much building had to
go in before you can undertake those
micro actions,
so like here you can move your hand.
Well that's great.
How do you get the hand?
Well,
you know,
it took a long time.
It took almost all of the three and a
half billion years before he managed to
come up with a hand.
So even underneath the,
the micro-actions,
there's this massive evolutionary
history that's been built up partly as a
consequence of some of the unchanging
features of the environment or at least
in consequence of some of the slower
changing features of the environment
that has given you this incredibly
complex body that's really good at doing
some things and not very good at doing
other things at all.
And so that's how you solve the
relevance problem.
And I actually think it's one of the
most powerful arguments for the
necessity of evolutionary theory.
It's like this problem is so complex
because it's not only do you have to
adapt to the environment across time so
you don't have to build a body that
adapts to the environment.
It's worse than that.
It's like the train passing through the
box,
the environment's not stable,
it keeps shifting and turning and moving
and twisting and so not only do you have
to adapt to the environment,
you have to adapt flexibly to the
environment while it transforms itself
at different levels of,
of,
of what would you say at different
levels of totality,
because sometimes there's minor changes
in the environment.
Sometimes you know a meteor hits the
earth and you know,
were plunged into darkness for four
years or there's an ice age or something
like that.
So the levels of transformation in the
environment can be radical and the
evolutionary process has to keep up with
that.
And the way it works apparently like I
don't believe this is the whole story,
although it's more or less the whole
Darwinian story is that something more
or less works and that makes a million
copies of itself and there's tiny
variations in those copies often at
least in principle because of copying
error,
which is where I think the theories week
and then they all die except like two.
And so why didn't those die?
And their answer is,
well,
they happened by chance to very in the
direction that the environment varied
and so they get to continue.
And so the reason evolution works is
because everything dies,
everything fails.
So because he's saying,
well,
keeping up with a randomly changing
environment is impossible.
Well,
so how do you do it while you do a
million things?
Most of them don't work and,
but you only have to succeed enough to
propagate yourself once.
So now I think that that's not exactly
right because I don't believe that our
understanding of evolution is complete.
There's a bunch of reasons I don't
believe that one is DNA is pretty damn
complex.
It's not obvious how it could have
evolved.
And even the people who discovered DNA,
we're very,
very perplexed by the fact that it
existed.
So one of them,
and I told you this,
thought that it came from outer space
and it involved somewhere else.
You know,
and you know,
you might think about that as a crazy
theory,
but I'm cosmic winds,
solar winds and that sort of thing can
propel tiny things.
Vast distances rep relatively rapidly.
And over 13 point 5 billion years,
you can really get around.
I think the estimates if even if you use
sub,
if you use transportation methods that
are about the speed that we have,
you could call a nice the whole galaxy
and some like 20 million years,
something like that because it's
exponential.
So 20 million years is a tiny,
tiny subset of three point 5 billion
years.
So it's not as far fetched as it sounds.
The problem is it doesn't address the
problem which is yeah.
Okay.
It came from somewhere else.
But how did they get there?
Right.
It just pushes the problem back.
But there's this other issue too,
which is called MPG genesis Epi,
genesis,
and that's really put old spoke in the
scientific wheels in the last 20 years
because the theory was 20 years ago that
all evolution proceeded through random
mutation and it was random.
Right.
But it turns out that's not exactly
right because there are,
there have been a number of
demonstrations that if something happens
to generation a that will produce a
transformation in the genetic
information that's transferred to to,
to a generation b.
and the transformation often seems not,
not merely a consequence of damage,
but actually a form of adaptation to the
new environment.
So now that's a tough one,
you know,
because when I,
20 years ago when I was studying
evolutionary psychology and evolutionary
biology,
if someone would have said what you can,
you can transmit acquired
characteristics,
it would've been like a year over there
with the creationists because that was,
that was no goal,
that was against the rules.
But it does happen.
And the fact that EPA genesis happens at
all means that there's a lot of things
about how DNA works that we don't know.
And I actually think what's happening is
that the DNA is a very,
very complex microcomputer and I don't
know exactly how it operates,
but maybe it's a quantum computer.
It's very complex.
Remember it's had three and a half
billion years to figure out what's going
on.
So like,
and it's pretty good at surviving.
So you don't want to underestimate it.
And the structures that builds at the
molecular level are so complex.
It just,
if you,
if you.
There's some great animations of those
things going on,
a molecular level on the net.
They're so complex that you can't help
but think of the mess computational when
you watch them,
they're not random processes.
Mad like I watched the little molecule
that checks for error in a DNA
replication string.
I mean it checks for in DNA replication
string man out of how to figure out how
it does something like that without some
form of computation strikes me as
impossible anyways.
I think what happens is that overtime
the DNA plays like it can manifest
itself in many different forms and it
also capitalizes on mutation.
I think that's how it works.
Now you know there's other,
I'd say kind of weak evidence for that.
Maybe it's only evidenced by analogy,
but if I take one of you and I put you
in a radically new environment,
new genes will turn on in your brain and
code for new proteins and so it's like
you're sitting there,
but in some sense there's a whole set of
potential use that are sitting there and
a lot of that potential is actually
locked in the genetic code.
I mean,
it's dependent on the information that's
in the environment around it because
it's not all in the code,
but it's enough to get the process
started.
So if I take you out of situation a and
put you in situation,
be you build new brain structures at the
micro level,
so you're actually a different person
and you know,
that's a very interesting way of
thinking about the consequences of
something like exposure in
psychotherapy.
It's like,
okay,
you're all timid and there's eight,
18 things you're terrified of.
And so you go out and you master one of
them.
It's like Poof,
your brain is not the same,
so maybe now you're a little braver and
then you know,
you go master another one in the bunch
more of you turns on.
Now I don't know if when one thing turns
on something else,
turns off,
you know,
if it's,
you know what I mean is that there's
only so much of you that can be turned
on at any one time,
but,
but maybe a lot more of you could be
turned on then is turned on.
So I think,
you know,
it looks like that because people who
really challenged themselves across the
span of their life,
they develop talents in multiple
directions,
you know,
people can really be amazingly good at a
ridiculous number of things.
So.
Okay,
so
Sokolov and vinegar over the show,
spinnaker Nova showed that you modeled
the world right down to the finest
detail.
But then Dan Simon and his crew showed
that no,
you don't.
You're so blind that you can't even
believe it.
It's like,
okay,
those are not the same set of facts.
So how do we reconcile that?
Okay,
well here's one way of getting up a bit
of a sense of it.
Look straight ahead,
okay?
Now concentrate not on what you see in
the middle of your vision,
but in this side's probably better if
you look at a person to do that.
Doesn't really matter though.
So look at straight ahead but,
but pay attention to what you see in the
periphery.
Okay?
So I can tell you what,
why,
what you'll see,
because some of it's very difficult to
detect way out in the periphery.
It's black and white.
You can't tell that though,
but we know that because if we change
colors way out in the periphery on you,
you can't detect the change and then out
to about here,
if something isn't moving,
it's almost impossible
to see it,
but as soon as it moves,
you can see that there's something
moving,
sort of like dinosaur vision.
You remember?
Um,
drastic park don't move because the
dinosaur can see you.
It's like,
well,
you have dinosaur movement detector
still built into your nervous system and
the question is why?
And the answer is,
well,
if you can't afford to have a lot of
your brain wired up to the periphery of
your vision because your head is only so
big,
then you have to concentrate on
detecting only those things that are
most likely to be relevant and moving.
Things are more likely to be relevant
because they can eat you moving.
than stationary things.
Especially if you've been in an
environment for awhile.
Right?
Because if you're in here,
it's like,
well,
the stationary things are going to stay
stationary so you can ignore them.
You don't even have to see them,
but the moving things,
while they're transforming at a time
rate that's relevant to you,
and so it's good to be able to detect
those.
Now the periphery of your vision is
actually wired in more directly to your,
to your,
to the lower levels of your nervous
system,
so it can trigger off things like
startle reflexes,
which are very rapid.
And it also triggers an orienting
response,
which is the movement of your sensory
systems in the direction of the
stimulus.
So if something over here moves,
then you go like that.
And then what you're doing is you're
nailing it with your central vision.
Now,
out in your peripheral vision,
if you follow the optical track back to
your brain and you'll see that the
peripheral retinal nerves don't attached
to a tremendous number of visual cortex
neurons,
but the central ones do so each of the
central neurons in your,
in your,
uh,
central vision,
the follow via,
each one of those is connected to 10,000
neurons at the first level of
elaboration.
And then each neuron is connected to
about 10,000 other neurons.
So it's 10,000 to the 10 thousands,
two neurons in and so a lot of your
brain is focusing on that tiny little
pinpoint that you use.
That's full vision and it seems to be
about big enough so that you can.
You can bring a face into high
resolution in the center and you can
track the movements of the various
elements of the faces.
If you.
If you look at someone and you look
about 18 inches to their left or to the
right,
you'll see that you can't see their nose
anymore.
You see a kind of a vague outline of
their face.
You can still see the color,
you can detect their eyebrows and you
can detect their mouth,
especially if their mouth moves or their
eyes move.
You just zero in on that right away.
And again,
so what's happening is that way out
here,
You're vision is incredibly low
resolution and then the resolution
increases to the center where it's very,
very high and you and but.
And then there's some tweaks like,
okay,
you can't really see out here,
but you can see motion and that's good
enough because as soon as something
moves,
you can turn your head because you can
turn your head and your eyes and then
you can focus that little pinpoint on it
and dance around because that's what you
do with the pinpoint.
It moves around very rapidly and then
you can scan that central area with,
with high resolution.
And so it's an efficient use of limited
resources.
So,
so partly the way that you manage in the
world,
which is very,
very complicated,
is that even your senses simplify it for
you.
You know,
there's only.
You can't see the entire spectrum of
electromagnetic radiation.
You can only see the visual light
spectrum.
It's very narrow.
There's a whole range of sounds you
can't hear.
There's things you can't smell.
So you know,
you're in a box and some things get
through,
but not everything.
So that simplifies things for you right
off the bat.
And you know,
hypothetically those things you do
detect where those things that it was
necessary for you to detect for you to
be here over this vast span of time and
no doubt there were variants all the way
through that tried to parse it up
differently,
slightly differently and that didn't
work out as well.
So they aren't around.
So you're around because of this,
of death and replication so that,
you know,
it's an interesting take on debt thing
because you're the product of an
unbelievable number of deaths,
right?
Because all of those experiments have to
take place in some sense for there to be
you to,
for you to be here at all.
So anyways.
Okay.
Then.
So you can see with your central vision
that you're focusing on one point and
then you reduce the others too to low
resolution representations,
maybe even cartoons.
And then I also think,
although I don't know this for sure in
someone has undoubtedly done the work.
My suspicions are,
is that in the periphery you don't
update,
you know how your screen updates 60
cycles a second,
something like that.
You updated your vision at about 60
cycles per second,
and we know that because if the screen
resolution or if the screen update
decreases below 60 cycles a second,
people can start to see it flicker,
so we have a refresh rate.
It's around 60 hertz and some people can
see flicker at higher
and higher hertz the nap,
but,
but most people can't.
Sixty is about right,
so that's another way that you deal with
the fact that there's way too much for
you to deal with your.
Your temporal resolution isn't very
high,
you know,
so the smallest meaningful event for you
is about a 10th of a second long.
Now it's if you're in a car accident or
you're in some situation where it's an
emergency and you get a massive burst of
dopamine,
you might be able to speed that process
up by 100 fold.
Who knows,
but you're going to be absolutely
exhausted instantly when you do that.
I don't know if you've ever experienced
that in a car accident or something like
that,
but people often report that time slows
down dramatically and but then
afterwards they're just there.
They're done.
So the reason you don't see a thousand
times as fast as you do is because you'd
have to be eating like a Hummingbird,
right?
You need a big Vat of nectar attached to
you and you'd be just sipping on it,
are gulping it down nonstop.
So you're kind of restricted in terms of
your temporal resolution.
Okay.
Well then what else do you do to
simplify the world?
Well,
this is where the tool concept of
concept,
the two old concept of concept starts to
become useful because you're actually
aiming at things all the time.
And I really liked the aim metaphor
because if you understand the metaphor
well,
it really shed some light on what human
beings are like.
Chimps are hunters,
but they're not hunters,
like human beings are hunters,
were really,
really good hunters.
Chimps.
They have to kind of mob an animal and
then they'll tear it apart and they
liked.
They liked me,
so they'll definitely do it.
But human beings have been hunting and
an unbelievably sophisticated way for a
tremendous amount of time.
And there's a bunch of things about us
that aren't like chimps.
So one is we can throw and our bodies
are built for throwing.
Now you might think,
well that's not that relevant,
but if something is chasing you through
the Bush and you can throw a rock at it,
it becomes relevant very quickly and so
we're really good at taking projectiles,
specifying targets and hurling,
the projectiles out targets,
and we can do that with rocks and we can
do it with bows and we can do it with
rifles and we can do it with nuclear
weapons.
And so there's something about us that's
obsessed with hitting the middle of the
target.
Now there's an interesting side note for
that,
which is that the word sin is derived
from the Greek word Hamartia and
Hamartia is an archery term.
That means to miss the center of the
target.
So now that's something very much we're
thinking about.
It's a very lovely concordance.
And so we're built on this hunting
platform.
We can track moving things
extraordinarily well.
We have the amazing eyesight,
our eyesight's better than any primate
by a huge amount and better than any
other creature except for like hawks and
other birds of prey.
So,
and we also you,
so we have this amazing capacity to zero
in and here's some cool things about
your eyes.
So if you look at a gorilla,
you'll see that a gorilla doesn't really
have whites in their eyes and you might
think,
well that's kind of weird because we do.
And so what's the hypothesis?
Well,
if I'm looking at somebody at the back
of the room,
I can tell if they're looking at my
eyes,
if they're looking at my nose,
it's,
it's almost as if their face just gets a
little bit vaguer like we're not
communicating.
It's either icontact and so our ability
to specify the direction in which
another person's eyes are pointing is
phenomenal.
And you might say,
well,
why?
Well,
first of all,
there's a lot of expression around the
eyes,
right?
So you can imagine a coevolution the
coevolution is sharper and sharper
vision,
vision associated with detecting eyes.
And then also more and more evolution
for,
for emotional expression around the
eyes.
So there's that.
But then
the other thing that I wanted,
the reason that I would be interested in
that is because I want to know what the
hell you're up to because maybe you're a
friend and maybe you're full or maybe
you're interested in something that I
should be interested in and so we know
what people are like in that regard.
So you go stand out on the corner and
you look up and soon there are 10 people
gathered around you looking at and why
is that?
It's because when they see where your
eyes are pointed and embody you,
they think,
well,
that person,
they don't think this.
It's the equivalent of thinking.
They think,
well,
that person must be looking at something
interesting because that's what people
look at and if it's interesting to them,
then it's probably going to be
interesting to me.
Especially if it's in the sky.
It's like what the hell?
That's not supposed to be happening.
So you're looking at people's eyes
because you want to know what they're up
to in their facial display,
which is your face is unbelievably
innervated and controllable both by
conscious and unconscious means that
tells you what they're up to,
which is why you want to see someone's
face.
You don't talk to the back of their
head,
you want to talk to their face and you
don't like it when they're looking like
this or looking like that.
Or failing to make eye contact,
although too much eye contact as a
predatory stair.
So you know,
well you got.
You got to get the balance right.
So now what about the whites of the
eyes?
Well,
the theory is is that the reason we
developed the whites is because it was
easier to see where someone's eyes were
appointed.
If there was a dark circle in a white
space.
And what that basically meant was that
all your ancestors who are a little less
fortunate on the white side either
didn't mate or got killed probably
misunderstandings.
So,
so rois are.
I stand out against this bright white
background because that helps us,
that helps other people detect what
we're up to and that means we can trust
each other more easily and we can even
something as simple as like eye contact
in a situation where there's a
possibility of finding a sexual partners
is a very important component of that
because I contact indicates interest and
it also indicates at least in principle,
the possibility of approach.
And so approaches,
uh,
this dopaminergic Lee mediated and it's
a positive emotional state.
And that's also why interestingly
enough,
if you go into a grocery,
into a pharmacy and there's a rock of
magazines and there what's on the cover
always almost always beautiful woman.
Like on 50 percent of the men's
magazines,
there's a beautiful woman and knowing
100 percent of the women's magazines,
which is really interesting,
you know,
because you might think,
well why is that?
Well,
and the woman's eyes are always looking
out in a way that they're looking at
you.
So there was some interest.
So it's an invocation of interest.
And so,
you know,
magazines evolve,
all the ones that don't get bought fail.
And so what's happened is they all
converge to the same point in the same
point is the thing that's maximally
interesting to a magazine purchaser
is a fee is a beautiful female face,
whether it's male or female.
Now on the male side,
just also gadgets of all sorts.
So,
and that may be because men are more
gadget oriented than women.
So anyways,
and we also know that for example,
with men,
if you show them this is a funny little
study,
so you show them a view of the face of a
beautiful woman and her eyes are looking
that way or this way,
or they're looking right at him.
You can check the activity and the
dopaminergic center in a place called
the nucleus accumbens,
which is the same place that cocaine
hits face on,
I contact that thing,
lights up,
it lights up even more if she's wearing
a red dress,
right?
And you can get the same kind of
lighting up with a red,
curvy sportscar.
So it's the,
you know,
my,
my thought would,
I would,
I read that was the perfect situation is
like a beautiful girl dressed in red
purse on the sports car with some
cocaine.
Why?
Randy?
Yeah,
that's a good.
That's a good question.
I'm not exactly sure why that's wrong.
I do know why red ripe fruit
women have coevolved with right fruit,
sneaky of you by the way,
so that's why you know that you just
have to lead through women's magazine
and the lipstick is always associated
with apples that are glistening in some
way or a peach or something like that.
And where we were primarily fruit eaters
and the reason we have color vision is
to detect fruit ripe fruit.
And so part of the reason that also part
of the reason that fruit turns red or
colored when it ripens is because the
fruit that was successfully eaten by
creatures that distributed this six
seeds was the fruit that was right when
it was eating.
And so as the color vision evolved,
maybe there was a red tint for God only
knows what reason.
Then a positive feedback loop developed
and fruit got redder and redder and at
the same time women capitalized on that.
So that's partly,
I think what explains the association
between Eve and the apple in,
in,
in genesis,
because genesis is always also a story
about gaming site.
So yeah.
So that's why red.
So that's pretty funny.
I really think that's pretty funny.
So you know,
evolved more evolved.
Sensory significance is absolutely
everywhere,
you know,
and it,
it's so deep inside of us.
Yep.
I have to wonder about lead to it seems
like.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Red's a significant color.
But I think,
I mean,
and it's funny too because say say
there's a flushed face will.
That means it's infused with blood.
It's also a sign of health.
It's also a sign of sexual arousal,
but it is a sign of health.
And so you see in an old coke ads from
the 19 thirties,
the girls cheeks are so red that,
you know,
it looks like she has a fever so often
it's a,
it's a form of signaling that indicates
a health.
So that's another part.
I mean these are multiply determined,
right.
And is there anything as complex as
vision?
Yeah.
And blood means,
hey,
maybe don't go there or maybe it means
there's something to eat.
Right,
right.
Yep.
You mentioned that there was another
period of
facial expressions,
but depending on whether you're angry
or.
Oh,
definitely.
Yeah.
Well you can see that those things would
loop together.
Right.
Once the color vision starts to adapt,
it's probably the color vision for fruit
is way older I would suspect because
when we developed it we had for so,
but once the,
once the ability's there and we lose our
facial for then it's possible to
capitalize on that ability to detect the
signaling.
You know,
when we're talking about a
transformation over about we were,
we were living in trees about 60 million
years ago,
so the transition between us and them is
60 million years.
The separation from champs is about
seven.
So,
and,
and you know,
chips skin is so dark that you're not
going to get a lot of signaling.
So.
Alright.
Okay,
so back to this little diagram.
Now,
here's the,
here's the idea,
and this is also informed.
This is deeply informed,
although I didn't know when I developed,
when I was working on these ideas,
this is deeply informed by a guy named
Norbert Wiener who was one of the 20th
century's massive geniuses and a force
behind the development of computation,
and so this is a cybernetic model.
He invented cybernetics.
Now I didn't learn this from no Norbert
Wiener because I learned it from Jeffrey
Gray,
but Jeffrey Gray's sources learned it
from Norbert Wiener way back in the 19
forties.
In fact,
there was a convention back in the 19
forties that when you're presented many
of his ideas at that many psychologists
attended,
including Sean Psj,
and so piaget's theory is very much
influenced by cybernetics as well and
all,
many,
many of the standard psychology.
Cognitive models are cybernetic,
and so they're grounded in thinking
that's actually doing engineering
thinking and not psychological thinking
at all.
Yep.
Cybernetics,
no dianetics.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So,
okay,
so
what,
how might you conceptualize the
fundamental elements of a personality?
Well,
this is,
this is what it looks like to me.
The first thing is you're a moving
creature.
So here's a funny story.
There's this little animal whose name I
forget,
and it's juvenile.
It's an ocean animal and it's juvenile
state.
It swims around.
Okay,
so it's juvenile state.
It has,
it has to coordinate it's movements and
interact with the changing environment.
So it has a brain,
but then when it turns into an adult,
it attaches itself to a rock and turns
into something that's sort of like a,
you know,
a piece of coral.
It promptly digests its own brain.
So the issue is,
unless you don't really need a brain,
if you're not going to go anywhere,
right?
So a brain is going places thing and we
have a very big brain and so it's like
we're always zooming around doing things
and you know,
we've got these hands that enable us to
manipulate things and transform things.
And so the brand is for doing things.
It's not just for perceive it.
Roughly speaking,
the back half of your brain is for
perception.
The cortical part,
mostly visual perception,
but some auditory and touch a lot of
digital.
And the front part is for output motor
action,
and as you proceed,
imagine the front part starts halfway
here.
As you proceed from the midline forward,
the auction becomes more and more
abstract until when you're dealing with
the dorsolateral prefrontal Cortex,
you're thinking abstractly.
Now,
people think that when they're thinking
abstractly,
they're thinking about representations
of the world,
you know,
because we think we think about objects,
but that isn't what we're doing.
What we're doing is rehearsing potential
schemas of action.
So we have this abstract space which you
might think about as a duplicate world.
You have an idea,
you test the idea,
like you would test it if you were
acting it out in the world,
and if the consequence of the imaginary
testing is you encounter grief,
then you don't implement the idea in the
world.
Now you know that doesn't always work
because there's tradeoffs between short
term pleasure in longterm punishment.
That makes it complicated.
But what seems to have happened is that
as we've evolved,
we're very sneaky creatures.
You know,
for billions of years.
The only way that you could figure out
whether you're right or wrong was to go
out and do something and if you died you
were wrong.
So,
but now you can think about doing
something.
Andy,
of the consequence of running the
simulation in your head is that you die,
then you don't do it.
And so what you're basically doing is
spinning off multiple potential use in
multiple potential universities and
running them as simulations,
you know,
and now we really do that now because
we've externalized it onto the computer.
Right?
Which is what we're doing with really,
really complex video games.
So it's so smart.
That's,
it's an amazing evolutionary advance.
Now.
It doesn't work that well because
sometimes you run the simulation and you
think,
you know,
this would,
this is a stupid idea and then you
probably have a beer so that you could
go do it.
So,
but you know,
all things considered,
that's still what this abstract spaces
for.
I should tell you something about this
too,
because you're going to hear from neuro
psychologists that a lot of what the
dorsolateral prefrontal cortex does,
the prefrontal cortex in general is
impulse control and that's.
That's wrong.
That is not what it does and part of the
reason I know this is because the
correlation between prefrontal cortical
cognitive ability,
which is very tightly associated with Iq
by the way,
like the correlations like point nine,
so you could even argue it's the same
thing.
Fluid Iq in particular,
the correlation between Dorsolateral
prefrontal cognitive capacity and
conscientiousness,
which is like longterm goal directed,
future oriented planned activity is
zero.
Okay?
Zero is a very bad correlation when
you're driving,
you know the old idea,
you correlation doesn't imply causality.
Well wrong.
It does strongly imply causality.
It doesn't demonstrate it because with
every crop causal relationship,
there's a correlation.
So 100 percent of causally related items
have a correlation,
right?
One hundred percent correlation.
So,
well,
not necessarily,
but it implies correlation does not
prove it,
right,
but zero,
that's,
that's bad.
That means that those things aren't
related.
Now,
if you think about it,
you can understand why they have to be
unrelated because if you embodied your
abstractions,
then you wouldn't be able to experiment
with them.
You just act them out and then bang,
you'd be dead,
so you have to separate the cognitive
activity from the embodiment completely
so that you can choose which of your
potential selves to incarnate,
so to speak.
Now,
the prefrontal Cortex is a complex place
and the lower parts of it seem to be
more related to the relationship between
cognitive activity and the control of
behavior,
but we have tried 50 tasks.
I bet trying to get a correlation with
conscientiousness and we haven't found
one.
We cannot cope.
The reason I'm telling you this because
conscientiousness is a very good
predictor of longterm life success,
right?
It's,
it's you guys get your grades for two
reasons.
One,
you're smart if assuming you are and two
that you work hard,
assuming that you do that eats up almost
all the variance in your grades.
Creativity is zero correlation with
grades at u of t by the way.
So I think it's extraordinarily comical
and completely completely unsurprising.
So it's hard for an institution to
greater creativity because it's an
institution and the problem with being
creative is that you,
you forced people to come up with a new
grading scheme.
It's like,
no,
they're not going to do that.
So.
Right,
because you come up with something
creative,
it's different.
Well,
what do you do with that?
You say,
don't do that.
That's not what I want.
Even if it's a great thing,
it's like,
yeah,
you have to take your great thing and go
somewhere else with him.
You know,
I've got five minutes to mark your damn
paper.
So.
All right.
So anyways,
the,
this,
this capacity for abstraction is
divorced almost completely from
embodiment and that's a good thing
because that allows us to experiment,
but it's a bad thing because actually
doing the embodiment turns out to be
very difficult.
It's like your body's got all these
habits built into it that you've been
working on for a long time.
Here's another piece of advice.
Do not practice things that you don't
want to become because one of the things
that happens,
let's say
you you,
you take Danish speakers and you've
played Danish backwards to them and you
do a scan of brain activity so their
brains lighting up like mad because they
don't know how to listen to Danish
backwards.
So you get a whole bunch of brain
involved in a new task,
but then as you practice the task and
routinize it,
less and less brain is involved.
So what happens is the activation,
and this is in your standard right hand
male and the reason I'm using that as an
example because that's the kind of
simplest default brain in a sense.
Women are more diffusely organized and
so it's harder to exactly talk about
their neurological structure and in a
simple way,
but in a right handed male.
What happens is the,
the activity starts to shift to the left
and then it shifts backwards and as it
does so the amount of tissue that's
activated get smaller and smaller and
smaller and smaller until you've built a
little machine that takes care of that
sort of thing.
But the thing about that machine is that
it's a little machine,
it's a habit and it's actually there.
It's built into you.
So be careful what you practice because
if you practice it enough,
then it becomes.
It's like it's you,
it's the default you.
And then if you want to change it,
you can't just undo that stupid machine.
It's there permanently.
What you have to do is you have to build
another middle machine that's shuts it
off and then another machine that does
the other thing,
and then if you get stressed,
the little machine that shuts the first
machine off will stop working.
In fact,
your stupid habit will come.
So.
So you know,
people used to talk about the
development of character and there was
something about that that was absolutely
right,
because character is how you build
yourself across time and it really,
really matters.
Only practice what you want to become.
If you,
if you practice other things developed,
then you'll become them.
Not,
that's not so good.
Okay,
so back to this now gray and Sokolov in
vinegar it over.
We're going to talk about them for a
minute.
Now.
They used to talk about animals,
they were mostly thinking about animals,
rats,
mostly as having an expectancy model,
and so you take a rat,
you throw them in a new environment.
What does he do?
Well,
the first thing he does is freeze
because God only knows what's out there
and so he's like paralyzed rat.
He's just seen the Medusa.
He's paralyzed and then if nothing
attacks him,
he starts to calm down a bit and then
you start sniffing because rats are all
smell and he sniffs around and he's
trying to detect cats.
Say now rats have such a good sense of
smell.
If a rat eat something that makes it syc
will never eat it again.
But if a rap smells the breadth of a rat
that ate something that made him sick,
he won't eat that either.
Right?
So rats,
a man,
they can smell things so that.
And animals are built around the smell
brain.
So there are a lot different than us.
We,
we have.
Did I tell you about the,
the t shirts study of symmetrical men.
Oh,
that's a funny one.
Yeah.
So we know that.
One of the things that signifies
physical beauty as symmetry,
right,
because the reason for that is that all
things considered symmetrical,
people are more healthy than
asymmetrical.
Asymmetry indicates that something's
gone wrong somewhere in the process of
development.
So we like symmetry in beauty and a
and that's fine and that's all the way
across the animal kingdom.
So butterflies,
there are butterflies that won't mate
with another butterfly if it deviates
from cemetery.
Some absurdly tiny amount.
Like really it's micro,
it's micro measurement deviation.
I guess they have a butterfly template
and if you know the,
the potential mating butterfly doesn't
match.
It's like flipped her off,
you know,
you're not getting anywhere so,
so that's fine.
But cemetery.
So this researcher,
God only knows what possessed him.
He took a bunch of men ranging from
symmetrical,
asymmetrical,
you know,
judged by a panel and then he had the
shower and then he had them wear a tee
shirt for like four hours and then all
of them.
And then he gave these tee shirts to
women and said,
okay,
rate these,
the,
the scent of the t shirt from,
you know,
positive today.
Negatives,
well the women overwhelmingly preferred
the symmetrical guys,
so yeah,
no kidding.
Okay.
So you just bloody well never know
what's,
what's behind that attraction,
you know,
we know something.
Symmetry is a big one,
but there's a bunch of other ones too.
Yep.
That was just wondering.
I know
you're like,
oh yeah,
there's a bunch of things.
Yeah.
So,
um,
hi,
here's another study.
This is a cool one.
So this is one of the few psychological
fact.
We don't have many psychological facts,
you know,
we have a lot of hypotheses about
things,
but this is as close to a fact as we've
ever gone.
So back,
you know,
decades ago the Israelis children were
raised in and those were basically,
um,
they were basically daycare for kids
group daycare,
but they,
the kids were more separated from their
parents then they might be in a regular
daycare anyways.
Oh,
the Israeli kids were in these boots and
so then we have detailed marriage
records of the kids and so you know,
that people very seldom Mary,
their siblings and they're very seldomly
in a sexual relationship with their
siblings.
And you might say,
well why is that it's the case across
cultures with with very specific
exceptions like often high ranking
nobility can,
you know,
they have an option,
but generally speaking there's a
powerful incest taboo as well as between
parents and children.
So,
so some research and decided,
well how do you know who your sibling
is?
You know,
roughly speaking,
what exactly is it that's not turning
you on,
let's say?
Well,
so they checked out the cupboard some
records and they found that Israeli
children who were raised in the same
Kabuto never married each other.
Whatever happened,
seemed to,
you know,
it was as if that close,
close
contact in the very early years
triggered whatever the sibling anti
response is.
And that was that.
It's probably smelled.
That would be my guest.
Now there's also another study,
one of the things they found with mice,
I hope it's mice,
is that mice will not make.
Is that right?
I can't.
Okay.
I'm going to garble this up,
but it doesn't matter because the point,
the underlying point is valid,
even though I'm going to mess up the
details.
Animal studies indicated,
if I remember correctly,
that mice will not mate with other mice
who have an rh factor that would
increase the probability of a
miscarriage and neither will women.
So women,
well,
not with mice obviously,
but women women do not like the smell of
men who have rh factors that in
combination with theirs would produce
sub optimal,
um,
offscreen.
And when you ask them why they don't
like the smell,
they say it smells like my brother,
something like that.
So anyways,
so anyways,
that's quite remarkable.
Now,
back to the rats and the expected
Seymour.
Okay,
so we already know that
you can get an orienting response out of
a human being if something deviates from
expectancy.
Now people started studying this in rats
and the original conceptualization was
expectation.
So you have an expectation of how the
world is going to lay itself out.
That's your model and nanny of the world
deviates from that.
Then you have an orienting reflex and
what the orienting reflex does is
protect you from predation.
That's the first level of the orienting
response.
It's really,
really primitive.
It's mediated only by a few neuronal
connections.
So it's unbelievably rapid and then
after that there's anxiety and the
proclivity to explore that both gets
activated.
So it's first protective.
Then you orient towards the managing.
You're walking down the street here,
a really loud noise behind you.
It's like really loud so it startles
you.
Well you go into a crowd so that if a
tiger jumped on your back,
it would be hard for it to get your neck
and then you know,
tenths of a second later you'll turn.
You'll assuming you don't get attacked
by a tiger,
you'll swivel and turn and orient all
your senses towards the locale that was
specified by the sound because you have
stereo at a stereo auditory system and
you can localize events in space using
now.
So you already am towards it.
That's part of the orientation reflex.
It's a reflex.
It's not voluntary.
So and then once you got your eyes
trained on it and your ears,
then you start to explore it and then
you might get,
you might phrase,
you might get out of there,
which is a panic response.
That's another thing that can be
triggered by the orientee reflects
different circuit or you might think,
well,
what's going on over there?
It looks interesting and then you go
approach it.
Now those two,
the exploratory part is mediated in part
by the Hypothalamus,
which is a very,
very old system and it has a whole
section about half of it is devoted to
the circuitry that you would use to
figure out what was going on if
something that you didn't understood
happened and then you have a whole other
circuit that's Hipaa Campbell and make
delek that regulates the exploratory
circuit that says,
be careful because while you're
gathering information,
you might get killed and the anxiety
circuit takes primacy generally speaking
over the exploratory circuit,
and the reason for that is you don't
want to get information and be dead.
So caution is the watchword.
Now,
the other thing that you might think
about,
which is an extremely useful thing to
think about,
okay,
let's go back to that diagram I showed
you with the hierarchy,
right?
So you got the motor actions at the
bottom and you've got the high level
abstractions at the top.
Okay?
So you're tickling the baby and somebody
comes home and says,
if you tickle the baby this way,
then the baby has more fun.
And so how do you respond to that?
Well maybe you're a little peeved
because you're doing perfectly fine with
this baby and you know someone's coming
in,
altering your tickling micro personality
and you know if you're irritable you'll
say,
well why didn't you just go off and
they'll find a baby of your own to play
with?
And if you're not,
and if you're not that irritable,
you might say,
well,
okay,
show me what to do.
You know there'll be a tinge of negative
emotion.
They're generally speaking,
depending on how the person has
approached it,
but your self concept can probably
handle a micro change to you're tickling
routine.
Okay?
So that's going to produce only a little
bit of anxiety and irritation.
And the reason for that is that the
threat to you is proportionate to the
magnitude of the system that's being
modified by the challenge.
Now this is really useful to know,
okay,
practically,
and this is why,
so let's say
you're having an argument with your
partner and you say you're a stupid
person and you've always been a stupid
person,
and as far as I can tell as far into the
future,
as I can see,
you're going to remain a stupid person.
So what are they supposed to do?
What are they going to do when you say
that?
They're going to cry,
like if you mean it,
they're going to get angry if you mean
it and they don't like you very much.
And why is that?
Well,
it's like it's.
It's a salt basically.
The only way really the only thing that
you can do in a situation like that is
walk away,
ignore it,
respond in kind or in degenerates into
violence,
not see it because there's no
discussion.
You haven't left the person anywhere to
go.
You've gotten right to the top of their
hierarchy and said everything about used
wrong and worse than that,
all the mechanisms that we could use to
correct it won't work.
So those are fighting words,
so don't do that unless you want to have
a fight.
So then you might say,
well what would you do instead?
And the answer is deliver the least
amount of information you possibly can.
And so let's say you come home and your
person is watching tv and you were kind
of hoping they'd greet you at the door.
You can't.
You shouldn't break down into tears and
say you're a stupid person.
You've always been a stupid person that
you're couldn't be a stupid person in
the future.
You should say,
I have this peculiarity and that is that
when I come home I don't have enough
confidence to just be happy.
I would like you to come and say,
just shut the TV off for two minutes.
Come to the front door and say hello.
Then you can go back and watch your TV.
Would it be okay if you did that?
And they'll think,
well,
you'll have to pay for it somehow,
but then they'll,
they'll probably do it.
And so.
But the thing is,
is you got to specify the routine that
you want transformed at the highest
possible level of resolution,
and you want to,
you want to recommend the minimal
necessary change that will satisfy you.
So you can't say,
if you love me,
you know how to greet me at the door.
Hi non-helpful.
Because they're stupid,
right?
So are you.
So you have to spell it out.
It's like,
what are you wanting to exactly what
would make you satisfied?
And then you have to have your person
like grudgingly practice that a few
times and you have to let them do it
very badly and also in a bad temper.
And then you have to reward them for it.
And then maybe three months later
they'll do it properly.
So you need to know that because that's
what people are like.
It's very hard for them to learn new
things and they're very resistant to it,
but they're very responsive to reward.
So another thing,
this is partly what bf skinner figured
out.
So when he was training rides and he
wanted to do something,
one of the things he would do is he put
maybe he was going to train the robot to
climb up a little ladder and they mean
he could get rats to climb ladders and
then climb across the little monkey bars
and then spin around three times and
then you know,
whack a ball and then eat something like
ego and incredibly complex behavior out
of Ras.
And the way he did that was patients.
So he put the ladder in the cage and the
rat would just run around doing wrap
things and then it would put its hand on
the,
on the first rung and skinner would give
it a pallet.
And so he did,
you know,
after even once the rats going to be
like standing in the immediate vicinity
of the ladder and then the frequency
with which it's going to go like this,
it's just increased so that he does it
again,
Bang Pallet.
Well soon the rabbit is just going like
this,
right?
So then you wait until the trials the
other hand.
So you give it a pellet then,
well then it's going like this and then
because it's going to get bored,
it will go like this.
It'll hit the next stair bang.
You give it a pellet suiting the routes,
climbing and doing all the little things
you want it to do.
Now the problem with that is you have to
be patient.
You have to wait until the rat does what
you want.
Okay?
That's more relationship advice.
Wait until the rock.
That was what you want and then reward
it and it's unbelievably useful and it's
also extraordinarily positive.
I mean I'm being
comical in so far as I can manage that
about the situation,
but people love reward and they love
attention.
People love attention more than anything
else.
And so if you're.
What will you watch through the day and
when your partner does something that's
good,
say man,
that was good,
or something like that.
You can be inventive and then they'll do
it more.
And if you do that a whole bunch,
like for a year there'll be doing things
that are good for you just all the time,
but you have to be patient,
which is very annoying and you have to
suppress your response to only respond
to negative things,
you know,
because what we know about the
expectancy models is that
a deviation from expectation produces a
burst of negative emotions,
you know,
so you come home and the whole house is
clean,
but there's like,
I don't know,
the dog has shed on the rug or
something.
And the person who overlooked,
that's like,
you're not going to see the clean house,
you're going to see that rug with the
dorm for on it.
You're going to say,
why didn't you clean up the rug with the
dog for?
And they're going to say,
good luck getting me to clean up the
house again.
And you know,
because the thing is,
is the exception stands out and what's
done doesn't.
And the reason for that is you can just
ignore what stuff because it's done.
It doesn't get in your way.
So it gets invisible really quickly.
So you really got to watch that
tendency.
One of the things neat you said was that
if you really want to punish someone,
you don't punish them when they do
something wrong because they expect that
that's not a punishment.
They expect that they might even be
relieved by it.
You want to punish them when they do
something right,
because then you'll really hurt them.
And so that's something to think about
in your.
If you're in a relationship,
man,
if someone's done something right,
do not punish them.
You do that two or three times and
that's it and you're not going to get
them do to do that anymore.
So judiciousness,
watch what they're doing.
If something happens that good,
that's good,
notice it and you know if they've done a
bunch of things,
don't concentrate on the things they did
wrong.
That's not smart.
It's really hard on them too.
Like this.
In some sense,
this sounds manipulative and selfish,
you know,
because I'm teaching you how to train
your partner,
but you should also teach them how to
train you because it would be really
nice if you could come home and the
person would say,
what?
What did you do today?
And you say,
you know,
here's a bunch of things I did,
and they said,
they say,
well,
this looks really good and that was
great.
Why don't you do some more of that?
And you're like,
oh boy,
it was a great day.
And so you know,
you can train them to train you properly
and that's a really helpful thing,
especially if you do it over a few
years,
you know you can.
That's how you have a good relationship
because you're both clueless as hell to
begin with.
You don't know even what would make you
happy,
much less what would make the other
person happy.
And so you've got to figure these things
out bit by bit and then you have to
inform each other and then you have to
be patient enough to let your partner do
these things really badly.
I'll give you another example.
Sometimes sometimes I,
I see couples sporadically in my,
in my clinical practice,
I'm not a couple's counselor and so,
but sometimes when I'm working with
someone,
there's an issue that needs to be
discussed with,
with both people because otherwise it's
just stupid.
And one of the things I often recommend
to people,
especially once they have kids,
is that they set aside to use an
anachronistic phrase,
date,
date nights.
Well,
everyone hates that idea.
Like they say,
well,
you know,
they'll just say that I'm not doing
that.
That would be one objection.
We're just not doing that,
you know,
that's what we did before we got
married.
Um,
they'll say,
well,
my partner would never go for that.
They've got a bunch of excuses why that
isn't going to work.
And so I've heard all those excuses.
I know all of them,
and then maybe I convinced them,
yeah,
sure.
I know this is stupid.
It's awkward.
It's,
it's,
it's a artificial that's okay,
just try it once.
So then they go and try it and then they
come back and they say we had an
absolutely miserable kind.
Really.
We had a miserable time.
We couldn't agree on what movie to go to
and then,
you know,
she took me to her movie and I really
didn't like it.
And so we fought all the way home.
We're never doing that again.
And I say,
well really you've got 30 years for 100
days,
that's 12,000 days.
Okay,
so you're not going to do that.
You're going to spend the next 12,000
days without having any real romantic
evenings and interactions with your
spouse.
That's your plan.
And I liked doing,
I liked doing arithmetic with my
clients.
Say they hate that hate or if it's like,
well no,
that sounds like a bad idea.
I said,
okay,
well would you like some romance in your
life?
Are you just done with that?
I'll really like,
you know,
people can go for a long time with no
romance at all.
Say,
well no,
maybe we'd like some of that.
Well how much once a year?
Well,
no,
once a month.
Well,
no,
once every two weeks while sometimes
people are really busy,
it's like,
okay,
that beats the hell out of zero.
Once a week,
twice a week.
Okay.
Whatever.
We're gonna we're gonna.
Start with a range.
Okay.
What would a good evening look like?
Like if you could both get exactly what
you wanted,
what would it look like?
Well then they have to think about that
because the previous theory was my
stupid partner should know what I like
and that's what their partner is
thinking too.
It's like good luck with that because
no,
they don't have a clue.
Especially if they're men,
So you have to tell them what you want
and how they could deliver it and vice
versa,
which is very awkward and horrible.
And then you have to practice it for six
months because you know what?
It takes a lot of practice to do
something sophisticated really well and
then if you do that it's like poof.
You got it for the rest of your life.
So it's worth the aggravation.
You know when the first time the rap
puts its pop on the ladder,
it's just sort of doing it accidentally.
You can't expect it to do it well and
that's exactly how to view your own
progress and the progress of your
partners.
Like let them do it badly for awhile.
At least they're doing it so.
And if you think they should do it
faster,
well look real hard and see how easy it
is to change your own behavior because
it's really hard to change your own
behavior.
Everybody says I'm going to exercise
three times a week and new year's and
it's like no one does.
They bind the memberships and then they
feel guilty for having them,
but they don't actually go to the gym
and that's a perfect example of how
difficult it is to transform behavior.
Okay,
so back to the diagram here at
expectation.
So
the early models of expectation where
cognitive models and the idea was that
the rat makes a little model of the
world and then he operates it in that
world according to what he expects.
Now there's a problem with that model.
There's a bunch of them.
The first is now we know that animals
don't make comprehensive models of the
world and that's a huge problem.
The problem is,
well,
what did they get rid of and how,
but the way you get rid of that problem
is that you introduced motivation into
the equation and it's interesting
because the behaviorist,
so I always thought of animals as blank
slates and so they never really took
motivation seriously as a contributor to
cognitive modeling,
but and it's also the case that probably
ever since the,
the enlightenment,
people have thought about emotion and
motivation as forced as opposed to
rationality.
You know,
so you were rational in so far as you
didn't let your emotions and your
motivations influence you,
but that's a.
that's a foolish theory.
There are times when it's inappropriate
for certain purposes to let certain
motivations interfere with your
observations,
but generally speaking,
you never think about anything without
being motivated.
Because why would you?
Like?
There's a trillion things you could
think of and you're not going to think
of.
Most of them.
You have to have a reason to think of
them and the reason is is that while all
the time you're operating in some sort
of motivational structure and you can
sort of model them using the same kind
of hierarchy that we used to model the
personality as such.
So I'll give you an example.
So let's think of some basic motivations
and emotions.
Those are good categories by the way,
because there's no such thing as
motivations and there's no such thing as
emotions.
The things we loosely categorize into
motivations and emotions each have their
own brain circuitry and so there are
similarities between them and there are
differences.
They're not clean categories,
but we're going to use the terminology
anyways because we don't have a better
one for my purposes.
You can roughly define a motivation as
opposed to a emotion as a motivation is
really something that establishes,
you could say a goal,
but it doesn't.
It establishes one of these.
It doesn't establish a goal and it
doesn't drive behavior.
So what it does,
let's say you're hungry and it's
nighttime.
You want to have a peanut butter center,
so imagine you're sitting there typing
away and all of a sudden you this little
image of having something to eat creeps
into your head.
It's not usually quite specific.
It's there's something that you would
like dig so you think,
oh,
I could really use some popcorn.
Let's say she typing away and the stupid
popcorn thing keeps popping up and
finally you know,
your whole body's starting to get into
the popcorn and you think,
oh,
to hell with it.
I'll go make some popcorn.
And so what's happened is that your
hypothalamus,
roughly speaking,
has,
is monitoring your internal body state
and it thinks that you need some maybe
need some salt,
but maybe you need some folk and so it's
gonna start popping up,
not a dry.
It's not like all of a sudden you're a
robot,
you know,
like a popcorn and seeking robot and
you're laying out your chained together.
I'm conditioned popcorn making and
eating routines.
That isn't.
What happens is that what happens
instead is that you start to envision a
new state of being and that state of
being has a goal which is you eating
some popcorn and it has you where you
are,
which is in an insufficient state of
popcorn,
and then what's happening as well is
that this,
the,
the motor processes that you would use
to implement that are also disinhibited
there.
There you already know how to do it.
They get disinhibited,
so or you could think of them as getting
primed.
They're not,
they're getting disinhibited,
but you can think of it as being primed
and at some point that becomes
overwhelmingly overwhelming enough,
say pressure from the Hypothalamus,
which is really what's bloody well in
control says,
yeah,
Yeah,
enough like Internet surfing off to the
popcorn and so you leap up and then what
do you do?
You reorient the way you're looking at
the world.
Everything in the world becomes low
resolution or even zero,
except those few things that are
relevant to your new quest down the
stairs.
You Go,
you find the right pen,
you find the popcorn getting irritated.
If you can't find it right,
because now you see it's interesting
because your emotions align along your
goals.
As long as you're pursuing a beeline to
your goal and everything's laying itself
out,
not as you expect,
but as you want,
then your emotions stay positive,
but as soon as something deviates,
then you're irritated.
And the reason for that is that like
let's say you can't find the popcorn pad
while your brain is computing.
Well,
something like this.
This is obviously not how it works,
but it's an x amount of energy and
matter from popcorn means it has x
value.
If you expand a whole bunch of energy
running around in your clueless state
trying to acquire popcorn,
you can easily get to the point where
you've expended more energy and time
than the popcorn delivers.
And if you do that for a month,
then you die.
So.
So it's perfectly reasonable for you to
get irritated when the path links to
your destination increases radically.
And you might get even more irritated if
you can't find any popcorn.
And then it's like,
oh no,
I have to dispense with the popcorn
micro personality.
And it's all irritated because you know,
it sort of alive,
it's irritated that you have to squash
it and then you have to come up with,
well maybe I could have a peanut butter
sandwich,
you know,
pop up comes a new little micro
personality that orients itself towards
the goal.
And so all the time you're doing that,
you're always in a motivated state.
Now it's not a drive because it's not
deterministic,
but it does have a behavioral element.
You have all these [inaudible] and sub
routines.
They're are stored in your body,
you know,
all your,
your,
your body capacity or your skills and
you know which set of those you're
likely to use if you're going to do x
thing.
And so those get prepared.
And then your perceptions,
real orient towards the new goal.
It's like a hunting goal.
You're fixated on it.
Then your emotions orient long that.
So as long as things are going well,
you're happy,
you're hopeful.
Things are proceeding.
That's positive emotion,
that's dope.
Um,
energetically mediated.
And if things aren't going well that
it's either,
well,
it's any amount of negative emotion for
mild irritation to like full blown
temper tantrum.
So,
so that's.
And you're okay now.
That's the simple story.
The complex story is,
okay,
you're hungry,
you're thirsty,
you're tired,
you're hot,
you're cold,
you're lonely,
you need to play.
Okay?
So let's say you've got,
for the sake of argument,
let's say you have eight fundamental
motivational systems.
Now who cares how many?
It's a finite set under 20.
It depends on whether you include anger,
is anger,
motivation or emotion is pain,
motivation or emotion?
We don't care because they're not formal
categories.
So anyways,
there's this,
there's a,
there's a set number of them,
and then so they have to run to
satiation.
And so what satiation means is they set
up an end state.
You perform the routines,
you achieve the end state,
the system shuts down,
it's satiated.
Now you'll experience that as
satisfaction,
not as pleasure.
Now you think,
well,
what's the difference?
It's,
it's,
it's tight,
it's complicated.
But it's important.
The kind of positive emotion that people
really like is associated with the
search and the hope not with the
acquiree,
because what happens when you acquire
is,
well,
you're no longer in this state,
which has a,
uh,
an impulse to action in it.
But that's exciting.
That's fun.
You know,
you're on the track of something.
It's like you're alive while you're
searching for something,
but then you find it.
It's like,
good,
you need to find it,
but then the whole thing disappears.
And you're sitting there thinking,
well,
I've just graduated now what?
Right?
Because that's what will happen when you
graduate.
It's like,
Hey,
you're a student,
you've got status,
you've got a,
you've got a hierarchy of values,
you've got a way of orienting yourself
in the world and you have an identity.
It's like,
so you're,
you're in there and everybody's happy
about it.
So then one day you graduates like
success.
Well,
really it was like,
poof,
that's gone.
And the next thing you know,
you're like handing out coffee at the
local starbucks.
So what you're doing,
you get the point.
You've experienced this all the time in
your life.
You hit a pinnacle,
you've attained something,
but the problem is is that
now what?
You have to conjure up a whole new you,
so some of it is sat satisfying,
you've accomplished the goal,
but some of it's just a big pain in the
neck.
It's like,
oh,
student me is disappeared and now it's
frantically searching for employment me,
and that means doesn't have the status
and and it is in this space,
a much more radical uncertainty,
so,
so don't be thinking that getting that,
getting to where you want to go is what
you want.
What you want is to bloody well make
sure that the voyage is worth it.
Now and it's very interesting because
people are really,
really,
really wired up this way and I think
it's because we're so radically
exploratory,
so when you're,
when you're proceeding towards a valued
goal,
let's call that a cue,
that goal attainment is about to occur.
It's going to occur in some chain.
A leads to b leads to c leads to d and
so on.
That's your like a hound on a trail.
It's,
it's positive.
It's like,
yeah,
this is working.
Yeah.
This is working.
Yeah,
this is working.
That's positive.
It's moving you in hand,
and that's really where you experienced
a lot of your positive emotion.
That's dope.
Up near GP mediated.
That's the system you'll kick with
cocaine or any of the other drugs of
abuse that people use that don't put
anxiety.
It's a very,
very desirable motivational state.
I read a while back,
somebody who said you can buy anything
but you can't buy wanting anything,
and that's a staggeringly interesting
comment because you think,
well,
you know he's wanting a positive state.
Well you don't have it,
so that's kind of annoying and you
think,
well no,
I don't want to launch things.
I want to have them.
It's like,
yeah,
don't be so sure about that.
So one of the things,
one of the ways people have figured out
how to deal with that is that they
decided to want something that they
can't get.
And that's actually extraordinarily
smart and it's a deep archetypal idea.
So here,
here's an example.
You've Seen Pinocchio,
right?
Okay.
So Nokia was about a puppet marionette.
Does that mean someone else is pulling
the strings?
Right?
We don't know who,
sometimes it's virtually Satan himself.
You remember the Stromboli?
There's another character just after him
is the coachman,
the coachman.
He's like King of the thieves and he
ends up pulling Pinocchio strikes.
So there's one scene in the Disney movie
where the coachman reveals himself and
he's completely ready,
is really big teeth.
He's a,
he's a satanic figure and he scares the
Fox and the cat who are like low level
criminals who think they're bad but you
know,
have never really met bad.
He just scares that right into the
corner.
And so it's all of a sudden this person
opens up and reveals the architect
behind and then closes back down,
pulling Pinocchio strengths.
Okay,
now he's a married man.
Well,
you know,
the first question that arises is who's
pulling your strings?
And that's a really good question.
One of the things young said was,
people don't have ideas.
Ideas have people.
And you know,
you can think about that for about three
months and it should make you afraid the
whole time because as soon as you,
as soon as you,
as soon as you get that,
you think,
oh,
like let's say you're an idiot log of
some sort,
because some of you probably are
Socialists Fascist environmentalist,
something that has just on the end.
It's like you think those are your
ideas.
They're not your they're tools and
that's fine.
If you want to be a tool of those ideas,
you go right ahead,
but you don't know where those ideas are
leading and they could well be leading
somewhere.
You do not want to go.
Now the plus side is you don't have to
take any responsibility for it because
you know you're just.
You're just drifting in an ocean of
thought.
But one of the things that I learned
from young was you should figure out
just exactly which ideas are possessing
you and then you should decide if those
are your ideas and the probability that
they are a zero.
They're not your ideas.
It's hard to have your own ideas.
You have to derive them from your own
experience,
you know,
and when you,
especially when you're not very old,
you don't have that much experience,
and so you can,
you can grab books full of ideas and
claim them for your own,
which is not acceptable.
You can use those ideas to inform your
ideas,
but they're not your ideas.
You're just a puppet,
you know,
in the Pinocchio movie is very
interesting that way because he's a
puppet of forces that are really not on
his side.
Seriously.
No one on his side.
So.
Okay.
Anyways,
back to the Pinocchio Movie.
Give me one sec.
So Japan doesn't have a son now.
Japan was a good guy,
right?
He said,
Tony Maker.
He's got this little warm cabin.
It's cozy.
He's a good guy,
he's friendly,
he has a little cat.
He pays attention to his little fish.
She takes care of that.
So we know Japan is a good guy and he
makes this property.
Thanks band.
I've got a puppet,
but maybe I'd rather have something
real.
That's a good question for parents.
You want to pop it or do you want
something real?
And answer is generally,
often all just have a puppet as long as
it does exactly what it.
Maybe it be a medical school puppet
because that's certainly one good form
of puppet.
So okay,
so Japan.
Oh,
decides because he's a good guy.
He thinks,
no,
I don't want this thing to have strings.
I want it to be its own thing.
I want it to be a tournament's
individual.
Real.
Okay.
So what does he do?
He wishes,
right?
What does he wish on a star?
Why do people wish on stars of all the
crazy things?
Well,
it's a divine thing,
right?
It's a divine thing.
It's like there's heaven.
It's all.
It's the infinite.
You go out at night and you see the
stars,
which you can't in the city,
but you go out somewhere dark and you
see the stars and it's like it's you and
the infinite,
and it really is.
It's a perfect representation of your
relationship with the infinite because
the university is about as an infant as
you need,
and it's going to give you a sense of
awe and that's partly why archaic people
thought that God was in the sky.
It's like it's not.
They weren't stupid.
These people,
they thought God is what fills you with
awe.
So you look at the guy and you think,
wow,
you know,
that's something and it's an.
It's an instinct.
It's not a cognitive construction.
So anyways,
you aim at it starts this twinkling
thing in the darkness,
right?
It's the light in the darkness and it's
above.
It's above the worldly environment.
It's something transcendent,
and so that's what you better wishes on.
It's like,
I'm going to aim high.
That's what he says.
Aim High and he thinks,
well,
it's not very likely,
but I might as well aim high.
That's a very good piece of advice.
You want to aim so high you can't attain
it because then you've got something
worth it might be.
Think that's such perverse.
That's such a perverse per piece of
advice.
It's why would you chase something you
can't have?
Well,
the answer might be because of the
chasing is worth it and then you might
think,
well,
what's worth it?
Well,
I can give you a hint about that too.
It's like develop your character because
what you've got is what you carry with
you wherever you go,
and it's way better to be able to do
things than to be rich because if you're
rich,
well then that disappears.
Poof,
you're poor.
But if you can do things short of being
demolished and even then people are
unbelievable and overcoming those
things.
It's like you're.
You're on the way.
Here's an interesting experiment we did
with with undergraduate women,
so there's this idea in evolutionary
psychology.
It's called hyperthermia and
Hyperthermia is the tendency of women to
choose mates who are slightly older than
them on it's about four years on average
cross culturally and who are higher in
the status hierarchy than they are.
Okay?
It's very well documented tendency and
people who are cynical about that think
women want wealth and I thought,
well,
it's not a bad theory because it kind of
evens the scales.
It's like you're going to have a family,
you're basically a chimpanzee baby
clings to its mother's for for 5,000
miles in the,
in the three or four years that it's
doing the clinging.
It's like it's a major league
impediment,
you know,
and if you're a new mother,
your,
your life is so much more complicated
than it is when you're a single that
it's not even the same conceptual
universe.
It's a major league responsibility and
it slows you down.
So then you might think,
well the logical thing to do would be to
balance the scales a little bit and
that's perfectly reasonable.
But I thought,
Nah,
I bet your women are smarter than that.
I bet you can fool them.
And the pickup artists do that all the
time because they mimic status.
So you,
you can follow them,
but they're not.
They're smart.
So what we did,
I never published this be for a bunch of
reasons,
but okay.
So what we did was we took,
we took pictures of the same guy,
you know,
just kind of an average looking.
He's all right.
And we had four stories about them and
one story was a poor,
useless guy.
That's an easy story,
right?
You know,
sits on his couch,
plays video games.
Each cheetos covered with dust.