Yeah,
Dr Warren Farrell is the author of books
published in 17 languages and they
include two award winning international
bestsellers,
why men are the way they are.
Plus the myth of male power.
Warren has been chosen by the Financial
Times as one of the world's top 100
thought leaders.
He is currently the chair of the
commission to create a White House
council on boys and men.
He's the only man in the u s to have
been elected three times to the board of
the National Organization for women now
in New York City.
Dr Farrell has appeared repeatedly on
Oprah today.
Good morning,
America and has been the subject of
features on 20 slash 20 in Forbes,
the Wall Street Journal People Parade
and the New York Times.
His Co author of his newest book is Dr
John Gray.
The author of men are from Mars.
Women are from Venus.
Once again,
this is the book we're going to talk not
only about the book today,
the new one,
the boy crisis,
but also about Dr Farrell,
his career and his goals and his aims
and all of that.
And so I'd like to introduce everyone to
Dr Warren Farrell and ask him to tell us
what he's up to and why.
Well,
I guess what I'm up to sort of the
evolution of maybe all that time since
1969.
And uh,
when the women's movement surfaced,
I was very interested in it and we felt
that women really need it to be able to
be equally respected and enter the
workplace and have options open.
And I was upset that women were not
playing sports to the degree that I felt
that was creating the benefits to them
of sports.
And so I started articulating this and
started talking to my doctoral
dissertation advisors about doing this.
And their first reaction was war in the
women's movement.
It's just a fad.
And I said,
I don't think so.
I think this is the beginning of the
change of,
of gender roles from both men and for
women.
And so I will talk with them about that
eventually convinced them that I could
change my dissertation and that led me
to being seen by now as someone who was
a man who was receptive at a time that
the feminist movement was getting a lot
of accusations of being man haters.
And so I think I served the purpose of
here's a,
here's a man,
a real life flesh man who advocates,
but we're advocating here,
um,
get up and say what we're saying.
It's going to be harder to call you a
man hater.
And so,
um,
the,
I started doing that and then ended up
speaking all around the world on women's
issues and the value of,
of women being secure enough and
competent enough to be able to share the
breadwinning burdens that men handle.
Um,
and that was my focus for until the mid
seventies.
And in the mid seventies I began to see
that the feminist had made a great deal
of progress.
And was.
Everyone was sort of getting on board
who was in,
at least in the sort of middle class
above an educated.
And so,
um,
that was,
but it was also a huge number of
divorces occurring.
And so I began to say it's important for
the children to have both parents after
divorce and,
uh,
Betty Friedan and Gloria Steinem and a
woman named Karen necro agreed with me,
but I'm now the board.
I was on the board of now at that time
had gotten elected as a result of
advocacy to the board of now and my
fellow,
um,
and you know,
female co workers on the board of now
said we were at a dilemma here.
And the dilemma is that the women are
writing us saying they're gonna withdraw
from now if they don't have the option
to determine what happens with the
children after divorce.
And we do,
we don't want to lose now membership
because it's not only important for
family purposes,
but for all the other agendas we have.
And so I said,
well,
the important thing is not women's
rights or men's rights.
The important thing is knowing what's
best for the children.
And they said Yes,
Warren,
great theory,
but we really need to focus on
empowering women and at a broad
spectrum.
And so they ended up all voting in terms
of giving women the option to be fully
involved with the children or not,
depending on the,
under the guise that women know the best
though the children the best and
therefore they know what's best for the
children.
And so now,
and I began to have a significant amount
of tension over that point.
And Betty Friedan and Gloria Steinem
didn't weigh in.
They weren't on the board of now.
And then all the other boards of nows,
um,
around the country began to go the same
way that the New York City now went.
And so that led to my disengagement.
And also I started forming hundreds of
men's groups,
one of which I think,
you know,
was joined by John Lennon.
And um,
and that was a,
that had a big impact on both the people
in the groups that I began to see what
memes pain was.
And so I began to articulate men's pain
in as well as women's pain in my,
um,
in my presentations and when I was only
articulating women's pain and women's
challenges,
I would always almost always get
standing ovations and maybe an average
of three invitations for a new speaking
engagement.
And that was helping me live financially
very well.
Um,
but then when I started to integrate the
perspectives and feelings of men from
the men's groups,
uh,
there was a lot of,
um,
I think I didn't see those standing
ovations.
Why not?
Why not
for new speaking engagements went from
three to two to one,
and then eventually to zero.
Well,
it seems,
it seems self evident in some sense that
if you're articulating truthfully and
carefully what would be good for either
sex in some sense,
you have to be articulating what would
be good for both and unless you view the
battle,
unless you view reality as a battle
ground between the sexes.
And then as an,
as a zero sum game,
we can't have an intelligent
conversation about what's good for women
or what's good for man.
We have to have a conversation about
what's good for men and men and women
and women and men and women.
And so why do you think,
what was your sense of why it was when
you started to raise these other issues
that you were,
that you were admitted immediately
unpopular.
Two questions.
Why do you think that made you unpopular
and why is it that you saw early
cottoned onto the fact that there was
something going on that wasn't exactly
kosher in relationship to now push for,
for,
for a particular kind of family
structure and a particular view of
women's rights?
Yes.
I think what happened for me was,
um,
I,
I just,
when I started focusing on what was best
for children and then I began to,
we only had minimal amount of research
for that at that point in time.
This is your early seventies and,
but we had enough for me to make a case
to the board and when I saw the
resistance,
the degree to which there is,
there was two things happening.
One is we don't want to lose our power
base.
We don't ever want to have a woman say
whatever options she wants should be
close to her,
and so I began to see that the women's
movement was caring more about women
than they were caring about the
children.
That was the first disillusionment that
I had.
Okay,
so you're a first year,
first ethical point in some sense is
that when you're speaking about families
and you have to balance the rights and
responsibilities of men,
women and children,
that it makes sense to you to put
children's wellbeing first and foremost,
and then to place men and women as
individual say or may perhaps even as a
couple below that.
Yes,
exactly.
What I was saying was that freedom of
choice is wonderful,
but when you make the freedom of choice
to have a child,
you then start prioritizing the needs of
the child you made,
but you knew that those needs were going
to be the child's needs first.
When you made that free choice,
so it wasn't like you were coerced into
the,
into or pressured into making that
choice.
You made the free choice to have a child
that incorporates the need to put the
child's perspectives before yours.
That's part of your free choice.
Right?
So it's basically the freedom there is
the freedom to take on a certain kind of
relatively permanent responsibility and
then to abide by that come hell or high
water essentially into the future
that the children should not respect the
parents needs because part of what I
talked about in the crisis is that ain't
nobody happy,
that everybody has to be happy at a
family and that and that part of
choosing a child to be responsible is
teachers and the child not just to have
its needs met,
but to also a care about what,
what,
what their moms or dads needs are being
met as well.
And that has to be very primary and
primal and introduced early.
Um,
but that the,
uh,
and then secondly,
um,
I also felt to end and Betty Friedan and
felt this way also that the,
the women's movement would never go as
far as it could go unless the,
unless men were equally involved and
proud of being involved in the fathering
role because a woman who has to take on
the entire response,
a woman who wants to break glass
ceilings and go as far as she can but
also wants children can do that.
All of the man is working full time and
she's working full time.
Either the children get neglected or um,
you know,
or something,
something has to go.
And so,
uh,
when we will often say to me,
you know,
I want to be a habit or a woman and I
say,
you can be a habit.
All women revere.
Find a man who wants to be home full
time with the children and let's reshape
society.
So we're saying that,
that men are not only worrier warriors,
that we,
that we praise and call heroes when they
go to war and they die for us,
but they're also warriors if they
choose.
If you,
if you choose a man who wants to be
fully involved with the child,
let's honor him and respect him because
we know that the social bribes that we
gave men to die allowed men to be
willing to sacrifice their lives in
exchange for being called hero.
Uh,
well,
if we,
if we read frame being a father as being
a different type of hero,
men will follow because men basically go
wherever the praise goes.
Okay?
Okay.
So in the seventies,
so you started to put forward the case
for children and to some degree as well,
simultaneously the case for fathers.
And you received a fair bit of
resistance as a consequence of that.
And it sounds like the way you're
setting up the argument is that the
conflict.
What was the conflict though?
Was it that the women who were being
appealed to by now wanted untrammeled
freedom of choice for them under all
circumstances?
Because the reason I'm asking is because
if you have children,
obviously half the children you have or
female,
and you assume that if it was a matter
of of women's opening up,
what would be best for women in any kind
of medium to longterm manner that the
concerns about daughters would be
perhaps even if it isn't concerns about
psalms,
it would be concerned about daughters
that would emerge is paramount even over
the concerns of the mother.
So.
So what is it that was.
I still don't exactly get why it was
that you weren't being successful
because it doesn't make sense
because the car,
the priority.
There was two things happening
simultaneously.
One was such a strong emphasis on
freedom and the freedom manifested in
two areas.
One is in the area of divorce in
divorce,
that women were often saying,
I don't like my husband.
I want to start a new life.
I want to be able to move out of state
if I wish to to get a job that I want or
my new husband,
my new husband or boyfriend has a.
has a wants to move out of state.
And so I want to be able to take my
children or child with me,
um,
because,
and,
and I know what's best for my child,
which would be like the medical
community saying we don't want women to
be participating in the medical
community because we know what's best
for the patient and not,
not I,
not that women might have separate,
um,
a contribution to make.
On the other hand,
there was the,
there was women who wanted to have the
freedom to be able to have children
without being married.
Um,
and so 53 percent of women under 30
today who have children in the United
States have children without being
married.
And the belief was again,
that women knew what was best for the
children.
So we could,
they,
they could take this on if they want it
to and they couldn't find a man that
they really wanted a,
that they can raise a child by
themselves with the children that
themselves.
So,
so part of it was actually driven by
questioning the necessity of the nuclear
family.
I was the smallest viable unit and part
the.
That's correct.
And B,
uh,
the,
the feminist community started,
um,
when I,
when I would go to a feminist rallies
and so on,
there would be many books about,
you know,
then in the nuclear family being the,
the patriarchal that were oppressing
women.
And so there,
so I think the feminist,
the feminist movement grew out of two
huge iterations.
One was the civil rights movement where
there was an oppressor and oppressed.
Then there was the,
um,
the,
the movement of not just civil rights,
but um,
after the,
after the civil rights movement came
the,
the Marxism and the belief that there
were oppressors and oppressed in among
Marxists.
And a lot of the feminist movement,
the early feminist movement was very.
We had groups like red stockings and
many other groups like that that were
socialist worker,
party type feminists that very much
believed in Marxism.
And they had the dichotomy of oppressor
versus oppressed.
So when it came to men,
men,
because we earned more because our
biological,
not our biological parents socialized
and biological responsibility was to
earn the money and do that.
That type of nature of providing the
feminists movement looked at the fact
that we earned more money once we had
children and so therefore we must be the
oppressor like those,
like the porch was he a of Marxism and
women must be the press.
So we have two things happening
simultaneously.
This belief that the oppressors are
wanting to be equally involved with the
children.
And then secondly,
men having no idea why they had value.
Third men who are very few men that did
study the value of being a father,
how important it was to children didn't
speak up about it and women can hear
what men don't say.
So we had this world then where women
were sharing the burden of a bread
winning,
but no one was even interested in asking
the question about whether men could
share the burden from women of,
of,
of earning a [inaudible],
providing equally for the family.
And,
and women weren't even interested in
that because there are so focused on
their freedom and so men as the
oppressor.
And so there was no space to articulate
the value of fathers and men in the
family.
Okay.
So,
well,
you know,
your terminology is interesting too,
because you're attributing the,
the desire of the women who were pushing
against what you were saying,
say you're attributing that to a desire
to freedom,
but it seems to me that you could easily
use irresponsibility as a terminology
there,
you know,
because free,
free,
well freedom without concern,
for the medium to longterm consequences
of your actions,
especially when you're bringing in,
when you're dealing with minors,
when you're dealing with children,
that's not freedom.
That's irresponsibility.
That is absolutely a responsibility.
And that is where we as a society have
failed to come in and say,
um,
you know,
first of all,
whenever either sex wins,
that is a woman wins custody,
for example,
whenever either sex winds,
both sexes lose.
And it's worse than that.
Whether they're whenever either sex
winds,
both sexes,
Lewis.
And in the case of,
of family,
the children lose enormously.
And we also need to sort of understand
exactly what is it that,
that leads to children and doing so much
better when they have fathers involved.
I was,
I started researching that and it ended
up,
as you know,
with the boy crisis,
ended up with more than 70 different
ways that when children have their
father involved in about an equal way
that they do so much better than.
Yeah.
Well it would be a lovely thing if you
could detail out some of that now and
then we'll go back to the,
the,
the political ideological story here,
but,
but see,
one of the things that's happened in
Ontario recently is that we've,
our,
our government is introduced legislation
that is predicated on the idea that all
families are equal and the,
the idea behind that you could argue is
laudable.
I,
I wouldn't argue that,
but you could argue it,
that you know,
people have a variety of ways of solving
the problem of having children and that
there's a variety of viable solutions to
that problem and that no one family
organizational type should be privileged
above the others.
I mean,
I suppose with the exception of
multi-partner marriages,
which we still don't approve of,
let's say the problem with that as far
as I can tell is that it does appear
from the research that the nuclear
family is the smallest,
smallest viable unit,
which is not to say that there aren't
single mothers or single fathers who do
an admirable job under trying
conditions,
but part of the problem,
this is a deep problem,
is that whenever you.
Whenever you pause it,
something as a value,
so you might say,
well,
we want intact families,
mother and father.
That's that.
That's the value we're heading for
because that seems to be best for the
children.
Then you produce a rank order of
accordance with that and the people who
aren't in accordance with that value.
You can easily make a case that they're
being discriminated against and we're in
a situation in our society now where
even if the discrimination occurs,
let's say,
because of the pursuit of an admirable
value,
it's regarded as prejudicial and I think
that's fed by that underlying hypothesis
that was anti nuclear family.
That any sort of hierarchical structure
is part of the tear radical patriarchy.
It's something like that that's running
underneath it.
So anyways,
let's review if you would be very
helpful.
I think for everyone,
some of the many ways that it's
necessary for children to have fathers,
why that's better and perhaps also for
for society as well,
not just for children.
Absolutely.
Children that have a lot about an equal
or more than equal father involvement
have a number of things in common as a
rule.
Then obviously there's reversals of this
and not that everyone gets this,
this,
this pattern,
but the first is they're far more likely
to have postpone gratification and I'll
elaborate on that a little bit more.
Postpone gratification is probably the
single most important quality to
becoming successful and becoming
successful,
especially being employed in a job that
has some meaning for you is one of the
most important ingredients in happiness
and a sense of purpose and a sense of
motivation and a sense of willingness to
get up in the morning and so I'm in a
little while.
I'll be happy to just trace back how
that postpone gratification happens more
when you have a father.
Yeah,
cause I'm really interested in hearing
about that.
Second.
Second layer is for children that have
an equal amount of father involvement
are far less likely to be depressed.
They're far less,
more likely to be assertive and not
aggressive,
which is something you usually think of
men as being aggressive,
but actually the children of both girls
and boys whose fathers are involved are
far more likely to understand the
distinction between being assertive and
being aggressive and choose
assertiveness.
Boys,
another surprising one for me,
um,
and doing the research was finding that
boys and girls who are raised with about
an equal amount of father involvement
are far more likely to be empathetic
because I always thought of empathy
coming predominantly from moms and I'll
be happy to explain in a bit why it does
come more from moms,
but why the outcome for the is not more
empathy.
The outcome for the child is less
So a little bit more on that later.
Far more likely.
Both boys and girls should drop out of
school.
If there isn't far father involvement,
I'm far more likely when a,
when a,
when a relationship breaks up,
um,
a child that has not had significant
father involvement is much more likely
to be depressed and be withdrawn and b,
feel alienated.
I'm far more likely to be addicted to
video games,
far more likely to be addicted to video
porn.
I'm far more likely to have few social
skills,
few emotional skills to do worse in
every academic area,
but especially in reading and writing,
which are the two biggest predictors of
success are far more likely to have a
lower sperm count have.
Um,
and here's an amazing thing.
I just discovered toward the end of the
research for the boy crisis I saw in
pediatrics magazine,
and that children who by the age of nine
don't have a significant amount of
father involvement.
Both girls and boys are likely to have
shorter telomeres.
And as most of us know,
the telomeres are pivotal in predicting
life expectancy.
So boys and girls,
the average shorter telomeres for a nine
year old boy or girl without father
involvement was 14 percent a w,
I'm sorry.
It was a 14 percent shorter,
but the boys tell it mirrors were then
again,
40 percent shorter than the girls.
So here this was predicting about a 14
percent shorter life expectancy for the
average child without father involvement
by the age of nine already.
And yet the boys were suffering more.
So two things fascinated me.
There is,
you know,
all the things like,
dropping out of school and things like
that.
I asked myself,
well maybe this is because boys with
father involvement,
I'm just have better,
you know,
better neighborhoods.
Um,
they,
the father's earned more,
the families are more,
maybe it's a matter of poverty versus
poverty.
So I started looking at a boys and girls
growing up in and good quote,
good neighborhoods with good schools and
comparing them with boys and girls
growing up in poor neighborhoods in poor
schools and found that the boys and
girls growing up in good neighborhoods
with poor schools that did not have
significant father involvement.
Did about the same as boys and girls
growing up in poor neighborhoods with
poor schools that did have father
involvement.
That father involvement was really as,
as good a predictor of success,
um,
as the quality of the school system,
the quality of the neighborhood and the
socioeconomic class.
And this is what's led to,
um,
uh,
to the psychologist I'm gathering
together behind people like worship 100
psychologists and researchers saying,
you know,
this is not a correlation.
The involvement of father,
this is not a matter of socioeconomic
issues.
This is a matter of actual father's,
father's,
father's involvement.
Especially the biological father's
involvement actually makes a significant
difference.
We have been wrong about the assumption
that this was probably just a
correlation.
And so the more I looked,
the more I found just every nightmare of
a parent to be so increased,
uh,
when there was not a significant amount
of father involvement.
And I was seeing,
I was dating between before I married
lives.
The woman you just met just before we
got on a,
before we got married 14 years ago,
um,
I was dating a number of women.
Almost every woman had a,
was a single mother,
and these,
every single woman was working her rear
off line to balance her life.
Every woman used the word overwhelmed by
the way she felt.
Um,
every,
almost every woman said,
well,
I'd like my dad and the dad involved,
but um,
but when the.
But I started listening to the butts of
the women and then listening to men who
had,
wanted to be more involved with their
children and listening to what the
differences were between what the Mit,
what made the men feel,
not wanted,
what made the men feel excluded and why
the women felt that they needed to not
have the man involved.
And I saw this entire set of
misunderstandings here and if I hope the
boy crisis does anything,
it's just sort of explained,
you know,
here are the 10 major things that Dad's
do that that's sort of a noi.
Women or make women feel that they're
not protecting their children
adequately.
Which when they understand the purpose
of these things and dads get their
homework done enough to articulate to
the moms the purpose of these things
that will realize that the,
that these are necessary ingredients in
a child's life.
Okay,
so that's a good,
that's a good place to go next.
So you laid out a whole slew of reasons,
a slew of consequences of fatherlessness
and will return back to the causal
relationship between men do and these
beneficial outcomes.
But if you could go on now to tell us
what it is that men are doing at a micro
level than we could return to the causal
link between that and not positive
outcomes.
And you said that those also caused some
contention in the household?
Yes.
I'll give one example of,
for example,
will be I'm a father is rough housing
with the kids and the moms looking over
and saying looking askance and thinking,
okay,
when should I interfere?
When should I not interfere?
And the mom saying to herself,
I'm Jimmy,
you know,
um,
please keep the kids away from the,
the Credenza.
They are paid the kids away from the the
couch because they could hit their head
there.
Why don't you wait,
have they to tomorrow when you can take
this outside.
I feel much safer the kids,
and then the mother is sort of
hesitating to not be overly controlling
and yet at the same time she's feeling
she has to monitor the husband as well
as monitor the husband with the kids and
she's feeling in the back of her mind
like I sooner or later that's going to
be,
there's going to be an accident here and
I'm going to be upset with myself for
not being stricter,
but on the other hand,
the kids seem to be having fun,
so I should let things go.
Well,
you know,
there's A.
There's a cycle biologist named Jaak
Panksepp who was one of the world's
great biological psychologists and he
studied rough and tumble play in in
animals.
So rats,
for example,
a huge part of the socialization process
that's key to the development of the
prefrontal cortex in juvenile male
routes in particular emerges and matures
as a consequence of rough and tumble
play.
And one of the amazing things that
Panksepp discovered it,
and this truly is an amazing thing,
is that,
um,
if you,
if you pair two rats together and then
let them play repeated bouts,
the big rat will dominate the little rap
to begin with in the first bout.
But if the big rat doesn't let the
little rat win about 30 percent of the
time in repeated play boats,
then the little rat won't play anymore.
So you get an emergent morality in
emergent play centered morality even
among rats as a consequence of rough and
tumble play.
And that rough and tumble.
I did a fair bit of research on rough
and tumble play about all,
it's probably 20 years ago now,
15 years ago anyways.
And it's really quite clear that rough
and tumble play helps children
parameterize their bodies so that they
know how they extend and,
and,
and also what limits there isn't the use
of physical interactions with another
person.
What's fun,
what's provocative,
what's pushing it too far,
what's painful?
And of course kids love rough and tumble
play as well.
They're just absolutely starving for it.
And we've squeezed it out of the
kindergarten is the nursery schools,
the elementary schools,
the junior high schools,
all of that and for and for bid.
And what Panksepp also found was that if
you deprived juvenile routes,
have the opportunity to engage in active
rough and tumble play,
that they showed symptoms that were
broadly analogous to those have
attention deficit disorder in human boys
and that you could also treat that with
Ritalin the same way in routes as you
could with boys.
So there's that rough and tumble play
issue,
you know,
when you might think to the question is
one question is why might a mother be
distrustful of the rough and tumble play
episode?
And some of that might be sensitivity
with regards to the kids.
But huge part of that also was trust on
her trust with regards to the father,
you know,
because it's rambunctious and noisy.
And if she trusts,
let's say that that act of masculinity
that plays rough,
then she'll stay away and let the fund
happen.
But if there's distrust running through
the family,
then then she'll stand between the kids
and the father.
And then he won't get to involve himself
in that way and then he'll turn off and
I've seen that happen.
Many,
many families.
Okay.
So there's rough and tumble play.
That's a big one.
What else?
What else do you see?
Let me take the.
The evolution of how rough and tumble
play goes in all the dimensions of the
slippery slope that it leads to.
So the,
the father,
the what the mom,
when the mom or the dad knew is that
this rough and tumble play leads to the
types of things that you just mentioned,
but you're also evident in,
you know,
an elephants and so on.
But it also leads to the distinction
between a child being able to
distinguish between being assertive
versus aggressive.
So the.
So the kid starts,
for example,
maybe I'm kicking the dad and the wrong
place or poking the data and the eyes
are pulling the dad's hair.
And the dad says,
sweetie,
you can fake.
You can fake.
I contacted the left and then move to
the right to win in this wrestling
match.
Or you can,
um,
you know,
you can do this,
this and this.
But you can't do these things and if you
do do these things will stop the rough
housing.
Yeah.
So there.
So there is a really important issue
there.
So two things there.
So imagine that.
Imagine that a rough and tumbled boat is
like a dance.
Okay.
And the point of the dances so that both
people are having a good time while it's
happening because otherwise it's not
play right.
And then as soon as either party is no
longer having a good time,
you've actually snapped out of the cycle
biological function of the play circuit.
So basically what you're telling the
child by putting those rules on is we
can interact physically within a very
limited set of parameters and you,
you have to learn to do is to be sophist
as sophisticated player within that set
of parameters.
And you want to learn how to push the
boundaries,
right?
Because the most fun rough and tumble
play is right on the edge between
assertiveness and aggression.
So.
And you can see kids,
like I used to work in daycare centers
when I was a kid when I was 18,
19 and the kids would line up to rough
and tumble play with me because that was
still allowable then and they were so
desperate for it,
it was just ridiculous and I could
really tell the difference between the
kids who had engaged in that sort of
play and the ones that hadn't and the
ones that hadn't were painfully awkward
and they would hurt themselves and you,
when you wrestled with them,
they put their thumb in your eye or.
And they would cry often too when they
got surprised but not hurt,
you know,
because they couldn't tell the
difference between just being startled
and being hurt.
And so they were fragile.
And that also made them not fun to play
with.
And the thing that's so interesting
about that too is piaget talked about
this when he talked about the
development of children is that,
you know,
the more sophisticated pretend play and
then sophisticated cognitive play that
emerges say between five and seven.
And then with the cognitive play older
than that is that unless you have that
underlying cycle motor embodied dance
down,
you don't get to really proceed in a
sophisticated way to those higher levels
of play because other people don't want
to play with you.
So the rough and tumble play,
the importance of that can hardly be
overstated.
So
absolutely.
And the framework here is that when you
set up a system where you said that men
are part of the patriarchy,
their,
their desire is to dominate women and
make rules to benefit the expensive,
the benefit men at the expense of women.
You have a framework or an emotional
setting which does not,
is not conducive men saying,
here's my value or women's saying,
let me see what the checks and balances
of parenting is that leads to the best
of you coming out.
And the best of me coming out,
all of that has sort of skipped over and
inherent sense of father knows best to
father knows less.
Um,
and,
and so the,
the,
the process that I'll be sharing in a
moment of what rough housing leads to
and the slippery slope that happens when
it doesn't happen,
um,
is,
is what is not even been nurtured as a
possibility to be articulated in this
culture at the.
I also think too,
you know,
that if you have a partner who hasn't
been played with,
then that partner can't tell the
difference between Boisterous
rambunctiousness and aggression and if
there's a hypothesis about domination
and the patriarchy running its course
underneath that,
then there's going to be conceptual
confusion about the physical
interactions that have the appearance of
submission and dominance because that's
part of the rough housing play routine.
That,
that is going to be viewed through a
lens of tyrannical interaction rather
than just good fun.
I mean you can tell the difference
because if the kids are rough and tumble
playing,
they're unbelievably enthusiastic about
it and engaged and laughing and giggling
and like they'll play right to the point
of exhaustion because they need it.
They need it so much.
But that's a hard thing to observe from
the outside.
If you're not accustomed to that,
and if you don't have that framework of,
of um,
of men having a dad's having a value to
begin with,
absolutely no.
So here's,
here's maybe what might bring,
be helpful for a mom to understand that
the rough and tumble play we now know
helps children distinguished between
being assertive and aggressive,
but a number of other things off also
happened during that play,
which is a bond that is created between
the father and the child.
And in almost every I've been doing
expert witness work to help children
have both parents.
You have to divorce.
I've observed more than 50 families and
um,
and usually the father interacting with
the,
with the children.
And in almost every case,
every case,
I try believe that I have seen this,
this,
this bond is used by the father to say
things like,
okay,
we no more rough housing.
Now tell you what,
you get your homework done.
You get your chores done,
you get all ready for bed,
brush teeth,
teeth,
brush.
Well,
and the bedtime is 9:00.
Whenever you get all that done,
we'll have between the time you get it
done and the time of 9:00
in order for you to have some more fun
either with rough housing or reading my
favorites,
favorite story or whatever.
Whatever you prefer.
It's your choice.
Well,
you know with,
with Panksepp's work too,
he found that the little rats,
the rats will work to enter a play arena
because because play,
you think play is a so panksepp
established very,
very clearly that there is a primary
place circuit in mammals.
It's a separate cycle,
biological circuit.
It's not exploration.
It's a whole different motivational
drive,
but that the activity in that circuit is
intrinsically pleasurable and part of
that appears to be because it's so key
to proper socialization that it.
It's regarded by my children and by
social mammals as intrinsically valuable
and so it makes perfect sense that that
can be used as a source of primary
reward.
And I think your comments about the the
man and the kids binding themselves
together through play is also really
important because one of the things that
I do with young man who,
you know,
I think young men tend to be somewhat
alienated from infants who are under
about nine months old because they're
not really equipped to know what the
hell to do with them.
I mean they can learn and they can be
good at it,
but it's not their domain of natural
expertise.
But once a kid hits about nine months
and starts to be able to imitate and to
pound end to end to play and to respond
to gentle teasing like that's a perfect
time for the father to swoop in.
Just very helpful for a mother by the
way,
who wants to have another child and to
start really cementing a relationship
that's based on that interest in
combination of,
of high energy fun.
Plus the disciplined interactions that
are necessary as a precursor to that.
And if you interfere with that,
then you stop the farther from being
able to form that pro from liking his
kids.
Really.
You know,
because that's how the liking comes
about is,
is through play and so it's,
it's crucial.
It's crucial significance.
Absolutely.
And thank you.
The,
the,
the additional framework that you're
placing on this has really deepened my
own understanding of the
neuroscience written by Jaak Panksepp.
It's on my reading list on my website
because he lays out the findings from
the animal literature on the primary
place circuit.
It's really,
he should have won a Nobel prize for it.
I mean discovering an entirely new
motivational system in the brain,
a major,
major contribution and to also.
The other thing that he did that was so
cool and sort of reminded me of John
Piaget's work a little bit is he made a
very strong case that out of play
emerges an ethic and you know that.
That's why I was so interested when you
mentioned that interactions father
actually increase empathy because you
know,
if someone has empathy for you,
that means that,
I mean that can lead to a certain kind
of narcissism,
right?
Because you're always the center of
attention.
You're not empathic unless you learn
that you're not any more important than
the next person and particularly the
person that you happen to be playing
with.
So.
Okay,
so let's continue with,
with what fathers are doing.
Yep.
So in that rough housing,
what happens is that the bond that is
created by the dad allows the dad to
say,
you know,
here's will continue the rough housing
if you get between 8:30
and nine,
if you,
if you have everything done,
um,
but so that the child learns to postpone
gratification from doing the what it
loves to do right then and there that is
the rough house with and deal with what
it has to deal with before it gets more
of what it needs.
And so,
but the.
So That's interesting.
So you,
you actually think,
and I wonder if there's been any,
any.
See we don't know much about the origin
of the trait conscientiousness,
which is at least in part,
the ability to delay gratification.
And it is after intelligence.
It's the best predictor of longterm life
success,
especially in managerial and
administrative jobs and algorithmic
jobs.
It's not associated with creativity,
but that's.
That's a side issue.
So your hypothesis is that the primary
way men are socializing that is by using
work to play as a.
As a,
as a bridge,
yes.
The,
the.
That that play creates a bond.
So a lot of the problem is when,
when moms often say,
you know,
you have to do this,
you have to do that,
you have to do that.
The mother is often experienced by the
child has sort of the disciplinarian
who's always making him or her do things
and there's a seeds of rebellion start
to occur of sort of like how much am I
going to be myself?
How much am I going to do what mom does?
Do I want to be a mama's boy?
Or it doesn't even have to know.
You're just sort of feel like you're
being pushed down by all the rules.
But with dad,
the bone that is,
or moms who rough house with the
children,
a bond is created and from the end and
you want to return to that,
that connection.
So you.
It's like a child going on a
rollercoaster,
you were,
you know,
there's an enormous amount of safety but
you also,
and excitement,
but it also an enormous amount of safety
and so you trust the data to combine
that both and you want to return to
that.
So you're willing to focus on getting
done what you need to do your homework,
your chores,
your brush,
his teeth or whatever in order to get
what you want to do,
which is,
you know,
of postpone gratification.
But now let's take the slippery slope
when this doesn't happen.
So.
Okay,
so let me,
let me just add one more thing to that.
Well,
the thing that's so cool about that is
that you've also provided a really
intelligent piece of parenting advice
for,
for fathers.
It's like,
because you're so,
let's say bf skinner,
who was the famous animal behaviorist
demonstrated quite clearly that you
could train animals with reward more
effectively than with threat or
punishment.
Now,
threat or punishment is necessary.
Obviously we wouldn't have biological
systems,
subserving those emotions if they
weren't necessary,
but but reward is harder to use because
you have to be much more attentive and
intervene when something good happens
and so you really have to be watching.
But your hypothesis here is look,
father's,
spend a bunch of time playing with your
kids and having as much fun as you can
with them because I formulating that
bond.
You can use that as a,
as the source of reward that will be
appreciated by the child with regards to
disciplinary strategies.
So it's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a twofold victory.
One is it's fun and you get to like your
kids and have a good time with them,
but the second is you have a very
positive means of disciplining them in
the best sense,
encouraging them and disciplining them.
So that's,
that's a really useful thing to know
product
thickly.
So deepening the trust to the kids like
that.
Like you're playing and you're right on
the edge that you were talking about,
but there's dad to make sure that the
fund doesn't get too hard for you,
for him,
for your sister.
And so on and so that that's all
happening at the same time.
Now when the right and that's embodied,
you can see that two ways,
that's embodied trust.
So if you toss a little kid up in the
air and catch them,
I mean it's very exciting to them both
being tossed up because of the threat,
but then the relief that occurs because
of the safety that's put in there,
so it's not abstract.
It's really demonstrated.
And then our dad taught you that child
up and,
and then in fact missing the child,
quote unquote,
and the child lands on the bed and
weren't like,
Oh yeah,
I was missed.
You going to catch me.
But also recognizing as well that shows
that that shows that things can happen
that aren't entirely what you predict,
but within the confines of a trusting
relationship,
that's still okay.
And then you could also imagine if the,
if the dad is wrestling with more than
one kid at the same time,
then he's also acting as just referee.
Right?
So,
and then the kids learn how to be
judicious in the distribution of
attention.
They learn how to play.
Fair,
they learn how everybody,
how everybody can have a turn and
everybody wins out the same time and so,
and that bonding is what is part of what
creates,
just everything you just said is part of
what leads the child to have empathy
training.
And the empathy training came from.
No,
you were too rough on your sister there.
If you try it again,
you can't be that rough.
Oh,
you still continue to be that rough.
Okay.
Let's no more play.
That's right.
Play stops when everyone isn't having
fun.
What?
My kids were little,
we had this couch that was a sectional
in six pieces and so we could put the
couches facing each other and then we
put up the,
the uh,
the backs all the way around it.
So it was like a little wrestling rate.
And so then I would take the kids in
there and just wrestle them half to
death,
you know.
But one of the things I used to do was
if one of the kids was rough with the
other and made them cry,
then I noticed that the kid who made the
other kid cry wouldn't look at the
crying kid.
They look away and avoid.
And so I always used to say,
no,
you look,
you look and you see what happened
because that,
that triggers that embodied empathy.
And then you can easily have a
conversation and say,
look,
you know,
is that how you want the game to go or
do you want everybody to have fun?
And the thing is,
once the kid actually looks,
then they've got it right because they
can't escape from that empathic
identification.
And so
yeah,
when the child doesn't have that said,
we have all this data now these 70
different areas where children do so
much worse when they don't have a father
involvement.
So let's look at the next stage of that.
When,
when,
when that father does not do this
roughhousing housing and as just one
example of many and um,
and does not as not enforcing
boundaries,
the child then doesn't learn to have
that postpone gratification.
So we have hard data on this that
children grow.
Children raised predominantly by dads,
are only 15 percent likely to have adhd,
children raised predominantly by moms,
so 30 percent likely to have adhd.
So if we looked at what we just talked
about,
the children that are raised by the dads
are learning that they have to postpone
that gratification you see in order to
get the reward that they want.
Now you take that capacity to postpone
gratification to school.
The child without postpone gratification
assigned a homework assignment,
doesn't really feel,
is oftentimes distracted by a text
that's come in,
distracted by,
um,
the opportunity to play video games
distracted by wanting to exchange notes
with other kids is distracted,
distracted.
Well,
yeah.
If the distraction thing about the disc,
there's no need to explain adhd.
What there is a need to do is to explain
why every kid doesn't have it.
And the answer is,
the answer that you just laid out is
that some kids learn how to control
their district.
Distractability doesn't require an
explanation because people are
distracted by what's immediately
rewarding.
And that doesn't require an.
It's like addiction.
Actually,
addiction doesn't require explanation
either.
What requires explanation is the
development of the resources that allow
you to withstand addictive pressures in
the face of the fact that they're
always,
they're everywhere and they're powerful.
So it's,
it's,
it's development of control.
That's,
that's really the curious issue.
And I've never heard this,
I've never heard anyone make this
connection between the use of play as a
reward.
And that delay of gratification.
Now it's a very,
very interesting idea.
That's very interesting.
And then let me take it another step
further.
So when this delayed gratification is
happening or does not happen,
and then the boy isn't able to finish
homework,
he started speaking,
beginning to feel ashamed of themselves,
or if he's athletic and his parents
believe that it's really going to be
helpful to the child to have beautiful
dream.
Sweetie,
you want to be an NBA player and you're
tall and you know,
you continue practicing.
You can be an NBA,
NBA player,
you can have your dreams,
but he doesn't have that postpone
gratification.
So cannot do the boring repetition that
comes with all success,
including being an Olympic star or an
NBA player or anything else
playing the piano or learning to read or
great example.
Certainly the violin.
Um,
and so you,
so anything that is his dream,
the bigger the dream,
the bigger the disappointment and it's
not just disappointment that he fears
will happen to his parents.
Uh,
but also the sense that he says he's
gonna do one thing in school.
His P,
his teachers,
his peers are not respecting him as
much.
He,
um,
he,
the cheerleaders aren't going first and
10 and a concussion again to him,
they're doing it to somebody else at
first and do it again.
The um,
and so the,
the boy is beginning to feel shame.
Yeah.
Well,
you think,
you think shape.
Look here.
Here's the precondition for shame.
So let's say that you are attracted by
goal naturally.
And you know,
maybe that's scaffolded by your parents,
maybe it's scaffolded by your peers,
but it's something that you're naturally
turning your attention towards.
It grips you in some sense.
Okay?
And and we'll assume that it's a
difficult goal.
And so then there's an ethic that
emerges out of that,
which is that if that goal is valuable
and it's difficult,
then there's sacrifices that have to be
made,
delays of gratification that have to be
implemented in order for you to be
worthy to attain that goal.
Okay?
That's all part of the game.
If you think about it as a game,
well then then if you observe yourself
unable to play the rules of the game,
play by the rules,
then how can you not have any?
How can you not suffer shame and self
contempt because you've already adopted
an ethical framework,
which is this is worth attaining.
And if you observe in yourself,
then the inability to attain it because
you're constantly being distracted,
then you're going to have contempt for
yourself.
There's no way out of that.
This is something I learned from nature.
Here's the terrible thing about that
because that's a great pathway.
Denial isn't because let's say you pause
it for goals in succession that you find
valuable and then you observe yourself
unable to discipline yourself to attain
the goals while the most after four
successive failures,
it's like,
ha,
homer Simpson said to bark,
he said to Bart,
um,
you tried and you failed,
and then you tried and you failed again.
What did you learn?
And,
and homer says to Bart,
the conclusion is never try.
Right?
And so if you fail a few times,
that's at attaining something of
importance because you see that you have
no discipline,
then the logical response to that is to
cease positing goals.
Absolutely.
And that's a,
that's exactly what happens.
And,
but we have through technology,
so to have a perfect escape and that
escape is into video games where you can
identify with the hero and you can lose
the game as often as you wish to with
nobody noticing.
And then as you begin to get better with
certain,
you know,
certain manipulations,
you can play that game with certain
types of people and increase your,
your skillset at the game,
but you're never able to translate that
into everyday life,
uh,
where you know,
and so you start becoming addicted to
that game,
which is,
you know,
which are designed to increase your
dopamine without having to actually
achieve anything.
Well,
the thing about the games that's,
that's different,
like the video games,
what's different?
So again,
for a little kid has to be immediately
rewarding.
That's why rough and tumble play works,
for example,
has to be immediately rewarding.
And then the game shades into real life.
But as the game shades into real life,
what happens is the rewards are deferred
and you get more and more disciplined at
not being immediately rewarded.
Like when you're learning to read or
play the piano for the longterm goal.
The thing about video games is that they
do require the development of skill but
be there,
but the immediate reward is built in
along with the delayed reward because
otherwise the game wouldn't be fun for
someone who's learning.
And so the problem is is that a lot of
real life games aren't necessarily fun
while you're learning them because you
have to attain a certain level of
mastery and that requires discipline.
That's also what's wrong with the idea
that children can just learn in keeping
with what they're spontaneously
interested in.
It's like there's some truth in that
because why not file follow a child's
interests,
but the problem is,
is that many highly skilled endeavors,
virtually any endeavor that it's going
to be of economic or productive utility
requires a apprenticeship where there's
a lot of grinding.
There's a lot of just disciplinary
disciplined repetition.
And so,
okay,
well alright,
so,
and then one more dimension of that is
that as the boy gets to boy,
girl age,
if he's,
if he begins to sense that he's
heterosexual,
he noticed is that the girls are far
more interested in going out with the
quarterbacks.
So the student body presidents or the
performer type boys that are sort of
honored in the school system and in life
in general,
and so he begins to start withdrawing
and fearing that he can attract those
girls,
especially the ones he's most
biologically addicted to.
Beautiful ones that cheerleaders,
he starts withdrawing into porn and porn
is not a huge issue,
but the porn basically,
his stimulus is based on,
uh,
the dopamine increasing with each new
stimulus.
And so as,
as it gets addicted to that dopamine,
he begins to get addicted to only being
able to be stimulated when the risk
taking is higher and higher.
So finally,
he succeeds in one girl,
woman being able to come over to his
house and be sexual with her,
but he's so unable to be turned on just
by the mere maybe light touch of a hand,
um,
or turned on by just being fascinated by
what she's saying.
And the interaction or some combination
of the drama of being with her combined
with a little bit of touch is so used to
a huge amount of stimulus that occurs.
And when he gets to be trusting of her a
little bit,
she said,
he says,
can you be this way?
Can you do this?
Can you act this way?
And she feels like just some piece of
object that is being traded in for the
poor and eventually gets disgusted with
him,
withdraws and he begins to say,
you know,
all right,
this convinces me I him as worthless as
I thought I was,
and the only thing that will give me
satisfaction is back to the porn.
And what became a little bit of an
addiction becomes more of an addiction
even as he's also becoming
simultaneously frequently addicted to
video games at the same time.
And so all of this is that slippery
slope from the the rough housing that
the father is not able to articulate to
the mother about the value of that
combined with the trust that you were
integrating with.
That combined with the lack of post,
the bond,
a combined with the postpone
gratification being taught.
And then when the Postgrad postpone
gratification is not taught the slippery
slope down the hill to shame,
self disgust and fear that if that.
If he tries anything,
he's just going to prove to himself and
to everybody around him that he's one
more failure and the degree to which he
articulates that desire to try something
is the announcement publicly to a group
of people that he's pretty much going to
say today,
I'm going to try this and tomorrow it's
gonna be a failure until he,
until he becomes enormously shamed.
In worst case scenarios,
this can lead to such depression that it
creates a,
a desire to commit suicide and in the
very worst case scenarios.
It's a belief.
I believe we've seen the school shooter.
Yeah.
Well that bruise resentment.
Absolutely man.
That bruise resentment and anger like
nothing else
and and who they have resentment and
anger about who were the people that
have rejected him,
who were the classmates?
It's the teachers.
Nobody appreciates that sweet
sensitivity inside of him and sees him
well,
I am so angry at that and one day I just
want a.
I have a desperate need to get their
attention and say I count.
I matter.
Pay attention to me.
And you know,
at the worst case scenarios,
only a very small percentage,
but in worst case scenarios,
you can understand the school shooting,
shooting,
emerging from that.
Yeah.
Well for every,
for every kid who goes and shoots up a
school,
there's a thousand who were fantasizing
in a direction that's headed that way,
you know,
and not.
And some of that's at the beginning of
that,
it's something like,
while I'm very angry at people because
they don't see the value in me,
but if they get to the point where
they're doing something like fantasy,
extreme violence there are so far past
that even they think they've developed a
real hatred for everything.
And,
and,
uh,
wish to see it obliterated.
And,
and that's,
you know,
that's.
Well obviously that's the most terrible,
terrible outcomes that might be
generated.
Okay.
So you talked about,
you talked about rough and tumble play
and delay of gratification.
You tied empathy into that.
What are their other cardinal things
that you're seeing fathers do?
Because that's pretty early on in life,
right?
So you're looking at the interaction
with kids there between say a year old
and five,
six years old,
seven years old,
something like that.
Um,
what do you,
what else do you see happening with
fathers both out the early stages and
then also later on?
Yes.
Another important thing is,
is the concept of hangout time now for,
for a mom listening to this who has a
daughter,
uh,
we now know that children who have
daughters who have a significant amount
of hangout time with,
with,
with your dad's,
that creates more psychological
centerdness than any other single
phenomenon with,
uh,
with boys.
It's also very important.
So for example,
um,
let's say you're in a divorce situation
and a father has the child for a short
period of time,
let's say on a Saturday.
And he picks his child up from a soccer
game and says to,
let's say Josh,
Josh,
how did the game go?
The and the kid is more,
especially if more likely to say,
okay,
it was okay,
well tell me more josh.
It was just okay dad.
And so,
but if he can.
So if at that time the dad has to drop
the boys off to the moms because it's
the end of visitation time,
there's nothing that happens beyond that
is going to be,
you know,
people,
kids in particular,
I think although it also happens with
couples is that,
you know,
one of the things that you do to the
person that you're with to task if they
care,
is to be somewhat withholding of
information that might be relevant to
see to what degree you will be pursued.
Because,
you know,
if you asked me whether I've done
something,
how it went,
one of the things I'm going to want to
know is do you really care?
And if you're my father,
I'm really gonna want to know that?
And so one of the ways I can I can gauge
that is by asking you,
but that that's,
that assumes that your answer is going
to be reflective of your actual being.
And there's no reason to assume that a
better way of doing it is for me to be a
little bit withholding and a little bit
resistant because then I can see,
you know,
are you going to poke me a bit?
Because that's a fun thing to do.
If you're Kinda Tz you can say,
look kid,
you know,
poke him in the chest a few times.
It's like loosen up and talk to me,
you know?
And usually if you do that with a kid or
even an adolescent,
they'll laugh and kind of push your hand
away and go dad.
But they're happy to have that
additional product,
right?
To bring them out of their shell.
And it's a demonstration that the kid
actually cares.
And you do need time for that.
So.
So you see the kid,
if he's done well or she's doing well,
I'm very happy to say,
Oh,
I scored three goals today.
That's more than it's ever been scored
in the history of our school.
Is that incredible?
No problem.
They'll share that right away.
But the reason for the hesitation on
saying something that they're ashamed
of,
like I remember one father was saying
that the boy came home and he had been
the goalie the week before,
but the following week he was not chosen
to be goalie and he couldn't understand
why.
And so he hesitates to say something for
his dad because he doesn't want the data
to sort of either lecturing him or
disapprove of him or be disappointed in
him and,
or be,
um,
you know,
sort of like feel like that's not my
son,
you know,
I want my son to have scored the goals.
Um,
so with all those fears,
the child,
especially the boy when it comes to
performance,
will keep any failure to perform
effectively to himself.
But now if,
if the dad drops the child off at mom's,
that never gets sorted through.
If the dad has hanging out time with the
children,
let's say they're doing homework
together and dad maybe is watching the
TV and the kid is doing homework and
then they appear about the same time
getting something from the refrigerator
and they have a little discussion about
what he wants for dinner and they and
the data asks him to help make dinner
with them rather than just sit and do
take no responsibility,
which does tend to do so.
They asked the children to be helpful
with the dinner making and preparing,
not just serve them and so in that
process of the child chopping up stuff
and doing that type of boring the thing,
the child will tend to say,
you know,
dad,
I was goalie last week but I wasn't
going this week.
What's that about?
And the data will and what the FA and
the child might say that to the mom even
more quickly,
but the child's expectations with the
mom is the mom will give the child
assurance the end and say,
sweetie,
it's no problem.
You're fine.
You're wonderful.
You're a very good goal.
Maybe the coach wanted to give the
other,
the other kids a chance because you're
so good,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Whereas expect from data bit more
confrontational questioning.
Okay.
Well,
one of the things I've noticed in
talking to my clinical clients about
their intimate relationships is I've
been trying to gauge rules of thumb for
minimal necessary interaction,
time to maintain a relationship.
And with couples I've observed that they
need like one or two sessions of
intimate time together a week at
minimum,
something like that or things start to
go south,
but they also need,
as far as I've been able to tell about
90 minutes of communication time across
a single week.
Just keep each other updated in
relationship to their stories.
And so,
two questions.
One is,
do you have some sense of how you would
characterize hangout time and how much
of it there is,
how much of it there needs to be in
order to not go below,
you know,
a dangerous minimum.
And then the other thing I'd like to
pick up on is you had talked a little
bit about,
um,
the more confrontational approach that a
father might take when discussing a
failure or an inadequacy or something
like that on the part of the child.
And so I wanted to relate something that
I've learned about talking to majority
male audiences in the last year and a
half,
two years about responsibility and
discipline and all of that.
See,
you might think that calling someone on
their failure is harsh and judgmental,
but,
and it is in a sense,
but it's not harsh and judgmental about
their potential,
you know.
So if your kid comes to you and says,
you know,
I screwed up and here's what I did,
and it did go so well,
and you say,
that's okay,
you're a wonderful kid.
Then the kid stuck in a bind because
they're not feeling so wonderful and
they failed.
But if you say,
well look,
you know,
you're,
that was stupid.
Like,
what the Hell's wrong with you?
Here's what you could do.
Like,
you're better than that man.
Get it together a little bit.
Let's come up with some strategies so
that you can figure out how that's never
going to happen to you again,
and so instead of putting your faith in
who the child is right now,
which I would say in some senses,
the heart is the hallmark of impulsive
empathy.
You put your faith in who the child
could be and that's encouragement and I
would say in,
in circumstances of failure,
especially where the child is motivated
to try again,
encouragement,
beats,
it beats impulsive,
empathy,
hands down as a mark of faith and who
the child might be.
Yes.
And it takes a while for the child to
both reveal its vulnerability and also
to have a faith that the,
that the parent,
um,
that,
that the child tends to open up like a
flower to the,
to the degrader she went when she or he
realizes that the security that the
father is creating by being with them
and talking the problem through,
is there now an ideal setting,
a father who's wise or a mother who's
wise,
I will not give a solution right away,
what we'll ask the kid.
Something like,
um,
so what did you observe?
What's your best guess as to what
happened last week versus this week?
What do you think was the judges?
It was the coaches best intent,
um,
and let the.
And oftentimes inside of the child is a
willingness or is a sense of probably
what really did happen.
But a fear of acknowledging it to
himself or herself and especially
acknowledging it to anyone else because
the person who they might acknowledge it
to will not have respect for them.
And so being able to sort of have the
hangout time facilitates enough time to
feel both that large basket of those
large arms of security and nurturing
surrounding him or her,
uh,
the,
the fact that the father is not going to
give up on time,
uh,
with me,
we'll be here for me and I can.
And then when the father or the mother
facilitates the exploration inside of
himself about what the problem might be.
Let's say the help in,
in a Carl Rogers,
yeah,
Rogerian type of sense,
um,
uh,
to,
to find out the part of him that already
knows the answer.
Then the child is experiencing both
respect and a willingness to be
confronted by a.
If I don't have the answer inside of me,
my father will tell me the truth about
what I might be a need to do next.
And he'll have an that telling me the
truth about what he needs to do next is
his way of respecting me without even
paying.
He's respecting may because he wouldn't
be confronting me with the truth if he
didn't respect me.
Yeah.
And more specifically,
not even more specifically than me,
if he didn't respect my intrinsic
ability to overcome obstacles and to
grow,
right,
which is the best,
the best answer to someone who says I
have a problem,
is,
well,
I have faith that you can overcome that,
right?
Not that you don't have a problem or
that you're okay the way you are.
It's like,
yeah,
that's the problem man.
But you know,
and then you know,
there's another thing that you're
talking about that's very much in
keeping with,
I would say standard,
but relatively deep clinical wisdom,
which is that,
um,
people are much more likely to follow a
set of injunctions if they generate them
themselves.
And so we've had some really interesting
experiences with the program we
designed,
called the future authoring program.
And it helps people come up with a life
plan.
So they have to craft a vision for their
operations across the six or seven basic
dimensions of life,
like intimate relationships and family
and career ambitions and education and
resistance to temptation,
drugs and alcohol care of mental and
physical health.
And so on.
Those fundamental dimensions,
use of productive use of time outside of
work to ask themselves what they would
want if they could have what they wanted
to need along those domains,
three to five years down the road to
craft a vision based on that,
um,
on that array of wants and desires,
and also to write a counter vision which
is,
where could you be if you allowed
yourself to fail,
catastrophic,
where,
what might that look like in three to
five years and then to produce a plan.
And it's had remarkable effects.
Particular now young men are doing worse
than young women in academic
environments.
So the program doesn't seem to have as
much effect for young women,
but that might be because they're
already doing better,
but it has a walloping effect on young
men.
In fact,
for Vo in vocational junior college
settings,
our latest piece of data which was
generated was published last year,
showed that we could reduce dropout
among young men,
especially aimless ones who hadn't done
very well in high school.
We could drop their dropout rate 50
percent and so and,
and one of the things I've observed
about young men,
and this might be because they're more
disagreeable and confrontational than
young women,
is that unless they have formulated
their own plan,
they're unlikely to do something.
So when you're talking,
I think this is true with,
with,
with young women as well,
you want to talk to them and say,
well,
look what,
what do you think about what happened
and how you're going to get out of it?
Which is an excellent question because
it says to the child,
you can think about what happened and be
accurate and you can think of a way out
of it.
And that's the encouragement,
right?
And that's what you want is to,
you don't want to protect your shelter,
your child.
You want to encourage them.
And so that collaborative problem
solving is a great way to do that.
Absolutely.
Right.
And I've seen this over and over again
and certainly the data that I gathered
for the boy crisis very much,
um,
uh,
shows that as well.
And you said the hangout time is part of
what helps to do that,
but also the,
the,
the checks and balances of parenting is
so pivotal for mothers and fathers to
understand.
And right along the lines of what you're
talking about is,
is um,
so mother and father,
let's say,
have the child come home from school and
say m and S.
and the child says,
you know,
Mrs Meyers,
she hates me.
She hates me.
I,
I can't,
I can't be okay in school.
And maybe the child's in second or third
grade and a mother is sort of reaction
will tend to be more likely to be
something like,
oh sweetie,
let me hear more.
And then when child complains more about
how much Mrs Meyers hates the child,
the mom will tend to come up with a
solution like,
let me talk,
wait till next week on Monday I'll talk
to,
I'll make an appointment with the
principal and we'll talk about seeing
whether you can get into a different
class than Mrs Meyers a dad will.
Dad's will tend to say to a greater
degree,
um,
sweetie,
in life,
you have to learn to get along with
people who can't get along with you.
Um,
what do you think is making Mrs Meyers
upset about you and the child may or may
not be revealing.
And so the child will say,
well,
you know,
um,
do you want me to talk to Mrs Meyers
about it?
well if I talked with Mrs Meyers about
it,
you know,
what do you think Mrs Meyers would say,
and then the child under the threat of
possibly the dad talking or the mom
talking with Mrs Meyers will begin to
say what a little bit of what Mrs Meyers
fields and then,
um,
and then negotiate a,
a,
an opportunity to talk to Mrs Meyers and
then bring this as Myers and the child
together have a discussion together.
And so to see whether the child did Mrs
Meyers can work out and understanding
where the child begins to understand.
No,
it is not the Mrs Meyers inherently and
hates,
hates Jimmy.
It is that there's something else going
on here.
And so the result of working all that
through,
um,
is a way of facilitating the child to
discover,
um,
it's almost solutions to a problem
talking rather than getting a solution
rather than being enabled by the,
by the system to,
and by the parent who will eventually
disappear from the child's life or worse
yet not disappeared from the child's
life.
And uh,
and so,
and so these,
um,
these are,
but oftentimes the mom says,
you know,
the child is having a problem here.
Uh,
why are you being so insensitive?
What are you blaming,
you know,
Jimmy,
for,
for creating this problem.
Um,
he's,
he's telling you that not only does this
is Myers hate him,
but he also,
she had other kids hate Mrs Meyers as
well,
and so it's not Jimmy's fault that I
use.
And so the mom will feel dad as being
insensitive.
What in fact dad is being differently
sensitive.
Um,
and,
and sort of longterm postpone
gratification sensitive.
Yeah.
Well that's,
that's the thing.
And not that's a lot colder,
a virtue,
you know,
because it also sounds very much like
it's grounded in these psychobiological,
at least partially cycle biological
differences between men and women.
So women are higher in negative emotion
and the more empathic and that's that
short term empathy.
And so that's perfectly in keeping with
the approach that you just described and
the advantage.
See,
that's a particularly advantageous
approach to very,
very young children,
especially infants,
because to be wired properly,
to take care of infants,
the infant is always right.
Hey,
up until about nine months of age or
maybe a year of age,
the right response to your infant,
if that person is crying,
is there's something you should do about
it as fast as possible.
We've talked a fair bit about what
fathers can do to,
to help their children learn to delay
gratification and so on.
We've talked a little bit about what
might,
what mothers can understand about how to
facilitate that and how to trust it.
Um,
maybe we could talk a little bit about
what families might do in order to
improve the,
improve the performance of their boys.
And their girls,
you talked a little bit in your book
about a family dinner nights and their
importance.
Yes,
the most important.
We,
we already know that family dinner
nights are important,
but what makes family dinner nights even
more valuable is when they don't become
family dinner,
nightmares and knowing how to structure
them so that they don't become family.
Dinner Nightmares.
Uh,
when somebody comes up to me after a
presentation and says,
know I can't get my children to give up
electronics at dinner.
I already know the beginning of the
problem.
That is that the children are in charge
of the parents.
Um,
and well,
what can I do to encourage my children
to get involved with,
you know,
to,
to leave the,
the,
um,
the behind.
And,
you know,
number one answer is to require them to
get what is not an option to sit down at
dinner.
But maybe some nights you'll want it to
be,
some nights not.
But if you're having a family dinner
night,
especially structured family dinner
the number one rule is no electronics at
dinner.
If that rule is violated,
then the electronics are taken away for
a reasonable period of time and to take
it away right away for a reasonable
period of time.
Once the rule is understood,
right,
and you could imagine that instigating
wars in various households.
Yes,
exactly.
And so,
um,
and then you begin to structure that
family dinner nights so that everyone
has an opportunity to talk and everyone
has at the beginning I'm a structured
amount of time that they can check in,
just say how their week went or how that
week was going since the last time.
So everyone knows that it's not 40
minutes for so and so.
And one minute for me,
the interest in family dinner night be
zero for the one that's one minute.
Well,
that's an extension of the idea of a
fair game too.
And a refereed fair game.
Everyone has that.
As a family,
our job is to make sure everyone's needs
are being handled,
thought of,
and cared about,
which is the way empathy is created.
Empathy is not created by a parent who's
always empathetic with files,
needs or desires.
When a parent is always empathetic with
each child's needs and desires,
the child becomes narcissistic,
not apathetic,
and that's one of the things that we
have made a mistake with.
You could say that three or four times
in a row I think,
and that would be really good,
right?
Because that's so crucially important
because you know if,
if what you're learning is to put other
people's feelings at the same level of
importance as your own,
then obviously that's associated very
tightly with delay of gratification with
learning how to listen with turn taking
with fair play with a,
with a refereed interaction,
all of that and so,
so the other.
The other thing that happens too and you
see this with couples,
is that if they have that time together,
something analogous to family dinner
night.
Although I think the family dinner ideas
are really good.
One for reasons I'll mention here in a
moment is that what you're doing.
Imagine your family has a story and the
story is where we came from,
where we are and where we're going
together as a unit and then so and then
each of the individuals within that
story has a story and then what you're
doing in those family dinners.
That interaction time is you're taking
the individual threads of the individual
story threads and you're weaving them
together to make the collective story
and that keeps everyone up to date and
on the same page and and able to unable
to empathize and also a deep manner.
Because if I don't know where you are,
what you're up to,
I can't figure out what you're thinking
or feeling.
And so I have to know what story you're
acting out right now and so to you.
And in order for you to know that.
For me to know it.
You have to be able to tell your story
and I have to be able to ask you
questions about it.
And then I think the other thing that's
really important about the shared meal
is that,
you know,
human beings are really weird creatures
because we seriously share food and
we're social eaters.
People don't eat well if they eat on
their own.
And so it's deeply rooted into us that
idea of sharing food.
And so part of the extended process of
socialization is to get everybody to sit
down around food,
to be polite and thankful for the fact
of the food,
to enjoy that,
but then also too,
to be able to give and take well that's
being shared.
And that's,
I would say if the most fundamental
element of socialization is something
like the embodiment of rough and tumble
play,
the next layer on top of that would be
the ability to sit down and share food
and have a civilized and have civilized
discourse.
So literally,
and that civilized discourse really
needs to have the respect for story is
so,
so pivotal.
So I teach,
as you probably know,
a couple of communication courses around
the country and one of the,
one of the dimensions of the single most
important,
um,
thing that kills marriages are almost
all relationships are biologically
oriented,
inability to handle personal criticism
without becoming defensive.
Uh,
so my first job is to teach couples how
to get around that biological propensity
to become defensive when they hear
criticism,
one of the many steps in that process,
which is much too long to go into now,
but to give them a picture of,
of a picture of a person,
happens to be Mario Cuomo,
the former governor of New York.
That was the,
that was done by four artists,
have a picture that was taken at the
exact same time,
same place,
et cetera.
And there are four different types of
artists that paint a picture of him like
Andy Warhol and Modigliani and so on.
And so the end work with every couple
of.
To understand that when you hear your
partner's story,
you will owe,
even though you're all looking at the
same thing,
there will be a different picture that
is being.
That is being created by each person at
the table.
And so the job of couples is to
understand how much of a sacrifice each
person would make so that the other
person would live and yet how we're
often not able to handle personal
criticism and to sort of reorient
ourselves before we handle personal
criticism,
to move ourselves into a place of really
being fascinated by our partner story,
but at a fail,
but at a family dinner table,
um,
that has to happen with every single
member of the family that,
that when I say,
why,
what,
when person a says let some things,
what would,
what were you talking about in school?
And somebody says,
well,
we're talking about the me too movement.
And person a says,
oh,
the me too.
Movement is stupid.
So person besides the me too.
Movement is the best,
most progressive thing that's ever
happened.
Um,
and so it is,
it is very important that the person who
says it's the best thing that ever
happened is listened to fully by the
person who is a who believes is stupid
and vice versa.
And that there is no,
there is that there is facilitative
questions that the family trains people
to ask.
Now this is
right.
So part of it is know the story before
you offer criticism.
No,
Carl,
Carl Rogers had good advice about that a
and,
and you probably already know this,
but it's worth reiterating for people
who don't.
So Roger's rule was when you're
listening to someone,
then first of all,
don't assume that either you or they
know what they're talking about or what
they're going to say because people
think people think by talking,
so you've got to give them a chance to
get it all out before you jump on it
because they might change their own mind
in the mid,
in mid stream,
but so.
So that's important.
Let them formulate the problem before
you jump in with a criticism.
But then the next thing is,
and this I really love this,
I think it's really useful,
which is that once the person has laid
out their story,
you get to say,
this is what I heard you say.
Do you agree with my formulation?
Because that stops the list.
First of all,
it indicates to the speaker that the
listener actually listened,
or if if if there's an error,
then the speaker can say no,
that's not what I meant at all,
and then there can be some
clarification,
but it also forces the listener to not
turn the speaker into a straw man
because it isn't only that.
I have to summarize what you said.
I have to summarize what you said in a
way that you agree with and you know
that that's also a useful technique if
there happens to be some wide variation
in verbal ability among the participants
and there might be because of age,
for example.
And so you know,
because it might be that even if you're
a somewhat incoherent and stuttering and
impartial in your formulation.
If I'm an older sibling,
say I might be able to summarize it back
for you in a way that's actually helpful
to you from the perspective of a
cognitive scaffold.
And so,
yeah,
so,
so the thing you know,
we know that human beings organize their
personalities at the highest level
through narrative and that narrative is
not only thought it's spoken and so you
speak your personality into being in
these sorts of shared environments that
you're describing and without that your
story is fragmented and incoherent and
so were you.
And so you can see why those shared
social look,
if shared meals weren't so damn
important,
people wouldn't evolved the capacity to
engage in them.
Right?
I mean there are central to our social
life and to have that abandoned in a
family is really a catastrophe.
I think so
really is everything you said?
Absolutely.
Every part of it.
I so agree with you and we know when you
say did that historic something,
oftentimes someone will say,
I'm repeat what they heard.
They say and then the person you asked
to die distort anything and the person
says,
yes,
I think you just sort of this.
And then the other person will argue and
say,
no,
I said that.
And you know,
the rule of the game is the person who
is speaking whatever makes them feel
heard,
that's when you have a distorted
anything and it's your job,
it's your job to assist is like the
customer's always.
Right,
right.
But that doesn't mean you have to agree
with them.
It just means you have to have got the
damn story straight.
That's right.
And that's.
So that's also important.
Some people really do make the mistake
of thinking that if I get correct what
they,
that they had said that means I agree
with them.
No,
it doesn't mean it only means you've
heard them.
And then,
you know,
part of what a family dinner tonight is
about is having a chance to have
somebody,
if it's a personal criticism or be able
to respond to that and have the person
who,
um,
who is listening to what made the
criticism to begin with here that
response and ask if there's any
distortion on what they've heard to
begin with.
And the,
the,
the biggest challenge for people.
Almost everybody.
I remember I was interviewed once by NPR
and they said,
you know,
how can you,
some of the people who are allied with
the men's movement.
They are,
yeah,
they seem like hateful people.
And I said,
well,
if you're,
if you're calling yourself progressive
as opposed to a as we do,
because I consider myself more on the
liberal side of most things.
Um,
and then our first job is to listen.
When people feel heard,
they stopped painting and you know,
hating is,
comes from a buildup of not being seen,
not being heard,
being distorted,
being blamed or caricature in a negative
way before your,
before your heard it.
So that is the job of every,
you know,
every person that calls themselves
progressive is to start hearing rather
than arguing first.
Well then at least you can figure out
what to argue about because one of the
things that happens with,
with Kristalina communication in the
family when the stories are being
unfolded,
as you can identify what the problems
are and what they're not like.
If you,
you know,
you might be irritated at having to
listen to your spouse layout in the
stumbling and they're stumbling manner,
a particular problem,
but if you understand at the same time
that they might be dispensing of 98
problems and only focusing on two,
it's worth the wait.
So,
okay,
one other,
another question for you.
Um,
there are people who aren't in the
position where they can have male
involvement with their children,
let's say.
And so what,
what do you recommend,
if anything,
for single mothers who are trying to do
the best job they can with their kids
but are having a hard time pulling in
male attention,
what do you think they can manage for,
first of all,
acknowledge yourself for the enormous
amount of,
um,
faceted job.
You're either taking a second as you
look through the differences,
mothers and fathers to ask yourself
whether there's any way you have maybe
not valued your former husband in a way
that can,
um,
that would,
that would draw him into the fold.
But at the answer to those questions are
in no,
I have value at him and I still can't
draw him into the fold.
Essentially a deadbeat.
Sorry about that.
Um,
then here's some options.
The number one,
the,
the greatest amount of evidence is it
involving your children with cub scouts
is a very,
um,
has a very well developed program for
developing character,
motivation,
integrity,
loyalty,
um,
a sense of making promises that you
keep.
Um,
so very good.
Studies have been done,
have children involved in cub scouts for
two years or longer,
but this means not just getting your
child involved in cub scouts here or
there.
Um,
but,
and if your child doesn't like something
that's happened,
making sure your child gets back into
the fold and deals with what,
um,
know that it shouldn't be your child's
choice to go to cub scouts or not.
Go to cub scouts as part of your
parental responsibility to get him there
later to boy scouts.
Or it doesn't have to be cub scouts or
boy scouts.
Uh,
the y's.
Some y's have good,
good programs also for,
for young boys of mankind.
Project has good programs for young boys
now for the first time,
they have a real good help,
assistance to help boys with fathering.
Um,
the boys clubs have some good programs
with young boys.
Get Your,
get your child,
um,
that a male mentor try to get your child
to a school that has a significant
number of males in at the age that your
child is,
especially if your child is very young.
It's very important that a child not go
from a mom only home to female only
schools because the child will start
searching for an identity from somebody
that's usually destructive,
like a gang leader that will give a
false identity.
And so these are just some of many,
many things.
If you see it,
we often think that a child needs a male
mentor.
Yes,
a child does need a male mentor.
Try to vet the mentors carefully,
obviously,
um,
or you get your child to have faith if
you're at all involved in faith based
communities.
And even if you don't believe in God,
God or not,
not get your child involved in a faith
based community,
uh,
where there's a good male counselor,
um,
who has groups for children,
for young people,
oftentimes young people that are having
troubles,
um,
the,
the ability to be encouraged to express
your feelings to other males and see
that your son is not just having the,
is not isolated in the problems he's
facing.
Um,
but,
but there's many other boys his age that
are having the same problems.
Getting him to be able to express his
feelings about that,
his fears about that to see me,
to have a,
have a little experience has done where
he paints a mask for themselves and what
the mask says.
And then what,
what is really being said underneath the
mask.
A good fiscal male facilitator can be a
wonderful encourager of a boy to express
his feelings rather than repress his
feelings in a society that is as well.
And then we,
what we all have a need to do is to get
out there and say something very
damaging has happened in our society in
the last 50 years.
We've had what I started this work with
the government,
with the commission to create a White
House council on boys and men.
I started that after a call from the
White House to say asking if I wanted to
be an advisor to the White House Council
on women and girls because of my
background with the National
Organization for women.
And I said,
absolutely,
but there also needs to be a White House
council on boys and men.
Well,
for eight years we work to make that
happen and now we're working with the
trump administration to make that
happen.
And no one is getting on board yet.
But the importance of making that happen
is that there has to be entire change in
attitude and atmosphere,
that we are not just living in a
patriarchal world dominated by a
patriarchy.
That the world was dominated by a need
to survive.
Yeah,
right.
Absolutely.
Well,
there is a mother's both sacrificed so
much of their lives in the hope that
their children would have better lives.
Women made sacrifices of careers,
meant dads or dads made sacrifices in
their careers.
There are very few dads have multiple
children that that followed the glint in
their eye because you usually fulfilled
occupations that make you fulfilled,
um,
are not occupations that pay well.
So most of our fathers gave up
fulfillment in order to do the things
they needed to do,
like be a fire,
a fire fighter or a coal miner or being
willing to be disposable in war in order
to be able to make their generation
safer and have more options and to have
all the sacrifices that our fathers made
called male privilege or male dominance
or is such an underserving of men so
that,
that entire attitude,
it's also an underserving of women to
state that the entire cultural structure
to date has been patriarchal in origin.
That's right.
And you know,
you could argue what the definition of
Patriarchy is,
but just understand that your father and
grandfather and great grandfather all
all did the exact same thing as your
great grandmothers and so on.
Did they?
They gave their lives in the hope that
they're your life and their children's
lives would be better with greater
amounts of opportunities and most of
them sacrificed a great deal.
My father managed the company and my
mother was very unhappy and aiden had
his,
his company in Europe.
My mother was very unhappy living in
Europe rather than in the United States,
which was more comfortable for her.
So my father eventually gave up his job
and so fluid brushes from door to door
for a year in order to be able to make
sure we had enough money at least to go
to a state college.
And then my mother had a decent home
over ahead and so that the children.
And so
yeah,
well that's all associated with a little
bit of gratitude for the past.
It really is.
We should be,
instead of criticizing the world is
being patriarchal or as parents as being
stupid.
We should really be saying,
mom,
dad,
Grandpa,
grandma,
thank you for making our mastery of
survival enough so that we didn't have
to focus so much on survival,
but let us not misuse our opportunities
by blaming men for the world that they
created that was destructive.
Uh,
understand that we're living a 50
percent longer now than we were 120
years ago.
And,
um,
and that serves as a result of all the,
all the progress that you have made.
Um,
and so yeah,
this is why we're,
you know,
I worked so hard to create this White
House Council on boys and men and why
we've created a patriotic count to be
able to sort of make a begin to raise
some money to be able to make this
happen.
Whether it happens by the patriotic
count or some other way,
we need to have a total revisiting of
the belief of women.
Good men,
bad women are oppressed men oppressors.
And instead of the monologues of Hashtag
me too.
We need to have dialogues and said human
resource centers becoming a h,
e,
r rather than hr.
That is all focused on her,
not,
not him in her.
We really need to have dialogs at work
about what's working for women,
what's not working for women,
what's working for men and what's not
working for men and so we really need to
have a fundamental revisiting of um,
male,
female and um,
and all,
all of our gender roles in the past.
That's an excellent,
that's an excellent place to bring our
conversation to a close,
I would say,
look,
I'd really like to talk to you again
about probably about pay gap at some
point.
We really concentrated on,
on what you've been outlining in this
book and your new book and the boy
crisis and I would certainly recommend
people who are interested in this sort
of thing to go out and pick it up.
It's full of facts and that's kind of
Nice and it's concentrating on something
that's of crucial importance.
And I think maybe that people are
starting to recognize as crucial as of
crucial importance.
I certainly hope so and so your work has
been very useful to me and I appreciate
it very much.
The time that you spent today being able
to talk to me and I hope we get a chance
to talk again,
I would love to talk about the pay gap.
It's really impossible to believe that
there is not a patriarchal world if you
believe that men are in more money than
women do it for the same work.
And so one has to really start with that
fundamental understanding that it's
much,
much more complex than that.
Um,
and a very,
very different story than pretty much
anybody perceives.
Yes,
absolutely.
So will,
we will definitely schedule that in.
So.
Okay.
Well thank you very much.