[inaudible] [inaudible]
I haven't seen people since the last
time I was.
I was originally planning to speak to
you about responsibility.
I wanted to suggest that you should be
leery of trusting people whose primary
concern here's to be their own rights or
the rights of the hypothetically
oppressed groups that they
hypothetically could by no means
necessarily to speak for.
It's still want to do that.
It's better for young people to
concentrate on the responsibility rather
than the rights they've been cared for
all their lives,
but other people being as of yet unable
to give back to the world what it takes
to mature their survival.
It's not merely initiative obligation
either.
Young people,
not only young people need meaning in
their lives as well as do regard from
others.
Meaning is to be following in
responsibility.
People find meaning and the
responsibility of their careers,
their families,
their friends,
the chairman,
the work they do for others,
the education they pursued,
the voluntary obligations they undertake
and the suffering they endeavor to
reduce.
It's not the rights that are granted to
you by others so that you can be awarded
your rewards and privileges that will
make your limited and mortal life
worthwhile.
It is.
Instead,
the sacrifices you make to the highest
good that you can conceptualize and
strive to attain.
Beware the peddlers of rights and wish
to turn you into someone who is similar,
Tanium,
asleep,
privileged and victimized.
Why narcissistic,
noisy,
demanding,
chronically unhappy and of little use to
themselves or other people.
Instead,
sort yourselves out shoulder your
responsibilities,
make yourself useful to others.
Find the heaviest burden you can bear
and bear it stoically forthrightly and
admirably.
Having dealt with that,
I'll turn it to something that I believe
is more pressing.
You're all here because you're concerned
about the future.
I'm concerned about the future too
because of that concern.
I feel it necessary to say a few words,
which I'm still trying to formulate
properly about the newest form of
political pathology to manifest itself
in this.
Our district,
they confused in chaotic Western
society.
Truly.
However,
I should not say newest.
I should stay say in stamp the
resurgence of an exceptionally dangerous
logically and thoroughly discredited
older ideal one the dude entire
societies and huge populations to
unnecessary suffering and the bloody and
done fortunate and all too forgotten
from 20th century.
The idea equality,
the reasonable value placed among other
values,
but again the dog,
but he only made it to the highest place
and promoted blindly later with an
undertone,
undeserved,
nuorder,
Devon's resentment,
jealousy spike in hate.
It's not just equality and it's more of
Banal.
Next prestige is not merely equality of
opportunity.
To say that I don't talk about what
equity and quality of outcome,
the ultimate can rapid wolf in the most
caring,
the sheep's clothing.
It's line of equity is being raised as a
group and it's the very social justice
warriors,
the very postmodern,
neo Marxists activist activists whose
words I despise.
We're waiving it everywhere.
The danger,
this presents can barely be overstated.
It needs to be stopped.
When I spoke at mcmaster university last
year,
the profane chapters students under the
spell of the reprehensible professors,
ideological idiocy insisted
repetitively.
This is where we draw the line.
This is where we draw the line referring
to my hypothetical bigotry and uncaring
attitude towards the individuals they
reported to represent.
Today I want to draw a line of my own
and I encourage you to join me.
In doing so,
we have to bring the confused
historically ignorant and resentful
purveyors of the terrible doctrine of
equality,
of outcome to a halt.
We have to draw a line before the
functional structures that make up our
society,
our underminded damaged beyond repair.
So I'm going to talk to you today about
the great errors,
the self,
righteously caring attitude of the
equity purveyors hide within the
confines of their low resolution in
cautious elder,
rhythmic ideological propaganda.
I cannot present a complete argument,
but I can at least help like the
territory that must be mapped in more
detail and publicize broadly
for Dan takes hypothetically well
meaning people on the left had been
beating the drum for a society where
equality of opportunity is the norm by
large.
This is also a goal supported by people
in the political center and on the
right.
Society is better served in individuals,
better provided with the means of moving
forward forthrightly and with hope when
arbitrary impediments to the realization
of their abilities are eliminated to the
degree that is possible.
However,
even the elimination of inequities
related to opportunity is something that
must be attempted with all new carer.
The ability to raise children
thoughtfully and carefully and to
provide them with high quality
education,
social networks and the opportunity to
develop their own skills and interests
is not something equally distributed
among all parents.
It's beans that some children will be
provided with opportunities that others
will lack.
Governmental or other organizations may
attempt to provide redress for such
inequality,
but that's done at some risk.
A substantial proportion of what has
done positively for children and good
families occurs at such a young age.
The government intervention,
however well meaning would mean
invasion,
occupation and colonization of the sound
salmon to a degree like they do produce
negative consequences.
It's far outweigh whatever positive good
might be done.
A good rule is done.
It might be that nervous society,
you should strive to do whatever good to
be done for disadvantaged children and
their parents.
It does not civil tediously interfere
with or make more difficult.
The Goodman is already being done by
parents who are skilled and fortunate
enough to do the demanding job in an
admirable and socially productive
manner.
Substandard debate between those on the
left interested in broad scale social
interventions to improve life quality
for those who are less fortunate and
those on the right who wish to protect
and maintain the integrity and the
rights of the family must continue.
I'm cramming so that the dangers that
lurk on the unmoderated extremes can be
minimized.
We don't want to let any children suffer
unnecessarily.
We don't want the abilities and skills.
They might develop an offer to society
to be wasted,
but we don't want impersonal,
large scale systems suffering from the
pathologies of gigantism to interfere
with the function of the basic family
unit,
which despite me to this inadequacies
has yet to be replaced.
Even conceptually I anything remotely as
functional.
Okay.
The provision of universal secondary and
to a degree postsecondary education has
11th the planes deal substantially.
The safety net provided by universal
healthcare plays the same role as does
the offering of old age pension,
disability allowances,
unemployment insurance and welfare.
Although individuals across the
political spectrum continue to debate
the details of size and implementation
associated with such benefits of income
redistribution,
there is substantial agreement among all
regarding the essential utility.
It might be also noted that there are
conservative as well as liberal and left
wing arguments to be made in favor of
some flattening of income inequality.
The data indicating that serious crime
including most important they nail on
male homicide,
maybe driven to levels that threatened
social stability when inequality
increases beyond some hypothetical
optimum are solid and persuasive.
Thus there is a case to be made for
enhanced social stability through the
intelligent of at least opportunity and
perhaps I didn't come stuff as well as
the case that is made by more or less
bleeding individuals on behalf of
abstract fairness.
Nonetheless,
there are already questionable practices
associated with improvement of the
quality of opportunity,
of equality,
of opportunity that it be set in place.
In addition to those over you noted,
these include most particular the so
called affirmative action programs that
have become almost universally
instantiated into higher replaced within
promotion processes that characterize
most large,
large modern institutions in place
theoretically to provide redress for
historical inequalities.
Shows is the history of slavery that
characterize the American black
population some six generations ago.
Perhaps a case can be named for such
things as well,
although they are associated with clear
dangers.
The most egregious of these is the
insistence tied it.
Take me to the claims of those enamored
with postmodern identity politics that
certain group oriented aspects of human
identities such as race,
sex,
and now sexual proclivity of gender
identity are sufficiently real and
important.
So the judgment of people on the grounds
of the individual competence alone
should be suspended in favor of ill
defined.
Planes of social justice are the minor
and these include statements in job
postings indicating that applications
from individuals with certain specified
group level attributes are particularly
welcome.
What dangers are associated with such
practices?
Well,
the first is that specified particular
welcome on the part of some groups
clearly implies less welcome on the part
of others as the postmodern theorists
who push such things forward would be
first to point out such thinkers
constantly make the claim that value
structure is by necessity exclude and
should be flattened.
For that reason they don't extend the
same rationale to attempts to hire a
preferentially.
However,
because the Marxism that lurks behind
there hypothetically pure postmodern
reasoning justifies identification of
people by group identity and selection
on that basis because of its insistence
that the dialectic of oppressor and
oppressed characterized as all so called
power structures.
The second problem is that only a very
narrow subset of the wide range of
potential group identities and therefore
group paid qualities can possibly be
identified and rectified by such
practices privileging those alphabets of
group identity above all others.
Again,
using the hollowing terminology of the
postmodernists themselves means
instantiate those and those and only
those elements as vitally characteristic
of the individuals in question to
encourage or select on the basis of race
and sex.
And the other is sacred descriptors of
the modern anti individual left is
similar tediously to insist that those
are the categories upon which people
should be judged.
It doesn't take much in the way of
intelligence and insight to see how
easily this process can be reversed and
used in the opposite direction by those
on the radical right who might be
inclined to insist that ration sex are
precisely the relevant categories by
which people should be judged for the
very purposes of exclusion and
prejudicial discrimination.
Those on the left,
hypothetically oppose with sauce for the
goose is sauce for the Gander.
Such a reversal is making itself
currently manifest in the increasing
proclivity of those attacked,
for example,
for their quote white privilege and
quote to start insisting on their racial
identity as a primary hallmark and to
shift from guilt to overt claims of
supremacy.
What else could we get possibly expect?
Something very similar happened with the
black power and black is beautiful
movements in the late sixties and early
seventies the third problem is the
tendency for demands for equality of
opportunity to devolve evermore rapidly
in serious into demands for equity,
which has now become defined as
equality,
not opportunity,
but the outcome itself.
This is happening currently at a rate
that beggars belief give the absolute
catastrophes that social,
economic,
and political policies predicated on
equality of outcome have produced in the
past.
What does equity mean?
It's predicated on two ideas,
each more pernicious than the other.
The first is that all social
institutions must produce outcomes of
whatever sort that are precisely equal
across all possible group identities.
The second is that social institutions
that do not produce those equal outcomes
do not produce them because of
institutional racism,
sexism,
or other ism.
That is as well characteristic of the
explicit and implicit prejudices of
those individuals who make up the
institutions of questions.
Health.
There are a number of logical reasons
why sex demands cannot be net and
they're not desirable.
Even in principle.
Surrounding those logical reasons is a
plethora of historical data indicating
most recently in Venezuela that economic
policies predicated on the idea of a
radical equality are catastrophic.
Even genocidal.
We'll start with the logical reasons to
determine whether or not a given
institution is inequitable.
The institution is first stratified
according to the hypothetical privilege
and power get awards to different
individuals who occupied different
positions within it.
Then the demographic makeup of those
strata are analyzed along lines of
racial,
ethnic and gender identity as well as
sexual proclivity and contrast it with
the demographics that have obtain in the
general population surrounding the
institution.
Okay.
What is wrong with this
first
section?
Analysis are predicated on the idea that
institutions primarily the function to
distribute resources and reward.
That's only one of the many functions.
It's a hallmark of the kind of
ideologically rigid conceptualization,
the dry such assessments.
Then only one factor is ever considered.
This makes being right and being self
righteous above it,
a very straight forward manner,
radically and observing,
reducing the cognitive demands that a
truly comprehensive analysis would
require.
Complex,
hierarchical social organizations are
not simply your mechanisms for
distributing resources and rewards nor
are they in case it needs to be said
merely structures of power,
privilege and oppression.
They are in part of course both of these
until radica societies they be mostly
me.
Both of these,
my name is functional.
It's free societies
such as those that primarily
characterize the west.
Despite it's flaws,
they are also structures of
responsibility and production.
The evidence for this is overwhelming by
historical and current world standards.
People in the West will house and wealth
stay.
In fact,
we're more currently threatened Michael
obesity than by starvation with few
exceptions.
Everyone has indoor plumbing,
central heating,
access to education and connections to
the worldwide web,
which provides on an entirely rely on a
basis more information at lower cost and
this ever been available previously.
The fact that the West does this with
great efficiency comparatively speaking,
can be seen in the fact that immigrants
move virtually without exception from
the great balls of dysfunctional to
radica societies from all over the world
to the comparatively freedom productive
countries of Europe,
North America,
Australia and New Zealand.
And not the reverse.
[inaudible]
are complex social tools of production
make and do things and we'll report
bleed maybe and do things the people
want regardless of what might be
regarded as their consumers.
Triviality.
No centrally planned economy produces a
selection of shampoos or toothbrushes or
automatic and watch blinders were kite
surfing kinds of things or lightweight
bicycles or video games.
A hardy minded and judgmental social
justice advocate might dispute this.
Such a hyper productionist trivial,
but it's still very likely to spend
hours per day texting his or her friends
and desirable political cliches on
expensive I iphones and androids one
minutes.
Meat is another man's poison is by no
means clear.
Who should judge whether something that
someone else desires.
Maybe acceptably produced in a world
where absolute privation still exists.
Okay.
Because our hierarchical organizations
make new things that people want and
because the people differ in their
competence.
In doing so,
different people experience different
demand for their services.
We adjudicate such demand with pay.
This is the alternative to slavery.
If you are producing things that people
want,
then you are entitled to charge what
people are willing to pay for your
services or to refuse to provide such
services at your whim.
If you choose,
you get this privilege because what you
provide for other people as value and it
is therefore useful for other people to
encourage you to continue to provide it.
They don't have to buy your offering
either anymore than you have to produce
it.
Although that's not the very definition
of freedom is certainly constitutes an
important element of freedom.
Okay.
Because some people are more confident
making or doing those things,
they can demand a higher price for their
participation.
This is because of what they're
offering,
not because of what they intrinsically
deserve.
It may be the case that I'm early
elements of identity determined to some
degree the differential probability that
any given individual will come to occupy
a place for he or she can offer the
fruits of their labor.
But if there's also the case that their
skill at production is a major
contributor,
this is the demonstrated empirically
complex jobs,
administrative,
managerial,
nonacademic required,
high intelligence and high levels of the
big five personality trait
conscientiousness that most careful of
psychometric investigations into such
things have clearly demonstrated that a
combination of intelligence and
conscientiousness,
which can both be accurately measured
correlates at about 0.6 with longterm
life success in such occupations,
some of the remaining variation in
success can be attributed to random
factors such as health and even
counterproductive of fair systemic
prejudice alone with a fair degree of
measurement error as productivity and
success for notoriously hard to
quantify.
Now,
nonetheless,
correlations of that magnitude are
exceptionally rare in the social and
health sciences and they are not to be
easily and carelessly dismissed.
The same thing can be said with regards
to success and entrepreneurial and
creative endeavors,
which when complex also require
intelligence but demand big five traits,
openness,
which is a dimension indexing capacity
to produce novel ideas and perceptual
frames.
To the degree that traits obviously
logically lead to productive success
actually predict steps to success.
The systems in which success such
success manifests itself can be regarded
as examples of fair and reasonable
gauge.
It should also be pointed out that many
said games exist so that people who are
not conscientious or intelligent work
creative still have the chance to win it
popularity and say it desire for vision,
time in the formulation of close
interpersonal relationships are in the
provision of safety,
insecurity,
these other domains of potential
achievement or differentially valued by
people in accordance with their
intrinsic traits of personality.
This means that a person who was
primarily agreeable for example,
may well choose to maximize their
engagement in interpersonal
relationships out the cost of career or
entrepreneurial success,
and who is to say that's not a
reasonable trade off.
It is also the case that there are many
more elements of group identity that
must be reasonably considered if the
case could be made that the elements of
race and sex,
et Cetera,
must be considered.
People are differentially successful
because they are older.
Older people are wealthier.
Well,
why?
because they've had their whole life to
generate wealth.
Is that fair or unfair?
Should it be rectified or is it
reasonable?
There are younger.
They're better at sports.
If you're younger,
you're more likely to attract sexual
partners if you're younger.
Some things are better for men and some
things are better for women.
Some things are better for attractive
people.
Some things are better for people who
are up the majority race or religion or
tribe or language.
Some things are more accessible to
unattractive people,
so character acting,
for example,
falls into that category.
People have different interests.
People have different education.
People have different levels of mental
and physical health and people
differentially regulate their use of
drugs and alcohol.
Those are all dimensions upon which
people can be categorized by group and
there's no reason to privilege,
race,
sex,
sexual identity,
gender identity,
gender expression and um,
above these other dimensions of group
identity which are equally valuable,
which are equally valid and play into
who we important role.
People judge different outcomes as a
different worth,
love children's leisure,
power,
duty,
surface pleasure,
aesthetics,
novelty,
spirituality,
all of these factors and many more to
determine inequitable outcomes.
How then should people be properly
categorized to ensure equity?
Even a small set of entities can be
categorized in near infinite number of
ways.
Who's going to measure all these
differences?
Who's going to determine which of them
are important and which of a mark who's
going to measure the outcomes and some
of the up to complicate issues further,
who is going to determine whether they
are biologically instantiated,
socially constructed or mere choice?
Apparently like gender.
Are they mutable or fixed and
deterministic if they're immutable
merely as a matter of choice as
legislation in Canada.
Now,
incest is,
for example,
with regards to gender identity and
gender expression that should those
differences and also be regarded as
relevant determinants of an equity.
If people could make change their hope
categorization merely as a consequence
of an act of will,
why would you consider that a relevant
category to determine levels of
inequality?
Furthermore,
who's going to measure and determine the
rewards?
Are we going to insist that everyone
must be equally posture and outgoing,
equally assertive and enthusiastic,
equally private and introverted,
Carrington polite or demanding and
competitive,
industrious and orderly,
creative,
interested in ideas.
What are those outcomes?
Less important or less worthy of note,
that corporate position or economic
compensation,
are we going to swallow without
question?
The idea that career position in
monetary gain or the old be Jenkin
values that exist that should be
considered that are worthy of merit.
It's a very strange thing for those on
the radical left to insist that the very
criteria by which large corporations
judge the utility of individuals are
precisely those that should be used to
assess equality of outcomes,
fairness and diversity.
Let's say it again.
It isn't what you deserve for intrinsic
reasons that determines your outcome.
It's the word that others attributed to
your offerings.
Think of an offering on Ebay.
No sellers says,
I am Azur Bay Sham and my mother was had
mother has Alzheimer's and I'm not well
educated but I tall and strong,
although not very attractive and I was
bullied as a child but I'm quite
musical.
Although I only have one print and I'm
slightly overweight and prone to
anxiety,
so you have to pay the $50 for my
secondhand crock pot.
[inaudible]
they say,
instead I have this item and you don't
care who I am and I don't care who you
are except that I would describe it
honestly and ship it and you will pay
for it.
You can agree on a mutually beneficial
price that's trade.
The reward runs both ways.
Trade is not charity.
Trade is mutually beneficial.
Trade does not and cannot rectify
historical or biological injustices.
It can only hardly and momentarily
satisfying.
The people engaged in the particular
trade.
Attempts to redistribute through trade
tend to kick it back.
Look at that is the way people there
have now lost an average of 18 pounds.
Cuba can barely feed itself.
Everything is running down and barely
functional.
I think one of the most comical things
I've seen in recent years was the motor
convoy transferring Fidel Castro's
damned corpse to the,
to the,
uh,
to the cemetery breaking down in the
middle of the front
session.
Everything is run down in Belize,
functionable.
Why?
Because the problem of distribution is
so complex that it has to be outsourced
to the collective intelligence.
Knows person,
group of persons or imaginable
computational device can perform the
calculations of the price.
The measurements can even be made.
This is because of the price of anything
is dependent on the price of everything
else.
And to make it worse is always shifting
flawed as the free market system is.
We don't have anything better,
but let's say instead we transfer
determination of power,
status,
privilege and desire to a group of
people.
What group,
how do we regulate their biases and
correct for the rape?
It's how do we limit their power,
how do we protect ourselves against
their ideologies and hatred?
And entrance.
How do we discriminate the desire to
help the unfortunate from the wish to
destroying the weld constituted and
successful?
We don't and we can't and we won't,
but we'll have those basket political
maneuvering,
most convinced of their righteousness,
least aware of their ignorance and
limitations of knowledge.
And Sue,
most filled with resentment and hatred
will instantly rise to dominate such
positions.
And then all hell will break on it.
How do we know this?
Because it already happened and it
killed 100 million people.
And maybe I'm told the others destitute
and miserable,
and it just about destroyed the world.
We already ran this experiment and fail,
and then we ran it again and it fail.
And then we ran it again.
And then they fail.
And then we replicated the failure.
No one who was not eight,
your rent would dare to experiment
concepts,
things again,
unless they were malevolent.
So which it is,
which isn't youth purveyor as an equity.
You merchants of yesterday's poison.
Are you ignorant or 1100
[inaudible].