So the grades will be posted on
blackboard as soon as they're ready and
all open up the blackboard.
So you can see.
All right,
so onto the next round of clinicians.
We're going to focus mostly today on
Carl Rogers.
I'm going to start with some background.
Carl Rogers was a phenomenologist and so
it's useful to know what that means
because you hear people use words all
the time like,
well maybe not all the time,
probably not the grocery store usually
like phenomenology or existentialism,
postmodernism and structuralism and all
those things.
It's not.
It's frequently the case that
it isn't that easy to figure out what
they're talking about and sometimes
that's because they don't know,
you know,
because it's actually quite difficult to
make a reasonable conceptual distinction
between all those different modes of
thinking.
And phenomenology came out of philosophy
and its earliest advocate was a guy
named Edmund has several and it's most
famous proponent was probably heidegger
and a high degree.
Gotten lots of trouble because he ended
up supporting the Nazis at least to some
degree.
So that's pretty good reason to get in
trouble.
All things considered,
you know,
although,
most people did that for 30 some years
in Germany,
so not that that's any excuse.
Obviously
it's hard to exactly get your head
around what the phenomenologists are
talking about.
I was reading about David chalmers this
morning.
I don't know how many of you know about
David Chalmers,
but he's a philosopher who started the
Tucson conventions on consciousness and
chalmers.
I'm not sure what I think about
gentleman.
He's very charismatic and he's got away
with words and setting up those
convention center has done a great deal
for the study of consciousness.
But um,
sometimes I think that what he pointed
out to scientists was obvious.
It's funny,
you know,
when they're,
when psychology was primarily behaviors,
which was back in the fifties,
it came as a big shock to psychologists
when certain psychologist started to
talk about cognition.
They called that the cognitive
revolution.
And you know,
I think it was obvious to everybody but
psychologists at that point that people
thought.
And I think it was perhaps the same
situation with philosophers if it's
pretty obvious to everybody that
consciousness was a tough nut to crack,
but the philosophers kind of ignored it
and chalmers brought it back into the
academic.
Mainstream.
Phenomenologists are really all about
consciousness.
They just accepted as a fact
rather than trying to deny its existence
because it can't be easily reduced to
its material.
Substrate.
Chalmers big point was that he couldn't
understand why evolution couldn't have
produced creatures exactly like us who
have no conscious awareness that you
call them.
Zombies fundamentally said that the
existence of consciousness as an
enduring mystery.
Well,
I think that's true.
I don't not sure that we've got anywhere
in terms of figuring out exactly what
consciousness is,
despite a lot of time and effort put
into it and despite a lot of tremendous
amount of work done on the brain.
But anyways,
the phenomenologists are.
They just took it as a fact.
Now,
heidegger believe that western
philosophy had lost its way really since
the time of the Greeks and he thought
that phenomenal or that is primary field
of focus should be being itself,
not reality,
but being,
and it's not easy to understand what he
meant by it being,
but
the phenomenal field,
the idea of a phenomenal field somewhat
captures it so
for height of your reality was what you
experienced.
So he sort of you sort of tip the
tables.
Instead of presuming an objective world
and then deriving the subjective from
it.
He presumed that
the entirety of your experiences were
real
and that included your emotions and your
felt motivational states and your dreams
and your fantasies and even your
delusions.
Now,
that doesn't mean that people like
heidegger thought that all the elements
of lived reality belonged in the same
category.
So if you thought that
dreams and the reality that you've
shared with other people were
indistinguishable from one another,
you'd be just as pathological to a
phenomenologist as to anyone else.
But they were trying to get back to the
central mystery of life.
Which is that
there is something rather than nothing,
I suppose the that we experienced it
and that's the place where Roger Starts.
One of the presumptions of,
of the Rogerian is,
is that in order to help someone,
you have to put yourself in their shoes
fundamentally,
so you have to try to see the world from
their perspective
and that means adopting
the viewpoint.
It means adopting the reality that
manifests itself to them
so that you can develop an empathic
understanding,
body focused understanding of the person
that you're talking to.
So let's talk about Rogers for a minute.
He was a devout fundamentalist
Protestant and I think that's important
to know because a lot of his thinking
has a very strong Protestant flavor.
I mean the reason I concentrate on such
things and the philosophical background
at these things because you have to
understand the axioms of the thinker
that you're dealing with or you actually
don't understand them at all.
And when you're assessing the axiomatic
presuppositions of the paper,
you're usually outside the thinkers
thought in some sense,
right?
Because you're looking at axioms,
but you don't get it unless you.
Unless you know the axiom,
and so Carl Rogers thought was deeply
grounded in his protestantism,
but his,
his father in particular was a
scientific farmer and applied the
scientific method on the farm that he
grew up in,
and so rogers had a devout
fundamentalist background of the sort
that was more typical in the thirties
and the forties,
but he also had a powerful
understanding of the scientific method
and practical observations of its
utility.
So
He.
His first academic training was that the
Union theological seminary seminary in
the mission of of that seminary was to
evangelize the world in their
generation.
If I remember correctly,
it was when he was on a boat to China to
serve as a missionary that he first
started to question the absolute reality
of his,
of his Protestant beliefs.
It isn't that he abandoned them,
particularly.
Instead,
he incorporated them into a approach to
psychotherapy that fulfilled all the
preconditions for this.
There's this,
there's this striving towards a kind of
interpersonal perfection that goes along
with protestantism.
There's an idea that the most important
realization of the most fundamental
reality is to be had in direct and
honest communication between two people
and
two or more people.
That's a place where you might say,
if you're thinking about it
symbolically,
that the living word emerges and Roger's
thinking is deeply,
deeply rooted in in that kind of
conception,
and it's partly that he believed that if
you could integrate yourself properly,
if you could put yourself together in
some sense at every level of analysis,
then you'd be able to exist and
communicate in a way that was.
There's a eddie and flavor to this that
was optimally beneficial to you,
but also optimally beneficial to other
people at the same time and a lot of
that would emerge in your interactions
with each other in communication.
So here's something to think about.
This is a way of approaching what Rogers
was up to.
Imagine how you use words.
Now,
you could use words instrumentally,
but start with that.
If you imagined that you want something
from someone and then you might think,
well,
how can I phrase my argument so that I'm
going to get back from this person and
then you might think,
well,
what sort of argument would appeal to
that person and what buttons can I push
and how can I get what I want,
and then you're using words in an
instrumental way.
You're using them as tools to obtain
what you desire from other people.
Now,
I think if you do that completely,
you're a psychopath.
I mean that because a psychopath has no
room for you at all.
It's about him or her and you're there
to be used as an instrumental target.
Now,
I'm not saying that every time someone
uses language instrumentally,
they're acting like a psychopath,
but
that's the logical conclusion to that
form of language use.
Now,
then you might think,
well,
you can manage a little kids trying to
do that to their parents,
right?
Siblings will often collude.
We'll have a little conspiratorial
conversation about how to approach one
parent or the other.
Usually by isolating the parents.
That's a good strategy and then they'll
phrase their requests so that they can
extract out the desired benefit.
Um,
I follow these pickup artists online.
I'm very interested in their use of
psychology and they are instrumental
light would users,
right?
So their trick is they're developing a
whole little hope or of verbal tricks
that they use in attempts to seduce.
It's a very narrow focus and it's
instrumental language.
It says if the,
the personhood of the,
of the target is irrelevant
fundamentally.
So it's a fairly pathological.
It can become pathological,
very easy.
So then you might say,
well,
how would you use language if you
weren't using instrumental?
Because you know,
you have to have a career and you have
to be goal oriented,
you have to be aimed towards things.
And so since you have to be goal
oriented,
how can it be other than that,
you would use language instrumentally.
One of the Rogerian position would be
would be that
you should try to become aware of the
totality of your subjective experience
so that not only do you feel it in an
embodied sense,
but that you represented at a that you
represented and the representation would
be mostly in terms of articulation.
It isn't clear that Roger is considered
other forms of representation,
but
for Rogers,
the movement towards health is an
integrative process and it gets very
body focused,
but the outcome of that integrative
process which Rogers would say is the
ability to live the good life is that
your language is no longer instrumental.
What you're doing instead is attempting
to state the truth as you see it because
of course your truth as a partial truth.
Obviously the basket you can do is,
well,
I really think the best you can do is
not lie because you can't tell the truth
because you're too damn stupid,
right?
You don't know enough to tell the truth,
but you can certainly do your best to
represent what you know is clearly as
you possibly can in your communication
with other people.
And so rogers believed that it was the
moral responsibility of the therapist to
do that personally and then that to the
degree that that was being done in the
therapy and the therapy
relationship and the therapeutic
relationship,
that that in and of itself would be
healing.
And so basically Roger's theory is that
honest communication heels.
No,
you know,
that's quite an interesting theory.
No,
it's not.
It's not completely unaligned from
Freud's earlier claims,
right?
Because Freud
basically presumed that it was.
I didn't put so much of a moral element
on it.
He reviewed the person more as as being
trapped between titanic opposing forces,
the IED underneath and the superego on
top important illegals are crunched up
in the middle and as a consequence of
being pulled and product and crushed by
those titanic forces,
pathology was likely to emerge and he
talked about repression.
But for attendant,
if you repression as an unconscious
process for for Rogers,
the moral element of the therapeutic
process is much clearer,
I believe.
And most of the time when you listened
to Rogers or you read what he had to
say,
the injunctions that he's laying out or
moral injunction now,
it's quite interesting because you don't
necessarily of psychotherapy as a moral
endeavor and I really never thought
about it that way fully until I read.
I was reading were on trust at the same
time,
but you don't talk,
wait out.
The proposition in this book that most
of the problems,
many of the problems that people came to
see a therapist about,
we're actually moral problem since they
were moral problems of various sorts.
Now sometimes the person was in trouble
because they had done something
seriously,
seriously wrong.
You had one client,
if I remember correctly,
and he discovered,
that she had killed her children and she
did that when they were young.
She had them.
She let them become exposed to
tuberculosis.
I think it was.
She didn't take the proper precautions.
And the reason she did that was because
she wanted to marry someone and he
wasn't very interested in her children.
So you might consider that a moral
problem apparently.
Apparently it was weighing on her
conscience,
you know,
as might well now it's a strange thing
because in some sense what she did was
turn a blind eye to something she could
have prevented it in legal terms that's
known as willful blindness,
but she knew whatever that means.
Well,
there's lots of different levels of
knowing,
right?
You can know something in your body,
you can know something in your
imagination.
You can know something in articulated
form,
you know,
so the whole issue of knowing it's a
very complicated,
but rogers
definitely believed as far as I can
tell,
that
there was a moral dimension to life that
it was identifiable.
That in some sense it was linear,
that it had an observable process which
was the continual integration of
experienced within the phenomenal field,
the ironing out of contradictions within
the phenomenal field.
So you might think,
well,
what happens when you,
when you feel one way and you say
something else,
I mean,
you're all in,
you're all perfectly
familiar with that experience.
In fact,
my experience with people has been that,
and this is another issue with
instrumental use of language.
You know,
you say,
well,
what are you using your language for?
Well,
have to get what you want,
but that can be consciously manipulated,
but then maybe we'll say,
well that's what the psychopath is like,
except the psychopath is not only
consciously manipulative.
He's also unconsciously manipulative
because he's been practicing it for like
three decades,
so all the little machines in his head
header deceptive to and they run on
automatic so he'll just lie just to see
if he can pull one over on you because
that demonstrates that not only is he
smarter than you,
but that you deserve to be victimized
because you're such an idiot.
So.
But people use instrument language like
that.
Not only consciously to get what they
want,
but you know,
it's something that we definitely think
of is characteristic for example,
of teenagers.
Right.
I mean there isn't a teen movie that's
been made in the last 50 years.
I don't claim that it doesn't deal with
the negative consequences of using
instrumental language.
Right.
Basically the team has put in some
position where they're being polled hold
by maybe various social forces,
different friendship groups or,
or there's a
um,
but there was a
contractor
interrelationship between what their
friends and their parents want or what
their friends wanting their school wants
or what they want and their friends want
or what the school wants.
So all of these things are pulling and
pushing in different directions and the
directions are essentially in some,
in some sense the directions or moral
because they're all about what to do.
And the plot of the movie is how the
teenager,
it's usually a Rogerian plot.
It's usually about how the teenager
comes to more to fuller self
realization,
right?
And that they're able to,
that they're able to stave off the,
the temptations that are posed sometimes
by the authorities so they don't become
too obedient and sometimes by their
peers so that they don't become only a
reflection of peer pressure
question.
Absolutely peer pressure is up here if
your pressure is absolutely fab.
And so if you're using language to fit
in,
well that's also instrumental use of
language and for and for Rogers,
that would be one of the sources of
pathology.
Now
it's very much worth taking this
seriously.
So
here's an example that I thought about a
lot.
What do you do if you're at work and
someone tells you to do something that
you don't want to do.
And I don't mean that.
Forget,
assume you're disciplined,
you know,
assuming that you're not just lazy and
worthless and that's why you don't want
to do it.
And you want to ask yourself that first,
right?
Because maybe you're just being lazy and
worthless and you should pull yourself
together and do the thing you know.
So,
but failing that,
let's say that you're being asked to do
something that you're finding,
you're having a very difficult time to
get motivated to do so that'd be one
clue.
And that it's also making you uneasy.
So you're waking up in the middle of the
night and you're being anxious and it's
running through your mind.
And
what should you do?
Well,
it's your job.
Someone who's in the hierarchy above you
is telling you to do it.
Maybe you should just do it.
Well.
Then you might ask yourself,
well,
why can't you just go ahead and do it?
You know,
you might say,
well,
maybe it's quasi criminal and you're
afraid of getting caught,
but let's forget about that for a
minute.
Let's assume that the profitability,
maybe it's a low level moral
transgression,
it's not precisely illegal and even so
the probability that you're going to get
caught is very low.
Why would it bother you and should you
take that seriously?
Now Rogers would claim that the reason
it would bother you is because it would
make the structure of yourself system
inconsistent.
So
imagine you're trying to organize a
group of people to do some tasks.
You know,
like maybe they're in a row and you have
to fill in a hole in the road and so you
have to put people in a row and if you
hadn't drugs down the line,
you know,
if you got one person in there who's
trying to put rocks,
the rocks go the other way or dropping
them or something like that,
well then obviously the entire structure
is not going to function properly and
it's because there's an internal
inconsistency in 10,
you know,
it's a fundamental presupposition of,
of,
of logic.
It's maybe the most fundamental
principle of communication that a thing
can't be itself and something else at
the same time.
That's the principle of
noncontradiction.
Right?
And so the hypothesis here would be that
you have to follow the principle of
noncontradiction with regards to the
organization of your own self and the
self would be,
Roger's thinks about that as an art,
a differentiated field,
subfield of the phenomenal field.
Right?
So you're always experiencing things and
part of what you experience is the EU at
the center of that.
And that's the self as far as Roger's is
concerned.
And the proposition would be you have to
organize the self in a non contradictory
manner or well,
or what well,
or you feel negative emotion.
Now he would think about that as anxiety
general.
Yes.
The narrative around the test make it
work.
Well that might work.
You know,
I mean that's a very good and
complicated question because what you're
asking is,
well,
why wouldn't,
why can't be rationalized effectively.
That's really.
Well
the.
That's a postmodern theory I would say
in some sense because the postmodern
like to claim that there's nothing
outside of the text,
right?
And then things in some sense are
infinitely malleable and that the
malleability comes as a consequence of
the different narratives that you might
might weave.
But Rogers would point out that,
well,
the first thing that you pointed out is
that stupid,
which it is.
I mean there's all sorts of things that
are characteristics of your
characteristic,
of your experience that have a non pecs,
like phenomenology,
you know,
like I think it's very,
very difficult to claim that pain is,
is textual.
No.
And we do know that you can,
you can manipulate the way an organism
feels pain quite extensively.
So for example,
if you whack the dog on the nose with a
newspaper,
every time it goes to eat,
it will starve to death.
You can teach it not to eat very
rapidly.
And so what you're doing is you're
teaching the dog that hunger is
punishing and then it transforms Hungary
into anxiety and then it won't heat.
So the reason I'm telling you that is
because even something as fundamental as
hunger,
which you might think about as I'm a
basic phenomena,
can be modulated by learning.
But there are limits to that.
They're evident limits to that.
Now,
I think the problem with reading a
narrative is that even if it's complex
and sophisticated and so you've
convinced yourself,
that doesn't necessarily mean that the
actions and perceptions undertaken as a
consequence of that formulation are
going to be commensurate with the rest
of your personality.
It's a big risk,
you know,
so and I think it is the risk that
people run when they tell themselves or
act out a deep falsa now because for
Rogers,
you could also act out false hoods,
right?
In fact,
the philosophers call that a
performative contradiction.
That's when you say one thing and do
another.
It's a form of lie,
but it's an embodied line.
Rogers was,
he was a very.
He was very cognizant of embodiment as
a,
as a central human feature,
so you know,
he was very concerned about the fact
that the representational structures had
to take into account the realities of
the underlying biology and those.
So those would be felt states in a
sense.
So I think the Rogerian answers,
you can't get away with it that easily.
What that'll do is it'll produce
contradictions as you move forward and
those contradictions will will unsettle
you either in a minor way or in a deep
way.
Now,
as far as I can tell by Rogers,
never really formalized a theory about
why something is deep and why something
was shallow in terms of it's
misrepresentation,
but we've already talked about that.
If you think about the hierarchical
structure that I've showed you,
many times,
the idea there is that higher level of
the abstraction that you mess around
with the more of your personality you
pathologize said,
I've been thinking this week too,
that that hierarchy,
you know the one I showed you many
times,
I believe I have anyways,
little aids in rows.
I think that's the structure of the
unconscious actually,
so and you'll miss about without at your
peril because you're programming your
own perceptions and your actions and so
the Rogerian presupposition,
and this is why I'm talking about the
presuppositions that underlied his
thinking because the Rogerian approach
is based on a deep presupposition,
which is that honest integration
matters.
Now you could say,
well,
perhaps not.
It's like,
well,
that's the question that people have
been debating since the beginning of
time,
but my experience as a therapist,
just so you know,
I've never seen anyone get away with
anything.
I think every time you do something that
you know isn't right,
you're going to get all up for it.
Sooner or later.
Now you made me blinded yourself so
badly because of your ms apprehensions
and deceptions that you can't see the
causal connection between what you did
and the punishment.
In fact,
sometimes it takes years of
psychotherapeutic investigation to,
to lay out the causal narrative,
but why?
Why would anybody ever think they can
bend the structure of reality and get
away with it?
You know,
to me it's like,
you know those plastic rulers,
it's like you can hold one of those in
front of your nose and bended forward
and that's fine,
but as soon as you let go,
it's going to hit you in the face and so
you know,
then you're going to curse face faith
because you've got hit in the face,
but you bent the down ruler.
Yup.
Economic incentive as far as like you
need to survive in order to have a life
and your view raped,
like having your economic needs as being
higher than dealing with this unsettled
have been in the scenario because that's
like being at work and fulfilling the
needs of the task has been assigned to
you by your superior than you still
have.
You still get to survive so you can take
easily to have a roof over your head,
but you just have to sort of deal with
the consequences of this slight subtle.
Well,
I mean,
no,
I would say sometimes people are put
into positions that unsettled them and
they don't know what to do.
You know,
they're kind of,
they're screwed if they do this and
they're screwed if they do that and
that's all they can see to do and people
get put in those situations all the
time.
But,
and I,
I'm not really going to talk about those
except that people really suffer for
that.
Um,
partly what Rogers is talking about is a
form of optimal organization,
right?
So it's to be considered as the final
goal in some sense.
It's what you're working towards.
I think it's very difficult to live in a
way that you,
so that you never encountered
contradictions as you move forward.
In fact,
that's precisely what does happen as you
move forward and it's up to you on the
fly to Oregon to organize your response
to those contradictions in a manner that
doesn't destabilize the entire
structure.
But you know,
the entire structure is a strange thing
because again,
Rogers Rogers has gotten a
psychoanalytic.
Well,
it's not exactly right.
It's complicated
the hierarchy that Roger's describes his
characteristic of the self.
This is something he doesn't discuss
that much.
The hierarchy that you make of yourself
as not independent of the way that you
fit into hierarchies in the world.
So really by hierarchically reorganizing
yourself the same time you're
hierarchically organizing the world.
And so part of the problem is,
is that if you destabilize yourself or
if you come up with a sub optimal
solution,
there's a,
there's a twist there that's going to,
it's going to follow you up.
Now it may be the best that you've got.
Sometimes that happens,
you know,
I'm not saying that you can always solve
a problem in an optimal manner,
you know?
Do you remember the movie Sophie's
choice?
Did you ever see that movie?
Um,
Sophie,
it's a movie about that,
about Germany during the Nazi period,
she had to choose which of her two
children was going to be shocked.
Well,
you know,
it's pretty hard to come up with an
optimal
solution to that problem.
Right?
So
Roger's though didn't really think that
that actual problems in life constituted
psychopathology.
That's sort of more the existentialist.
Although he had an existential twist.
He was thinking more that what
constituted psychopathology per se
instead of just plain ordinary suffering
was the contradictions that arose
because people fail to use their
potential for articulation in a manner
that continually fostered their
integration.
So he would say,
well,
to the degree that you were going to use
instrumental language,
it's not a term he used,
but it's a good summary of,
of his philosophy that you were bringing
to bear on yourself unless and others
around you.
Unnecessary pain and suffering,
and that was psychopathological.
It's psychopathological because it's
unnecessary because in principle it
could be avoided.
So.
So that's the idea.
And so the idea as well as the
organizing principle that brings you
into this optimally functioning
hierarchy is your commitment to truth,
to accurately represent what it is that
you experience.
And that's again,
you know how Piaget talked about the
fundamental truth as a process rather
than as a state or a fact it's the case
for Rogerian phenomenon phenomenology as
well,
and you could kind of understand that
because of course therapists are dealing
with people,
living people and life is a process,
not a state.
And so rogers was concentrating very
much on the process which he regarded as
absolutely crucial and believe that the
process,
the process properly implemented would
bring about the best possible
organization and then we'll update that
organization as necessary to.
So it's a radical idea.
But I would also say that it's
fundamentally rooted in his Protestant
Christianity because one of the tenants
of Christianity is that the word orders
chaos.
And so that idea was lurking at the
bottom of Roger's conceptual structure
and you know,
he was intelligent enough to articulate
it fully in a modern way.
But that's still where it came from.
Now it's an older idea of Christianity.
So
now Roger is also believed some other
things in there.
And this is where I think he gets a
little bit optimistic,
but,
but he's no fool.
So Rogers is one of those optimists you
really have to contend with.
Now he believed,
and I think this is a classical
Protestant belief,
is as well that what evil was was
basically the absence of good and that
people had a strong in intrinsic impulse
towards the good that you could help
them realize and the way you help them
realize.
That was by setting the preconditions
for the emergence of that good,
and he believed that the preconditions
were
the provision of a space for
communication.
We're.
There was no judgment in the sense of
rejection.
And so here's the Rogerian theory with
regards to therapeutic endeavor.
Now the first thing is,
and this seems critical and I think
Rogers was right about this,
that a client has to want to change,
and this is.
This is a funny thing about therapy
because my observation has been that
it's not something you can impose on
people unless they've decided that
things could be better and that
alterations in,
in,
in something they're doing might make it
better.
It's a nonstarter.
And so I've had clients who were court
ordered to attend therapy and that's
just complete waste of time,
especially if they're more on the
psychopathic end of things because
you're just,
if they don't want to change,
they're not going to learn.
And this is actually another Rogerian
principle because Roger's had an
educational philosophy as well and the
educational philosophy was students will
not learn things that are not relevant
to them.
And so one of the teachers duties was to
make the material at hand relevant
because that would
help the students remember it.
Why remembered if it's not relevant to.
One of the things I tried to do in my
lectures,
I try to tell people when I'm lecturing,
why they should know this.
And the fundamental answer always,
if you push it down far enough,
is that if you know this,
your life will go better.
And so will the life of people around
you.
So you should listen because then
there's some things that are sharp and
pointy that you will run into while
you're wandering around in the fog.
So and,
and that's the fundamental issue.
It's,
it's necessary to know these things and
so if you're dealing with someone who
hasn't decided that there's something
wrong and that they have something to do
about it,
then maybe they could change and that
would make things better.
You're not going anywhere,
and Rogers would also say that's
actually a precondition for a
relationship period because he didn't
really make much of a distinction
between a therapeutic relationship and a
genuine relationship because he thought
the genuine relationships with
therapeutic and so one of the principles
that you can extract from that is that
if you're in a relationship,
one useful proposition is that,
well,
you're pretty perfect,
but you're probably not quite as perfect
as you could be.
And so it's possible that your partner,
no matter how deeply flawed they are,
might now and then have something to say
to you that would,
if you incorporated,
would bring you to an even higher state
of perfection.
Right?
And so that's,
that means you have to listen and it's
worse than that.
And this again is a Rogerian
observation.
You might have to help them criticize
you because maybe they're not very good
at it.
You know,
and so there's something they're trying
to tell you and they're stumbling way
and it's,
it's an actual thing,
but they can't articulate it and so it
would be easy for you just to,
especially if you're trying to use
language instrumentally and to get away
with it just to,
while you could even make fun of the way
they're poorly articulating the problem,
that's a really good one because then
you can convince them not to do such
things in the future.
But if you take the other stance,
which is,
well,
I've got some things to learn and you've
got some things to learn and you've got
some things to teach me and I've got
some things to teach you and God only
knows when that's gonna happen,
but it might happen.
So the object of the conversation is for
each person to help the other person
make their point.
You know?
And that's a lot different than winning
the argument.
And I can tell you one thing,
you will not win an argument with any
intimate partner ever because you're not
playing the game of the argument.
You're playing the game of iterated
arguments across time and so if you win
an argument,
you just set up another one winning and
solving the problem or the same thing,
so from a Rogerian perspective,
winning would be the maintenance of your
current self structure at the cost of
failure to integrate some disintegrated
element of the phenomenological realm.
Maybe it'd be the unhappiness of your
partner.
That might be one of them.
Now you can.
If you win the argument,
that's the rationalization issue.
Fundamentally you don't have to change,
but the fact is you do have to change
because the way you are is giving rise
to this situation and that's not going
to change unless you fix it.
So winning an argument,
fixing something,
those are completely different things.
You fixed the thing,
it goes away and often you know,
couples have to have conflict because
there's no difference between conflict
and thinking.
Thinking is a form of war.
It's just that you,
you,
you make it an interior form of war,
right?
You can't have a without conflict
because life is different.
Difficult and people differ from one
another.
So they have different value structures
and so you can't just ignore that you
have to set up a dialogue because it's
not necessarily obvious who's right.
Of course,
Rogers believed that in the therapeutic
realm too.
So he thought if therapy as something
that emerged as a consequence of the
adoption of certain axiomatic
presuppositions and those were
things could be better than they are and
you could make them that way and that's
also true for me.
And then the next presumption is,
well maybe we can figure out how to do
that in a collaborative with
collaborative communication.
So Rogers believed that the therapist
was just as transformed during the
therapeutic process as the person.
In fact,
if that wasn't happening then whatever
was happening wasn't the kind of healing
therapy that Rogers would like to have
happen.
And he also said that,
I'll read you something he said later,
but he also pointed out quite strongly
that that's why people don't really like
to listen.
You know,
like maybe there's some flaw in your
cell structure at some fundamental
level,
fundamentally axiomatic level,
you know,
maybe you're narcissistic.
That'd be a good one.
And you know,
if you listen to people,
they're going to tell you you're
narcissistic.
Well you don't want to find that out
because it's going to blow a huge hole
and you're gonna blow blow a huge hole
in yourself.
Structure that's not very fun.
But
hypothetically,
that beats running into the obstacles
that you will run into if you're
narcissistic repeatedly as you move
forward through life.
So you can either live with your flaws
are correct.
That's the.
And then the,
the,
the pathway to correction is dialogue,
communication.
So
now the next part of the Rogerian
therapeutic frappe yes,
yes.
What's the difference between a genuine
criticism genuinely giving her
perspective or just arguing point?
Well,
that's a good question.
Let's see if we can,
let's see if we can formulate that.
So the first difference might be,
well,
what's,
what's the outcome we're looking for?
Like let's think about that.
Let's think about that in the context of
a,
of an intimate relationship,
a familial relationship.
So you have a wife,
let's say,
and you've got some kids this one,
or what are your options?
What do you want?
Hopefully better.
Okay.
So that's one thing we're so that we're
trying to establish the domain of the
earth.
We're gonna we're going to try and make
things better.
What would better look like?
You think
of any negative emotion?
Feeling.
Okay.
So.
So there's something.
Okay.
So that's a rough area.
Presupposition.
Is that part of what you're doing when
you're making things better is to
decrease the probability that negative
emotion will arise short term or long
term?
Short term.
First.
That's what bothered me.
Oh,
okay.
So that's an interesting thing because
what if you have to experience a
tremendous amount of short term pain in
order to make long term progress.
If it's different from the pain that
initially got me thinking about it,
that seems like an improvement
potentially.
Okay.
Well
I'm going to address your question
completely from the admin perspective,
but that's okay because it works for
Rogers as well.
It's just easier to explain
freedom from unnecessary suffering
in the short,
medium and longterm across as many
people as you can imagine.
Manage.
So we'll start with you and your family.
Okay.
How are you going to do that?
You don't know.
That's what you have to talk about,
but you cannot have that conversation
until you've got that framework right.
So and it's very,
very tricky because in the midst of the
argument,
there's going to be tremendous
temptation to oppress and deceive and
humiliate and,
and treat with contempt and hurt and
punish and threatened all of those
things.
Right?
And that that's partly reactivity in the
short term and then it's not,
that's not properly integrated into the
overarching hierarchical structure.
So you've got to keep bringing yourself
back to that.
It's like why should you control your
impulses?
Well,
because their manifestation in the
present,
they're spontaneous and impulsive
manifestation in the present.
Well,
although that may be very,
it may carry with it a feeling of
freedom and power,
maybe destroying the very structure
that's going to provide you with peace
and stability over the medium and long
run.
So it's again,
it's the idea of contradiction.
Now if we're having a discussion,
okay,
so let's say,
well we'll do this in a very local
fashion.
So like
let's say you're having a discussion
about with your partner about who's
going to cook dinner.
Okay.
So you think that's a simple discussions
like it's not a simple discussion.
It's a horrible discussion.
It's where the war between the genders
manifests itself.
It's one of the places and dissolve it.
Weirdly not.
You actually have to solve the war
between the genders or.
Good luck with that.
There it is.
Right in your house.
Right?
It's like a snake in the garden.
There's no getting rid of it.
Okay.
So then you might think,
well what's our aim for dinner?
Well,
do we want to have wretched,
miserable rotten food served by a
resentful person to a bunch of
ungrateful rats who complained and
sniffle.
It's like,
no,
let's assume we don't want.
We don't want that.
Okay,
good.
Well we've got no one we're not aiming
at.
So like,
alright,
who's your cook dinner and when and what
are the rules by which we decide that.
Huh?
That's a tough one because you can
return to roles,
right?
That's what you.
That's why people have roles.
So they don't have to have stupid
conversations like this,
but that time is gone.
Okay.
So what do you do when there's no role?
Well,
I could make you do it,
maybe you could either do it physically
by force or I could just intimidate you
or I could make life miserable for you
if you don't do it or you know,
there's lots of ways of using power.
Problem with that is you're not worthy.
You're not without your own book.
What happens?
And for every step I take towards making
you miserable,
you'll get your chance.
So probably we don't want to use force
plus that's not so good for the kids,
you know,
as from a role model perspective and
hypothetically would want things to be
happening to them.
So tyranny looks like it's out and I
don't want you to subjugate yourself
because maybe like maybe you're very
agreeable.
Let's say that because that's often a
problem in communication between men and
women.
The guys more disagreeable then the
woman is.
And so if he like Jack Sock,
the level of conflict show back off
because she doesn't like conflict for
all sorts of different reasons.
So that's another way of winning.
Except then the person who loses his all
resentful and you end up with,
you know,
horrible,
miserable food fed to warning partners
who are complaining and struggling.
It's not a good solution.
Right?
So then what you're left with,
well then you've gotten negotiation.
Okay.
So I might say,
well do we agree that we need to have
dinner?
Well,
you know,
we might think,
okay,
well we can agree on that.
How often should we have it at home?
Well that's going to require a fair bit
of thought.
You want to go out now and then how
often?
How much is that going to cost?
What are we going to spend?
Wherever you going to go.
Okay,
who pays?
Okay.
So that's going to be like a whole
conversation.
So let's say we figured that out.
It's like five days a week we're going
to stay home.
Okay,
who's going to occur?
Well,
do you like cooking?
Do I like cooking?
Got something sorted out.
So that would be,
that's like a little discussion with
your own physiology in some sense.
You know,
what's your felt state while you're
preparing the food?
And maybe he'll say,
well,
I like it all cooked if,
if,
if there's someone in the kitchen with
me and uh,
you know,
someone else cleans up afterwards,
um,
then it turns out that I don't mind
cooking.
Well then you might say,
well,
it's not minding good enough,
or do you really want to enjoy it?
It's like,
what's the preconditions?
Preconditions would have to be met for
you to enjoy it while you want to think
about that,
because if you can get the person either
of you who the hell cares to enjoy it,
then it's sort of self sustaining,
right?
You put that into place and then the
thing runs smoothly across multiple
iterations.
And so then you might think,
well,
what are the preconditions for us to do
that in a way that would be joyful that
say,
okay,
well that's a high,
that's a high bar.
It's like,
well,
one or the other,
but should learn to cook because
otherwise we're going to be eaten like a
can of Spaghetti or some other sort of
horror.
And that's not very high quality.
So that probably have to be solved.
And then there's the problem of how you
react to the person when they cook,
you know,
like,
do you just assume that that's their
bloody responsibility and if they don't
live up to it,
there's something wrong with them,
or do you notice what they're doing and
express some appreciation and gratitude
and,
and in a way that would increase the
probability that would happen again,
that'd be a better solution.
So then you have to negotiate about how
you're going to do that exactly.
Maybe even right down to the level of
words,
but what you're saying,
I see what you're trying to serve a
higher order by doing that,
right?
You're trying to.
You're trying to satisfy basic
organismal needs,
the provision of food.
But food is complicated for human beings
because we just don't.
You just don't put dog food in the bowl
and child down.
Even dogs won't do that.
Our dog won't eat less.
We're eating no.
So human beings are extremely social
leaders,
so you have to get that right and so.
But the conversation will only take
place in the proper manner if your
orientation is proper in the,
during the conversation and the
orientation needs to be,
how can we make this better for both of
us in the long run and for the people
around you and that you have to bow down
before that in some sense as the
highest,
highest order principle that you're
serving.
And then you can stumble around trying
to work that out and then you might say,
well,
you cook three times a week and I cooked
twice and I'll take care of once.
And uh,
then of course you have to get the whole
grocery thing settled out and that's a
whole other bloody complicated
conversation,
but it needs to be done.
And then you might say,
well,
let's run this for a couple of weeks and
we'll see how it goes,
and then we can meet again and we can
discuss what worked and what didn't.
And the goal is to make it better,
make it better,
make it better and make it better.
And then no one's trying to win.
Well,
it depends on what you mean by when I'm
not trying to defeat you.
Why will have to live with you?
That'd be the first reason is like,
what the hell?
Good.
Is it defeating you?
Unless I want someone wandering around
like this.
You don't resentful and bitter.
Maybe I do want that.
But I don't think that's a very good
place to start.
So when you have a client come in to see
you,
the rule is I can tell you the rules
aren't used because they're Rogerian.
Um,
I will tell the person what I think
so I won't tell them that what I think
is right.
But if they're doing something and I,
I have a reaction to that of some sort
that'll usually express itself in a
fantasy or a thought and I'll just tell
them what happened.
And you know,
I tried to do it as gently as I possibly
can because you can use the as a club,
but then that's not the truth.
And then it needs to get the honest
response of one person to what their
life.
And I'll tell you,
I've seen lots of people who've never
got the honest response of any one
person ever in their whole life to what
their life and so they have no idea what
they're like or what's annoying other
people or how they should behave or any
of those things.
So even though I'm not going to be right
and you know,
in that my reactions won't be precisely
accurate representation of the average
response of other people,
which is basically what you're trying to
model.
It's going to be a lot better than
they've had so far.
And then the other precondition is
you're going to try really hard to get
yourself together,
whatever that means.
We're going to talk about whatever that
means and I'm going to support you in
that.
And that's our goal.
And that that's a variant of Rogerian
unconditional positive regard.
And his,
his unconditional positive regard in
some sense was,
was the setup for the therapy.
So the presupposition is your valuable,
although maybe you're a little on the
bent and twisted side,
but you know,
maybe you could be straightened up into
something that's like deadly.
And uh,
we're going to start with that
presupposition and we're going to learn
along the way,
but that's what,
that's what we're,
that's what we're aimed at.
So the unconditional positive regard,
it's like a human rights thing because
the basis of the idea of human rights is
that people are valuable,
they have some intrinsic value,
you know,
and the thing,
I think maybe it's pr,
it's reasonable to presuppose that from
the Rogerian perspective is that what's
valuable about you as you're being
right,
you're a conscious,
you're a locus of experience,
and as such you're a unique locus of the
experience.
And as such you have something to
contribute that no one else can
contribute.
And that that's valuable.
It's intrinsically valuable.
That's the basic presupposition of the
idea of human rights,
by the way.
So if that's acted out in the
therapeutic session,
but it's acted out in any relationship,
that's therapeutic.
Here's a,
here's a counter example.
Let's say you're trying to smoke,
trying to quit smoking.
You're trying to quit smoking,
okay?
And your friends smoke.
Okay?
So what are they doing?
Like do they offer you a cigarette at
every possible opportunity because
that's very common.
People do that very commonly.
Why?
Well,
maybe they're mad that maybe they're mad
that they can put smoking or maybe if
you quit that they didn't,
that would cast a bit them in a bad
shadow or maybe they're just being
malevolent or maybe it's a game or
whatever,
but one of the things that isn't is in
the best interest of the person who's
trying to quit smoking or drinking or
eating or you know,
or behaving in any sort of dismal manner
that's self defeating across time.
And so one of the things that,
you know,
I had a client just a while back and he
was talking about I'm an older sibling
and he used to make these models very
complicated models.
He was quite young at this time.
His sibling was like a decade and a half
older,
so he was like 10 or something like
that.
Make these really complex Martin's.
He'd spend a couple of weeks building
them and then when the older sibling
came in,
he just smashed them up.
Like we'll see what kind of stress this
thing can take.
It's like,
okay,
what's going on there?
Well,
I wouldn't say it's unconditional
positive regard with the aim of
encouraging the person and bringing them
to fruition.
It's quite the opposite and it's an
instrumental use of action.
It send the point is not to elevate me
or you or both of us.
The point is I'm going to be the monster
at the top of the hierarchy.
If you're all crunched up in lying at
the bottom,
that's just fine.
And that's a very common set of
motivations.
And you might ask,
well why isn't that okay?
Well that's a good question.
I think the right answer to that is as a
long run game,
it's counterproductive.
No one benefits.
So there's local benefits to you for the
short in the short term.
So.
Alright,
let me read you some things that Rogers
wrote.
Okay,
this is a good one.
This is because this is his statements.
Here's some of his axiomatic
presuppositions.
So this is what you need to cleave to.
If you're going to engage in the process
of Virginia in therapy,
you have to want to be independent.
Now that's an interesting.
I don't know,
maybe we can actually have a discussion
about this.
You know,
Freud thought the eatable complex was
universal and what he meant by that.
People just don't have this discussion,
but we can give it a shot.
We'll see how it goes.
What he meant by that was that
the,
that's struggling out of the family.
The primary family is very,
very difficult.
So I can give you an example.
So I had another client,
very bright guy,
second generation guy for Middle East
and uh,
he was heading for a pretty good career.
Is a smart guy.
Nice.
He'd done a lot of work to get this
career going is in that position that
was difficult to obtain.
You had to move to a different city in
order to pursue this career.
And his parents were very upset that he
was moving off the street they lived
yet.
Okay.
So
from the Western perspective,
roughly speaking,
this is where it gets tricky.
The proper thing to do on behalf of the
parents.
Would have been to support him in his
attempts to be to establish himself
independently.
The parent's perspective was,
you're betraying the family by moving
away.
Now the question is,
is it reasonable to presume that
independence is an absolute value?
I mean,
we're having words about this.
That's for sure.
The wars have been going on for a long
time.
For Rogers.
If you didn't value independence,
you couldn't get going in this form of
therapy.
Freud thought that all cultures where
heatable to one degree or another and
you know,
thought that wasn't true for northern
Europeans
and that was part of the reason why
Human Freud came to a crossroads.
So
think about that.
Okay.
In any case,
for Roger's only independence value
individually were suited for client
center therapy.
Here's more ECC.
Yes.
Honest,
can you.
You're not another definition of
independence.
A
good point.
I don't know if you can be completely
consistent with yourself and your
family.
Well that,
that that's a very useful way of the
way.
That's a very useful way of phrasing,
phrasing your question.
That's a very useful way of phrasing the
issue.
No.
Can you be.
If you're honest,
does that mean you're independent?
It's a good question.
Might mean that because it means that
you're at least say again from the road
next to take it from the Rogerian
perspective.
If you're speaking for yourself now,
that would be yourself in relationship
to other people.
The integrate itself,
right?
Not the kind of instrumentals useless
self that's wandering around causing
trouble.
They're still your.
Your unique position that has to be
contended with.
Right,
and the fact that you're your own kind
of bounded entity with its own destiny
and path and its own particular
biological structure
and
it's possible that the way that you
define independence is that that
particular knee is properly integrated
into the collective,
so that's a good.
That's a good issue.
Okay.
Assuming a minimal natural,
a minimal mutual willingness to be in
contact and to receive communications,
we may say that the greater the
communicated congruence of experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual,
the more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same qualities,
mutually accurate understanding of the
communication's improved,
psychological adjustment and functioning
in both parties and mutual satisfaction.
The relationship pretty good.
I bought this so basically what he's
saying is that
if we're communicating and I tell you
what's actually going on with me the
best I possibly can and try to get rid
of all of the motives that have nothing
to do with communication,
then that's going to work out quite
nicely in the long run.
It's gonna work out for both of us and
for the relationship.
It's good.
It's an interesting hypothesis.
I can tell you that people don't do
this.
You know,
I showed you that Gottman,
I don't know how many of you looked at
that length godman studies on marital
satisfaction.
Right?
But I thought that was really
interesting because I've seen people
like that.
Lots of times,
you know,
they're on the surface,
everything's fine,
but well sometimes the tension is so
high you can hardly even stand to be in
the room with the people you know,
because you can just add,
add,
add an embodied level,
you're mirroring the distress,
you know,
we get a pit in your stomach,
it's hard to breathe and you just know.
It's probably smell I think is what it's
trans is,
is what it's communicated by,
you know,
smell affects us and all sorts of ways
we don't understand.
So here,
here's an example,
women like the smell of tee shirts that
men wore,
if the men are symmetrical better than
the men aren't symmetrical.
So that's a good example of how smell
affects you,
affects you in lots of weight.
So anyways,
um,
what gartland observed was that
basically the couples weren't getting
along.
We're just lying to each other all the
time,
right?
Because they were pretending that
everything was all right,
when in fact nothing was already at all.
Their bodies were going haywire.
That's a technical term,
hayward.
So it was way too stressful for them.
And you might say,
well,
why is that bad?
Why shouldn't you be like that?
Because that's a good question.
Well,
one is if your stress responses are to
elevated,
we know what happens.
That's the generalized stress response.
Your cortisol levels go up and then,
well then you age the fat,
so if you want to age fast,
that's a very good way of doing it.
But if that's not your goal,
your goal is peace and harmony.
Then pretending that everything's all
right without communicating isn't going
to work.
And so the couples aren't saying things
like
there's something about the way we're
talking and it's making me extremely
nervous,
you know?
And then actually trying to figure that
out.
It's like,
I wouldn't say,
well,
you're making me nervous because,
well maybe you are,
but maybe not.
Maybe I'm just a nervous type.
God only knows.
Let's see if we can sort this out or
maybe I'm nervous about something else
completely.
No,
maybe I'm nervous about women.
So there's lots of digging to do.
Okay.
So you can think about that and you
think,
well,
is that a reasonable proposition?
Now
you can try this,
this is an excellent,
this is,
I'm not going to tell you how many
specific psychological exercises,
but this is a really good one.
It's hard to
reel communicational curves and the
evaluative tendency avoided when we
listened with understanding,
so the evaluative rogers various is
difficult to understand with regards to
the relationship between evaluation and
unconditional positive regard because he
tends to speak as if the evaluation is
bad,
but really what he means is hierarchical
elevate evaluation,
which is your worst that meet or I'm
better than you,
so like those things might even be true
in any given case,
but they're not relevant to what we're
doing.
Right?
We're trying to do something other than
that.
So when that creeps in,
I think about his dominance hierarchy.
Maneuvering not happens all the time.
When people are talking,
you know,
they're just maneuvering around in a
dominance hierarchy.
They're trying to communicate.
So that's the evaluative tendency.
What does this mean?
It means to see the expressed idea and
attitude from the other person's point
of view to sense how it feels to him to
achieve his frame of reference.
In regard to the thing he is talking
about stated so briefly,
this may sound absurdly simple,
but it is not.
It's an approach which we have found
extremely potent in the field of
psychotherapy.
It's the most effective agent we know
for altering the basic personality
structure of an individual and improving
his relationships and his communications
with others.
That's a quite the statement.
No,
the most effective agent we know for
altering the basic personality structure
of an individual.
If I can listen to what he tells me,
if I can understand how it seems to him,
if I can see it's personal meaning for
him,
if I could sense the emotional flavor
which it has for him,
then I will be releasing potent forces
of change in him.
If I can really understand how he hates
his father or the university or
economists.
If I could catch the flavor of this
sphere of insanity or his fear of atom
bombs or of Russia,
it will be of the greatest help to him
in altering those very hatreds and fears
and in establishing realistic and
harmonious relationships with the very
people and situations toward which he
has felt hatred and fear.
We know from our research,
by the way,
Rogers was one of the first clinicians
who empirically evaluated the outcome of
psychotherapy and so he actually more or
less established the idea that therapy
outcomes should be measured
scientifically and in doing that,
he in some sense,
he set down one element of the standards
by which modern clinical psychologists
are actually trained in practice because
the modern clinical psychologist is a
scientist practitioner.
So the idea is that you should be
trained as a researcher and as a
practitioner and that's quite unique.
Doctors,
medical doctors for example,
are not trained that way.
Although you could make a very strong
case that they should be.
We know from our research that such
empathic understanding,
understanding with a person,
not about him.
It's such an effective approach that it
can bring about major changes in
personality.
Now,
some of you may be feeling that you
listen well to people and that you've
never seen such results.
The chances are very great indeed that
your listening has not been of the type
I have described.
Fortunately,
I can suggest a little laboratory
experiment which you could try to test
the quality of your understand the next
time you get into an argument with your
wife or your friend or with a small
group of friends.
Just stop the discussion for a moment
and for an experiment institute this
rule.
Each person can only speak up for
himself once he has first restated the
ideas and feelings of the previous
speaker accurately and to that speaker
satisfaction.
Now,
that's the annoying part,
right?
Because if you're in an argument,
you're going to use all sorts of
rhetorical devices in order to win.
One of the most obvious of those
rhetorical devices is that you make your
case and I only half listened because
I'm formulating what I'm going to say to
you next and then I.
I try.
I impose a bias in my processing of your
argument and so that what I addressed
when I talked to you is the sort of
argument that you'd make if you were
weak and stupid and contemptible,
and then I go after that and that's
basically a straw man approach,
right?
I take your eye,
take your position,
and I try to make it into this scrawny
little rowdiest thing I can possibly
manage illustrating that it needs to be
rubbed out and then I'd rub it out.
It's like the rigid approaches are
actually exactly the officer by the way.
It's the approach that Dostoyevsky he
took to his characters when he wrote his
great novels and it's also the approach
that all great novelists take to their
character.
Because if you're a great novelist,
you've put yourself inside the hand of
the murderer.
Right?
And Dostoevsky was created that.
So in crime and punishment,
for example,
the main character going,
the cough is a lawsuit and he's all
obsessed because he's lost his faith in
God and he's got all these weird ideas
that emerged in Europe at the end of the
18 hundreds that if there's no god,
everything is permitted.
And so he's thinking,
well,
my moral just because I'm a coward,
which was a Nietzschean proposition
actually meets.
You said most morality is cowardice.
He didn't say that morality was
cowardice.
He said,
most of the time when people are being
cowardly,
they pretend that's moral,
which is absolutely right.
Anyways,
he's wrestling with this idea that
morality is just cowardice and that once
fundamental beliefs have disappeared.
You can do anything you want and the
only thing that's there to stop you is
your own fear.
So that's rattling around in the back of
his head.
Now,
at the same time,
he's more or less starving to death and
his sister is going to essentially
prostitute herself to raise enough money
so that he can stay in law school.
Now it's not exactly that she's going to
go off and marry this guy that she
doesn't love who's quite rich and she's
going to do that to keep him in law
school.
So that's sort of sucks,
you know,
he's not very happy about that.
And then he's living in this horrible
flop house and the woman who runs it is
Dostoevsky,
sets this up quite nicely.
She's the sort of person that if she was
run over by a horse cart,
everyone would be pleased.
She's grasping,
admitted and miserly and horrible and
mean and malevolent and cruel and all
those things.
And then to make it even worse,
she has this nice who isn't very bright
that she basically treats as a slave and
tortures in orders around all the time.
And then she has all these people who
were living in her building,
which she doesn't take care of it and
she's just grasping money out of him all
the time and she doesn't do anything
with money.
She just puts it in a little chest and
she lives like a on bread crumbs and
dust.
So.
So Dostoyevsky's very careful to set
this situation.
Not,
it's like,
okay,
is there such a thing as right or wrong?
Well,
Russ Golden,
the,
these pretty puzzled about that.
Plus he's hungry and he's drinking too
much and you know,
he doesn't eat broccoli.
Well that's why he's hungry.
So his head is a little on the adult
side and then he's got this terrible
moral conundrum.
It's like there's this horrible woman
and she's torturing her niece and then
her sister is gonna go into a loveless
marriage and he can't stay at law
school.
And so we rationalize it.
It says,
Oh,
here's a solution,
man.
I'll just get rid of that old woman.
No one's gonna miss her.
Now I'll be doing the world a favor by
getting rid of her and then I'll take
your money and then my sister doesn't
have to become a prostitute,
roughly speaking,
and I get to go to school and I'm going
to be a good guy.
And so poof.
Perfect.
And if there's no ultimate right and
wrong and I'm sad,
it's an instrumental argument.
Right?
Well,
so he kills her.
and you have to read a book if you want
the rest of the story.
Uh,
suffice it to say that things do not go
exactly as he predicted.
So the first thing he figures out is
that the person you are before you hit
someone with it,
someone with an ax and the person you
are immediately after you hit someone
with an apps are not the same persons.
So you know,
he assumes constancy of identity across
every experience that turns out to be
seriously wrong.
So Dostoevsky man,
and he does such a,
it's to terrifying book.
It's the most psychologically accurate
book I ever read,
I think.
But the reason I'm telling you about it
is this is what made Dostoevsky so
courageous.
It's like he,
he generated up a murderer who is
basically him as a young man and he gave
this kid every reason to murder ever.
And He,
everyone he could think of.
He tried to make the case for murder as
strong as he could possibly make it.
So he wasn't generate,
not some,
you know,
two dimensional bad guy.
And then he has the,
he has the argument.
And so that's so brilliant,
right?
Because if I really want to have a
discussion with you and I want to get
somewhere wherever somewhere might be,
I want to help you make your argument as
strong as you can on the off chance that
you have something to say that I don't
know and maybe you'll do the same to me
and then then we can have the discussion
and we can get the things solved and
then maybe it won't be around to plague
us anymore.
Well,
people don't do that in relationships,
you know,
they,
what they do is maintain fragile piece.
And I actually think that probably works
if you're,
if you're bounded by roles,
and this was a union on observation,
so young believer that you didn't have
to have an individual relationship if
you were in a traditional culture
because women did women things and men
did men things and they walked along the
path in parallel and there were no
conflicts because there were no.
There were.
But you know,
they're there.
Most of what you were supposed to do was
laid out for you.
And you know,
monitor people don't like that idea,
but just try negotiating over who should
do,
who should cook dinner,
see if you set a lap for you,
make a decision about whether the roles
are useful or not.
Because you know,
I'd been in lots of houses where that
fight had been going on for 35 years.
I've never solved.
So camps couldn't eat.
Neo is the food was terrible.
The husband and wife are at each other's
throats,
you know,
fine.
So it's really hard once you're under
the rules to.
Once you're out of the rules,
you have to do it as an individual.
But that's a trek.
Tremendous demand.
It's an unbelievable demand.
It's the same demand that essentially
that Dostoyevsky he put on himself.
It's like
we're partners will say you are one
weird and unwieldy and malevolent and
peculiar creature and so alive.
So like how the hell are we going to
sort that out?
Well,
you better be awake if you're going to
sort that out.
And then.
But the alternative is the Gottman
situation,
right?
Everything's fine.
And your heart's racing and your
cortisol is generating and you know
you're having murderous dreams.
I've had clients who were very motivated
to commit homicide and they had their
reasons and one client I'm thinking
about,
she thought it was her moral duty to do
this because the person that she hated
had really hurt their family.
Like not in some trivial way but like
hurt them as badly as she possibly
could,
but there was nothing she could do about
it.
There was no legal recourse and so she
was a very moral person.
In fact,
somewhat I would say it doesn't matter.
She's a very moral person and this was
just driving her crazy.
It's like I have to act,
I have to act.
I can't just let this person get away
with it because it was also ongoing.
Well,
but what are you going to say?
stop thinking about that.
You know,
you could put your thoughts to a more
productive use.
It's like,
it's not unhelpful,
but you can't.
You can't help a person like that at all
until you put your.
You put yourself in their situation.
You think,
okay,
if I was in that situation and that had
happened,
what would I do?
And then the first thing I thought was,
oh,
I'd be having the same kind of burgers
fantasies so that that doesn't seem like
it's possible that that's not a great
solution.
So let's see if we can come up with
something else.
But the danger there is that you have to
put yourself in that situation and
people don't like to do that because
they think,
oh,
well,
I've never had murdered his fantasies.
So like if you would never have
murderous fantasies,
I would actually say there's something
wrong with you.
If you're not capable of that,
then there's like there's a path of you
missing.
It's in there man.
And when,
when,
when someone's pushing on you at some
point in your life and they will,
you better have that reserve capacity or
they're just going to mow you right
over.
So you could see what this would mean.
It would simply mean that before
presenting your own point of view,
it would be necessary for you to really
achieve the other speakers frame of
reference to understand his thoughts and
feeling so well that you could summarize
them for him.
Sounds simple,
doesn't it?
But if you try it,
you will discover it as one of the most
difficult things I've ever tried to do.
However,
once you have been able to see the
other's point of view,
your own comments will have to be
drastically revised.
You will also find the emotion going out
of the discussion,
the differences being reduced and those
differences which renamed being under
rational and understandable sore.
So Roger's thought that courage was a
prerequisite for empathic understanding.
It's interesting too,
because you know here,
here's a.
here's a question for you.
It's like check you trust people
or more specifically,
you know,
should I trust you?
Well,
you might think if you've heard me talk,
you'd think,
well,
there's no way you should trust a person
because they're just so full of snakes
and malevolence that it's just
absolutely mind boggling.
So why in the world would you ever trust
something like that?
Well then you can think about it this
way.
There's two kinds of trust.
There's the kind of trust you have when
you're too stupid to know better and
that's not trust,
that's naive and that is not a moral
virtue and there's the kind of trust you
have when you know that the person your
car can do and you are completely full
of snakes and you decide as an act of
courage that you're going to trust the
person anyways because that of all the
things you could do to help lead them
and the discussion towards the light,
that's the most important.
It's like I'm going to assume that in
our interactions,
your impulse towards the good is going
to be victorious.
Now isn't if you're interested in this,
you could go online,
you can watch Paul Bernardo,
you remember Old Paul Bernardo.
Okay.
There's videos of Paul Bernardo online
when he's talking to a bunch of RCMP
officers and judges.
They're trying to extract some more
information from him about some murders
that remained unsolved.
You want to see a psychopath,
that operation,
you can just watch those videos.
It's amazing.
He,
he runs the meeting like he's the CEO of
Apple.
It's amazing.
So.
And that's a problem I would say to some
degree for the Rogerian approach,
right?
Because.
Well,
what about Paul Bernardo,
you know,
is everyone fundamentally oriented
towards the good?
Well,
it's a reasonable presupposition.
Most of the time I think it works better
if society is organized themselves
according to that principal because
otherwise we know,
for example,
that one of the mite thing,
what's a natural resource oil,
right?
For a
box site or iron ore or forget about all
that.
The fundamental natural resource is
trust.
So if you look around the world and you
look at economies like Japan,
for example,
Japan has no natural resources,
right?
While they're filthy rich.
Why?
Because the economy is basically
predicated on interpersonal trust.
So when there's been some lovely work
done in economics regarding precisely
that without trust,
your oil just sits in the ground or it
leaks out of the pipelines because
nobody weld with the property.
You know,
there isn't.
There's no reason to assume that you're
going to be able to do anything
cooperative or collaborative,
so trust is a necessity if you're really
willing to understand the person in this
way.
If you're willing to enter his private
world at see the way life appears to
him,
you run the risk of being changed
yourself.
You might see it his way.
You might find yourself influenced in
your attitudes or personality.
Risk of being changed is one of the most
frightening prospects most of us can
face.
If I enter as fully as I am able into
the private world.
If the neurotic or psychotic individual
isn't there a risk that I might become
lost in that world,
most of us are afraid to take that risk.
The great majority of us cannot listen.
We find ourselves compelled to evaluate
because listening is too dangerous.
The first requirement is courage and we
do not always have it,
so it says 3:00 on this.
That right.
Well,
that's a good place to start.
There.