Since the scientific age began,
we've lived in a universe where the
bottom strata of reality is considered
to be something that's dead like dirt.
It's like it's matter,
it's objective,
it's external and there isn't any
element of it that lens any reality to
phenomena like meaning or purpose.
That's all been relegated to this
objective and in some ways to the
illusory,
but it's by no means self evident that
that set of presuppositions is correct
because we lack infinite knowledge and
there's many things about the structure
of being that we don't understand the
main one being consciousness.
We can't account for it at all and we
can't account for the role it appears to
play in the transformation of potential
into actuality,
which is a role that's been recognized
by physicists for almost a hundred years
now and which remains one of the biggest
unsolved mysteries in science.
There are other ways of looking at
what's real and these other ways have
some advantages and one of the
advantages they have is that they
protect us knowing these other ways of
of operating within reality,
defining reality,
protect us from certain kinds of
pathologies.
And modern people are prone to a fair
number of pathologies that stem from the
assumptions of their,
of their,
of the systems they use to define
reality.
And one of those pathologies is,
uh,
a kind of a nihilistic hopelessness,
which is a consequence of the
recognition that in the final analysis,
nothing really has any meaning.
And because life is difficult,
and that's a meaning that you can't
escape being forced to abandon your
belief in a positive or a transcendent
meaning can leave you week.
The Times when you really can least
afford to be weak.
And there's more important pathologies
that it's opened us up to two.
And those are pathologies that belief.
And I think we saw the most horrifying
examples of that.
Hopefully the most horrifying examples
in the 20th century where people whose
belief systems were shattered,
at least in part by the competition
between religious and scientific
viewpoints turned in large numbers to
mass movements that were in error in
every way a substitute,
a moral rational in some sense
substitute for religious beliefs that
appeared no longer tenable.
And the consequence of that was it was
just about annihilation because we came
close to an isolation twice,
once in the 60s and once in the 80s and
even without the totality of
annihilation,
we lost hundreds of millions of people
as a consequence of pathological belief
systems and the 20th century.