Hey,
how's it going,
everyone?
So today I have a very special guest,
Dr. Jordan B.
Peterson.
He's a professor of psychology at the
University of Toronto and a practicing
clinical psychologist.
And I want to read just a,
just a little bit of,
um,
of,
of paragraph,
just a little piece from his,
his arm,
his own website.
And Jordan Peterson has published more
than a hundred scientific papers
transforming the modern understanding of
personality and revolutionizing the
psychology of religion and his now
classic book maps of meaning.
They're the architecture of belief as a
Harvard professor,
he was nominated for the prestigious
Levinson teaching prize and is regarded
by his current University of Toronto
students as one of the three truly life
changing teachers.
Uh,
Dr. Peterson.
Thank you for coming on and tiering
that.
Is it,
is it safe to say,
is it fair to say that you are
considered a rock star now?
Well,
my youtube channel seems to be,
have become very popular.
And uh,
I've been,
yeah,
I mean I hate to use that
characterization,
you know,
but,
um,
yeah,
there's been an explosion of media
interest and then public interest in the
sorts of things that not only the sorts
of things that I've been dealing with
say sort of philosophically and
politically,
but also in the,
in the lectures that I'm putting up for
people on,
on Youtube,
which I'd been doing for about about
four years now.
And I think it's the combination of the
stance that I took on,
on compelled speech and,
and on political correctness in general
and also the content that I've been
provided with the people that they come
to the channel for the,
for the political controversy,
I suppose.
And they seem to stay for the content.
So that's pretty,
it's been,
it's remarkable.
I mean,
I don't know what to make of it.
It's,
it's remarkable.
Yeah.
You like it.
There's been like a,
a shift of people wanting to,
they like,
they want to hear stuff like this.
They're,
they're really excited to hear like a
position of free speech when,
when,
when a lot of people actually have been
kind of railing against it.
And um,
it's really interesting the type,
the Times that we're in because
unfortunately it's coming from a lot of
people on the far left.
There's like this a Torah,
a authoritarian left type of movement
taking a foot.
And that's basically war.
Most people kind of a recognized you
from because they saw a protest,
uh,
that was going on at your university,
um,
about,
and it was about a bill see 16.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
Yeah.
Well cause I made a video that,
that where I,
I expressed my opposition to the go.
The Canadian government's attempts to
make certain kinds of speech mandatory
and also our to oppose the University of
Toronto Human Resources Departments,
attempts to impose,
uh,
what I regard as inappropriate and,
and likely harmful so-called unconscious
anti bias retraining on the,
of their,
uh,
human resources employees,
which I think is a very dangerous
incursion into the civil rights of,
of,
of their staff as well as being based on
very poor science in my estimation.
So yeah,
people,
uh,
there was a protest as a consequence of
that and that got a lot of attention on
youtube and that was one of the things
that drew a lot of attention to my
channel.
So,
yeah,
absolutely.
I mean it's what,
it's how I found you.
It's um,
I actually did a video on it and I saw
that you tweeted it out,
so I was actually like,
oh,
he,
he seen it.
And I,
I feel,
I feel strange because I'm like the type
of content I make.
I try to be a very lighthearted,
I tried to have people,
I try to be a crack a lot of jokes and
have people at least have some fun
through through the madness.
So when I was also like seeing that,
I was like,
oh,
I wonder,
I wonder what he thinks because I don't
know,
I got a real kick out of your,
out of your coverage.
I thought it was really funny.
And it's funny because some of the best
conversations that I've had with people
on Youtube so far have been with people
who have,
uh,
who are,
who have a background in comedy,
roughly speaking.
And I think it's partly because people
who have a good sense of humor and who
have a comical take on things are also
likely to tell the truth because there's
almost nothing funnier than telling the
truth.
Right.
If you say things that other people
think but won't say,
then you know,
there that often makes it very funny.
And I thought you're,
oh,
I think your general very comical and
wedding so
well that,
that,
that I appreciate that a lot because,
yeah,
like,
uh,
I don't know,
hearing,
stuff like that.
Sometimes I'm like doubting myself.
I don't know.
I'm like,
should I,
should I try to be more,
cause,
excuse me.
Um,
I'm in,
I'm kind of,
I guess I've been shoved in this,
uh,
this community called this skeptic
community on Youtube.
And,
um,
I,
I do try to be skeptical,
but at the same time,
like I said,
I tried to be more just on the comedic
side.
I was thinking about being more serious
and try to be like,
say more respected,
I guess in the,
in the,
in the community that I'm in.
But I kind of want to just,
I was like,
no,
no.
There's,
there's enough people.
I don't know if you're,
um,
if you watch,
say if there's any,
any youtubers and taking in particular
that you watch,
I don't know if you've,
uh,
seen say anyone like Sargon of a cod or
armored skeptic.
Yeah.
And,
um,
have you had any
I'm going to be on star gone show and
in,
in the relatively near future
I suspected that much.
Um,
especially he just did a video about it.
I saw it,
um,
recently.
And that was actually something that I
wanted to ask you about cause he was
talking about mcmaster university and
um,
and that's actually something that I
wanted to,
I really,
I was really interested in and knowing
like say,
um,
was this,
how do you like you officially like on
you just like a target now we're now
you're being shut down where we've seen
it happen to other people,
people that like say the Milo
Yiannopoulos,
but you know,
he's a,
I can say a provocateur and so it's,
it's very telling that they would go out
of their way just to shut you down when
I know it just seems like you're not
saying anything that is irrational.
You're not saying anything that is even
remotely extreme.
And a,
I just wanted to get your take on how
did you feel when,
when you got,
when you got your,
your,
um,
shutdown at all?
Because when I was there,
I didn't really think of it as being
shut down.
Um,
and the reason for that is because
things aren't exactly what they appear
to be anymore.
And so for example,
now when I go and talk at places,
the place I'm talking out is barely the
place where the event is happening at
all.
The real event happens on Youtube.
And so I went there and I saw all these
people acting in a very,
what would you say?
Well,
it was partly a,
a vulgar manner because they were
yelling things at me that were,
um,
just,
they just Asinine,
they're not the sorts of things that
you'd expect.
Even protestors who had any sense to be
shouting.
They're,
they're,
they're just,
they're just low rent insults,
you know,
low grade insults and behaving very
badly and laughing about it and on their
cell phones and misbehaving in a,
in a very bad way.
And,
and having the goal,
for example,
to appear at the mcmaster talk behind a
huge banner with a hammer and sickle on
it.
Like,
as far as I'm concerned,
I really mean this.
There is no difference between appearing
behind a banner with a hammer and sickle
on it and appearing behind a banner with
a swastika on it.
And the fact that you can get away with
that at a university and that that's
considered,
uh,
what would you describe it as a
reasonable stance in the aftermath of
the events of the 20th century where we
know that at least a hundred million
people were killed by communist
totalitarianism is absolutely
reprehensible.
But when I was at mass mcmaster,
I thought,
and I thought this ever since that
first,
that first protest where I,
where I was shouted down,
increasingly the appropriate thing to do
when surrounded by protesters is to
document it and let them,
let them destroy their own credibility.
And so far,
virtually every time I've had an
encounter with the radical social
justice types and I just let them be,
which,
which is I think a reasonable approach.
They've undermined their own position
dreadfully.
And so I don't think of it being as
being shut down at all.
I just think about it as another route
to victory and even an effective route.
Cause I may be 150,000 people have
watched that protest now at mcmaster
university may be more far more people
than were at the event itself.
So
No.
Yeah,
you're absolutely right.
It,
it actually,
I mean it wouldn't,
this stuff does happen.
It does bring,
it brings these issues to light and it
shows just how ridiculous these people
are acting and showing that like you,
you take them seriously.
And I 100% agree about the,
the hammer and sickle thing like 100%
because,
um,
especially when you see what's been
happening at say for instance,
like trump rallies around the United
States where a lot of these people that
consider themselves a communists or
Marxists or whatever,
or um,
antifascist they're just just beating
the hell out of people in the,
in the name of fighting fascism.
It's,
it's the most,
it's the most like,
it's the most ironic thing that I,
I've,
I've witnessed in quite a while.
It's,
it's pretty,
it's pretty sad.
It's pretty sad to be honest.
But,
um,
like you said though,
people are,
um,
and just in droves is just trying to shy
away from that and be like,
this is not,
this is not the way to go.
And so yeah,
it actually is a very good thing that,
you know,
will say there's the silver lining for
you getting screeched at and shouted
down and everything.
It's,
it's
a massive silver lining because now I'm
in a situation that I suspect is very
frustrating for those who are opposing
what I'm doing,
where if I go speak somewhere and there
are no protestors,
then I get to speak and I'll get a
viewing of a couple of hundred thousand
people.
And if I go somewhere and I don't get to
speak,
then that gets a viewing of a couple of
hundred thousand people.
And so at the moment I'm in this
extraordinarily fortunate position where
as long as I don't do anything to
unforgivably stupid and get carried away
or get arrogant or anything like that,
that um,
as long as I've cautious as if I keep
pushing forward with what I'm doing,
then I seem to come out in a positive
light either way.
And that's a great position to be in.
It's an amazing position to be in an
eye.
It's also been,
I've learned some really interesting
things here as well.
So one of the things that's happened,
you were talking about my youtube
popularity,
I can tell you some details about that,
that you might be interested in.
First of all,
the overwhelming majority of the people
who come to see me live and who are
watching my youtube videos are men.
It's about 90% men.
And you know,
you might think that that's because my
political stance say it doesn't
necessarily appeal to women,
but I don't think that that's what it
is.
Because when I looked at the
demographics for my lectures,
my personality lectures in my other
university lectures that I put online
since 2013 even before this political
issue became central,
let's say about 85% of the people who
were watching my lectures were men.
And that's strange because about 75% of
psychology students in universities are
female now.
And so I've been trying to figure out
why is it that men are coming to watch
me and why is it that men are watching
my lectures and what I,
so I've been speaking to these audiences
about a variety of different things and
I've been concentrating mostly on the
right to free speech,
um,
and in an apolitical,
in some sense,
like I'm making the case that it's
necessary for free speech to be placed
above all other political virtue so that
no matter who it is,
no matter who positioned that's being
put forward,
they have an opportunity to engage in
political dialogue.
But also I've been talking an awful lot
about responsibility and responsibility
is the other half of rights,
right?
Because your rights are my
responsibility and my rights are your
responsibility.
And so you actually can't have a
discussion about rights without having a
discussion about responsibility unless
you're willing to forget about half of
the story.
And the radical leftists in particular.
And even the moderates I would say have
been pushing this idea that the quality
of life that someone enjoys is entirely
dependent on the rights that they are
granted or the rights that they take to
themselves.
And I have been putting forward the
counter story,
which is,
well just hold on a minute there guys.
You should be concentrating more on
responsibility that you should be
upholding in the community and getting
your act together as individuals and
living in a way that makes you valuable
to your family and to your,
to the broader community and learning
how to bear a heavy load,
like a civilized human being and the
man,
the young man,
they are so hungry for that message.
Just,
just unbelievable.
Their eyes light up.
And you know,
I,
I've got this program that I wanted to
talk to you about too.
Uh,
I designed this program a while back
called future authoring.
And that's available@selfauthoring.com.
And it's a program that helps people
write out a plan for their life three to
five years down the road.
And so what the program asks you some
questions it asks you,
okay?
So imagine that you were taking care of
yourself like you're someone that you
were cared for.
So you're,
you're,
you're trying to set your life up so
that you have a good,
high quality,
valuable life.
However you want to define that.
That's up to you to define it,
um,
in Eros to think about,
well,
what do you want from your friends?
Or Hoe do you want your friends to be?
What do you want for your career?
How are you going to educate yourself?
How can you use your time in a high
quality and productive way outside of,
uh,
outside of your obligations?
Um,
how are you going to handle drugs and
alcohol?
Um,
what do you want for an intimate
relationship?
How are you going to structure your
family?
You know,
the,
the basic can take about that as the
basic dimensions of a,
of a functional life.
So the question is,
if you could have what you wanted,
what would that look like?
And assuming what,
what you wanted was also best for you,
you know that you were heading in a
positive direction.
So you're asked to think about that.
And then you're asked to write for 15
minutes without too much concern for
grammar or structure about what your
life could be like three to five years
down the road if it was set up in a
manner that you would find optimal.
And then you're asked to write a counter
position,
which is all right.
So think about yourself critically for a
minute.
And then imagine that you let your bad
habits and your resentment and your
hatred and,
and everything about you that's,
that's subpar.
It's suboptimal.
Get the upper hand and it augured into
the ground.
What sort of hell would you be in three
to five years down the road?
And so we basically imagine you specify
a heaven that you can strive for and it
held that you want to avoid.
And that sets you up for maximum
motivation a cause.
You're running towards something you
want and you're running away from
something you don't want.
And then you're asked to lay out an
implementable plan and to come up with
detailed rationale for what you're going
to pursue.
So,
okay,
so that's all a long story.
But we've tested this program and a
number of universities in Europe and in
North America,
and we found the same thing each time.
We found that it,
it works better for,
for students who are doing worse.
It's not just for students,
by the way,
but we've tested it in students because
it was,
it was an easy population to actually
assess its effectiveness.
And so,
um,
we found that it increased student's
grade point average by about 25% and
decreased the probability that they
would drop out of university by about
25% so about,
so huge effect.
But what was really cool was that the
biggest effect was on men.
And if you look in the universities now
and it schools for that matter,
women are outperforming men.
Definitely.
And I think it's because of the men.
Well I,
we don't have to get into why that is,
but they are.
But if they do the future authoring
program,
the men catch up.
And then here's the kicker.
This is,
this is something I think is absolutely
fascinating.
So when we did our,
our big study in Holland,
I worked with a woman there named
Mikayla shippers.
And uh,
uh,
another professor named Ad Cheaper's and
we ran about 7,000 students through this
program now.
And then we broke them up,
not only buy,
buy,
buy sex,
but also by ethnicity.
And so we broke them into male and
female and also Dutch national and no
one western ethnic minority.
And then we looked at,
at their initial performance before they
did the program.
And so the higher performing people
where the Dutch women and then the Dutch
Dutchmen and then the non Western ethnic
minority women and then the non Western
ethnic minority men who were out
underperforming the Dutch women by about
70%.
So a huge margin and dropping out far
more frequently.
When they did the program,
the nonwestern ethnic minority men
caught up to the Dutch women and passed
them within two years.
And then we,
no kidding,
man,
that just blew me away.
And so like,
cause that's,
that's so unlikely,
right?
Usually when you,
when you produce an intervention that's
designed to improve things,
first of all,
it usually fails.
Sometimes it makes things worse.
And even if it does succeed,
what usually happens is,
is it makes the higher performing people
do even better.
But that isn't what this did.
What it did was take the people who were
doing the worst and it increased their
performance up to the point where they
were indistinguishable from the high
performers.
And so,
so there's a bunch of things about that
that's interesting in the first is that
people make the claim all the time that
say in European communities that if
you're a visible minority,
the reason that you're not attaining the
same,
uh,
accomplishment level,
let's say,
is because of sociological or political
or economic reasons.
But we produced a psychological
intervention that helped people get
their acts together at the individual
level to set concrete goals for
themselves that they want it and that
removed the effects.
And so that's one of the things I wanted
to talk to you about because you know,
among your listeners there are going to
be people of,
of all sorts who are drifting and,
and a lot of what I'm doing when I'm
talking to live audiences as an on
youtube is to,
is to tell people,
help people figure out how to get their
act together and aim at what they want.
But what it,
what seems to be the case is if you can
get men to sit down and think about how
they can take responsibility for what
they want in a way that would also
simultaneously benefit the community.
Their performance goes way up and their
quality of life improves and their
mental health improves.
And,
and I've got like hundreds of letters
now from people who have listened to the
lectures or done that program and said
that,
you know,
it's turned their life around and
stopped them from being nihilistic.
Stop them from wasting their time
constantly and doing foolish things and
set them on a path that they regard as
much as much more powerful.
That's the thing too,
it's,
it's not that,
the other thing that isn't taught to
young men now is that the reason you get
your act together so that you have power
and influence,
right?
So you get strong and indomitable and so
that nobody can get in your way.
And I don't mean that you become a cruel
monster.
Although being able to be a cruel
monster is actually extremely useful,
but doesn't mean you should be one.
But being able to be one is means that
you're no pushover and who you know,
you're,
what kind of man are you.
If you're a pushover,
you're hearing you're not good for
yourself or anyone else.
So anyway,
so that's been very exciting.
Yeah,
it sounds amazing.
The results are just like,
that's,
that's fantastic.
Like hearing that stuff.
And I,
and I totally understand that and it's
something that,
say for example,
it's something that I kind of would need
where I was even telling one of my
friends the other day that,
you know,
I'm like,
you will,
you'll,
you'll succeed much better,
especially if you have something mapped
out.
Like if you have it,
if you actually can physically see it,
if you not just like,
you know,
thinking about and you're bouncing all
over the place.
It's something that I've,
I would do a lot and say recently I've
been say,
okay,
I want to get better physically and
mentally,
especially physically.
And uh,
I've just been kind of all over the
place in war.
I was just like,
okay,
I need to sit down and I really need to
figure out what I'm going to do and I
need to,
I need to actually just write it out.
And this is,
this is the type of food I'm gonna eat.
This is all this legwork.
When I can actually see it.
Like it's so much,
it's easier to,
to just obtain,
it's so much easier to like,
it's,
it's not just,
I dunno,
like I always just feel like saying your
head,
you have so many thoughts.
So it's hard to just lock on to one
thing though when you can actually just
like focus on to something like that.
Um,
like this program that you have,
it sounds exactly what a lot of people
would need.
Sounds like something that like my,
my friend that I hang out with,
um,
like,
every week it sounds like something that
he can really benefit from.
So,
and I'm sure he'll watch this because he
actually does watch my channel.
He's like,
he's a good guy.
I think what I'll do is maybe what I'll
do is I'll set up a discount code for
your viewers and I'll send you that.
You can put it in the lake and your
youtube video link.
Oh,
definitely.
Yeah,
that would be good.
And I'll send you a couple of codes to,
and if you feel like,
if you,
if you're inclined to do the program,
if you're interested,
maybe we can have a conversation about
it after you're done.
Yeah,
I'll give it a shot,
man.
I mean,
I,
I'm sure I could benefit from it myself
if,
especially my,
my,
my audience knows how,
um,
how chaotic my life has been.
How,
um,
they,
they never know what setting I'm going
to have in the background because I move
around so much and I'm,
I mean,
I'm just,
I'm just trying to,
you know,
I'm,
I'm figuring things out as I go do and
I'm very open and honest,
so I never,
I don't know.
I never,
I never tried to hide the fact that I
just like,
oh,
I don't know what I'm doing.
I'm,
I'm getting pretty old.
I mean,
I'm not old,
but I mean it just to a standard of,
I shouldn't be bouncing from place to
place because I'm,
you know,
traditionally I should probably have my
own spot and,
and it should be completely focused in
and established.
And,
you know,
like I said,
I just,
so you've obviously latched onto
something.
I mean,
you've,
you've produced a pretty successful
youtube channel,
so how,
how,
how common,
how did you manage that?
Well,
it was,
um,
I,
I mean from a young age,
I always knew that I wanted to entertain
people.
Like I just didn't know exactly what I
thought it was going to be through music
because I always would play music.
I always,
uh,
you know,
started playing the guitar and the drums
and stuff.
And,
uh,
when I,
when I kind of reg recognize that that
wasn't really what I wanted to pursue
because of just the,
the independent,
like the independent thoughts and the
stuff that I want to do,
the visions that I have,
it's very hard to work with people,
especially when there was other people
have their own type of visions and
ambitions.
So when there was something like
Youtube,
oh,
when that became a thing,
um,
I started just,
just putting some stuff out there.
Like I actually,
I honestly thought I was going to be
like a gaming channel when I first
started the channel.
Um,
that was the first thing that I was
going to try to do,
especially since,
uh,
gamers were doing so well.
It's like I would love to be a part of
that community,
but when I saw,
um,
like I said,
free speech being threatened when I saw
a,
the thing that propped up like say in
2014,
ah,
Gamergate.
And,
um,
and,
and then there was all little where a
lot of these,
you know,
radical leftist,
we're,
we're going after things like metal and
saying that metal is sexist and stuff
like that.
Um,
and we need to,
we need to do something about it.
And,
and that's when I started just putting
out some content and people were
starting to listen.
And,
um,
it's no secret that it's no secret that
people,
a lot of people like to listen to me
because they think like I'm a breath of
fresh air.
It especially,
you know,
there's,
there's this,
there's a,
and there's a stigma,
um,
you know,
of,
of black Americans where people are so
shocked too that,
oh,
wow,
it's so nice to meet somebody that's not
x,
y,
z.
And you know,
it,
it sucks to say that it sucks to say
that,
but it's just,
it's just the truth.
I mean,
you know,
the,
the black men that I know in my area or
say that I've met and I've lived in say
south central Los Angeles just smack Dab
in the middle.
And it's just unfortunate.
It's an unfortunate community.
They're not really interested in like
say they can really benefit from a pro
the your program because they're,
they're just not interested in anything.
And a lot of people that I've met and
I've worked a bunch of different jobs
there,
they just,
they already,
they feel like they're,
they're doomed already.
Their,
their,
their destiny has already been set.
They are,
it's a terrible thing for people to say
because the world is full of more
possibility than people generally
realize.
And um,
you know,
here's a couple of things that are,
that are interesting in that regard.
So you,
you may or may not deal with it.
I've done a lot of work on the
psychology of religion.
And one of the things I did was look
into the origin of the word sin.
And strangely enough,
so the word sin means essentially to
violate the sacred moral code,
something like that.
And you can think about that is breaking
a rule,
but that's not exactly the right way to
think about it because sometimes it's a
sin not to break a rule.
You know,
if the rule is is,
is unjust or,
or tyrannical or outdated or blind,
then it's up to you to break the damn
rule and to suffer the consequences.
And so to sit and means more to go
against your own spirit and to violate
your own spirit and to violate your own,
your own proper motive being,
you know,
to not to be true to yourself.
And it's actually derived from a Greek
word and the word is
[inaudible]. [inaudible] and [inaudible]
is an archery term and it means to miss
the center of the target.
And so in my,
in my role as a clinical psychologist,
I'm always dealing with helping people.
Uh,
you might think what I'm doing is curing
mental illness,
but that's,
I don't think that's really what I'm
doing.
What I'm doing is helping people get
their lives together.
And lots of people come to me not
because they have mental illness big
because they have very,
very complicated lives.
They have,
their families are fractured or,
and they're under extreme societal
pressure and they're,
you know,
they have economic trouble and maybe
they're sick and like life is hard on
them and they have real problems.
And what we try to do is to figure out
what the target is and then figure out
how they can hit it.
And I can tell you a couple of reasons
why people fail.
And one reason is is that they don't
ever define what constitutes success.
So they never even aim at the target.
And my experience has been,
if you specify a target intelligently,
like he can't,
you don't want to shoot your Arrow at a
target that's 50 miles away that you
can't see,
you're not going to hit it.
You have to put a target that's pretty
close and then it's sort of within your
skill level.
But most of the time if you set up a
target property and you practice,
you can hit it.
And so the idea that people have that
they're do from the outset.
That's,
that's true.
If you believe it.
And I know,
and I'm,
I'm not trying to say that that life is
equally difficult for everyone and you
should just pull up your socks and get
at it.
I'm not saying that because I know full
well that that's not true,
but you can overcome a tremendous amount
of,
uh,
opposition.
You can,
you can defeat a very,
very powerful set of adversaries if
you're locked onto goal that you truly
value and that and that you've thought
through and articulate it.
And writing that down does really help
as you observe before the psychological
literature on that is very clear.
So I would say don't,
don't make the mistake of assuming that
your life is doomed without putting that
theory thoroughly to the test.
And you know,
the other problem with that idea,
and this is something that goes along
with nihilism,
is that you might say,
well,
it's,
it's pointless and I'm doomed and the
world is against me.
It's like,
yeah,
the problem is that also gives you an
excuse not to take any responsibility.
And maybe that's the underground reason
why you're,
why you're saying that you're doomed and
that everything is stacked against you.
You know,
that,
and that's not to say that there aren't
structural inequalities and all of that
because obviously there are so,
yeah.
And,
um,
and that's something that I 100% agree
with you.
I think that,
but I think,
yeah,
I think leaning more towards,
I think there's a lot of people that
just try to opt out and they then,
you know,
they don't want to take any
responsibility.
I think there's a bigger influence of
that where there are clearly there are
clear cut examples of,
of people just thriving,
you know,
um,
through the,
the worst of circumstances.
I made this video called message to
millennials at,
at New Year's around New Year's.
And that got to be very popular.
And I think it was,
I think I made the future,
I think I talked about the future
authoring program in that video,
but one of the things I had thought
about was I thought it would be comical
and this was after I came across you,
I thought it would be comical if I could
run a discount code for the future
authoring for black guys,
but I didn't know how I would do that.
But what's the demographics of your,
of your,
of your viewership,
do you know like who watches you?
There's a very small amount of,
my demographic normally is like say a
Caucasian male of course.
And because of that there's a,
there are some,
some black dudes that just don't even
want to,
that,
you know,
they want to call me a coon or an uncle
tom or whatever.
And they're saying that I'm catering to
the due to the white man and all this.
And
why do they say that though?
Because I mean like why is,
why is that,
why is that something that would be
directed against you?
Because that seems like a,
like it's a curious kind of insult,
you know,
I mean I understand being insulted,
I get insulted,
but you,
your,
you have to wonder sometimes why it's
that particular kind of insult that gets
directed against someone.
So why do you think that's being,
why are you,
why are you being put down in that
particular way?
I just feel like,
I feel like it's there.
I feel like there's a lot of people that
are just being told to think that way.
I don't,
I don't think genuinely because I never
really had that issue.
Um,
I,
I really didn't have that issue growing
up with,
um,
with like say when I would be in a,
in a,
in the black community.
Um,
there were a lot of them because there
were some people that just like,
say for example,
that maybe grew up in a private school a
little bit and they had a diff,
a little bit of a different start.
Maybe they're an empty vessel and they
were just able to just have like books,
like just literature and it didn't
really grow up on TV and stuff.
And that's kind of how I got my start.
And then from there I just kind of
entered the public spirit of,
of school and everything.
And so most people were pretty cool with
me.
But then as I started to gain a little
bit of notoriety,
I started to notice that there's,
there's quite a few people that,
and I'm like,
where are you getting this thought
process from where I'm,
I'm,
I'm like a trader or I am a coon if I
don't,
if I'm not exactly like you,
if I'm not like say you know,
the stereotypical bt black guy that's
just only exclusively into hip hop,
you know,
I like,
I love listening to hip hop,
but you know,
I also actually like,
um,
metal a lot more.
And because of that thing,
it's like,
oh,
you're,
you're a,
you're whitewashed or you're this.
And I'm like,
why?
Why?
Like why,
why are we,
he
seems particularly dopey to think of you
as a sellout because you've made
yourself a presence on youtube.
It's not like anybody's handed that to
you on a silver platter.
It was just something,
I mean,
that sort of thing is open to anyone.
And,
and we're in the wild west frontier days
of youtube and you built yourself a
following,
pretty much of your own accord.
So I don't see,
I,
I mean it's to obviously some of it's
got to be to do with resentment and
jealousy.
You'd say that because that sort of
thing that generally drives insults.
Right.
But I saw the same,
similar thing happening.
I thought it was very distressing at
that free speech rally that we talked
about.
There was a kid there who now works for
rebel media,
Nikki opion guy and he's pretty dark
and pretty articulate,
you know,
and,
and now he's cut himself a good career
with rebel media,
which is pretty funny.
But,
um,
when he was speaking at the open mic,
because it was an open,
open mic session,
the woman who founded black lives matter
in Toronto was standing about 12 feet
away from him.
And she yelled coon Adam about a times
and I thought,
well,
she's,
she's someone I have who I think is
almost utterly contemptible and yeah.
And,
and because her,
her behavior generally speaking is
beyond reprehensible.
But I thought that was,
I thought that was a remarkable thing
for her to be doing.
Absolutely.
Jaw droppingly appalling things to think
to do.
But I was also curious about why that
particular insult.
What does that mean to her?
I mean,
I,
I wonder that myself.
Um,
I wonder that myself,
especially because like reading up from
my understanding of what a coon actually
is and what a coon,
uh,
used to be was kind of like the,
was kind of like the whole,
uh,
the,
the shucking and jiving term where you
had to like turn on,
you had to like put on like a,
a show to entertain,
you know,
the,
the masses or whatever.
You had to,
you had to like,
you know,
um,
for example,
be very stereotypical,
like say a lot of people that,
a lot of people in the black community,
the ones that are calling people a black
people like me,
a coon or kind of,
they're actually the ones that are at
koons themselves.
Actually,
the Wa the way that I'm like,
yeah.
And it's like hate you mean?
Yeah.
And it's like,
dude,
it's so,
it's so embarrassing to see how like the
descent that I get on my channel,
I get a lot of,
um,
valid criticism from people.
Sometimes they'll,
they'll tear me a new ae because
sometimes I'm just,
you know,
I deserve it.
Sometimes I deserve it.
But when it comes to like,
um,
black people,
usually the ones that are,
you can visibly see their thumbnails and
avatars.
It's just,
it's,
I actually feel very disappointed
because it's usually just an ad hominem.
It's usually Kuhn and it's usually sell
out.
I can just do the keyword search and,
and um,
search Koonin they see you as somebody
joking around because I was,
I made a video like about a year ago or
something just called like Hashtag
[inaudible] Macoun just basically
embracing it,
kind of showing me,
I don't really,
I don't really buckle.
I don't,
I really don't care.
Like the Ad Hominem attacks and just,
just petty insults.
It,
it does not affect me at,
at whatsoever.
So that was actually,
um,
I,
I was supposed to make a shirts and
everything like that,
but I kind of got a little bit behind.
Um,
but yeah,
just kind of showing people that,
hey,
it's,
you know,
whatever,
just let that just slide off of you.
And,
um,
it's,
that's all,
that's all they have.
And I,
I just,
it does kind of break my heart a little
bit.
I feel like,
say,
I would hope that I would be somewhat
of,
um,
like of an example of,
hey,
you know,
it's not,
it's not hopeless.
Like you can,
you know,
it's,
it's stop,
stop talking about systemic racism and,
and saying that it,
you know,
chopping a doomsayer and try to better
yourself,
you know,
try to,
if you're,
if you're living in a bad situation,
how,
how can you get yourself out of it?
I always use my mother as an example
where she talks about just,
um,
all this stuff that she went through.
She went through a lot of stuff.
And,
and to be able to,
uh,
raise two kids and,
you know,
put us,
uh,
give us a good start in private school,
private elementary and,
and then on,
and then I went to public school
afterwards.
But I had,
it just gave me a huge advantage to
where my mind felt incredibly stimulated
to the point where I remember doing
like,
uh,
fractions and taxes when I was in first
grade.
Uh,
dealing with those type of things that
were,
it was very typical that the time.
But now like very useful to the point
where,
hey,
I do my own taxes,
I don't have any problems with that.
And like people are always like,
oh,
I don't know what to do.
I've got to pay somebody some money.
And I'm like,
Nah,
dude.
What?
I think also the insults,
like there's a,
there's a,
there's a kind of,
there's a kind of challenge that's
associated with them too.
So if someone,
like if you're involved in a particular
worldview and someone comes up who
actually challenges that either by what
they say or what they do,
the first thing you're going to do
because you don't want to recalibrate
your entire belief system is you're
going to throw horrible things at them
and see if any of them stick.
And so I guess partly what happens is
that,
and I'm in,
I mean I've been insulted in that way as
well because people have called me a
bigot and,
and it turns than up.
And uh,
I was protected against that to some
degree I think because I'd already put
500 hours of videos online.
And so if I was any of those
reprehensible things,
people probably could have found that
out pretty quickly by going through the
material that I put online because I
every,
almost every word I've uttered to
students in the last five years has been
recorded and is publicly accessible.
So if there was anything in what I was
saying or what I believe that was
actually,
it actually deserved that kind of a
derogatory classification,
then it would be found out very rapidly.
But it's also the case,
I think that people,
when they throw those sorts of things
that you,
there's a part of them that's hoping
that you can withstand it and tell them
exactly why they're wrong.
Just on the off chance that you're the
real thing.
And so you know,
you're,
you've got a certain amount of success
that you generated yourself.
And so people are going to say,
well you sold out and then they're going
to sit back and watch and see what you
say is like,
well,
I said he's sold out.
Maybe it's true,
but maybe he can defend himself too.
So it's sort of like people will throw
the worst that they can at you and see
if you can withstand it.
And that's part of the way they test to
see if they actually should pay any
attention to you.
And so,
so how come,
how come you're able to let the insults,
let's say,
why do you,
why do they,
I mean they must bother you to some
degree,
but they don't bother you that much and
you don't let them stop you.
And why is that?
Well,
it's the only thing like that,
that the only thing that bothers me is
like say the insults when it,
when it comes to,
especially when it comes out,
when it's race related,
the ones that bother me are the ones
that like say when it comes from,
when black people in general,
the ones that I would cause feel like
say my content could help out.
Uh,
some,
some black Americans.
I've made some videos about saying,
you know,
stop basically stop just thinking that
they're,
the world's against you.
Stop just thinking that uh,
United States is this a systemic,
a systemic racist system in 2017 or
whatever.
And you can't,
there's just no point of trying,
like,
stop telling your children that,
you know,
like give them a,
give them a boost.
I would think that they would help me
out.
So that's the only time when,
when they say stuff to me like that
everybody else,
um,
I've been on the Internet for so long
that people are just going to talk and
say some of the worst things.
And most times they would never say it
to your face.
They would never,
most people,
now it's starting to,
but now I'm starting to see a shift
though,
especially from looking at the protest
and,
and the speeches that you were trying to
give him and when people are trying to
shut them down,
what I'm seeing is what normally used to
just be fantasy becoming reality and
like in the,
in the entire spectrum where like say if
you've ever,
I don't know if you've ever actually
been on tumbler.com I don't know if
you've actually logged on there,
but see a lot of tumbler at all.
Yeah,
it is.
Um,
I would say that a lot of stuff that you
hear nowadays,
like when you hear about gendered
pronouns diseaser and all the weird
things that are coming up foot and the
other Ken and,
um,
people just being just mean and just
nasty to a lot of that stuff.
I would see that was tumbler.
Like I've never heard of any type of,
you know,
a hundred different type of,
uh,
pronouns until,
ah,
tumblr and I don't know what this was
like the safe space for them,
I guess.
And now do you think Tumblr is like
that?
Why do you think that's focused there?
I've,
I've wondered that myself.
um,
I,
I have a friend that I was,
I respect her greatly,
but she's one of those people that,
that,
you know,
uh,
changes her name and her and her
pronouns and this and that and had a
boyfriend that,
um,
you know,
he has a beard and stuff,
but he's like,
call me.
She,
and I'm like,
okay,
I'm sure.
Um,
but,
and I'm trying to figure out like what,
where I can't find the root and,
and seeing like his was there like a
giant presence or maybe a public figure
that maybe started talking about these
ideas because I don't know,
the only thing,
that earliest thing that I could really
find,
I remember like say back in 2011 I
started seeing a trend happened in Texas
where it was being wolves.
Those were on that twilight movies.
This,
the twilight started to come out.
Maybe it was even younger because I
think the toilets were,
yeah,
it came out a while ago on the movies.
But um,
I started seeing that a bunch of people
are starting to dress like wolves or
putting tails on and all these things.
And I was starting to see stuff like
that and maybe it was just the pop
culture,
things like that.
We're making it socially acceptable.
And then it started to be discussed on
forums and everything.
And then maybe tomorrow.
I don't know how it became the,
the,
the ground zero,
but it seems like that for me and now
it's just being translated into
academia.
Like your,
you're starting.
Okay.
So That's interesting because you know,
one of the things I've wondered about
with all this identity
transformation,
and this includes not only the sort of
gender let's call it play that you're
talking about,
but also that other kin,
uh,
universe,
it looks a lot to me like the sort of
fantasy play that's characteristic of
kids when they were about ages say from
about four to about nine or maybe four
to 11,
you know,
that that would be the,
the,
the maximal extent of it.
And I wonder to some degree if what's
happening is that because,
because I don't think that modern kids
get enough chance to engage in fantasy
play.
Like,
like pretend play like they did 30 or 40
years ago,
that maybe that was,
that's been pushed aside by,
by mass media.
It's being pushed aside by computers and
video games.
It's been pushed aside by cell phones.
And it's also less common because
children's play is so structured now,
partly because they don't have very many
siblings and play dates are set up in
kids' lives are hyper structured.
And so kids have to go through that
pretend play period.
And I'm wondering if maybe because we've
suppressed that in our society,
if it's blossoming out in universities
when kids get away from their parents
and can start to experiment with their
own identity,
if they,
if they're doing that through uh,
in,
uh,
because it looks like pretend play.
I'm going to pretend to be a boy.
I'm going to pretend to be a girl.
I'm going to pretend to be an animal.
I'm going to pretend to be a war wolf.
It's fantasy play and there's a lot of
objection when people say,
well,
I'm not going to play your game.
You can play your game,
but I'm not going you,
you don't have any right to compel me to
play your game.
But it may be that there's a
developmental impulse that's being
manifest there that didn't get its
chance to express itself at the proper
stage of development.
Something like that is it really is
strange.
It is.
And I,
I,
I feel like there definitely is some
type of correlation because when you,
when,
when I was,
when I was a kid and when know we're
going out,
we were like,
oh,
I was just,
I'm old enough to where we didn't have
any type of a technology other than like
say the Super Nintendo was,
was like,
oh,
this is amazing.
And I'm,
no,
I would take the bus.
I can only think kids can do this
anymore.
Just take public transportation.
I'll be back by sundown.
I would go to another shitty,
sometimes I'll just go ride my bike and
me and my friends would have like
missions.
We would do crazy stuff hugely.
Like,
um,
I wish I recorded some of this stuff so
I can remember it.
But my point is that yeah,
definitely kids don't have anything like
that.
And like you said,
the,
with the mass media,
with a,
with the video games,
as much as I love video games,
there is so much structure that you
can't really,
you can't really branch out and really
create the,
you're very limited to what you can do.
Even when like bdo games when you can
like create a character and stuff.
Sometimes that's as far as it can go,
but you're still kind of limited to
where you,
where you can,
you,
you can't fantasize.
It's why I say I still like,
I still love reading books because you
can just,
you create your own world in it.
And then sometimes if somebody has read
the same book,
you can compare and contrast and be
like,
how do you see this character?
Even though if sometimes they describe
them,
you'll still have an imagery of how they
look.
And I think that
boy,
because I think what happened in part
was that,
you know,
kids engage in pretend play when they're
too young to read,
but then when they start reading
fiction,
they are still engaging in pretend play
because they have to imagine the
characters.
Whereas in movies and in video games to
characters are basically put forth for
them and that,
and that there's utility in that because
there,
there can be additional structure but
the law,
but the problem is,
is that additional structure also stops
you from having to use your imagination.
And it's,
it's through your imagination that you
experiment with all the different things
that you could be.
And maybe that's just being pushed later
into development now.
And that's why the young people are so
outraged when you,
when you violate their there pretend
identity,
you know,
they look like kids playing to me except
that they're really,
they're too old to be doing that.
Yeah.
I mean,
and that's where,
and that's why it's so,
it's so absurd to me that say something
like,
uh,
see 16 it could even be like,
pastor did that.
There's even a need for it that there's,
because like you said,
it does seem like make believe and
pretend and it's like,
how are you taking,
how can you take this seriously?
How could you take this seriously and,
and,
and what's happening?
It also seems like such a,
a major,
uh,
regression,
like something that you're trying to
hammer down on,
like say on free speech,
you can get in trouble by misusing
someone's pronouns.
And then now,
um,
recently,
uh,
m one oh three motion the motion has
been brought up and um,
what has been going on with in one word
in one or three?
Have you been keeping up with that?
Oh yeah.
Well,
well,
one of the things that's happening
that's really interesting is that,
um,
as far as I'm concerned,
so I'm going to do a couple of lecture
series or a lecture series in the next
year and I'm starting in May.
And what I want to do is start at the
beginning of the Bible and talk about
the psychological significance of all
the stories right from the beginning to
the end.
But I also,
and this is something I,
my Patriot patrion funding is helping me
with this.
And then there's something else that I
want to do in parallel,
which is that I started talking to a
group of moderate Muslims about a week
and a half ago while and some a couple
of months ago.
Very,
very smart people and very committed and
they want to put forth,
uh,
they want to start the process of
describing what a reformed and moderate
Islam might be.
And so,
and I think that's the right way to go
with regards to the tension that exists
between the West and the Islamic world
or even within Canada,
between,
there isn't a lot of tension in Canada.
Yeah,
I'm about anything really.
But to the degree that there is tension,
what needs to be done between new
immigrant communities and the
communities that they're integrated to
obviously is for a dialogue of consensus
to be B to b started.
And hopefully that I'm going to engage
in that.
And that's the proper way to fight
Islamophobia.
But the,
the current government insisted that
this motion,
which is,
it's not a bill,
it's just a,
it's emotion,
which is a expression of commitment on
the part of parliament to go and study,
uh,
um,
an issue or to make a moral stance on an
issue.
And they described
the concern with the emergent
Islamophobia and the opposition parties
in Canada complained about the
specifications of Islam in this,
in the wording of this motion and said,
well,
look,
we can,
we will all support an Auntie prejudice
and anti harassment and
antidiscrimination motion cross
religions,
no problem.
But if you use that word Islamophobia
specifically,
we're not going to support it.
And so they offered to the,
to the current government the
possibility of unanimous consent for the
motion,
but the originators of the bill wouldn't
withdraw the wording,
which I thought was absolutely appalling
because Islamophobia is a really,
it's not a good word,
stress ball.
It takes a medical term phobia and uses
it politically,
which is really a treacherous and sneaky
thing to do.
And second,
it specifies a specific religion when
there's no evidence that that religion
is being specifically targeted.
I mean it might,
there's no real evidence in Canada that
the adherence of that religion or
suffering from any more discrimination
then the adherence of other minority
religions or even the adherence of,
of so called majority religions.
So it was a very bad idea.
But,
and so I,
I think just other approach is better.
And so my I publicly opposed m one oh
three a with a certain amount of the
fact because I'd be talking to the
people who,
who are running for the leadership of
the official opposition in Canada,
the Conservative Party.
And I've talked to a number of them
about [inaudible] three and about also
we shoes of responsibility among young
men because the conservatives finally
have something to sell at young people
and they never have it for the first
time in the history of,
of conservatism during my lifetime
anyways.
The Conservatives have something to sell
to young people and that's
responsibility.
And so we've also been talking a lot
about that.
But,
um,
so,
so there was some opposition to I'm one
or three and I think the proper way to,
to progress with that too,
to reduce the tension between the
Islamic world in general but also
Islamic newcomers in Canada and,
and longer term Canadians is to engage
in a dialogue with moderate people.
And I hope that that's going to get off
the ground.
We've,
we've got the ball rolling in some very
people already on board.
We've got the ball rolling for that and
I hope I'm going to play a role in that.
So that would be really exciting.
It would be really fun to do that in
parallel with this biblical series.
So,
cause then I can,
I can approach the fundamental stories
of,
of Judaism and Christianity at the same
time as engaging in a public discussion
about the meaning of Islam and the
implications of Islamic belief for,
for,
for the broader political culture.
So that's an exciting opportunity.
No doubt about it.
Yeah,
that sounds great.
And it sounds like a great way to go
about it too.
If you can do those things
simultaneously,
especially he's still,
there can be any talk about like,
oh,
he's just a criticizing Islam or,
or,
or whatever.
When you also,
you're just,
you're,
you're talking about just religion and
that kind of across the board,
you know,
and I'm trying to understand it.
Yeah.
And I think a lot of people are too,
and I think that's kind of like what's
so frustrating about what's been
happening and things like say in one or
three even like existing or say
something for quite some time on,
on youtube that just,
there are certain words that if you put
it in your title,
your tags,
like your video would be demonetized.
They're saying it's advertiser,
it is an advertiser friendly.
And you know,
sometimes you wouldn't even be saying
anything harsh.
I like say sometimes they'll say,
I would just love to have an honest and
open dialect about Islam because I think
there's a lot of people that don't
understand it.
Now there was a lot of people that are
just like,
oh,
all Muslims are this.
And I've seen quite a few people that
are like that.
I'm like,
wow,
I think we need to talk about this.
And,
and people don't want to talk about it
because people that were full time,
you're not gonna make any money off of
it.
And it sucks.
Like,
I feel like it's such more of a
important issue that I would just,
I wouldn't like say I put out a video,
um,
this just talking about what happened in
London not too long ago,
just because I,
and I knew it was going to do monetize
my,
like,
why not?
I want to just at least put it out there
and just saying,
can we,
can we talk about this?
Can we,
can we be honest and say that there's
definitely some type of issues.
And like on both sides,
there's,
there's just,
um,
you know,
there's a lack of communication and I
think,
yeah,
what you're,
what you're gonna do is,
is fantastic because it's,
it's desperately needed.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well,
you know,
I'm fortunate because last April when I
set up my patron account,
which was way before this political
political issue exploded,
I did it mostly out of curiosity because
you know,
I was making,
I would say,
fairly low quality videos from a
production perspective.
I was just using an ipad on a,
on a tripod.
Okay.
I was just using an ipad on a tripod and
I thought,
well,
maybe I could,
you know,
I,
by that time I'd had about a million
views.
And I thought,
wow,
that's,
that's a lot,
man.
If I wrote a book that sold a million
copies,
I'd be dancing a jig out on the street.
So I was starting to take youtube
seriously because I thought,
I thought about it for a while and I
thought,
well,
oh,
I see what's happening.
This is,
this is like a Gutenberg revolution.
It's the first time in human history
where the spoken word has as much reach
as a book and as much permanency.
And that's a whole new thing,
man.
And,
and it's way faster than a book.
Like you can,
as you know,
you can.
Well,
this video we're making right now,
we can have this published and in front
of an audience,
an immense audience,
and attract a couple of hundred thousand
viewers within a few days.
It's unparalleled.
And so I thought,
oh,
I'll set up a patriot and account
because that was a new thing too.
And because I was,
I've been really curious about how
creative people can monetize what
they're doing and it's very difficult.
And so I was looking into that and I
found Patriot and I thought,
well I'll set up a patriot account,
see what happened.
But I was fortunate because I decided
not to use advertiser generated revenue
on Youtube.
I decided to use patron and I didn't
know it at the time,
but that also made me more or less
immune to threats of such things as
demonetization,
which is,
which is a form of,
it's not exactly a form of censorship,
it's more,
it's more like,
it's more like an attempt to turn the,
the tremendous diversity of music on
youtube into elevator music.
Right.
It can be contentious because then you
can't sell advertising on it.
Well,
if it's not contentious.
And interesting.
No one's going to watch it.
So it's a,
it's a suicide move in some sense on the
part of the advertisers because if they
sanitize youtube,
then all that's going to happen is
another,
another free speech video site is going
to pop up and people are all gonna flock
there in no time flat.
Like it's longterm suicidal move.
But um,
but there are ways to protect yourself
against it.
Um,
and,
and Patriot on seems to be an
interesting way of doing that.
How many,
how many youtube videos have you had?
Demonetized
um,
I've had,
I've,
luckily I haven't had too many,
I probably had a total of like six.
And um,
the,
the ones that,
the main ones that have been demonetized
where the were pretty old and I wasn't
really going to generate any money for
them anyways.
So it was,
and however,
this month,
um,
I've had one of them that was one of my
better videos,
the,
or at least it did better.
And it was the one about,
um,
the,
the attack in London and that was
immediately to monetize.
And I was just like,
well,
okay,
fine.
And then another one,
because because of,
um,
the whole ad hysteria with a bunch of
the companies pulling out,
they started to crack down a little bit
harder.
And they am,
I responded to,
there's this company called Mike and
they just still put out a bunch of
nonsense.
Like a lot of people are starting to
pull back a little bit on their social
justice warrior,
ultra progressive nonsense,
but they're still pushing on.
And they had a video called things by
people killed in 2016 and we're just
like a bunch of trends,
right?
A dancing moves and all this stuff
saying that if why people do it,
it's,
you know,
it's cringy a,
and I'm,
and it's still,
you know,
just being,
it's only true for nerdy white people.
It's right.
I mean,
that's really what it comes down to
like,
but like,
I mean,
and it comes out even like say,
I mean just nerdy people in general when
you see people dance or do something
that just have no rhythm,
it's just so cringey but you just can't
look,
you get the secondhand embarrassment.
Right.
And um,
but yeah,
they just put out some ridiculous stuff.
So I reacted to that and that video did
very well and that got demonetized
recently,
so I'm like,
oh great.
So I'm not going to get anything from
that anymore.
One last thing I want to ask you because
people really wanted to know,
uh,
what is your opinion on pineapple pizza
as a topping?
Um,
well a pineapple is upon you hate,
you hate pizza.
I used to work at a pizza restaurant and
I learned was that you actually have a
lifetime maximum of pizza ingestion and
once you hit that,
you can't actually eat any more pizza.
And so I hit that when I was about 16
cause I worked in a pizza restaurant for
about four years.
And so I ate my 10000th pizza and that
was like,
oh,
that's it,
man.
There was something about the spice.
I think it might be a Reagan know that
that specific spice that I don't like,
and so even covering it up with
pineapple,
that would improve it,
but it still makes it really difficult
for me to eat pizza.
All right.
Fair enough.
Sounds good.
All right.
I'm Dr. Peterson.
Thank you so much for taking the time
out of your,
I'm sure your insanely busy schedule to
talk to me,
man.
It's been an absolute honor and it was
real fun and I like your channel and I
wish you the best of luck,
truly,
and I hope you,
I hope you get yourself oriented and,
and knock 'em dead.
Good.
Most definitely,
man.
Thanks again.
I appreciate it all.
All right.
Bye.