Okay.
Hi everyone.
Back on February 20th I announced that I
was going to go to 12 different cities
in North America and talk about my new
book,
12 rules for life and a variety of other
things,
and so we arranged theaters and put
those tickets up for sale and they've
proved very popular.
I did the first one this week on Sunday
in New York at the beacon theater to an
audience of about 3000 people and it
seemed to go very well.
The consequence of that is that I'm now
announcing another 20 cities and this is
the video to make that announcement.
I'm also appearing as a guest with
several other speakers,
including Matt Dillahunty,
Sam Harris,
a number of times,
and also Sam Harrison,
Douglas Murray,
and so the announcements for those who
will be included in the description of
this video as well.
All these talks are going to occur from
may through June,
and I'll just list the cities.
You can get the cities and the dates
below.
Toronto,
Washington,
Chicago,
Detroit,
Denver,
San Francisco,
Seattle,
London,
Toronto,
Boston,
Philadelphia,
and Houston,
Dallas,
Austin,
and Phoenix.
Rick Jeevak,
Washington and Richmond.
Charlotte,
Nashville and Atlanta,
Louisville,
Indianapolis,
and Milwaukee,
Minneapolis,
Seattle,
and Vancouver.
That's twice with Sam Harris,
Portland,
Sacramento,
and San Diego,
Long Beach,
thousand oaks,
and finally Dublin with Sam Harris and
Douglas Murray.
I've done about 10 of these talks
already.
Three in London,
one announced her damn one in La,
San Francisco,
Vancouver,
Toronto,
and New York.
I've really looked forward to them and
it's a real privilege to be able to
speak about important issues pertaining
to psychological development with an
enthusiastic and involved crowd.
And I hope that the lectures are useful
and,
and
that there is useful for the people that
I'm speaking with as they are engaging
and worthwhile for me.
So if you'd like to buy a ticket,
then I'd like to see you there.
And I look forward to seeing you in your
hometown in May and June.
So thanks very much for your continued
support.
I hope we get a chance to have a
meaningful and productive evening in the
very near future.
Bye.