As I've mentioned to you before,
each of the three aspects of experience.
So the things you know,
the things you don't know and the fact
of yourself have a very ambivalent
underlying structure,
both positive and negative so that the
things you don't know are interesting
and compelling and the sources of new
information,
but also the source of the things that
undermine you both physically and
mentally.
And the things that you know,
of course your culture disciplines you
and shapes you into a full person but
also at exactly the same time molds you
and crushes you in a particular
direction rather than any of the other
directions you might have gone in.
And then finally,
with regards to the individual,
we spent a substantial amount of time
discussing the individual's capability,
capacity to make order out of chaos and,
and sometimes to make chaos out of order
in the service of a higher order.
And that's all to the good.
But just like culture and nature have
there negative aspects.
So did the individual,
and I think personally this is where
Christian mythology in particular comes
into its own.
I think of all the major religions,
Christianity has the most thoroughly
developed what you might describe as
formal model of evil.
And that model isn't part of the
canonical writings of Christianity,
say encapsulated in the Bible,
but part of the cloud of sort of natural
mythology and storytelling that
surrounds the canonical writings.
So you could say that although
Christianity and Buddhism have spent a
substantial amount of time developing up
a representation of the hero,
Christianity in particular has also
spent a substantial amount of time
developing a formal portrait of the
figure that stands in opposition to the
hero.
And I think the most appropriate term
for that figure who takes multiple forms
in mythology is the adversary.
Because
the adversarial spirit is a spirit that
stands in opposition to everything
stands in opposition to nature,
stands in opposition to culture,
and most specifically stands in
opposition to that aspect of the human
being.
That's both exploratory and creative.
Now,
the last time we talked,
I had a chance to describe to you how
the figures of the adversarial brothers
emerge naturally at the end of genesis
as a,
as a Coda to this story.
Right?
Adam and eve developed self
consciousness.
They develop knowledge of their own
mortality and death.
And as the primordial parents of
humanity,
their first children take the form of
the hostile brothers,
which is to say that if you're the child
of nature and the child of culture,
the sort of ultimate parents,
then as an individual,
you take two forms,
a positive form in a negative form,
and the negative form is characterized
in many ways by a kind of absolute
hatred of the good hatred of the
positive form.
And I think that you can't understand
the full human propensity for evil
without considering more than the
territory allity more than the innate
territoriality of human being.
So if you look at animals,
well,
animals are territorial and they fight
to preserve their territory,
and it's a rational struggle.
They're fighting for resources and for a
place that they can,
that they can operate in,
live in and reproducing inefficiently.
But human beings are substantively
different from that in that they're
agonistic conflict.
Their aggression often seems to be
motivated by something more akin to the
pure desire for destruction rather than
for any rational land whatsoever.
And so from that perspective,
I would say as an example,
the fact that Hitler ended up committing
suicide in a bunker beneath Germany's
capital at the end of the Second World
War when Berlin was in flames,
when all of Germany was in flames and
when his country was completely defeated
after tens of millions of people had
died in the conflict,
including of course the 7 million or so
people that were killed in the
Holocaust,
the normal mode of interpretation of
that would be what a terrible defeat for
Hitler,
but an equally valid and I think an
equally valid prime of facie argument.
And one I think that's actually more
valid is that it wasn't a defeat for
Hitler at all.
It was precisely what he was aiming at
right from the beginning because his
mode of being was intensely adversarial.
And I would also say that it's certainly
possible that the full nature of his
motivations weren't even necessarily
clear to him as they unfolded across
time during the Second World War.
No more than the full motivations of any
human being are necessarily accessible
to them as they act out,
whatever it is that they act out.
So Carl Young says,
for example,
that we,
we act out great mythological stories.
That doesn't necessarily mean you know
the story.
It just means you act it out.
So for example,
you see people whose lives are
repetitive bouts of tragedy and what
they're acting out is a tragic story,
and they know it in so far as they're
actually acting it out,
but they don't necessarily have an
explicit model of the relationship
between their patterns of behavior in
the constantly tragic outcomes they
produce.
Well,
that doesn't even necessarily mean that
what they're doing isn't voluntary
because things can be voluntary,
even if you don't understand them fully.
There's an aspect to the human psyche
that's a nest of vipers,
so to speak,
because you can't necessarily trust what
you see.
And that means not only when you're
looking at someone else say,
but even when you're looking in the
mirror,
you can't be sure that what you say
you're doing is exactly what you're
doing.
Your motivations aren't transparent and
they may not even be clear.
So I suppose the idea that lurks behind
this formalization is that freedom of
choice is such a good that one of its
subsidiary necessities,
which is that there has to be a polar
distinction between good and evil is
worth having.
Freedom is so important that it
justifies the distinction between good
and evil.
And I think that our,
I think that's a reasonable way to
presume
it's reasonable to presume that that's
the manner in which experience is
actually structured.
And there's complex reasons for that.
One would be that under the most optimal
circumstances,
which is something we'll talk about as
this proceeds to a close,
that means in a sense you can have your
cake and eat it too,
which means the potential existence of
good and evil allows for freedom of
choice.
And then if the choice is always towards
the good,
then you have the benefits of freedom of
choice plus the benefits of the good.
The only price you have to pay is the
constant possibility of evil.
It's very much like the structure of
Christianity,
so you have the highest God whose whose
highest son is Christ,
but you have the figure of the Satan
lurking in the background who's also got
a filial relationship with the highest
God.
It makes for a confusing kind of
theology because in many situations,
of course,
Christ is identified specifically with
God the father,
but Satan always lurks in the background
and his,
his existential status is indeterminate
because since God is everything,
then it's very difficult to make the
case that the evil spirit isn't a
derivative of God.
It's not easy thing to get straightened
out rationally.
And I think Milton in paradise lost does
a very good attempt,
makes a very good attempt to explain
exactly what this might mean,
how there could be an overarching
transcendent power.
And there could be two subordinate
elements to that.
One evil in one good without destroying
the idea that God as such as good and
without eradicating the reality of evil,
very,
very complex argument to make.
Now the notion of evil is also very,
very complex idea.
So if you look at our arguments that,
uh,
support atheism,
and I've mentioned some of these like
Ivan's argument in the brothers
Karamazov where Ivan says,
wow,
the world and as such experiences such
must be evil because it's predicated on
the blood of innocence,
the suffering of children.
The fact that there's vast injustices in
the world is indicative that there's no
such thing as a good God or to speak and
less personified terms is evidence that
the structure of experience as such is
an untenable morally.
It shouldn't be because it's predicated
on suffering.
Jeffrey Burton Russell,
who's written a whole series of books on
the nature of evil.
It makes a very clear distinction
between different categories of terrible
events that I hit.
I think help bring this into clarity,
so imagine this,
imagine first that it's useful to make a
distinction between tragedy and evil.
Okay?
Now,
tragedy is when the bad befalls the good
and earthquake is tragic,
so or diseases tragic.
Now it's easy to regard a disease or an
earthquake as evil as well,
but the problem with that is that
doesn't seem to be any motivation to it,
and so it's more likely,
it's more reasonable to think something
like,
well,
people are vulnerable.
They have to be vulnerable in order to
give existence a viewpoint.
One of the consequences of their
vulnerability is that they're
susceptible to tragedy.
Okay?
If their vulnerability is a precondition
for being,
then the fact that they're susceptible
to tragedy isn't necessarily an evil.
It's just a consequence of their
limitation.
Then you say,
well,
what constitutes evil if you can't put
earthquakes and diseases and so forth
into that category?
Well,
there didn't seem to be something more
dependent on choice,
which is the argument that Elliot is
making.
Say
the rural does all sorts of terrible
things to people,
but there are frequent,
it's frequently the case that people act
in such a way to make things worse
rather than better.
Right?
So if you look at the consequences of
the rise to power of the Nazis,
for example,
it doesn't seem reasonable to put the
Nazi concentration camp in the same
category from an ethical perspective as
the earthquake,
right?
Because the earthquake is an emergent
consequence of the rules that govern
physical existence.
Whereas the Nazi death camp is something
that was planned.
It didn't have to be.
It seems to be an aspect of choice.
And this seems to be the idea that's
lurking underneath both this mythology
and Eliade addys comment on it.
It's
the mere fact that the world is
terrible,
does not mean that it's evil.
But then when you look at specifically
human actions,
there's this aspect of twisted choice
that fry also makes much of it.
He says,
if you,
if you look at the structure of human
history and you try to explain why it
has such a bloody and terrible course,
it doesn't seem sufficient just to
attribute it say to the conditions of
existence or to ignorance.
It seems more like there's,
uh,
a force behind it,
so to speak,
manifest,
say,
and every individual that's actually
aiming at the suffering instead of just
allowing it to happen or instead of not
stepping in to stop it,
but actually aiming at it.
Okay.
Now,
so let's take a look at the story.
It's,
and,
and let's take a look at the leading
figures.
So we know,
for example,
that the figure of Satan and
Christianity is associated with a number
of strange forms,
right?
The first association we know of is that
he's associated with the,
with the dragon and in the garden of
Eden,
right?
So there's,
and so that there's a profound
ambivalence and Christianity about the
meaning of the opening act of genesis.
Because on the one hand you have,
when Adam and eve are still profoundly
unconscious,
they don't suffer,
but they're profoundly unconscious,
right?
They're not self conscious,
they're not aware of themselves.
So in many ways there's still animals.
So there's a gnostic line of
speculation.
The gnostics were a Christian sect that
believed that a redemption could at
least partly be attained by
understanding rather than just faith.
The gnostics believed that the the
serpent tempted Adam and eve towards
self consciousness was a more developed
aspect of God then the God that had
created Adam and eve to begin with
because the unconsciousness that
characterized Adam and eve was to
underdeveloped to be perfect.
And so they had to be tempted forward
into a more fully developed
consciousness.
And so although classical Christianity
associated the serpent in the tree with
Lucifer,
who's the bringer of light,
who Satan,
the gnostic thread of reasoning said,
well,
wait a minute,
it's not that simple because yeah,
self consciousness makes you aware of
death and vulnerability and and knocks
you out into the profane world.
But there's an aspect of it,
the kind of looks like enlightenment and
you know this already in your own lives
because often when you believe something
and you're unconsciously convinced of
the adequacy of that model and then you
find that it's not sufficient,
right?
And so you crumble in in disappointment,
you put your trust in someone and you
find out,
say they're not worthy of that trust.
And that,
that the evidence that enlightens you
breaks that frame of reference and makes
you collapse.
You think that's a terrible thing.
You can't help but feel that as a real
betrayal and as an act even of evil.
But then a year later,
two years later,
you might look back and think,
God,
you know,
I really needed that.
I really needed that lesson because as a
consequence of learning that I'm much
more mature and much more likely to
establish stable relationships.
And so it's easy to see that from one
perspective something can be terrible
and then from another,
it might not be terrible at all.
And even in classic Christianity,
you get this strange ambivalence about
the events in genesis that runs
something like this.
Well,
yes,
it was an act of the,
of the most evil spirit,
the spirit of enlightenment,
the spirit of rationality,
or the bringer of light,
Lucifer to knock Adam and eve out of
their transcendental unconsciousness and
to start history,
it was an evil act,
but on the other hand,
it was also the precondition for the
later emergence of Christ.
And as,
as the Christians are concerned,
that's the greatest event in history.
So without this initial opening act,
right,
this tragic opening act,
there'd be no reason for the whole
redemptive story and therefore
considered from the perspective of the
total story.
The opening tragedy cannot purely be
considered evil.
Very,
very complicated line of reasoning.
Now the other thing you see here,
and I think this relates back to our
initial map,
is,
and this also helps you understand the
way people think.
Now,
I said already that it's real easy to
confuse tragedy and evil,
right?
Okay.
So what that means is that it's real
easy to confuse the negative aspect of
the unknown.
With evil.
And likewise,
it's very easy to confuse the negative
aspect of culture with evil,
your own culture,
the tear radical aspect of it,
or the culture of other people.
So it's very easy for,
for example,
for us to demonize the foreigner.
And that's basically because there's a
part of our mind that presumes that all
things that strike us negatively,
all things that produce negative emotion
on our part,
like fear are the same thing.
So there's a blurry category of evil
that's all terrible natural things,
all terrible social things.
And then whatever nastiness the
individual can generate among
themselves,
it's much more useful to draw a clear
distinction between these different
categories because that clarity of
thought can help you,
can help you focus in most specifically
on those things that the individual is
responsible for in terms of turning the
world to waste.
So Milton says this figure of Satan,
Lucifer,
the,
the light bringer,
always associated with rationality.
Milton presents him as a remarkable
creature,
right?
He's the head highest angel in God's
heavenly hierarchy.
He is Christ elder brother in,
uh,
in a similar mythological vein.
He's the most powerful angel that ever
lived.
So at least in the opening stages of
this act,
Satan is presented as something
absolutely remarkable.
Now,
the problem is here,
his very remarkable Nis starts to work
against him.
And what happens is that as he grows in
power and strength in this heavenly
hierarchy starts to become convinced
that the omniscient himself,
whatever that transcendent figure is,
is unnecessary.
So the idea is that whatever Satan
represents decides because of his own
pride,
his own belief in his own sufficiency,
that the transcendent can be eradicated
from consideration the way Milton
presents.
That is as a revolution in heaven,
fundamentally.
So imagine that the story is something
like this.
Well,
George Kelley,
way back in like 1955 noted that what
human beings like more than anything
else,
really when you get right down to it is
to be right.
Why?
Well,
it's a pain to be wrong,
right?
Because if you're wrong,
then the little structure that you're
using to conjure up the world has to
dissolve.
And then you have to do a lot of really
aggravating work,
exploratory work and creative work.
To put it back together.
And during the time,
before you put it back together,
then you're flooded with negative
motivational states,
right?
You don't know which way is up,
metaphorically speaking.
So we don't like to be,
we don't like not to be,
right.
And,
and so what does that mean?
Well,
psychologists know that people have a
very strong confirmatory bias,
which basically means that if you bring
a frame of reference to bear on the
world,
the probability is very high,
that you will look for confirming
evidence and you will discount
disconfirming evidence.
Now the other thing that is
characteristic of great figures of evil,
like Satan is their tendency to lie,
right?
So Satan is prince of the lie.
Now what does that mean exactly?
So Tsl Eliot wrote this poem called the
cocktail hour.
He talks about this woman,
he goes in for psychiatric treatment.
The woman says to the psychiatrist,
I'm telling Ya,
I really,
really hope there's something wrong with
me because I'm having a miserable time
of it.
And as far as I can tell,
there's only two options here.
Either I'm okay and I'm having a
miserable time because the world is
terrible,
in which case there's nothing I can do
about it.
Or there's something wrong with me at
some level of analysis that I don't
really comprehend and although that's a
painful option,
I'm really hoping it's true because if
there's something wrong with me,
possibly I can fix it.
And if there's something wrong with the
structure of the world,
well what's there to do about that?
Often what you see in psychotherapy is a
battle between those two perspectives
going on in the minds of the client that
the client is in a situation where
they're repetitively facing tragedy,
they have a specific viewpoint about the
world,
like their viewpoint might be,
well,
when it comes right down to it,
you really can't trust other people and
they have all sorts of reasons for
believing that maybe they were abused as
children or they've had a bad
developmental history,
a number of relationships that haven't
gone well.
They have all the facts at their
disposal to justify that particular
perspective.
But the truth of the matter is,
is that as long as they hold on to that
belief and won't let it go and no wonder
they won't,
they're going to continue to suffer.
And part of what you're always doing to
someone in therapy saying,
you know,
yeah,
you go to a pretty coherent view of the
world and all that,
and I can understand why you'd like to
cram the whole world into that coherent
perspective.
But the truth of the matter is,
as long as you hold onto that and won't
sacrifice it,
right,
we'll go through this terrible period of
disillusion.
It's always going to produce the same
tragic consequences.
So as long as you hold onto your belief
rigidly,
everything around you is going to go
from bad to works.
Fry says with regards to state's,
he says,
a demonic fall as Milton presents.
It involves defining southern rivalry
with god rather than simple
disobedience.
And hence the demonic society is a
sustained and systematic parody of the
divine.
One associated with devils are fallen
angels because it seems far beyond
normal,
normal human capacity in its powers.
We read avast ending and descending
angels on Jacobs and play those ladders
and and similar that there seem to be
demonic reinforcements in heathen life.
That account for the almost superhuman
grandier of heathen empires,
especially just before they fall too.
Particular notable passages in the old
testament prophets linked to this theme
are the denunciation of Babylon in
Isaiah 14 and attire and is equal 28
Babylon is associated with Lucifer.
The morning star who said to himself,
I will be like the most high.
Okay,
so let's translate that into modern
language and forget about Babylon.
Let's take the Soviet Union for example
instead,
and let's say something like this,
I will be like the most high.
Well,
first of all,
it's not difficult to read Stellan into
that from a personal perspective,
but then it's more complicated than that
because you can't blame the Soviet Union
on Stallon when the wall fell down.
We know that one third of east Germans
were KGB informers.
You can't blame that on Stellan.
You have to blame that on the one third
of the East Germans who were KGB
informers right?
It's this,
this totalitarian presupposition
presumption is distributed through the
whole society and there's a leader in a
hierarchy and all that,
but they're not the people to be
identified with the fact of the
totalitarian state.
It's distributed through the whole
society and it's precisely this.
It's what I don't know.
I don't need,
I don't need what?
I don't know.
One of the things I really liked about
this sort of Christian metaphysical take
on the problem of evil is that it,
it adopts strange first principles like
if you're an a,
if you're an empirical scientist,
it's very difficult to come to terms
with the notion of free choice,
right?
Because we don't have deterministic
models of free choice.
We don't,
we don't know how that might occur.
Although it seems to be a reasonable
phenomenological observation that if
there's anything true about existence,
about the facts of existence as it's
subjectively construed,
the fact that you seem to have the
faculty of choice seems paramount or
primary.
Now one might say,
well,
that's just a delusion and we know that
because our deterministic models have
been so powerful.
Or One might say,
well,
alternatively we're going to presume the
subjective experience to be true and
say,
well,
are deterministic models just aren't
sophisticated enough?
And there's no real reason to choose
between either of those on a priori
basis right there perhaps equally
plausible.
And we also might note from the
deterministic perspective of course,
that if you go down far enough in your
analysis of physical structures down to
the quantum level,
say then deterministic models don't hold
it all.
So determinism has its limits at the
lower end or high resolution into
physical inquiry.
I have no idea what that might mean for
free choice.
It just means that there are levels of
analysis that deterministic models do
not describe.
Christianity takes the stance that the
subjective,
the subjective sense of freedom is
accurate and then tries to build the
world from that point.
It presumes that see an axiomatic
principle and so you have God in
Milton's paradise lost saying with
regards both to Lucifer,
n two human beings who are fallen,
he says,
so will fall.
He and his faithless progeny,
speaking of human beings whose fault,
whose but his own engrade he had of me
all he could have.
I made him justin.
Right,
sufficient to have stood though free to
fall.
And I like that.
I think that makes a fair bit of sense
to me.
I started to understand this most
particularly as a consequence of reading
Carl Young because you has this really
interesting notion and I think it's tied
to the idea in genesis that as soon as
adam become self conscious,
he hides from God.
So what if it was this,
and we can take an evolutionary tack on
this too.
What if it was this?
What if it was the case that if you
never turned away from any phenomenal
logical evidence,
then you build a personality that would
be strong enough to withstand tragedy?
What if that was the case?
So the idea here being,
let's say you are the person who notes
that his or her friends don't exactly
trust,
trust him.
What do you do?
Well to hide away?
You just walk away.
And then of course you never learn
anything.
But let's say by contrast you say,
well,
no,
no.
The first time you get any evidence that
you're not 100% trusted,
you say,
look,
I got this Pang in my heart saying the
communication between you and I is not
exactly straight.
Now something's going on here.
Either you haven't got your frame of
reference with regards to me,
right?
Or there's something wrong with the way
I'm looking at the world.
Those are the options.
So let's have it out.
You've got this attitude and it's doing,
it's hurting me.
Tell me what you have to say.
And I'll tell you what I have to say.
And we'll exchange this pattern
information.
And as a consequence,
we're gold.
Both going to walk away a little bit
more.
Well put together.
So God says,
yeah,
yeah.
You know,
people get distorted and twisted and
bent and warped,
but that's their own problem
fundamentally.
Cause they have this capacity just to
turn away.
And as they turned away,
they get weaker.
And as they get weaker,
the world gets worse around them because
they can't deal with it.
And they keep making mistakes.
And well,
that's a terrible consequence and all
that.
But if they just wouldn't turn away to
begin with,
then there'd be no problem.
And there wouldn't be no problem because
the world would stop being tragic
because the world's tragic,
right?
I mean,
there you are little and vulnerable and
you know,
things can roll right over you.
The world would never lose its tragedy.
But the idea be instead that you could
handle it without becoming corrupted and
that would be sufficient.
So the idea would be,
it's a tough situation,
all things considered,
but it's also an interesting and
compelling and beautiful one.
And it may be that if you didn't turn
away the interesting and beautiful and
compelling aspect would overwhelm the
tragic aspect and that would be fine.