No,
I use this picture to represent my
class.
You might not know anything about this
picture.
It's a picture of Jonah being thrown out
of a whale's belly after spending three
days inside.
It's an old biblical story.
It's a myth.
It's a fairy tale.
That's.
That's one way of looking at it and and
I don't mean that in a derogative
manner.
We know for example,
that somebody gribbins brothers'
fairytales are perhaps 50,000 years old.
It'd be traced back.
The really,
really old and old stories are strange
and they're strange because only been
told generation after generation after
generation,
so you can imagine that something
retooled over such an expansive,
expansive time has been reduced to its
just many,
many times and nothing in the story
anymore.
It's all meaningful in some sense.
Sort of like a a story that's one way of
thinking about imagine that you took 100
books,
hundred adventure books,
and you had to extract out the central
features of an adventure.
For now it's hard to do that.
It's like you're averaging across the or
something like that.
Instilling them in some manner.
You get up Amanda and denture and it
would be like a myth upon which all
adventures are based and this story is
actually one of those stores,
and I'm going to tell you what I think
the story means,
and I'm not saying that this is all the
these,
because most stories of this sort are in
some sense in exhaustible,
just like great works of art are
inexhaustible there.
There's more information in them than
you can possibly articulate.
That's what makes the
profound.
That's why you go look at them,
because otherwise someone could just
tell you about paying and that would be
the end of that,
but that doesn't work.
So,
so Jonah is being stood up by this whale
and of course on your face,
if that's an impossibility,
because
live inside a whale,
that's why it's impossible.
Now,
you may remember and likely do that.
You all know a story about someone who
is inside whale.
That's Pinocchio,
right?
And uh,
you know,
you go to that movie,
maybe even as an adult,
you watch that movie and Japan goes down
there and the whale and doesn't mean
quote this big cavernous inside.
You don't really care that that's,
there's a bunch of things you don't care
about.
You don't care that these are drawings
and not real people.
You don't care about that and you don't
care that inside of a whale isn't a
cavern and you don't care that
Pinocchio's a puppet for that matter.
None of that matters to you all.
And that's because you're really strange
creatures and you don't even notice when
you're doing something out.
And that's one of those times when you
are.
But if someone taps you on the shoulder
and says,
you know,
when you're just watching drawings of a
puppet operates can really move the
condom asleep and now he's at the bottom
of the ocean.
You have no idea why he's going to
rescue his father and you're just
sitting there and all you're okay with
that.
And you'll say,
shut up because I want to finish
watching the movie.
And so that's interesting.
You see that.
Tells you something about your
unconscious.
If you're a psychoanalytically minded
because you're doing something that you
cannot account for now,
you might say,
well,
it's enjoyable.
Well,
that's deep,
man.
You're really going a long ways with
that.
The it is a why is it comprehensive?
Will be why is it enjoyable?
See just exactly what are you doing
better and you think that whatever you
are doing there is so valuable that you
will actually pay to do it.
Weird.
Very,
very weird.
And you know when you read about let's
say the archaic ritual of tribal people
and you ask yourself just what are they
up to?
You might think,
well,
they're up to the same thing that you're
up to when you go see a movie.
So then you might also notice that the
most expensive artifacts or among the
most expensive artifacts that human
beings create our movies,
it's been hundreds of millions of
dollars on
and we consider that a good deal.
And you know,
it drives our technology too because the
high tech movies like the marvel movies
that require so much computer animation,
they actually drive the demand for high
end graphics chips.
So our technological,
it sounds forward,
is actually motivated in part by her
desire to represent things fictionally
in evermore spectacular manner.
So John,
well let me tell you the story of Jonah
and I'll tell you why I'm going to tell
you.
This is from Camille Paglia,
who's a critic of the modern university
and very brilliant woman,
I would say,
very controversial,
credibly rapid speaker.
She can think so fast.
It's just unbelievable.
She's really fun to watch it if you
like,
that sort of thing.
Vicious adversary in an argument.
She says,
the number one problem in academia
today,
it's not ignorant students.
Professors
let's substitute narrow expertise and
theoretical sophistication of foster's
turned for breadth and depth of learning
in the world.
History of art and thought our isn't
interconnected with work.
A fabricated tradition,
overconcentration on any one point,
isn't distortion.
Here's,
here's the problem.
I wrestled with this one.
To understand some of the things that
I'm going to teach you about,
there's some things that you kind of
have to grasp as a whole.
You know,
sometimes you have a flash of insight
and a bunch of things that you didn't
know were related.
You haven't done that.
That's supposed to happen in
psychotherapy when you link different
disparate patterns of behavior together
because you've linked them saying with a
single cause and you get this like cited
feeling of illumination and possibility
and there are forms of communication
that require the simultaneous Lee,
the simultaneous realization of a
multitude of disparate.
So now I'm gonna
move.
You can be like that.
You know,
you listen to a movie,
you watch a movie and then you don't
know what the hell's going on and then
something happens near the end and
everything fits together and it's
because you started seeing the thing as
a whole.
And a lot of the things that we.
A lot of the ways that we interact with
the world that are mysterious
are like that there.
And this is what Pega is referring to is
that.
And this is a psychoanalytic
proposition.
I would say our romantic proposition,
wow,
no,
no idea roughly is that
way out in the periphery of reality or
all those things that not only do you
not know,
but you don't even know you don't know,
right?
Eric completely blind to their existence
and then there's unknown things that you
have some suspicions about him and
there's unknown things that you can
start to imagine and act out and
dramatize,
and so all of that is on the periphery
of our knowledge.
Lots of psychoanalytic dictum.
Where do thoughts come from?
They're just getting dreams are the
birthplace of thoughts.
Fantasy.
It's not that surprising.
Fantasy is the birthplace of ideas.
You know,
thinking about what you're gonna do in
the future.
You enter into a reverie of dream state
and you contemplate multiple
possibilities and then you start
thinking through,
use your imagination to search beyond
where you are and the collective human
attempt to do that is our mysterious
humanistic artistic tradition,
which is very difficult to justify from
a formal articular point of view.
What good is dance?
What is it that you're doing when you're
dancing?
You don't care because you like to
dance.
Why?
Well,
you don't know.
You do spill into you music.
Music's a human.
Universal cultures used music to
organize themselves,
right?
They use music to catalyze their
identities.
They use music to unite around.
No and more archaic societies.
Less differentiate societies,
let's say no.
A mask to represents part of the family
tradition will have a particular design
and there'll be a particular song
written for it and he'll be a particular
dance about the song and the dance or
something like the symbolic
representation of a mode of being in the
world.
Like maybe the mask is a wolf mask and
so we locked out the wolf and there's
music that goes along with that and you
think,
well,
what are you doing when you're acting
out the wolf?
And part of that is what you're trying.
We're trying to understand both it.
It's an event.
It's imitation in part and you know if
you live in the natural world and if you
have attended,
if you're preyed upon,
then understanding the things that
you're hunting and preying upon is
useful and there's also perhaps perhaps
useful things to learn from them and so
we play this strange symbolic game with
the world like children's pretending.
That's another way of thinking about it
and we do that to act out and to begin
to understand things we don't understand
like how it asks us.
For me,
the most important question in life is
not
what the world is made of
and in fact I would say that's a
relatively new preoccupation of,
of humankind.
You know,
we didn't really formalize.
You could say that the ancient Greeks
originated,
laid the groundwork for the emergence of
an empirical science
and then
it emerged more formally with Bacon and
Descartes Newton
600 years ago.
Not very long,
like a blink,
blink of the eye in human terms
for that.
People were engineers.
They can build things and so forth,
but they didn't know how it.
They weren't scientists.
They didn't really conceptualize the
world as an objective place.
We do that automatically because science
seats so far into our
set of presuppositions that doesn't make
us good scientists by the way,
but it does make us believe that the
fundamental reality of the world is an
objective real and I'm not going to
dispute that you get early,
but leaves one set of questions are
answered
probably by its nature because it wasn't
designed to answer the question than
that.
The rest of us.
How should one conduct oneself in the
world and that's an important thing
since you're alive and academically,
you rather stay alive and while you're
alive,
you probably don't want to suffer
anymore than you have to and no more
stupidly than you have to and it might
also be good if some of the things that
you wanted actually happen and so you're
motivated to know how to act and people
are always telling each other how to
act.
We're sending each other information all
the time about how to actually do that.
What are the expressions on her face?
And of course when we parked the people,
we always look at their face and that's
because their face tells you what
they're up to.
No.
If they're smiling,
paying attention to you,
well then you can assume that you're
doing something right.
And if they're looking annoyed or
discussed it,
that's a particularly bad one.
Then you might think you might take a
hit from that,
especially if you know three or four
people are doing it at the same time.
And so we're reflecting,
reflecting some ideal for one another
constantly.
And the more attentive you are,
the more likely you are to act in
accordance with that ideal.
And the more like you like who you are
to move towards it,
you may not even know what the ideal is
in an articulate sentence.
In fact,
you probably don't.
You know,
you could come up with a while.
I get no good person is nice and
friendly and cooperative.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's all just cliche.
But you don't know your conception might
be very hollow.
It's very likely that it's very hard
even though he may be back in a minute.
All right,
so anyways,
this is a story I'd say historic,
it's,
it's what would happen,
collected a bunch of stories and then
you extracted out of the story from and
it's sort of a story about destiny and
it's couched in a religious language.
Um,
but that's okay because most of these
distilled stories are formed.
The foundation of religious texts and
religious texts and Agnes and myths and
stories are,
as I said,
part of the outer perimeter of our
society.
They have a,
they have a coherent nature and it's all
form a foundation and it's on that
foundation that everything that you take
for granted risks,
even if you don't understand the
foundation.
So I can give you an example.
There's a metaphysical idea that
underlies western civilization and that
metaphysical idea is that the individual
has transcendent worth.
That's,
that's the idea from which the notion of
natural rights is derived.
And of course,
our legal system is predicated on the
idea that you have certain natural
rights that are enshrined in the bill of
rights,
for example,
and you're in the states,
wouldn't have built the bill of rights
was being formulated within the
legislation.
Original legislation that founded the
state is being formulated.
The formulator said,
we hold these truths to be self evident.
What does that mean?
They're axioms of faith.
They're propositions and there's no
proof for them.
They're their mode of operation in the
world and so the hypothesis is something
like,
well,
if I treat you like there's something
about you that has transcendent value,
implicit intrinsic value,
whatever that might be,
there are stories,
vocab,
and we'll talk about and you do the same
to me,
and then we set up a body of laws that
recognize this,
the sovereignty of the individual so
that the law itself has to act with
respect towards every individual.
Even if that individual has done
something reprehensible,
which is very weird.
If you think about it,
then our society will work better and
well,
perhaps that's true,
but for better or worse,
that is what this society is predicated
on and that's a very,
very,
very old idea.
It's an idea that people came to with
great difficulty because it was over
thousands of years that people learn how
to take their little tribal groups which
are always squabbling with one another.
As human beings.
They're very violent and tribal groups
are by no means civilized.
There's no noble savage like the
Europeans thought.
You studied tribal groups in the world
today.
The murder,
the death rate by violence is
unbelievably high,
so
something that unites a tribe within a
tribe,
it's often kinships,
but then tribes come together to form
larger civilizations and they have to
determine some sort of method of
principle that guides them so that they
can cooperate and come together without
destroying one another and they have to
extract out of principle by which the
society might function and that has to
work and then as societies get bigger
and bigger and bigger and bigger and
bigger,
they have to bring more and more of
these diverse traditions together and
extract something from them.
It has power and functional utility and
that allows people to unite.
And so
this is one of the stories that talks
about that.
It's a storybook individual
responsibility and what happens when
it's not heated,
so you know,
because we could say you are a social
creature linked to the core and of your
environment is other people and those
other people want something from you.
You want something from them.
So you're going to play games with them.
You're either going to be good at it,
you're going to bad,
but you're going to play games with them
and so the game might have rules where
you sophisticated
and you'd expect that because as
behavior more and more approximates an
ideal student sets a thing exists,
then more and more sophisticated than
the nature of the ideal is perhaps more
and more complex and physical can
understand.
You get a hint of that stuff.
We can get a hint of this because you
will see if you pay attention to your
own soul,
your psyche,
your unconscious,
you will see that there are people that
you admire and the people that you have
contempt for it and that's,
and it doesn't necessarily.
Then you're 100 percent accurate in your
judgment.
You know it's not such a bad idea to
criticize here first
impressions,
but those states exist and so there's a
reason you admire someone and there's a
reason you have contempt for someone
that may be multiple reasons and that's
a hit to your intrinsic value structure.
It's a hint about your intrinsic value
structure.
You wouldn't admire someone unless there
was something about them that you value
and perhaps that you would also like to
be able to do and you wouldn't despise
someone or have contempt for them if you
didn't feel that something they were
doing was wrong and that it would be
wrong.
If you get it too,
and so you're bringing to bear on the
situation and implicit morality,
then you have to do that because as I
said,
you can act without a morality because
if you're going to act,
you're going to try to make things
better that otherwise why bother and if
you're acting to make things better than
some things have to be better at.
Some things have to be worse,
and that's a value structure,
so you have one.
All right,
so Jonah
gets a call from God and God tells him
that there's a city,
Nineveh that's falling into moral
disarray.
Now,
what does that mean?
Well,
it's a universal story.
It's like all cultures are always
falling into disarray.
It's their nature.
Just entropy does that,
right?
Things change.
The world changes.
The environment changes in the culture
doesn't keep up very well,
and then of course it has corrupt the
elements and so it's an interior eternal
story.
The individual is always placed in
relationship to a culture that somewhat
corrupt and then the question is well do
about and if the answer is nothing,
well then it'll just get more corrupt
and if the answer is be corrupt too,
then it will just get more corrupt.
So the answer has to be to host the
corruption because that's the only way
it's going to start.
Now God threatens to destroy this city
because of its corruption and I don't
think you need to presume anything
particular the metaphysical about that
to understand that it's very
straightforward that the more corrupt
the culture is and the less trust is
possible between individuals,
the less productive with the culture is
going to be because why do anything?
If some person is going to come and take
it,
you know it might even be these
different culture is so corrupted.
If you aren't good for something and you
produce resources,
you're actually more likely to get
killed because you have something of
value.
So like there's just,
you're just not going anywhere with
that.
And why would you work if you didn't
have any sense that you know you could
store up the value of your work for some
reasonable time in the future.
So if this society is corrupt and
there's no trust,
it's degenerate.
Might live for a while,
but he isn't going to last very long.
And so that's the idea.
Corrupt society.
He's collapsed.
Stephanie is open.
What corruption means anyways,
Jonah fake snow,
no bloody way.
I'm not going to that city.
It can go to hell as far as I'm
concerned and that's really what he
thinks and why in the world should I do
anything about it anyways?
And these are good objections.
It's like,
why would you do that?
And you'll face this,
believe me in your life,
you will face this.
In fact,
you've already do always,
constantly,
continually in small ways perhaps when
you're interacting with people who
aren't treating you properly when you're
acting,
and those might be your parents,
they might be your friends,
they might be people that can work
place,
they might be professors,
they're playing a crooked game and you
don't like and you know it's crooked.
And so then the question is,
what would you do about,
well,
if you know your credit,
no,
it's crooked.
It's not so good to play along with it.
I mean,
let's say that you know it's crooked by
your own standard,
devalues it.
D degrades you to play a long winter,
you to stand up and oppose it.
Well,
no,
probably not.
You're probably gonna do Jonah did you
don't want to ship and get the hell out
of there and you know,
now it's a logical thing to do,
but it doesn't solve the problem.
And I think this has something to do
with human ethical responsibility
because there are other old stories,
and I'll tell you one like me were the
son of the king,
the lion king,
the son of the king.
He goes and he's pathetic,
adolescent,
and then he shamed by the reappearance
of his old girlfriend and him turning
into something vaguely useful and he
opens his eyes and he goes back and he
fights scar and no,
it's a scene of hell,
right?
Because there's fire everywhere.
He fights scar,
scar killed.
His father,
casts him into the pit,
roughly speaking,
and then the rain comes and then you
know the movie returns to its beginning.
Fundamental Paradise,
Paradise lost,
paradise regained.
That's the movie,
and and that's the story of human
beings.
You know you're in a place that's
working out pretty well.
Something happens to knock you off your
perch.
You're down in chaos for a good amount
of time and maybe you never get out,
but maybe you learn something down
there.
Maybe you strengthen your character,
then you pop up to a new place and maybe
it's better and better.
You.
Now,
I'm not being overly optimistic about
this.
I know perfectly well that people
encounter
impediments during their life that they
find almost impossible to recover from,
but it's the best shot you have.
So anyways,
Jordan runs away,
but God is very happy about that because
it's actually Joe,
his destiny is necessary for Jonah to
repair the city so God sends a storm
and the waves were high and I think what
that means is because the water is often
a symbol for the unconscious and that's
because things learned down there in the
water and then you could pull up that
are useful monsters,
things that you can pull up,
their useful.
You can fish for the fishing in your own
being for answers,
which is what you do when you try to
think.
You ask yourself the question and maybe
you can answer appearance.
It's like,
where did that come from?
You didn't know what the answer was
before it appeared,
when it just popped into being an
nowhere.
Who knows?
So you finish.
So anyways,
the waves come and the bolt's going to
be knocked over it and that's what
happens.
I think when know when you know you
should do something mean everyone has
the experience.
I believe perhaps you would be willing
to put up your hands if this experience
is foreign to.
Okay.
There's part of you telling you you
should do something and it's hard to do
it effortful and maybe you're afraid of
it,
and so you don't do it.
You just procrastinate,
right?
And so how do you feel about that?
Good.
I mean,
so what?
You feel that you're betraying yourself,
your anxiety actually gets worse,
not better,
even though you know you can put it off
moment for moment,
but that doesn't help because every time
you put it off,
the anxiety just grows a little bit.
You're proud of yourself.
You have a sense that
you're making things more chaotic than
they should be known.
If you do that long enough,
I'm sure many of you have not
experienced.
If you do that long enough at that
becomes habitual,
things will get so stormy around you.
Then you will fall right into this feed,
to the chaos,
into the watery chaos,
and maybe you'll drown.
So it's not a very good idea to run from
your destiny.
Let's say
whatever that might be and you need an
estimate.
You need it because that's what gives
you meaning and you need meaning in your
life because life is hard.
So you know you need something to boxes
yourself against that.
So anyways,
we make Jonah.
Jonah says that's probably my fault
because like I'm running away from
something I'm supposed to do and you
know on gardens very happy about that.
So why don't you just throw me over.
Overboard.
Crew is very happy about that,
but the waves are really starting to
come up with Joan is pretty insistent
that he's the cause of the problem and
so maybe draw free draw lots and Jonah
is chosen and so they decided to
collapse it into the ocean and
immediately everything's calm.
So he's a center of chaos because he's
not doing what he's supposed to do.
It's fine.
Well then a whale comes up and swallowed
the whale for three days.
No,
that's a weird thing.
Well,
that's the way all the dependencies in
drag,
it's that thing that you have to go out
there and conquer,
get something of value.
Now,
when you made an error,
when you
fallen off the path where you deviated
from what you know you should do,
you produces a state of internal chaos
and worried and concerned.
You're thrust into the unknown.
You're thrust into unknown territory and
chaos.
You don't know what to do and that's
often symbolized by have you encountered
with a monster,
like a dragging somebody that lives
under the water.
That's I think the reason for that is as
far as I've been able to tell is that
human beings,
because we'd be prey animals for forever
in her battle with carnivorous lizards,
for example,
and alligators and even dinosaurs
because there were dinosaurs around at
the time of our most distant ancestors.
There was even a cap at one point that
was.
It was adapted with pierce human skulls,
so it had a head that was exactly shaped
and grab you here through the back of
your skull.
So like we've come through some rough
times.
Man.
We have a system in our mind.
It's a threat Predator detection system.
That's the thing that makes little kids
thinking about monsters in the dark,
right?
Because while there is monsters in the
dark,
parents always say,
well,
there's no monsters in the dark.
It's like that's not true.
Dark is full of monsters.
There might not be any in your room
right at that moment,
but that doesn't mean there aren't
monsters in the dark crimes.
Take place like criminals don't get up
at six in the morning and like,
you know,
have breakfast and go rob a bank can do
that sort of thing at night.
People do the things that are fit for
the night tonight and lots of predators
are nocturnal and you can't see very
well in the dark and kids aren't stupid.
They've evolved to stay pretty damn
close to the fire because of the kids
that wandered away from the fire kicked
off by hyenas and lions and crocodiles
and whatever else the hell it was out
there to eat the unwary.
So
the circuit that we use to defend
ourselves against predators.
As we've evolved cortically,
that circuit has come to represent what
we don't know in general because the
predators,
a person count don't know.
And so evolution is a conservative
forest and we'll use the circuits that
to representing new things.
So the unknown,
the chaos is often represented by a
monster swallows you up and pulls you
down.
I didn't know when you're feeling
terrible,
you know what I'm saying?
Well,
I'm feeling hot.
I'm feeling down well,
why is that?
Well down is worse.
I guess you're flat on the ground when
you're down or you're in a hole or
something like that.
You're hiding in a hole.
You know it's down and you're threatened
by something.
If you're threatened by your own
inadequacy,
that might be part of it.
Maybe that's partly what you imagined as
a monstrous force because you know your
proclivity towards oppressed
procrastination and your weakness of
character is part and parcel of why you
happened to be in the underworld.
And that's the underworld of
mythological underworld.
That's where you go when things fall
apart.
And if you understand that,
if you know that that's what that means,
thank you.
Have One of the keys that opens up
ancient stories to you and you
understand things you,
your life can be organized going very
well.
And then something comes up and
everything changes.
Some axiom that you were living by it.
It might be the existence of a partner
might be a job that maybe your health,
any of those things
go on and you go somewhere,
you go somewhere.
It's a state of being.
You're still in the same world,
but it's not the same all anymore.
Everything about it is different.
It's all negative and dark.
You don't know what to do.
You're confused.
And so what do you do down there in the
underworld when things are falling
apart,
especially if hope is it's more possible
case scenario and you realize that you
actually had something to do with your
device that's really annoying.
You know when something bad happens to
you and then you know you grind yourself
into bits trying to figure out what the
hell happened,
and then you realize that,
well you were playing a causal role.
Now sometimes you're so depressed.
You assume you're playing a causal role
and you work.
It's not an easy to figure out by any
stretch of the imagination and it isn't
the one who chose something terrible is
at fault for it,
but sometimes you find that you are off
the path somehow and maybe even that you
knew it and didn't attend to it,
and that's why all of this kid
and so then down there in that chaos,
you decide that you're going to do what
you're supposed to do instead and then
maybe you get to rise up again,
renewed.
If you're locking and then you can go
fix the city and that's what this
story's about and that's why I picked
the image to represent the course.
Because really what happens,
you see it with the psychoanalysts,
the road due to health.
If you're not doing well,
which means that as you act in the
world,
you're not getting what you want.
There's something wrong with your match
between your presuppositions and your
actions,
habitual and the way the world is
responding to you so it's not turning
out for you.
And the question is,
well,
what can you do about that?
And one answer might be to examine
yourself for presuppositions and action
patterns that are not serving you will
find out what they are and what to do
about.
Maybe some of that is maybe you're not
moving forward because of fear.
That fear is grounded in terrible
experiences that you've had in the past
that he's never been able to understand
and maybe one of the ways of gluing
yourself back together and expanding
your personality so that you could in
fact live properly in the world,
is to go back to those terrible events
and untied,
straightened them out and understand the
and drop them,
and that's what psychotherapy is about.
In large part,
psychoanalytic behavioral doesn't
matter.
What are you afraid of?
What are you avoiding?
What are you finding to develop maybe
from fear,
maybe from avoidance,
God only knows maybe from discuss.
How can you get over it?
How can you reclaim those parts of your
self?
I sent in the first lecture that I was
going to try to provide you with Schema
into which you can place the theorists
that we're going to discuss
requires going down deep.
To do that,
your presuppositions,
my presupposition,
and this is a psychoanalytic
presupposition,
it's predicated
on a poetic tradition,
I would say rancher tuition.
I learned most of it for breeding young
was Carl Young.
The
help me understand that we're nested
inside a dream.
I guess we don't know everything.
We have to take things as givens and
things that be taken as given to nested
inside stories and we accept the stories
and then outside of the stories is the
absolute,
you know,
and that's partly.
The stories are tricky,
you know,
if one of the classic stories,
Very Jonah's story I would say is
St George and the Dragon Story was
represented in renaissance and your
immediate
thousands and thousands of ways.
It's like the story of St Patrick who
chased the snakes out of Ireland.
Same idea.
And the typical say George story is
hobbit or Harry Potter.
So in the second volume of Harry Potter,
correct me if I have any of these
details.
Roger,
remember there's that snake,
the Bass lisc.
So there's this magic castle,
right?
You guys have no problem with magic
castle.
No problem.
Here's an artist.
He was an orphan.
He goes to the magic castle to learn how
to be more than normal with the models.
He has a muggle family,
were not too happy with them.
I'll go family like as representatives
of normal people think they have some
blacks now.
Of course,
the reason for that is that,
well,
that's what teenagers often feel.
Both your parents elt is this.
These could really be my parents.
I must have some other parents who were
like together.
Those are like magical parents,
right?
Parents that live in the sky,
and of course Harry Potter has earthly
parents.
Thoughts.
Mongols nervously I think is the kid.
He's at one.
He's a wonderful piece of work.
You know,
it will form a spoiled,
the old form selfish very far from the
ideal.
He's a foil for Harry and of course he's
appreciated.
Doted on and Harry is actually punished
for his virtues.
That's a classic story.
Him To be punished for your virtues.
If you look at the story central story
in Christianity,
the central story in Christianity is
about someone who is precisely punished
in the worst possible,
waiting for the highest possible
virtues.
That's what it makes it an architect of
the story because there isn't anything
more unfair than that,
and so it's a limit in a sense.
It can't be worse than that.
Being punished for being,
you know,
unworthy.
It's like,
yeah,
I will at least make sense,
but to be punished because you have your
act together and you're a good person.
That's real punishment.
That's what happens to Harry.
So luckily you find out things magical
like convenient and off he goes to
wizarding school and you know that's
actually like taking.
That's actually like going and studying
the humanities.
I mean it was when they still were.
No,
because it's through the humanities that
you,
that you made contact with the magic of
your culture and that makes you more
than merely the child of your parents
because you are more than married the
child of your parents or the child of
nature and you're the child of culture
and until you understand what that
means,
understand that you have two sets of
parents,
like the divide here always has two sets
of parents.
You can't construe yourself property as
an individual.
You're not situated properly in the
world,
you don't know what your
responsibilities are,
you can't orient your values property
and you will suffer for that because as
far as I can tell,
because life is so difficult,
you have to do something that's truly
work while in order to justify it and so
on.
That's what all these stories tell you.
That's story of Jonah is telling you.
It's like you have an ethical duty to
straighten things up and if you don't do
it,
you're going to be soaring
and that story's apple everywhere.
Well now,
St George.
Well,
let's go to Harry Potter.
We're talking about.
So he goes off the magic castle and he's
learning to be a wizard and he's kind of
an interesting character because he's
not really good and we find out what I
think that's because because they have a
piece of all the marketing.
Isn't that what happens?
Yeah,
and that's what that means is that
to be good,
truly good,
you kind of just follow the rules.
That's,
that's very clear in the merit order
store and you also have to be able to
understand malevolence and in order to
understand malevolence so that you can
withstand it.
You have to understand that part of you.
That's
because if you don't,
you're naive.
If you're naive,
you're easy pickings and so that's a
union idea too and the union idea is
that part of personality development is
to understand your shadow and the shadow
is those things about you you do not
want to admit to and you could learn
about your shouted by reading history.
You can read about Auschwitz,
you've been redeveloped the
concentration camps in Russia and you
can imagine yourself as a garden
instead of as a heroic rescue robot,
unfortunate victims,
which would be very,
very unlikely.
And once you can imagine yourself as a
guard,
which is a terrifying thing to do,
then you understand something about
yourself.
And I actually think,
and I think this is also from students,
got a young but you cannot have proper
respect for yourself until you know that
you're a monster because he won't act
carefully enough.
Or you think,
well,
I'm a nice first night,
never do anyone any harm.
It's like,
you know,
safe.
You can be sure of that and the harm
that you do.
People can come in many,
many ways and so if you regard yourself
as harmless,
inoffensive,
nice,
well where do you have any reason to be
fearful?
You're like a teddy bear sitting on the
shelf.
Even if you throw it at someone,
no one's going to get hurt,
but that was the one that your life,
because you're a human being and human
beings are some vicious creatures and
there's utility and knowing that because
it's also the case,
you know when the Harry Potter series
very could stand up against fool to
learn and understand and speak his
language because he was effected by him
to some degree.
Very,
very interesting idea.
Anyways,
in the second hand,
the reason I tell you this,
and this is where thinking about
how long were each of those
500 pages here longing and there was how
many of its seven and how many were
sold.
I mean,
how many of you read every Harry Potter
book?
Right?
That's how many of you read at least
one.
Okay?
How many of you saw the movies?
It's like you're all in a cult.
You are.
I'm telling you.
Really,
that's the truth.
It's really the truth.
So in the second volume,
there's a snake that zipping around
there,
the bass list,
right?
And it lives in the underground.
That's chaos.
That's chaos,
and that's because wherever you are,
you're on thin ice and underneath your
thin ice as chaos.
And here we are in this unbelievably
civilized environment and everyone's
getting along perfectly,
but you know the lights,
the electricity,
sewage system is working.
No one's hungry.
It's like you can be peaceful,
but if any of that fell apart and it
could easily fall apart because it's a
bloody miracle it ever works at all,
then the chaos that's just underneath
the surface is going to come up right
now.
And it's useful to know that because it
makes you properly grateful.
If you really understand it,
it makes you properly grateful for the
bloody miracle.
It is that you can be here in peace.
So anyways,
there's this snake that's underneath the
surface and it's no joke,
it's vague and it's ancient.
It's always been there.
And what happens if you look at it,
it turns you to stone,
right?
You're paralyzed.
Well,
that's the,
that's the Gorgon,
that's Medusa.
The woman with the head of snakes.
And if you look at her,
it paralyzes you.
What does that mean?
Well,
you're walking through the jungle and a
snake appears.
What do you do?
You freeze and no bloody wonder because
you're a prey animal and that's what
they do when they see things that are
going to eat them.
And so the snake,
well,
lots of people still die from a snake
bite.
And
our ancestors were,
I don't mean our ancestors like you
know,
tens of millions of years ago when they
were living in trees and were very big,
they made a nice snack for a snake.
And there's a woman named Lynn Isabelle,
who's an anthropologist at Ucla who's
correlated the presence of carnivorous
snakes with the acuity of primate
vision.
And what she found was that the more
snakes around the pattern of primates
could see.
So,
and we're particularly good at picking
up patterns like snake camouflage in the
Lord half of our visual quadrant here,
when people generally don't like snakes,
you can learn to handle them.
No snake fear appears to be a native to
native disease and it tends to increase
as you age rather than decreasing.
You can overcome it.
Well,
my daughter had snakes and one day
versus the spinner,
it was a fairly big snake
and she hasn't paid attention to it for
awhile.
So it nailed her.
And from then on she had had very
difficult time grabbing the snake.
It was like once
shy permanently.
She also told me years later she had
nightmares about snakes all the time
when she had a snake in the room.
You know what?
I think it was probably the smell.
So anyways,
so Harry Potter decides he's going to go
after the Vassilis Greg,
he's going to go out there and face the
thing that he's most afraid of.
So does that way down in the dance.
So it's like Joan up going down into the
depths and he faces the task list kind
of bikes and you know that's.
That's right,
because if you go down into the depths,
you can get fit.
It's no joke.
I mean this is a hero story,
but the thing about the hero stories,
it's actually real.
The thing that you're facing is actually
dangerous.
And even though facing it voluntarily
might be your best bet and is likely
your best bet,
because that's the central story of
humanity.
That doesn't mean you're going to
succeed.
It's the thing.
So anyways,
he gets bitten,
right?
And he's going to die.
Now he's rescuing Jimmy.
So that's the St George Story.
If you go after a dragon,
dragons like to capture virgin,
God only knows why.
I think it's how it goes.
I think it's because one of the things
that male humans have done from the
beginning of time just chase the damn
predators away.
And I suspect that the males from God
only knows how long ago who were
particularly good at that we're rewarded
with female attention and why the hell
not so.
It's deeply rooted inside of us,
that idea of facing the unknown and
freeing the woman.
So the idea there is that if you.
It's a male idea in large part I can
talk about central female myth and then
we'll proceed.
Idea is that if you're the sort of
person who can stand up against the
unknown and the frightening,
then you're also likely develop into
that sort of person.
Then you're also likely to develop into
the sort of person that other people
will find attractive.
So you know,
and that's why you don't believe that
the inside the shadow was the anima,
which is like a female finger.
So his idea was something like,
you don't.
If you look watch movies as long as this
data male guy,
is there a romantic movie you said he's
a nice guy and he's a friend and you
know,
the woman tells him everything that she
has liked him a bit.
She likes the guy who's like got an edge
and who's capable of,
I would say ma'am,
but at least of aggression.
That doesn't mean she wants him to be
aggressive,
but it does mean is that she wants him
to be able to be aggressive.
That would be good,
and so he's the romantic target and so
he's the person that's incorporate
shadow.
He's suddenly respectable and perhaps
useful and so.
Well,
that's a very little storage.
So let's,
let's think about this for a minute.
I've already offered you a proposition.
I think it's an important proposition.
I'm offering you this proposition so
that you can make sense of art and
literature and mythology and religion
and dance and all those strange
ritualistic things that human beings do,
which seems central to us,
including included not least,
the ineradicable tendency.
I've asked to seek out stories of heroes
when I should finish the Harry Potter.
Harry Potter goes down there to rescue
Virginia,
but is that.
There's a formal name,
Virginia anyways,
which is very virgin.
So it gets just.
Yes,
Jeanette.
That's it.
It gets better and the bite is poisonous
and so there is dying.
This doesn't seem to be so good.
And then what happens?
And again,
you guys swallowed this.
It's no problem.
So what's his name?
The dumbledore character.
He's got a bird,
right?
So he's the wise old man.
He's the ruler of the castle.
He's the ruler of the magic castle.
He's the magic king.
He's like God the father as far as Harry
Potter is concerned.
And he has a bird.
What kind of bird is it?
Is a phoenix.
Right?
And one of the things that's very
strange,
but phoenix is that,
well it's a mortal,
but in a strange way,
you know,
it may have some as I think 100 years
and it gets older and older and then one
day the burst into flames and turns into
an egg and then you get a new phoenix.
So that was a symbol of transformation.
It's a symbol of transformation.
The burden is a spirit or psyche.
And so here's what it means in part,
you know,
you know how when you learn a lesson in
your life that that's not very pleasant,
right?
It's not like when you learn something
important,
it's the best day of your life.
It's often the importance of what you
learned is often proportionate to just
how wretched it is to learn it.
You know,
you learn things the hard way.
You learn things by getting hit because
obviously if you're doing is working,
you can get what you want and there's no
learning in that and that's happy.
It's when you're doing something and you
hit an obstacle and Nydia bloody well
hit it hard and then you know,
you recoil and then down into the depths
you go and you have to sort your out.
You realize that you're,
you know,
this particular kind of idiots and that
you should probably fix that and that's
really annoying and difficult and you
know,
and maybe you're down in the dumps and
anxious for quite a while and then you
get it repaired more or less than,
you know,
you put yourself back together.
That's the Phoenix who into flames,
Bang a new you.
And so you know,
that's the ability to learn.
Human beings are very strange creatures,
right?
Because we're very malleable compared to
most animals.
Like grizzly bear is now in prison
bears.
A thousand years ago it was like
whatever.
They are the same thing.
They do the same thing,
there's no transformation,
but human beings we have this massive
brain and you know,
it's a pain because if he'd have to take
care of human children until they're 40
and that's a big burden and so,
you know,
we pay a big price for it.
It also makes child birth very difficult
and,
and it's costly.
You have to eat a lot because we have a
big brain,
uses a lot of energy and so you know,
you pay a price for it,
but the advantage is your plastic you
can learn.
Now learning is a strange thing because
you can take a minute of just acquiring
more information.
You could also think of it and this is
more accurate as
finding out something that you're doing
wrong.
So that's sort of built into like a
character caring element of your
character,
presumption of your perception or a deep
habit really built into you.
So neuro structure,
right?
It's a lie and you have to kill it
because it isn't working properly and
the pain that you go through in part
when you're suffering because he did
something stupid,
is something like you're,
you're.
The neurology can never get this quite
right.
It's the pain of the depth of that
structure and that could be a huge chunk
of,
you know,
if you really have to go through a
massive revision,
it's like the person that comes out the
other end might be the same at all.
You know,
that happens.
For example,
if you're trying to combat alcoholism,
which is just,
you know,
ratchet thing to do because well,
all your friends are alcoholics in your
family drinks too much.
The only thing you know how to do when
you're socializing is to go to the bar
and drink too much.
You know,
you spend like 20 hours a week on it.
It's like,
it's not just that you're addicted to
the substance.
It's like that's how you live.
And so if you want to stop being an
alcoholic,
not only do you have to stop drinking
alcohol,
but you have to stop seeing all your
drunk friends and maybe you've had them
for your whole life and you have to have
continual battles with your drunk family
and then you have to figure out
something to do with that 20 hours.
It's now like hanging around your neck
like an albatross.
And so you have to live that whole part
of the personality die and a new part
has to spring forth.
And that's what the Phoenix is.
Phoenix is the capacity of the person to
transport.
And so when Harry gets bit by a snake
and the threes is him,
he gets seriously injured.
The Phoenix comes in Christ,
some tears in his wound
repair,
some May.
He's back to life.
And the strange thing is,
that's okay with all the viewers.
Why would that be?
There's nothing about if it's rational,
nothing.
Magic castle that's not rational.
Giant snake underneath it.
That's a little more rational
turning you to stone going down there to
face it,
being rejuvenated by a phoenix.
It's like,
yeah,
that's okay.
We can watch that little swallow.
It will be completely engaged in it.
Then the reason for that,
because it's a myth,
it's about how people.
It's a medicine about how to act,
how to conduct yourself in the world,
face the things that you're afraid of
that would otherwise paralyze you to let
the depth of what is insufficient vote
you will occur,
and then to wait for the rebirth.
Okay,
so science is about what the world is
and
myth and drama and dream of young
parents.
All of that.
Let's say the aesthetic and artistic and
fantastic side that's more about how
things should be.
It's more about how to act.
There are lessons in how to act and
they're abstract lessons.
People are capable of abstraction,
right?
So you say,
well there's something new and there's
something about you and there's
something new and it's not about you.
And so we'll take all the good things
and make one good thing on that and you
take all the bad things and make one
batch of that.
And then we sort of understand the
difference between good and bad.
And we get better and better and better
and better at that over the centuries as
we distilled out.
And then we have a figure of ultimate
good and if they of ultimate evil and
that helps us understand what those two
things are.
Those are the hostile brothers.
That's a very common mythological
motifs.
And you could say,
well they're at war inside you.
And I think that that's a universal
truth.
It's an existential truth.
The domain of ethics and morality is how
are we in the world and what should we
be?
What's the good?
And the reason I'm telling you,
oh,
this part from the fact that you should
know it because this is what you should
know if you go through university,
is that the bears directly on issues of
health.
You're trying to accomplish something.
Say if you go see a psychotherapist,
you know you can see what I'm trying to
help you,
but you know,
that's not really what you're trying to
do when you go see your therapist is get
your life together.
And that's not the same thing.
You know,
like mostly when I'm acting as a
therapist,
it's not like I'm directly treating
mental disorders,
mental disorders aren't.
They're just not neat little boxes.
It's not like someone has a fully
functioning life but they have an
anxiety disorder and then you bring them
in,
you treat the anxiety disorder and he go
back to their fully functioning life.
It's not like that at all.
The disorders tangled out into their
life.
You know,
if you're depressed,
well usually either workplace isn't
going very well and your relationships
with the people around you are damaged
and you know you're connected in the
actual with all of these things and so
when you come to see a therapist,
you have to work on putting your life
together in a sustainable manner and
that certainly not just removing the
mental illness is very rare now.
And then you see someone who's depressed
whose life is together and they're are
just depressed because something's gone
wrong probably biochemically and so with
someone like that.
Have you been asked to give them an
Ssri?
I can't give them to you,
but I can recommend them.
Recommend they go see a doctor anyways
and that's sometimes just does the trick
because you know their life is actually
pretty good.
They just can't see it,
but that's funny.
Rare man.
It's usually the case that someone comes
and sees you with things that are in a
serious state of chaos and all of that
has to be addressed in some of it's
psychological and a lot of it's just
practical.
It's embedded in there in the world.
That's what the behavioral psychology,
behavioral psychology is particularly
concerned about.
So anyways,
psychology,
especially the clinical end is
predicated on necessarily predicated on
the question,
how is it that we obtain good,
good,
and what would that be?
One of my clients first come to see me.
One of the things I often ask them is,
okay,
well let's say you look a year ahead.
What do you want?
What are we aiming at?
What would,
what would your life isn't the way you
want it to be?
How would it look if it was the way you
wanted it to be these parking that way
and we ain't get them right.
When we look for impediments,
psychological impediments,
fears,
avoidance strategies,
that sort of thing,
and we developed strategies and we try
to move towards that.
I would say ideal.
Do you understand the categories?
You have to understand something about
the nature.
Now categorization is a tricky thing and
we're gonna run through some complicated
ideas relatively quickly.
You know,
you think you put things in the same
category because they're similar,
but the problem is is that first of all,
that's not an answer.
It's just the restatement of the initial
proposition and second of all,
you can put things in the same category
that are by no means identical and you
often do that.
And third,
it's things are things that are similar,
are often also importantly different.
And so peggy,
which element of similarity,
you know,
like let's say you have a group of
books,
will,
are they the same will obviously no
because they're all the same book,
but the category of books,
it's a pretty strange category because
the content that the book differs
completely well when you could still
make a group of books and you pick some
arbitrary element that unites them.
And consider that grounds to make a
category.
There's other categories and more
scientific categories in scientific
categories.
10 actually contain things that are
very,
very similar across multiple dimensions.
Protons are like that as far as I can
tell,
there's nothing that distinguishes one
proton from another.
Same with electrons.
And you know,
the set of triangles is like that
because you can define it precisely,
but most of the categories that human
beings aren't so neat.
And the problem with that is that unless
the categories are neat,
like scientific categories,
it's very difficult to investigate them
scientifically.
So for example,
you might do research on a group of
people with anxiety disorders,
but the problem with that is that the
anxiety disorder category is so
heterogeneous that it's almost
impossible to identify the commonalities
across all the people are in that
category.
And that's part of the category isn't
actually a scientific category.
It's a hybrid category.
It's a practical category.
I can give you an example of that.
Wow.
No,
I can't say it anyways.
Many of the DSM categories.
So these are categories for second
pathology require.
If you're part of that category,
imagine there's seven symptoms that you
could have read symptoms that you could
have put you in that category,
like social personality,
eight symptoms.
You still kick,
you hit you bite,
you know you're abusive.
I don't remember the category categories
precisely,
but you can be in the category.
If you have symptoms two through five
and you can be in the category.
If you have symptoms six through eight,
they aren't the same symptoms,
but you're in the same category.
Do you think?
Well,
how they.
How can that be?
Well,
that's a family resemblance category.
Roughly speaking.
Lots of the things that we use our
family resemblance category.
There's a prototype and then if you have
enough of the features of that prototype
and the prototype has 10 features and if
you haven't six of those features,
you get to be in that category,
but it means that the categories are
actually quite diverse and that's one of
the problems that plagues
how psychiatry as a science and clinical
psychologist and science really big
problems because if the categories are
homogenous and it's very difficult to
draw conclusions about the members of
the category and the psychologists and
the psychiatrists that those are
scientific categories but what they're
not and they can't be hard because
they're aimed at the classification of
health or ideal versus non health are
not ideal and partly because they play
multiple roles.
You category isn't there just to provide
neat demarcations for scientific study.
The categories there to give people a
language to talk about certain symptoms
to diagnose because you know when you
come in and you have a set of
acceptance,
you might want to know what they are so
that you also know what they aren't.
It's really a relief often to find the
diagnosis and then of course the
diagnosis has certain implications for
treatment and for billing and for all of
that,
so the category has to play all those
roles,
so there's multiple types of category
and the categories that we're talking
about in relationship to the apology,
art,
scientific categories,
their categories and vote the world
construed as a place to act,
so here's the way to think about it.
You're always looking at the world
through a framework of reference and you
have to do that because there isn't very
much if you can't see the whole world at
once,
and in fact the amount of the world you
actually see is so small,
you can't believe in the central part of
your vision is zipping around,
producing a pretty high resolution
representation of exactly what you're
looking at,
but outside of that center,
like if I look at you,
I can't see her eyes.
I can see your glasses,
but barely.
I can't even tell whether you're male or
female.
The person passed that.
I can't see it all.
Now,
you don't notice that.
No,
you don't notice that you're not blind
because your central vision is always
popping around illuminating that tiny
space that you sit down blind.
It's just mind boggling,
and I'm sure some of you have seen the
invisible gorilla video where a gorilla
comes into the video and you don't
notice,
which is somewhat shocking because you
would think that you'd notice the
gorilla,
but what happens is that you actually
don't notice something unless it
interferes with what you're doing and
because what are you going to do?
Notice everything.
You can't do that.
If you've heard of no one say anything.
So what you do is you pick something to
focus on using something that you value
because why else would you focus on it?
So that means that you're telling the
system determines the direction of your
perception.
Bloody well,
think about that for a minute.
That's a Buddhist idea,
right?
People,
people live in a kind of illusion and
sometimes that illusion causes suffering
and they can transform the way they look
at the world and that can release them
from their suffering.
But the idea that you do live in an
illusion,
well,
I don't know if it's exactly illusion
bucket.
You certainly do live within a framework
of perception that's determined by your
values.
Now that is so weird because we never
think of the world and something that
reveals itself through our values,
but of course if a course it does
because you look at you want you it what
you want and once you pay him,
the world lays itself out for you.
And that's exactly how perception works.
That's why this way you're always
somewhere that's point day that
somewhere in some place in some time and
you're always have some notion about
what you want to have happen next.
You know you're going to go to the next
class.
Maybe you've got a plan after this.
In this class,
you have a plan.
You're hoping to learn something about
presuming you have a goal with regards
to a grade and that's nested inside your
desire to get a degree and that's nested
inside your desire to be educated and
have a career and,
and,
and have a successful life.
So attending to me at the moment,
the reason you're doing that is because
all of those values exist within you
simultaneously focusing your attention
and so you're attending to me and
knocked to something else,
assuming that all of you with your
Computers Open Art,
surfing the web,
which you might be,
but assuming that you're focusing,
whatever you're focusing on is directed
by what you value.
And some of that can be unconscious.
In fact,
a lot of it is unconscious because you
know,
it's very difficult for you to get
control of what you pay attention to.
You know what that's like.
You're trying to study kind of a boring
paper.
Christ,
your attention is just like everywhere,
you know,
maybe you'll vacuum under the bed
instead of doing the paper,
you know,
you can't get a grip on that thing.
So your attention has an autonomy and
that's another psychoanalytic idea,
you know,
because you kind of think,
well,
you're in control.
It's like really ever tried telling
yourself what to do.
Does the,
how does that work for you?
I'm going to go to the gym three times a
week,
right?
Sure.
I'm going to quit eating sugar for a
month.
It's like how long does that lasts?
Fifty minutes.
Three chocolate bars.
So you're this,
this,
and this is Freud central insight.
I would say you're an autonomous group
of spiritual agents,
let's say personalities and they don't
really get along very well and you ego
will say is by no means necessarily in
charge and that's a very strange thing
to realize,
but you can really realize that by
noticing how little control you have
over your attentional focus.
Okay,
so you've got on your pointed a,
you're going to point b,
you're always doing that.
We'd have it as structure of value and
it changes what the point a to point B
is,
but the structure itself doesn't change
it.
When you're looking at the world,
what you see is not objects,
tools,
and they make you happy.
Those are things that facilitate your
movement forward and you see obstacles
and those are things that make you
unhappy.
Then when you encounter an obstacle,
one of the problems is as well,
you don't get to where you're going and
that's a problem,
but the other problem is if you
encounter an the frame might be wrong,
right?
Because you never know.
It might be just something that you
could easily might be a fatal flaw in
your whole plant and so obstacles have
this dual nature.
They get in your way,
but they can also take your planned down
and so they can reduce anxiety.
So my point is this,
there's a book called visual ecological
approach to visual perception was great
book.
Alright Gibson,
Jj Gibson,
Urd member correctly,
and this is,
although I thought of this while back,
I realized eventually that it wasn't
very intelligent.
His theory when he believed was that
when people looked at the world,
you still have value first,
project second.
So for example,
for Gibson,
if you're standing by a cliff,
you don't see a play off and then think
about the fact that you might fall and
then feel free to use a falling off
place.
And part of the seeing of that part of
the act of seeing is being afraid of
that because your eyes are connected
right to your emotional system and part
of what your eyes do is count the
articles,
but your eyes do all sorts of other
things like they comparing fractions,
it prepare you for gripping,
be preparing for emotion.
None of that actually requires the
existence necessarily the existence of
your perception of the object.
So people who are blind sight and if you
show them so they think they can't see,
but if you flash them an angry face,
they'll show a skin conductance
response.
And that's because the visual pathways
to the Amygdala,
which does face facial emotional
processing and still be active.
These are people usually have a stroke
so your eyes are okay,
but they've destroyed the visual cortex.
So.
So anyways,
it's perfectly plausible and at least at
one level of analysis,
when you look at something,
you see it's utility first.
So you see a chair and you might say
Cheddar is an object,
but I wouldn't say that beanbag chair
and the stump is a chair and they don't
share much in common except that you can
sit on it and so you know the chair is
the chair is basically conceptualized by
its functional utility and when you look
at a chair,
what you perceive is its function
utility and the chair tells you what to
do.
It says sit on me and so and there are
people who have pre frontal damage and
they engage in something called
utilization behavior.
If they're walking down the hallway,
a door open,
they have to walk through it.
It can not do what the object tells them
to do.
That's called utilization behavior.
So that's how the world is laid out.
And I would say inside that don't mean
you're in a predictable world.
You're in the world that you understand
that,
that you know,
and then if you hit an obstacle or if
you're outside that domain,
you're in the unknown.
You're in unknown territory.
In the mythological world in the world,
for you could conceptualize the world as
a stage for an option
and
this is a shakespearean quote that sort
of sums it up quite nicely.
All the world's a stage and all the men
and women merely players,
they have their exits and their
entrances and one man in his time plays
many parts and you might say,
well,
is that really true?
And the answer to that is only depends
on what you mean by truth and now really
is the answer because there are
different ways of defining truth.
So,
and it isn't self evident that there's
only one way of defining true that's
appropriate.
You know,
the truth might be more like a tool and
you know,
we are a tool using creatures and
reading.
What we're trying to do with our
conceptions of truth is to work through
the world successfully.
So even science is supporting it
shouldn't be subordinate to our use of
the world as a tool because if it isn't
useful tool,
like what are we doing with it?
You know,
just generating technology that might
destroy the world.
That seems like a bad idea,
so,
so I think that the world has to o is
actually the fundamental sort of truth
and I think that that's a Darwinian
idea,
right?
That to our notions about the world have
evolved through a Darwinian process and
that it's appropriate for us to regard
as what is most real.
Those things that reliably ensure are a
continuation of our life and the
probability of our propagation and if
you're a true Darwinian,
I don't think there's a way out of that
argument and it isn't self evident by
any stretch of the imagination that
seeing the world as well as objects is
the way that our brain works.
In fact,
I don't think it's the way it works at
all and I think that that's why we're so
wired for stories,
right?
It's a mystery.
You know,
like you won't line up for two hours to
go see a lecture,
but you'll line up for two hours.
Maybe you'll even camp overnight if
you're mythological imagination has been
seized for God only knows what reason.
By Star Wars and you know that's a
source of mythologies.
It's the mythology of the modern person
and it fills a gap and that's why people
do it
so that to me speaks of men,
the manner in which our psyches are
constructed and that's a union idea.
That's the idea of the archetype
essentially,
that to be human is to participate in a
certain pattern of being and that that
pattern of being is acting out socially.
It's not individually,
but it's also part of your structure.
Even your perceptual structure as a as a
living organism of your particular type,
and it wouldn't be the case at least
depart for the hero myth which is go out
where no one has gone before.
Face the terrors of the unknown,
gather something of value and return is
the central story pub.
It's not the only central story,
but it's.
It's out there in the top three.
Many of the dram and if you engage
yourself in are variations of that
story.
Can you watch it over and over and over
because you're trying to learn how to do
that.
If that's what you need to do to live.
Okay,
okay,
here's the,
here's your Nike.
What's common among people?
Well,
the self conscious,
we know of our own existence that we
know have our own limitations and so
that means that he has a certain innate
terror and fragility.
Our,
our,
our existence is a problem to us and in
some sense what we're trying to do when
we search for meaning is to search for a
solution to that problem and that can be
security,
but it can also be molded.
So for example,
being engaged in something worthwhile
seems to be a good medicine for being
fragile,
you know,
because it's like,
well I'm doing this.
It seems worthwhile and the fact that
there's a price to be paid for it and
things can be followed me.
The darn good I'm willing to put up with
that because what I'm engaged in seems
to be appropriate.
A sufficient significance to justify all
that.
We all become self conscious and we're
all trying to do something about that.
Figure out how we deal with it.
So there's a landscape that we inhabit,
I would say within which that takes
place,
the human being self conscious job,
too tragic and doomed to be aware of the
human being has two elements and that's
the element that seeks to go.
Then there's the other element that
seeks,
I would say
revenge and destruction and we have our
reasons.
You don't.
If something tragic happens,
students tragic and unfair,
and it really brings the low probability
that you're going to become resentful
and want revenge is extraordinarily high
and no wonder and you know the
archetypal representation is not as evil
itself and the archetypal representation
of good if you could do is the hero.
And so those things in habits,
permanent elements of the human psyche
and then what else is universal to us?
Well,
we live in a society.
You can say that's deep,
that's deep.
It's not just human society like we've
lived in a society forever so you don't.
Lobsters don't have the time and they
used their serotonin system at least in
part to keep track of their dominance
position.
And so you can use antidepressants on
lobsters when they get defeated.
They don't feel so bad for being
defeated in a fight,
and so you just think about that because
any depressants do the same thing to us.
We're so bloody social that the circuits
that evolved 300 million years ago when
the lobsters in us headed shared
ancestor are still operating at the base
of your brain.
Now,
my status is so important to people and
reputation mean that serotonin system
governs your emotional regulation.
How people respond to you.
Okay,
thank you man.
That matters.
That's why you're on facebook all the
time and checking your texts and
obsessing continually about your online
presence.
As soon as soon as you're doing that,
you know,
contacting people frantically and seeing
what the updates are.
It's like where are where?
How are you held in the esteem of
others?
Very,
very important and that's because it
determines your emotional regulation.
It's really important.
So we exist in a society always and this
society as to elements,
the tyrannical element of the society
that would be the tyrannical king.
Roughly speaking a very common.
Here's the logical theme.
You see that in the lion king to right?
If that scar and of course you see it in
the real world almost continually and
then the benevolent king who is the
source of all the good things about
culture,
you know,
and you can see these things play out
August mythologies in political terms.
So I would say for example,
continually harping about the oppressive
nature of the Patriarchy is part of a
myth.
And the myth is that society is
oppressive.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
obviously you know because you have to
be quite a bit like you and you have to
be quite a bit like you even if you're
not so that you can get along great.
Everybody sacrifices a tremendous amount
of their individuality to the common,
to the common motive being asked.
There's a tyrannical element to that,
but by the same token,
it's the basis of cooperation and the
stability of society.
And then the final element is perhaps
often represented in a masculine manner
by the way,
society.
And I think that's because our primary
domicile structures,
given the creatures we are like
chimpanzees.
The primary structures of dominance are
masculine and then outside of what's
known is the unknown.
And we always have to contend with that
and it's wonderful in that it's the
source of all new things and it's
terrible in the place where all the
things that destabilize you've come
from.
And so this is a good representation,
although not the only one.
So that's the feminine
nature,
that's the masculine order and that's
the individual who's destined to suffer
in the grasp of those two things.
Finish this next time.
Yup.
All right,
good enough.
We'll see you next time.
Okay.
So today to begin with,
we're going to finish
the last lecture and then with any luck,
we're going to start the next one
fanatically late anyways.
Well you know what?
All the lectures for the next call for
the whole course,
hopefully we'll be thematically linked
it to some degree given the knowledge,
they're about the same topic,
but some are more types of late.
So I started telling you
last week about this idea of the voyage
to the underworld and I want to tell you
a little bit more about that
young in particular,
conceptualize the voyage to the
underworld as a journey into the
unconscious and the unconscious.
For the psychoanalyst is a place of
fantasy and dream and implicit
presupposition and habit.
That's all crap.
There is an unconscious and
it's perfectly reasonable to
conceptualize it that way.
That's the big difference,
I think,
between the psychoanalysts and the later
more empirical scientists is that the
psychoanalysts sort of envisioned your
psyche's as a place of living partial
personalities instead of cognitive
computational systems that they took
into account.
The fact that you're alive and the parts
of you are alive and you know there's a
neuroscientist named Gavin.
They
don't know how to say his name guys in
India.
That's wrong.
Does that,
is that and go?
Yeah,
I think that's it.
Anyways,
he did some of the earliest experiments
on split brains and so sometimes if you
have intractable epilepsy,
which I wouldn't recommend by the way,
I'm one of the surgical procedures for
mediating gets negative effects.
There's something called a cut the
corpus callosum and it's very large
number,
a very large structure in the brain that
connects the two separate hemispheres.
And No,
it's not obvious why we have two
separate hemispheres,
although I'll probably do a little bit
about why I think it is,
but anyways,
they do communicate.
And uh,
what is that Nigga
demonstrated was that you could tell one
hemisphere something without the other
one knowing that both hemispheres we're
conscious and that the consciousness was
somewhat independent.
Really strange.
It's very interesting.
It makes very interesting reading,
reading,
you know,
because it suggests that fragments of
ourselves,
you can think of,
you have fragments of yourself within
you that are like low resolution
representations of,
you know,
and the,
and the psychoanalysts would think of
those more as they're kind of like,
they're kind of like one giant.
That might be a way of thinking about if
you were thinking about it in a
fantastical way.
So there's the angry you and you know,
you all come into contact with the angry
you.
It's a rather rigid.
That's the first thing you might say
about it.
It's impulsive than short term.
It doesn't take much about the past
unless it's bad things about whoever
you're angry at,
in which case it makes them a lot.
It's not too concerned with longterm
future consequences and mostly at wants
to be right
and you know when angry you disappears
and normal view,
assuming such a thing exists,
reappears.
You can be perfectly shocked about how
angry you behave and in fact sometimes
if angry you really gets out of hand
like it might in a battle and the war.
It might do things that you just can't
imagine that you would do.
And under those circumstances you can
reveal parts of yourself to yourself
that are so foreign and so horrifying
that it will leave you with
posttraumatic stress disorder because it
is the case that
many but not all.
People who suffer from post traumatic
stress disorder especially it's
battlefield related,
get it because of something they did
rather than something they saw or
something that happened to them.
And that's really we're thinking about.
You know,
I mean there's a lot of weird potential
nested inside people and you know,
you don't see it under normal
circumstances because the circumstances
are normal and part of the reason that
we like the circumstances to be normal
is precisely so that we don't see those
parts of people we don't want to see.
And that's really,
you were knowing.
It's really worth knowing because
that's why people are so identified with
your culture,
why they need a coach.
You know,
the terror management theorists types.
It kind of think of culture as a
mechanism that inhibits anxiety.
Think about it psychologically,
like it's something inside your your
hand,
let's say,
um,
and it gives meaning to advanced and
stops you from collapsing into chaos and
protects you from death anxiety.
But
that isn't done right.
It's sort of right.
But that isn't what your culture is.
Your culture is a set of value Laden
presuppositions that you orient yourself
in the world that match the set of Value
Laden presuppositions.
But everyone in your culture has and
acts out.
And so what that means is that when you
believe something and you're among your
own people,
you believe something implicitly,
the way you look at the world and the
way you act things out,
you act about everyone expects you to
act the bowel,
they're happy about it,
in fact.
So there's a match between what you're
doing,
what you see and what you're doing and
what other people expect.
And it's that matched,
that regulates your emotions.
It's not the belief system,
it's the match.
And so part of the reason that people
are so tied to their cultural identity
is because their cultural identity
regulates their emotions and in a
profound way like this is no joke.
You know what I mean?
One of the things that stabilizes human
nervous systems is that you have a
domain of competence.
There's many domains of competence.
And of course in some of those domains
you're completely incompetent,
but they met me not matter because you
don't go into that domain.
So you have some area of specialization
which you might think of as your sub
tribe.
You know your university students.
And so some of you are lower status by
the rules of the university game and
some of you are higher status by the
rules of the university gate by the
tribe.
And so the higher status people tend to
be the ones who fit into the academic
environment,
you know,
and,
and find it conducive to their mode of
being and all who also do well and their
serotonin levels rise.
And you know,
the neurochemicals that moderate mood
particularly are serotonergic.
It's Serotonin,
it's lots of other things.
It's an oversimplification,
but that'll do for now.
As you become dominant in a hierarchy,
your serotonin levels rise.
And what that means is that happy things
make you happier and sad things make you
less sad.
Tunes your nervous system.
So if you're down at the bottom of the
hierarchy,
you have your failing.
It's like,
Hey,
hardly anything makes you happy and
everything makes you nervous.
And it's no wonder because it's not very
good down there.
So
the,
the societal structure which which is an
elaborated dominance hierarchy,
regulates your emotions because of the
match between your expectations and the
behaviors of the people within that
structure,
and then your position within the
hierarchy regulates the rate ratio.
Let's say empty intensity between
positive and negative emotion,
so you mess with people's status at your
peril and you disrupt their culture.
They don't like that and no wonder
because when it's disrupted,
they fall into chaos and chaos is just
anxiety.
Anxiety is bad now,
but it's not just anxiety because when
you fall into chaos but things fall
apart for you.
Of course you're uncertain and anxious
because you don't know what the hell is
going on and you don't know where you
are and you don't know what to do.
Pants,
anxiety provoking and maybe you can't
even understand your past property and
more of that.
As I said,
that happens with people could be
trained and so you fall into this state
where nothing is certain.
The way you construe the world isn't
certain and even the way the world is no
longer certain because you don't know
how to act or your actions aren't
working,
and so the world is presenting itself as
something that's chaotic.
It's not just psychological.
The chaos is a weird intermingling of
the chaotic world and the chaotic south
and that's what happens when you get
unemployed,
like devastated,
right?
It's devastating to people and if you
could say,
well,
that's psychological.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
but they're unemployed.
That makes the world far more
incomprehensible and uncertain.
It's not just psychological,
it's psychological and that's bad,
but it's also real and that's even
worse,
and then those two things can spiral,
which they often do because you know if
you don't set your expectations properly
for a drug search and assume that you're
going to get 49 rejections for every
interview,
which you really need to know because if
you get 49 rejections,
it's not because you're useless because
the baseline for rejection is 98 percent
and that's okay because the base rate
for rejection for everything is 98
percent.
No matter what you do,
but you need to know that so that you
don't feel that it's like something
wrong with you.
And of course you only have to get it
right once that India had the job,
that it's a lottery,
but you have to set yourself up.
You have to take,
okay,
well,
I'm going to look for a job.
I need to.
How many resumes can I tolerate?
Sending out a day?
You know,
it has to be enough so you don't feel
like other useless moron and it can't be
so many that you're overwhelmed by the
burden.
So and I help people do this sort of
thing all the time.
So maybe you decide,
well,
you're going to send out 10 a day and
you're going to work two hours on it and
it's going to take six months,
and then you know you've got your
parameters set properly and you would
know what to expect in the world.
And your emotions are regulated and so,
but the state of being unemployed,
it doesn't just produce psychological
consequences.
So the distinction between the psyche
and the world in some sense is quite
arbitrary.
And the psychoanalyst,
I think,
err too much on the side of the subject.
They came to think that too much of you
is inside of you and too little of us
outside.
When part of the reason I believe that
it's because of my clinical experience.
I love the psychoanalyst map.
They're brilliant,
they're brilliant or deep.
They grappled with real problems like
with the problems when people have real
problems and I need profound problems.
There really profound moral problems or
problems of good and evil really know
there are things going on in their
family that are so terrible that well
the terrible.
There are some times fabled lie upon lie
upon,
lie upon lie for decades and decades and
decades.
Awful.
And that's not exactly inside them.
It's out there in the world and lots of
the people that I see,
very famous critic of psychology,
I can't remember his name,
but I probably will
criticize practice of psychology quite
effectively in the believe in the early
sixties.
The Myth of mental illness by Thomas sat
as zed,
a s zed.
It's classic.
You should read it if you're interested
in psychology reading like it's.
It's a classic and he basically said
most people have problems in living.
They don't have psychological problems,
and so I've experienced,
despite my love for the psychoanalysts,
very frequently what I'm doing as a
therapist is helping people have a life
that would work.
You know,
and you can parameterize that.
It's like,
what do you need?
How about some friends that will kind of
like that?
How about an intimate relationship with
someone that you can trust that maybe
has a future?
That'd be good.
How about a career that puts you in a
dominance hierarchy somewhere so at
least you've got some possibility of
rising,
some possibility of stabilizing yourself
and their schedule and a routine because
no one can live without a routine.
You just forget that if you guys don't
have a routine,
I would recommend you get one going
because you cannot be mentally healthy
without a routine.
You need to pick a time to get up
whatever time you want,
but pick one and stick to it because
otherwise you've disregulate your
circadian rhythms and they regulate your
mood and eat something.
In the morning.
I had lots of clients that anxiety
disorders are one client who was
literally starving.
Very smart girl,
cheat.
There's very little that she liked.
She kind of tried to subsist on like
half a cup of rice a day.
She came to me and said,
I have no energy.
I come home and all I want to do is
watch the same movie over and over.
What is that weird?
And I thought,
well,
it depends about rj work,
you know,
it's weird,
but whatever familiar is looking for
comfort.
So I did an analysis of her diet.
It's like three quarters of a cup of
rice.
It's like you're starving,
eat something,
you know,
you'll feel better.
So she modified her diet and they're all
or anxiety went away and she had some
energy.
It's like,
yeah,
so schedule.
That's a good thing man.
And your brain will thank you for it.
It will stabilize your nervous system
with a bit of a plan.
That's a good thing.
You need a career.
You need something productive to do with
your time.
You need to regulate your use of drugs
and alcohol.
Most particularly the alcohol because
that does eat a lot of people
in your family,
like the family,
you have your parents and all that.
It'd be nice if you all got along.
You could work on that.
That's a good thing to work on.
Then you know what?
You probably need children at some point
and that's life.
That's what life is and if you're
missing,
you know you may have a good reason to
not be operating on one of those
dimensions.
It's not mandatory,
but I can tell you that if you're not
operating reasonably well on four,
I think I mentioned six,
if you're not operating reasonably well
on at least three of them,
there's no way you're going to be
psychologically thriving and that's more
pragmatic in some sense than
psychological.
Like human beings have a nature.
There's things we need and if we have
them well that's good and if we don't
have them well then we feel the lack.
So behaviorists,
behavioral psychologists concentrated a
lot more on that sort of thing.
No.
What's practical strategizing?
Make a career plan,
figuring out how to negotiate because
that's bloody important.
Figuring out how to say what you need,
figure out how to tell the truth,
figuring out how to listen to your
partner in particular because if you
listen to them,
they will actually tell you what they
want and sometimes you can give it to
them and maybe they'll return the favor
and if you practice that for like 15
years,
well then maybe you don't constantly
giving each other what you want.
Well Hooray.
That would be good.
And then there's two of you.
Under most circumstances,
it's better to have two brains than one
because people think differently because
of their temperament mostly.
And so the negotiation is where the
wisdom arises and it's part of the
transformation,
the psychological transformation that's
attendant on an intimate relationship
and one of the fundamental purposes of a
long term intimate relationship.
Anyways.
When that falls apart,
chaos ensues and that's why is
represented so continually and myths and
stories,
and I'm going to walk you through a bit
of that more today.
I talked about the story of Jonah.
Now,
here's something to think about.
The internal representations of language
meaning evolve partly from our pre
linguistic ancestor's knowledge of
social relations like modern monkeys and
apes.
Our ancestors lived in groups with
intricate networks of relationships that
were simultaneously competitive and
cooperative.
The demands of social life created
selective pressures for just the kind of
complex,
abstract,
conceptual and computational abilities
that are likely to have proceeded.
The earliest forms of linguistic
communication.
Although baboons have concepts and
acquire propositional information from
other animals,
vocalizations,
they can articulate this information.
They understand dominance,
relationships,
and matrilineal kinship,
but they have the words for them.
This suggests that the internal
representation of many concept
relations,
an actual action sequences does not
require language and the language did
not evolve because it was uniquely
suited to represent the thought.
Well.
You know,
you can think without laying well,
take the case of someone who's deaf and
mute.
They have no language.
Well,
they can operate in society,
they learn how to represent other people
and they do that with image.
Now,
the postmodernists who I
despised would be a reasonable way of
putting it,
have this proposition that there's no
meaning outside language and it's a
powerful argument by the way,
but it's seriously wrong.
There is a meaning network outside of
language and it's what language is
grounded in and that's this pre verbal
comprehension of the world.
It's an embodied comprehension.
The world animals have lobsters have it,
you know,
this particular scientists say far
talks about our shared history with
higher primates.
That probably goes back 20 million
years,
something like that slip from the common
ancestor with chimps about 7 million
years ago.
Um,
but you know,
lobsters have dominance hierarchies.
They are,
they have a nervous system at all,
which is partly what you're studying
quite extensively.
And so they have a social structure and
they understand it.
Like at one lobster,
you're a lobster to be quite a shock to
you.
If it happened and you were fighting
with another lobster and you lost,
you would remember that.
And the next time you saw that lobster,
you'd scuttle off somewhere else and you
know that.
And all the lobsters and an area.
No,
who's taught lobster and who isn't.
And Pop lobster gets the best bloody
place to be.
And the best food.
So this dominance issue,
this cultural issue,
the fact that we live in a social
environment is far deeper than people
usually consider it.
It's also worth considering.
This is what you might think of from an
evolutionary perspective.
You know,
you think of natural selection as
producing evolution,
right?
Well,
random mutation with natural selection.
But here's something to think about.
And Darwin knew this,
but Darwin was really smart and the
biologists who followed in his
footsteps,
even up to now,
I've only expanded out a fraction of
what he had the same.
You know,
he was very interested in sexual
selection.
Now one of the things about human beings
that's unique is that human females are
picky majors.
You're choosing a.
they're also sneaky because you cannot
tell when they're articulating and with
many other female animals,
you know,
so
they have hidden ovulation and their
choosing and they tend to choose men who
are more successful in the dominance
arch.
Well,
there there is a shock.
I mean you have a choice.
Why don't
you pick someone who's at the bottom of
the competence hierarchy,
all that's probably not going to work
out very well for you and since women
bear the burden of reproduction,
it's perfectly reasonable for them to
search out someone who's going to be
helpful,
so productive,
fair,
generous,
and you know when you think of a
dominance hierarchy,
you might think,
well it's the powerful guy.
The aggressive guy say that rises to the
top of the dominance hierarchy.
That's not true.
It's not even true among chimps.
Like you can get a chimp tyrant,
but then what happens is other chimps
ganging up on him and tear him to pieces
and they don't do it nicely.
They don't do it nicely.
And the chimps that tend to maintain
their dominance for long periods of time
have a pretty wide network of friends.
Roughly speaking with whom they engage
in reciprocal interactions like grooming
and they actually pay a lot of positive
attention to the female chimps who have
their own hierarchy by the way and to
their offspring.
So they're like baby kissing
politicians.
And so the idea that it's raw power that
produces dominance is a,
it's just wrong.
It's wrong.
Now,
you know,
tyrants pretty damn of unstable business
being a tyrant.
There's lots of people who want to kill
you.
Plus,
you know,
you tend to rule over something
approximating Pale.
So maybe that's why we're better than
being a subject in hell,
but it's not much better.
So anyway,
so this social social now,
so what this means,
think about this for a minute.
So imagine,
imagine what I tell you.
Bear some resemblance to the truth.
I think there's quite a lot of evidence
for it from a,
from a biological perspective.
I mean,
this choosy mating thing occurs with
lots of species.
You know,
here's this bird called the bower bird.
You've got to look up bower birds,
man.
Those things are,
you just can't even believe they exist.
And so when the Mayo Bower Bird,
he makes this really complicated nest
that's close to the ground.
He weaves it.
It's really quite nice.
You couldn't make one.
So.
And then he sweeps this the yard in
front of the nest and then he runs
around the forest or flies because he
has a bird finding pretty things.
So maybe he'll find a nice collection of
red leaves.
And so they'd helped take the red leaves
one by one and fly back to his front
door and make a little square.
You know,
he's a bird so it's not a great square,
but it makes a little patch of red and
he takes a look at that and then he goes
off and find something blue and had he
decorates it,
makes a little piece of abstract art in
the front of his nest.
And a lot of male bowerbirds do this all
at the same time.
And so then the females come along,
they hop on something nearby and they
kind of look at it like this,
check it out.
And if they're happy with it,
well then things proceed.
But if they're not,
they'd fly off to someone else's piece
of abstract art and if a mail piece of
already rejected by like three females
in a row,
he gets irritated and brushes it all off
with his weight and then he makes
another one.
It's like,
well,
they obviously have a sense of a very
well developed sense of beauty.
It's so cool.
You know,
and I guess the idea is that who knows
what the hell the ID is,
the female birds,
like artistic mail,
something like that.
But if you're thinking about it
biologically,
maybe it's an indication of
intelligence,
right?
It's a marker of intelligence.
It's certainly the case that female
humans prefer creative men.
So wonder horse.
We wouldn't be creative if that wasn't
the case.
So that imagine that there's two primary
forces of evolutionary selection
operating on us and they're not really
the natural world,
which is what people always think like
the environment,
you know,
the animals and the trees and nature.
But it isn't nature that selected us.
It's to other things.
Partly it's two things.
So one is the dominance hierarchy.
The male dominance hierarchy is one of
the primary mechanisms of selection,
so it's like,
oh,
women are faced with a hard choice.
Which guided laughter,
right?
That's a hard choice.
Well,
so they do the same thing that people do
with the stock market.
They outsourced the cognitive problems,
the computational problem to the male
dominance hierarchy.
Then they just let the mail sort
themselves out however they're going to
and then the appeal from the top and so
what that means is the dominant male
dominance hierarchy itself is a
selection mechanism because if you fail
at it,
then you don't leave any offspring and
so what that means is at least in part,
is that we have adapted to be better and
better at attaining status in dominance
hierarchies.
God only knows how long a period of time
and that doesn't mean just power.
You know what it might mean?
Cognitive flexibility because you could
imagine,
do you want me to its hierarchy a
dominance hierarchy,
b dominance,
hierarchy seeds.
Okay,
so if like if you're really successful,
you've climb up dominance hierarchy a
right,
but you'd be in seat.
No.
If you have the landing,
those you just be a failure,
so then you could say the ideal human
being as someone who can climb to the
top of a dominance hierarchy,
no matter what the dominance hierarchy
is,
right?
So we've evolved to.
We've evolved such that success across
the set of possible dominance
hierarchies is the target and I think
that's why we have general intelligence
because general intelligence is a
general problem solving mechanism and
it's a single factory,
but there is intelligence is a single
factor.
It's not divisible despite what people
like
Robert Sternberg and Howard Gardner
falsely played.
So and then from the female perspective,
females are the next gate keeper and
that's why they're often.
Mother Nature took me a long time to
figure this out.
Why the hell is it nature?
Feminine,
multiple representations,
so very various.
It's extraordinarily common mother
nature.
You don't think a father of Mother
Nature.
It's like why?
Well,
nature brings forth new forms,
so that's feminine.
Nature selects in fact,
that's the definition of nature.
From a Darwinian perspective.
Nature is that which selects women
select their nature and that's partly
why far more men than you might think,
like far more terrified of women because
to be rejected as a romantic partner by
a woman is to be classified as vaguely
acceptable life form.
Huh?
No value in propagating.
All
right,
so it's a major,
major rejection and no,
I've had
some clients and many,
many people write to me whose primary
problem is that?
They're so careful.
Women,
they can't even approach them.
Very,
very,
very cool.
So alright,
I'm going to show you this little
triangle thing.
Cool.
Okay.
So your no nonverbal,
right?
Nonverbal.
So what happened?
Well,
here's mother triangle.
I'm guess mother triangle has circle as
a child and triangle
is maybe a friend,
but not one that's very welcome.
According to mother and a
child circled was trying to play with
triangle filed and mother doesn't like
that.
So she goes out there and pecks the hell
out of them,
chases them away,
pushes child circle back into that hole,
goes into the that.
And then Charles Circle isn't very happy
about that.
Running around causing trouble and it
manages to escape and then bad child
train shows up and they play together
and run around and run around and run
around and run around with mother
chasing them and then they will.
Maybe they elope.
Who knows,
and then mother triangle has it fit and
blood was in the house,
right?
Reasonable.
Would you consider that a reasonable
story about what happened?
Perhaps you had other interpretations,
but I suspect they were vaguely along
that line,
but the point here is the point of this
experiment is how much information do
you need from which to derive the
narrative and the answer is like none.
It just.
It's just immediate.
You can watch some triangles moving
around a box and instantly you
personalize it and that's because that's
what your life and the reason you're
like that is because your environment
isn't nature.
Your environment,
these culture,
your environment is other people,
other people,
and that was even more true for
chimpanzees and so forth that especially
animals that had a limited diet like
gorillas,
they pretty much all eat leaves.
You know what?
Chimps spends like 12 hours a day
chewing and that's where they have got
like this.
It's like you can't eat leaves,
you know,
have you tried,
they have no nutrition,
so if you're going to eat leads,
you have to eat a lot of them and then
it takes like three months to digest.
And so what we've done,
and this is pretty cool because smart is
that we've traded gut for brain and
that's what we're so spelled and the way
we manage that it appears is that we
learned how to use fire to cook things
and that meant that we had high quality
nutrition much higher.
It's easier to digest things especially
neat.
And so because we invented fire,
we didn't have to have so much in test
items.
We could spend a little more time on the
brain.
So human beings really are fire users.
We invented fire or discovered it or
mastered it at least a couple of million
years for a long time.
So that's all pretty cool as far as I'm
concerned.
So that's partly how we think
and that's naturally how you think.
You think a certain way.
And so we'll say that your fundamental
architecture is social cognitive,
you tend to view the world as a persona.
And the reason for that is that the
world in which you emerge as a being was
primarily social.
What you needed to know was who's the
big primate,
who's the little primate,
who's related to who,
you know,
among chimps.
If a big chimp is threatened by a small
chip,
well,
you know,
the big chimp just care this small chip
party,
but the big chimp will back off if it
knows that the little chimp is
associated with some really big chimps.
And so the little chip can bowling the
big chimp because it's part of a
dominant family.
And that's because the nervous system of
the big gym doesn't respond to the
little chimp,
like a little chimp.
It responds to the little chimp,
like it's a little chimp with four great
monsters attached to it because it's
true.
So it's nervous system is actually
responding to the network around the
champion.
And so that's exactly what you.
Well,
it's not exactly what you're like
because you're not chips,
but you know,
it's that kind of platform that
constitutes the evolutionary
underpinnings of your psyche.
So what does that mean?
Well,
it means this is like perfectly fine to
us,
right?
Can animate things.
Rabbits are people.
No problem.
We'll go along with that.
You remember Roger Rabbit,
I presume most of you watch that.
So this is the detective who's name I
don't remember.
He asked to go to toontown because
there's cartoons and there's people and
they share the same world.
And you could go into toontown the.
It's kind of annoying because cartoon
figures,
they're kind of annoying,
like slapstick types and so he's very
happy to be there.
And this is what it looks like.
Everything's animated,
meaning alive.
Anima means soul underway.
So everything has a personality and you
know when you're reading books to kids,
his son has a personality,
train,
has a personality,
Jeff has a personality.
It doesn't matter what it is,
it has a personality and that's because
the child is learning to understand the
world using the architecture,
social,
cognitive,
architecture and so.
And the thing that's really interesting
about that,
it's just blows me away,
know evolution is conservative and so
once it's produced something it has to
build on it.
It's like dos the operating system.
It's like really?
It's still there.
If I remember correctly,
under windows 10 you can get rid of the
damn thing because it's part part of the
structure down and it's like the
keyboards we use,
which are actually designed to slow
typers down because with mechanical type
writers,
if you type too fast,
the keys with jam.
So they divided device,
the keyboard to slow you down and we
still use it,
which is stupid,
you know,
you want the high frequency letters
close to your middle fingers.
That's what it's like at all.
But we can't change it because everyone
uses it.
So your body plan,
that thing has been around a long time,
man.
If you look at mammals particular,
anybody even lizard,
there's so much like us in their,
in their skeletal structure that is just
mind boggling,
you know,
enroll variants of the same
symmetrical four legged.
How here structure.
And so you have to build a what you
have,
and if you have a social cognitive
architecture,
then you have to first understand the
world through the social cognitive
categories.
And what sort of bloody strange about
that is it actually seems to work.
We actually seem to develop a coherent
representation of being.
I would say I'm being.
That's not the same as nature.
It's not the same as the world because
when we think of the world we think of
the objective world,
and I'm not talking about the objective
world,
I'm talking about the world of human
experience.
And we see that through social cognitive
filter and it makes perfect sense to us
and it works.
That's so strange.
So anyways,
everything's got this animated nature
and we don't have a problem with that
fact.
We actually find it quite fun.
No people go visit the Disney toontown
and participate in it to have fun with
it.
And so that shows you as well how,
how natural it is for us to view things
this way.
You know,
cars have faces,
right?
Designers know that.
They know that people don't want a car
with three headlights because like who
wants to be associated with the three
eyed monster?
No one.
It's like two eyes.
That's something you could be
comfortable with.
And so cars have faces,
BMW's and the new ones,
they really look cat like you know,
and they have sexy curves.
They do,
they do.
There's been MRI studies of that.
So
if you show man photographs of
attractive women looking directly at
them,
there's a little part of the brain
called the nucleus accumbens that lights
up because to have someone look directly
at you,
especially if they have like a smile.
It is interpreted as an invitation to
approach and women,
they have the same damn problem because
with women,
because if you go into drugstores saying
you look at women's magazines,
they're all the same.
They've all evolved to the same
endpoint.
They all have an attractive woman on
them,
all of them,
and they're looking right out.
And so when women see that,
they actually see it as something to
approach.
It's an ideal.
And now you know,
people say that those beauty ideals are
oppressive to women.
All ideals are oppressive,
but the empirical research,
some of it down here suggests that
interacting with those images
helps the performance,
the psychological function of helping
the woman to equate yourself with the
ideal and in most cases that actually
produces a pop and elevation in mood and
you know,
think about it.
You're really going to go to the
magazine store when you're just looking
for something to do and you're going to
buy something that makes you feel
depressed and the oppressed.
It's like,
no,
you're not going to do that.
Magazines that do that to you,
they will die because no one will buy
them and there's a reason they all
turned out the same way.
It's like they're just responding to
demand.
So
faces.
Oh yes,
with regards to the sexy curves,
so
woman who looks woman's picture looking
right at us,
man,
we'll produce this activation in the
primary reward system.
Cocaine produces the same response and
Sodas,
sports cars,
especially curvy red sports car.
So that's why you often see an
attractive woman sitting on a curvy red
sports car in an APP because it's,
you know,
if there's an ad for beer on the side,
it's like,
hey,
everything's perfect.
So,
and you know,
those are all primary reward
representations that may produce
attraction because part of positive
emotion,
the Dopa beneath filament,
urgently mediated element of positive
emotion isn't approach emotion.
It's not a satiation satisfaction
emotion.
It's all good.
There's something good here I can move
towards.
And that that is what happiness is.
That's directed what happiness is.
It's not attaining something because
that just puts you in a whole new
problem.
You got to figure out what to do next.
All right,
so I suggested to you
that one of the problems that we have,
that problem,
I would say is not what the world is
made out of,
but how we should be in the world
because we're alive and how we should
be.
Well,
it's fairly straightforward.
Not so much pain would be good.
That'd be good.
Not Too much anxiety.
Hey,
we're on board for that.
I'm little pleasure down then some
stability,
uh,
not dying.
That's a big one.
And then let's say from a Darwinian
perspective,
propagate.
And so that's what Raymond out.
And the reason we did that is you just
think about this,
it's so amazing.
So every single one of your,
of the relatives you have in your
ancestry,
every single one of them
successfully produced a child who
successively successfully produced a
child all the way back to 3 billion
years ago.
It's bloody unbelievable.
Like the probability that you exist.
Well,
it's 100 percent because there you are,
but the probability of predicting that
you would exist,
you know,
if you tried to get predicted,
it's like the chance that the chances
that you're here so infinite testable,
that it's just absolutely mind boggling.
Think about that unbroken sequence of
success over literally over billions of
years.
God,
it's amazing.
And so you have to,
obviously you have to think that there's
a pretty strong proclivity for that to
happen.
I mean,
some of that,
obviously it was a necessity,
but not only that,
I mean it's necessary that impregnated
females have an infant.
It isn't necessary that they keep it
alive so you can account for that
continuity.
Mary,
from necessity,
you have to interject at least a small
amount of consideration that the care
that's associated,
especially with taking care of infants
because they're,
you know,
there are a lot of work that's there to
say this.
It's actually,
I think it's manifested in the
personality trait.
Agreeableness looks to be like
agreeableness is one of the dimensions
were admitting women very most
substantially.
Agreeableness looks to be like the
manifestation of the maternal instinct.
Now men can be agreeable to because of
course male human beings to take care of
children.
You know,
you're a grizzly bear female.
You just chase the damn mail away
because he'll kill your cups.
That's not so helpful,
but they're not maternal at all.
Quite the contrary.
But you know,
human manner are pretty damn maternal.
They're not as a wait a minute on
average,
although some women are less maternal
than some men because you know the
curves overlap.
But on balance,
how are we in the world?
Well,
we're aware of our own vulnerability,
who are aware of our own shortcomings,
let's say,
and that's I think that's partly from
being a social being because people are
always signaling your shortcomings to
you to such a degree that you even say
go your shortcomings to yourself because
while you might as well fix them before
someone else points them out,
that's guilt and know when Freud called
that the Superego,
the superego is kind of like the
internalized representation of the
judgmental father and culture I think is
represented as a father figure.
God,
the father dies say because it's
actually.
It's actually quite a bit like there
isn't all CNI and it's all of these
watching you.
It's a really,
really intelligent way of
conceptualizing it because the group
which is more or less eternal is
watching you all the time,
all the time.
And it's judging all the time.
And we know that if you put people in a
room when you put a pig eye on the ball,
you know nick,
you give them an opportunity to cheat on
some little cheesy thing.
You know,
nothing too important.
If they're in the room with the big guy,
they're less likely to cheat if they're
in the room with no light at all,
so you know,
and what do you do?
You keep an eye on your kids and the
reason you do that and so they don't
misbehave and we keep an eye on each
other and so we have a representation of
that and as far as I can tell,
we represented as a transcendent figure
of judgment and just like.
Yeah,
Hey,
that's a pretty good metaphor.
So
one of the.
This is a major intellectual about the
major intellectual and it's raging in
universities.
It's basically a battle between post
modernism and traditional and tradition.
I think that's the right way of thinking
about it for the postmodernists.
Human beings have no nature.
We're blank slates and everything that
we are as inculturating,
so we're completely malleable and all
elements of our identity or going on the
other side are the traditionalists who
are,
I would say grounded more in
biology on the one hand,
but also in historical
humanities tradition that suggests that
people have in nature.
I explained some of that nature.
Most people want to have friends as part
of your nature,
you know,
most people want to find love part of
your nature and you suffer without it,
so you know,
he could say those are all social
constructs,
but
you can say you can say anything so you
know,
and
no one ever trust someone who has one
explanation for everything.
You know,
how much intelligence does that take?
You got one explanation.
You just try to note for every
phenomena,
this is an alternative.
Now,
here's what happened in part
nature.
Back in the late 18,
hundreds was very interested in the
disillusion of traditional faith and in
the West we fell out of our myth.
That's a way of thinking about it.
You start believing in its fundamental
axioms was he stopped believing that
there was such a thing as a transcendent
deity.
For example,
if you didn't mesh well with the
emerging scientific viewpoint,
and so in the late 18 hundreds,
Nietzsche announced the depth of God,
which sounds fairly presumptuous,
but it wasn't something.
He was celebrating the full quote and I
haven't gotten it exactly right.
His thoughts here,
we've killed them and we'll never find
enough water to wash away the rivers of
blood like that.
It's a lot different than what you see
scrawled on bathroom walls and meet you.
Apply that in the 20th century.
Millions of people would die in the
conflicts over what values we're going
to reign as an alternative to that
tradition,
and he particularly brilliantly
pointed to communism.
He said that's where it's going to be,
and dusty,
she did the same thing and so
since then there's this been this battle
and the battle is kind of like this.
The battle is on the one hand between
social construction,
social constructionist utopians who
believed that human nature is infinitely
malleable and that with the proper
transformation since society,
you can bring the part about the perfect
state in the perfect human being and
and traditionalists
and you and I think is the classic
example of this who believed that there
is a human nature and it's deeply
embedded within us and that the culture
is we set up,
have to manifest themselves in
accordance with that nature or they will
fail.
Oh,
young believed in the existence of a
narrative,
the hero myth,
roughly speaking,
and he explained his connections to
various religious traditions,
staggeringly brilliant manner.
Camille Paglia,
who I would recommend that they picked
already told me that you know,
she,
she's already concluded after going
through a radical feminist period early
in your life,
that the proper way for society to
Orient itself is within a mythological
structure and that that's part of what
the humanities provides
and the alternative is
rational arguments over what values are
going to dominate and it isn't obvious
that rationality can solve that problem.
I don't think it can.
That's humans point.
David Hume said,
you can't derive an entrepreneur is
right.
You cannot use science as a guide to
behavior.
So what do you use?
Instinct,
instinct,
manifested in imagination and the
evolution,
the evolved structure of your organic
cultures,
something like that.
Do they have a structure?
That's the question.
Okay,
so you ask yourself this question,
what is it that every human being shares
regardless of place and time,
so any universally comprehensive
language that would be a Meta narrative,
a myth,
the hero myth.
Let's say a myth about what a human
being not only his life but shouldn't be
asked to speak to us about those aspects
of experience that we all share because
otherwise we just kept the damn story.
Now we go to how we go to the stories
that we understand that all the time
like star wars and it really doesn't
matter what country,
you know,
everybody gets it more legs.
So obviously there are stories that you
can understand and mutually,
you know,
we understand the law of stories.
We understand stories of conflict,
we understand the stories of betrayal,
we understand stories of anger.
And that's because we can feel jealousy.
We can feel love,
we can feel anger.
It's his party.
It's right there.
We even know where the circuits are,
you know,
and then you're like other animals,
they feel that too.
So very similar emotions as far as we
can tell.
So
here's,
this is derived in large part from you,
but not only,
um,
here's what we share,
natural world social world and the fact
of our existence as an individual.
And that can be represented different
ways.
It can be represented as you,
the known and the unknown or it can be
you culture and nature,
all the same representations and the
cultural representation tends to be
male.
That's gone.
Father,
let's say,
and they
representation.
The Feminine Representation tends to be
female.
This is the known
culture apollonian control that's
associated with the sun son
consciousness,
the cane,
the patriarch,
the cloud because it pushes up the
earth.
The Phallus obviously order and
authority and the crushing weight of
tradition,
the wise old man and the tyrant dogma,
the day sky,
the country down the iron heights,
the ancestral spirits,
the activity of the death
Captain Hook.
He's a tyrant and that's why Peter Pan
doesn't want to grow up to become him
and that's why Peter Pan doesn't grow
because he thinks that adults are
pirates.
Why is captain hook a tyrant as a
crocodile?
Laid his hand in the crocodile has a
clock in its stomach and the reason for
that is that the crocodile is time and
time's over and he got a piece of
Captain Hook and he's not very happy
about.
He's bitter and resentful and too
radical,
and when Peter Pan looks out adulthood,
that's what he sees and he thinks,
why should I sacrifice the potential of
childhood for the singularity of
tyranny?
And so we stay as immature his entire
life and he's king of the lost boys.
Jesus break.
There's a porn star named Jeremy.
Can't remember his name.
Really good
guy.
He didn't miss it.
Something funny.
I was watching a documentary about him
and he said the funniest thing.
He said,
alright,
with that hero to people who think
people like me are heroes.
Hey,
what a drag.
I mean,
he's just in this horrible situation.
He doesn't admire the people that admire
him,
but he gets inspired by them all the
time,
but it's sort of like Peter Pan.
It's like,
well,
he's kicking the lost boys.
He doesn't get windy though,
right?
She grows up.
She has family.
He asked to contend himself with
Tinkerbell,
and you know what?
Tinkerbell doesn't exist.
Well,
that's what happens.
You can do it for a lot.
That's a representation of culture.
That's a nasty
hell kiss.
Kiss the statue of Stellar.
Who cares that he murdered 30 million
people culture?
Well,
you know,
in university you hear a lot about the
patriarchy and how oppressive it is.
It's like,
yeah,
definitely.
No,
I'm kidding,
but you know,
it's kind of useful as well as provides
to eat the food.
All of that which kind of
counterbalances to some degree culture
has opposed development.
Tenant take advil,
but the individual has a positive over
the negative element.
Nature has a positive element and a
negative element and if people tell you
a one sided story which has the
ideological story they leave out that
you say all culture is terrible.
Human being or despoiled and nature is
perfect.
It's like no nature kills you.
Culture keeps you alive and there's
things about you that are honorable and
good is wellness.
Things about you can learn and you need
to know both of those.
And that's what the great stories tell
us.
Alright.