Okay,
so
we're actually going to take a step
back.
Historically
talked about Carl Rogers last time
as a phenomenologist.
So we started our brief foray into the
ideas behind phenomenology,
but now we're going to go back in time
the up and we're going to talk about the
end of the 19th century and we're going
to discuss Nietzsche and Dostoevsky and
Kierkegaard in some detail.
And the reason we're going to do that is
because those three men,
I s I would say more than anyone else in
the 19th century laid the groundwork not
only for what would become
psychoanalysis and then later
personality psychology and clinical
psychology,
but they also describe the broader
social,
political and cultural situation that
modern people find themselves in now
and their thought is exceedingly
sophisticated and it's really worth
grasping because if you can get it,
you know,
we're going through these personality
theories one of the time and we're
making,
going to make for reason to biology and
neuro psychology,
you need a structure underneath that.
You need to understand a structure
that's underneath all of that to slot
everything into.
Because that way you can understand it
in more detail.
And so
partly because ideas develop
historically and also an idea as a seed
and out of the seed,
other plants grow and,
and so forth,
the plant grows and so forth and
branches off.
If you can get back down to the origin
point,
then you can often understand the entire
structure more straightforwardly.
And also these three men are so
brilliant that it's,
it's a joy to encounter their thinking
even though it's,
it's very,
very,
uh,
some verses seriously subversive.
So we're going to start with this
diagram,
which you'll remember.
So,
okay.
You're,
so think about this from the Piaget of
perspective.
Like we made the point that as the child
puts itself,
let's say together,
it starts by practicing micro routines,
micro motor routines,
and those are accompanied by perceptual
frameworks.
And,
and also they're incorporated into a
motivational value system because
they're motivated actions.
And then the child practice is
sequencing those micro personalities,
we'll say together to make ever more and
more complex and ever more and more
integrated macro personalities.
And so that's basically what this
diagram describes.
Um,
we were looking at it from an adult
perspective.
So you know,
if you're going to be a good person,
you can decompose being a good person
into sub of being a good person and you
can decode it.
So being a good person as an abstract
ideal,
but as you move closer and closer to the
point where the goodness is manifested
in action,
you move closer and closer to actual
movements in the world.
And so the abstract category good person
is actually made out of,
you could think about it as a very
complex melody of motor motor actions
and perceptions.
Perception is very tightly linked to
motor action because whenever you
perceive anything,
you're doing it in part by actively
investigating world's partly why your
eyes are moving around all the time.
And if,
if you're listening,
you move your head,
you know,
to touch something,
you have to actively investigate it.
So it's always an activity of
exploration.
Now in some ways
when you think about the child piecing,
it's,
it's being together from the bottom up.
You can think about that as a biological
process unfolding.
You know,
and you could take up the child is
crawling and then learning to walk as a
biological process unfolding.
But that's an oversimplification because
human beings exist from day one in a
very,
very social world.
And so what that means is the way that
those behaviors are sub micro
personalities start to organize
themselves is always under the influence
of,
of the society in which they're
embedded.
And so,
you know,
Piaget talked about the child has as,
as being,
uh,
as,
as having reflex basic builtin reflexes
at birth,
and that,
that those reflexes are that elaborate
it up into more and more complex
structures.
But you can think that even the
elaboration of those basic reflexes,
even right from the beginning,
like there's a routing and sucking
reflex,
which you can,
you can listen from a child by tapping
on the side of it's cheap when it's very
new,
newly born,
and it'll search to try to put what's
happening in its mouth.
And that's,
that's,
uh,
that's part of the reflexive process,
the builtin perceptual motor unit that
allows the child to begin to suckle.
Now,
the thing is though,
what it suckling isn't a static and
objective entity.
It's a person.
And part of breastfeeding is the
establishment of a relationship,
a complex relationship.
Because it's also not only a feeding
relationship,
it's a caring relationship.
It's a relationship that's based on
tactile interaction.
There could be nervousness associated
with it.
Uh,
and,
and often is,
especially for a new mother,
it's a very complex dynamics social act.
And so what that means is that right
from the beginning,
in order for the baby to engage in that
process properly,
it has to allow its initial reflects of
movements to be modified by social
necessity immediately.
So for example,
if a baby is breastfeeding,
it can't bite.
And you know,
it doesn't have any teeth.
So being bitten isn't necessarily a
catastrophe,
but it's not pleasant.
And so what will happen if the baby
bites the mother is that the mother will
pull away and startled the baby and then
the baby will cry.
And you know,
the mother will be at least startled by
the,
by the error.
And so the baby has to learn to,
it has to learn to be civilized in some
sense right off the bat.
Now,
you know Freud was talking about the
process of socialization.
He tended to concentrate more on toilet
training.
No,
because he thought of that as the first
place where the first major place where
the ID of the child,
which,
or which Rogers would regard as an
organismic as the organismic
experiential domain is brought under
control of the superego.
Right?
Because at the baby,
obviously it's fundamental biological
function is to relieve itself,
but that has to come under very,
very strict social control.
And it's a,
it's a complex form of learning.
You know,
what's basically the acquisition of
voluntary control over what was here too
for an involuntary reflex essentially.
And so that can go well or it can go
badly and it can vary,
go very badly.
So I,
I knew a family who had a daughter at
one point and that daughter would only
defecate in her diaper when she was
three.
So that meant she had full of voluntary
control of her bowel function,
but there was no way she was going to
participate in the social ritual that
surrounded proper toilet.
There was a war going on like a serious
war.
And that sort of thing happens while not
infrequently.
And of course you remember in the crumb
movie,
the mother,
uh,
the boys accusing the mother of giving
them enemas and her of course denying
that any such thing happened,
which was something that made both of
them roll their eyes,
you know?
And they all laughed,
but it's really not particularly
amusing.
So anyways,
my point is,
is that even at the micro level,
the manifestation of what we'll call
micro personalities expands and
organizes into an environment that's
conditioned by social expectation.
Okay.
So then,
then,
and this is something we haven't talked
about before.
One thing you might ask is,
okay,
where does the social expectation come
from?
Now that's a very complex question
because in some sense that's the same
question is that as,
where does culture come from?
And that's partly a complex question
because you have to take into account
evolutionary history which provides the
substrata for the development of
culture.
So that would be human biology.
I've take that into account and then you
have to take human history into account
and,
and we're,
what you don't have to take into account
is not clear.
Right?
Because it's very difficult to,
to track the origins of the social
routines that make up the fundamental
social contract.
You know,
we know how to behave properly roughly
speaking.
We have a set of expectations in a set
of wants for about the way that other
people are going to behave with regards
to us and they return the favor and
everyone is participating in this and
everybody basically knows it unless
they're very poorly socialized.
And you can usually tell that right
away.
You know,
kids can tell that because if a three
year old is playing with another three
year old and one of them is poorly
socialized and so maybe has the
behavioral repertoire of a fairly badly
behaved two year old,
the other three year old being socially
sophisticated will say will not play
with the first.
So even though they might be perfectly
happy to play for a time with an actual
two year old,
so it doesn't take very long,
it's really hard about the age of three.
The children are already sophisticated
enough to have embodied the rules that
constitute appropriate cultural behavior
and those rules or their patterns
actually for the,
they're not exactly rules for the child
because the child couldn't explicitly
state them,
but they can act them out.
Now you remember now,
Piaget talked about this a fair bit,
right?
Because he said that part of the way
that the slightly larger micro
personality say of a two year old are
integrated into the broader social world
is through games that are played with
peers and with older children.
And the Games are ways that like a game
is fundamentally a negotiated.
It's a negotiated sphere of action and
perception that has a particular goal
and the goal is defined by the players
and the sphere of interaction as defined
by the players.
And so then if you're a good player,
what happens is that you become part of
a higher order structure and the higher
order structure is the game.
So if you're playing soccer,
all of a sudden if you're civilized,
what you do is you manifest those
behaviors that are appropriate to
playing soccer and you subordinate your
voluntarily subordinate,
your individuality at that point to the
higher order structure of the game.
That's a communal agreement.
So it's a basic social contract.
And so you practice being part of basic
social contracts by playing games.
And you can do that with games that are
in some sense relatively straight
forward and regulated by strict
conventions and articulated rules.
And so that would be like a soccer game
or you can do it in a more complex way
and on the less,
uh,
less,
less structured and less articulated
manner by engaging in dramatic play.
And so what children usually do when
they're doing that is that they'll
gather round little group and they'll,
they'll lay out the drama.
So the drama would be we're going to
simulate x,
we're going to send you like a family.
And then everybody is assigned a role.
And so you're supposed to act out your
role,
but exactly how you're supposed to act
it out is left open during the gate so
you can riff and,
and improvise.
And basically what children are doing
when they're doing that is acting out
the family and you know,
because they need to get the family in
their bones.
Because being a parent isn't a set of
ideas about parenting.
It's a set of behaviors.
It's a dance that you learn to have with
your children and with your partner.
And it's very complicated and the rules
go far beyond what you could ever
articulate.
You know,
cause you can ask yourself a question
like,
well how should you discipline a child?
Well first of all,
you can argue about that forever.
But second of all,
you cannot actually elaborate a set of
principles that will guide your behavior
in every situation where a child is
likely to disrupt the social
circumstance.
So you have to be smarter than you can
say in order to be good at doing
something as complicated as disciplining
a child.
No,
because discipline also means
encouraging,
right?
Cause it part of discipline it as well.
You shouldn't do those things.
But another part of it is you should
definitely do more of those things.
And so it's the inculcation of a moral
code.
And a lot of that's done through um,
nonverbal behavior and through,
uh,
providing a role model for spontaneous
imitation and all sorts of things that
aren't verbal.
Okay.
Now,
so,
so piaget talked about the game and then
you can take that game's become more and
more complex and more and more abstract
and more and more like real life as you
mature until they may be the games
transform into what sociologists would
refer to as roles.
So the role you're playing at the
moment,
at least in principle,
is student and you know it's a game and
it's a game because it's a fiction in
some sense,
you know,
it's a fiction,
it's a dramatic fiction in some sense.
The only reason that it exists as a role
is because society is structured in such
a way that enables,
this too enables you to do what you're
doing and to live at the same time.
So it's not exactly adaptation to the
normal,
you know,
to the natural world and in a sense of
the in,
in,
in any sense of the word.
But it's also,
it's also real life or maybe it's almost
as close to real life as you ever get
because almost everything that modern
people do,
and maybe this is true for a long time
into the past is game like in its
structure.
So the game's just get more and more and
more.
They're more and more and more
encompassing in some sense.
But you can,
you can,
it's almost,
you can almost say that it never comes
to the point where what you're doing is
no longer playing a game.
Now that's a bit of an
oversimplification,
but because there are games and medic
games,
but we won't talk about the [inaudible]
games at the moment.
Okay.
So now you can understand sort of some
of the lower order games and you can
even understand some of the higher order
roles like you,
you could basically articulate in some
sense what it means to be a student.
But if you go up the hierarchy,
you know,
cause good person,
a subset of good person could be good
student.
You can kind of articulate what it means
to be a good student,
although you can't fully articulate it.
But if you go at levels above that,
like be a good citizen or be a good
person,
but it gets more and more difficult to
fully articulate because of course it's
more and more abstract and in
encompasses more and more territory and
so by the time you're at the top of the
hierarchy,
so to speak,
be a good person.
Well it's much,
it's a much more complex phenomena then
you can articulate it,
can't be fully articulate it.
Now I want to read you something that
needs,
you said,
now you have to listen to this carefully
because there's some very interesting
things about the way Nietzsche writes.
He writes a floristic Lee and I need for
Islam is a short statement,
often only a sentence,
but more typically a paragraph.
Next,
very,
very densely packed with ideas.
And I think you could say in some sense
that if you read Nietzsche,
the stuff that I'm going to read right
now is from beyond good and evil that
every single sentence has an idea in it.
And it's often an original idea.
And that's a remarkable accomplishment.
I mean,
I've often gone through books and
marked,
I usually fold the top of the page over
mark where I think there's an idea worth
keeping.
It's an idea I haven't run into before.
So it's an original idea.
And I would say in a typical book I
read,
there's none of them.
There might be one or two,
but with nature there's probably 20 on a
page.
And so it makes it,
if it's,
he's packed a tremendous amount of
information into a very,
very small space.
And one of the things,
and he tried to do that and there was a
bunch of reasons.
One was his health wasn't very good,
although he was an early stage genius.
He was a full professor in Germany,
I think when he was 22 or 23 which is
impossible because if you don't become a
full professor,
especially 130 years ago,
140 years ago in a German University at
the age of 23 it just isn't possible.
But he was a spectacular genius.
But his health failed him.
And so he had a very difficult time
writing.
And so what he did was spend an awful
lot of time thinking and a very short
period of time writing.
And so what that meant was that he would
take a tremendous amount of thought,
genius level thought,
and then compress it into like a single
sentence or a single paragraph.
And he said that he liked to fuck
philosophize with a hammer.
And in some sense,
you know,
not,
you know about hierarchy did I just
showed you,
you know,
we talked about the idea that if you hit
something disruptive in your life that
the magnitude of your response is
proportionate to the,
to the elevation of the level,
right?
It's much more damaging to be accused of
being a bad person,
you know,
seriously than it is for someone to
complain about,
you know,
which side of the plate you happen to
put the forecourt.
So,
and I think you can say that you can
sort of think of those uh,
nasty hierarchies of value as nested
hierarchies of,
they're almost like maps in the sense
there,
their little units of they ways that you
know how to maneuver in the world and
not in.
What that means is that as you go up the
hierarchy,
the map is larger and larger and more
comprehensive.
And so if you blow out someone's map of
like which fork to put on the table,
that's not so bad,
they can rectify that no time flat.
It leaves 99.99% of their personality
and tech.
But if you fail a crucial exam for it,
for example,
and part of the reason that you're going
to fit you're a student is because you
want to go to medical school.
You know,
that'll blow out like 50 or 60% of your
personality.
Or at least it'll feel that way.
And that's because what's happening is
that the structure that you use to
regulate the relationship between you
and the world has become damaged at a
high level.
And that invalidates,
like if you're not a student,
if you're not a good student anymore,
then all of the sub factors that make up
being a good student might be invalid.
And you know,
you might've put a lot of effort into
being a good student.
And so if all of a sudden you're not
that,
you have to ask yourself,
well what exactly am I and where are all
the errors?
And that's a very,
that can be,
well that's an extraordinary difficult
cognitive problem because you've built
that structure.
Who knows,
you know,
over what period of time it might be 15
years or something like that.
And you've been practicing building that
structure and it's a huge part of your
identity because someone might say,
well what are you even,
and you'd say a student,
you know,
they might say,
what do you do?
But they could easily say,
what are you,
I'm a student.
While if you're not a student,
at least in so far as you deserve to
find student,
then just exactly what are you
all right.
So nature,
you know,
when he packed a lot of information into
a sentence or a paragraph,
you have to be very careful reading him.
And young is like this too,
because he'll throw some information if
you that's packed into a paragraph and
it'll be the kind of information that
disrupts high level structures.
You won't even notice it.
But that,
and it's because he's so subversive and
he,
he wanted to do that.
It was an aim of his,
he had his reasons to do it.
He would say that you have to be broken
down to nothing before you can be
rebuilt.
So it's like a trip to the underworld
thing.
So,
and I suppose in many ways that's what
philosophy is.
You know,
it's,
you don't learn a new principal without
allowing old principles to disappear
because you can't have the new principal
and the old principal at the same time.
So almost always any radical learning
involves the destruction of old habits
and of action and perception.
And that's,
that's a kind of death.
Like it's a,
it's a,
it's an abstract death,
you know,
but that doesn't make it not painful.
And the thing is,
if the abstract death is of sufficient
intensity,
it can drive people to suicide because
they regard killing themselves as easier
than making the reparation,
you know,
facing the anxiety and the suffering
and,
and going through the intolerably
difficult task of retooling.
They may well regard that as more
emotionally threatening then death.
And so,
and that,
that's not that rare.
I mean suicide is rare,
but it's not that rare.
So you know,
and it's certainly a behavior that
everyone is,
I suspect everyone here has known
someone who was touched by suicide in
some way.
You know,
it might not be your family member or
even your extended family member,
but the probability that you know,
someone who knows someone who committed
suicide is extremely,
extremely likely.
So Nietzsche is a very dangerous,
dangerous thinker.
I'm the only person I know who kind of
approaches him in that regard is young
and young is actually less troublesome
because a lot of what Dostoyevsky offers
is,
is destruction.
It's intelligent,
brilliant destruction,
but he doesn't really offer a solution.
He sort of sketches out the
possibilities of a solution.
And he died young and then in many ways
what happened was that young picked up
where [inaudible] left off and tried to
solve the problems that need your left
unsolved.
So it was nature for example,
in some sense along with Dostoyevsky who
really definitively announced the death
of God at the end of the 19th century.
In that left people in some ways bereft
of belief and we're going to talk about
why that's so important in a moment.
What union was doing was trying to,
while he was trying to rescue the
farther from the underworld in the sense
he was trying,
he tried to go back to the religious
traditions that Nietzsche had had
described as fatally anachronistic and
demolished by the claims of science.
He attempted to go back to those
religious traditions and reassess them
from a psychological perspective to pull
back the necessary meaning that was
embedded in them so that people could
reunite with their culture and and in
principle not be so prone to
pathological belief systems like
ideology that tend to rush in where
there's a gap.
You know when he just said very clearly
and Dostoyevsky knew this as well by the
end of the 19th century,
is that that the death of God would mean
that people would turn on mosques to
rationalistic ideologies and that would
be murderous.
They knew that was coming and that's an
amazing prediction.
It really is amazing prediction.
It just shows you how thoroughly they
understood the structure.
Okay,
so I'm going to read you something by
nature and then we're going to return to
the hierarchy so that you can kind of
understand something deeper about the
way the hierarchy is structured.
Okay?
Now he's talking about philosophical
ideas here and he's actually talking
about articulated efforts.
So one way that you might think about
philosophy is that philosophers or
originate articulated moral principles
and that is often the way that people
think about,
especially in moral philosophy.
It's like it's the philosophers who come
up with the ideas,
but that isn't what needs you believe.
Here's what he said in step.
Okay?
Separate philosophical ideas are not
anything optional or a tournament.
So evolving.
They grow up in connection and
relationship with each other.
However,
suddenly an arbitrarily,
they seem to appear in the history of
thought.
They nevertheless belong just as much to
assist them as the collective members of
the fauna of a continent.
Okay.
So it's a very interesting idea.
So the first idea that he's putting
forward is that you could,
the best way to think about a
philosophical system,
say a philosophical system of ethics is
as if it's different statements are
animals related to one another in an
ecosystem.
So he has a biological metaphor in some
sense for,
for,
for the emergence of a philosophical
system.
It's quite an interesting way of
thinking,
of course.
And it makes sense because if a
philosophical system of ethics,
which is a philosophical system that
tells you how and why you should behave
a certain way is about how you should
act and you're a biological being,
then of course,
it only makes sense that the concepts
themselves,
which are guides to actions,
can logically be,
uh,
considered,
biological entities.
They're abstracted biological entities,
but they still have the same nature as
biological entities.
And that means according to Nietzsche,
that they're subject to the same rules.
Now,
this is the sort of place where he
foreshadows floyd deeply,
so
nature says
they never last belong just as much to
assist them as the collective members of
the forerunner of a continent.
This is betrayed in the end by the
circumstance.
However,
unfailingly,
the most diverse philosophers always
fill in.
Again,
a definite fundamental scheme of
possible philosophies under an invisible
spell.
They always resolve once more in the
same orbit,
however independent of each other,
they may feel themselves with their
critical or systematic wheels.
Something within them leads them
something impels them indefinite order,
the one after the other to wit the
innate methodology in relationship of
their ideas.
Their thinking is in fact far less a
discovery.
Then erect,
then a re recognizing or remembering a
return and a homecoming to a far off
ancient common household of the soul out
of which these ideas formerly group
philosophizing so far,
it kind of activism of the highest
order.
Okay,
so here,
here's the idea.
There's,
there's two fundamental ideas that are
embedded in this which actually need you
differentiates.
All right,
I'm going to read you another section
that illuminates the first one.
Gradually it became clear to me what
every great philosophy up till now his
consisted of namely the confession of
its originator and a species of
involuntary and unconscious
autobiography and moreover that the
moral or immoral purpose in every
philosophy has constituted the true
vital germ out of which the entire plant
has always grown.
Okay,
so this is a very radical statement so
because what needs you to saying is that
philosophy is even when they declared
themselves a rational are deeply
personal and they're also necessarily
embedded within a motivational structure
that is either pro life or anti life,
something like that.
So there's no value free philosophizing.
What there is is the expression of
biologically and culturally conditioned
being which is conditioned by let's say
the same sort of fundamental forces that
Freud described in the,
in the in the biological realm and then
that's conditioned by the cultural
processes that you just discussed in
relationship to Pha and then what the
philosopher does is observed that all of
those things are happening.
Allow that to be articulated and
confused that with his own thought,
oh,
it's a brilliant idea.
Now here's a way of thinking about it.
Now,
one of the things Piaget said was that
once children start to play games,
when they're young collective games,
you can watch the children play the
collective games,
like maybe eight kids are playing
marbles or something like that.
And then you can take the young kids out
of the game and you can ask them what
the rules are.
And what'll happen is you'll get a
diverse set I diverse and paradoxical
set of articulated rules.
And what that means is that the children
can play the game when they're in the
game and we're in the or in the context
of all the other people.
Because in some sense the game is
embedded in pieces in all of them.
And as long as they're all there,
that all works.
But if you pull the child the way they
don't have the intellectual wherewithal
to do,
describe the patterns of behavior that
make up the game.
And that's only to say that they know
things that they can't say.
Because you might say,
well,
the game,
the rules of the game come first and
then the game emergence.
But that's wrong.
It's the game comes first and only after
that do the rules emerged.
And of course there's that,
you know,
there's a reciprocal relationship
between them because once the rules are
somewhat articulated,
then the game becomes more structured,
you know,
and,
and the rules can become more structured
and so on.
So the articulation changes the rules.
What needs she is saying the same thing
applies to societies.
You says like as in so far as you can
consider society a collective game
played by millions of people over vast
spans of time.
It's a game of games in some sense.
And it emerged from the bottom up.
It emerged out of biological impulses
and an interpersonal and social
interactions,
conditioning and,
and,
and shaping everyone's behavior and
perception.
And that happened way before anyone
could articulate what those rules were.
Now you remember when nature was
writing,
there was no real sense of how old the
earth was or how will the universe was.
I mean,
people thought,
even the radical people talk thought
maybe in terms of hundreds of thousands
of years,
you know,
and now we know that the universe is 14
billion years old and that the earth is
4 billion years old and that life has
been plentiful on the earth for 3.5
billion years.
You know,
so that the historical context within
which we've originated has expanded,
uh,
by,
by orders of magnitude since the last
19th century.
And so then what you think that means is
that the way that our games have been
organized stretches impossibly back in
time.
Now,
I already told you,
I believe the story about lobster
dominant is higher,
right?
So even lobsters that's 400 million
years ago,
lobsters arrayed themselves in a social
space and they regulate each other.
And that means the lobsters essentially
have a lobster society.
And you know,
each lobster has biological pre
dispositions that are quite determined.
There are quite,
uh,
the lobster is quite a deterministic
creature.
But nonetheless,
the way that those biological
predispositions manifest themselves is
conditioned and shaped by the social
surrounding.
And so you think,
well,
lobsters start to play games 400 million
years ago.
And you know,
as we've taken the tremendously long
evolutionary journey across that time,
we'd be playing social games the whole
time.
And that means that the way that we
interact with,
with each other has evolved and it's
even shaped the way our bioenergy
manifests itself because that's how
we'll culturally,
and then out of that as we became more
capable of abstraction.
And maybe that's,
you know,
that's something that really took off
probably 7 million years ago.
And with modern human beings emerging
about 150,000 years ago,
cause we,
we separated from the common ancestor of
peep of human beings in chimpanzees
about 7 million years ago.
You can tell that by doing analysis of
genetic differences.
So the brain expanded very rapidly after
that point and our culture became more
and more conscious and articulated then
complex and larger and more
technological,
you know,
so it became in some ways more dependent
on social norms and less dependent on
deterministic biological
predispositions.
But we've still been doing that for a
very long time.
There's,
there's good evidence that,
um,
you know,
we started using fire about 2 million
years ago when,
uh,
forgive me if I told you this already,
but you know,
if you look at a human being and you,
and you look at a champion z,
there's a bunch of things you see that
are very different morphologically.
Uh,
the chip is much shorter,
much,
much wider and way more powerful.
So like a normal mail champ is about six
times as strong as the strongest Olympic
athlete.
So don't mess with chimps.
They'll tear you apart.
They're really,
really strong and dangerous.
So,
but the chimp has shaped sort of like
this,
you know,
they have a huge gastrointestinal
system,
roughly speaking.
And the reason for that is mostly what
they eat is leaves and leaves,
have no color of content.
And so they have to eat immense numbers
of leaves and leaves are hard to digest,
so they have to choose them like mad.
So the typical chimps sits around eight
hours a day chewing and then they have
this tremendously long gastrointestinal
system because it takes that long to
extract any nutrients out of out of
leaves.
While we circumvented that man,
as soon as we invented fire and fire
allowed us to outsource our digestion
because if you cook most things,
vegetables,
but more importantly meet,
if you cook them,
they become much more bioavailable and,
and it takes much less energy to digest
them.
So that way you can shrink your gut and
grow your brain.
And so that's apparently what we did
because here we are,
you know,
relatively slim at least compared to
chimpanzees.
And so fire popped up 2 million years
ago.
It's a real cultural revolution.
But you know,
that's so old that culture revolution
content completely reshaped our bodies.
And so this interplay between biology
and cultures can you going on for an
unimaginably long period of time and it
conditions everything we do.
Now here's a complicated idea.
Okay,
so imagine a wolf pack.
Now Wolf pack is a pretty calm,
complicated social group.
It's a fair bit like a primordial human
group,
which is why dogs have been with us for
25,000 years.
Maybe they were wolves that first
started to follow us around and scavenge
or more likely,
I think someone went out some primordial
hunter,
went out hunting,
killed a wolf female,
found the pops and brought one home for
the children to play with,
you know,
and that was the origin,
the origin of the dog.
I think it was something like that.
Cause dorms are basically,
they're basically genetically identical
with wolves.
Now the thing is is we can get along
with dogs and the reason we can get
lauren with dogs,
because dogs have a social organization,
you could call it a dominance hierarchy.
That's a fair bit like the human social
organization.
And so you can see that part of what it
means to be human is the same thing that
it means to be a pack animal,
like a dog or a pack animal.
Like our domesticated down flight
courses and the cows for example,
which we can domesticate partly because
their social.
So some of the structure of our social
organization is the same sort of
structure that an animal dominance
hierarchy has,
like a chimpanzee dominance hierarchy,
for example.
And so we know that chimpanzees and
other primates,
monkeys for example,
are acutely aware of the levels of
hierarchy in their social structure.
And there are,
I think it's vervet monkeys.
This is a very funny experiment.
So imagine that the talk vervet monkeys
are like celebrity monkeys,
you know,
and the bottom vervet monkeys are like,
dissolute street people.
And so then you take some pictures of
dissolute street people who are just at
the bottom of the hierarchy and you take
some pictures of celebrities and you
show pictures to a human audience and
the human audience,
we'll look at the celebrities longer.
Well,
if you take the vervet monkeys and you
take photographs of the top ranking
vervet monkeys and the bottom vervet
monkeys and you showed them to vervet
monkeys,
then the vervet monkeys will look at the
top Reiki Verdun,
vervet monkey photographs more than the
bottom ranking vervet monkey
photographs.
So in some sense there transfixed by the
individuals who are higher up in the in
the social order.
And that makes sense,
right?
Because what you should feel,
especially in a fairly aggressive
dominance hierarchy,
what you should feel,
the closer you are to the bottom of the
dominance hierarchy,
the closer what you should feel for
whatever's at the top of the dominance
hierarchy.
That should be,
it should be closer and closer to all.
Now when people feel off,
they get chills running up and down
their back,
their neck.
Well,
why?
The reason that happens is because it's
an,
it's an,
it's an activism.
It's a hangover from the time that when
you were threatened by something awe
inspiring,
let's say a snake or a banner or
something like that,
your hair,
your for would stand up.
And the reason for that is so that you
look bigger and you still see this
happening all the time with cats,
right to capsule.
Normally cat's face each other this way,
right?
But if they start to fight,
they turned sideways and that,
so they each look bigger than they puff
up their fur and their tail.
And that's to show the other cat that
they're really a lot bigger than the cat
first thought.
Now of course they're both doing that,
so it's a little bit pointless,
but they're just cat.
So you know you can give them a break.
But the point is,
is that they pile over erect and that's
the same thing that happens.
For example,
when you're listening to very powerful
music and it deeply affects you and you
get chills.
It's like the hair stands up on the back
of your neck and that's a signaling of
all.
Now the reason you should feel odd to
award something that's higher up in the
dominick's heart he is because that
thing has power,
like is there,
well,
there's more than one reason a that
thing has power.
You better be careful of it because it
will put you in your place and fast.
And part of the reason the dominance
hierarchy exists is so that everybody
knows their place and they don't have to
be reminded of it by being half killed
on a regular basis.
You know?
So maybe your nine on a scale of one,
one being the top,
maybe your number nine it's not so good,
but number nine and not hurting is a lot
better than number nine in line.
They're bleeding on the ground.
And so what happens with dominance
hierarchies is they usually arrange
themselves in part by power.
But by no means only in power.
Everybody knows where they are and
pretty much everybody stays there and
not even happens over multiple
generations.
Same in complex primate dominance.
Troops status is heritable.
So,
and you know that there's not much of a
leap between that inheritable bonnet
peace among human beings.
It's a reflection of,
you know,
it's much more complex among human
beings because it's articulated and
structure.
But it's the same basic thing.
Now,
Nietzsche's point was so now imagine,
now here's another problem.
So
imagine that.
Okay.
Okay,
so you've got a garment,
it's art and it's fairly stable and one
of the things you want to do is climb to
the top of the dominant Turkey.
And the reason you want to do that,
there's all sorts of reasons.
High quality mates.
That's the primary reason that's
particular true in humans.
If you're male,
because males are much more differential
reproducers that females,
which means a lot of males fail to
reproduce completely and some reproduce
a lot.
Where's the typical woman reproduces at
least some.
So that means competition is more
intense among men.
And that's part of the reason why
dominance hierarchies tend to be tilted
towards male power because competition
means more to them.
The outcome is more crucial.
So now part of what happens is that as
people compete within the dominance
hierarchy,
what they're doing is to try to figure
out who it is that is fit to be on top.
Now you might think that that's a matter
of power,
you know,
in fact your basic social left,
the social constructionists would have
you believe that that was all there is
to it,
is that the whole dominance hierarchy is
nothing but a power system.
And the people on top are there because
they have power and what's there is
power.
And by that they need the ability to
enforce their will on other people.
While that's a,
that's a dopey theory and the reason for
that is,
is that if unit dimensional,
you know,
we,
that people are multifaceted,
there's no single motivation that's
cake.
You know,
for Freud it was saks and aggression and
like if you're going to come up with a
couple of potent candidates,
those are two.
But there's lots of other ones.
People are playful and play as a primary
biological circuit.
You know,
we suffer,
we're hungry,
we're thirsty,
we're affiliative.
Like there's a lot of biological
necessity
driving the makeup of our personalities.
And there were biological
subpersonalities to arbitrarily call one
of them.
The source of something as complex as
social organization is,
it's,
it's a,
it's a false form of monotheism.
It's a crazy idea.
And it's,
it's the kind of idea that only people
who really don't like to think would
have.
Because once you come up with that idea,
it's all power.
You don't have to think anymore.
Someone can say to you,
well,
why is complex phenomena x the way it
is?
Why is the economy arranged the way it
Well,
it's so that the people at the top can
maintain their power.
Well,
yeah,
sure.
But maybe that accounts for 10% of the
reason it doesn't get close to 100%.
There's lots of reasons why hierarchies
are structured the way they are and
sheer physical force is one of them,
but it's,
it's unstable.
So,
so Frans de Waal,
who was watching chimps organize their
dominance hierarchies in the art of Zoo
in Holland,
noted quite quickly that it was fairly
typical or recent possible for the
meanest,
ugliest,
strongest mail chimp to be the dominant
guide.
Sometimes it was the chimp who learned
to pick up a garbage cabin who act the
hell out of it with this stick because
that intimidated his enemies.
You know?
So it's uh,
it's a bit of create three creativity
there.
But what,
but what the wall found was that the
stable hierarchies were never run by
barbarian chimp dictators.
And the reason for that was that
coalitions of other males would take
them out.
And it's because you know,
you think,
well if you're,
if you're one antisocial,
aggressive male in your tough,
it's like okay,
here are tough.
But three lesser friendlier males who
are bound together in friendship pact
which chimpanzees form quite intensely.
It's like as soon as that guy turns his
back or it has a bad day or gets hurt,
they're going to jump in there and tear
him to pieces.
And that's exactly what happened.
So what below found was that the stabler
chimpanzee dominance hierarchies were
run usually by males who are affiliate
of end gregarious who remembered their
social obligations.
So that meant with,
with regards to their friendship network
and who are also very good to the
females and the infants in the true,
even if they weren't his.
And the idea there is that power is an
unstable basis for the maintenance of a
dominance hierarchy across time.
Because some sense,
even among chimps,
you have to have the consent of the
governed because you'll get a revolution
otherwise.
And so you know you're going to get a
revolution if you put people in or
animals in a situation where they have
nothing to lose.
And so what that means is there are
constraints on how you can act well.
You try to move up the dominance
hierarchy system.
Cause if you're too aggressive and
selfish and you're not grooming anyone
else and you're not communicating with
the other creatures in the truth,
they're going to gang up on you and take
you down.
And so if you're going to maneuver your
way up the truth,
you have to be do it in a manner that
civilized enough so that you don't get
everyone against you.
And so what it means is that to maneuver
up a power hierarchy,
especially a complex power art creek,
you have to be a lot more than powerful.
So,
okay,
now,
so now we've got this idea that there
are principles governing the movement of
peep of creatures up a dominant tart
even among the animals.
And one of the defining characteristics
of the,
that that one of the characteristics
that necessity makes the limit that
process is that over time the troop
can't let anybody climb the dominance
hierarchy who will destabilize the whole
dominance heart.
Cause then that's it game over.
So at the very least,
you have to learn how to climb up the
hierarchy so that you don't destabilize
it while you climb because otherwise you
get to the top and there's nothing left.
While an animals know this,
they know this instinctively.
So for example,
when wolves go at it,
you know,
first they puff up and they grow with
each other and they put up their
shoulders and like they get more and
more aggressive until attack is
imminent.
And often one of them will back off with
there's no fighting,
no one gets damaged and the,
and so that's the typical situation.
It's like one says,
yeah,
okay,
you know,
I'm,
I'm out of here.
And God only knows why that is.
Often I suspect the wolf with the higher
serotonin level wins because it has less
negative emotion.
And Sarah Donin levels go up as you move
up the dominants heart now.
And then they'll go into,
they'll actually have a fight,
but the fight usually doesn't last very
long.
And then the loser will rollover throw
which show its throat to the winter,
which is quite a behavior cause wolves
tear the throats out of,
of of their prey and the top woolful
back off.
And you know,
you think about that's unbelievably
sophisticated morality.
You know,
there,
there's echos in there of the New
Testament injunction to love your enemy
because that's exactly what the wolf is
doing.
And you know,
it doesn't know this because it can't
articulate the rule,
but what it's doing is acting as if even
the thing that attacked you is valuable
in its own right.
If it's part of your truth.
And you know,
you can see there the,
the,
the ancient biological origins of the
idea of the,
you know,
of the,
of the equality and value of each
individual.
So these things have deep,
deep,
deep roots.
They're not arbitrary,
they're not arbitrary and no one
invented them.
And that's exactly what Nietzsche is
saying here.
To understand how the abstruse
metaphysical assertions of a philosopher
have been arrived at.
It is always well,
and why is to first ask oneself what
morality do they or does he a mat
accordingly.
I do not believe that an impulse to
knowledge is the father of philosophy,
but that another impulse here as
elsewhere has only made use of knowledge
and mistaken knowledge as an instrument.
But whoever considers the fundamental
impulses of man with a view to
determining how far they may have here
acted as inspiring genie or as demons
will find that they have all practiced
philosophy at one time or another and
then each of them would have only been
two.
Glad to look upon itself as the ultimate
end of existence and the legitimate lord
of over all of the other impulses.
So what is he saying there?
Well,
you know,
it makes you,
makes this explicit in passages that are
related to this one.
He viewed the human being as a
collection of sub souls and the sub
souls who are grounded in their
existence in Boston biological
underpinnings.
And that was the case for every human
being in that made us roughly similar.
It certainly made our groups roughly
similar.
And so these,
each of these biological subsystems
conceptualized as a sub soul was
something that had its own viewpoint,
had its own rules,
it had its own games and they would,
they jockey for precedence.
Now you know that because sometimes
you're sitting there reading and you're
trying to concentrate on a higher order
goal,
like completing your classes and you
know,
some biologically determined subsystem
pops up and says,
you know,
this would be an excellent time to go
have a coffee.
You know,
and you might do everything you can to
not allow that thing to take over.
But often it does.
And often that's despite what you think
you might actually want to do.
And then later you're all upset about it
because you've procrastinated yet again.
But you know,
nature viewed the psyche as a place you
could almost think of yourself as a set
of apps.
It's like your brain is a set of animals
and the animals are all dependent on one
another.
But each animal needs to be boss from
time to time.
And each animal wants to be boss more
often than it should be.
And then you know,
the higher order cortical systems are
there to figure out how to sequence all
of these other animals so that they all
get what they need without interfering
with each other across large spans of
time in the presence of many other
people in a manner that sustain.
That's what very,
very complicated.
Okay,
now,
so let's go back to the hierarch.
So you have the hierarchy and overtime.
Now remember this hierarchy stays there
for a very long period of time.
And remember as well that the people who
climb to the top of the hierarchy are
much more likely to leave offspring than
the people who don't.
And so then what that means is that the
hierarchy in park is one of the primary
selection forces operating on humanity.
And what that means is that we evolve
towards the thing that can most
successfully climb the dominance heart.
And so that means that we evolved
towards the thing that has the best
probability of ruling properly.
And that that's not just cultural,
it's cultural because it's the continual
interplay between cultural and biology.
Going back,
we'll say 400 million years or more.
Okay,
now,
but it's even more complicated than
that.
And this is one of the things that you
have to understand if you really want to
understand what needs you meant by the
death of God.
So cause that's his most famous
pronouncement.
God is dead and we have killed them and
we'll never find enough water to wash
away the blood now.
So he wasn't announcing that in triumph.
He was announcing it in terror.
Okay,
now imagine this.
So as human society becomes more complex
and as our brains become larger and
larger so that we could track larger
social organizations and we can organize
more complex communities,
what happens is that here to,
for isolated tribes of people come
together and then they have to engage in
conflict and negotiation.
And partly what they're in conflict
about is what is the way that you should
act and what should the values be?
Now there's an old mythological idea
that the gods fight in heaven to see who
is the dominant God.
While you can imagine all of these
individual tribes,
they had their ideals and those were
creatures of their imagination.
But those were imagined representations
of proper behavioral patterns.
And they saw there was this transcendent
10 super ordinate.
And so then try bay would come into
contact with tried b and the guards
would clash and out of that and,
and all the death and destruction that
went with it,
the two tribes would integrate.
And maybe that would take hundreds of
years.
And the religious system that sat above
that,
which was the representation of the
dominance hierarchy,
would also transform.
So you take,
try bay and you take try b and then
you'd take tried c and then you'd take
tribe d and they all accumulate across
time and,
and,
and sort out and articulate and
represent all of their beliefs.
And what happens is that this tribe has
a game and this tribe has a game in this
tribe has a game.
And then if you put all those games
together,
they,
they tilt.
So that a metagame emerges out of it.
It's,
it's like if,
if it's,
if it's fortunate,
the best of all three games gets put
together in a larger game and it has to
be the best because otherwise it won't
work.
The thing will fall apart.
Right?
Because if,
if,
if your family unit isn't functional,
it'll disperse,
you know,
and,
and maybe people will die because of it.
It has to have the,
it has to be iterative and it has to be
playable across time without falling
apart from internal pressure and without
getting white belts from the health
side.
So it's very tightly constrained.
So then I,
let's say this happens over tens of
thousands of years,
we could say what would happen in the
Middle East because we know that it has,
Mesopotamia came together,
for example,
it was the aggregation of multiple
tribes and all of the Gods of those
tribes.
And we know the Mesopotamians organized
all those gods into one God,
his name was Marduk.
And that the story that they tell about
the aggregation of the gods into one is
the story of the gods getting together
and voting on which of them should be at
the top.
And then we know that the Mesopotamian
emperor was charged with the
responsibility of acting out that top
God and that that's what made him a good
emperor.
And he got reminded of that every year
at the new year's ceremony.
He had to tell all the ways that he
hadn't been a good Marduk and then he'd
get punished for it,
and then they would reenact the battle
of the gods and recreate this martech
character.
Okay,
so,
so you can understand how that might
have come about.
Now you could say that the idea of that
emergent ideal,
that was not,
that wasn't rational.
It was the consequence of conflict and
cooperation in,
in the real world across times.
The representations of that were,
you know,
we might think about them as narrative
representations or if they're deep
enough,
even as an anthology,
you can take about those as the,
as the soil from which religious
presuppositions emerge.
And so what happens is that what you
have at the top of the dominance
hierarchy as your representation of the
good person is no different in its
totality.
Then the idea of the sovereign God that
has emerged across thousands and
thousands of years of human history.
So the whole structure has this thing at
the top and it's regarded in
imagination,
has divine,
it's the consequence of the represent.
It's the consequence of the battle of
representations of morality in
imagination across thousands and
thousands of years.
And that's a reflection of the actual
conflict and restructuring of societies
across all of that time.
So then you have this thing at the top.
So we could say in the West,
in western Europe,
that thing at the top is Christ and
that's the dying and re re the dying and
the diamond revivified and hero.
And we talked about reasons for that.
That's the thing that can go to the
underworld and then come back up.
Okay,
that's the top.
What happens when it disappears?
What will turns Dostoyevsky for that?
This is from notes from underground.
So this is someone who's in the
underground and that's where you go when
your value systems collapse.
I'm a sick man.
I'm a spiteful man.
I'm an unattractive man.
I believe my liver is diseased.
However,
I know nothing at all about my disease
and do not know for certain what ails
me.
I don't consult the doctor for it and
never have.
Although I have a respect for medicine
than doctors you,
sorry.
It's I'm extremely superstitious
sufficiently so to respect medicine.
Anyway,
I am well educated enough not to be
superstitious,
but I am superstitious.
No,
I refuse to consult a doctor from spike
that you will probably not understand.
Well,
I understand that though.
Of course.
I can't explain who it is precisely that
I'm more declining in this case,
by my spite.
I'm perfectly well aware that I cannot
pay out the doctors and extract revenge
by not consulting them.
I know better than anyone that by all of
this I'm only injuring myself and no one
else,
but still,
if I don't consult a doctor,
it's from spike.
My liver is bad.
Well let it get worse and he's a civil
servant.
I low ranking civil servant and he's
retired because he got a little bit of
inheritance.
He says,
when petitioners used to come for
information to the table at which I sat,
I used to grind my teeth at them and I
felt intense enjoyment when I succeeded
in making anybody unhappy.
I almost always succeeded.
For the most part.
They were all timid people.
Of course they were petitioners,
but you know,
gentleman,
what was the chief point about my spite?
Well,
the whole point,
the real standard,
lay it in the fact that continually,
even in the moment of the acutest
spleen,
I was inwardly conscious with shame that
I was not only not spiteful,
but not even embittered and that I was
simply scaring sparrows at random and
amusing myself by it.
I was lying when I just said,
now that I was a spiteful officials,
I was lying from spike.
I was simply amusing myself with the
petitioners and with the officer and in
reality I never could become spiteful.
I was conscious every moment in myself
of many very many elements,
absolutely opposite to that.
I felt them positively swarming in me
these opposite elements.
I knew that they had been swarming in me
my whole life and craving some outlet
for me,
but I would not let them out,
would not let them purposefully,
purposefully would not let them out.
They tormented me until I was ashamed.
They drove me to convulsions and sick
and be at last at last.
How are they sick of me now?
You're not fancying gentleman that I am
expressing remorse for something.
Now that I'm asking your forgiveness for
something,
I'm sure you're fancying that however I
assure you I do not care if you are.
It was not only that I could not become
spiteful.
I did not know how to become anything,
neither spiteful nor kind.
Neither a rascal nor an honest man,
neither hero nor an insect.
Now I'm living my life out in my corner,
taunting myself with the spike bliss and
useless constellation that an
intelligent man can not become anything
seriously and it's only the fool who
becomes anything.
A direct person I regard as the real
normal man
as his tender mother nature wish to see
him when she graciously brought him into
being on the earth.
I envy such a man til I'm green in the
face.
He's stupid.
I'm not disputing that.
But perhaps the normal man should be
stupid.
How do,
how do you know?
Perhaps it's very beautiful in fact,
and I am the more persuaded of that
suspicion,
if one can call it.
So by the fact that you take for
instance the antithesis of the normal
man that is the man of acute
selfconsciousness who has come,
of course not out of the lap of nature,
but out of a retort.
This,
this is also almost mysticism gentlemen.
But I suspect this to this retort made
man is sometimes so nonplussed in the
presence of his intense assists,
the normal man that with all his
exaggerated selfconsciousness,
he genuinely thinks of itself a mouse
and not a man at all.
It may be an acutely conscious miles,
yet it is a mouse.
Well,
the other is a man and therefore et
Cetera,
et cetera.
And the worst of it is he himself,
his very own self,
looks on himself as a mouse.
No one asks him to do so.
And that's an important point.
Now,
let us look at this mouse in action.
Let us suppose for existence for
instance,
that feels insulted and it almost always
feels insulted and it wants to revenge
itself too.
There may even be a greater of a
cumulation of spite in it.
Then in the man of nature and truth,
the base and nasty desire to vent that
spite on it's a sale.
It rankles perhaps even more nastily in
it than in the man of nature and truth
for through his innate stupidity,
the ladder,
the normal man looks upon his revenge is
justice,
pure and simple.
Well in consequences,
his acute self consciousness,
the mouse does not believe in any
justice at all to come at last to the
deed itself,
to the very act of revenge.
Apart from one the one fundamental
nastiness,
the luck with smiles succeeds in
creating around it.
So many other nastiness is in the form
of doubts and questions adds to the one
question.
So many unsettled questions that there
are inevitably works around it,
up around it,
a sort of fatal brew,
a stinking mess made up of it's doubts,
emotions and of the contempt spat upon
it by the direct men of action who
stands solemnly about it as judges and
arbitrators laughing at it until they're
healthy sides eight of course,
the only thing left forward is to
dismiss all that with a wave of it's
Paul and with a smile of assumed
contempt in which it does not even
itself believe and creep ignominiously
into its mousehole.
There in its nasty,
stinking underground home are insulted,
crushed and ridiculed.
Mouse promptly becomes absorbed in cold,
malignant and above all everlasting
spite for 40 years together it will
remember it's injury down to the
smallest most ignominious details and
every time we'll add,
I've itself detailed,
still more in ignominious,
spitefully teasing and tormenting itself
with its own imagination.
It will be ashamed of it's imaginings,
yet it will recall it all.
It would go over and over every detail.
It will invent unheard of things against
itself,
pretending that those things might have
happened and will forgive nothing.
Maybe it will begin to revenge itself
too.
But as it were piecemeal in trivial ways
from behind the stove incognito without
believing either in its own right to
vengeance or in the success of its
revenge,
knowing that from all its efforts at
it will suffer a hundred times more than
he on whom it revenge is itself.
While he,
I daresay we'll not even scratch if self
on its deathbed,
it will recall it all over again with
interest accumulated over all the years
now
the idea that needs your dog's Kioski
were developing was that
the dawning consciousness in western
society of the mythological substructure
of the value system and the
impossibility of conceptualizing that or
proving the validity of it's structured
from scientific means doomed it to doom
the people who were encapsulated in that
system to formal disbelief in it.
And what they concluded from that was
exactly what dos Dsd just described,
which is that someone with that level of
acute self consciousness and cultural
self knowledge would immediately come,
become fragmented to beyond belief,
unable to act,
unhappy,
resentful and dangerous.
And both the Osteus in nature and in
their works.
And Dostoyevsky develop this idea most
particularly in a novel called the
Devil's said that once that you had got
to that point,
which was inevitable if you were smart
enough to take seriously what was going
on,
it was only a tiny step to
identification with a murderous
ideology.
Okay.
Now,
some of the existentialists started to
work up what you might regard as a
solution to this problem
and I'm going to read,
okay,
character guards
solution.
It is no cure.
Character Guard was a Danish existential
philosopher and he lived earlier than
nature and he was in some sense,
you might think about him as the first
modern psychologist he was.
He was the first person to
conceptualize,
for example,
of the separate entity of anxiety and
despair.
It is now about four years ago that I
got the notion of wanting to try my luck
as an author.
I remember it quite clearly.
It was on a Sunday.
Yes,
that's it.
This Sunday afternoon I was seated as
usual out of doors at the cafe in the
Fredericksburg Garden.
I'd been a student for half a score of
years,
although never lazy.
All my activity.
Nevertheless was like a glittering
inactivity,
a kind of occupation for which I still
have a great partiality and for which I
perhaps even have a little genius.
I read much spent the remainder of the
day idling and thanking or or thinking
and idling.
But that was all it came to soy.
I sat there and smoke my cigar until I
lapsed into thought among other
thoughts.
I remember these
you are going on.
I said to myself to become an old man
without being anything in,
without really undertaking to do
anything.
On the other hand,
wherever you look around you in life and
in literature,
you see the celebrated names and
figures,
the precious and much heralded men who
were coming into prominence and who are
much talked about the many benefactors
of the age,
who know how to benefit mankind by
making life easier and easier.
Some by railways,
others by omnibuses and steamboats,
others by telegraph,
others by easily apprehended compendiums
and shortly cycles of everything worth
knowing.
And finally the true benefactors of the
age who make spiritual existence easier
and easier,
yet more and more significant.
And what are you doing here?
Am I soloed?
Khoi was interrupted for my cigar,
was smoke gout and a new one had to be
lit so I smoked again and then suddenly
this thought flashed through my mind.
You must do something,
but in as much with your limited
capacities,
it will be impossible to make anything
easier than it has become.
You must with the same humanitarian
enthusiasm as the others undertake to
make something harder.
This notion please be immensely and at
the same time,
it flattered me to think that I like the
rest of them would be lovely and
esteemed by the whole community.
Okay?
For when all combined in every way to
make everything easier,
there remains only one possible danger,
namely that the ease become so great
that it becomes altogether too great.
Then there is only one want left though
it is not yet felt want when people will
want difficulty out of love for mankind
and out of disparate my embarrassing
situation,
seeing that I had accomplished nothing
and was unable to make anything easier
than it already was,
and moved by a genuine interest in those
who make everything easy.
I can see that as my task to create
difficulties everywhere.
Same idea in different words,
a traveler,
this is Nicha and this is part of the
development of his answer to the
conundrum that he raised.
A traveler who had seen many countries
and peoples and several continents was
asked what human traits he had found
everywhere and he answered.
Men Are inclined to laziness.
Some will feel that he might have said
with greater justice,
they were all timid.
They hide behind customs,
end opinions
at bottom.
However,
every human being knows very well that
he is in this world just once as
something unique and no accident,
however strange we'll throw together a
second time into a unity,
such a curious and diffuse plurality.
He knows it,
but he hides it like a bad conscience.
Why?
From fear of his neighbor who insists on
convention and veils himself with it.
But what is it that compels the
individual human being to fear his
neighbor and to think and act heard
fashion and not to be glad of himself?
A sense of shame perhaps in a few rare
cases in the vast majority,
it's the desire for comfort and inertia
and short dot inclination to laziness of
which the traveler spoke.
He's right.
Men are even lazier than they are
timorous and what they fear most is the
troubles with which any unconditional
honesty and nudity would burden them.
Only artists hate this slovenly life in
borrowed manners and loosely fitting
opinions and unveiled the secret.
Everybody's bad conscience.
The principle that every human being is
a unique wonder.
They dare to show us the human being as
he is down to the last muscle himself
and himself alone.
Even more that in this rigorous
consistency of his uniqueness,
he is beautiful and worth contemplating
as novel and as incredible as any work
of nature.
And by no means dope.
When a great thinker despises man,
it's their laziness that he despises for
it is on account of this.
That they have the periods of factory
products and seeing indifferent and
unworthy of companionship or
instruction.
The human being who does not wish to
belong to the mass austerely seeds must
merely cease being comfortable with
himself.
Let him follow his conscience,
which shouts at them.
Be Yourself,
what you are at present,
doing,
opining,
and desiring.
That's not really you.
Yeah.
That's neat.
Nietzsche and Dostoyevsky and
existentialism in,
that's the bare beginning of the thing.
Yeah.