Okay,
all right,
so I suggested to you last class that
human beings world as a place of action
through the lens of their social,
cognitive,
biological,
substructure,
and I made that argument on the basis of
the supposition that our primary
environment was actually other people
and I mentioned to you,
I believe that those other people are
arranged in hierarchies of influence and
authority or power or dominance,
which is often how it's construed and
that the dominance hierarchy as a
structure is at least 300 million years
old,
which makes it older than trees and it's
for that reason that you share the same
neurobiology to govern your observations
of your position in the hierarchy as
lobsters do,
which is a remarkable fact.
You know,
it's remarkable that the lobster uses
Serotonin,
has the mechanism to adjudicate it
status position,
and that modifying the Serotonin
function in the lobster can produce
changes in its behavior,
can,
can overhead the lobster overcome
defeat,
for example.
Which is very much equivalent to what
happens to a human being when they take
antidepressants.
You know,
it's,
it's a good example of the conservation
of biological structure by evolution and
another,
a good illustration of the continuity of
life on earth.
It's really amazing.
But the other thing,
it is a testament to his,
the ancient nature of the social
structure.
Now we tend to think of the social
structure as something other than
nature,
right?
Because society is,
I suppose mythologically opposed opposed
in a narrative way culture as opposed to
nature.
It's the town in the forest,
but the town has been around a long
time,
so to speak.
And the structure of the town is also
part of nature in the dominance
hierarchy is part of nature.
And because it's so ancient,
you have to consider it as part of the
mechanism that has played the role of
selection in the process of natural
selection.
And so,
um,
roughly see what seems to happen is that
there is a plethora of dominance
hierarchies,
especially in complex human communities
and many of them are masculine and
structure in that their dominance
hierarchies that primarily men compete
in or that has been the historical norm.
And that some men rise to the top based
on whatever the dominance hierarchy is
based on and they make their
preferential mates and it's a good
strategy for women to engage in because
why and and many sorts of female animals
do precisely this is they let the males
battle it out and then pick from the top
and or often the dominant males.
There's no choice on the part of the
females.
It's the dominant males just chasing
away the subordinate males.
But with humans it's usually the case
that the females have the opportunity to
do at least some choosing.
And so we have,
if you think about that,
what that implies is that we have
evolved to climb up dominance
hierarchies and then I would say it's
not exactly that even because there are
many different dominance hierarchies.
And so the skills that you might use to
climb up one might not be necessarily
the same skills that you would use to
climb up another.
And so then I would say what we evolve
evolve for instead.
Um,
and I'm still speaking mostly on the
masculine edge of things.
Historically speaking is the ability to
climb up the set of all possible
dominance hierarchies,
right?
And that's,
that's a whole different idea.
It's like the average hierarchy across
vast spans of time and I think it's for
that reason that we,
among others that we evolve general
intelligence because general
intelligence is a general problem
solving mechanism and it seems to be
situation independent,
so to speak.
And of course there's been an arms race
for the development of intelligence
between men and women because each
gender has to keep up with the other and
women have their own dominance
hierarchies.
There's certainly no doubt about that.
And of course now men and women more
increasingly compete within the same
hierarchies and we don't exactly know
how to sort that out yet because it's an
extraordinarily new phenomena.
But in any case,
because of the,
uh,
the permanence of the dominance
hierarchy,
it has come to be represented in
fundamental narratives because human
beings,
and this is something that we share
everywhere.
It's the thing the Wall Street bankers
shares with,
uh,
with the,
Kelly Harry Kung bushmen who are among
the genetically speaking,
they seem to be very close to what the
original,
most original human beings were like in
Africa before the Diaspora for about
50,000 years ago.
But,
you know,
both of those people,
despite their vast differences live in
communities that have a hierarchical
structure
that are composed of individuals that
are embedded in a natural world,
you know,
the world outside of the dominant
Turkey.
And so that's the standard human
environment I would say.
And so stories that rely on the
representations of those environments
and their interactions are what you
might describe as universal stories and
that's why people can understand them.
And I would say further,
and this is drawing substantially on
say,
derivations of the work of Carl young
because I think he delved into this more
deeply than anyone else.
So a lot of this stuff is quite union in
its,
in its origins.
Um,
we,
the commonality between human beings.
So you know,
you,
you have to have commonalities in order
to communicate,
right?
Axiomatic commonalities because
otherwise you have to explain everything
and so there's many things that human
beings don't have to explain to one
another.
We don't have to explain anger when we
don't have to explain jealousy.
We don't have to explain fear,
we don't have to explain pain,
we don't have to explain joy.
We don't have to explain love,
et Cetera.
Those are built into us and so their
predicates of being human and you could
say that those human predicates and the
standard human environment produce
standard narratives and then you could
say even further,
and this is more of a leap,
I would say,
is that those who act out the role of
the victor in those standard narratives
are precisely the people who attain
victory in life on and I would say
biologically defined in that they make
more attractive partners,
but also I believe that there's an
alignment between human wellbeing,
which is a very weak word and
participation in these metanarratives
that drive success because,
well,
do you want to be a failure or a
success?
Well,
you know,
it's hard to be a success.
You have to adopt a lot of
responsibility and so you might be
willing to take your chances as a
failure,
but I can't exactly.
I'm not going to make the presumption
that that's going to put you in this
situation other than one where you
experienced a lot of frustration,
anger,
disappointment,
depression,
pain and anxiety at the bottom of the
heap,
and so generally that's not what people
are aiming for.
Although under certain circumstances,
if people don't like responsibility and
are willing to take their chances,
they might take the irresponsibility and
it's apparent freedoms over the
necessity of thinking things through the
medium and long run.
Anyways,
we stop here.
I suggested to you that one of the
primary narrative representations was
the known or culture or order.
I think there was a or the explored
territory or the dominance hierarchy.
I think those things are basically
interchangeable from a,
from a representational perspective,
and you know in the movie The lion king
that's represented by pride rock,
which is the central place of
orientation founded on Rock,
which is the sort of thing that people
embed their memories in.
That's why we make sculptures and
gravestones and that sort of things.
Roc stands for permanent than to have
rock under your feet is to be on a solid
foundation and that's a pyramid in some
sense in that movie.
And the pyramid has topped by the king
and Queen and their offspring.
So,
um,
that's,
that's the divine couple.
That's one way of thinking about it.
And Simba of course is the newborn hero
and you know,
you,
you understand that even though it's
lions and drawings of lions at that and
animals are acting it out,
it's completely irrelevant to you that
those characters happen to be animated
and that what you're watching is a
fiction.
So,
and I would say to you with regards to
fiction,
you know,
you might say,
well is fiction true or not?
And the answer to that is yes and no.
It's not true in that the events
portrayed in fiction occurred in the
world.
They didn't,
but they're fiction is true the same way
numbers are true.
I would say like,
you know,
if you have one apple and one orange and
one banana,
the common malady between all of those
three is one and you might say,
well,
is one as real as one fruit is the
abstraction one as real as one fruit and
I would say it depends on what you mean
by real,
but representing things mathematically
and abstractly gives you incredible
power and you could make the case that
the abstraction is actually more real
than the phenomena that it represents.
And certainly mathematicians would make
that case.
They would say that mathematics is in
some sense more real than the phenomenal
world.
And you know,
you don't have to believe that mostly
it's a matter of choice in some sense,
but you can't deny the fact that an
abstraction has enough reality so that
if you're proficient in using it,
you can really,
you can change the world and,
and,
and in and in insanely powerful ways.
You know.
I mean,
all the computational equipment you
people are using are dependent on the
abstractions one in zero essentially.
And I mean look at what emerges from
that.
And so I would say with regards to
fiction,
if you take someone like Dostoevsky or
we think it's a favorite of mine,
by the way,
I would highly recommend that you read
all five of his great novels because
they are unparalleled in their
psychological depth.
Um,
and so if you're interested in
psychology,
Dostoyevsky's the person for you,
tolstoy is more of a sociologist,
but Dostoyevsky man,
he gets right down into the bottom of
the questions and messes around,
uh,
a transformative reading.
Anyways,
Dostoyevsky's characters,
this character named her skull and the
cove is a character in crime and
punishment and risk.
And the coffee's a materialist
rationalist,
I would say,
which was around rather new type of
person back in the 18 eighties.
And he was sort of taken by the idea
that God was dead and took and convinced
himself that the only reason that he,
that anyone acted in a moral way in a
traditional way was because of
cowardice.
They were unable to remove from them the
restrictions of mere convention and act
in the manner of someone who rose above
the norm.
And so he's tortured by these ideas.
He's half starving.
He said,
law student who doesn't have enough to
eat,
he doesn't have much money,
and so you know,
he's not thinking all that clearly
either and it's got a lot of family
problems.
His mother's sick and she can't spend,
send too much money and his sister is
planning to engage in a marriage that's
loveless to someone who's rather
tyrannical,
who he,
she hopes will provide the family with
enough money so that he can continue in
law school and they write him brave
letters telling him that she's very much
in love with this guy,
but he is smart enough to read between
the lines and realize this,
that his sister is just planning to
prostitute herself in,
you know,
in an altruistic manner.
And he's not very happy with that.
And then at the same time as all this is
happening,
he becomes aware of this pawn broker who
he's,
you know,
pawning his last possessions too.
And she's a horrible person and not only
by his estimation,
she pawns a lot of things for the
neighborhood.
And people really don't like her.
She's grasping and cruel and deceitful
and and resentful and like,
and she has this nice who's not very
bright,
intellectually impaired,
whom she basically treats as a slave and
beats all the time.
And so risk called Nicole,
you know,
involved in this mess and half starved
and a bit delirious and possessed of
these strange new nihilistic ideas.
Decides that the best way out of this
situation would be just to kill the
landlord.
The,
a pawnbroker take her wealth,
which she,
all she does is keep it in a chest,
a free,
the nice.
So that seems like a good idea.
So remove one apparently horrible and
useless person from the world,
free his sister from the necessity of
this loveless marriage and allow him to
go to law school where he can become
educated and do some good for the world.
You know,
so one of the things that's lovely about
Dostoevsky is that he,
you know,
when sometimes when one person is
arguing against another or when they're
having an argument in their head,
they make their opponent into a straw
mat,
which is basically they take their
opponent and caricatures of their
perspective.
And try to make it as weak as possible
and,
and laugh about it,
and then they come up with their
argument and destroy this Straw man and
feel that they've obtained victory.
But it's a very pathetic way of
thinking.
It's not thinking at all what thinking
is when you adopt the opposite position
from your suppositions and you make that
argument as strong as you can possibly
make it.
And then you hit your perspective
against that,
that strong iron man,
not the straw man.
And you argue it out,
you battle it out.
And that's what Dostoevsky does in his
novels.
I mean,
he's the people who stand for the
antithesis of what Dostoevsky Dostoevsky
actually believes are often the
strongest,
smartest,
and sometimes most admirable people in
the book.
And so he takes great moral courage to
do that.
And uh,
you know,
in rascal of what he wanted to do was
set up a character who had every reason
to commit murder,
every reasonable reason,
philosophically,
practically,
ethically,
even.
Well.
So ruskell Nicole goes and he kills the
old lady with an ax and it doesn't go
the way he expects it will because what
he finds out is that post murder risk,
golden cove and pre murder riscal Nicole
have are not the same people at all.
They're not even close to the same
people.
He's entered an entirely different
universe and Dostoevsky does a lovely
job of describing that universe of
horror and chaos and and and deception
and and and suffering and terror and all
of that,
and he doesn't even use the money.
He just buries it in an alley as fast as
he can and then it doesn't want anything
to do with it again.
Anyways.
The reason I'm telling you all this is
potentially to entice you into reading
the book because it is an amazing,
amazing book,
but also because you might say,
well,
is risky is what happened to risk in the
cove?
True.
Are the stories in that book?
True?
And the answer to that is,
well,
from a factual perspective,
clearly they're untrue.
But then if you think of [inaudible] as
the embodiment of a particular type of
person who lived at that time and the
embodiment of a certain kind of ideology
which had swept across Europe and really
invaded Russia in,
which was actually a precursor,
a philosophical precursor to the Russian
revolution,
then Ruskell Niqab is more real than any
one person.
He's like a composite person.
He's like a person who's irrelevancies
have been eliminated for the purpose of
relating something about the structure
of the world.
And so I like to think of those things
as sort of met a real matter real.
They're more real than real.
And of course that's what you expect
people to do when they tell you about
their own lives,
about their own day.
You don't want a factual description of
every muscle twitch.
You want them to distill their
experiences down into the gist,
which is the significance of the
experience and the significance of the
experience is roughly what you can
derive from listening to the experience
that will change the way that you look
at the world and act in the world.
So it's valuable information and they
can tell you a terrible story and then
that can be valuable because that can
tell you how not to look in the world,
look at the world and act in it or are
they can tell you a positive story.
You can derive benefit either way,
which is why we also like to go watch
stories about horrible psychopathic
thugs.
Um,
you know,
and,
and hopefully we're learning not to be
like them,
although there are additional advantages
in that,
you know,
someone who you might be some say that
someone who is incapable of cruelty is a
higher moral being than someone who is
capable of cruelty.
And I would say in this follows younger
as well,
that that's incorrect and it's
dangerously incorrect because if you are
not capable of cruelty,
you are absolutely a victim to anyone
who is.
And so part of the reason that people go
watch anti heroes and villains is
because there's a part of them crying
out for the incorporation of the monster
within them,
which is what gives them strength of
character and self respect.
Because it's impossible to respect
yourself until you grow teeth and if you
grow teeth,
then you realize that you're somewhat
dangerous and or maybe somewhat
seriously dangerous and then you might
be more willing to demand that you treat
yourself with respect and other people
do the same thing.
And so that doesn't mean that being
cruel is better than not being cruel.
What it means is that being able to be
cruel and then not being cruel is better
than not being able to be cruel because
in the first case you're nothing but we
can naive and in the second case you're
dangerous but you have it under control
and you know a lot of martial arts
concentrate on exactly that as part of
their philosophy of training.
It's like we're not training you to
fight.
We're training you to be peaceful and
awake and avoid fights.
But if you happen to have to get in one
and the.
I guess the philosophy also is,
is that if you're a competent at
fighting,
that actually decreases the probability
that you're going to have to fight.
Because when someone pushes you,
you will be able to respond with
confidence and with any luck,
and this is certainly the case with
bullies,
with any luck,
a reasonable show of confidence,
which is very much equivalent to a show
of dominance,
is going to be enough to make the bully
back off,
and so the strength that you develop in
your monstrousness is actually the best
guarantee of peace and that's partly why
young believed that it was necessary for
people to integrate their shadow and he
said that was a terrible thing for
people to attempt because the human
shadow
which has all those things about
yourself that you don't want to realize
reaches all the way to hell.
And what he meant by that was it's
through an analysis of your own shadow
that you can come to understand why
other people are capable and you as well
of the sorts of terrible atrocities that
characterize,
let's say,
the 20th century.
And without that understanding,
there's no possibility of bringing it
under control.
When you study Nazi Germany,
for example,
or you study the Soviet Union
particularly under stelling and you're
asking yourself,
well,
what are these perpetrators like?
Forget about the victims.
Let's talk about the perpetrators.
The answer is they're just like you and
if you don't know that,
that just means that you don't know
anything about people including
yourself,
and then it also means that you have to
discover why they're just like you and
believe me,
that's no picnic,
so that's enough to traumatize people
and that's partly why they don't do it
and it's also partly why the path to
enlightenment and wisdom is seldom trod
upon.
Because if it was all a matter of
following your bliss and doing what made
you happy,
then everyone in the world would be a
paragon of wisdom.
But it's not that at all.
It's the.
It's a matter of facing the thing you
least want to face and everyone has that
old.
There's this old story in King Arthur
where the night school off to look for
the holy grail,
which is either the cup that Christ
drank out of it,
the last supper or the cup into which
the blood gushed from his side was
poured when he was crucified.
The stories vary,
but it's.
It's basically a holy object like the
phoenix in some sense that's
representation,
a representation of transformation,
so it's a.
it's an ideal and so King Arthur's
knights who sit at round table because
they're all roughly equal.
Go off to find the most valuable thing
and they and where do you look for the
most valuable thing when you don't know
where it is?
Well,
each of the nights looks at the forest
surrounding the castle and enters the
forest at the point that looks darkest
to him and that's a good thing to
understand because the gateway to wisdom
and the gateway to the development of
personality,
which is exactly the same thing,
is precisely through the porthole portal
that you do not want to climb through.
And the reason for that is actually
quite technical.
This is a union presupposition too,
is that,
well,
there's a bunch of things about you that
are under developed and a lot of those
things are because there's things you've
avoided looking at because you don't
want to look at them and there's parts
of you you've avoided developing because
it's hard for you to develop those
parts.
And so it's,
it's by virtual necessity that what you
need is where you don't want to look
because that's where you've kept
it.
And so,
and that's why there's an idiosyncratic
element of it for everyone.
Your particular place of enlightenment
and terror is not going to be the same
as yours,
except that they're both places of
enlightenment and terror.
So their equivalent at one level of
analysis and,
and different at another.
So anyways,
back to fiction and,
and,
and what it does is it distills truth
and it produces characters that are
composites and the more they become
compass,
it's the more they approximate a
mythological character.
And so they become more and more
universally true and more and more
approximating religious deities.
But the problem with that is they become
more and more distant from individual
experience.
And so with literature,
there's this very tight line where you
need to make the character more than
merely human,
but not so much of a god that,
you know,
one of the things that happened to
superman in the 19 eighties,
superman started out,
he's got a heavenly set,
a parents bought,
by the way in an earthly set of parents.
And he's an orphan like Harry Potter.
Very common theme is that when Superman
first emerged,
he could only jump over buildings.
You know what I mean?
Maybe you could stop a locomotive,
but by the time the 19 eighties rolled
around like he could juggle planets and
you know,
swallow hydrogen bombs and you know,
he could do anything.
Well,
people stopped buying the superman
comics because how interesting is that?
It's like something horrible happens and
superman deals with it and,
and something else horrible happens and
superman deals with it and it's like,
that's dull.
He turned into such an archetype.
He was basically the omniscient,
omnipresent,
omnipotent God.
And that's no fun.
That's like Godwin's.
And then God wins again and then again,
God wins and you know,
so then they had to weaken him in
different ways with Kryptonite,
you know,
so green Kryptonite kind of made him
sick and red Kryptonite I think,
kind of mutated him,
if I remember correctly.
And anyways,
they had to introduce flaws into his
character so that there could be some
damn plot and not something to think
about.
You know,
there's a deep existential lesson in
that in that your being is limited and
flawed and fragile.
Um,
you're like the genie,
which is genius in the little tiny in
the little tiny a lamp,
you know,
this immense potential but constrained
in this tiny little living space as
Robin Williams said when he played the
genie in Aladdin.
But the fact that you have limitations
means that the plot of your life is the
overcoming of those limitations.
And that if you didn't have limitations,
while there wouldn't be a plot and maybe
there would be no life.
And so that's part of the reason why
perhaps you have to accept the fact that
you're flawed and insufficient and,
and live with it.
And consider it a precondition for
being.
It's at least a reasonable.
It's a reasonable idea.
So anyways,
one of the main characters is the
country,
the known,
the explored territory.
We went over that a bit and it always
has two elements.
I mean your country is your greatest
friend and your worst enemy because it
squashes you into conformity and demands
that you act in a certain manner and
reduces your individuality to that
element that's tolerated by everyone
else and it it constrains your potential
in a single direction and so it's really
tyrannical,
but at the same time it provides you
with a place to be and all of the
benefits that have accrued as a result
of the actions of your ancestors and all
the other people that you're associated
with.
So there's the good tyrant or the bad
tyrant and the good king and those were
archetypal figures and that's because
they're always true and they're always
true simultaneously.
Which is partly why I object to the
notion of the patriarchy because it's a
mythological.
It's the.
It's the,
what do you call that?
It's the apprehension of a mythological
trope,
which is that of the evil tyrant without
any appreciation for the fact that the
archetype actually has two parts and the
other part is the wise king and you know
you can tell an evil tyrant story about
culture,
no problem,
but it's one sided and that's very
dangerous because you don't want to
forget all the good things that you have
while you're criticizing all the ways
that things are in error.
That's a lack of gratitude and it's a
lack of wisdom and it's.
It's founded in resentment and it's.
It's very dangerous both personally and
socially.
I told you that captain hook is a tyrant
because he's got this crocodile chasing
them in.
The crocodile has a clock in its stomach
and that's death.
It's like obviously,
right,
tick,
and it's a crocodile and it's under the
water and it's already got a taste of
him.
So he's being chased around by death and
that makes him terrified and resentful
and,
and cruel and bitter.
And so he's a tyrant and he wants to
wreak havoc everywhere.
And then Peter Pan of course,
looks at Captain Hook and thinks,
why the hell should I grow up and to be
a tyrant and sacrifice all the potential
of childhood.
And the answer to that is the potential
sacrifices itself.
If you don't utilize it as you mature
and you just end up a 40 year old last
boy,
which is a horrifying thing to behold,
it's almost as if you're the corpse of a
child,
the living corpse of a child.
Because who the hell wants a six year
old,
40 year old.
You're a little on the stale side by
that point and not the world's happiest
individual.
So you know
your potential is going to disappear
because you age anyways.
And so you might as well shape that
potential in a particular direction and
at least become something no matter how
limited rather than nothing.
So
Peter Pan,
that's a great story.
It's a great mythological story.
So
well.
So let's talk about tyrants.
Well,
not only are they mythological figures,
but they exist and they tend to be
deified.
Stalin was a,
for all intents and purposes,
God the father in Soviet Russia,
although he was pretty much only the
worst elements of Old Testament God who
was constantly smiling people and,
and wiping out populations and doing all
sorts of things that seem to be quite
nasty.
But nonetheless,
you know,
people worshiped him in many ways.
And,
and,
uh,
he's a representation of just exactly
what goes wrong when things really go
wrong,
when people stop paying attention and
when they all lie.
Because one of the things that
characterized the communist state was
that no one ever got to say anything
they actually believed ever.
And that was partly because one out of
three people was an informer,
which meant if you had a family of six
people,
two of them were informing on the
government about you.
And that included your own children and
you.
And if you were an informer,
you were often amply rewarded by the
state.
So that if you lived in an overcrowded
apartment building with three families
in the same flat and you informed on the
woman down the hall that you didn't
like,
she got shift shipped off to the old
concentration camp and you got her
apartment.
And so that was a lovely society and it
only killed about 30 million people
between 19,
19 in 1959.
So that's what happens when the
archetipal structure gets tilted badly
when people
forget that they have a responsibility
to fulfill as citizens,
as a wake citizens who are capable of
stating the truth and the archetype
shifts.
So there's nothing left of the great
father except the tyrant.
And let's not have that happen.
I mean,
the one on the right is really
interesting because consciously or
unconsciously,
you know,
there's Stellan surrounded by what is,
for all intents and purposes,
fire.
You know,
he looks like he looks like maleficent
in sleeping beauty when she shows up at
Aurora's Christening,
you know,
she puts her arms up in the air and
green fire surrounds her.
It's like,
like he's surrounded by fire and there's
Lenin above him who's like king of the
fiery realm and that's for sure.
So I mean,
all the terrors that happened in the
Soviet Union didn't start understanding
and they started under Lenin and Lenin
was stolen,
was definitely Lenin's legitimate son,
let's put it that way.
So,
you know,
this is another example of the
tyrannical element of the great father
and the sorts of things that can happen.
I mean,
I kind of got an evil kick out of this
ad was quite old,
you know,
it's kitschy in some sense.
And,
and you know,
it shows,
I don't think that's something you'd
ever see in a magazine today.
I'm 10 unusual stamps showing evil
dictator,
you know?
Um,
well,
fair enough.
I mean,
that's what he was and that's the
consequence and that's just a tiny bit
of the consequence because the Nazis
wiped out a very large number of people.
I'm often using compassion as a,
as a,
um,
as a justification.
So when they went after the mentally ill
and the terminally ill and uh,
those who,
whose intelligence was compromised for
biological reasons and,
and those who were too old,
they basically justified it by saying
that the enforced euthanasia was
merciful and that you were actually
being a good person by complying with
the requirements.
And so something to think about more
mythological representations.
I like these quite a bit.
So there's,
there Hitler,
as you know,
night of the faith essentially with,
I suppose that's a recreation of the
Christian Holy Spirit dove,
you know,
except its an eagle which is a bird of
prey.
And uh,
and uh,
what do you call those things?
A scavenger,
right?
So that's kind of interesting,
but that's Hitler as knight of the,
of the blood,
roughly speaking.
And there,
this is an allied,
a war poster essentially that
assimilates the Nazis to poisonous
snakes.
And you know,
we don't like poisonous snakes very much
and it's probably because they've been
preying on us for approximately $20
million years because snakes and
primates,
humans in particular co evolved.
And so the snake is a representation of
that which lies outside the comfortable
domain,
and that can be,
you know,
a snake obviously,
or it can be a an abstract snake and the
abstract snake is your enemy or an even
more abstract snake is the evil in your
own heart.
And this is going to be a bit of a leap
for you,
but there's this ancient idea that
developed in the West over thousands of
years,
far predating Christianity that at least
it's origins,
that the snake in the garden of Eden was
also Satan.
Which is like what the hell?
It's a very strange idea,
but the reason for that as far as I can
tell is that,
you know,
we have this circuitry that detects
predators and a predator.
A good representation of a Predator is a
snake or a monster that incorporates
snake like features like a dragon or
something like that,
or a dinosaur with lots of teeth or a
shark that lives under the water.
And we'll pull you down.
You know,
because I suspect a lot of our ancestors
met a nasty death at the hands of Nile
crocodiles while they were in the
African Veldt going down to get some
nice water,
so you know,
that's the thing that jumps up and pulls
you under and you know,
not happens in your own life because
things jump up and pull you under,
you know,
and use the same circuitry.
We use the same circuitry to process
unknown things that upset us as we once
used to detect predators who were likely
to invade our space.
And so and,
and human beings are capable of
abstraction.
And so,
you know,
you could think about the real Predator
that might invade your space and maybe
that's a snake or a wolf or,
or some kind of monster,
you know,
and that's pretty concrete.
And biological chimps have that,
you know,
chimps don't like snakes.
And so if you,
a chimp comes across a snake in the wild
than like a big,
let's say,
I don't know what live with chimps.
Uh,
I don't know if they're pythons,
but they have constrictors there
anyways.
So you know,
maybe there's like a 20 foot constrictor
and this and the chimp like stays a good
distance away from it,
but it won't leave.
And then it has this particular cry that
it outers that's called a snake ram wr.
Ay Ay.
And so it makes this noise,
which means something like,
Holy Shit,
that's a big snake.
And I actually mean that because the
circuits that primates use to utter
distress calls are the same circuits
that we use to curse.
Just so you know,
that's why people with Tourette Syndrome
swear because like what,
what's up with that?
How can you have a neurological
condition that makes you swear?
Well,
it turns out that got her role as effect
laden curses are mediated by a different
speech circuit and that's the speech
circuit we share with the Predator
alarms of other primates.
So that's pretty cool.
So anyways,
this is the chimp stands there and makes
this snake noise and then all bunch of
other chimps come running and you know,
some of them stay a fairways from the
snake and some of them get pretty close,
but they'll stand there and watch that
snake for like 24 hours,
you know.
So they're fascinated by it.
And you know,
if you've handled snakes,
you can understand that fascination
because they're fascinating,
you know,
and they're numinous.
I would say that that's the right way of
putting it.
A numinous is a word that means
intrinsically meaningful,
like fire,
you know,
you can't look away from fire,
if you're sitting in front of a
fireplace,
it's like you're staring at it and
that's because you're all descended from
the first mad chimpanzee who had some
weird genetic mutation that made it
impossible for to stay away from fire.
It was like the first chimp arsonist,
you know,
and,
and he figured it out and well,
hey,
now he was a chimp with a stick with
fire on it.
Like that's a mega chimp man.
And so,
you know,
we have that mutation in spades and no
wonder.
So anyways,
um,
so they,
they make this,
they have this reaction to snakes and
chimps that have never seen a snake.
If they're in a cage and you throw a
rubber snake in there,
it's like bang,
they hit the roof,
but then they look at the snake,
you know,
so it's like,
it's terrifying and fascinating at the
same time.
And you should look at the snake because
you want to know what it does,
but you should stay away from it because
it's a snake,
so you,
you're kind of screwed in terms of your
motivations,
right?
One is get the hell away and the other
is,
while don't,
don't let that thing do anything that
you're not watching.
And so that's really the reaction we
have to the unknown.
It's terrifying.
But we watch it.
And then,
you know,
the Meta story is that not only do we
watch it,
but we go explore it.
And so you might think,
well back in the garden of Eden,
so to speak,
when we were living in trees,
the snakes used to come and eat us and,
and our,
our offspring more likely and you know,
we weren't very happy about that.
And then we figured out how to maybe
maybe by accident drop a stay a stick on
a snake and that was a good thing
because the snake didn't like that.
And then maybe the next thing we learned
a little later was to like actually take
a stick and whack the snake with it.
And you can believe that the first
primate who figured out that was just as
popular as the Guy Who mastered fire.
And so we're pretty good at whacking
state snakes with sticks,
which is why a springfield has a snake
whacking day that's devoted to nothing
but that.
Right?
I don't know if you know that simpsons
episode,
but it's quite comical.
So.
Well.
So then you think about the snake as a
Predator and it's the thing that invades
the garden always because you just can't
keep snakes out of the damn garden no
matter how hard you try.
And then you think of snakes and maybe
you think of medicine aches and like a
medicine ache would be also a predator,
but maybe that's the Predator that
represents the,
the destructive spirit of the other
tribe because chimpanzees,
for example,
are quite tribal and they definitely go
to war with one another.
And so you think you abstract out the
idea of the Predator to represent
malevolence as such.
And then you take that one step further
and you realize that the worst of all
evil predators is the human capacity for
evil.
And then at that point,
you know you're starting to,
I would say psychologize or
spiritualize,
the idea of danger and making it make it
into something that's conceptual and
something that's psychological and
something that you can,
you can face sort of on moss.
I mean,
one of the things people had to figure
out was how do you deal with danger?
And so you figure out how you deal with
a specific danger,
but then because human beings are so
damn smart,
they thought,
well,
what if we considered the class of all
dangerous things?
And then what if we considered a a mode
of being that was the best mode of being
in the face of the class of all
dangerous things.
Well,
that's a lot better.
You get,
you get solve all the dangerous problems
all at once instead of having to conjure
up a different solution for every
dangerous thing.
And that's basically as far as I can
tell where the hero's story came from.
And the hero story is basically,
you know,
there is a community.
It's threatened by the emergence of some
old evil,
often represented by a dragon.
That's sort of typical say of the Lord
of the rings stories.
There's a hero,
often a humble guy,
but not always.
Sometimes a night decides he'll go out
there and chase down the snake,
maybe even or the serpent or the dragon
and maybe even in its layer and he'll
have a bunch of adventures on the way
that transform him from useless naive
hobbit into sword wielding hero and he
confronts the Dragon and gets the gold
and frees the people that it had
enslaved and then comes back transformed
to share what he's learned with the
community.
It's like,
well,
that's the human story fundamentally.
And that's,
that's our basic instinctive pattern.
And it's represented in narratives
constantly.
And that's partly what this sea,
this has meaning,
you know,
what this means?
Why,
why do you know?
Well,
you know,
because it draws on symbolic
representations that you already
understand.
You understand that a mess of tooth
snakes is not a good thing and that may
be the sensible thing to do is stomp
them and
it's not like you need an instruction
manual to figure out what the poster
means.
And so,
you know,
that's two different representations of
Hitler that sort of the Pro Hitler
representation.
And I would say that's the Anti Hitler
And you know,
that's the real Hitler,
who at this point does not look like a
very happy clam.
So.
So that's the known.
That's culture.
Now it's order and what's eternally
juxtaposed to culture and the known and
the explored and order is the unknown.
And the unknown is a strange place.
The unknown is actually.
It's a physical place like the unknown
is the place that when you're camping
and you're around a fire,
the unknown is everything outside the
circle of the light.
And you remember in the Lion King,
you may not remember when,
when,
when Mufasa,
that's the king,
right?
Goes and takes Simba up to show him his
territory.
He says he is the king of everything.
The light touches.
And that's a very old idea.
And you guys had no problem with.
That was fine.
That made sense.
And that I would be on the light was the
darkness.
And that was the elephant graveyard.
That was death.
That was the place of death and danger.
That's where the hyenas hung out.
And you weren't supposed to go there.
And so of course,
Simba,
because he's a rule breaking hero,
just like Harry Potter immediately goes
there.
And so,
you know,
that's like the forbidden fruit.
It's the same sort of idea.
If you want someone to do something,
the best thing to do is tell them that
they shouldn't and not explain why,
you know.
So for example,
if I said to you at the beginning of
this class,
look,
I've got one rule here,
don't sit in that chair no matter what
you'd be thinking the whole year,
especially if I reminded you just what's
up with that chair.
Like that's chairs magical.
All of a sudden you,
some of you might even,
while you probably wouldn't,
because this is a ridiculous example,
but maybe you know,
you come to class early and sit in that
chair just to see what would happen.
You know,
and people are very curious.
And that's exactly what we're like.
And that's a very old story too,
right?
It's like opening Pandora's box.
Don't open that box.
You'll be sorry.
It's like,
oh,
you know,
all of the horrors of the world fly out
and believe me,
you will open Pandora's box many times
in your life because you know with your
family or maybe your mate or maybe your
children,
you'll have this idea that they have a
box with things in it that you want to
know about and you'll say,
well,
I'm kind of curious about this
particular event,
so why don't you tell me about it?
And they say,
well no,
we probably really shouldn't open that
box and you keep bugging him and then
they open it and then all sorts of
things fly out that you didn't expect
and then maybe you think,
hey,
it would have been better if I would
have just left that damn box closed,
but,
and you can do the same thing to
yourself.
Believe me.
And so the Pandora's box idea,
the forbidden fruit idea.
That's,
that's a major league idea.
And part of the reason in the Judeo
Christian tradition,
why people are saddled with the notion
of original sin is because hyper
cortically developed chimpanzees without
much sense.
Can't keep their hands off things.
And so they keep exploring even when
they know better and every time they do
that,
they learn something that is,
that destroys the paradise that they
currently inhabit.
Right?
Because there's plenty in the.
And I never learned anything in your
life.
It's of importance without it having a
pretty damn destabilizing effect on you
at the moment of realization,
right?
You learn something happy.
It's like whatever,
you know,
that'll,
that means is that I was doing things
right,
like it's nice and everything,
but it's not informative.
You do something and all hell breaks
loose.
That'll make you think now it's for sure
you might never stop thinking for the
rest of your life.
So anyways,
the unknown,
the unknown is that which surrounds the
known.
It's unexplored territory.
It's usually represented as female,
I think for a variety of reasons.
And not,
not as female.
Exactly.
It's not the right way to think about it
as feminine.
And that's not the same thing because
feminine is a symbolic category,
whereas female is like an actual female.
And so you don't want to confuse the
metaphor with the,
with the,
with the actuality.
Um,
because we had these social cognitive
categories built in,
you know,
you might say masculine,
feminine and offspring,
something like that.
We had to use what we could to represent
what we were attempting to figure out
and we kind of mapped them onto the
external realities of being the best we
could,
using what we could.
And so,
you know,
nature is benevolent and it's fruitful.
All things come from nature and all
things come from the unknown,
right?
Because the known is already there.
It's the unknown that manifests the new,
right?
And so that's part of the reason for the
characterization of the unknown as
feminine.
Um,
and then there's also the case that
women play a massive role in sexual
selection among human beings.
So that from an evolutionary
perspective,
you're twice as likely to be a failure
if you're a man than you are.
If you're a woman in that you have twice
as many female ancestors as male
ancestors and you think,
well,
that's impossible,
but it's not.
All you have to do is imagine that every
woman has one child,
half the men have to,
and the other half have zero.
And so end of problem,
and that's basically how it works out.
So women are more choosy maters than men
by a substantial margin.
There was a funny study done by the guy
who established one of the big dating
sites and he looked at how women rated
men and they rated the 50th percentile
man at the 15th percentile.
So 85 percent of men were below average
according to women's ratings.
Now men had their same arbitrary choices
because of course they preferred younger
women to older women and they were more
swayed,
I would say by um,
by attractiveness,
but that didn't have nearly as big an
effect on their actually actual rating
of,
of women.
So anyways,
so,
you know,
from a,
from a Darwinian perspective,
nature is that which selects,
that's all it is.
And so sexual selection plays a massive
role in human evolution.
You know,
the fact that we have these massive
brains is very likely a consequence of a
positive feedback loop and sexual
selection,
you know,
because otherwise that's the only time
you can get really rapid changes in
evolutionary space where you get a
process going.
That reinforces itself.
So there's a little preference for
intelligence and then that produces more
intelligent men and women and then
there's a little more preference for
intelligence and you know,
maybe then that turns into the ability
to speak and,
or to master fire and then there's way
more selection for intelligence in the
brain just goes like this,
you know,
and women have paid a pretty big price
for that because your hips are basically
so wide that you can barely run and if
they were any wider than you couldn't.
And of course the,
the pelvic passageway through which the
baby travels is too small.
So it's really painful and dangerous and
the baby's head has to compress quite a
lot.
I mean they come out,
cone shaped often and then they're born
really young so you have to take care of
them forever.
Like what the hell,
you know,
a deer is born,
a fawn is born and it's like two seconds
later it's standing and then it's
running from a lion.
It's like,
you know,
it's like 15 minutes later and a baby.
It's like you just lies there and you
know,
utters plaintive noises.
That's all it can do,
and that does that for like 10 months
before it could skitter away from a
slothy if it was predatory,
you know,
so you really got to take care of those
creatures.
And so that's a big price to pay.
That's a big price to pay for our
critical evolution.
So anyways,
here's some of the symbolic
representations represents
representatives of the unknown,
the unconscious dot uneasy,
and four of the ID.
So that's sort of Freud's representation
of the unknown,
the terrors of the darkness.
That's the unknown.
The monsters that lurk there,
the source and the resting place of all
things.
The great mother,
the Queen,
the Matrix which means mater,
which means mother,
the matriarch matter,
mother,
the container,
the Cornucopia,
the object to be fertilized,
the source of all things,
the fecund,
the pregnant,
the strange,
the emotional,
the foreigner,
the place of returned and rest.
The deeper the valley,
the cleft,
the cave hell,
death and the grave because it's beyond
the moon.
Ruler of the night and mysterious,
dark and matter and the earth.
And you know all this because when you
watch a movie that's rife with symbolic
representations that draws on those
underlying metaphors and they're
natural,
I mean where does it,
which live well in a swamp for God's
sake.
She doesn't live in the penthouse of a
New York Tower.
She lives at a swamp and it's dark
there.
And if the moon's up,
that's a better.
And maybe it could be a crescent moon or
maybe it could be a full moon,
but you know,
which is live in the right place if
you're going to understand it
and you all,
you understand all of that.
And it's part of the structure of your
imagination you could say.
And so it's part of the unspoken
fantastical Ah,
imagination that unites all of us and
that makes us specifically human.
There is a good representation of the
underworld and the place of
transformation.
So that's hell in Isis.
In Egypt was queen of the underworld and
the underworld generally has a queen and
she usually shows up when order falls
apart.
And so you go to the underworld.
When your life falls apart,
that's what it means.
And so when you see these stories of the
hero,
you know,
journeying to unknown lands of terror
and danger,
that's,
that's what happens to you.
It happens to you all the time.
You know you're,
you're in this little safe space like
the hobbit in the Shire,
and then you know there's a great evil
brewing somewhere and you can no longer
ignore it.
So off you go into the land of terror
and uncertainty and better to go on
purpose then accidentally,
that's for sure,
because at least you can be prepared.
And we also know that if you're going to
face a threat,
if you face it voluntarily,
what happens is your body activates
itself for exploration and mastery.
But if you face it voluntarily,
same size threat,
then you,
you,
you revert to pray,
pray mode and you're frozen.
And that's way,
way,
way more stressful.
It's way harder on your body and so it's
better to keep your eyes open and watch
for emergent threats because you all
know,
you know what you're not doing quite
right and where your life is likely to
unravel.
You all have a sense of that.
And the best thing to do is to not
ignore that,
to pay attention to it,
to watch it,
and to take corrective action early.
And then you know,
you stay on top of things and things,
your little trip to the underworld might
be a few minutes long instead of a
catastrophe that produces posttraumatic
stress disorder,
knocks you out for four or five years
and maybe you never recover.
So.
And that's,
you know,
that's what these kind of symbolic
representations mean.
It's,
those are states of being that,
that,
that indicate being devoured and you can
be devoured by your own unconscious.
Jesus.
That happens all the time.
What does that mean?
Well,
you know,
and it's an autonomous thing in some
sense.
You know,
like if you,
if you get depressed or if you get
really anxious,
you don't have any control over that.
It's like it sweeps up over you and
pulls you down.
Wydown well down is where you go when
you're sad.
You don't go up,
man,
I'm up today.
Oh,
that's too bad.
No,
it's man.
I'm down today.
And while that's partly this,
and it's partly because this is
subordinate and it's partly because down
is closer to the ground and farther from
the sky,
like there's all sorts of reasons you're
feeling down rather than op.
Op is where you're aiming,
right?
Yay.
Mop.
You don't aim down.
Well,
the reason those phrases make sense
because they're locked deeply into this
underlying structure of imagination.
And while those are the architects of
the archetypal structures according to
young and um,
I,
I think that he's far as I can tell
he's dead accurate.
Um,
and I think we understand the biology of
such things much better than we did.
So there is more representation.
She's,
she's quite the friendly creature.
That's Kelly.
Um,
I like this representation better.
Those are heads by the way and hands.
Um,
so she sort of represents well,
very complex thing.
She represents death,
she represents transformation in this.
I really liked this representation.
I think it's brilliant.
So imagine that what the people were
doing who formulated these
representations,
what they were trying to do was to make
a representation of the domain of threat
itself,
right?
So that they could deal with the idea
that because we can say,
threat,
well,
what is that?
What the hell does that mean?
Well,
threat is the category of all
threatening things.
And so then you can think about threat
and you can think about threat across
all those individual instances and maybe
you can figure out how to deal with
threat,
right?
How,
what's the best way to be in the world
so that you most effectively deal with
threat.
While that's sort of like,
apart from how do you deal with pain,
that sort of like the ultimate question
of human beings.
You want to be terrified?
No.
So you want to be in danger?
So like,
you better figure out how to deal with
threats.
So first of all,
you have to conceptualize it.
So we'll take a look at this
representation.
So now it's Kelly sheer.
Her hair is on fire.
Well,
fire,
you know,
that's,
that's a numinous phenomena.
Dangerous but transformative.
She's wearing a headdress of skulls.
Um,
she has a weapon in this hand.
And,
and uh,
she has a tiger's tongue.
She often has a snake around her waist.
Need none of these do,
but she often does,
but in this case,
the stem,
that's because snake,
we've already covered that.
Well,
these things that looked like snakes
here aren't you notice how her belly is
concave?
Well,
it's because she's just given birth to
this unfortunate person that she happens
to be standing on and she's eating him
intestines first and that's a fire ring,
which he is in,
and then it's got skulls on the inside
of it.
It's like,
what's that supposed to do?
Well,
partly it's supposed to represent that
which terrifies you.
It's like,
yeah,
fair enough,
man,
because I don't imagine you saw those
things in there before I explain them,
but someone who was familiar with that
image would know what it meant.
It's like some poor artist was sitting
there thinking,
well,
how do I represent?
It's like,
Bang,
Whoa,
okay,
we'll put that down and then we won't
look at it again.
So,
and then what do you do with this?
You make sacrifices to it and you think,
well that's kind of primitive,
you know,
first of all,
well that doesn't really exist.
Well it does.
If it's an amalgam of threat symbols,
I can tell you that it exists.
That's for sure.
So it exists as an abstraction.
If nothing else do you offer it?
Sacrifices?
Well,
what the hell do you think you do?
What do you do it in class?
Why aren't you like drinking vodka and
snorting cocaine?
You know,
because you could be doing that instead.
Here you are listening to me,
you know,
slaving away in university,
you're young.
It's like,
really?
You've got nothing better to do than sit
there.
You know what you're willing to forego
today's pleasure for tomorrow's
advantage.
And that's what sacrifice is.
And human being's discovered that
dramatically first.
You know,
like we're,
we're apes for God's sake.
We didn't just leap up and think,
oh,
we better save for tomorrow.
You know,
we took thousands of years for that idea
to emerge and it emerged in dramatic
form and it was sort of like,
well,
society is sort of like a god no.
What they weren't thinking this through
is like,
if you're going to represent society
well,
it's like this masculine God.
That's always judging the hell out of
you.
That's everywhere,
all at the same time.
It's like,
yeah,
that's true.
Absolutely.
And what do you have to do with it?
Well,
you have to give it what it wants.
Why?
Why do you have to give it what it
wants?
Because it'll crush you if you don't.
And that's exactly right.
And if you're lucky and you give it the
right sacrifice,
then it will smile on you and you get to
have a good life.
And that was like,
that was the major discovery of mankind.
Man.
That was the killer discovery.
It was like the discovery of the future,
you know,
we discovered the future as a place and
it was a place that you could bargain
with.
You can bargain with the future.
Wow.
That's just what an idea that is.
You know,
it's,
it's so unlikely.
Well,
how do you bargain with the future while
you give it what it wants?
And you know,
some of that's you maintain your social
relationship and you know,
you make yourself useful to other people
and you shape yourself so that you can
cooperate with people and you,
you don't act impulsively,
and maybe you squirrel something away
for the next harvest,
even if you're hungry and you know,
and then the future isn't hell and you
make the proper sacrifices.
And so if you sacrifice to Kelly,
then she turns into her opposite and
showers benevolence on you.
And that's mother nature,
right?
It's like,
look out for Mother Nature,
man,
you know,
two weeks out in the right now and your
dad and it's not pleasant.
And then if it's the spring,
you'll last longer,
but the bugs eat you.
And so that's not very fun either.
So nature,
you know,
it's bent on your destruction,
but if you treat it properly and
carefully and make the right sacrifices,
then maybe one of her trees will offer
you some fruit and that would be okay.
And so,
believe me,
lots of people died trying to figure
that out.
So here's another way of looking at it.
So I said,
you know,
order and chaos,
known unknown,
unexplored territory,
unexplored territory.
I love this.
This is the Taoist symbol.
It's a symbol of being and being isn't
reality as you would conceptualize it as
a scientist.
It's more like reality as it manifests
itself to you as a living thing,
which is completely different.
You know,
science extracts out all the
subjectivity,
all it is,
there is an array of objective facts of
equivalent value and that's part of its
method,
but that's not the world in which you
live.
The world in which you live is full of
motivation and emotion.
It's full of terror and pain and joy and
frustration and,
and other people.
That's for sure.
And so that's the real world.
And so,
well that's what this is.
It's,
it's the real world.
And what is it made out of?
Well,
it's made out of all those things,
you know,
that can get out of hand,
because the explored territory and the
known can get so damn tight that it's
nothing but a tyrant.
And then it's all those things you don't
know.
And that's pretty exciting because you
know,
you want to go find out some things you
don't know and that adds a lot of spice
to life.
You want a little adventure.
You don't want to go out with someone
who's so predictable that you know
everything about them in a week.
You know,
unless you're hyper conservative,
you want to go out with someone who's
got there a little erratic,
like not too erratic.
Let's say they're a little dangerous,
perhaps not too dangerous,
but some of that at least you want
predictability with a bit of
unpredictability in there.
Well,
that's exactly what this means.
It's thick.
That's predictability with a little
unpredictability in it.
And what that also means is that what
you know can be turned into what you
don't know just like that.
And now it's going to happen to you.
Lots of times in your life,
man,
when someone close to you dies,
suddenly it's like,
poof,
order turns into chaos and now you're in
chaos.
And what the hell are you going to do
there?
And that's a good question because you
need to know what to do there because
you're going to be there and it happens
to you when your dreams fall apart,
you know,
I mean your dreams for your life or you
know,
when you discover something awful about
yourself that you didn't know or you
know,
it flips on you all the time and in
small ways.
Sometimes you know,
you have a fight with a friend or in big
ways that,
that wipe you out for while indefinitely
sometimes because you can fall into
chaos and never get out.
You know,
that's the people who are trapped in the
belly of the beast.
It isn't necessarily that when you
descend into chaos that you learn
something and you get back out.
You could just be stuck there suffering
until you die.
And that's,
you know,
I wouldn't recommend that.
You know,
it's something to avoid.
But it happens to people all the time.
All the time.
You see them wandering around,
you know,
shattered on the streets of Toronto,
they're done.
They're in chaos and there's so much
chaos around them that you won't even go
near them.
The chaos spreads like eight feet around
them and so when you see someone like
that,
you're like,
well first we're not going to look too
closely,
and people like that often don't like
you to look at them because that also
helps them remember where they are and
that's no pleasant thing and you're
going to just stay away from that.
Maybe you'll cross the street,
maybe you'll keep your head down,
whatever.
You're not going anywhere near that
chaos and no bloody wonder.
You know,
and,
and you don't think about it much after
you pass it because it's a hell of a
thing to think about and what are you
going to do about it anyway so you don't
know what to do about it.
You might just make it worse.
Well,
so chaos,
you know,
that's the other half of life and it can
turn into order sometimes better order.
That's actually what you do when you
explore,
right?
You explore,
you find out something new,
not too new,
not to Pandora boxy,
you know,
bite off as much as you can chew,
but no more and so that rearranges the
way you look at the world,
but you're doing it voluntarily so you
can kind of tolerate the recalibration
and you strengthen the order,
right?
Because now you become more competent
and I would say that you're trying to
live on the edge between order and chaos
and I and I mean that's a real place.
That's an actual.
It's a Meta place,
but it's more real than places because
it's so old.
It's such an old place.
It really exists and your nervous system
knows that it sees the world this way.
In fact,
the right hemisphere is roughly
specialized for chaos and the left
hemisphere is roughly specialized for
order,
which is why the left hemisphere tends
to have the linguistic elements and why
people are right handed.
And the right hemisphere has a more
diffuse structure.
It's more associated with negative
emotion and imagination and the to
communicate between each other through
the Corpus callosum and the right
hemisphere appears to update the less
left hemisphere kind of slowly,
often in dreams.
And so if you are hurt,
if your right hemisphere has hurt,
for example,
back here in the prior lobe,
then you lose the left part of your
body.
You can't move it anymore,
but you also lose the idea that you have
a left part of your body.
So it's like blindness.
It's a blindness to the left.
And so if someone comes along and says,
you know,
you're not moving your left arm,
you're going to say,
yeah,
well my arthritis is bothering me to the
I moved it for six months.
Well,
arthritis is bothering today,
or you know,
you don't move your left foot like,
well,
you know,
uh,
I'm too tired.
Well,
what's happened is the left hemisphere
has a representation of the body and
it's not being updated because the part
of the brain that would notice that the
left is gone because of a stroke.
It isn't there anymore.
And so the left already has a model and
it's not going to change.
Just it's hard to change your model of
yourself.
You don't have a tooth pulled.
What happens?
It's like your damn tongue is in that
hole for the next six months fiddling
around constantly.
And that's because you're rebuilding
your neurological model of your body.
It's like try it out with your whole
left side and see how well you do.
You know.
So this guy named Ramachandran was
experimenting with people like this and
one of the things he did was Kinda.
He was checking their balance and you
can do that by irrigating the ear with
cold water and that makes people go like
this,
makes their eyes move back and forth
because it upsets the vestibular system.
And what he found was that if he,
if he poured cold water in the left ear
of someone with right parietal damage
who had left neglect,
that they'd all of a sudden sort of wake
up catastrophic Lee,
they'd have a terrible reaction to the
fact that they were paralyzed on the
left and they would know that it had
happened and cry.
And it made all sorts of distress and no
wonder,
and then like 20 minutes later they
snapped back into their damaged mode of
being and they would not deny because
that isn't really what it is,
is that they couldn't update the model,
they just didn't have the neurology for
it anymore.
So they were backed in not noticing that
it was gone and coming up with stories
about it and so
well.
So that's a good example of how the
right and left hemispheres work together
and how they're kind of mapped onto this
weirdly enough so you know,
we're map were adapted to the Meta
reality.
And so what that would be is we're
adapted to that which remains constant
across the longest spans of time.
And that's not the same things that you
see flitting around you day to day.
Those are just,
they just like clouds.
They're just evaporating.
You know,
there's things underneath that that are
more fundamental that are more
fundamental realities like the dominance
hierarchy,
like the tribe,
like the danger outside of society,
like the threat that other people pose
to you and that you pose to yourself.
Those are eternal realities and we're
adapted to those.
That's our world and that's why we
express that in stories.
And so then you might say,
well,
how do you adapt yourself to this world?
And the answer to that is,
and I believe this is a neurological
answer,
I believe this,
that your brain can tell you when you're
optimally situated between chaos and
order and the way it tells you that is
by producing the sense of engagement and
meaning.
So let's say there's a place in the
environment you should be okay,
what should that place be?
Well,
you don't want to be terrified out of
your skull.
Like what good is that?
And you know,
you don't want to be so comfortable that
you might as well sleep.
You want to be somewhere where you know
you're kind of on firm ground here,
but over here you're kind of testing out
new territory and some of you who were
exploratory and emotionally stable,
you know you're going to go pretty far
out into the unexplored territory
without destabilizing yourself.
And other people are gonna.
Just put a toe in the chaos and you
know,
that's neuroticism basically,
that's your sensitivity to threat,
that's calibrated differently in
different people and some people are
more exploratory than others.
That's kind of extraversion and openness
working together and,
and intelligence.
So some people are going to tolerate a
larger admixture of chaos in their
order.
Those are liberals by the way.
And,
and I mean that technically liberals are
more interested in novel chaos and
conservatives are more interested in the
stabilization of the structures that
already exist and who's right?
Well,
it depends on the situation and that's
why conservatives and liberals have to
talk to each other because one of them
isn't right and the other wrong.
Sometimes the conservatives are right
and sometimes the liberals are right
because the environment's going like
this,
he can't predict the damn thing.
So that's why you have to communicate.
And that's what a democracy does,
is it allows people of different
temperamental types to communicate and
to calibrate the damn societies.
So anyways,
so let's say you're optimally balanced
between chaos and order.
So what does that mean?
Well,
you're stable enough but you're
interested,
right?
Because a little novelty heightens your
anxiety that wakes you up a bit.
That's the adventure part of it,
but it also focuses the part of your
brain that does exploratory activity and
that's actually associated with
pleasure.
That's the dopamine circuit.
And so if you're optimally balanced and
you know that you know you're there when
you're listening to an interesting
conversation or you're engaged in one,
it's a real conversation.
You know you're saying some things you
know and the other person is saying some
things they know,
but the both of what you know is
changing.
It's like,
wow,
that's so interesting.
You'll have a conversation like that
forever.
Or maybe you're reading a book like
that,
or you're listening to a piece of music
that models that because what music does
is provide you with predictable forms,
multilevel predictable forms that
transform just the right amount.
And so music is a very representational
art form.
It says,
this is what the universe is like.
You know,
there's a dancing element to it.
Repetitive and then cute variations that
sort of surprise and delight you and,
and you think,
wow,
that's so cool and it doesn't matter how
nihilistic you are.
Music still inside infuses you with a
sense of meaning and that's because it
models meaning that's what it does is
that's why we love it and you know,
you could dance to it and that sort of
symbolizes you putting yourself in
harmony with these multiple poll layers
of reality and positioning yourself
properly and you like that too.
You know,
you'll pay for it.
Oh boy,
I get to go dancing,
you know?
Oh boy.
I get to listen to music.
Like what the hell are you doing?
Listening to music.
What good is that?
Well,
you think that's a stupid question.
I don't care about your dopey criticism.
I'm going to listen to some music,
right?
There's no rational.
There's no rational argument against
music.
It's like you just don't even think
about him.
He just walk away from someone who's
stupid enough to ask that question.
It's like
some things are obvious.
Well
why?
Okay,
so that's pretty fun.
So what mediates between these two
domains?
While that's what consciousness does,
far as I can tell,
and that sort of the individual,
and that's the hero,
that's another way of thinking about it.
It's the logos.
That's another way of thinking about it.
It's the word that generates order out
of chaos at the beginning of time.
It's the consciousness that interacting
with the matter of the world produces
being.
That's basically it.
That's basically you for all intents and
purposes.
Um,
how do you do that?
Well,
the unconscious does it to some degree,
you know,
because it's with our fantasy that we
first meet the unknown,
right?
Well,
look,
say you're going out with a new person.
It's like what do you do?
You project a fantasy on them and then
you fall in love with the fantasy and
aren't used stupid because you're going
to find out that the match between your
damn fantasy in the actual person is
tenuous at best.
And so young would call that a
projection of either the anima or the
animus.
The Anima is what a man projects onto a
woman he finds desirable.
It's like,
oh,
she's the perfect woman.
It's like,
well,
how do you know that you've like seen
her for four seconds,
you know,
but it grips you and the same thing
happens in the opposite direction and
it's an action of instinct.
You know?
It's like you fall in love with the
image and but interestingly enough,
what you do in a relationship that works
is that you actually,
I think that what you see a rough
approximation when you project the ideal
and fall in love with it,
you see what could be.
It could be that,
but it's going to take a hell of a lot
of work because like you got no shortage
of flaws and the other person has no
shortage of flaws and so you're bringing
your flaws together and that's going to
produce a lot of and you're going to
have to engage in a lot of dialogue
before you approach that level of
perfection again.
But
maybe you can do it.
Then you get to live happily ever after.
Well,
wouldn't that be nice?
so the unconscious meets the unknown and
if it meets it with imagination and
fantasy and dream and art,
that's how you take.
So you don't just go from what you don't
know to fully articulated knowledge and
one bloody leap.
You can't do that.
You have to extend pseudopods of fantasy
and imagination into the unknown.
That's kind of what theorizing is like,
right?
Even scientifically,
you know,
you don't know something scientifically,
you generate a theory.
Well,
it's an imaginative representation that
you're unconscious is helping you
generate and so you meet the unknown
with fantasy.
That's what the unconscious is for.
From the psychoanalytic perspective.
That's what dreams do.
And you can see why you dream about the
future.
You know,
it's like,
well,
what's the future going to be like,
wow,
you have a little imaginative story
going on and it's like you don't really
create it and it sort of,
you watch it unfold,
you know,
maybe you can tweak it here and there,
but it sort of comes to you from
wherever the hell things like that come
from.
You know,
the unconscious,
that's the psychoanalytic answer.
It's not really much of an answer
because it's more like a representation
of a,
of a place that we don't understand,
but that's where creativity comes from.
And I mean some people are really
creative right down to the bloody core.
So in my clinical practice,
I often see people who are high in
openness because they're attracted to me
because they watch my lectures and you
have to kind of be high in openness to
like my lectures,
so because,
well you do because they go everywhere,
you know,
and they're not necessarily very
orderly.
So,
um,
so anyways,
lots of my clients are really high in
openness and they're funny people often,
especially if they're smart because
sometimes they have the most nihilistic
intelligence you can imagine.
It's just self critical and nihilistic
and brutally brutal man and smart.
And so they just criticize themselves
out of existence.
And so often I have to just try to get
them to quit listening to their
chattering raw self critical rationality
and go out and create something,
you know,
with their massive creativity.
And as long as they're doing that,
they're engaged in the world and happy
as hell.
But as soon as that self critical
rationality comes in and shuts down the
creativity,
they're just there just like walking
corpses,
you know,
and it's because if you're really open
like that's you're a tree and it has
some trunks and you know,
your,
your most prominent trait is the most
lively trunk.
And if you're a creative person and
you're not engaging in a creative
enterprise,
you're just,
you're like a tree that has been,
that has had its vitality amputated.
And so this is not trivial.
This stuff is.
This is deeply,
deeply rooted in your biology.
And,
and those are people often who have like
dream lives.
You just can't believe.
I have one client,
he has like four spectacular dreams a
week.
And most of the time we just spend
discussing them.
I mean God,
he and I had another client who could be
lucid in her dreams,
which is more common among women.
She could ask the damn characters what
they represented and they would tell
her.
It was like,
okay,
that was pretty weird.
And like a lot of the things they told
her were really helpful and they were
not things that she wanted to hear.
She,
she basically,
one of them told her she,
if she was going to live,
she'd have to go visit a slaughterhouse.
And the reason for that was because she
was raised as a little princess and
protected from horrible mother nature
until she hit puberty,
in which time she turned into an evil
villain because that's how the family
work.
Perfect child evil teenager overnight.
And then,
well that was hard on her and she wasn't
prepared because she thought the world
was princess world and she couldn't go
through a butcher store without having a
fifth and no wonder,
you know,
like really Jesus,
it's no wonder,
but you do it.
But she couldn't.
So we used to go to butcher stores and
that would make her cry.
And,
and um,
she was a vegetarian that would make her
cry and you know,
be mon the cruelty of the world.
And it's like,
yeah,
fair enough,
man.
Those are bloody slabs of meat.
It's like,
I don't know why everyone isn't
screaming when they walked through the
butcher store,
but,
but you got to get used to it band
because you can't live in the world
otherwise,
and so the dream character who was a
gypsy told her that she had to go visit
a slaughterhouse which seemed rather
impractical and so I asked her if she
could think of anything else to do and
she thought,
well,
why don't we go visit a funeral home and
and watch an embalming?
And I thought,
oh good,
that sounds,
that sounds like a fun way to spend a
day.
And so I phoned up a funeral parlor
and I said I declined.
It was terrified of death now and I was
a therapist who is also a little shaky
on the concept myself and so they,
they had no problem with that.
They deal with death all the time,
which is really something to think
about,
right?
A human being can actually have an
occupation where they do nothing but
deal with death and they don't go stark
raving mad.
It's like,
what the hell is up with that?
It's like working in a palliative care
ward where your,
your clients that you have a
relationship,
all they're going to do is die this
week,
next week,
the week after.
People do that.
It's like those people are tough man.
They're tough.
So anyways,
we went and watched this embalming,
which was,
I have a rather high level of disgust
sensitivity.
So it,
it was a little on the rough side for
me,
but she sat there and first,
well she was not.
We were outside this little room.
She was not looking at that know away
and she'd kind of go like this and you
know,
that was pretty good.
And then she'd go like this and then she
go like this and then then she watched
it and then she asked if she could go in
and she put on a glove and she touched
the body and she didn't have a fit.
She didn't have a panic attack and so
she walked away from their learning that
there was a hell of a lot more to her
than she thought there was and that she
could see things that she didn't think
she could see.
And live,
and after that she sort of had a
touchstone.
It's like,
well,
I'm kind of afraid of this.
Was it as bad as going to see the
bombing?
No,
it's not that bad.
Well,
I guess I can do it.
It's like an initiation,
right?
She had an initiation and so did I,
you know,
and I learned a lot from doing that.
I learned that one of the things you
need to do if you're going to be a human
being is to prepare yourself to be
useful in the face of death.
And so when you have a parent that dies,
which shatters people's ideas,
often they can't even think about it.
If you can't even think about that,
man,
you've got some thinking to do because
you need to be able to at least think
about that because otherwise you're just
going to be a wasteland when it happens.
And you never know.
You could even have a higher ambition.
Maybe you could even be useful when it
happens.
Instead of being part of the heap of
destroyed people who also have to be
taken care of,
you know?
And that's brutal.
You have to be brutal to be useful in
the aftermath of your parents' death.
You know,
you don't get to crumble and fall apart
and knowing you have every reason to,
so you've got to be kind of some tough
monster to manage that,
but you want to be useful in the face of
tragedy or do you want to be pathetic?
Well,
you make your choice so out of the
unconscious,
you get ritual,
you get dreams,
you get drama,
you get stories,
you could arc.
You get music and that sort of buffers
us.
We have our little domain of competence
and we're buffered by the domain of
fantasy and culture and that's really
what you learned about when you come to
university,
if you're lucky and,
and the professors are smart enough to
actually teach you something about
culture instead of constantly telling
you that it's completely reprehensible
and should be destroyed.
It's like why you would prefer chaos to
order is beyond me.
And the only possible reason is that you
haven't read enough history to
understand exactly what chaos means.
And believe me,
if you understood what it means,
you'd be pretty God damn careful about
tearing down the temple that you live it
unless you want to be at Denison of
chaos.
And some people do,
you know,
because that's when the impulses that
you harbor can really come out and
shine.
And so a little gratitude is in order
and that makes you appreciative of the
wise king.
Well being smart enough to know that
he's also an evil tyrant.
It's like that's,
that's a total conception of the world.
It's balanced.
It's like,
yeah,
we should preserve nature,
but good God,
it is trying to kill us.
And you know,
yes,
our culture is tyrannical and oppresses
people,
but it is protecting us from dying.
That's helpful.
You know,
and yes we're reasonably good people but
like don't take that theory too far
until you've tested yourself and you
know,
that's wisdom at least in part.
And that's what these stories try to
teach you.
There is a nice mythological
representation.
I love this one.
It's like the dome of the known and the
seeker looking outside,
you know,
that's a metaphysical representation,
and that is the world is,
it looks to us,
right?
You go out in the field and it looks
like there's a dome covering it.
It's a circle,
a big circle with a dome over it.
And you know what's outside the Dome
while the unknown,
right?
That's where heaven is theoretically,
you know,
it's a projection.
Obviously heaven is in the unknown.
Well,
it was localized in space.
I suppose that's partly because when
people looked up in the sky,
they were overwhelmed with all.
So it's a reasonable conclusion.
It,
it's a projection of an unconscious
presupposition.
It's a projection of fantasy,
you know,
heaven is a fantasy and,
and I'm not denigrating fantasy by the
way,
and it's projected imaginatively onto
the sky.
And that's part of the way you discover
what's in your fantasy.
Well,
this is us,
man.
We mediate between chaos and order and
you know,
those are the two archetypal
representations fundamentally,
you know,
um,
and I think they apply to both genders.
You know,
like women can act as the individual who
holds the world on his or her shoulders
and males.
Men can play a maternal role,
you know,
feet,
female,
human beings are quite masculine and
male.
Human beings are quite feminine and so,
you know,
maybe maybe this archetype dominates
among men in that archetype dominates
among women,
which I would say is that is the case as
far as I'm concerned,
although they're in our individual
conceptions,
of course those two things have to work
in conjunction,
but that's you,
the eternal mediator between chaos and
order,
which also has its enemy.
So that's,
that's horace there.
And that seth who's eventually turns
into Satan as the,
as the west progresses,
so to speak,
and that's represented there as well.
The temptations of I would say
resentment and hatred,
which everyone has to fight with all the
time.
Alright.
Initiations.
So this is cool.
This is a standard hero story.
And initiate initiatory rights are a
part of human heritage.
And so let's take a look.
This is from Eliana.
I would like even now stress the fact
that the psychopathology of the romantic
vocation is not profane,
it does not belong to ordinary
symptomatology.
It's not mental illness,
it has an ent initiatory structure and
signification.
In short,
it reproduces a traditional mystical
pattern.
The total crisis of the future Sharman
sometimes leading to complete
disintegration of the personality and to
madness can be evaluated not only as an
initiatory death,
but also as a symbolic return to the pre
cosmogony chaos to the amorphous and
indescribable state that precedes any
cosmogony.
While what he means by that is that I
suppose the mythological view of the
emergence of order that's a cosmogony is
that there's a state of potential and
chaos out of which order emerges.
And I,
you know,
here's,
here's how it is that you think that way
because you do think that way.
So you know,
imagine what you're facing when you're
facing the future,
right?
While you might say,
well,
the future is full of potential,
right?
It's full of potential.
What the hell does that mean?
You know,
you act as if that you act as if that
potential is really a real thing and
you're confronting it all the time.
I'm confronting the potential of the
future.
Well,
it doesn't exist yet,
so what you're confronting doesn't even
really exist.
What you're conceptualizing doesn't
really exist and in some sense you bring
it into being by plotting your path
through it,
while the pre cosmo going to chaos is
the same as the potential of the future,
it's exactly the same idea.
It's the realm of possibility from which
actuality emerges and you participate in
turning that possibility into actuality.
That's what you're doing all the time.
Now,
can I explain that?
Well,
no.
I have no idea how consciousness and the
substrate of the world interact.
I can only say that that's how it looks.
That's how it feels.
You know,
that's how people act and they'll get
into trouble if they don't manifest
their potential,
whatever that is.
That's all those things you could be
that you're not well,
where are those?
It's just potential.
While that's the chaos,
this is a.
that's the.
I would say that's the cosmos.
That's the cosmos that you live in all
the time.
It's a little story.
It's the thing that you extract out of
the chaos.
It sorta consists of your conception of
where you are now and your conception of
where you want to be at some point could
be 10 minutes,
could be three years it has.
You can slide it and then you have a
little plan about how you should move
your body to transform one into the
other.
That's your action pattern.
That's a little story and when you ask
someone to say what they were up to,
they'll tell you a little story like
that.
You know,
I was at someplace and I went somewhere
else and here's how I did it.
Then they might tell you more
interesting story,
which is I was someplace and something
happened that I really didn't expect and
it knocked me for a loop,
you know,
and that's a good divorce story.
I came home one night and my wife was
gone.
It's like,
yeah,
chaos and probably a bit of willful
blindness proceeding it.
We might suspect anyways down into chaos
and then,
well maybe you learn something down
there and maybe you don't,
but hopefully you do and you put
yourself together if you're lucky,
and then pop bang,
you pop up into another little structure
of order and that's an initiatory
process.
It's like you're somewhere stable,
falls apart,
or maybe you break it apart on purpose.
You do it voluntarily.
You know people do that all the time.
You know they do that.
For example,
when they experiment with drugs and they
do that when they go on wild adventures
and you know when they break themselves
out of their normal routine and throw
themselves somewhere,
they don't understand and hope that
that's going to produce a transformation
of personality.
That's the basic story.
That's the initiatory story.
Now,
this is William James who was the one of
the established rules of modern
psychology and I kind of an odd guy.
He was an early experimenter with
psychedelics.
Of course,
they'll never tell you that,
but he was and he has.
His drug of choice was nitrous oxide,
which is an inhalent gas,
which seems to be inert.
No one really knows why it works,
but it produces quite intense,
a hallucinogenic experience,
mystical experience.
Although if you breathe too much of it,
then you die because it doesn't.
It doesn't have any oxygen in it,
so,
so don't do that.
And,
and he wrote some really bad hippie
poetry back in the 18 eighties.
Well,
he was,
you know,
experimenting with,
with nitrous oxide is.
I'll read a little bit of that too.
You pure experiences.
The name which I give to the original
flux of life before reflection has
categorized it.
Only newborn Babes and persons in semi
coma from sleep,
drugs,
illnesses or blows can have an
experience pure in the literal sense of,
of that which is not yet any definite,
what they'll ready to be,
any sorts of what's fourth full,
both of oneness and of many dentists,
but in respects that don't appear
changing throughout yet.
So confusedly that it's phases,
interpenetrate and no points either of
distinction or of identity can be
caught.
Nineteen.
Oh,
five William James,
Journal of Philosophy.
You know,
a lot of these old guys that established
what we regard as fairly stable bodies
of knowledge were just as crazy as you
can possibly imagine.
They're just the most peculiar damn
people and they get sanitized,
you know,
as,
as they are represented in history and
that's no fun.
You know?
I mean,
it's much more interesting to know what
they were like.
They were just so bloody peculiar and
strange and involved in all sorts of
weird things.
It's a lot more fun to know that.
Here's his poem.
Wow.
Like right from 1968,
no verbiage can give it because the
verbiage is other incoherent,
coherent,
same,
and it fades and it's infinite and it's
infinite.
Don't you see the difference?
Don't you see the identity constantly?
Opposites united,
the same me telling you to write and not
to right?
Extreme,
extreme,
extreme something and other than that
thing,
intoxication and otherness than
intoxication.
Every attempt at betterment,
every attempted other month is a.
It fades forever and forever as we move,
it's like it's just about as incoherent
as postmodernist philosophy.
So we know for archaic and traditional
cultures that are symbolic return to
chaos is equivalent to preparing a new
creation.
It follows that we may interpret the
psychic chaos of the future Sharman as a
sign that the profane man is being
dissolved and a new personality being
prepared for birth transformation.
Here's a way of thinking about it.
Paradise,
Paradise lost redemption.
Classic story of mankind always.
There was a great past.
We're in a state of chaos.
We're heading towards a better future.
Everyone thinks that way.
The stories are based on that all that's
that.
Now ellenberger who,
who wrote a lot about the psychoanalysts
believed that Freud and young in
particular how to create an illness
which he regarded as this sort of
spontaneous shamonic transformation,
and he said a creative illness has these
elements.
It follows,
succeeds a period of intense
preoccupation with an idea and search
for certain truth.
It's a polymorphous condition that can
take the shape of depression,
neurosis,
psychosomatic ailments or even
psychosis.
Young was in that state when he wrote
this book called the Red Book,
which was just released last year,
which is full of visionary illustrations
and and it's very strange poetry and it
contains the,
the communications he had with
imaginative beings that he conjured up
when,
when practicing,
doing exactly that.
He practiced that for years and he had
these autonomous beings manifest
themselves in his fantasy and had long
conversations with them,
which is,
you know,
while he was working as a doctor and
having a sane,
normal life and well it's Kinda,
well,
it's really something.
Whatever the symptoms,
they're felt as painful while he thought
maybe he was going mad and some people
think he did,
if not agonizing by the subject,
with alternating periods of alleviation
and worsening throughout the illness.
The subject never loses.
The thread of is dominating
preoccupation.
It's often compatible with normal
professional activity and family life,
but even if he keeps to his social
activities,
he's almost entirely absorbed with
himself.
He suffers feelings of isolation even
when he has a mentor who guides them
through the ordeal like the and
apprentice with his master.
The termination is often rapid and
marked by a phase of exhilaration.
The subject emerges from his ordeal with
a permanent transformation in this
personality and a conviction that he has
discovered a great truth or a new
spiritual world.
Many of the 19th and 20th century
figures regarded universally as great
niche,
a Darwin,
Dostoevsky,
tolstoy,
Freud Young.
We're all additionally characterized by
lengthy periods of profound
psychological unrest and uncertainty.
Well,
you don't generate a new theory without
some birth pangs,
right?
Because you're all theory has to bite
the dust first.
And when you're old theory bites the
dust.
It's like,
where are you?
You don't know.
Do you know if you're going to come up
with a new one?
No.
Here's a cool thing.
This is my daughter.
She was five years at this point.
She was playing prince or princess with
Julia and her three year old.
She said,
dad,
if we killed the dragon,
we could use his skin,
his armor.
Wouldn't that be a good idea?
I thought,
hey,
yeah,
that's,
that's a hell of an idea,
kid.
You know,
you go right after the thing that
frightens you the most and you develop
something that protects you from doing
that.
It's like,
where did she get that idea?
Well,
good work Kiddo.
She had plenty of dragons in her life,
so
the following dream was described by my
daughter Mckayla.
Three years,
nine months old,
above my son Julian.
One year,
Julian was in the process of toilet
training and rapid speech development
was having some trouble controlling his
emotions.
MCKAYLA liked to call him baby.
We had several discussions about the
fact that he wasn't really a baby
anymore.
She told me this story while I was at
the computer,
so I was able to get it verbatim.
She wasn't very happy with the idea that
he wasn't a baby anymore because she
kind of liked her.
The baby.
She took care of that baby you lot and
her little brain was having a hard time
with the notion that whatever that thing
is now it isn't a baby.
It's like,
well,
where's my baby?
And believe me,
plenty of mothers go through the same
thing.
Then they attempt to keep their children
babies for the rest of their lives,
so this is what Mikayla said,
the dream.
Julian's eyes fell out and then he
falled into pieces.
I said,
what sort of pieces?
She said,
Julian pieces and the bones fold out to
then a whole God,
him and there was water in it and when
he came out he was big mom.
Julian isn't a baby anymore.
No,
he's a big boy and a bug with legs go
out.
I'm out cause bugs can swim and the hole
was in the park and it moved into the
backyard and he fall into it.
A tree burned and left the whole.
I thought,
wow,
that's so amazing.
It's like it was a.
It was a shamanic transformation dream.
It was like the tree that's the tree of
life had burnt and left a hole.
The kid fell.
Intuitive,
dissolved them right down to his bones.
This little bug,
which would be a union representation of
the self,
like Jimminy cricket,
by the way,
in Pinocchio.
The bug was the thing that was alive
that helped them through the
transformation.
He stepped out and now he was big.
It's like that was her little brain
conjuring up the notion of radical
transformation.
So this is cool.
I hope this works.
This is a dream that my nephew had.
Someone animated
Jordan Peterson is a clinical
psychologist from the University of
Toronto.
Do disagree with some of those
fundamental ideas.
Put his thoughts and fixing problems.
Merge with my stomach values
within one of his maps of meaning
lectures.
He tells a true story about a four year
old boy,
his nephew who for months was suffering
from terrible night terrors,
terrors that were waking him up,
screaming.
This boy,
by the way did have some areas of
instability in his family life,
Jordan versus the young boys hosts and
the boy was running around,
dressed as a need with a sword,
a shield,
and a helmet.
At nighttime,
he would take a sword and shield to bed.
So Jordan goes back into him and the boy
described his dream and the dream.
He's standing thrown by me.
Hey dwarves.
These dwarves had beaks and every time
you were trying to move the doors would
jump up and Beta and very fretting
scenario for a young boy,
and if you look behind all the doors
away in,
up back,
there was a dragon,
and every time this dragon with puff
owed fire and smoke,
more dwarves will be created so there's
no point fighting off the doors because
more would just be made.
So Jordan tapped him and asked,
what could you do about that?
So the kid says he could jump up in the
dragon's head,
could put a's with a sword,
but he couldn't see.
Then he could go during the route to the
box where the fire came,
chrome,
carve a piece out of that box,
thereby destroying it and use that
pieces of sheet.
The change before Jordan a was already
acting out in life.
What he knew he had to do,
and after that conversation he had no
more nightmares.
This is what Marcus really is meant when
he said the impediment to action
advances action.
What stands in the way becomes a way.
He was telling us that we must not shy
away from problems or shutting our
personal responsibility.
You must be willing to sacrifice or
conference who does Roseboro problems to
solve them and then take something away.
Well,
there you go.
So yeah,
he was waking up screaming at night for,
for weeks,
the night terrors.
He couldn't really remember what the
hell was going on and there was
instability in his family.
His parents got divorced soon after and
he was off to kindergarten and that was
kind of destabilizing them too.
And so it was fun to watch him zip
around as a night.
It's like,
where do you get that idea?
Well,
you know,
he watched TV,
watched movies.
He is a little imagination.
Was aggregating the picture of the hero
and then he was trying to act it out.
That's what he was doing,
pretending right.
I'm pretending to be the thing that
takes on the unknown.
And then he has this amazing dream.
It's like it's mind boggling.
It's so sophisticated.
It's like,
well,
here I am and there's troubles
everywhere and they're biting me.
They're jumping up on me and it's like a
hydra,
you know,
in the Hydra,
you cut off a hydros head and seven more
heads grow.
It's like,
that's life,
man.
Solve one problem,
seven more appear.
Right?
So also that was the dragon at the
background.
Chaos itself and chaos kept breeding
these evil little dwarfs,
which is what it does.
It's like it's one damn trouble after
another.
You fight this one off,
fight this one off.
It's like,
who cares?
The Dragon?
The dwarf generating machine is still
working in the background.
So He.
I asked him and that was purposeful.
What could you do?
See that's a leading question that
implies that there's something that he
could do.
He said,
well,
I take my dad that was missing in the
animation and we'd go,
well,
poke to drag.
It's always out.
Go right down to the source of the
problem,
extinguish it,
make a shield.
Right?
So that meant that he would have
strengthened his character by the
encounter.
So brilliant.
And then I talked to his mom for months
afterwards,
done no more night terrors.
What had happened.
Yeah,
identified with the mythological hero.
He identified with St George and the
dragon he identified with that little
bloody tree dwelling primate who 20
million years ago was the first one to
drop a stick on a snake.
He adopted the classic human mode of
being in the face of uncertainty and
construed himself as that which could
prevail.
End of terrors.
Well,
I guess we're done a.
So we're going to do something a little
different than the syllabus today
because we've got this one hour,
two hour problem and I already can't
cover constructionism reasonably in two
hours or one hour that was supposed to
be today.
So I'm going to do instead is continue
on the line that I've been pursuing,
but I'm going to expand it up more into
union psychology,
which is the what we're going after
after constructivism anyways.
And so I can weave the constructivism
and the depth psychology together and
it's nice to do that because it gives
you a kind of a coherent view.
So just so you know,
we're,
we're one lecture ahead at the moment,
roughly speaking.
And I'll do constructivism on Tuesday
for two hours.
So.
All right.
So I showed you that enemy animation I
told you about my nephew,
his dream,
which is a remarkable dream,
you know,
really,
it's just amazing,
amazing dream and
it's got this archetypal pattern.
The pattern is that there's a threat and
worse than that,
that there's,
there are threats and at the back of it,
there is that the fact of threat itself.
You see,
so human beings,
we're so smart.
Hey,
so this is so amazing that we figured
this out.
So you imagine,
well human beings are the only creatures
that can really conceive of the class of
all threatening things right now.
It's kind of why we can be permanently
anxious.
There's.
So it's sort of annoying.
So you know,
here you are and it's safe.
There's no lions here or a or anything
that might prey on you,
but you can think of something to be
anxious about.
No problem.
You know,
I'm,
I'm certain you've got some little
skeleton rattling around in your closet
somewhere that's like eating away at
you.
And so I think part of the reason we're
so damn awake human beings is because
we're always anxious,
like,
and you have to be awake when you're
anxious and the anxiety system actually
activates your reticular activating
system and that,
that,
that actually produces.
It's the substrate for consciousness.
If you snap a few fibers in the back of
your brain that are part of the
reticulating activating reticular
activating system in a car accident or
something,
you'll go into a coma and that'll be
that you're in,
you're not getting out of it.
It doesn't take much of an injury either
in the right place.
So anyways,
so human beings have been struggling
with this problem of threat forever.
A really for as long as there's been
life or at least as long as there's life
with a nervous system.
And you know,
that's several hundred million years.
It's a long time.
And of course
it's easy to,
you know,
to respond to a particular threat.
Think about zebras,
they're out there on the belt and
there's lions everywhere,
right?
But the zebras are like,
they're calm because there's lions are
sleeping.
And so the zebras don't think
apparently,
oh my God,
what was going to happen with those
lions wake up because they don't think
that way.
You know,
they're not going to be happy if the
line goes into a hunting crouch and
starts it's hunting approach obviously,
but it's not like the zebras are
freaking out nonstop because there are
lions around,
you know,
so they can react to specific threats.
But human beings,
partly because we discovered the future,
which was a big mistake,
it was a big mistake because the future
is an uncertain place.
We realized that,
well,
there isn't any threat right now,
but there might well be some tomorrow
and if there isn't some tomorrow,
well maybe next week or next month or
next year.
Like it's common.
And so there's danger.
So it's the category of danger,
you know,
and out of the category of danger
emerged specific threats.
And the dragon seems to be a symbol of
it is a symbol I believe,
of the ever present fact of predatory,
slightly predatory threat.
But our nervous systems as they've
become capable of abstraction,
have used that underlying architecture
to represent more abstract category,
so it's not the,
it's not a Predator like a dragon is not
a Predator because there are no dragons,
but maybe a dragon is a snake and a and
a crocodile and maybe a leopard and
maybe a,
a predatory bird all mangled into one
monster.
A monster is actually technically
something that's made out of disparate
parts.
And so it's a good symbolic
representation for the unknown as such
that which lies beyond the campfire,
let's say,
and what lurks out there.
And so the eternal problem is what the
hell do you do with the Dragon?
And that also explains why the dragon
typically is at treasure guarder right?
Because it's even more,
the problem is even worse out there in
no man's land out there in potential
there's threat and,
and,
and like mortal threat.
But there's also endless opportunity and
riches and wealth and,
and,
and the possibility of attracting
someone and all of that.
And so while the dragon,
you can't just be afraid of it,
you just stay in your burrow the whole
time.
And lots of animals more or less do that
is,
you know,
especially the nocturnal ones,
they just hide away.
But that isn't what human beings are
light because we're not only praying
animals,
we're also predators.
And then of course we're crazy.
We're absolutely insane.
Chimpanzees,
right?
We're crazy.
And so we're always out there mucking
about with things and with our fingers
and our thumbs and,
and taking the world apart and putting
it back together.
And we're crazily exploratory and
troublemaking.
And so we don't just run from dragons,
we go hunt them down.
And so
and so there's a story here,
there's the oldest story that mankind
knows and literally it is the oldest
story that we know is this stories.
And the story basically is there's a
bounded space,
a walled garden,
a walled city in,
on all the original cities were walled
because if they weren't,
barbarians would swoop in and they just
steal all your stuff.
And so,
you know,
that was kind of pointless.
So you know you wanted to have some
major league walls surrounding your
territory,
so that's inhabited space and inside
that is your little dominance hierarchy
and so all you primates knew exactly who
was who inside that space so you didn't
have to fight with each other and you
could predict each other's behavior
because you believed the same things and
saw the world roughly the same way and
acted the same way and so you were sort
of secure.
But then the problem is is that that can
always be breached.
There's always something outside of it
that's a danger,
and so that's signified by this,
this little creature here is this dragon
and that that twirl in its tail is very
common among dragons.
It's actually,
it's actually a symbol because imagistic
languages,
images to symbols have an ancient
language and it.
It's referring to something that's
basically eternal and see it lives down
here in this,
in this cave,
because it's an underground thing,
it's an underground thing and you can
kind of imagine what that's like and
sometimes this happens in initiation
rituals among archaic people.
They're gonna win.
They're going to initiate.
Usually the young men,
because nature initiates women all by
itself,
I'm usually the young men,
maybe they'll put them in cave and leave
them there,
you know,
for like,
well,
who knows,
who knows how long,
and so you've got to think what's in the
cave.
Caves are dark man.
I don't know if you've ever been in one,
but like they're dark and they're really
dark and so not only is there whatever
there is in the cave and you don't know
what the hell is in the cave.
There's whatever you imagine might be in
the cave.
And so when you're in that cave and
you're alone,
you,
you're confronting the devils and demons
and monsters of your own imagination,
you know,
and so then you have a chance to perhaps
deal with that and overcome it.
And that's perhaps part of the
initiation ceremony,
you know,
and that's part of growing up because
you have to learn how to face the things
that terrify and upset you and,
and re cast them and put them back
together.
We talked a little bit about this idea
of the pre cosmo Gona chaos that,
um,
that,
uh,
Eliana refers to an end.
That's the stuff out of which order is
produced at the beginning of time and
it's also the stuff out of which you
constantly reproduce order and the
unions,
the psychoanalysts,
especially the really deep
psychoanalysts like young Freud was a
more surface psychoanalyst and that's
not an insult.
There's some things that Freud figured
out there is absolutely amazing.
He was a precursor to young for sure
for young.
The Hero's journey was the journey
inside the unconscious and that would be
perhaps in some sense that the,
the willingness to face everything
terrible that's happened to you and to
think it through and to articulate it
and to come to grips perhaps with your
own capacity for malevolence.
That was a really important part of
union ideas.
That the first step towards
individuation,
which is the manifestation of your full
self,
let's say,
was the discovery of your shadow and
your shadow is the part of you that will
do terrible things under the right
circumstances.
And maybe even without that much
provocation.
And you know,
and it's a terrifying part of you to
come into contact with because it sort
of,
it sort of the way that you're
specifically attached to the archetype
of evil now it's like that's a good way
of thinking about it.
And you know,
modern people,
they don't really think much about the
bunch of both the idea of good and evil,
but that's because they're,
most of them are so damn naive,
you can just barely even comprehend it.
You know,
if you read any history,
if you really read it like,
and you,
and you don't come away with the idea
that evil exists.
It's like you're just reading the wrong
kind of history.
You know,
it's just unbelievable what people can
do to each other.
And we're so imaginative,
you know,
and one of the things I figured out
about people,
the reason that we're,
we have the knowledge of good and evil,
let's say,
is that because we're self conscious and
we know about ourselves,
we know about our own vulnerability,
right?
You know what hurts you.
You really know what hurts you way more
than an animal notes.
And so,
and you're also creative and so once you
know what hurts you,
man,
you can really hurt someone else and you
can do it in such a creative way.
You can draw it out,
you can make it excruciating.
You can take people apart physically and
psychologically and you can keep them
say even right on the edge of death so
that you can keep doing that endlessly.
And you know that happens a hell of a
lot more than you think.
It happens.
It happens a lot and so
well.
And you think,
well,
you know,
that doesn't involve me.
It's like,
Oh yes it does,
man.
That's the problem because you know
you're human and that's the sort of
things that human beings are capable of
or not.
I'm not saying you're all,
it's all probable that you do that ever
or or that,
but I'm saying that,
you know,
you gotta take that into account when
you're looking at the world and you
think about all the perpetrators out
there.
It's like,
it's not like there's perpetrators and
their victims.
That isn't how it works.
It doesn't work that way at all.
And so the horrors of humanity as well
as the noble elements of humanity are
all elements of your central being and
for young,
and this is the terrible thing for using
the pathway to higher wisdom was through
the terrible portal of while you could
say hell for that matter.
Really.
And so who wants to do that?
Man?
It's like no,
you know,
like maybe you're resentful about
something.
Well you probably are because like
everybody's resentful about something
you know,
and resentment is just vicious emotion.
It's really useful.
It's really useful because if you're
resentful about something,
it either means that you should grow the
hell up and accept the responsibility
and quit sniveling around and whining or
it means that someone actually is
oppressing you and,
and pushing on you too hard and bullying
you and demeaning you and you have
something to say or do that you're not
saying or doing and no wonder you're not
saying or doing it because you know it
can be really dangerous to say things or
do them to free yourself from,
from being oppressed.
You can get it a lot of trouble in the
short term.
For doing it so it's easier just to not
say anything sort of day after day in
the short term you protect yourself but
just crushes you.
And then the resentment comes up and
resentment.
Man,
that can just get so out of hand.
You know,
it starts with resentment and then it
starts.
It goes to the desire for revenge.
You know,
because you'll play nasty little tricks
on the person that's oppressing you at
any chance.
You'll talk about them behind their back
and if they want you to do something,
you'll do it badly.
Or you'll do it grudgingly.
Or you'll do a half rate job and you'll
set up little traps and you know,
so it puts you in a poisonous space.
And then if that,
if you really start to dwell on that,
say in your basement for three or four
years about just exactly how terrible
the world is and how that's focused on
you and how everyone's rejected you.
And how you get to this point where
you're thinking that,
you know,
existence itself is a kind of poisonous
endeavor.
And that the best thing for you to do is
go out there and do as much,
create as much mayhem as you possibly
can,
and if you really get to a dark place,
you think I'm going to create as much
mayhem as I possibly can by targeting
the most innocent thing I can possibly
imagine.
And then you end up shooting kids in
Connecticut and that's how you get
there.
And so that's a bad road man.
There's dark things down there,
but you can go there and people do and
they go through the whole of resentment
and resentment can tell you you've got
something to say.
You bloody well better say it.
You've gotta free yourself from what's
oppressing you.
You have to stand up for that because
otherwise you become oppressed.
And then once you're oppressed,
that's just not so good.
And so like in your marriage and your
relationships,
you gotta tell people what you're
thinking.
You don't have to assume you're right.
That's a whole different story because
you're not because you're,
you know,
ignorant and you're biased and you know,
so you're not right,
but you can stumble towards Europe,
this expression of yourself and then you
can listen to the other person and hope
that they tell you some way that you're
stupid.
That's useful so you can be a little
less stupid in the future because that
wouldn't that be good.
And so you know,
you go after the unknown.
You don't protect what you know.
You already know what you know.
You go after what you don't know.
That's why you have to talk to people
you don't agree with.
That's why you have to talk to your
enemies because they're going to tell
you things you don't know.
You could even listen to them.
It's possibly know a thing or two you
don't know,
but people don't like that.
You know,
they just talked to people who think the
same way and then they just stay stupid.
And so that's.
And that's not good because if you're
not wise,
the world will wall up you.
It'll flatten you and,
and far more than it has to.
And then you'll be bitter and resentful
and you'll be part of that force,
that wall ups instead of the forest that
fights against that.
So while,
so you go after the dragon and that's
what,
that's what this guy is doing.
He's going after the dragon hint.
It's threatening the society because it
always does chaos.
What's outside of order always threatens
order.
Always,
always.
And so you have to step forward,
you know,
in this manner,
voluntarily and,
and,
and go after that when it's still
manageable.
Right?
And that's the case in your own life
too.
So you know,
if you're,
if you've had a proclivity to be bullied
in the past,
you know,
and you want to get out of that,
what you have to do is you have to make
yourself awake to the,
to the,
what would you say to the,
to the initial stages of that sort of
bullying emerging in your life.
Again,
that sort of domination.
And you have to step forward against it
when it's still in its developing
stages.
Because maybe you can just not have it
happen.
That would be better.
And so you have to be ready to speak
what you have to say more or less on a
moment's notice.
You,
you can't be impulsive about,
you know,
like if you and I are talking and you
make a mistake or I make a mistake,
even if it's bothers one or the other of
us,
we should just write it off because it's
like one encounter,
what the hell,
you know,
maybe we had a bad night's sleep or
something,
you know,
so you've got to be a little forgiving.
But if it happens twice then you know
you should be a little awake and you
should remember both times.
And then if it happens a third time,
it's like that's when you,
that's when you act and you say,
look,
we talked and this happened.
And I thought yeah,
whatever.
And then you did it again and then you
just did it again.
Well then the person who is basically
like,
what are they going to do?
You know?
No,
well maybe they might argue with you,
but you kind of got them and you're
generally.
If you just point that out to people
just like that,
just that you noticed and are willing to
say something about it,
they'll back the hell off.
They'll often apologize and sometimes
you even make them a little more
conscious,
which is like,
hey,
that's not such a bad idea.
That's what all this means.
And so this caught this chaos idea.
It's so for union,
it was the unconscious,
right?
It was the contents of your unconscious
and so that might be the unknown past
that threatening past that you have
never dealt with might be the
threatening future.
It might be too threatening present,
but you realized as his,
as he got older that that the
unconscious was also the world when you
think,
and so the chaos is not only your
unconscious mind which meets the
unknown,
but it's actually the unknown itself
mingled together and you think,
well,
what the hell does that?
That's why the dragon is a land creature
in an error creature.
It's matter and spirit at the same time,
and this sort of gets us into
constructivism because the
constructivists think that basically
what happens is that you encountered
those elements of the world that don't
fit into your theory and out of those
new elements you make the world through
your perceptions and you make yourself
by incorporating the information and
transforming yourself and that's how
piaget explains the development of a
child.
If the child starts out with some
reflexes,
basic reflexes and manifesting the
reflex is produces results in the world,
and then the child has to reorganize its
perceptions to take into account the
transformations and so then it,
it gets a little more sophisticated and
then it can do a few more things and
then it can manifest more changes in the
world and then it modern.
It attracts them and modifies its
perceptions and actions to account for
them and it just keeps doing that and
that's how the child boots itself up
like a computer does.
It's a very cool idea.
And so from from the Piagetian stance,
so it's constructive.
The stance you could think of the world
as a latent pool of information,
it's something like that with a
structure obviously,
that you can interact with with your
little fingers in your body and your
mind and your eyes and your mouth and
you make changes happen and you track
them and you've modeled them and you
build your skills and as you continue to
do that in the safety of your house
initially under the care of your parents
who,
who fill in where you're ignorant,
you,
you just emerge more and more competent
and confident and ready to move ahead.
So that's,
that's how the constructivist idea
works.
And so,
so there's kind of a chaos id at the
bottom of that,
which is that out of which you emerge
and the world emerges at the same time
because you know you don't see reality.
Not at all.
You see almost like an animated version
of reality.
You know,
like when I look at you,
I just see the front of you.
I just see the outside of the US EU at
this height.
I don't see any of your internal
structure.
I don't see the back part of you at all.
I don't see your family.
I don't see your history.
I don't see your future.
You know,
I just see this slice of you.
You're so complicated.
I just see this little like
oversimplified slice of you right now
and I think that's the reality and it's,
it's,
it's sort of the reality,
the way that the simpsons,
a simpsons character is you.
It's like it's sort of like you and it's
enough so that you can watch the story,
but the real you man,
God only knows what that is and that's a
union idea.
You know that the real you is something
that radically transcends your
perception of yourself or your
conception of yourself and that you get
to that hire you at least in part by
going into the darkest place.
And so it's a hell of an idea,
man.
It's really.
But it's the old idea of initiation.
It's as old as time that idea and
there's something to it.
And we definitely recreate it.
And psychotherapy like this isn't an
airy theory.
It's quite the contrary because what you
do and as a psychologist always,
always a behaviorist say that the most,
the most logical clinical type of
psychologist or behaviorist is that an
initiatory Sharma and even though he or
she doesn't know it because what they do
is they say,
okay,
well let's take a look at your life.
Like,
okay,
you got a bunch of problems and they're
like massive dragons and you're just
like,
you're not going anywhere with those
problems here.
Just cowering in the corner.
And what the behavior therapist does is
cut them,
cut that dragon into those little dwarfs
until the doors are small enough so that
you can really kick the hell out of them
and so and that by the way they do that
is they take the problem and they
decompose it into elements that are
small enough that you have a reasonable
probability of mastering them.
So you take the problem apart into
intuit's micro problems.
Careful,
careful analytic process and then you
think,
okay,
well how could we progress a little bit
this week?
And some of that is to face to practice
facing things you're afraid of.
So like if your agoraphobic and you
can't get on an elevator,
you can't get on a taxi and you can't
stand up to your husband,
and I'm saying husband,
because most agoraphobic are women,
most of them are middle aged women and
most of them were too dependent for most
of their life.
So that's a monster.
It's like society,
husband,
elevator,
taxi,
subway.
It's a monster and it's that place you
will not go and that's because you feel
this high and everything else looks this
big.
And so and partly that's because you've
run away and when you run away from
something it grows and chases you.
Which is,
well,
it's exactly what happens to a prey
animal man.
If you go in the woods and you find a
bear,
especially at Grizzly,
while you're in real trouble,
if it's a grizzly.
But if it's a black bear,
you know,
generally speaking,
if you stand your ground and make a hell
of a lot of noise,
that thing,
we'll leave you alone.
But if you run well,
what's it supposed to think?
It eats things that run from it.
So that's exactly where that idea came
to come from.
You turn tail and run and then the thing
that you're afraid of is really a
monster and it's gonna get you and eat
you.
It's like,
well that's true psychologically as well
and the same circuits that we use to
when we were,
you know,
out in the forest,
even even in trees,
the same circuits that we used to parse
up the world.
Then into safe territory and place where
the predators loom is the way we parse
up the world now,
which is safe territory and the place
where the predators loom.
It's just become abstracted way up,
abstracted way up.
So.
But it's the same damn circuits.
We know this like the same circuits you
use to forage for information.
Just dopaminergic circuit is the circuit
that squirrels used to forage for nuts
and you think,
well why?
Well it's because there's no difference
between information and food.
Like you trade information for food all
the time.
That's what you're doing when you're
working,
especially if you're working on a
computer.
So the idea that there's,
there's an equation between information
and food.
It's like,
well,
obviously obviously there's an equation
between them,
so of course you'd use the same circuits
and I mean the damn squirrel has to
remember where the nuts are and so for
him information is food.
Even so in what happened to human beings
is that we started thinking,
Hey,
maybe it's better to go after
information than it is to go after food
because going after inflammation
produces more food than just going after
food.
And so that was a pretty damn smart
idea.
So we're still doing that.
So anyways,
this is what you're supposed to be
doing.
And so,
and this is what behavior therapists do,
they decompose your problems.
What are you afraid of?
Well,
okay,
you're afraid of everything.
Well,
let's get something specific you're
afraid of.
Well,
I'm afraid of an elevator.
Okay.
An elevator.
So I have a client,
she's afraid of elevators.
The elevator door opened.
She goes,
that's a tube.
And I thought,
oh wow.
I thought it was an elevator,
but for you it's not a bloody elevator.
It's death.
And so that's what you're afraid of.
It's worse than that.
You're afraid of being trapped inside
there in the dark alone,
alone,
not knowing if anyone is going to rescue
you,
stuck there with your damn imagination
freaking out.
It's like,
and if that's not,
and then maybe you have a heart attack
because you're so terrified and you die.
It's like,
you know,
so that's the elevator.
Well,
it's no bloody wonder.
No one's going to get into something
like that.
And then maybe underneath that is your
distrust in the mechanisms of society,
right?
Because you know a normal person that
was weird creatures,
they'll get an elevator.
What the hell?
They don't care.
And partly it's because they have an
implicit belief.
Even if the thing stops,
somebody will come along and rescue them
and usually you don't even think about
it,
right?
It's like,
wow,
what the hell?
It's an elevator.
It's like
the danger is invisible to you
and it's partly because you implicitly
trust the structure and so maybe you go
into the unconscious presuppositions of
the person who is terrified of the
elevator in the subways and you find out
they have a real problem with trusting
authority.
That's partly why they don't get along
with her husband,
why they'd never been able to stand up
for themselves,
so then you say,
okay,
well you're afraid of the damn elevator,
but it's not an elevator.
It's a tomb and the tomb is partly you
and partly it's partly the elevator and
partly your unconscious mind and so
well,
what can you handle?
Can you go and look at an elevator from
10 feet away?
It's like,
yes.
Okay.
How about nine feet away?
Yes.
Five feet.
Four feet?
No.
Okay.
No problem.
Four and a half feet.
We're going to go from that elevator and
we're going to look at the damn thing
until you're bored of it because that's
what we're trying to.
You should be board of the elevator
because then you're not afraid of it.
Obviously.
It's like it's an elevator.
You just don't notice it.
Right?
All of these things around here that you
don't notice.
I'd take you out of here to ask you what
color the walls are.
You haven't gotten any idea.
You know,
I,
I suspect for most of you there's not a
chance you'd be able to identify the
gender of the person who's sitting next
to you unless you know them.
It's like you just don't remember
anything and why should you?
Everything works like you don't have to
pay attention to it.
It's like,
does that stay up?
Yeah,
it's still off.
Yeah.
Still up.
It was like,
really?
No,
you know,
you get bored of that real quick and so
then you just ignore it and.
But the agoraphobic has had that veil of
ignorance torn away and what they see
behind it is mortal threat and so that's
really what you're helping them deal
with.
And so this week there are four and a
half feet from the elevator.
Next week they're a foot from the
elevator and the week after that,
the horrible gates of hell open and they
look inside and they don't run.
And so,
hey,
they're tougher than they thought they
were.
And that's what you're teaching them.
Actually.
You're not teaching them that the world
isn't dangerous because that's a stupid
thing to teach someone bloody right.
The world is dangerous.
It's terrifying and sometimes people
under a realize that and the veil lifts
and they see horror everywhere.
They see that and then they think,
well,
I'm just a little rabbit.
I'm over here in the corner.
I can't move.
I'm petrified.
And then they can't move.
They hide it home.
They cower at home because everything
has become a predatory domain and so
what you teach them is you're not as
much of a rabbit as you think,
and part of that is that you help them
grow some teeth so that they can go home
and have that fight with their husband
that they should have had 25 years ago
and it happens very frequently with
agoraphobic clients that you get them so
they can go on the damn elevator and
they can go on the subway and they can
take a taxi.
Maybe they learned to drive,
wow.
That get some upon me and then there are
a little tougher and so then they can
stand up from the for themselves and
they go back and like their husband
might not be very happy with any of this
really.
It depends on what sort of guy he is.
You know,
if he's a real tyrant,
he might be just perfectly happy that
he's married to someone who was afraid
of her own shadow because then she won't
ever leave and so that's a nasty little
story and believe me,
it's not uncommon.
So she gets tougher by facing what she
fears and what she finds out is there's
a hell of a lot more to her than she
thought.
And that's really what happens when you
do behavior therapy with someone who's
agoraphobic.
It isn't really that they get less
afraid.
It's that they get braver.
That's way different.
It's because brave is alert and able to
cope.
Naive is there's no danger.
It's like hell yeah,
right.
There's no danger.
Jesus.
What a stupid theory that is.
So anyways,
that's what all this is.
That's,
that's the story man.
And it's a.
it's a major story.
It's the story of human transformation
and growth.
It's the evolved evolution of mankind.
It's like it's a major story and we've
been working on the damn thing for like
God only knows how long,
you know.
Snakes and primates,
coevolved and our vision are sharp,
Sharp,
sharp vision seems to have been an
evolutionary adaptation forced on us by
the presence of predatory snakes and
we're talking tens of millions of years
ago and human beings have unbelievably
sharp eyesight.
The only thing that can see us as birds
of prey and they have like an eagle,
a bald eagle has eyes as big as ours,
and it has to phobias that phobia is the
central part of the vision.
So an eagle is all eyes man,
and so,
but human beings,
we're kind of like that too.
And like half our brain is devoted to
visual processing.
We have acute vision in Madagascar where
there are primates with no predatory
snakes.
They're lemurs.
They can't see worth a damn.
And I'm an anthropologist named Lynn.
Isabelle did a comprehensive study
worldwide trying to account for the
acuity of primate vision.
And what she found was that the more
predatory snakes in the vicinity,
the sharper the eyesight of the
primates,
and so we have a really sharp eyesight,
so that means a lot of us were eaten by
snakes and none of your ancestors,
fortunately because otherwise you
wouldn't be here,
but a lot of those who fell by the
wayside were snake snack and you know,
when you're little and living in a tree,
a snake is no damn joke.
And even now with lots of people get
bitten by snakes and people are phobic
of snakes at quite a rate.
And some of that actually seems innate.
There's arguments about cycling between
psychologists about this,
but even the ones who don't accept the
fact that it's innate,
except the fact that you can make
someone afraid of a snake by
conditioning just like that,
we're trying to make them afraid of a
flower by conditioning is really,
really hard.
So we're at least at minimum prepared to
be afraid of snakes minimum.
And I believe it's.
I don't,
I believe that fear is actually innate,
although you can learn to control it.
So anyways,
so that's that story and like what a
story man,
so amazing,
amazing story.
You see the Dan of the dragon here is
littered with skulls and bones.
That's what that is.
So the,
the thing is no joke,
it's like look the hell out and that's
this,
you know,
and look it up on the top right hand
corner there.
You know,
that's from Peter Pan,
right?
All you remember,
Captain Hook,
we talked about him already.
He's a tyrant and he's a tyrant because
he's afraid of death and that's all he
sees in life.
And so it makes them cruel and bitter
and death has already taken part of it,
right?
That's why he has a hook and that damn
crocodile's chasing him,
tick,
tick all the time.
And of course that's the same situation.
You're all in,
man.
There's a crocodile with a clock in its
stomach chasing you and it could easily
turn you into a tyrant.
It can turn you into a tyrant or a
cowering victim or a hero.
Those are the options fundamentally.
So that's the Gorgon looking at her own,
the Medusa,
looking at her own reflection,
you know,
mother nature with a head full of
snakes,
you know,
a terrifying vision and that's actually
to some degree in archetype that men get
confused with women and you know,
that's the witchy part of women and
that's the part that's attractive,
attractive,
but rejecting,
rejecting,
rejecting.
It's so many men are petrified by women.
They won't approach them at all.
They have no idea how to talk to them.
They're just petrified into immobility
and that's way more common than you
think.
And so that breeds resentment.
Like you wouldn't believe,
you know,
you'll hear the guy who shot up like,
um,
Dawson College.
It's like,
what the hell do you think motivated
him?
It's like he,
he,
that's what he saw and it was because as
well he was,
my opinion is he was too goddamn useless
to be attractive to anyone.
And so that's a hell of a place to be
in.
You know,
it's,
that's the problem too.
If you're chronically rejected by
people,
it's often because of your own
insufficiencies,
you know,
whether that's cowardice or lack of
social skills or whatever it is.
It's like you can't just brush it off
as,
oh,
well,
you know,
no one likes me,
but really I'm okay.
It's like,
no,
wrong.
If everyone rejects you,
there's probably something wrong and
it's probably deep and difficult and
it's gonna be horrible to fix.
And so it's,
this isn't a trivial problem.
It's not a trivial problem at all.
And so,
you know,
that's mother nature for men too,
because from the sexual selection point
of view,
if they,
if they're not selected as a mate,
nature has taken them out of the game.
Right?
And so,
you know,
people don't really like that.
They're not that happy without.
And so by getting all whiny about it and
then getting violent is like,
that's just not all.
Not really very helpful.
Although it's very common.
So this is Lynn,
Isabelle,
and evolutionary arms race between early
snakes and mammals triggered the
development of improved and large brain
in primates.
A radical new theory suggests these are
old representations.
I really liked this one.
This is.
I don't remember.
I think it's Greek,
but it doesn't exactly look Greek.
It might be older.
It doesn't matter.
Anyways.
You see it's the same thing.
Same ideas as as Graham's dream,
right?
It's like there's this thing that
exists,
this,
this multi-headed snake,
and it's got this infinity problem.
It's everywhere.
That's that little circle down there,
and the problem is,
well,
what do you do with it?
You cut off one head,
seven more.
Grow.
That's the eternal problem of life.
And the problem is they're there.
There is the category of problems in
life and it ain't going anywhere.
And so the question is,
can you deal with the whole category at
the same time?
That's the thing.
That's how to be in the world is to deal
with that category all at the same time.
And so how did,
how did human beings,
what did they come up with as a
solution?
And that's so cool too,
because the solution they come up with
not only was the heroism that allows you
to approach what you're terrified by and
what you find offensive and to learn
from it,
but also the idea of sacrifice and that
was played out by cultures everywhere,
including human sacrifice.
And you think,
what the hell was up with those crazy
bastard so long ago?
They were sacrificing to God's all the
time.
What kind of clueless behavior was that?
Burned something and please God burned
something valuable and please God.
It's like,
what was with that?
What were they thinking?
Well,
they weren't stupid.
Those people,
if they were stupid,
we wouldn't be here.
They were not stupid.
And believe me,
they lived under a lot harsher
conditions than we do.
So those were some tough people,
man.
You know,
back then you'd last about 15 minutes.
So you don't want to be thinking of your
ancestors as stupid,
like there's no real evidence that we're
much different cognitively than we were
150,000 years ago.
So anyways,
sacrifice.
What does that mean?
Sacrifice?
Well,
it's a discovery man.
It's the discovery of the future.
It's like the future is actually the
place where there is threat and it's
always gonna be there.
So what do you do?
You make sacrifices in the present so
that the future is better,
right?
Everyone does that.
That's what you're doing right now.
That's what you're doing here.
That's what your parents are doing.
When they pay money to send you to
university,
they think let you can bargain with
reality.
It's amazing.
You can bargain with reality.
You can forestall gratification now and
it'll pay off it at it,
at a place in time that doesn't even
exist yet.
It's like,
who wouldn't believe that?
It's like that's a miracle that that
occurs and it's not like people just
figured that overnight,
you know,
we were champs for Christ's sake.
Like how are we going to come up with an
idea like that?
While it's like,
well we thought about it for 7 million
years and you know,
we got to the point where we could kind
of act it out,
but we didn't know what we were doing,
but it was a emerge.
It's like a dream.
It was so the terror of the future is a
dream and the solution to the terror,
the dream of the terror of the future is
another dream and,
and it,
it comes out in mythology and in fantasy
and in drama where you act out the
sacrifice and then it's a step on the
way to full understanding.
So we can say sacrifice now instead of
doing it,
you know,
although we still do it,
it's just not concretized like it used
to be.
We do it abstractly and we all have
faith that it will work,
you know,
and we also set up our society so that
it'll work.
And one thing about,
you know,
I'm not a fan of moral relativism for a
variety of reasons,
partly because I think it's an,
it's an extreme form of cowardice.
But anyways,
apart from that,
no,
no.
There's minimal ways that you can set up
a society that will work.
And so one of them is that this society
has to be set up so that your sacrifices
will pay off or you won't work and then
the society will die.
And so it has to make promises.
People have to make promises to one
another,
and that's what money is.
Money is a promise that your sacrifice
will pay off in the future.
That's what money is.
And so if the society is stable,
you can store up your work right now.
You can sacrifice your impulses and you
can work and you can store up credit for
the future and then you can make the
future a better place.
But society has to be stable enough to
allow for that.
Hyperinflation will do you in.
So the promise that's implicit in the
currency is the promise that what you're
doing now will pay off in the future.
And if people don't have that promise,
then well we know what they do because
in in gangs,
for example,
and say gangs in North America,
the time horizon of the gang members
shrinks rapidly because they don't
really expect to be alive,
pat much past 21.
And so they get really impulsive and
violent and like,
why the hell not that's,
that's what you do when,
when the future doesn't matter,
when it's not real,
you default back to living in the moment
and you take what you can get right now
and no wonder because you don't know if
you're going to be around in a,
in a year and you get whatever you can.
Well you can bloody well get it.
And that's like anarchy that state.
And so you don't want to live in.
Some people like to live in that state
because they're already wired for that,
you know?
And so they're,
they're much more comfortable in those
conditions.
They're,
they're kind of like warrior types,
I would say in some sets.
But you know,
for most people that's just where that
stress,
we'll just do 10,
you know,
the stress of a life like that.
So
that's a pretty horrible picture.
The one on the right I think,
and you know,
it's creepy picture and don't you think
doesn't,
it seems like a creepy picture to me.
Yeah.
And so that's quit silicone oil,
if I remember correctly.
He was an,
he was an Aztec Dragon,
God,
and that's the eye of horus.
By what?
By the way,
this little thing here,
and I'm that.
See the Egyptians?
They worshiped the I.
Yeah.
Well that's cool because it.
Well,
why did they worship the eye?
wake the hell up and look at the world.
That's your salvation to do that.
Pay Bloody attention,
especially to the things you don't want
to pay attention to and use your vision.
Have some vision and you can use your
vision to see into the future and that
is your.
That's your redemption.
And the Egyptians,
they didn't know how to say that,
but they knew how to represent it and
that's how they represented it.
Like the pupil on that as completely
open,
completely dilated.
And that's a god.
As far as the Egyptians were concerned,
it's horace.
And I'll tell you a horror story at some
point.
So early primates develop a better eye
for color,
detail and movement and the ability to
see in three dimensions,
traits that are important for detecting
threats at close range.
Humans are descended from these same
primates.
Alright,
so now the initiation way,
when you go into psychotherapy or when
you make any supreme moral effort,
which is roughly the same thing,
you have to confront that which you do
not know.
Now I mentioned the cat called Primo
cosmo going to chaos and the idea that
at the end of [inaudible] life,
he sort of thought of the unconscious
and the world as the same and you think,
what the hell does that mean?
But here's what it means.
So let's say you're in a longterm
intimate relationship and you get
betrayed.
Okay?
So what is it that you see when you see
your partner at the moment,
you know of the betrayal?
Well,
you see the pre cosmogony chaos and
here's why.
Well it rattles your unconscious up
because you don't know anything anymore.
You don't know what the past was,
right?
You don't know what it was and it's
supposed to be real and all of a sudden
you don't know what it was.
And so you come up with wild ideas about
what it might have been and what it
represented,
and then you don't know what the future
is going to be anymore.
So then your fantasy fills that space
and you don't know who the hell you're
looking at.
That's for sure.
And you don't know much about human
beings and you certainly don't know
anything about yourself.
And so all of a sudden,
not only is everything in chaos inside
your mind,
but everything is in chaos in your
world.
And it actually is.
And there's no telling the difference
between those two things.
You know.
And so then you're just sheer shattered.
And so then you go talk to a therapist
for like two years and you think,
what happened?
What was the reality?
And the reality is because who knows
what the reality was like.
But as far as you're concerned,
the reality is I better represent this
properly in my head.
I better figure out who I was,
who that person was,
what we did together,
and what it meant.
Because I do not want this to happen
again.
And so you're healed when you get to the
point where you've grasped the bloody
moral of the story,
what went wrong and how can I not have
that happen again?
Because that's the purpose of learning,
right?
That's the purpose of memory.
It's to prepare you for the future and
so you have to pull out of that massive
chaos,
a functional representation that
increases your wisdom so that you're not
this naive target.
The next time you enter into a
relationship,
so at least you can have another
relationship without being so
traumatized that you know you,
you're done and you know it can take
people years to talk that through
because this landscape of potential
opens up when when they're betrayed,
it's like anything could have been the
truth.
Well you to sort through that,
you have to wander through all that mess
and it's really painful and emotional as
well.
You have to sort through all that mess
to come out with the new you,
right?
The renewed you and so
well this is a representation of it.
This is how people act this out.
By whatever method he may have been
designated.
The Shaman is recognized as such as only
after having received two methods of
instruction.
The first is ecstatic dreams.
Trances envisions.
The second is traditional shamonic
techniques,
names and functions of the spirit,
mythology and genealogy of the clan,
and the secret language.
Well,
one of the things that happens,
this happens to you even if,
if you encounter something terrible like
could be trail.
What happens is that you have to take a
journey into the domain of morality
essentially,
which is,
well,
how did I act and how did that person to
act and how should have they acted and
how should have I acted,
and so,
and that's part of your cultural
structure.
And so that's the idea of rescuing the
dead father from the depths.
Right?
And that's what we'll show you some
examples of that.
So
this is a critical issue with regards to
the shamanic transformation,
is that people go through these
terrible,
terrible experiences,
often drug induced by the way,
with regards to the sharp,
and they usually use psychedelic
chemicals of one form or another,
often mushrooms.
But uh,
but they've come up with some very
strange concoctions like Iowasca down in
the Amazon and Iowasca has an amazing
substance.
It's made out of the bark of one thing
and another plant whose name I don't
remember that hardly even grow in the
same place and that has to be cooked
together in a special way and no one has
any idea how the damn Amazonians figured
that out.
It looks impossible.
And if you ask them,
they say,
well,
the plants told us how to do it,
which was western people don't find very
helpful,
but the Germans are perfectly healthy,
happy with that.
That description in Iowasca takes them
apart and it does that in part because
it's effects the serotonergic system
very,
very powerfully,
like all psychedelics do and it
transports them to another world and
that's how they interpret it.
And,
and,
and what we know about psychedelics,
you can put it in a thimble and then
throw the thimble away.
We know nothing about psychedelics.
There's new experiments going on at
Johns Hopkins,
for example,
with Psilocybin,
which is part of this active chemical in
magic mushrooms.
Same structure.
Basically as LSD and masculine and all
the real psychedelics have basically the
same structure except the one that's
derived from m Anita area,
which is called muscular enoch acid and
it's a.
it's its own weird thing that no one
knows anything about.
Anyways.
They have profound neurochemical effects
in very small doses and I'm the research
group at Johns Hopkins has given
Psilocybin to research subjects,
you know,
purified been because they started the
new experimentation with psychedelics
and that's been banned for like 40 years
because psychedelics were so terrifying
to our culture that we just put them
away and it's like,
oh no,
we're not going there.
And so even from a research perspective
and even though some of the psychedelics
look very promising for the treatment of
disorders like alcoholism and they
recently used psilocybin to help people
stop smoking down at Johns Hopkins and I
think they had an 80 percent success
rate,
which is just like,
that's just absolutely mind boggling and
so.
But if you give people psilocybin and
they have a mystical experience,
which is very common among people who
take these sorts of chemicals,
then their personality transforms
permanently such that one year later
they're one standard deviation,
higher in openness and openness is the
creativity dimension and that seems to
be a permanent transformation.
And so that's really remarkable.
And about 80 percent of the people who
undergo the Johns Hopkins Experiments
report that the experience is like one
of the two or three most important
things they've ever.
That's never ever happened to them.
And so.
Well that's,
that's something,
you know,
it's like.
And then there's this guy named Rick
straussman down at,
I think it was at the University of
Texas and he did experimentation with
DMT,
dmt,
dimethyltryptamine I remember if I
remember correctly,
is the active ingredient in Iowasca and
you produce it in your brain and it's in
plants.
It's like a very common chemical.
But DMT is a weird hallucinogen because
it has an extraordinary short mechanism
of action.
It's like,
and people who take it report that
they're blasted out of their body,
like out of a cannon.
And then they go out somewhere and
encounter beings of various sorts and
then 10 minutes later they're back and
virtually everyone reports that,
which is really strange.
And,
and so strassman was giving people dmt
intravenously so that the trip would
last longer.
He could,
this was all,
all,
you know,
nih funded,
uh,
experimentation all cleared with the
relevant ethics boards all conducted
within the last 10 years.
And he basically quit doing it because
he was a pretty straight scientists,
you know,
who he was measuring heart rate and
pulse and all that sort of thing,
trying to look at the physiology.
And then the people he was giving these
chemicals to kept coming back and
telling him these,
these crazy stories.
And uh,
well it just,
it was too much for him,
you know,
and no wonder,
because they all said the same thing.
And he'd say,
well,
that was a dream.
And they'd say no.
And it was the most real thing that ever
happened to me.
And he'd say,
well,
you know,
it's an architectural experience.
And they'd say,
no,
no.
That was no archetipal experience.
I went somewhere else.
And I saw things and I'm back and like,
I don't care what you think and like who
the hell knows?
Right?
Because it's all subjective.
But,
but the weird thing about it is that
everyone's reporting the same thing.
How the hell do you account for that?
And then the shaman,
you know,
when they take these psychedelic
chemicals,
they basically say the same thing.
They say,
well first of all,
it more or less killed me.
That's this.
No,
I dissolved to skeleton.
And then I climbed a tree that Unites
Heaven and earth and I went into the
realm of the gods and they gave me some
information and I'm back.
It's like,
okay,
well,
you know,
we don't really know what to make of
that.
And we.
And certainly that's what len describes
when he describes the MNEMONIC is
romantic procession,
not the shamanic initiation.
There's dissolution to a skeleton first.
And then like a death is symbolic death
or experienced as an actual death and
then bang up into the realm of the gods
and then they come back.
It's a very old idea.
And that's a medieval representation of
the tunnel that people travel through at
the end of their life to,
you know,
to find the light,
which is a very common near death
experience report.
And people don't have any idea what the
hell to do with those reports except
say,
well,
it's the paroxysms of the dying brain,
which you'd expect to be a hell of a lot
more random in my opinion.
And the idea is there's a rebirth after
that and you know,
here this is the Scandinavian
representation of that tree that unites
Earth with heaven.
And so there's the Scandinavian
representation.
It has a snake snakes down here eating
it.
And then that's the Amazonian
representation.
It's like,
how the hell do you account for that?
I mean,
those,
those pictures are so similar that it's
just,
it's beyond belief.
Well,
you know,
we lived in trees for a long time,
a long,
long,
long time,
millions of years,
and there were lots of snakes around
them.
And so the idea that reality is that
tree that's surrounded by a snake that's
in us,
man,
it's down there,
it's deep.
And there's something about it that's
true,
not true,
like we normally think of truth,
but truth true in an entirely different
manner.
So.
And all.
That's pretty damn strange.
We'll stop with this.
My son drew this when he was seven years
old.
Blew me away man.
I thought it was so cool.
So I had it laminated.
And so here is what it is on the right
hand side,
that's the order.
It's like the Yin Yang thing that's
ordered left side chaos,
right?
And those are all mushroom houses,
which I thought was amazing.
And then there's this river that runs
right down the middle,
like the line for order and chaos.
And then there's this tree that goes up
to heaven and that's having up there.
It's like there St Peter,
there's the pearly gates,
there's the cloud.
It's like it's.
He never went to church,
you know,
it's like what the hell?
And then there's a little bug there that
goes up and down from heaven to earth.
And that was him.
I thought he had a very organized
psyche.
That kid,
he was a very,
very stable kid and still is.
And he drew that and I thought,
Jesus,
that's just bloody well,
unbelievable.
And I still think that when I look at
it,
and that's a great example of an
archetype.
And so we'll see you Tuesday.