I'm Dr. Jordan B. Peterson, a
professor at the University of Toronto.
I'm a clinical psychologist and
author of the bestselling book,
12 rules for life,
which has sold more than 3 million
copies worldwide being translated into 50
languages and which I have lectured
live about 150 cities all over North
America, Europe,
Australia, and New Zealand.
I've also produced a series of popular
podcasts which will now be featured
weekly on the Westwood One
podcast network every Sunday,
and which I will be hosting with
my daughter Mikayla Peterson.
If you want to understand yourself and
other people far more deeply and keep
abreast of the latest scientific
discoveries and philosophical ideas,
then the Jordan would be Peterson podcast
on Westwood one might be just what
you're looking for. It's a call to
individual responsibility, courage,
and truth in the face of the
trouble and tragedy of life.
Listen and subscribe for free today.