Oh,
hi
guys and girls and interested others.
So on October 18th,
I received a letter from the University
of Toronto asking for my silence with
regards to what I've been discussing.
On September 27th,
I made a video I called fear and the
law,
which was a discussion of what I believe
to be a set of particularly insidious
legislative moves on the part of the
provincial and federal governments in
Canada.
I'm laying the groundwork for requiring
a certain kind of compulsory speech
from,
from the citizens of Canada.
And I commented in that video that I
believed that the act of making the
video itself and discussing the issues
that are relevant to that legislation
was probably illegal.
I'm on October third.
I made another video decrying the
University of Toronto Human Resources
Departments,
recent decision to make anti racism and
anti bias training mandatory partly as a
consequence of their interactions with a
group called the black liberation
collective,
which is,
I'm not a particularly savory group to
say the least.
And then on October fifth,
I did another video by recorded another
video laying out what I described the PC
game,
which is,
um,
uh,
an ideologically motivated victimization
slash perpetrator game.
And I outlined some counter tactics in
those videos.
I said that discussion of gender issues
has probably become illegal now in
Canada,
maybe even a hate crime.
I'm one of the consequences of that was
a number of lawyers wrote articles
saying that I was just scaremongering
and that bill [inaudible] for example,
doesn't have that intent.
I didn't say precisely that bill
[inaudible] had that intent,
although I believe it opens the door to
such things.
But I did say that the surrounding
policy discussions on the Ontario Human
Rights Commission,
which is not a good place,
um,
indicated that,
that it probably had become illegal.
And I would say the fact that the
university has now written me two
letters,
suggesting that in fact what I was doing
was illegal.
Makes my argument better than any but a
better than anything I could do.
I also said that biological sex,
gender identity and gender expression do
not vary independently.
And they don't vary independently by the
way,
even though that's become axiomatic in
the underlying legislation,
and they don't vary independently
because the overwhelming majority of
people have a gender expression,
gender identity and biological sex that
are the same in that 98 percent of
biological males identify as male and
dress as males.
And the same is true of females.
So they don't vary independently.
People confuse that with me saying that
there were no such thing as say
nonbinary people or transgender people.
And I never said that,
but that doesn't really matter.
Apparently.
Uh,
my fundamental concern was that we are
now legally required to use an approved
language when speaking and when speaking
about fundamental issues like gender and
there's very few issues,
more fundamental than gender.
And I said that I wouldn't do it because
it is a very dangerous requirement.
It's the first time that I can tell
where instead of restrictions on free
speech being of the sort,
that there are things you can't say say
hate crime things.
And I'm not an advocate of hate crime
laws,
by the way,
hate crime speech laws.
I think they're dangerous.
But in any case,
I can understand why people think
they're necessary,
but this law requires us to use a
certain kind of approved language.
And I thought that that was a line we
shouldn't cross.
I also said I wouldn't mouth the words
of the ideologically possessed and that
was with regards to gender neutral
pronouns because those pronouns which
haven't passed into common usage by the
way,
because they're very awkward and not
well crafted to me,
they're words that have been produced by
a certain kind of radical left wing
activist radical egalitarianism whose
ideology I regard as perhaps posing the
most serious threat to the freedom of
the West that currently exists.
And so I'm not going to use their words.
And I said that free speech is in
serious danger in Canada because of an
onslaught of radical leftist ideology.
So that was basically my,
uh,
my claims.
Um,
I got a warning letter from Suzanne
Ferber,
chair of the psychology department.
I'm a in the background,
David Cameron,
Dean of the Faculty of Arts and science.
Cheryl [inaudible],
vice president,
provost and Kelly,
Hannah Moffat,
vp hr and equity.
The person by the way,
who's now responsible for the mandatory
anti racism and anti-biased training
initiatives at the University of Toronto
and who has refused to disavow her
department's Association with the Black
Liberation Collective,
despite the fact that they,
they will not disavow violence in the
pursuit of their aims.
And in spite of the fact that two of the
people who produce,
who organized that particular
organization have a history of
misbehavior to put it,
um,
to put it mildly.
The letter said,
the initial initial letter said that,
I mean to me did not recognize the
rights of others to tell me which
personal pronoun to use when addressing
them.
And yes,
that is something I do not recognize.
It.
Do not recognize the rights of others to
tell anyone which personal pronoun to
use when addressing them.
I'm standing by that the UFT said that
was required to acceptance of their
statutorily protected right to equality
and equal treatment.
So now my failure to use,
um,
preferred pronouns like Zi answer or
whatever pronouns people want for that
matter is,
um,
is transgressing against their rights in
a,
in a manner that,
that appears to contravene the
legislation that,
that it's interesting that the
university warned me of that because of
course,
that's exactly why I made the video to
begin with.
The letter also said,
I do not accept that gender
identification can be independent of
biological sex.
The UFT said that was discriminatory as
well.
I did not say that.
And I informed the UFT that their letter
did not do a good job of actually I'm
accusing me if they didn't accuse me
properly of what I said.
And I offered to give them the letter
back so that they could write it
properly,
but they refused.
So,
um,
then it stands the way it stands.
So,
but we won't talk about that letter too
much because we muzzled talk about the
newer one.
So the consequences of,
of what I did were crazy.
Really.
There were two demonstrations at the
University of Toronto.
The second one,
which was the free speech.
The first one was our demonstration
against me personally,
I would say,
um,
because of what I had dared to say.
And the second one was a free speech
rally that was organized by students.
I have nothing to do with it except that
I came to speak at it as did lauren
southern,
who's a journalist for rebel media that
has obtained massive online and youtube
coverage,
partly because lauren southern was the
victim of what appears to be an assault
at the free speech rally.
And that has now been viewed by,
I would think several million people.
It got what I did go mass and the
demonstrations and all of that got
massive traditional media coverage.
Uh,
the national,
the national radio in Canada,
uh,
the,
national TV,
all our major stations,
a huge number of newspapers,
columns,
op-eds,
all sorts of things.
So it's been one of the biggest stories
in Canada for the last 10 days,
I would say,
and massive online coverage as well.
Um,
and so I think the reason for that,
because,
you know,
I just sat in my office and made a video
about bill [inaudible] and complained
about political correctness,
but I did something different.
You see in this is what I think the
difference is,
is that people complain a lot about
political correctness but they never get
the tire to hit the road or are they
never hit the nail on the head with a
hammer.
See,
what I did was I said I don't like
political correctness and here's
something that I'm being required to do
by politically correct people and I will
not do it.
I won't do it,
period.
And I stand by that I am not going to
use made up pronouns to refer to people
if we sort this out linguistically in
the next 20 years.
And,
and we spontaneously come up with a term
that solves some of the problems with
gendered pronouns that perhaps we have.
Although I'm not convinced that we have.
But if a spontaneous and I'm a and
consensus oriented decision is made
around the use of a new term,
then I'm willing to adopt it as well as,
as,
as much as the next person.
But I'm not having it forced on me and I
don't think anyone else should and I'm
not using the damn made up words by
radical left wing activists.
And that stopped.
So anyways,
I also got two letters from the
university.
I'm the first letter said you believe
that some of your commentary may be
illegal.
Yes,
I believe that that's why I made the
video because I don't think that the
sorts of things that I was saying should
be illegal in a free society.
I think it's unbelievably dangerous and
short sighted.
The letter said,
I must comply with the law including the
Ontario Human Rights Code.
Um,
and I must consider the impact of my
words and actions on my students and
colleagues.
While let me tell you this,
I considered the impact of my words and
actions on my students and colleagues
extraordinarily carefully.
Um,
I might say,
in fact,
I considered the impact of my words and
our actions far more carefully than did
the people who wrote these letters,
and I'm going to explain why I believe
that.
So the second letter,
which actually requested my silence,
the first one was more of a warning,
was signed by David Cameron,
dean of the Faculty of Arts and science,
and see a Ben Nelson,
vice president,
faculty and academic life.
And I read it in the previous video so
you can help post it as well,
so you can look at the details,
but I'm going to go over it more or less
topic by topic now.
I'm going to analyze it.
I'm going to deconstruct it.
That's what you might think for all you
postmodernists out there.
Here's an example of deconstruction in
action.
Okay.
So the first part of the,
the,
uh,
letter detailed out essentially what the
University of Toronto understands to be
my comments and,
uh,
and the complaints the UFT has received.
Then the ut are outline their
hypothetical commitment to free speech.
I'm talking about my refusal to use
gender neutral pronouns.
Describe that refusal as illegal.
Um,
so,
so the letter first details out my
comments,
um,
you know,
discusses the fact that I made these
videos and then the states that,
um,
there are ongoing concerns about those
videos that have been expressed by a
variety of,
of groups and individuals at the
university.
The next part of the letter,
at least in principle details the
University of Toronto's commitment to
free speech.
Now I found this interesting and rather
orwellian way,
George Orwell of course,
discussed the use of something he called
doublespeak,
which is to say one thing and mean
another or maybe mean precise out there.
So in the letter that the second thing,
the University of Toronto does it stress
that it has a commitment to free speech,
but then of course,
later in the letter it decides that that
does not extend to its professor's
choosing their own pronouns.
So you can decide for yourself how deep
that commitment goes.
Um,
then they discussed that my refusal to
use gender neutral pronouns is,
um,
probably illegal.
Now,
there's a variety of ways of looking at
this.
One way of looking at it is that there
is a provision in the Ontario Human
Rights Code.
Yeah,
this is it,
that any act or thing done or admitted
to be done in the course of his or her
employment by an officer or official
employee or agent of a corporation,
et cetera shall be deemed to be an act
or thing done or admitted to be done by
the corporation trade union trade or
Occupational Association,
Unincorporated Association or employer's
organization.
So basically what that says,
that section 46 point three,
one of the human rights code is that if
you have an employee who says something
and it's not a good thing,
then you are responsible for it as if
you said it,
which is another part of the legislation
that I was actually complaining about it
in the initial videos.
And so the ot,
I think partly they wrote me this letter
maybe because they had a conversation
with their legal department and they
said,
well,
you know,
this professor might be right.
This could all be illegal.
Maybe it's even hate speech and if and
if he's doing it then because you're his
employer,
you're also responsible for it.
So maybe that's part of the reason for
the warning letter,
but anyways,
they've decided that my refusal to use
gender neutral pronouns is potential.
It's certainly discriminatory,
discriminatory,
as far as they're concerned and may also
be illegal,
which I would like to stress again,
was exactly why I made the videos to
begin with.
So it's not like they're reminding me of
something that I don't know.
So the next part of it was,
uh,
a discussion of distress in the
University of Toronto community.
They have received communications from
individual students and employee groups
finding my comments unacceptable.
Emotionally disturbing and painful.
Um,
you know,
you can watch the videos yourself,
see if they're emotionally disturbing
and painful.
I might point out that if listening to
my comments is painful,
then if you think that's painful,
then it's possible that nothing actually
painful has ever happened to you in my
life,
in your life.
Like I was thinking over the last couple
of weeks,
people have been asking me about how
stressful this is.
It's like,
well,
it's,
no,
it's no walk in the park,
I can tell you that,
but compared to something that's really
stressful,
like maybe a family member has cancer or
you know,
or that's a good one or,
or you're,
you've,
you've actually been thrown in jail by
an authoritarian society are being
tortured.
I mean this is not very stressful.
This is political dialogue and you know,
I would say that there was a week or two
there where I thought my job was
probably in danger and maybe it still
is,
but compared to a real pain,
real pain,
real suffering even that is,
I wouldn't call it trivial,
but it's not traumatic.
That's for sure.
Anyways,
the statements,
my statements and the invective that is
followed caused them to fear for their
safety and they become the target of
specific and violent threats.
Well,
I certainly think that threats directed
to people are reprehensible and I'm,
I'm not calling for that.
I'm calling for reasoned and articulate
debate,
but I would also like to point out,
and this is another part of the letter
that I seriously object to,
is that it would have been much better
had the University of Toronto written me
and said,
look,
we've received a whole variety of of
communications regarding your videos.
Some positive and supportive and some
critical and negative and having
carefully reviewed all of these.
We've decided that it would be in the
best interest of the university and
maybe in keeping with our policies and
the relevant laws.
If you stopped saying these sorts of
things that you're saying,
but that isn't what happened.
The letters select selectively omitted
to mention the fact that the University
of Toronto has received a petition that
has at least 5,000 signatures in support
of me and also several hundred letters,
which I know because I've been cc'd on
them and that it appears that the bulk
of public opinion is also on my side.
None of that was mentioned in the letter
and that also taught me how institutions
become corrupted when free speech is in
danger.
Because,
and I've often wondered this because I
know that such things happened in the
Soviet Union where people over decades
swallowed very large lies and seems to
me that this is the way it happens.
Institution start writing letters that
are,
uh,
that contained sins of omission,
right?
The omit,
relevant information and that's and,
and present a very biased in one sided
view of an issue.
And then once that's written down,
it becomes the reality because one of
the things that psychologists do know is
that if you write down a set of
opinions,
those rapidly become your core beliefs
even if you don't think that you had
those beliefs before you wrote the
letter.
So and then of course the issue with the
threats.
That's a real interesting one because
when lauren southern was assaulted at
the u of t free speech rally and that
was captured on video and more than I
would maybe 2 million people have
watched that now the university didn't
say a thing about it in their public
communications.
But when there were threats,
rape threats made by some bone headed a
morons online.
And we don't know who these people were
by the way.
We don't know if they were trolls.
We don't know if,
if they were provocateurs,
we don't even know if they were the such
social justice warriors themselves.
And I wouldn't put it past them because
they've done that sort of thing in the
past.
So these were threats from unverified
sources that were posted online.
The university immediately sent out a
memo stating that,
you know,
an unsafe,
potentially unsafe atmosphere had been
produced on campus and that,
you know,
the university decries or as opposed to
all sorts of violent and aggressive
accent expressions.
They're up.
But they didn't send out the same memo
when,
when Lauren southern was assaulted at
the free speech rally.
And,
uh,
they also,
and this is particularly the case with
Kelly hand and moffit,
who's the human resources vice
president,
I informed her,
and many other people have that the
black liberation collective from whom
she's taking advice with regards to
antiracism training has,
is,
uh,
is the next best thing to a promoter of
violence in,
in,
in seeking social change according to
their website.
And is has,
is run or has been organized by two
women who have manifested in their
public behavior a number of things that
I think a reasonable person would regard
as reprehensible.
So that's another interesting thing is
that the bar,
the one sided reporting of what
constitutes a threat anyways,
they say that they trust that these
impacts were not my intention,
although they certainly implies strongly
that it's my fault.
And that's another thing I object to
because here's the thing to think about.
Imagine that there's a forest in front
of you and it's extremely dry.
It's extremely dry.
It's been a long hot summer,
or maybe it's been a drought and there's
a hot wind blowing and it's tinder dry.
And there's a lot of deadwood because
there hasn't been a fire for a very long
time.
And so the,
the conditions are poised for a
conflagration and someone comes along
and,
and uh,
produces a spark.
You can't blame the conflagration on the
spark.
Now I sparked this storm,
but that doesn't mean the deadwood
hadn't already gathered.
There's a lot of things that our society
needs to talk out and to lay.
The trouble that's emerged because of
these videos at my feet,
I think is a,
to call it an underhanded ploys is a,
is a very mild statement.
You know,
it's like Jordan Peterson is responsible
for this media storm about political
correctness is like,
I think I don't think so much as I might
like to take credit for it from a purely
egotistical perspective.
I'm the groundwork for all of this was
late,
well before I made my videos.
And the only reason I had they had the
effect they did is because I actually
said that there was something that the
pc,
uh,
thugs want me to do that I'm not going
to do.
So I drew a line and it happened to be
around issues of gender nomenclature,
but it could have been somewhere else.
And so of course,
because of that,
I've been,
um,
attacked in various ways
on the gender issue,
which is also a very important issue
which we need to discuss.
But,
you know,
it could have been in some way.
It could have been any other issue where
anybody else drew a line anyways.
Then they request that I start repeating
these statements.
Okay,
so here we go.
I am not going to use made up pronouns
to refer to people at their whim.
I'm not doing it and I'm not going to be
silent either.
And that's that.
And then they remind me that I have an
obligation to uphold the law into
including the Ontario human rights code
and to deal fairly and ethically with
students.
Which,
um,
yeah,
well I knew that there might be a legal
issue and that's why I made the videos
to begin with.
So that hardly came as a surprise and I
actually think it's quite comical in a
darkly ironic way that the university
itself is the institution that's
verifying my primary concern,
which was that making the video itself
was likely illegal.
We need to think about that because
that's a bad thing.
It's a bad thing.
It shows you very clearly that freedom
of speech is under attack in Canada and
elsewhere of course as well.
And that's why there's been so much
international attention given to this is
the sequence of events.
So,
um,
they also suggest that this might
behavior undermines my ability to
conduct essential components of your job
as a faculty member.
I disagree with that.
Most of them mentally.
My fundamental job as a faculty member
is to speak what I perceive to be the
truth.
And that doesn't mean I'm right and it
doesn't mean that I am speaking the
truth,
it's that I'm trying to speak the truth
and I'm also trying to listen to people
so that I can speak the truth more
carefully and I'm not going to stop
doing that.
And that does not undermine my ability
to conduct essential components of my
job as a faculty member.
In fact,
that is precisely and absolutely my job
as a faculty member.
And then of course to act consistent
with the law and university policy.
While we've already covered that,
I'm telling you,
here we go.
I sat in the first video that making the
video was probably illegal and the
University of Toronto agrees with me or
they wouldn't be warning me.
So we need to think about that and then
there's a bit of hand waving about the
uft deploring acts of violence and the
disruption of civil debate.
Well,
they might deploy it,
but they didn't do anything about it and
they didn't even report on it when it
happened.
And so I think that their claims,
their fundamental claims to have a,
let's say peace and safety as their
primary concern and I'm not even sure
that should be the primary concern
because truth trumps peace and safety.
I think that their actions,
you know,
the administration's actions do not
indicate a very clear commitment to
exactly to exactly the principles state
they claim to uphold.
So,
okay,
so what did I do about this?
Well,
here's what happened.
I went and meet,
met the Dean,
David Cameron on Friday.
I dropped in on him.
Um,
he was kind of nervous as far as I can
tell.
He's an older guy.
I think he's a decent guy.
Um,
he listened to me.
I think we had a very productive
conversation.
I went through my concerns about the
letter and then what I suggested to him
was that the University of Toronto host
a series of debates,
a debate or a series of debates.
I would like to see three of them where
we discussed such things as,
um,
the biological determination of gender
versus the environmental determination
of gender identity.
That would be a good debate.
We could have a debate on whether
Western society is an oppressive
patriarchy or an enlightened
civilization.
I'd like to have that debate.
And then the last debate would be
freedom of speech,
be something like freedom of speech
versus social justice.
So that would be three topics I said we
could have a civilized debate.
The university could host it,
um,
and we could sort these things out like
civilized human beings and maybe the
University of Toronto could be a beacon
on a hill,
so to speak,
which is what we should be.
And um,
maybe it would also help all the
universities in the United States and in
the western world that are wrestling
with these sorts of things,
clarify the issues and,
and move our society had in a productive
and peaceful way.
Because I thought about before I went
into the meeting with the Dean what the
best possible outcome could be and that
wouldn't be victory for me because I'm
not after victory for me.
I'm after truth and peace.
At least that's what I'm trying to be
after.
And so I thought,
and I discussed this with my and my
family,
what would be the best possible outcome?
And one,
you know,
one not good outcome would be the
entrenchment of the two positions into
increasingly rigid blocks and the
escalation of the situation in a
nonproductive way.
But then another productive way would be
to think of this as an opportunity and
say,
look man,
we could have a real discussion at this
university.
It's a great institution with shoulder
our damn responsibility.
We'll have a debate and will enlighten
ourselves and the public.
And so I'm going to meet with David
Cameron here in about half an hour and
I'm going to find out what the
university has to say about that.
So thanks very much for listening.
And I guess I'll close with this.
I would say to my fellow Canadian
citizens,
you guys better wake up,
you know the true north is no longer
strong nor free as far as I can tell,
and are our rights to free speech are
under assault and you better wake up
because it's not pretty and it's not
good and it's happening a lot faster
than you think.
One of the things that happened on
Friday,
it was,
it was announced in the globe and Mail,
is that the liberal government,
the justice minister,
so to so called justice minister has
decided that to pick our judiciary,
which is one of the most important
things that can happen in a country.
The candidates for the judiciary now
will be required to produce a dossier
listing out their group identities,
race,
religion,
sex,
gender,
identity,
gender expression and all the things
that differentiate us by group
membership.
And then the people who picked the
judiciary are going to be subjected to
unconscious reeducation of their
unconscious,
so unconscious anti racism and anti bias
training so that they don't,
so that they're not biased when they
review the candidates with the aim of
selecting candidates on the basis of
their identity,
which,
and I think there's nothing more racist
than that period.
And so that almost passed unnoticed.
And I would say with regards to
unconscious bias training,
first of all,
we can't measure unconscious bias very
well.
This is all the implicit association
test and you can look that up.
We can't measure that very well because
the test isn't very reliable.
It was never intended to be used to
document individual's unconscious bias.
But that's where this idea has come
from.
Um,
there's huge debate on what that bias
means.
Like,
I don't believe it.
I don't believe that it means what the,
what the proponents of unconscious
racial bias say.
It means the science is far from
settled.
And I mean far from settled.
It's a serious topic of discussion.
And,
and,
and then to educate people out of their
unconscious biases.
Man,
that's an Orwellian thing,
you know,
it's one thing to pete controls people's
speech that's bad enough,
especially when you start controlling
what they can say instead of what they
can say,
but then to go after their unconscious
minds and then to make that a
precondition for the panels that select
our judiciary,
it's like this isn't good,
this isn't good.
And I'm speaking as a psychologist and a
student of authoritarianism and
political psychopathology.
So wake up,
this isn't good.
Do something about it.
And I've got a website started that I,
that I'm where I'm going to post things
that people can do.
So.
But that'll,
that'll happen later in the week.
So anyways,
thanks for listening.
That's all I've got to say for now.
Bye.