Hi everyone.
It's January 15th a few weeks ago in a
discussion with Dave Ruben,
I announced that I would be closing my
patrion account as of today,
so I am doing so as Dave has or will
shortly.
I'm not pleased about this in any way
and patrons,
innovative service helped me a lot when
I was first in trouble because of the
videos I made criticizing the Canadian
compelled speech bills,
see 16 and the University of Toronto's
forest anti-biased training policy,
but I don't think what patron has
decided to do in the case of Sar gone
have a cad.
Carl Benjamin was right and I think it
sets a bad precedent so that's that
I'm actively working on an alternative
platform has a competitor to patron.
In the meantime,
I've set up a simple rather featureless
alternative,
which is now where the support bar on
the lower left hand side of my videos
points.
This is for those who would like to
continue their patronage or begin his
new supporters.
My financial situation has stabilized
substantially since I originally set up
a patron account and I did it then in
March of 2016 to see if I could fund
further development of my youtube
channel,
which is not and has never been ad
supported.
However,
it seems that a substantial number of
people want to indicate and provide
their support on a continued basis,
feeling inclined by all appearances to
provide something reciprocal in return
for the content they have been provided
with.
Although I would likely continue to
generate video content in any case,
seeing all that support definitely
incentivizes me on an ongoing basis to
make generating youtube content,
uh,
top priority as well as allowing me to
continue to fund the small team I have
working on an online education project.
I've discussed a bit in various
interviews in the past,
about 5,000 of my patrons have already
left the platform in protest,
so I'm already down to about half the
number of subscribers I once had.
Approximately 2,500 of these have
transferred their support to the
alternative I spoke of earlier.
Although an unknowable proportion of
this 2,500 have new lease signed on.
Thank you very much to all my patrons
and all my viewers and listeners and
readers for their past support and to
all of those who have transferred their
contributions to the alternative system.
So let's see how this goes.
I think I have it set up here to delete.
We'll see right here.
Disabled my account.
Well,
you're goes,
all right.
12 I have to withdraw $11 and 21 cents
it looks like that happened.
So let's see now if I can do this
one more step by the looks of things.
That's it,
ladies and gentlemen.
All right there.
It's nighttime in Switzerland where I am
now.
Anyway,
so I tried to sign in and it's
definitely gone.
So I just thought I'd let you know that.
Thanks again.
We'll talk to you soon.
I've got a couple of new youtube videos
that'll be up in the next week
and I'll see those of you who are coming
to my shows in California and New
Zealand and Australia over the next
month.
Bye Bye.
All.