I didn't quite get through what I wanted
to in the last lecture.
So I think I'm going to steal half an
hour from this lecture and do that and
then we'll go to this lecture.
So,
because I didn't get a chance to read
you some of the things I wanted to read
you
what they're really worth.
Three,
they're really worth hearing.
So I think I'm going to do that.
So one of the things that I've spent a
very long time trying to figure out is
what motivated people to do the terrible
things that they did in the
concentration camps,
particularly in the 20th century in the
concentration camp was pretty widespread
phenomenon.
I mean,
it's still being used extensively in
North Korea for example.
And most of the popularity population
there is starving.
Um,
so it's not like it's done with yet.
Anyways.
The best authors that I've ever read
with regards to insights about the kind
of totalitarian possession that leads
people to commit extraordinarily brutal
atrocities in the service of their
belief have been ball soldier knits and
who's not normally considered a
personality psychologist,
but also Viktor Frankl.
And the reason I have you read soldier
Nixon is because I think soldier knits
and has a more,
I mean Frankel's an amazing thinker,
but soldier knits and is one of those
geniuses that comes along about every
100 years.
So,
and I think soldier Nixon wrote the
most,
the most pertinent and analysis of the
relationship between individual
cowardice and the propensity to adopt
totalitarian beliefs and then the
propensity to commit acts of cruelty in
the name of those beliefs.
Now it's a really tricky issue.
I mean
it's,
it's commonly been assumed,
for example,
that people who are right wing
authoritarian people are right wing
authoritarian because they're afraid of
people who aren't like them or they're
afraid of ideas that aren't like their
ideas or something like that.
It's,
it's often a fear based explanation.
And it seems to me that there's
something to that.
You know,
it's,
it's hard for me to imagine,
you know,
if your,
if your belief systems are disrupted by
a piece of information that you don't
particularly want to receive,
it certainly does expose you to a
tremendous amount of chaos.
And so,
you know,
we've talked about situations,
for example,
where perhaps you received the
information that you knew a loved one
has been unfaithful to you or betrayed
you.
Now part of what you're going to feel in
relationship to that,
his anxiety and it's because it
destabilizes your past and all your
memories and d stabilizes your future
and it destabilizes your,
your present.
And so that presents you with a whole
bunch of uncertainty where at one point
you had a pretty functional map and you
knew how things related to one another
and how you should act.
And so it's reasonable to presuppose
that that produces fear,
especially because we know from,
from work by someone,
people like Jeffrey Gray
for example,
who were going to talk about in the next
lecture,
that if you expose laboratory animals to
novelty,
which is certainly an annex,
something unexpected is something novel
or something anomalous,
it's something novel that they react.
You can,
you can conceptualize the reaction
roughly in two ways.
And you can say,
well,
they become afraid.
They manifest anxiety,
which you can dampen down with
antianxiety drugs like valium,
benzodiazepines,
barbiturates,
and alcohol.
Um,
but they also manifest curiosity.
But the,
but the anxiety usually supersedes the
curiosity.
So the anxiety has to wear off before
the coup curiosity will come forward.
And that depends to some degree on the
magnitude of the novel event and
calculating how large novel of is turns
out to be extraordinarily difficult.
But we'll talk,
we'll talk through that as well.
And so the anxiety models and so those
would be,
so things is things like terror
management theory,
for example.
The anxiety models are pretty good,
but they're missing things.
They're missing things.
And there's a,
so here's a couple of things that they
might be missing.
I've pursued the idea that when you
encounter a
datum,
we'll say,
cause it could be a stimulus or it could
be an idea or it could be a person,
but let's call it a piece of information
that contradicts your axiomatic
presupposition.
So your theory then,
what might happen,
the hippocampus is a brain area that
seems to do something like detect mick
mismatches between what you expect or
want to have happen and what actually
happens.
And it seems to send a signal down to
the reticular activating system,
which is the part of your brain that
actually governs consciousness.
So it's what wakes you up in the morning
and puts you to sleep at night.
And also what makes you wake up very
suddenly.
If you hear an unexpected noise at
night,
it stops,
it stops it,
it releases the reticular activating
system from inhibition.
And so it's basically the hippocampus
does something like tell your reticular
activating system to take it easy as
long as everything's going the way you
want it to go.
And if it doesn't go the way you want it
to go,
then it releases the reticular
activating system from inhibition.
And what that seems to do is to release
a whole variety of underlying
neurological circuits from inhibition.
So then you become anxious but you also
become curious.
But it's possible that you'll become a
lot of other things too.
And this is,
this is part of the generalized stress
response as far as I can tell him.
What happens when,
when you manifest the general stress
responses that your body prepares for
everything.
Why?
Well,
cause you don't know what to do when
something you don't expect happens.
It's like the definition of not want
knowing what to do.
And so because your body's pretty smart,
it just ramps itself up in terms of its
preparation,
which is very stressful.
Technically speaking.
It's stressful because you're burning a
lot of energy and resources that you
could devote to other things,
suppresses your immune system and gets
you ready.
You know?
So and,
and at,
at,
you know,
for any length of time that can be fun
in small doses.
In fact it is because people like
novelty in small doses,
but in large doses and chronically it's
like that's death itself,
you know?
So it seems that people really don't
like to have their,
their expectations dashed or,
or more accurately,
they don't like it when what they want
to have happen doesn't happen,
which isn't exactly the same thing.
So the question is then,
what does happen when what you want to
doesn't happen?
How exactly do you characterize it?
One way of characterizing it as fear and
another way of characterizing it is
something like generalized disinhibition
of potential.
That's another one.
And I think that one's more accurate.
I think it's more accurate because it's
more comprehensive and it's deeper.
But then there's a third variable that
we're going to talk about quite a bit
that,
that everybody's just sort of coming to
terms with now,
which is that it turns out that people
who are tilted towards right wing
authoritarianism,
first of all,
they're high in conscientiousness and
they're,
and they're low in openness.
And if you fractionate
conscientiousness,
which you can,
you can break it into two things.
You can break it into industriousness
and orderliness and industriousness is a
bang dead on predictor of how well you
guys do in university.
It's,
it's damn near as powerful as
intelligence.
It's not as powerful,
but we can't measure it as well either.
And so that's industriousness.
We don't have,
we don't know anything about
industriousness.
You know,
we know how to measure it through self
report and we know how to correlate
those self reports with life outcomes.
We have no neuropsychological model for
it.
We have no conceptual model for it.
We have no pharmacological model for it.
Uh,
did I say animal model?
We have no animal model for it.
It's like we don't know anything about
it except that it predicts longterm life
success better than anything else except
Iq in managerial,
administrative and academic positions
like grades.
So but orderliness,
that's a whole different story cause it
turns out that orderliness,
we haven't published this yet,
but orderliness is associated with
sensitivity to discussed and that's a
weird thing because for a long time we
thought that all the negative emotions
loaded on neuroticism.
So this is big five speak fundamentally
that you know,
pain and anger,
frustration,
disappointment,
shame,
guilt,
anxiety and fear.
We're all,
if you were more likely to feel one,
you're more likely to feel all of them.
And all of the negative emotions clump
together.
And that's basically what neuroticism is
from a big five perspective.
But it turns out that disgust,
sensitivity loads on orderliness.
Now I tell you man,
that is one major finding.
It's like I think
because we know we know a fair bit about
disgust,
sensitivity.
Now give me one second.
That's mostly,
at least in part through the work of
Jonathan Haidt.
He was a very,
very,
very smart guy who started scouting,
discussed before anybody else figured
out that it was worthwhile to discuss or
to just do I investigate roughly
speaking,
you know,
and he fall.
He found that people who are disgust
sensitive,
we're very obsessed with moral purity.
You know,
it turned out to be the same thing.
So bodily contamination and moral
impurity are roughly the same phenomena.
And then it turns out,
I really figured this out when I was
reading Hitler's table talk cause
Hitler's table talk by the way,
it was a book that was put together of
Hitler's spontaneous speeches discussion
while he was eating dinner for like
three years.
You know,
it's a fascinating book because it
really gives you some insight into how
he thought.
And he was a very,
he's a very peculiar person cause he was
very high in openness,
which is a creativity dimension and very
high in orderliness and people like that
aren't very common.
But anyways,
his whole metaphor for,
for,
for German,
for the area and race,
the whole metaphor was body.
It's like the areas,
we're a pure body with pure blood and
they were under assault from parasites.
And so it was a disgust metaphor.
You know,
it wasn't fear.
it kinda sounds like fear because you
could say,
well Hitler was afraid of the Gypsies
and he was afraid of the Jews.
And you know,
he was afraid of non ariens.
But,
but,
well first of all,
I don't think it's reasonable to say
that the Nazis were precisely possessed
by fear.
That is exactly how they looked.
And if you look at conservatives,
I'm not calling conservatives Nazis by
the way,
but they're,
you know,
the Nazi philosophy is an extension of
political belief on the right,
just like totalitarian communism.
And this is extension of political
belief on the left.
So you can fall into a pit either way,
you know,
but
the Nazis were,
first of all,
they're German and the Germans are a
conscientious people,
so to speak.
You know,
they have a very advanced industrial
society.
Their engineering is very precise.
To what degree that's a national trait.
God only knows to what and to what
degree.
That's a consequence of,
of uh,
you know,
sociological pressure.
We don't understand anything about those
sorts of things.
But,
um,
Hitler was absolutely obsessed with,
with purity and with willpower and those
things go together.
So orderly people seem to be very
enamored of their own willpower.
It's something like that.
They sort of worship it as the top God,
so to speak,
and like,
uh,
anorexic people tend to be very orderly
and they get discussed.
I think anorexia is a disorder of
disgust.
Anorexic girls,
they get completely disgusted by their
own bodies,
you know,
and that's a fair,
think about that.
That's a very tight line because there's
any number of disgusting things about
bodies and you have to attend to that
because if you don't,
then you end up contaminated in a
variety of ways.
You know,
you can catch us sexual disease for
example,
or you can just catch a disease or you
could be developing infection or any
number of things that will take you
down,
you know?
So it's,
it's very difficult for human beings to
get the calibration right with regards
to,
you know,
their bodies and their feeling about
their bodies and the fact that you also
have to keep the damn thing clean and
organized and are otherwise,
you know,
all hell breaks loose.
And it's no joke.
When Hitler was before Hitler,
you know,
started the concentration camps and went
after when we had after things in a big
way,
is very,
very concerned with the hygiene of the
German people,
you know.
And he did things like,
uh,
his first,
here's his first stop policy
implementations where tuberculosis
screening and had people go around in
vans and ex-ray everyone to try to get
rid of tuberculosis.
It's like,
yeah,
you know,
let's get rid of tuberculosis.
And then they started cleaning up the
factory so they,
you know,
get rid of the bugs and the rats and
sweep them all out and plant flowers out
front.
It was like a beautification campaign
and they used Zyklon B to do that.
And Zyklon b was the gas that was used
in the concentration counts.
It's like,
that's quite interesting.
And that movement from insects in rats
to human beings.
And that there was an intermediary
there,
which seemed to be mental hospitals
because the next day and they did was go
and clean up the,
you know,
the people that the Nazis,
Hitler in particular,
but the Nazis and general felt were
inferior or contemptible or something
like that.
And like contempt and disgust seem to go
very tightly together.
And contempt.
That's a vicious emotion.
So like if you're in a relationship with
somebody,
close relationship and they start to
become contemptuous of you,
and you could tell that because they
rolled their eyes,
the probability that you're going to
divorce them or separately from them is
extraordinarily high.
Contempt is a very corrosive emotion.
And anyways,
so you know,
the transformation and purity campaign
of Hitler just extended and extended and
extended and extended and extended.
And you know,
God only knows where it would have
ended.
And I also think that's why he was a
worshiper of fire because fire is a
purifying substance.
And the Nazis really used fire as a
symbol of their,
of their movement because Hitler would
have these massive nighttime political
rallies,
you know,
with 150,000 people all put in perfect
squares,
you know,
with this massive background of fire and
light.
And you know,
and it all seems to boil down to the
fact that he was extraordinarily disgust
sensitive and not became a cardinal
element of his political platform.
And then that was associated with
orderliness and that,
you know,
you can try,
you can track it all the way down to the
biology.
And there was a paper published in Plos
one,
which I should really put on the website
about a year ago.
And I unfortunately,
I don't remember who published it,
but they were looking at,
you know,
let's say iss to your political
attitudes.
I could do that,
say with an authoritarian scale
authoritarian and belief scale.
Cause authoritarianism has been studied
quite a bit since the end of World War
II.
Nobody really knew what to do with it in
relationship to personality.
It doesn't matter.
You can,
you can assess it,
you know,
to with a reasonable degree of accuracy.
These people went to,
they did two things.
They did a cross country survey and then
within country surveys,
so you imagine you could,
if you were looking at a phenomena,
you could look at the country level,
you asked Canada or you could go into
the u s and then you could look at a
state level.
And it's nice to do the analysis at both
levels to see if it replicates itself
across the two different conceptual,
you know,
two different conceptual strata.
And what they've found is mind boggling.
It's Nobel prize winning stuff as far as
I'm concerned,
is that the correlation between the
prevalence of infectious disease in a
locale and the degree to which are
authoritarian beliefs were held in that
locale was bout 0.7.
It's like you never see that in the
social sciences.
That's higher than the correlation
between Iq and grades,
which is about as good as we ever get in
terms of prediction.
So it's like really it's that high,
you know.
And one of the things that that implies
is that one of the ways to get rid of
right wing authoritarian attitudes,
assuming that you want to get rid of
such things is too is through public
health.
You know,
it could easily be that the reason that
we're all tilted fairly hard to the
center and even to the left is that
everybody's clean.
You know,
we've got suit,
we've got functioning sanitation and
she's like,
Oh,
don't have to worry about that anymore.
So,
and believe me,
like people used to have to worry about
that before the antibiotics.
It's like you get an infection man,
your dad and that's on its way back by
the way.
Cause we keep using antibiotics for
everything under the sun.
Just very,
very,
very stupid.
Anyways,
so I,
I gave you all that background because
you know,
it's a tangled mess.
The,
the authoritarian personality issue.
There's a sociological element to it,
which is the disease element.
And then there's the existential element
that we've talked about in detail where
there seems to be also something about
people's unwillingness to stand up for
themselves and develop their own beliefs
and adhere to the truth and to adopt
authoritarian,
you know,
extremely rigid,
authoritarian belief systems and then go
persecute people for them.
And we don't know how to separate all
those things out,
but I thought I would read you some
things that were written both by soldier
Knutsen and by Frankel about a,
the concentration camps in Germany.
Cause Frankl was a concentration camp
survivor survivor and be the
concentration camps in the Soviet Union
because soldier Nansen was a
concentration camp survivor.
He was a rather fortunate concentration
camp inmates in so far as there is such
a thing because he had,
he had some specialized knowledge that
made him sufficiently valuable not to
starve to death.
So,
so here is one of soldier Nixon's
descriptions of one of his experiences
or that some firsthand observer told him
because when he wrote the Gulag
archipelago,
he,
he wrote a lot about his own
experiences.
But he also wrote a lot about the
experiences that other people had
related to him while he was in the
camps.
So
one of the people he met told how
executions were carried out at a dock,
which was,
uh,
which is a work camp hum.
It destructive labor camp on that mature
river.
They would take the opposition members.
So these were people who weren't
communists.
A lot of people who got thrown in the
gulag prisons and the Soviet Union were
basically political prisoners.
Right.
You didn't have,
you weren't a staunch communist or
you've been turned in for some,
you've being turned in for political,
uh,
what would you call it?
Um,
treason,
you know,
by a neighbor who really wanted your
apartment.
And so they turn you on,
you need to get hold off to
concentration camp,
and then,
you know,
your neighbor would get your apartment's
very pretty arrangement for everyone
concerned.
So the,
the gulags were full of political
prisoners.
They were also full of normal criminals,
murderers,
rapists,
thieves.
And those guys basically ran the camps.
And because the stalinists thought that
murderers,
rapists,
and thieves,
that they were,
um,
what would you call those?
You could rehabilitate them because they
were actually victims of an unjust class
structure.
So,
you know,
hypothetically you could save them,
whereas if you had rich parents or maybe
your parents owned farm or maybe they
just had a bloody house,
God only knows then you were socially
suspect element because he came from the
bourgeoisie,
it not the proletariat.
So you got thrown in jail alongside the
murderers and rapists and thieves and
you know,
they were regarded as morally superior
to you,
which is,
you know,
something that only a bloody communists
could think through and come to that
conclusion,
you know,
it's mind boggling.
So anyways,
a lot of what happened in the counts
was,
you know,
political murder essentially.
And so this is what Solzhenitsyn's
talking about in this particular case.
So he says,
this is how executions were carried out
at a dock,
a camp on the [inaudible] river.
They would take the opposition members
with their things out of the camp
compound on a prisoner transport at
night and outside the compound stood
those small house of the third section.
The condemned men were taken into a room
one at a time and they're the camp
guards sprang on them.
Their mouths were stuffed with something
soft and their arms were bound with
cords behind their backs.
Then they were led out into the
courtyard where harnessed carts were
waiting.
The bound prisoners were piled onto the
carts from five to seven at a time and
driven off to the Gorkha,
the camp cemetery on arrival.
They were tipped into big pits that had
already been prepared and buried alive.
Not Out of brutality,
no,
it'd be Nasser tained that when dragging
and lifting them,
it was much easier to cope with living
people.
Then with corpses,
the work went on for many nights at a
deck and this is how the moral political
unity of our party was achieved.
Now you see what seems to be happening
there is that the people who are engaged
in these activities are classifying
those who oppose their political beliefs
as contemptible and therefore worthy of
destruction.
And that that seems to be partly a fear
response.
You know,
that which is not us,
but it's also,
it seems very much also to partly to be
tied very deeply into this disgust and
contamination system about which we
don't know much about the cognitive
elements of that system.
Although one of the things that's that's
worth considering,
you know,
this has gone through my mind,
is that,
you know,
you might ask why the hell to human
beings categorized things because other
animals don't really do that the same
way.
We really categorize things like mad and
you think,
well,
we're all,
first of all,
we're omnivores,
right?
That's a kind of a weird problem because
if you're omnivores,
you can eat anything except the things
you should need,
you know,
and making a clear,
and that's a real problem.
If you're a Koala bear and all you eat
is eucalyptus leaves,
it's like Poof,
problem solved.
Unless the eucalyptus leaves aren't
around and then you die.
But if you're an Omnivore,
you have to run all over the place and
you can eat damn near anything.
But you have to keep track of the things
that will kill you and the things that
are poisoning the things that are
contaminated and the things that are
good for you and it's,
it's not an easy thing to do that.
So it seems like part of our
classification system and the cognitive
elements seem to actually have emerged
out of out of contamination and
discussed concerns and that seems to be
grounded in some sense in what,
you know,
our,
our ability to make decisions about what
we're going to put in our mouths and
not,
you know,
like people don't like to put disgusting
things in their mouth.
Generally speaking,
you know,
you can overcome that.
So people will eat,
you know,
moldy cheese,
but you really have to work to overcome
that and you have to work to overcome
your,
your disgust at eating bitter
substances.
So you have to develop a taste for
coffee and you have to develop a taste
for all of us because a lot of things
that are bitter are actually poisonous.
So,
so the,
the idea that there are things that you
can put in your mouth that are good for
you and there are things that you can't
put in your mouth cause they're bad for
you,
is rooted somehow very deeply in our,
in our ideas of categorization and also
in our ideas of morality.
Right?
And you think of morality as a higher
order,
cognitive function.
But think about,
you know,
modern people are as obsessed with food
as the,
as the victorians were obsessed with sex
and people are making divisions,
primary divisions of morality based on
what each other eat all the time.
You know,
the vegetarianism movement or the Vegan
movement is a really good example of
that.
I mean,
those sorts of concerns have been
present throughout human history as far
as I can tell,
because there's lots of ancient sex that
don't,
that are vegetarian and just lots of
people in India who are vegetarian
primarily and often for religious
beliefs.
You know,
so it's a matter of,
and it,
it also seems that we divide,
we tend to divide people into groups,
even ethnic groups on the basis of what
one group is allowed to eat and what
another group will eat.
And so,
you know,
um,
Christians elite will eat swine.
And that's something that,
uh,
you know,
more,
more conservative Jews and Muslims in
general won't touch.
It's disgusting and it's contaminated,
you know?
And it isn't fear.
Exactly.
It's something other than fear.
It's more,
and the danger of conceptualizing it in
terms of contaminated and disgusting.
And you see this a lot in the language
that the say the Auschwitz camp guards
used with to the people that they were
putting in the ovens,
for example,
they weren't people,
they were rats and insects.
That was the language.
It's not like people are afraid of rats
and the insects,
you know,
I mean,
it's a rat.
That's not a big problem,
but you can easily hate it.
And it is something to be destroyed,
you know?
And so we also don't know to what
degree,
when you use the disgust system to
classify someone,
whether you're automatically putting
them into the category of disgusting
thing that should be destroyed.
And there,
there's a woman named Martha Nussbaum
who's a legal scholar and she's
suggested she's liberal.
And she suggested that
our legal decisions should never be
based on discussed,
you know?
But then I read Nussbaum and I think,
well yeah,
it's easy to say that except the disgust
system is what stops you from eating
things that will kill you.
And you can't just shut the damn thing
off because you know,
it's a fundamental biological mechanism
and it orients you in the world now.
And so we don't know how to control it.
Spillover say into radical political
belief,
but just saying,
don't do that or you know,
you know what I mean?
It's not wrestling with the problem
because first of all,
you don't want to be not disgusted by
things.
That's a really bad idea.
But by the same token,
you know,
if you get too radical about that,
you get to orderly then not,
you know,
if you're anorexic he can't even stand
your own body.
That's really not a good thing,
you know,
cause at the anorexic,
so I've worked with,
they often talk about their fantasies
and they look at their body and what
they see is like corruptible flash
basically.
And they have fantasies about purity and
the purity is they want to reduce
themselves to bone.
You know,
cause bone is white and it's pure and it
doesn't have this sort of corruptible
flesh hanging off it.
And you know that that seems to go along
with fairly severe perceptual
aberrations.
So cause a anorexics don't really see,
seem to be able to look at their body as
a whole.
What they seem to do is focus
obsessively on parts and they can never
really get the parts together.
So you know,
and I don't exactly know how that's
associated with disgust either except
that that hyper,
you know,
that hyper alertness and hyper
concentration could easily be associated
with analysis of things that that might
be disgusting and dangerous.
Anyways,
Frankel,
the most,
this is from the Nazi concentration
camps.
The note most ghastly moment of the 24
hours of camp life was the awakening
when Adh is still nocturnal hour.
The three shrill blows of a whistle,
Torres Petty Leslie from are exhausted
sleep and from the longings in our
dreams.
We then began the tussle with our,
which shoes into which we could scarcely
force our feet,
which were sore and swollen with a Dema
and there were the usual moans and
groans about petty troubles such as the
snapping of wires,
which replaced shoe laces.
One morning I heard someone
whom I knew to be brave and cry like
a child because he finally had to go to
the snowy marching grounds in his bare
feet as his shoes were too shrunk and
for him to wear.
And these gospely moments,
I found a little bit of comfort,
a small piece of bread,
which I drew out of my pocket and
munched with absorbed delight
Lord of what happened in the Gulag camps
was that,
you know,
these people that were putting in the
camps where we're putting into work
brigades and you know,
so there was a huge canal that was dug
in the Soviet Union,
I believe it was in the 30s and I
believe,
I don't remember the canals name at the
moment,
unfortunately,
but they killed 300,000 people in three
months building it because they were
pick axing dirt in the,
in the brutal cold to build this canal.
You know,
because it had to be done now.
And you know,
according to Solzhenitsyn's description,
by the time they finished the canal,
while 300,000 people had died,
but it was too shallow to be useful for
the,
for the purpose they wanted to put it
to.
And so basically it was built but never
used.
And so then you think,
well,
what was the purpose of the canal if it
was never used?
And the answer to that is the purpose of
the canal was to kill 300,000 people
while they were working on it.
You know?
And if you think that people can't have
such purposes,
then you're not thinking very hard
because they certainly can't.
And stellan certainly did.
Yeah.
Here's soldiers,
Nixon's comments about about work camps
during the winter.
And this is Russia,
right?
It's like Russia has a winters in cold
lower than 60 degrees below zero work
days were written off.
In other words,
on such days,
the record showed that the workers have
not gone out to work,
but they chased them out anyway and
whatever they squeezed out of them on
those days was added to the other days.
They are by raising the percentages.
Okay.
And the serve biomedical section wrote
off those who froze to death on such
cold days on some other basis.
Okay.
And the ones who were left who could no
longer walk,
and we're straining every sinew to crawl
along on all fours on the way back to
camp.
The convoy simply shot so that they
wouldn't escape before they could go
come back together.
The,
when I was studying this material,
I was also looking at him poetic
representations of contamination and
corruption and evil.
And so I'm going to read you a poem from
William Blake that seems to sum up the
attitude that's necessary to harbor
before you would be capable of doing
such things.
This is from the complete works of
William Blake.
Oh rose,
thou art sick.
The invisible worm that flies in the
night in the howling storm has found out
that I bet of crimson joy and his dark
secret love does die life destroy.
This is something I took out of the
Gulag archipelago,
the volume two of the Gulag archipelago,
which is an amazing book.
The Gulag archipelago itself is an
unbelievable work of literature.
It's,
it's,
it's phenomenal.
It's,
it's an immense book.
I think it's 2,700 pages long and it's
written in little tiny type.
So it's,
it's 2,700 dense pages and it record
Solzhenitsyn's,
uh,
experiences of the concentration camp
and the concentration camps and the
stories that he gathered,
the individual stories that he gathered
that describe it qualitatively.
But Solzhenitsyn also made an attempt to
put the hit the camps did write a
history of the camps and also a history
of the political and social institutions
that gave rise to them.
But at the same time,
a psychological analysis of the
conditions that made these camps
possible and probable.
And he identified the fundamental
problem in the Soviet Union has the
willingness of the Soviet citizens to
lie to themselves and to each other on a
constant and ongoing basis.
So to some degree it's a reflection of
the idea that I told you about before of
the instrumental use of language.
Language was something to hide your true
self behind,
not something to communicate about.
And people were very unwilling to
discuss anything that might be
considered a shortcoming of the system
in any way possible.
No matter how bad the system God.
And no matter how bad they were
suffering,
because by definition the system was
always already perfect,
right?
You told me I had already come.
And what that meant was that if you were
suffering and it was utopia,
there obviously was something seriously
wrong with you.
And the best thing to do with a creature
that was as seriously garnish dre is you
was to get rid of them and often in the
most brutal way that could possibly be a
management.
And so that happened to lots of people.
You know,
in East Germany,
they estimated one out of every three
people was a government informer.
So the line,
and this is Solzhenitsyn's analysis of
what happened in the Soviet Union,
he didn't believe that any of that could
happen unless the entire citizenry had
made an unspoken pact that they were
never ever going to say anything that
was true to each other or to themselves
under any circumstances whatsoever.
And he believed that that was the
precondition.
You know,
I've already mentioned these sorts of
phenomena are very complicated,
but he believed that that was the
precondition for the absolute corruption
of the state.
And that's really worth thinking about,
you know,
and soldier knits and also said that,
I think this was in his,
in his Nobel prize speech,
but it might've been as Harvard address
cause he was invited to speak at
graduation at Harvard.
And the newspapers ripped him apart by
the way,
because he was quite critical of,
of Western society despite the fact that
he had been granted asylum in Vermont.
You know,
and it was so interesting to read the
crit criticisms because you know,
people base,
even people who should have known a hell
of a lot better,
you know,
like smart people,
we're very irritated at soldier knits.
And for daring to say that there was
anything wrong with the West,
given that he had been asylum,
you know,
by the Americans in Vermont,
I personally thought they were lucky to
get him,
you know,
and I think that's the right attitude
toward someone like him.
But,
um,
anyways,
so the book itself,
the Gulag Archipelago,
the second volume is mostly personal
experiences of one form or another.
And it's,
you know,
enough to,
while you've read some of it
hypothetically,
you know,
it's an unbelievably brilliant book,
but the three volumes together,
you know,
2,700 pages,
it's,
they're,
they're almost unbearable because
they're written by someone who's
basically screaming at the top of his
lungs for like 2,700 pages.
That's pretty impressive.
You know,
I read this study once about rats.
So if you put rats in a,
in a normal environment,
not,
not like you're single caged rat,
but your family loving hierarchy,
inhabiting,
exploring sort of rat.
If you make a natural habitat for them,
maybe you put all the family things at
one end so the rats can hang out with
all their kith and kin.
And then at the other end you,
you place a place where they can go
explore and maybe that's where you feed
them hay.
So,
so they get used to that and that's
home.
And then you put a cat in out there
where they're feeding and you know,
a rat goes out there and he sees the cat
and like,
that's hell for rats,
man.
He's back in his rabbit burrow and like
now,
and then what he does is he peaks his
head out of the borough and he screams,
no rat rat screams ultra sonic screens
for the equivalent of three weeks in
human hours.
It's like that rat that's one freaked
out rack and none of the other rats go
anywhere when that rat is screaming.
And that's really like,
I think of that as the equivalent of
Solzhenitsyn's book.
It's like,
it's,
it's a hair raising,
uh,
endeavor to plow your way through that
book.
But it's,
it's an indictment of,
of,
of 20th century morality in a very clear
indication of what happens at a
sociopolitical and an economic level if
people abandon their claim to
existential truth at an individual
level.
And that's something really worth
thinking about because one of the things
I derived from this was that if you want
to protect yourself against the
possibility that you would become as
corrupt politically or sociologically as
the Nazis for examples or,
or maybe the Soviet communists or maybe
the mile was communist sort of,
we could,
or the North Koreans,
I mean we could go on and on.
You might ask,
well,
you know,
if you're smart enough to assume that
you're not already protected because
you're not,
you know,
one of the things that's really worth
thinking about is there does seem to be
a direct causal relationship between
people's willing to willingness to
falsify their own personal experience
and the spread of unbelievable political
and economic corruption.
And one of the things we do know is that
if you want to make a country rich,
the one thing you absolutely have to do
is make sure that the people will in
fact trade honestly with one another.
So unless the default presupposition
between people is trust,
it's just damn hard thing to implement,
you know?
And I don't even understand any
country's ever managed it ever.
If the default presupposition is that if
we trade,
you won't screw me over.
We can get rich,
but if the default assumption is God
only knows what's up with you,
it's like forget it man.
I don't care how many natural resources
we've got,
we're going to stay poor.
So there's something that's incredibly
like truth,
I think is truth might be the only true
natural resource.
You know the Japanese are good example
because their culture,
their trading culture is fundamentally
honest.
They don't have any bloody at natural
resources at all.
The rich,
you don't explain that.
It's not an easy thing to do.
But anyhow,
I know your story from Solzhenitsyn
fire fire,
the branches crackle in the night.
Wind of late autumn blows the flame of
the bonfire back and forth.
A compound is dark.
I'm alone at the bar and fire and I can
bring it still some more carpenter
shavings.
Okay.
The compound here is a privileged one,
so privileged that it is almost as if I
were out in freedom.
This is an island of paradise.
This is the Marfino Shahram [inaudible],
a scientific institute staffed with
prisoners in its most privileged period.
No one is overseeing me,
calling me to a cell,
chasing me away from the bonfire,
and even then it's chilly in the
penetrating wind,
but she who's already been standing in
the wind for hours,
her arms straight down,
her head drooping,
weeping,
then growing numb and still,
and then again she begs pity.
Asley citizen chief,
please forgive me.
I won't do it again.
The wind carries her mons to me just as
if she were moaning next to my ear.
The citizen chief at the gate house
fires up.
His stove does not answer.
This was the gate house of the camp next
door to us from which workers came into
our compound to lay water pipes and to
repair the old ramshackle seminary
building
cross for me.
Beyond the artfully intertwined many
stranded barbed wire barricade and two
steps away from the gate house beneath a
bright lantern stood the punished girl
head hanging the wind tugging at her
gray work skirt,
her feet growing numb from the cold,
a thin scarf over her head.
It'd be warm during the day when they
had been digging a ditch on our
territory and another girl slipping down
into a ravine had crawled her way to the
flat of Keno highway and escaped.
The guard had bungled and Moscow city
buses ran right along the highway.
When they caught on,
it was too late to catch her and they
raised the alarm.
Yeah,
amine dark major arrived and shouted
that if they failed to catch the girl,
the entire camp would be deprived of
visits and the parcels for a whole month
because of her escape
and the women brigadiers went into a
rage and they were all shouting.
One of them in particular who kept
viciously rolling her eyes.
Okay.
Oh,
I hope they catch her.
The bitch.
I hope they take scissors and clip,
clip,
take off all her hair in front of the
lineup.
This wasn't something she had thought of
it herself.
This was the way they punished women in
the Gulag.
But the girl who was now standing
outside the gate house in the cold had
sighed and said instead
deadly.
She can have a good time out in freedom
for all of us.
The jailer overheard what she said and
now she was being punished.
Everyone else had been taken off to the
camp,
but she had been said outside there to
stand at attention in front of the gate
house.
This had been at 6:00 PM and it was now
11:00 PM to tried to shift from one foot
to another,
but the guards stuck out his hand and
shouted,
stand at attention,
whore or else it will be worse for you.
Now.
She was not moving only weeping.
Forgive me,
citizen chief,
let me into the camp.
I won't do it anymore,
but even in the camp,
no one was about to say to her,
all right,
idiot,
come on in.
The reason they were keeping her out
there for so long was it the next day
was Sunday and she would not be needed
for work.
Such a straw,
blonde,
naive,
uneducated slip of a girl.
She had been in prison for some spool of
thread.
What a dangerous thought.
You express their little sister.
They want to teach you a lesson for the
rest of your life.
Fire,
fire.
We fought the war and we looked into the
bonfires to see what kind of victory
would be
the wind was did a glowing husk from the
bonfire
to that flame and you girl,
I promise.
Okay.
Whole wide world will read about.
Right.
This is from Milton Paradise Lost
Mailgun when he wrote paradise lost.
He was trying,
he was trying to,
you can say that you can think in some
sense that that a huge part of the
mythological religious and philosophical
enterprise of the human race over the
last five or 6,000 years and perhaps
long before that has been an attempt to
segregate out what is the good,
the good way of existing and what the
evil way of existing now why we're
obsessed with good and evil is a very
difficult thing to understand.
I think it has something to do with our
self consciousness.
I think that because I don't really,
if you're an animal you can be a
predator.
But if you're a human being,
you can take it past that because if
you're a self conscious,
you can understand your own
vulnerability.
You know what will hurt you.
As soon as you know what can hurt you,
you know what can hurt other people.
And as soon as you know what can hurt
you and what can hurt other people,
then you can make a choice between good
and evil because you can start to hurt
other people just for the sake of
hurting them.
You know?
And that's as close to evil as I think
it gets.
And people have been trying to
conceptualize that for it because they
are trying to conceptualize it as well.
How it is that human affairs can go
dreadfully wrong insofar as that can be
laid at human feet.
You know,
sometimes it's earthquakes and sometimes
it's floods,
but sometimes it's not.
Sometimes it's people causing trouble
for the sake of trouble and they,
the human race has been trying to
understand the personality
characteristics of that mode of action
for thousands of years.
And a lot of that's emerged up in
mythology and stories and,
and more than in philosophy.
It's,
it's,
it's like the bad guy.
And in a movie it's like a low key,
you know,
that's a good example.
That's a good example of that sort of
thing popping up in,
in relatively modern culture.
You know,
what's the,
what's the embodiment of evil?
And that's what Milton was trying to
figure out when he wrote paradise lost,
you know,
and he was taking all these stories
about say,
tannic forces and hell that had
collected in,
in human culture for thousands and
thousands of years and trying to sort
them out and make some sense out of
them.
Some narrative sense,
you know?
And He,
uh,
yeah,
he believed that fundamentally evil
impulse,
the most evil impulse,
which you could characterize evil as a
Meta personality that exists across
people.
Because if you do something evil and you
do something evil and you do something
evil,
it's like there's some commonality
across that you can extract out the
commonalities and you can say,
well,
that's what this personality is like.
But then you can also say,
well,
that's a very powerful,
it's a matter of personality.
It's something that will never die.
And it's something that can actually
possess people.
You know?
And if you don't think that you know
that that's possible,
then you know,
you probably don't know that serial
killers tend to compete with one
another.
You know,
these sorts of things.
They're not,
they're not,
they're not fictions.
And the people who shoot up high
schools,
they're pretty damn
informed about the last person who did
the same thing in January.
They're trying to do a better job.
So,
you know,
this is serious,
this is serious matters.
And Milton's analysis,
you know,
he wrote what was considered the
greatest poem in the English language,
which is roughly speaking,
is paradise lost and what,
what,
what Milton would milton concluded?
And this is like a phenomenal logical
statement.
You know,
when we talked about the
phenomenologists,
we talked about them trying to wrestle
with the,
with the question of what constituted
being,
you know,
and human being.
What's the nature of your experience and
when,
then what's your relationship to that
experience?
You know,
and the phenomenologists and the
existentialists claimed that the proper
relationship was one of truth.
Fundamentally mill basically
conceptualized Satan and that's his
persona.
Effication of evil as the,
okay.
Either the embodiment of or the force
behind.
You can read it either way.
Okay.
The,
the mind that has made its decision,
that being itself is evil.
It should be eradicated.
If you read the Columbine killers,
the literary one,
if you read his,
his writings,
it's exactly what he concluded.
He concluded that being as such was
flawed.
You know,
people were contemptible being itself
was unsupportable ethically because
there was too much suffering.
It was too flawed in the best thing to
do,
which was to eradicate it
and so,
and conceptualized evil as resentment
against big now in,
in Milton's language that was resentment
against God.
But it boils down to exactly the same
thing.
You know,
when you can,
you can understand this,
it's,
so that would be like the architectural
roots of resentment.
That's a way a union would look at it
and you know,
you can see,
you'll see in your life that resentment
will emerge.
Like it'll emerge anytime something you
regard is unfair,
happens specifically to you.
You know,
and if it's bad enough,
you'll not only be irritated and angry
and hostile and self pitying and
destructive,
um,
and looking for revenge because of it.
All those things that will happen and
it's almost inevitable.
But um,
if you take that far enough,
then you get to the bottom of that.
And the bottom of it is that it would be
just as well in your estimation if
everything that lived ceased to exist.
It's interesting because not only did
Milton come to that conclusion,
um,
the great German,
yeah,
philosopher and author and poet Girtha
came to exactly the same conclusion.
He believed when he,
when he wrote Faust and faust started Mo
Mephistopheles about now there's so
Mephistopheles was a,
an Avatar of evil.
Fundamentally,
his basic creed was that existence
itself is so terrible in its fundamental
nature,
so tragic and flawed that we'd be better
if we just brought the whole thing to an
end.
Now you think that's a pretty damn
powerful philosophy actually.
And believe me,
there'll be times in your life where you
think that,
especially when something really
terrible happens to someone really close
to you in some arbitrary way,
you know,
maybe you'll have a child,
it becomes extremely ill and some
painful manner,
you know,
and that'll be enough to make you shake
your fist at heaven.
The problem with that attitude,
as far as I can tell,
because I've traced it,
I've tried to understand what are the
logical conclusions to adopting that
attitude and a logical conclusion is
that you take a bad situation and you
make it worse and that to me that means
it's logically and coherent.
If the problem you're trying to solve is
the fact that being is flawed in a deep
way and it's tragic and that people
suffer and they suffer on justly,
you're making the presupposition that
that's wrong,
that it shouldn't happen.
The fact that it's happening is what it
what undoes the whole project of being
so to speak.
And so what that means is that if you
actually believe that in your acting,
in accordance with that,
then the one thing you should not do is
make it worse.
And I can tell you the one thing that
will make it worse is that is if you
adopt that attitude,
it will get worse.
It'll get worse,
and at some point you'll be happy that
it's getting worse.
And at some point after that,
not only will you be happy that it's
getting worse,
but you'll be doing everything that your
imagination allows you to conceive to
make it worse and worse and worse,
faster and faster.
You know,
when there's a mythological conception
of hell,
and one of the elements of that
mythological conception is that it's a
bottomless pit.
And the reason for that,
I believe,
is that there is nothing that is so
awful that you can't make it worse if
you just try.
So,
and I've seen situations like that a
lot.
I've seen,
you know,
families locked and absolutely homicidal
unconscious battles where every single
person in the family was doing
absolutely everything they could to make
sure that no one was going to escape
from that and that it was going to get a
hell of a lot worse.
So Milton wrote
for whence,
but from the author of all ill could
spring so deep a malice to confound the
race of mankind in one route and earth
with hell to mingle and involve
done all to spite the great creator.
This is Richard the third from
Shakespeare.
I shall despair.
There is no creature loves me.
Yeah.
And if I die,
no,
saul will pity me,
nay.
Wherefore should they.
Since that I myself find in myself,
no pity to myself.
This is social needs.
Solzhenitsyn's description of the
staunch party members.
See,
I guess part of the contamination issue
with something like this is that,
you know,
you might say that one of the
preconditions for existing as a human
being is the ability to tolerate
contamination and anxiety and
imperfection.
You know,
that's certainly something you would
say.
He believed that in some sense you had
to make a pact with that in order to
tolerate exist.
You had to come to terms with that.
But you can fly from that in some sense.
You know,
and then then there's nothing about you
that's contaminated or strange or
disgusting that's all out there.
It's all somewhere else.
It's not you.
You know?
And then you build a wall between you
and that.
And then because that doesn't work,
at least in part,
there's no way of getting rid of the
contamination that the wall gets higher
and higher and more and more people are
on the outside and fewer and fewer of
you are on the,
and you know,
the impulse is to burn up everything
that's contaminated.
Yeah.
You know,
and,
and part of the problem with that,
and I think that this is why you can't
just conceptualize it as discussed,
you know,
cause you can think of that as a natural
territoriality you can think of is
natural and discussed.
You can think of is natural.
But there's something about people that
takes just that step further.
And I think that's the intermingling of
the,
of the contamination,
disgust and fear response with revenge
and resentment and the desire to hurt.
And if you get those things going
together,
especially if you also add in the
propensity to lie man life,
things are going to get really,
really ugly.
They're going to get really bad.
And so you know,
you have to come to terms with the fact
that you carry the contamination around
in you,
so to speak,
everywhere you go.
And that that's an ineradicable part of,
of limited being.
And then you can't be resentful about
that,
are hateful about it because if you are,
then you act in a manner that will
definitely make it worse.
So these,
this is social and it's the stories
about Communist Party loyalists who were
arrested by the gulag system and thrown
into prison,
not happening to them all the time
because no,
it wasn't like the system was plagued by
any real rules.
You know,
in fact it was probably even better as
far as the fundamental motives of the
system are concerned that you are
innocent when you got arrested because
that made it even more miserable and it
would be even funnier if you were
arrested for supporting the system that
was going to arrest you.
It's like that was the perfect form of
vicious ird.
And so that happened a lot to say that
things were painful for them is to say
almost nothing.
They were incapable of assimilating such
a blow,
such a downfall and from their own
people to from their own dear party and
from all appearances for nothing at all.
After all,
they had been guilty of nothing as far
as the party was concerned,
nothing at all.
It was painful for them to such a degree
that it was considered taboo among them.
I'm comradely to ask,
what were you in prison for?
The only squeamish generation of
prisoners.
The rest of us with tongues hanging out.
Couldn't wait to tell the story to every
chance newcomer we met and to the whole
cell.
Cause if we're an anecdote,
here's the sort of people they were.
Olga sleep Oseberg's husband had already
been arrested and they,
which was usually the KGB and usually in
the middle of the night and they had
come to carry out a search and arrest
her too.
The search lasted for hours and she
spent those four hours sorting out the
minutes of the congress of Staccato
vites of the brush,
low and British bristle and brush
industry,
of which she had been the secretary
until the previous day.
The incomplete state of the minutes
troubled her more than her children who
she was now leaving forever.
Even the interrogator conducting the
search could not resist telling her,
come on now,
say goodbye to your children.
Here's the sort of people they were
a letter from her 15 year old daughter
came to yellows,
Loveta cep cova in the cad sound prison
for long term prisoners.
Mama,
tell me why.
Right?
To me,
are you guilty or not?
I hope you weren't guilty because then I
won't join the Komsomol.
So that was a Soviet youth groups,
sort of like the boy scouts or the
brownies,
except it was the communist version.
Because then I won't join the calm
softball and I won't forgive them
because of you.
But if you are guilty,
then I won't write you anymore and I
will hate you.
And the mother was stricken by remorse
in her damp grave,
like sell within its with it's dim
little lamp.
How could her daughter live without the
Komsomol?
How could she be permitted to hate
Soviet power battery that she should
hate me?
And so she wrote,
I am guilty.
Enter the Komsomol.
How could it be anything but hard?
It was more than the human heart could
bear to fall beneath the beloved acts
and then to have to justify its wisdom.
But that's the price of man pays for.
Interesting is God given sole to human
dogma.
Even today,
any orthodox communist will affirm that
set Cova acted correctly even today.
They cannot be convinced that this is
precisely the perversion of small
forces,
that the mother perverted her daughter
and harmed her soul.
Here's the sort of people they are.
They were yt gave sincere testimony
against her husband,
anything to aid the party.
Oh,
how one can pity them if at least now
they had come to comprehend their former
wretchedness,
the whole chapter.
This whole chapter could have been
written quite differently if today,
at least they had forsaken their earlier
views,
but it happened the way Maria Daniel and
had dreamed it would.
If I leave here someday,
I'm going to live as if nothing
happened.
Loyalty
in our view,
it's just plain pigheadedness.
These devote to the theory of
development,
construed loyalty to that development to
mean renunciation of any personal
development whatsoever.
As Nikolai Adamovich villain,
chuck said,
after serving 17 years,
we believed in the party and we were not
mistaken.
Is this loyalty or pigheadedness?
No,
it was not for show and not out of
hypocrisy that they argued in the cells
and defensive all the government's
actions.
They needed ideological arguments in
order to hold on to a sense of their own
rightness.
Otherwise,
insanity was not far off.
You know,
people build memorials now they bowed
hoke Holocaust memorials.
There's a Holocaust memorial in
Washington and there's a Holocaust
memorial in Berlin.
And you know,
the,
the Motif for the slogan of those
memorials is we shall never forget.
And I think
you can't remember something you don't
understand.
Okay.
You can say you're not going to forget
all you want,
but
unless you understand what happened,
you can't remember it.
And we don't understand what happened,
you know?
And as far as I can tell,
you know,
the most important thing that happened
in the entire 20th century with regards
to evidence for,
for,
you know,
absolute existential catastrophes that
threatened the human rates at the
individual level and at the,
and at the state level and at the
international level,
it's all whatever it was that produced
the Nazis and that produced the Soviets
and the produced the Maoist.
And that hasn't gone away.
And that's partly because we don't
understand it,
you know?
And from what I've been able to tell,
and this is partly why teach you guys
about the existentialists and the
phenomenologists,
because they're not covered very often
in personality classes anymore.
It's because I do believe,
I do believe that there's,
I do believe it was demonstrated by
those who throw it through most
carefully,
that there is a direct causal
relationship between individual ethical
corruption.
And I can define that the corruption is
when the individual does something that
they know themselves by their own
standards to be wrong.
It's not a relativistic claim at all and
it doesn't really have much to do with
the truth.
It has to do with false hood cause I
don't think people can identify the
truth,
but I know they can identify false hood.
So,
and I think that people become corrupt
when they act out actions that they know
by their own moral standards to be
wrong.
And they,
they do the same thing in a Piagetian
sense when they refuse to accommodate to
what they've assimilated.
So if I pick up a piece of information
and it contradicts a dearly cherished
belief and then I refuse to take that
piece of information and transform my
perceptual and belief structures to
account for it,
then I'm doing the same thing.
That's willful blindness.
And that makes you smaller and smaller.
And the world more and more out of your
control and you weaker and weaker and
more likely to be paranoid and angry and
hurt.
And I also don't think that the
connections between people and the
society are as abstract and distant as
we think.
Because you might think,
well what the hell difference could it
possibly make?
You know,
the way I behave,
it's like,
well you're a node in the network.
You're not an individual connected by a
linear line to another individual
connected to a linear line by another
individual in line that's 7 billion
people long that would make you nothing.
You can just pull you out and you know
the line would reclose and that would be
the end of that.
You're a node in the network and the
networks communicating and we know for
example,
that you know you're roughly going to
interact with in some serious way a
thousand people in your lifetime.
That's a minimum minimum estimate,
you know,
so,
and all those people know a thousand
people.
So that's a million people that are one
person away from you and two people away
from you is a billion people.
And you know,
as soon as you get to three,
well that's far more people than there
are.
So you know,
you're only three or four or five
connections away from everyone.
And so it's very,
very difficult to know exactly how your
behaviors and misbehaviors echo and
ripple,
you know,
and we know that people can be
tremendous forces for good.
We know that because we do see people
like that from time to diamond.
We certainly know plenty about the
reverse and so god only knows what,
what role you play in determining,
you know,
whether the,
the part and the whole of mankind goes
seriously wrong or seriously right.
But I wouldn't dismiss it as a fantasy
from everything I've seen.
You know,
what you do definitely,
definitely affects your family and what
your family does definitely affects the
community and what the community does
definitely affects the state.
Like it doesn't take much rippling for
these things to start to have the facts,
you know,
it doesn't,
for example,
it doesn't take that many people in a
country to cheat on their income tax
before the whole damned economy falls
apart.
I doubt if it's more than 10% you know,
and it's pretty,
it's a miraculous that there are
countries where that doesn't happen.
Yeah
but there are,
God only knows why.
So
anyways,
it's worth thinking about,
you know,
cause people ask questions like,
well what,
you know,
does life have any meaning?
I can tell you one meaning that it has
like it's perfectly reasonable for you
to devote yourself to not producing any
more suffering than is absolutely
necessary because I don't care what you
think about meaning in the absence of
positive meeting,
it's pretty damn hard.
Tend to die you pain and you know you
could at minimum live in such a way that
you're least likely to create mayhem in
misery.
So you know,
maybe that's not enough,
but at least it's a start.
And I certainly know that if you don't
decide to live that way,
the probability that you can cause
serious trouble is extraordinarily high.
And so you got to ask yourself,
is that what you want?
You know,
cause it is sometimes what people want.
So I think it's an abdication of
responsibility and I think it's
resentful and week to do that.
So I think there's no,
there's nothing in it but,
and weakness.
Okay.
So that ends the philosophical part of
the course roughly speaking,
cause you can't separate philosophy from
anything because philosophy is about
what things mean.
And even though we're going to go into
psychometrics now and we're going to go
into biology.
Okay.
It's all building the same edifice.
So I'm,
I'm going to,
I'm going to start to talk to you a
little bit today about psychometrics
now.
Okay.
I doubt very much that any of you
decided to go into psychology because of
psychometrics.
Like that's the theory of measurement.
Basically.
It's,
you know,
it's kind of dry.
The theory of measurement.
It certainly wasn't something I was
enamored of when I was,
uh,
an undergraduate or a graduate student,
you know?
Um,
but then as I started to dig into things
and started to try to really understand
them and you know,
and understand means that you can use
the knowledge that you have to do
something valuable with that sort of
what understanding seems to me to be,
the thing I kept running into was the
fact that measurement is everything in
psychology.
As a science it's everything.
Because if you don't know what you're
measuring,
you have no idea what you're up to.
And then it gets worse because it turns
out that measuring things,
especially psychological things is
really,
really hard.
And so psychologists do it badly all the
time.
And sometimes it's because they just
don't know what the hell they're doing.
And sometimes it's,
it's willful blindness and sometimes
it's blind careerism and it's those two
things a lot.
And so one of the things I want to do
with you and for you for the remainder
of the course is to well teach you some
biology.
You know,
some neurobiology because actually there
have been some real biological
psychology geniuses and they've
outlined,
you know,
the,
the stigma of brain function quite
nicely and in a way that I think is
really interesting to know about and
that's important and useful.
But also to familiarize you with the
basic concepts of psychometrics because
you'll be armed against stupidity that
way.
And it's really useful to be armed
against stupidity.
And that's especially the case if any of
you are interested in science or if
you're interested in psychology as a
science.
Now how many of you are interested in
psychology?
Has a science,
okay,
so there's a substantial number of you
and I presume that some of you are
interested because maybe you hope to
make a career of it or you know,
or at least to finish your degree as a,
you know,
a psychologist with biological
orientation.
So either way you need to know,
you need to know what we're going to
learn in the next couple of weeks.
And the first thing you have to really
come to terms with is how the hell do
you know something is real?
That's a measurement problem.
You know now the people that we've been
talking about have been concerned about
that too.
And they argue about it because some of
them are more like objective material
scientist and some of them are more like
phenomenologists and so everybody's sort
of concerned with,
well what's the nature of the real?
But scientists have an additional
concern,
which is,
well how do you measure it?
And it's not a secondary concern.
The measurement is everything.
It's everything.
You can't get anywhere without the
measurement.
So then you think,
well what are people like?
You know,
what are people like?
Do they have beliefs?
Do they have attitudes?
Do they have values?
Do they have personalities?
Do they have emotions too?
They have motivations.
Do they have cognitions?
Do they have behaviors?
How do you separate those from one
another?
It's like,
good luck with that.
And then like how do you,
how do you assess them at micro and
macro levels?
How do you conceptualize them?
Like what's a unit of behavior?
That's a really difficult thing to
figure out her what's of value and is
what you value independent of your
personality?
Well,
what's your personality or what's a
trait?
You know,
and it's,
it's a complete mess.
It's,
it's,
it's something that's chasing its own
tail constantly.
It's been very difficult for
psychologists to come to terms about
this now.
So I can tell you something about
measurement theory first.
So one thing you might ask yourself is
like,
how is it that you determine what's real
in the world?
Okay.
So the first thing you might think about
is while this is an empirical idea,
you have census.
And so a radical in Paris in Paris would
say you get all the information about
the world from your senses.
So it's sense data.
Okay?
So,
so then you might notice and you might
think,
well,
okay,
let's say since data provides you with a
picture of the world and let's even go
one step farther and let's say,
well,
it,
it provides you with a picture of the
reality of the world.
Then you might say,
well,
how many senses do you need?
And it's one high enough while we have
two eyes.
So one eye doesn't seem to have been
enough for people.
And then,
okay,
it's two eyes and then,
but it's not just two eyes,
it's two eyes in hearing and then it's
not just two eyes and hearing it's two
eyes.
Hearing,
smell,
taste and touch.
Yeah.
Okay.
So That's interesting.
So what that means is evolution has
calculated that for a,
for a beast like you,
you need five dimensions of evaluation
before you can be certain that something
is real.
You can't rely on one.
You know,
you can't rely on too.
Now if you can see something and hear
it,
you're,
it's much more likely to be real.
Then if you can just see it or just hear
it.
But if you can see it and hear it and
touch it,
it's like at that point it takes a
pretty damn sneaky thing to fool you.
And then if you add taste and smell to
that,
it's like,
well,
what we've figured out is that enough?
If you could,
if you get those five things working,
you probably won't die.
And that's a good measurement of whether
that's sufficiently real.
Okay.
So That's interesting.
So your your sensory Operandi,
our measurement devices,
but you don't just need one,
you need five and then you think,
well are those the same or different?
Now it turns out that's a complicated
question because although this may not
seem obvious,
two things can be the same and different
in an infinite number of ways.
So one of the things you might say is,
well what makes,
why do you put two things in the same
category?
And you'll say,
well because they're similar.
It's like,
well actually that turns out not to be.
Why?
Because they're similar and different in
an infinite number of ways.
And so you can't use that as a basis for
categorization.
Plus it's just circular.
You put similar things in a category
because categories contains similar
things,
not helpful,
not helpful.
So
when you're trying to zero in on
something,
not only do you need to sense it,
but you need to use sentences that in
some sense are qualitatively different
from one another.
So you might,
you might almost think about them is
uncorrelated isn't exactly the right
phrase,
but they're different methodological
techniques.
So,
for example,
your eyes rely on light waves,
right?
And then your ears rely on sound waves.
And those are quite different.
They don't even interfere with each
other to any,
to any real degree.
And so that means what you're getting is
information from two independent
sources.
So that's helpful.
But then if you,
if you smell something or more
accurately,
if you taste something,
I don't know if you know this,
but it seems to be the case that taste
is a molecular phenomena that you know
that when you taste something,
you're actually assessing it.
I'm a molecular level and there might be
as many tastes in some sense,
or at least as many smells.
Cause you're sensing that at a molecular
level and smell is more complex as there
are substances.
Now,
people aren't quite sure about that,
but it's,
you know,
it's pretty,
it differentiates a lot.
And so you're detecting molecular
signatures with your nose and then with
your hands,
you're detecting the electron shells on
the outside of your fingertips are
pushing against the electron shells of
solid surfaces and they can't push
through.
And so that's basically what you're
detecting.
You're detecting the elect surface of
electrons more,
more or less,
and you can't push through it.
And so that's,
that's a different way of,
it's a different way of determining
whether or not something is real.
And so the reason I'm telling you this
is because there,
there was a famous set of papers
published in the 1950s by a researcher
named [inaudible] and another researcher
named meal.
And they were trying to figure out how
in the world should psychologists figure
out what a phenomena,
what phenomena is real.
You know,
it's the same question in some sense
that the chemists had disordered out,
but they sorted that out.
They got the periodic table of the
elements and that was the end of that.
That was a big,
that was a big step forward because they
got their basic,
they got their idea about what the world
was made of,
nailed down pretty damn tight,
and then they could move from that.
But in psychology it's like we have this
problem.
What are the basic phenomena?
Okay.
So what meal and chronback we're trying
to figure out is not so much what the
basic where,
but how it would be that you could go
about figuring out what they were if
they existed and they basically came up
with a strategy that's very similar to
the sense strategy.
So they're hypothesis was you can't
really tell if something is real unless
you can measure it using a variety of
different methods and get the same
answer.
Now the first thing you should remember
is that every psychologist knows this
unless they've been trained
extraordinarily badly.
Cause this is a key paper.
Okay.
It's a key paper of what's called
construct validation.
And a construct is a measurement,
you know?
And so the issue with construct
measurement is how do you construct your
measures so that you know they're
measuring something real.
It's not something peripheral.
You got to get this right.
And the rule from chronback in meal was
multi method multi-method.
Now there's a bit of a problem there
because it's not exactly clear when
you're using the same method and when
you're using a different method.
You know,
like if I,
if I say I filled out a questionnaire
about your personality and then you
filled out a questionnaire about your
personality,
is that the same method or a different
method?
Well there's some similarities and some
differences.
Maybe if I had you fill out a
questionnaire,
you know,
maybe I gave you an electric shock and I
had you fill a questionnaire.
I would about how you felt about that.
And at the same time I measured changes
in your skin conductance cause those
occur because you sweat a bit if you've
been stressed,
maybe I measure your heart rate
acceleration,
you know,
I might notice that when you report,
being unhappy or miserable or angry or
frustrated or disappointed or stressed,
you also show us skin conductance
increase because you're sweating a
little bit and your heart rate goes up.
And then I think,
well I've kind of triangulated on the
phenomena,
we don't know what the phenomena is but
at least we can measure it three
different ways.
It turns out that with heart rate for
example,
it's being damn tricky.
You know,
cause you might think,
well heart rates and objective measures
so you could get at what it index is
quite easily.
So you know,
if you get afraid your heart rate will
go up.
But if you get excited,
your heart rate will go up.
It'll go up if you take cocaine and will
go up if you run.
It's like,
so it's not exactly clear what heart
rate index is indexing.
It turns out that from the psychological
perspective,
the theory has developed to the point
where we,
we,
we assume that when I measure your heart
rate increase to a phenomena that isn't
associated with exercise,
say that what I'm actually assessing is
your bodies.
MMM.
The,
the intensity of your bodies preparation
to do something.
What makes sense,
right?
Why does your heart rate go up to get
more blood to your muscles?
Why?
So that you can go and do something.
So if your heart rate goes up,
it's because you're preparing to do
something.
What?
Well,
it depends on the situation.
So it's not that fine grained a tool,
you know?
So that's that.
That's a measurement problem.
Um,
so you want to measure the thing
multiple ways and you want to hope that
you get the right answer.
Now,
that's what a real scientist does.
A real scientists looks to see that
they've got the damn thing they want to
measure.
They've identified it and that it will
manifest itself across multiple levels
of measurement because then they can
sort of be clear that it's there.
Now this guy,
Jeffrey Gray,
who you're going to read about for the
next lecture,
he's a brilliant scientist and gray.
I love gray because gray,
when gray uses a word,
you know exactly what it means and he's
a behaviorist and those people are known
for precision.
You know,
the philosophers that we've been talking
about in the clinical psychologists,
they take a broad overview of the world
and that can be really useful.
But gray is a master of the reverse,
which is zeroing in on what something
means.
So when he says anxiety,
he usually talks about animals.
He means something specific about it.
He means that there's was a particular
biological circuit that gets activated.
You can measure that a variety of
different ways that it will respond to
the administration of barbiturates,
benzodiazepines,
or alcohol.
Cause those are primary anxie lytics and
that there will be certain behavioral
concomitance that are associated with
that.
So the theory has to work across
multiple levels of analysis,
pharmacological,
physiological,
psychological,
behavioral.
And then he thinks,
okay,
we kind of zeroed in on this.
Maybe we can cautiously move forward.
So Britt,
beautiful,
beautiful way to proceed and you get
results that way.
When he wrote a book called the
neuropsychology of anxiety at 1982 and
he updated it in 1999 and you know that
thing,
that thing stood the test of time
because he was absolutely rigorous in
his definitions and the behaviors were
very good at that.
When they measured something and defined
it,
you knew what it was very good.
Now it turns out that for a lot of the
things that psychologists study,
it's not so straight forward.
You know,
you can't get multiple measures of the
same thing.
And so you have to often,
you have to proceed forward with what
you've got in the hope that you can
accrue additional evidence later.
And I'm going to talk to you in detail
about one such approach and that's been
the psychometric approach with in
relationship to the establishment of the
basic personality traits.
So,
so what happened with the statistical
approach,
because that's primarily what we're
going to talk about is that the initial
discovery of the basic traits was done
only at a statistical level.
And then what happened was that as the
traits were established statistically
and people got more comfortable with the
idea that they might be real,
then the way they manifested themselves
across different levels of analysis
started to become understood.
So for example,
once I knew that there was such a thing
as extroversion,
I could start to associate certain kinds
of behaviors and certain emotions with
it.
And then I could start to document what
the neurological systems where that that
underpinned it.
And then I could start to understand the
neuro pharmacology and all that stuff
started to stack up.
And that's sort of where we are with
psychometric personality theory.
And the first element of psychometric
personality theory is a hypothesis.
And here here you think this hypothesis
through.
So this,
so imagine that one of the things that
human beings communicate about with
their language is personality.
I'm really interested in describing what
you're like to someone else and you're
interested in describing what I'm like
to someone else.
It helps us keep track of our,
of everyone's relationships and
reputations,
but it also helps us understand their
behavior and we're obsessively curious
about each other.
And it's no wonder because you know,
we're weird and unpredictable things,
but we're kind of useful too.
So the,
so the linguistic hypothesis,
and this is what started the
psychometric,
the psychometric movement forward in the
domain of personality,
there's a linguistic hypothesis and the
linguistic hypothesis is the important
variation in human personality will be
captured by the language.
Okay.
So that's like a hypothesis that the
language is a good measurement device.
We're trying to use the language to
assess and communicate about each other.
And roughly we've,
we've nailed the structure within that
language.
If we could figure out how to extract
it.
Now people debate that,
hey,
because it's not self evident that we
would have captured all the important
variation in personality in our
language,
but it's not a bad hypothesis and you
can test it.
And the way you test it is by deriving
personality based descriptions from an
analysis of natural language and then
seeing how those derived descriptions do
in the real world.
Do it predicting things,
do it being correlated with different
physiological structures,
do at predicting responses to
pharmacological interventions and so
forth and so on.
And the answer to that as being,
hey,
it's done pretty well.
So,
so the first hypothesis is that
important trait variation is
encapsulated in the language.
But there's another hypothesis,
and I'll leave you with this and you
really need to think about this because
psychologists do not get it right and
they should.
It's a sin.
It's a scientific sin not to get this
right.
The big five theorists,
and they're the psychometric guys who
did the language analysis,
they make a claim,
they make a strong claim and a weak
claim.
The strong claim is you can extract out
information about personality from the
language.
It lays itself out in five dimensions.
We'll,
we'll talk about what that means.
Extroversion,
neuroticism,
conscientiousness,
agreeableness and openness and that is
where all the important variation in
personality lies.
Okay?
That's the strong claim.
The weak claim is this.
We're going to forget about the strong
claim because you guys can evaluate that
as we go through it.
The weak claim is this in so far as you
can measure personality with language
and so that means with words or phrases
or sentences in so far as you could
measure it with language,
you're going to measure one or more of
the big five traits well or badly.
Now,
the reason I'm stressing this is so many
of you have taken many psychology
courses so far and you may have noticed
that people measure all sorts of things
with questionnaires.
They measure self esteem.
For example,
they measure self ethicacy.
You know,
they measure authoritarian personality,
they measure any bloody thing you can
think of.
There's going to be a questionnaire with
a name on it,
but the big five theorists say,
hey,
wait a minute.
We've got a hypothesis going here.
If you're using language and you're
measuring traits,
you're measuring one or more of the big
five traits badly or well,
and so what that means,
and no one's challenged this by the way
that the challenges,
we'll do five traits,
completely cover it,
or do we need six or seven?
And then maybe what's the hierarchical
structure?
There's questions about that,
but no one seriously questioned the week
hypothesis.
And so what that means is that all those
things you read about that are measured
by questionnaire
that have all sorts of different names
are elements of the big five that have
either been measured well or badly.
And so what that means is whenever you
read a psychological paper,
and this is something that's
particularly endemic in social
psychology,
no matter what they named the damn
measure,
if it's a questionnaire,
it's extroversion,
neuroticism,
agreeableness,
conscientiousness or openness.
And it's incumbent on the researcher to
prove that that's not the case.
And they don't.
Now,
the reason they don't in parties because
they don't know the psychometric theory.
And then the next reason is they do know
it,
but they ignore it.
And the next reason is if they know it
and ignore it,
then they can invent a construct and
name it something and they can conjure
up a whole career on it.
You don't get to do that.
We know some things exist in psychology,
Iq,
extroversion,
neuroticism,
agreeableness,
conscientiousness and openness.
They exist in so far as you can
encapsulate personality in language and
use statistical techniques to derive it.
Maybe other things exist,
but I don't think there's any credible
evidence that they do.
So.
All right,
so we'll pick that up on Thursday.