Well,
I have a question.
I guess I'd like to know a little bit
more about why you specifically chose
the title,
the master and the emissary.
Yeah.
That,
that's uh,
an attempt to explain what I believe to
be the relationship if he needs and
habits,
fears,
um,
that like most other things in life,
the in equal and asymmetrical and one of
the brain hemispheres sees more than the
other.
That is the one that I've designated the
master and it was the right hemisphere.
That's a weird inversion because people
often think of the left hemisphere is
the one that's dominant.
They do,
they do.
Traditionally that's been the case.
Uh,
but um,
as is becoming ever clearer,
the right hemisphere,
this has been a real steep learning
curve for some people,
but the,
the right hemisphere is in many ways
more reliable,
sees more,
understands more than the left
hemisphere,
which is like a sort of high functioning
bureaucrat.
In a way.
The idea of the story was simply that
certain matters needed to be delegated
not to only because as it were,
the master couldn't do everything.
He needed an emissary to go abroad and
do some of it,
but also that he must not get involved
with a certain point of view.
Otherwise he'd lose what it was if you
did see.
So that's what I'm really saying there
is,
there was a good reason why evolution,
really speaking,
the two brain hemispheres are separate.
And when you see it doesn't get
involved,
what's the advantage of,
of that,
that detachment from the involvement?
Well,
it's that,
um,
Ramonica Hall who you know,
is a great histopathologist.
Yep.
Um,
one of his findings was in primates are
more inhibitory neurons and then any
other animals.
And there are more in humans than in any
other primate.
And um,
there are many more being in
proportionally,
proportionately,
and there are more kinds as well.
So we think that about 25% of the
entire,
um,
cortex is,
is inhibitory,
right?
So it's a very strong effect.
And the Corpus callosum seems to be very
largely in the end inhabiting function
in the other hemisphere.
And that is,
I think,
because over time the two hemispheres of
had to specialize.
There are reasons why actually it can't
be,
I'm not going to go into now,
but I was talking about just a few days
ago.
That'd be evolutionary sake cacciatore
meeting.
But there are reasons way the Corpus
callosum has had to become more
selective and to inhibit quite a lot of
what's going on in the other hemisphere
because it enables the two to do
distinct things.
And of course they have to work
together.
But usually good teamwork doesn't mean
everyone trained to do the same row.
So differentiation is very important for
two elements to work together.
And inhibition is one way of doing that.
So effectively the two takes on the
world if you like,
that the hemispheres have,
are not easily compatible.
Um,
and we're not aware of that because at a
level below consciousness,
there's a metric control center that is
bringing them together.
So in ordinary experience,
we don't feel we're in two different
worlds,
but effectively we are.
And they have different qualities and
different goals,
different values,
different,
different takes on what is important in
the,
in the world.
And what meeting,
let me ask you about,
I,
I've got,
I've developed a conceptual scheme for,
for thinking about the relationship
between the two hemispheres and I'm kind
of,
I've been curious about what you think
about it and how it might map on to or
not you're your ideas.
So I've been really interested in the
orienting reflex and discovered by socal
off,
I think back in about 1962.
Right?
He was a student of Laureus and the
orienting reflexes manifested when
something,
at least in their terminology is
something unpredictable happened.
I've thought much more recently did.
It's actually when something undesired
happened happens and the laboratory
constraints obscured that.
And that turned out to actually be
important.
But,
um,
so,
and I kind of put together the ideas of
the orienting reflects with some of the
things I learned from young young's
observations on the function of art and
dreams.
So imagine that you have a conceptual
scheme laid out,
right?
We could say that it's,
it's,
it's linguistically mediate,
it's enforced on the world.
And then there are exceptions to that,
to that conceptual scheme.
And those are anomalies.
Those are the numbers that are
unexpected and the orienting reflex
orients you towards those.
And so those are things that aren't
fitting property in your conceptual
scheme that you have to figure out.
So the first thing you do is react
defensively essential because it might
be dangerous.
And then your exploratory systems are
activated.
So,
and the exploratory systems,
first of all,
our enhanced attention from an
intentional perspective.
But then,
and this is where the art issue sort of
creeps into it.
It's the idea would be something like
the right hemisphere generates an
imaginative landscape of possibility
that could map that a normally.
So you can kind of experience that if
it's at night,
you know,
like say you're sitting alone at night,
it's two or three in the morning,
you're kind of tired.
Um,
maybe you're in an unfamiliar place and
there's a noise that happens that
shouldn't happen in another room.
You can play with that.
So,
for example,
if you open the door slightly and put
your hand in turn on the light and you
watch what happens,
your mind will fill with imaginative
representations of what might be in the
room,
right?
So it's like the,
the,
the landscape of anomaly will be
populated with something like
imaginative demons.
And that's a first pass approximation.
And it seems to me that that's a right
hemispheric function.
And then that as you explore further
that imaginative domain,
which,
which circumscribes what might be,
is constrained and constrained and
constrained and constrained until you
get what it actually is and that
specialized in routinized.
It's something like that.
Does that seem like a reasonable,
what do you think about that as well
for a whole host of reasons?
Um,
one is,
you mentioned a defense and one of the
ideas behind my hypothesis is that the
right hemisphere is on the lookout for
predators,
right?
Whereas the left hemisphere is looking
for prey.
And this has been confirmed in many
species,
have never heard that second part,
amphibians and mammals.
Yes.
Um,
uh,
so,
so when you're in left hemispheric mode,
you're more in Predator mode and when
you'd wave home as well,
I mean,
of course we are not uh,
lizards or toads or marmosets or
whatever.
But in animals,
generally speaking,
this is the case getting and grasping.
And after all our left hemisphere is the
London.
It controls the grasping hand,
his left hemisphere and uh,
exploring which you mentioned is more
right hemisphere.
And when the,
when a frontal function is deficient,
um,
people often go into sematic mode of the
hand of that side and the left hand,
it's usually explorer,
few emotions,
meaningless ones,
but trying to explore the environment
and with the right hand it's grasping
pointlessly at things.
So they,
as it were,
the automatic thing is with the,
with the left hand,
the right hemisphere to explore with the
right hand,
the left hemisphere to grasp.
So when you said exploratory and you
said defense,
and you said also opening up to
possibilities,
these are all aspects of the way the
right hemisphere.
I often say the right hemisphere opens
up to possibility,
whereas the left hemisphere wants to
close down to a certain team and you
need both chaos,
chaos,
and order.
And you knew I loved him.
In your talk,
you talked about um,
uh,
chaos and order,
but if I may say so you've seemed maybe
you'd like to gloss that a little.
You seem to suggest that it would be
good,
we can't get rid of chaos,
but you've seemed to imply that it would
be better if we could,
whereas my view is it chaos and order
unnecessary to one another and there is
a proper sort of harmony
well balanced.
Well,
yeah.
okay.
That mean I think that's,
that's as deep a question as you could
possibly ask.
I would say in some sense some of the,
I would say there's a central
theological issue there.
The issue there is the,
you know,
in genesis the proper environment if
humanity is construed as a garden.
And so I see that as the optimal balance
of chaos and order because nature is
flourishes and it's prolific in his
chaotic,
yeah.
Then if you add harmony to that,
you have the garden.
So you live in the garden,
you're supposed to tend the garden.
Okay,
so now the garden is created.
It's a walled space because eden is a
wallet space.
It's a pair of day side.
So it's a walled garden.
That's it.
Now the thing is,
as soon as you make a wall,
you try to keep what's outside out,
but you can't because the boundaries
between things are permeable.
So if you're going to have reality and
you're going to have a bounded space,
you're going to have a snake in the
garden.
Now then the question is,
what the hell should you do about that?
Should we make the walls so high that no
snake can possibly get in or should or
should you allow for the possibility of
snakes,
but make yourself strong enough so that
you can contend with them?
And I think there's,
there's an answer there that goes deep
to the question of even maybe why
theological question of why God allowed
evil to exist in the world.
I agree with you.
It's like,
well,
do you make people safe or strong?
And strong is better and safe might not
be commensurate with being like,
it might not be possible to exist and to
be safe.
Well,
so existence is predicated on the fact
that we die.
Well was never safe.
Well it's certainly bounded,
right?
Yeah.
I mean it's inevitably wrapped up with
that sort of finitude.
So there's this old,
there's a lovely,
lovely Jewish id and ancient idea.
It's one of the most profound ideas I've
ever come across.
And so it's a kind of a Zen Koan and,
and here it is.
Is that,
um,
so it's a question about the classic
attributes of God,
Omniscient,
omnipresent,
omnipotent.
What is it being with those three
attributes?
Lock,
what kind of question is that?
The answer is limitation.
And the second answer is that's the
justification for being is that the
unlimited lacks the limited.
Exactly.
And so because limited is us
for anything to come into existence and
needs to be an element of resistance.
And so things are never predicated on
one pole of what is always a dipo.
Everything is,
has that,
uh,
diapers.
Yeah,
it's like a prerequisite for being,
it is and it's imaged in the yen,
yen idea.
Um,
but it seems to me very important
because in our culture we often seem to
suppose that certain things are just
good and other things are just about,
it'd be good if we could get rid of the
bad ones,
but actually my pursuing certain good
things that are good within measure too
far,
they become bad and so forth.
But let's go back to her and normally
thing because Ramachandran calls the
right hemisphere the anomaly detection.
And so I think that that's a very
important point because there are two
ways you can react to an anomaly.
One is two and both have to be explored.
One is to try and prove that it's not
really an anomaly and therefore you can
carry on with things as normal.
And the other is hopeful that that's,
that's the,
that's the typical left hemisphere
approach.
It doesn't want anything to have to
shift and quite reasonably,
you don't want to be chaotically
shifting if you're onto a good thing.
Too stressful.
Exactly.
That takes too much work.
And you might actually be mistaken.
So in a way it's perfectly correct to be
wary,
but it's not correct to be so wary that
you blot out anomalies.
And there's a lot of evidence,
as I'm sure you know,
the left hemisphere simply blocks out
everything that doesn't fit with it's
cheap.
It doesn't see it actually.
You're tall.
So it's a hugely important element and
the right hemisphere going hang on.
But the maybe another way of thinking
that will accommodate this better and
actually good science needs yes.
To be skeptical about anomalies,
otherwise there'd be chaos,
but it also needs to be able to shift.
And when an anomaly is really large
enough,
right,
right.
Quite a lot of them.
And they don't really fit very well
into.
Exactly,
yes.
Yes.
So there's a,
there's another observation that you
made,
which I loved it.
I loved this observation.
He was trying to account for radical
personality transformation,
right?
And so his idea was this,
and I think it's,
it's,
it's commensurate with the ideas of
inhibition between the two hemispheres.
So let's imagine the left is habitually
inhibiting the function of the right to
keep fear under control.
It does that all sorts of ways,
but so imagine that the right is I'm
reacting to anomalies and it's
aggregating them.
Okay.
The left camp deal with them.
So the right is aggregating anomalies
and maybe that's starting to manifest
itself in nightmarish dreams.
For example.
It's like all these anomalies are piling
up.
It's indication that you're on shifting
sound.
Also then imagine that the right
hemisphere aggregates normally is and
then it starts to detect patterns in the
anomalies and so now it starts to
generate what you might consider a
counter hypothesis to the left type
offices.
If that counter or hypothesis gets to
the point where the total sum in some
sense of the anomalies plus the already
mapped territory can be mapped by that
new pattern,
then at some point it will shift and the
person will kick into a new personality
consideration.
It's like a Piagetian stage transition
except more dramatic.
It is.
And what a Ph [inaudible] stage
physician is also like and subsumes both
is he galean uh oh fable.
The idea that,
um,
uh,
thing is opposed by something else,
but when it,
when there is a synthesis,
it's not that one of them is an
isolated,
they're both transformed and taken up
into the new hoe,
which embraces
before look like look like an
opposition.
Here's a question for you.
You know,
when I read Thomas Kuhn and I was
reading top piaget at the same time and
I knew that piaget was aware of Kuhn's
work by the way end.
The problem I had with Kuehne and the
interpretation interpreters of coon is
they don't seem to get something who,
who,
who interpret Kuhn has a moral
relativist in some sense.
They don't seem to get the idea of um,
increased generalized ability of a
plant.
So let's say I have a theory and a bunch
of anomalies,
a crew and I have to wipe out the
theory.
And so then I wipe out the theory and I
incorporate the anomalies and now I have
another theory.
So that's a descent into chaos.
That's my estimation.
That's the old story.
So the anomaly,
yeah,
disruption is the mythical descend into
chaos.
And then you reconfigure this theory
with the chaos and you come up with a
better theory.
Okay,
the question,
why is it better?
And the answer is what accounts for
everything that the previous theory,
accountants plus the anomalies.
So there's progress.
Yes,
exactly.
And but coon is often read is stating
that there is no progress that you know
there's incommensurate paradigms and you
have to just shift between them.
But there isn't,
there isn't cumulative knowledge in some
sense.
Well I think one thing that when we
probably would both agree about is that
we don't buy the story that you need
because nothing can be demonstrated
definitively,
utterly to be the case.
There is no truth.
I mean I think we both believe that
there are truths,
things that are true or than other
things.
And indeed,
if we're where we couldn't even talk and
we,
if we did,
and even to say that there are no truth
is itself a truth statement,
which is,
it's truer than the statement.
There are truths so everybody
automatically has truth whether they
know it or not.
Yeah.
Just because you were you,
you said why?
I don't think,
it's not only that you can't talk,
you can't even see no,
cause you don't know how to,
you wouldn't know how to discriminate
what coming into your brain.
So it's inevitable.
Um,
uh,
I think we would agree about that,
but I think that there's maybe a slight
point of difference between us in the
time I'm very willing to,
uh,
embrace the idea of uncertainty.
And I,
I maybe wrong,
perhaps you could expand on that,
but sometimes you come across as,
as a man who has certainties that
well,
it's a peculiar kind of certainty.
I'm certain that standing on the border
between order and chaos is a good idea.
That's a weird,
exactly.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Now you need to be in the sort of
slightly unstable position.
Yes.
You have to.
How do you have to be,
um,
what would you say?
Encountering as much uncertainty as you
can voluntarily tolerate?
Yeah,
but I think that's equivalent to
Vygotsky's zone of proximal development.
So when we talked a little bit earlier
about the idea of an instinct for
meaning.
So I think what meaning is,
it's,
it's the elaborated form of the
orienting reflex,
but what meaning does its function,
its biological function,
which I think is more real in some sense
than any other biological function is to
tell you when you're in the place where
you've balanced the stability,
let's say of your left hemisphere
systems with the exploratory capacity of
your right.
So that not only are you master of your
domain,
but you're expanding that domain
simultaneously.
And when you,
I think that when you're there and it's
a,
it's a,
it's a kind of a metaphysical place in
some sense that you're imbued with a
sense of meaning and purpose.
And that's an indication that you've
actually optimized your neurological
function.
Yes.
And the pimps,
we could gloss the idea of purpose
because I think there's
a difference between,
people get very confused.
I think about the idea of purpose,
particularly
whether there's a problem that
suggesting there is a purpose and I
believe there is a purpose or they're,
our purpose is to the cosmos.
Not just to me and suggest that somehow
it's all been predetermined by God.
But this is to misunderstand the nature
of time,
that there are time static slices and
God is there and he's sorted it all out
and the whole thing is just unfolding as
Bergson says like ladies fan being
unfurled.
It was extremely boring and,
and,
and an entirely static and noncreative
universe.
But actually something is at stake.
Things are unfolding.
They have overall a direction,
but actually exactly what that direction
is isn't known.
And I know it's a fool who says anything
positive about the nature of God,
but I'm not convinced that God is
omniscient and omnipotent either.
I think God is in the process of is
becoming,
God is not only just becoming but is
becoming family.
So being and becoming more,
becoming,
becoming as important thing.
Why do you think that it's also a
strange segue,
I mean I'm not criticizing,
but I'm curious what,
what drove you to that conclusion?
An awful lot of thing is really,
um,
I think that everything is,
is a process.
In fact,
I'm writing a book called,
there are no things,
there are processes and there are
patterns.
That's why I think music is so powerful.
Music is one of the most mysterious and
wonderful things in the universe and I
didn't think it was a tool foolish of
people to have thought that the,
you know,
plan a few motions were in a song.
No,
no,
no.
It's great.
It's the kind of music,
I think it is a very important insight.
Music,
you know I've said this in public
lectures that music is the most
representative of the arts
and music describes how those parents
should be arranged.
You're using representative in a very
different way.
It depends on what you mean by
representing the ultimate reality of the
cosmos.
Well I would like to say presented in or
that it's not representing anything.
It is actually when we're in the
presence of music,
something is coming into being,
which is,
which is at the core of the whole cosmic
process.
I think that's why people love music.
I,
they do and I mean I just hardly any
originality in the idea cause lots of
visitors say this,
that the sort of the movement of atoms
and the movement of planets and so
forth,
uh,
are more like a dance or more music than
they are like things bumping in track.
Right,
right,
right.
Um,
so uh,
kind of things as patterns that people
have made into tools.
I agree with you and tools and what the
left hand is who is always looking for.
It's always looking for something new to
grasp it.
Ray phase processes that if you,
it's all a matter of time.
Every single thing including the
mountain behind my house,
if you able to,
which is billions of years old,
if you were able to take,
as it were a series of like a time lapse
camera,
you'd see the thing morphing and
changing and flowing.
Everything flows as eric takes is one
second.
Everything flows.
It's just a question of over the time
period that you consider it.
It's a question of the time.
And so taking time out of things and
considering them in the abstract you
resonated from context,
particularly from the flow and from the
context of time changes them into
something else.
And I think that what,
uh,
in brief what Plato has done and what a
lot of the history of more recent
Christianity has done is two things,
defy God and have an perfect states that
are unaltered and torn.
And I think that it is an ever,
ever more wonderfully self
self exploring self actualizing process
that requires a degree of opposition as
a stream in order to have the movements
and the,
the,
the ideas and patterns in it.
It has to be constrained deck
when I've experienced want,
it's hard to describe these experiences
but when I've contemplated death deeply,
it's his struck me as a,
as a fundamental repair mechanism.
Like it's part of the mechanism by which
new things that are better are brought
into being.
Absolutely.
And I mean you see that in your own
being because of course without death
you couldn't live because you're dying.
The things about you that aren't right,
even at a physiological level are dying
all the time.
They are unfortunately,
you also completely die,
which used to be a bit of the
unfortunate side but more cosmically
speaking.
It does seem to me that death is the is
I dunno man,
I s it's,
I've had intuitions are intimations that
death is the friend of being and that's
like,
it's hard to get my head around that.
Pete,
do you agree with you and indeed that's
being said by the many,
many ways of people then than myself and
maybe even the yourself.
No,
but I mean I think that that's right,
that death is predicated on life,
but also that it shouldn't be seen as a
sort of something that's the negative.
It's,
it's a necessary stage in the process of
being,
becoming what it is and since everything
is ramified since nothing,
it's just isolated.
You and I may look or feel as though,
but as you often eloquently say,
we all have the history and we,
we have in time,
we come from a place,
but also as a culture,
we have history.
We can't detach ourselves from it were
expressions of it,
but we're also inevitably dependent as
all organisms are on the environment
where I end and where the quote
environment begins is,
uh,
I didn't like the word environment
nature,
which would suggest something that's
always been born whereas environments
around me from which I'm separate.
But anyway,
all of that is connected supposed to.
Yes.
So I would see us as like an idiot in a
stream or like a wave in the seed that
he was never separate
the coming together of physics with,
with this,
with a process philosophy,
a very strong,
when does that book come out?
When I finished writing
and I'm very worried that um,
it's getting bigger and is,
you know,
all the time I'm writing it,
I'm seeing more and more of things that
I am really must get to know more about.
It's an ever receding.
Um,
well it's a danger of a book that I know
that aims at something fundamental
because every run you never hit the
proper boundaries as it,
I need that war.
I also had experiences,
I would say when I was trying to
understand as they're imaginative
experiences,
when I was trying to understand,
let's say the necessity of evil.
No,
because that's also a fundamental
theological conundrum and a metaphysical
conundrum.
How,
why isn't that being as constituted such
that evil is allowed to exist,
right?
It's Ivan Carrabba's Arvs.
What critique of our valley,
Osha's Christianity essentially what
kind of God would allow for this sort of
thing.
The ancient question.
Yeah,
it's an ancient question and I mean,
part of what I thought,
what I've,
I mean I thought about the adversarial
element to that,
which is that you need to challenge
because you don't,
you're not forced to bring forth what
you could bring forth without a
challenge and the greater the thing that
you're supposed to bring forth,
the greater of the challenge has to be
so you need an adversary,
something like that.
But then I also thought that it would,
it's possible that that,
that being being requires limitation.
You might say optimal being requires
sprite,
free choice.
I know I'm going through a lot of things
quickly.
Free choice requires the real
distinction between good and evil.
Without that,
you don't have choice.
Well,
so maybe it's possible to set up a world
where evil is a possibility,
but where it isn't something that has to
be manifest,
you know,
where,
where it's an option open to you and a
real option and it has to be,
and the challenge that was presented to
you,
but it's something that you can not,
you can not move towards if you,
so if you,
so desire,
and that seems to me to be something
like the eth ethical requirement that
that's the fundamental ethical
requirement to avoid evil.
Doesn't mean it shouldn't exist.
It's not the same issue.
No,
it isn't.
It isn't.
Um,
an I,
I under one could recount it as the need
for otherness.
It goad,
need something other and that other,
if it's not going to be just part of God
has got to be free,
otherwise we'll be no creation.
I mean,
the,
the nature that there is something other
than,
than God.
Um,
it may in the end come from and come
back to,
right.
That God,
we know that divine essence or that
whatever,
but there's a wonderful thing I can't
figure out either.
Like in,
in the Christian idea,
there's the end of time where the,
the evil is separated from God forever.
And I think about that as a
metaphysical,
well,
you might think if it's a form of like
imagined,
it's a form of perfection,
a form of striving for perfection.
You fragment yourself,
you challenge yourself,
throw what's not worthy into the fire,
a lasting,
something like that.
And so what it,
what you end up with retained as much
better than what you started with
through the trials.
Something like that.
Well,
that sounds a bit like the dialectical
process that we've been talking.
And you have alluded to a couple of very
good,
um,
Jewish,
myths and there's one in the [inaudible]
Kavala,
um,
about the creation,
which I don't know if you know it,
but it's,
it's absolutely river thing to me.
Um,
the idea is that the primary being and
is off the ground of all being,
um,
needs something other to come into being
the creation and that creation.
What does that ends off do?
It was this his first act as it to
stretch out your hand and make something
not a bit.
The first act is to withdraw,
to create a place in which the canvas
something other than dance off.
And so the first stage is called Sim.
Solomon as it sounds negative,
as so many creative things do withdraw.
And then in that space the uh,
vessels and a spark comes out of ames
off and falls into the vessels and they
will shatter.
And that's called a chef a how can
you write?
Yes.
And then there is the third stage repair
in which,
um,
what has just been fragmented is
restored into something greater.
And so this process carries on and it's
in my terms,
very light.
What happens with the hemisphere.
The right hemisphere is the one that is
first accepting.
It is sort of actively receptive,
if you can put it that way too.
Whatever is new.
You were talking about Algorithm
Goldberg and so,
um,
and then whatever that is is then sort
of processed by the left hemisphere at
the next stage into categories.
So it's bit of that and try to
understand it,
but of course,
whatever it is,
as much bigger than any of the
categories.
So they all break down and it gets
restored and the right hemisphere into a
new hole.
Um,
the,
to comb the repair,
right?
Tiq Mti candidate.
And I need the,
the,
the kind of
easy way of thinking about it is
learning a piece of music.
Your first of all attracted to it as a
whole.
You then realize that you need to
practice that piece at Bar 28 and you
realize that,
you know,
at,
at bar 64,
there's a return to the dominant or
something.
And,
uh,
then actually when you go on stage,
you've got to,
um,
just forget all about that.
But it's not that that work was lost,
it's just that it's no longer present.
Right,
right.