Okay.
So now we're going to talk about the
phenomenological existential slash
phenomenological psych guy trusts and
their theories from the 1950s.
And as I mentioned to you before,
a lot of their thinking was motivated by
what had happened did in World War II.
When I,
when I lecture to you last,
I,
I pointed out,
I described Nietzschean Dostoyevsky's
summation of the world situation and
really the world psychological situation
at the end of the 18 hundreds.
And that was that
our new modes of thinking had undermined
our faith and our old modes of thinking.
And that was a problem because people
need something firm to stand on,
to orient themselves and to move
forward.
And so Nietzschean Dostoyevsky basically
both prophesied that the consequence of
that dissolution would be,
um,
increased probability of nihilism and
everything that went along with that.
And Dusty Yefsky wrote about that
actually quite extensively in a book
called notes from underground,
which if any of you are interested,
especially in clinical psychology,
that's a book you should really read
because it's one of the most brilliant
psychological studies of,
uh,
of a,
of a psychologically disturbed man
that's ever been written.
It's very accurate.
And there are sections in crime and
punishment that are like that too.
I think there are unsurpassed in their
representation of,
of psych,
of psychological phenomenon.
That was,
I don't,
I don't know how he managed it.
I mean Dostoyevsky was epileptic,
I don't know if you know that,
but he,
um,
he was arrested by the czar's men in the
late 18 hundreds for being a student
radical and they threw him in the main
prison in Moscow.
And then one day they took him out in
front of a firing squad and shot him at
six in the morning,
but they only use blanks,
which of course he didn't know about.
And that scared him so badly.
He developed epilepsy and then he had
epilepsy.
That can happen by the way,
um,
at Andy had epilepsy for the rest of his
life,
but he had this strange kind of
epilepsy,
which is actually not all that rare.
Um,
sometimes when people have epilepsy,
they experienced this phenomena.
They call an aura,
which is an altered state of
consciousness before the epileptic
seizure hits.
And they can be very strange these
auras.
So I read a case study once about a guy
who,
um,
his aura was that his hand was being
possessed by devils from hell and he
could feel the possession move up his
arm and into his shoulder.
And once it hit his head,
he'd have an epileptic seizure.
And so then there was another case,
um,
where,
where this man,
his aura was that his exact double had
appeared behind him.
But if you turn and if you turned to
look,
then you'd have an epileptic seizure.
But if he didn't turn to look,
then he wouldn't.
So these,
you know,
brain disorders are very strange things
because they're,
well,
the system that is disordered is alive
and it's capable of any number of
extraordinarily peculiar misbehaviors.
Anyways,
Dostoyevsky's aura was a world revealing
aura.
And so what Dostoyevsky would experience
was that the meaning of things got
deeper and deeper and deeper and deeper
and deeper.
And then just as he was on the verge of
discovering the secret to everything,
he'd have an epileptic seizure.
But he said that the quality of
experience during the aura was so high,
so overpowering,
and so deep that he would've traded all
of his normal experience just to have
had those experiences.
And he had them repeatedly.
And I really do believe that it was this
broadening of his,
of his vision and concept by his
epilepsy that transformed them.
Among other things.
I mean,
he went through some pretty damn rough
experiences because he was in prison
with rapists and murderers for a long
time in Siberia,
even though he was kind of an
aristocratic guy.
I mean,
he had a,
he had a rough time of it.
And I imagine that that also broadened
him tremendously given that it didn't
kill him.
But,
um,
I really do believe that the epileptic
insight was key to his,
like his unsurpassed genius.
And so,
and the his aura and other people do
experience epileptic aura symptoms like
that by the way.
And some people are so enamored of the
aura that they won't take their
antiepileptic epilepsy medication
because they don't want to forego the
experience that precedes the aura or the
actual,
our actual epileptic seizure.
So Dostoyevsky's experiences,
the op element of the aura is also
relevant to what we're going to talk
about today because both been swagger
and boss,
we're very interested in how meaning
revealed itself in the world.
And they had an,
they had opposing explanations.
I actually think they're parallel
explanations.
But um,
the meaning that Dostoyevsky experienced
is,
is an amplification of the normal manner
in which meaning reveals itself in the
world.
So I mean,
and people experience that sort of thing
in,
in various altered states of
consciousness.
It's been swearing or in boss.
So they work mostly in the 1950s.
And as I said,
they were very concerned about what had
happened in world war two.
And so Dostoyevsky and Nichi had
basically predicted that it was going to
be nihilism or ideological
totalitarianism.
And that's basically exactly what
happened.
And by,
by the time the 1930s appeared on the
horizon,
the Germans who had been,
you know,
they'd gone through an absolutely brutal
first world war and then they went
through hyperinflation of insane
proportion.
So in the 1920s Germany underwent this
partly because they had such heavy war
debts to pay for World War One.
The German German inflation got to the
point where it was literally upwards of
100 million marks to buy a loaf of
bread,
you know,
so they were taking wheelbarrows full of
money to the grocery stores.
You know,
what happened was their currency
devalued to zero.
And you know,
that actually happens to economies more
often than you might think.
So the thing just hit zero and that's
that.
And then it has to be rebooted,
so to speak.
So they had been,
the war was dreadful in hundreds of
thousands of men were killed or
brutalized.
Then their economy just absolutely fell
apart.
And then of course,
at the same time,
well a little bit earlier,
the revolution had taken place in
Russia.
Right.
You know,
right.
At the end of the first world war and
the communists had come to power and the
communists were agitating all over
Europe and in North America.
And you know,
their goal was to,
to produce a communist revolution that
was worldwide.
And so the Germans were all shorted out
that the communists were going to take
over the country,
which was a perfectly reasonable fear.
And you know,
instead of that,
what happened was that fascism or ropes
and fascism was a form of,
of state and totalitarianism.
And I think the Germans were so
desperate for order by that point,
that,
and that's what the fascists basically
offered them,
at least in theory.
Um,
unfortunately as it turned out,
they offered them a little bit too much
order or maybe a lot too much order and
things went dreadfully south.
But you know,
so then the whole world had to walk
through the horrors of World War Two.
And,
and it was shocking in a variety of
ways,
not only because of the brutality of the
warfare,
but because of the genocidal actions
that took place consciously by the
Nazis.
And you know,
and those actions were in many ways very
difficult to understand,
um,
mean here's why they're particularly
difficult to understand.
There were certainly times where the
brutality that the Nazis employed in
their eradication of their theoretical
enemies far surpassed the necessity for
the mere eradication.
But even worse than that,
so it went past eradication into real
torture constantly.
And not only that,
there are many situations in which the
Nazis,
especially near the end of the war,
they had to decide really whether they
were going to continue exterminating
Jews and Gypsies and homosexuals and all
the people they felt didn't fit into
their culture or whether they were going
to win the war.
And there were decisions they had to
make about the distribution of resources
where if they were going to pursue the
genocidal extermination,
that would mean it would decrease the
probability that they would win.
The war not happened a lot,
especially at the end.
And the Nazis always picked continuing
the extermination.
Now that's pretty damn interesting,
you know,
because you can think,
well on the one hand,
you know,
if,
if they are serving a creed and the
creed is world domination and this is
the extermination processes are
considered a step towards the actual end
point,
which is the establishment of a world
state of fascist world state,
or at least a fascist European state,
then you would think that the
extermination attempts would be
subordinate to that goal if they were
actually pursuing the goal that they
said they were pursuing.
But you know,
there's an old psychoanalytic idea,
which is really worthwhile.
It's like a surgical tool.
And I would say if you're gonna use it
in your own life,
use it carefully because you don't want
to do unnecessary surgery.
And the rule is,
and I think this is union rule,
but I can't remember exactly where I
read it.
If you can't understand why someone is
doing something,
look at the consequences of their
actions,
whatever those might be,
and then infer the motivation from the
consequences.
So if you see someone who seems to be
doing nothing except making everyone
around them and themselves miserable and
you can't understand why,
one of the hypotheses that you might
entertain is that they're trying to make
everyone around them miserable as well
as themselves.
And that's actually their goal.
And it's hard for people to understand
these sorts of things because when we
see phenomena like the columbine
shooters,
you know,
we always assume that the reason that
these people are doing these sorts of
things is for other reasons.
Then the reasons they that the reasons
that appear to motivate them or even the
reasons they say they're doing it
because the columbine killer,
especially the more literate one,
he said exactly why he was doing what he
was doing.
It's not,
it's as clear as it could possibly be.
All you have to do is go online and read
what he said and he tells you what he
was up to.
But people don't like to think that way
because they don't believe that anybody
could be consciously possessed of that
much malevolence without there being
some other kind of cause.
Like,
you know,
he was bullied at school or you know,
he was an outcast and those things were
only vaguely true and they certainly
weren't more true of having them.
They were true of,
you know,
how many people in high school are,
bullied in somewhat outkast?
Jesus,
it must be 10%.
It's probably more like 30 you know,
that doesn't mean that the schools are
blowing up all over,
you know,
all over all the time.
It's a completely insufficient
explanation anyways,
for whatever reason,
you know,
people turn to possession by very,
very strict ideological ideas and you
know,
they were willing to be possessed by
those ideas to the point where they
would undertake actions that you'd think
would be completely impossible for
theoretically civilized people.
You know,
it turned out that those sec actions,
not only,
we're not impossible for civilized
people,
but the people themselves,
you know,
especially in Nazi Germany,
they pretty much knew what the hell was
going on.
You know,
you don't take several million people
out of your population without rumors
spreading,
let's say.
And so,
you know,
we should never forget that Hitler was
elected,
you know,
when he was elected by a large margin
majority too.
It was a landslide vote.
The kind of vote that no modern
democratic leader ever gets.
So,
you know,
although it's difficult to,
it's difficult for people to swallow.
Um,
it's hard not to assign culpability for
what happened in Germany to the society
at every strata.
You can't just dump it on the leaders
and,
and in fact,
one of the things that,
here's,
here's something to think about with
regards to Hitler.
So,
because one of the things you might ask
is how the hell could he be so,
so absolutely compelling to his
audiences.
But here,
here,
I'll give you an explanation.
So let's,
let's make the,
let's make a few assumptions.
The first assumption is there are a lot
of resentful Germans kicking around.
Why?
Well,
they lost the first world war.
That wasn't so good.
And then there were a lot of brutal man
left because they'd been in the trenches
and they'd been shooting,
fighting and shooting at each other
under absolutely aborad conditions for
like years and years.
And so there were plenty of brutalized
men around.
Um,
and then their whole damned economy
collapsed because they were forced into
signing what historians regard is a very
punitive peace treaty.
And so like everything had fallen apart
to a degree that we can't even begin to
imagine.
And so,
you know,
in the 1930s,
the Germans were starting to get back on
their feet and,
and um,
when Hitler came to power,
he started not only to rearm but to ray
industrialize the economy and he was
actually pretty damn good at that.
So now Hitler was a good orator,
but he,
it isn't exactly clear that he was a
coherent philosophical theorize or
although to think of him as stupid as it
is completely missing the point.
He was by no means stupid.
Um,
I wouldn't say that he was particularly
educated,
but he had a very powerfully developed
aesthetic sense and he spent a lot of
his time designing the cities that would
be built after World War II was over in
those cities were generally
conceptualize by him,
has places where the arts or at least a
Nazi version of the arts could flourish,
you know,
so there's no real evidence that what
was wrong with the Nazis was that they
were civilized.
There's more evidence actually I think
that they were too civilized and I'll
talk to you about that later.
But anyways,
you think,
how did Hitler get all these people
under his spell?
Well,
here's a hypothesis that's basically
derived from union thinking.
And I should let you know by the way,
because sometimes young has been accused
of being an anti Semite and there's
various reasons for this,
partly because of what happened during
World War II.
And pardon me,
because I'm,
his theory drew heavily from
Christianity,
although for many other sources as well.
And he did believe that there were
differences in the psychology of people
with different ethnicities.
And now,
you know,
whether that's racist or not,
depends on whether or not you like the
person you're talking to because the
lefties think that there are cultural
differences in they're important.
But if you ever talk about them in the
wrong way,
then you're racist and the right
wingers,
while they just think there are ethnic
differences to begin with.
So it's a tricky,
it's a tricky issue.
If there aren't differences that are
important than who the hell cares about
multiculturalism,
it's not even worth preserving.
And if there are differences,
well then you're stuck with having to
deal with the differences.
So you're basically screwed either way.
So anyways,
young has been the target of many
accusations of antisemitism,
particularly by biographers who were
resentful and clueless and historically
uninformed.
And um,
I would say malevolent fundamentally.
Um,
he worked as a CIA agent,
it was just revealed last year and he,
he,
he provided psychological reports to the
American government on the underlying
psychological structure of the Nazi
leaders for years.
And he never told anybody about that
while he was alive.
It only came to light,
like it only came to light as far as I
know last year or perhaps a year before
that.
So.
So anyways,
the Germans,
you know,
they weren't very happy about the whole
damn situation.
And so when they were aggregating on
Mohs you think,
well what happens when all people get
together in a group?
You know,
when we talked about that last time when
we talked about Kierkegaard is idea that
as soon as you get a bunch of people
together,
no matter how truthful they are,
all as individuals,
instantly the crowd is not a truthful
thing.
And you know,
there,
there are,
there are real reasons for that.
Real psychological reasons.
So there's the famous ash experiments,
I hope that those are the right
experiments.
A S C h about line length,
you know,
so you draw two lines on the board and
they're the same length and you get the
crowd to collaborate with you and you
ask some poor sucker who doesn't know
about the game,
uh,
to play.
And you know,
you ask one person and they say,
no,
those lines are different in length.
And you ask another person,
they say,
well,
yeah,
they're quite different in length.
And another person says,
yeah,
the sure I can see the difference in
length.
And then you ask the poor pigeon,
you know,
are they different in length?
And he says,
yes.
You know,
and you can understand why.
It's like if all those other people are
saying it does either there's either
something wrong with all of them,
which seems unlikely or he's the victim
of a conspiracy,
which is a little on the paranoid side
but happens to actually be true in this
case.
Um,
or he's just not looking at it.
Right.
And you might think,
well,
the humble thing to think is he's wrong.
And so,
you know,
the fact that somebody might go along
with the crowd,
you know,
you can,
you can blame that on their,
on their ability to be social and
conventional,
which in many ways is a huge advantage
because if you are all antisocial and
unconventional,
you know,
I mean there'd be a good chunk of you in
jail and we certainly wouldn't be having
this,
you know,
delightful,
peaceful conversation that we're having.
So,
you know,
you don't want to underestimate the
utility of conventionality to too much
of a degree.
Anyway,
so
there's this funny story I read once,
I don't think it's true,
but it might be,
whereas psychology class got together
and decided they'd play a trick on the
professor.
And the trick was that he would walk
back and forth a,
and,
and the trick was that they wouldn't pay
any attention to them at all if he was
on the left side of the room.
You know,
they talk a bit and look,
look up.
And if he was on the right side of the
room,
then they'd really focus in and pay
attention.
And the story goes that by the,
you know,
by several weeks of this little trick,
they had them like lecturing right
beside the door,
you know,
and he wouldn't move from that spot.
And so the reason I'm telling you that
is it's pretty obvious that people can
respond to the cues that a crowd is
delivering.
You know,
when a good speaker does that,
right?
So a good speaker does a variety of
things and one is the never talks to
the,
to the crowd per se.
You know,
when you pick out specific individuals
and talk to them and they're sort of
reflective of the crowd and then you can
tell if everybody's understanding.
And uh,
the other thing that a good speaker does
is pay attention to the damn responses
of the crowd because you know,
if,
if a lecture is really a dialogue,
even though the,
the audience is only emitting nonverbal,
the nonverbal elements of the
conversation,
those nonverbal elements,
those damn things are important.
So you want to stay in touch with the
nonverbal communications.
Now Hitler,
he's kind of a chaotic guy,
you know,
he's very angry.
He's angry in part because he was a
frustrated art student.
He tried to get into art school like
four times.
So really the person to blame for World
War II was the foreperson committee that
wouldn't let poor Hitler into the,
I believe it was the Viennese School of
art because he really wanted to go,
you know,
and he had some artistic talent.
He was a little on the conventional side
by all appearances.
But you know,
I've seen some of his sketches and you
know,
he wasn't a complete piker and he kind
of felt maybe it would be okay for him
to go to university because he just been
through World War One,
you know?
And that wasn't much fun.
There's a story about Hitler where he
was out on in the trenches and he was
there with all his buddies and he
wandered off to do whatever he wandered
off to do.
And when he came back they were all dead
because a bomb had blended right in the
middle of them.
And you know,
you might think that would do the little
something to your psyche because after
an experience like that,
you're either going to think,
oh man,
things are pretty damn random and
horrible,
or there's pretty,
there's something pretty damn special
about me because I wasn't killed by the
bomb.
You know,
maybe God has saved me for a higher
purpose.
I mean,
you can be absolutely sure that if you
went through an experience like that,
that something like that would be
rattling around in your mind.
And he won.
He won a medal for bravery,
you know,
so he kinda,
and he,
after World War One,
he kind of wandered around like a lot of
men unemployed in sort of like a tramp,
you know.
So it wasn't very happy about that.
And,
and you know,
no wonder.
So anyways,
he didn't get into art school.
Now he didn't really have a fully
developed political theory,
you know?
And,
but he was pretty good at speaking,
so,
and there were lots of people who had
come to s to hear him speak because
people were sort of trying to figure out
what the hell to do about all the chaos,
you know,
so then you think,
well,
what did he,
what was hitting?
They're good at.
Well,
okay,
now I'm going to switch to a slightly
different story and then I'll get back
to this one.
So I don't know if you guys know about
the,
uh,
the daycare scandals that,
that were very,
very common in the 1980s.
So horribly common,
actually this infested many towns.
And usually what would happen is
somebody who is a little on the paranoid
side or maybe a lot on the paranoid side
was their children off to daycare.
And that was a whole new thing in the
80s,
right?
Because women were,
you know,
moving into the workforce like mad.
And so they were handing over there
often their infants,
kids below three say two total
strangers.
And you know,
for some of them that set up a fair bit
of worry.
Like it's still does.
And sometimes that word got out of hand,
especially among the people who are a
little on the little predisposed to
paranoid schizophrenia and maybe even
had had some previous episodes.
And so,
you know,
the kid would come home and the mother
would observe or not something kind of
peculiar about their behavior.
And then she'd fantasize about maybe
what that was.
And then when she started asking the
child if the child had been touched in
any particular way and you know,
and she keeps this up for a good length
of time.
And then the child would start to have
nightmares and then the child would tell
the mother about what the nightmares
were and then that would freak her out.
And so she'd ask even deeper questions
and soon,
you know,
her children were telling her that
horrible things were happening to them
at daycare.
And so then she'd go to the police and
they wouldn't look into recycling
patrick background.
And then the police would go out and
they'd start to interview other
children.
And if they interviewed them properly,
then the other children would start to
produce all these stories as well.
Because the now,
how did that happen?
Well,
a bunch of ways.
The first is
the police would ask leading questions
like,
did anyone touch you?
Well,
of course I'm going to touch the cans.
I mean,
people touch kids.
Did anybody touch you there?
Well,
that's not a question.
That's a piece of information.
The piece of information is if someone
touched me there and adult would be very
interested in that,
right?
So now at what's a child doing when he's
answering and adults questions,
wealth child doesn't bloody well know
what the hell do they know?
They're like three.
You know,
they can't hardly organize their story.
if you're talking to a kid and you want
to give,
get them to give you an account of their
day,
you have to really guide them through
the Organization of their memory.
And partly what they're doing when
you're doing that is they're looking at
you trying to figure out if they're
telling you the right things,
which is what they should be doing.
Because what they're trying to learn to
do is to tell people things in a way
that they'll understand them.
But that makes the child very,
very responsive to the nonverbal and
verbal cues of the adult.
You think about how fast those little
rats learn how to pick up language.
You know,
it's really very fast and no one really
teaches them.
They're just paying attention like mad.
So you get a bunch of cops who were on
how like a half cocked adventure and
they think there's some serial sexual
pervert in their midst and they go
interview,
you know,
1520 kids and they do do,
do it,
do it a lot.
They use little dolls and they do it a
lot and they do it a lot and they do it
a lot and sooner or later all the kids
start having nightmares and then they
start telling the cops there's all these
terrible things happen.
Like they're taking into underground
caverns in there,
strip naked and they're forced to like
leap frog over each other and like you
just can't believe what happened.
You can't believe it.
It's all documented in a book called
Satan's silence,
which was written by a social worker and
a lawyer.
It's mind boggling.
The longest prison sentence is in
American history were handed out to it
to a series of middle aged women who are
taking care of little kids.
And the FBI even came up with a whole
new criminal category,
late onset female sexual offender.
Well,
why didn't that category exists before?
It's simple.
There are no late onset,
middle aged female sexual offenders.
That's why we didn't need the category.
But once all these accusations came up,
well poof,
you know,
you had to have some damn category for
these poor women.
Some of them were put in jail for 350
years,
which seems a bit excessive given that
they're only going to last about 40 you
know,
they'd get 12 consecutive life
sentences.
So it,
and you know,
there was actually a situation where one
town went so far as to start digging
underneath the town to find these
underground satanic layers where all
these weird ritual things were going on,
you know,
and along with this was not one shred of
Collab of concrete evidence,
you know,
and the eventual conclusions and this
affected thousands of people.
The eventual conclusions was while
they're,
there actually isn't anybody who's,
you know,
Saint,
technically,
uh,
torturing children in daycare centers
now,
now anyways,
why am I telling you this?
Well,
what the children were doing,
you think about how the hell did the
children come up with these weird ideas?
You know,
I mean,
first of all,
we should note the children are not
stupid and they can also dream up the
most horrible things,
you know,
um,
because they have an imagination that's
capable of extending itself out into the
terrifying.
Now everyone knows that because all you
have to do is remember when you were a
kid,
you know,
when you were hiding under the covers
because there were horrible things in
your dark room.
You know,
you can populate the darkness with
monsters with no problem.
And you should be able to,
because there are monsters in the
darkness.
Even though your parents might tell you
there aren't,
it's like there might not be any door
monsters in that particular piece of
darkness.
And that's a perfectly reasonable thing
to tell your children.
But in the darkness as a whole,
it's like,
yeah,
look the hell out.
So the children aren't stupid now.
So then the PA,
the,
the adults start to question them and
the kids or the back of their brain,
the little imaginative part is thinking,
what do these people want?
What do these people want?
And so they'll throw him out a little
bit of information and they'll,
the adults will perk up.
They'll focus right on that piece of
information.
So maybe it's a cop who really hates
childs satanist abductors,
which,
you know,
it's perfectly reasonable stance.
And so when the child offers any
information about,
about the existence of such a thing,
while the cop will perk up and then the
child thinks,
oh,
I see,
well,
so sort of what's going on,
it seems to have something to do.
They don't think this consciously,
you know,
but their imagination is working.
How do I model the reality that's being
presented to me?
And that's when the dream start to kick
in too.
Okay.
So by
speaking in the appropriate way,
you can get all sorts of things churned
up in the,
in the unconscious minds of your
listeners.
And by watching them as well,
you can extract out there unconscious
desires.
Someone,
now I'm speaking to you all and you're
all irritated because your life has been
really awful for 15 years.
And I'm saying this and I'm saying that
and I'm saying this and I'm saying that,
you know,
and then I say something,
maybe I say something,
uh,
initially,
ah,
dismissive of Jews and you're all mad
and there's two or three people who go,
yeah,
and then I think,
oh,
I'm not going to hold.
That's kind of an interesting response.
And then,
you know,
I lay out a couple more ideas and some
of them don't get any response and
others,
you know,
people perk right up and,
and I'm not stupid and I'm trying to get
the bloody attention of the crowd.
And so if I do that 50 times,
the crowd's going to tell me an awful
lot about what they want,
especially if I'm willing to follow
them.
And I can do that easily because,
especially if I can start to work the
crowd a little bit,
because I can capitalize on their
emotional,
on their emotional,
capitalize on their emotions and the
display of that emulsion,
and I can learn to play that.
And then that turns into a positive
feedback loop.
And so Hitler's informing the audience
and the audiences informing Hitler,
and that's why you'll believe that
Hitler embodied the shadow of the German
people.
Yeah.
So that's another reason why you should
be careful what you say and why you say
it.
You know,
why you're looking for attention and all
of those things,
and actually what's motivating you and
actually what's motivating the people
who are listening to you.
Because God only knows where it might go
if you're not careful.
Well,
actually we do know where it goes if
you're not careful.
And it's not pretty,
that's for sure.
And to think that we've learned anything
from that,
it's like,
no,
that's not right.
We haven't learned a damn thing from it.
So because we don't want to understand
it now,
these guys were all concerned with that
sort of thing.
They're highly concerned with it.
Now,
Vince Wanger and boss had both been
influenced by Freud and bite you.
You can see in the bottom right hand
corner there,
that's a boss with you and,
and that's been swinger on the left and
boss at the top there.
So you know,
they're,
they're pretty thoughtful looking guys
and they were pretty damn smart and they
were quite philosophically oriented and
they had both studied heidegger and they
both studied Husserl who were German
philosophers on heidegger actually got
tangled right up into the Nazi movement.
And you know,
his philosophy has been cast under a
cloud of suspicion,
perhaps a well deserved cloud of
suspicion as a consequence of his
cooperation with the Nazis.
So it wasn't only stupid people who got
tangled up in this,
it was pretty much everybody who got
tangled up in it.
Then one of the things you might be
might think about,
and this is we're thinking about,
is that if you were there for any one of
you,
there's a 90% chance that you would have
got tangled up in it.
You know,
you wouldn't have been the person who
rescued the Gypsies is like forget that.
It's like,
unless you think that you know you're a
heroic far beyond the average and I
would be very,
very careful about assuming that you
could assume instead that you would have
been swept along with the crowd just
like everyone else because everyone else
was all right.
Now part of what these guys were trying
to figure out is in some sense there
were two things.
There was the,
the function and structure of belief
systems and then the nature of that
which transcends a belief system.
Okay.
So you know what transcends a belief
system is what you don't know if you use
that belief system,
right?
Because there are things outside of your
belief system and they have a nature as
well.
And you usually run into those sorts of
things when you make a mistake and
things don't happen the way you expect
them to or want them to or desire them
to.
So,
and then the other problem they're
trying to solve in some senses.
Well,
what's the appropriate mode of behavior
for an individual in relationship to
belief systems and to the world that
transcends the belief systems?
And the reason they were interested not
is because they thought,
well,
maybe it would be a good event.
Good idea of our belief systems didn't
get so damn pathological.
Because if they do,
then you know,
6 million people end up in ovens or the
equivalent and 120 million people end up
dead in battlefields.
And you know,
that doesn't count the stallon massacres
or mile who were,
you know,
made Hitler in some sense look like an
absolute amateur.
I mean,
Stalin starved 6 million people to death
in Ukraine in the 1930s and he was just
warming up.
You know,
I don't know how many,
how many of you have heard of the
Ukraine famine?
How many of you have you haven't?
Yeah,
well think about that.
You know,
how many of you knew Mao killed 100
million people?
How many of you didn't?
Yeah.
Well you might think about why you don't
know that.
You know,
you know about the Damn Nazis,
but you don't know about the horrors
that the communists perpetrated.
It's worth thinking about why?
Because the communists,
especially the Maoist man,
those people were brutal.
So it's really important.
Like of all the things we could possibly
learn psychologically from the 20th
century and is what these characters in
the 50s were concentrating on it,
it's like,
okay,
things can go powerfully sideways.
It was quite a shock to everyone because
in some sense,
you know,
everyone was pretty thrilled that the
beginning of the 19th century that
religion,
classical religion beliefs had crumbled.
You know,
the Marxist said,
well the damn religions were only there
to oppress the poor anyways and to keep
the priesthood in the aristocracy in
power.
You know,
you'll,
I'm sure you learn plenty of that in
your,
in your classes,
that sort of thinking,
you know,
it's power economics related thinking
and it's typical of,
of of what,
what would you say?
MMM.
Intellectually manipulative.
Left wing thinkers.
I would say that's basically the
routine.
You know,
they reduce everything to a single damn
motivation.
It's usually economics or power.
Then they explain everything from that
perspective.
It's like it's so boneheaded it should
be illegal anyways.
Okay.
The Marxists,
we're happy that religion had collapsed
because they thought that that would
eliminate an,
an entire strata of oppression.
And you can see that it's not like the
Catholic church,
for example,
was free of corruption.
You know,
it was in many ways it corrupt
enterprise and you could read it as
solely a corrupt enterprise.
And you know,
to hell with it,
it's good that it's gone.
And uh,
you know,
the Friday and it's basically thought
the same way.
And so did most intellectuals,
Freud thought that religion was nothing
than a,
than a childish delusion that people
identified with because they were afraid
of dying.
It was a,
you know,
it was a defense against death,
anxiety.
Look,
the Marxist argument and the,
and the Floridian and argument,
those are bloody powerful arguments,
you know,
cause you can see it.
You'll do,
people use their religious belief as a
defense against things.
They're too terrified to confront.
Well obviously,
you know,
does the Church press people?
Did it?
Oh,
press people,
get it,
engage in,
you know,
conspiracies with people in power across
centuries.
It's like,
obviously,
you know,
the question is,
well,
what do you make of that?
Well,
partly you make of it that all sorts of
structures do that.
It's like structures do that and you
know,
you can't just damn one structure and
thanked the others are gonna,
you know,
it's like the right wingers,
they're always owned about big
government,
how terrible that isn't.
Left wingers are always on about how big
corporations are terrible.
It's like,
well bank is terrible.
It doesn't matter if it's government or
corporations because things tend to tilt
towards corruption across time and then
that has to be taken into account.
But
anyway,
so the Friday comes and the
intellectuals in the Marxists,
we're all pretty happy when the
religious dream started to come apart
and they believe that the new edifice is
that they were going to construct
fascist and communist would be so much
better than what they replaced that,
you know,
everybody would be drowning in utopia.
And uh,
it's kind of too bad that isn't how it
turned out.
But it's certainly not how it turned
out.
How it turned out was,
hmm,
sometimes when you something down,
even
if you think it's terrible,
you end up constructing something on its
ruins that makes the previous terrible
look like the work of rank amateurs.
And that's certainly what happened in
the 20th century.
I mean,
no matter what you say about the
Catholic Church and its basic barbarism,
especially when you know they were
involved in the witch hunt in the middle
ages.
It's like those guys,
they were amateurs compared to the
fascists and the communists.
You know,
they were counting their victims in the
tens of thousands,
not the hundreds of millions.
So anyways,
things didn't go so well.
And so by the 1950s especially because
of the Cold War started the day the
Second World War ended,
right.
And it ended with the atomic bomb in
Japan and the Russians had the damn
atomic bomb like you know,
tomorrow.
Fundamentally.
And both the Russians and the Americans
had the hydrogen bomb by the early 1950s
and I don't know if you know this,
you can tell me how many of you know
this.
Do you know that a hydrogen bomb uses an
atom bomb for it's trigger?
Okay.
So the hydrogen bombs,
the atom bomb stands in relationship to
a hydrogen bomb.
Like the ignition cap on a shelf stands
in relationship to the gunpowder.
The atomic blast just gets the explosion
going.
So hydrogen bombs,
they're like way,
way more explosive than atomic bombs.
And so,
you know,
by the middle of the 1950s we'd pretty
much put herself in a position where,
and they were building some mighty big
bumps.
I mean,
really unbelievable.
Unbelievably big bombs,
you know,
400 times as big as the ones that wiped
out here.
Ashima like huge,
huge bumps and they're getting pretty
damn good at it.
You know?
So by the mid 1950s it was like
we developed enough firepower on both
sides of the Atlantic,
along with the missiles necessary to
deliver them,
which the Nazis had basically invented
in World War II.
Right?
It was all Nazi scientists who invented
rockets and they were all taken by the
Americans after the Second World War to
work on the American space program,
basically.
And so by the 1950s we had the missiles
to deliver the damn things too.
So not only were the psychologists who
were thinking about things sort of
shorted out about what happened in World
War II for good reason.
And then of course all the stalinists
horrors were starting to be revealed at
that point.
Although it took western intellectuals
like 30 years before they gave them any
credence at all.
Think John Paul Sartre was still a
member of the communist party up until
1970 it was very common,
particularly among French intellectuals.
You know,
even though the news was getting out,
oh,
careful observers,
like George Orwell had pretty much
figured out by the,
by the late thirties that not all was
right in the paradise of Stellan.
But you know,
people didn't thought he was a right
winger.
He didn't listen to a much,
even though he was a left winger.
Okay.
So are these,
these existential phenomenologists
they're trying to figure out,
we've got a big problem here.
The belief systems are seriously going
sideways and there's some indication,
you know,
there's some individual responsibility
for that.
I've some indeterminant nature.
Like if you live in a country where
everyone's turned into a fascist
murderer,
like is that your fault?
Well,
you know,
it's not obvious that an individual
should be held responsible for the
actions of an entire country.
But then again,
the country's made up of individuals.
So that's a very difficult problem to
solve.
You know,
and one of the tenants of Western law is
that you don't hold an individual
responsible for the actions of the
group,
even if he or she happens to be a member
willingly or unwillingly of that group.
But you can't ignore the fact that all
these things were made up of people.
And then you also can't ignore the fact
that it was individuals who were doing
the terrible things that were being done
to people.
You know.
So in Auschwitz for example,
one of the little tricks that the guards
used to do was to,
you know,
they bring the Jews off the freight
cars.
A lot of them had died in the freight
cars cause they are packed in there like
this,
you know.
So lots of them would suffocate or the
old ones would die.
Or the little kids would die.
And that was okay.
You know,
and then on along the outside of the
freight cars,
especially if it was winter,
well it's like 20 below.
And so the ones on the outside would
freeze,
but you know where you were going to get
rid of them anyways.
So that was just convenient mostly.
So then you'd take them to Auschwitz and
they'd all spill out speaking different
languages,
torn up from their family,
you know,
as miserable as people can possibly be.
And then one trick was to have,
you know,
someone who is not quite dead enough,
pick up a sack of a wet,
a sack of wet salt.
So that's 100 pounds and carry it from
one side of the compound to the other.
And then back,
you know,
one side and then back.
And you know,
you don't want to be thinking about
these campuses like,
like a football field.
These bloody things were cities.
They were big.
They held tens of thousands of people.
And so there's some guard.
He thinks that's pretty good joke.
And it's not just a few people that are
like that.
And we found out from the Stanford
prison experiment,
which every psychologist likes to think
of as immoral.
You know,
because we actually discovered something
with it that if you gave ordinary people
the opportunity to be fascist barbarians
in six days,
30% of them would be.
And you know what we learned from that
is that social psychologist shouldn't
run the Stanford prison experiment.
That's not the right conclusion to draw.
So some of these phenomenologists are
all where it all concerned about this.
It's like what the hell should we do
about that?
So they're starting to think about how
belief systems are constructed.
And so
the first proposition that they make is
that we should treat the reality that
we're dealing with as psychologists.
We should treat human experiences that
reality.
And so the reality for you from a
phenomenological perspective is
everything you experienced,
they assume everything you experienced
is real.
And they also assume that you can't get
more real than that.
And so your consciousness,
whatever that is,
is real and your dreams are real and
your emotions are real and your pain is
real,
which is a really useful thing to think
if you want to make sure that you're not
going to hurt people.
You know,
you kind of have to think that maybe
think pain should be treated as a
fundamental reality instead of as an ff
phenomena of some material substrate.
And so that's their first perspective.
And they took that from heidegger
because heidegger thought that western
philosophy had gone off,
got off on the wrong track,
you know,
3000 years ago because we didn't really
concentrate on being itself as the
fundamental mystery.
And so the fundamental mystery is why
the hail?
Is there anything?
And since there is something
experiential being what are its
fundamental elements?
And so that's the phenomenological
stats.
It's,
it's completely,
it's not the same as a scientific
approach because it starts with a
different presupposition.
You know,
the scientific presupposition,
roughly speaking is that things are the
objectively real elements of things are
the most real elements.
And there's no sense complaining about
that because it's an approach that works
tremendously well for many,
many things including making hydrogen
bombs for example.
But it's also reasonable to think that,
well it might not be the,
it might not be the whole truth and
nothing but the truth.
And maybe you could also suspect that
the fact that we can manufacture
hydrogen bombs also might indicate that
there's something trifle off with our
fundamental belief systems scientific
though they may be.
And that was certainly something that
concerned Heidegger,
even though he got all tangled up with
the Nazis.
So the phenomenologists were trying to
take apart experience as such and they
made some some hypotheses and then some
observation.
So the first is that we're going to
assume that your experience like
experience itself is real.
Now you just because dreams are real and
pain is real,
it doesn't mean,
and like objects that we can all
perceive our real doesn't mean you
should put them all in the same
category.
Like my dreams are not in the same
category of reality as this table
because you don't have access to my
dreams and you have access to the table.
But that doesn't mean that my dreams and
my pains and my emotions aren't real.
They're real.
So that's the first now.
Or You should know that this is a,
this is a proposition.
What they're saying is let's act as if
that's true and then worked from those
premises and see what happens,
see where we can get with it.
And that that's,
that's a perfectly reasonable thing to
do because at the bottom of a theory,
you also have,
you always have to put an assumption
because otherwise your theory would be
100% right and would cover everything
and it doesn't.
So you have to throw an assumption
somewhere in there at the bottom and
say,
okay,
we're not,
we're not questioning that.
That's the starting point.
So,
and it,
you have to do that because you're
ignorant.
You don't have a full theory.
So they don't like the idea that mind
can be reduced to matter.
They're not playing that game.
They're not playing the game,
that the subject is only up a phenomenal
and the object is real.
They're not playing that game either.
And it's partly because,
as boss says,
without a subject,
nothing at all would exist to confront
objects and to imagine them as such.
True.
This implies that every object,
everything objective is merely
objectively in being merely objectivize
by the subject is the most subjective
thing possible.
It's a radical claim,
you know,
but here's,
here's something to think about it.
When I look at that,
coke can,
you might say,
hi,
perceive the object,
and then I make inferences about its use
and then I evaluate it and then I use
it.
And you know,
that is not actually what you do.
In fact,
it's not obvious at all that what you
perceive our objects.
And,
and if you think about it,
well,
people weren't perceiving scientific
objects until like 1,514 50 so there was
no objective object before that.
So obviously whatever we were perceiving
was not precisely that because we would
have been scientists right off the bat.
George Kelly claimed that people were
natural scientists.
You know that we're always investigating
hypothesis and trying to disprove them
and so on.
And it's an interesting theory and that
it's right in a sense.
But fundamentally it's wrong.
We are not natural scientists were
natural engineers.
And when we look at the world,
we don't see objects.
And then in further use,
what we actually see is the use.
So for example,
when I look at that,
coke can buy,
my visual system activates my motor
cortex directly.
It can do that without me seeing the dam
can consciously to some degree,
because there are people with blind
side,
I've told you about those people,
they say they can't see.
But if you asked them which hand do you
have held up,
they can tell you.
So they might not be able to see.
But they can map patterns from their
visual system onto their motor output,
you know?
And that's basically what Piaget said we
do.
When we deal with the world,
we're embodied creatures,
you know?
And so what we see when we look around
aren't objects.
They're things we can use and things
that get in our way.
You know?
And that's the theory that was derived
originally from Jj Gibson who wrote a
great book on that called the visual
approach to ecological ecological
approach to visual perception.
And his science is a brand of pragmatism
and the pragmatists basically claim that
you know,
things including theories and
perceptions have a limited range of
truth and the truth that that,
that the limited range of truth is
determined by the match between your
actions and outcomes.
So I think this is a coke can,
is that what it is?
No,
but it's good enough for me if I want to
drink a bit of coke out of it.
God only knows what it is.
You know,
if you go into communist China and you
start advertising these things,
then what are they?
Cause this thing tells a story,
right?
What's the story like?
Really?
Do you need Coca Cola?
No,
it's like it's a bit of Frippery,
you know,
it's a bit of,
it's not unnecessary luxury.
It's not even very good for you,
but it's kind of fuzzy and it's sweet
and you get to buy it.
And why is that?
Because no matter how stupid you are and
your nutrition choices,
as far as our society goes,
you have the right to poison yourself in
whatever way you think best fits you.
And so when you send this little coke
can off to communist China,
this thing screams stupid individuality
all over.
And God only knows how it undermines the
state.
You know?
And if you don't,
if you're not thinking about that,
you're not thinking.
Think about what happens when we export
cars.
What does the car say?
It says,
Hey,
you can go wherever you want,
whenever you want.
You don't have to tell anybody at all
and you can do it in a really dangerous
highspeed manner.
It's like you want a political
statement,
wrap it up in metal and ship that thing
off.
And everybody goes,
oh,
I really liked to have one of those.
It's like poof,
communism disappears with that.
There's nothing that says individuality
and capitalism like a personal
automobile.
You know,
you even get to pollute the atmosphere
and ruin the planet with the damn thing.
But you know,
if you have to drive to the corner store
and pick up your damn coke,
it's like to hell with the atmosphere.
So don't be thinking that the things
that appear in front of you are merely
objects because they're not,
you know,
I started thinking about this,
for example,
when I was thinking about people going
down to Graceland to look at Elvis
Guitar.
You think
what exactly
is it that makes a good tart?
Elvis has guitar,
you know,
it's not exactly the guitar
cause it's just sitting there like any
old guitar,
you know,
and maybe you could even think about it.
You could take that and guitar out and
he could put another guitar in that look
just like it.
And it would still be all of us as
guitar cause no one would know.
And you might think,
well then that's not really,
Elvis has guitar.
But that's a funny thing because you
would only think that if you thought
that Elvis is guitar was the thing that
was made out of material that was
sitting right in front of you.
And that isn't what it is.
That's the only one's tiny little bit of
it.
That bloody thing is,
is a part of an incredibly layered
reality,
right?
I mean,
okay,
the people who want to go look at that,
they're looking at it in some sense
because of the magic that's emanating
from it.
But the magic is actually real.
You know,
the magic is the effect of that guitar,
let's say on the entire culture.
And those effects are the damn guitar
too.
And it's weird because when you go look
at Elvis Guitar,
you don't have looking at the guitar,
you're looking at the magic.
And weirdly enough,
the magic is actually real.
While can't think that way
if you're a materialist because you
think that the thing is the material,
it's like,
yeah,
right.
I can tell you another story.
So when the,
when the Europeans came to the South
Pacific islands,
the South Pacific islanders,
because there weren't that many of them,
they didn't have a very high,
highly technical society,
you know?
And so like if you were like Joe
Dominant guy in a Pacific island
culture,
you know you might be able to have a
stone ax,
like a wellmade stone ax because go out
and make a stone ax and see how long
that takes you.
It's like that's a bit of work.
And so if you're a high status guy,
if you've really worked your whole life
to be at the top of your Damn pyramid,
you get,
maybe you get had two axes,
you know,
it's like a red letter day.
You've got two axes,
you know,
which is more than any other animal has
by a lot.
So it's not trivial.
And then the damn missionaries come in
and they,
and they set up shop and what do they
bring?
Steel access.
It's like that's kind of a downer.
You know,
you've worked your whole damn life to
get these stone axes and that makes you
like head tribesmen and then you want
your kid wanders down to the local
missionaries and they say,
oh we got an extra steel ax here.
Why don't you take that back home?
And it's like,
it's so shocking because not only did
the missionaries have this thing that is
so much better than a steel ax,
it's like a jet plane compared to a,
to a wheeled cart.
Like they're really,
really different,
but the missionaries,
they don't even notice.
That's the horrible thing about it.
It's like the giveaway,
this thing that hasn't virtually
infinite value and it's like,
well,
it's okay.
We got,
you know,
a couple dozen of those sitting in the
store room and you know,
we're just willing to hand them out.
It was a little demoralizing.
It was a little demoralizing for the
Pacific islanders and so you know,
why was it an ax that the missionaries
gave away?
It wasn't.
You'd think that if you are a Westerner
and you had a bunch of access,
it's like,
yeah,
that's an ax.
It's like,
yeah,
right.
It's a lot more than an ax,
a lot more.
It's a weapon to bring down a whole
culture accidentally.
One of the things that the
phenomenologists claimed,
this is a cool claim.
I didn't know they claimed this.
It took me quite a long time to figure
this out because I thought I'd figured
this out on my own,
but it turns out that's very difficult
to figure out anything on your own.
Now,
when I was doing my investigations into
how the brain works from a
neuropsychological perspective,
not was informed a lot by Jeffrey Gray,
who we're going to talk about later.
One of the things I noticed was that you
don't actually,
you don't actually see things when you
first see something.
In fact,
when you first see something,
you don't even see it.
You react to it.
You rock too with your body.
So I can give you an example.
So you,
you're,
you have a partner and you have a
trusting relationship and then you find
out that they're,
you know,
they tell you or you figure out from
their phone or something,
they're having an affair and you look at
them and you think,
well,
what do you see?
And you think you see,
well,
you see the person,
it's like,
no,
you don't.
You do not see the person that's wrong.
What you see is a huge pit that you're
going to fall into and you don't even
know you see it,
but your body knows that's your blood
pressure goes through the roof and your
heart starts to pound and you sweat.
And the reason for that is your body
sees what you can't see and what it sees
as something it's seriously does not
understand it does not understand it.
It sees the territory behind the map,
right?
Because when I look at you,
for all intents and purposes,
really what I'm looking at is my
presuppositions about you.
And because you're a polite and well
behaved,
you're gracious enough to act in
accordance with those presuppositions.
So I don't even really have to look at
you.
And thank you very much for that because
it's very difficult to look at people
because they're horrifying and profound
creatures.
And so everybody walks around behaving.
So we don't terrify the hell out of each
other all the time.
Now when someone betrays you,
it's like Poof,
presuppositions gone.
Okay,
what's there?
Well,
God only knows and that's what your body
reacts to.
And that's partly why the
phenomenologists said we react to
meaning first.
We don't react to the object.
It takes a long time to see the damn
object.
So for example,
let's say that your person has betrayed
you.
Now you think you knew who they were and
you thought you knew who you were.
Ha.
Guess what?
You're wrong.
You don't know who they are.
And because you're such a moron,
that means you don't know who you are.
And it means you can't trust any of your
memories with that person.
And maybe none of your memories in any
intimate relationships at all.
Plus what about the future?
Well,
so when you look at the person,
what do you see?
You see all that.
It's like chaos,
whack.
That's what you see.
And that chaos is the meaning behind
your presuppositions.
And that's why the phenomenologists
would say meaning shines forth.
That's famous thigh.
It shines forth.
And that's the primary thing we
encounter.
It's like that smart.
And you know what's really weird?
That's how your damn brain is organized.
And that's weird.
A because you think,
let's think about it.
How do you define reality?
Now.
That's a tough one.
So I would say most of you define
reality like you're Isaac Newton or
maybe like your democritus who was the
first person who hypothesized Adams.
And so in the Newtonian world,
it's like billiard ball world,
right?
Everything is made out of little
billiard balls and they bang together in
a causal way and you can predict the
consequences of their banging together.
And if you extend it enough,
you can conjure up an entirely
deterministic world.
A happens causes b because it's see
always the same way and everything runs
like a giant clock.
That's Newton's model and it's,
and it was a clock model because you
know,
back at that time,
clocks,
man,
those things were pretty damn
impressive.
Clocks got the whole industrial
revolution underway.
And you know,
medieval cities would put an awful lot
of time and work into their clocks and
they thought those damn things were
really cool.
You know,
they could keep track of where the
planets were moving.
It's like that's a big deal.
A clock.
And then if you want to think about an
invention that changed the world,
it's like the clock's a big one.
Now we can measure time in the same way.
Everyone can measure time.
It's a big deal.
So the idea that the universe is like a
clock,
given that the clock can predict the
universe,
it's a pretty damn powerful idea.
It turns out that it's wrong because you
know,
causalities a mass,
no one really understands it.
And there are levels of analysis that
which causality just in the way we
experience it doesn't seem to imply it
apply at all.
You go down to the subatomic level,
it's probabilistic.
You can't predict single events.
And I don't believe that you can predict
the future.
You can predict parts of the future in
an extremely limited way for some
purposes,
for some span of time that,
and you can't even predict how long that
span of time is going to last.
You know?
And some things seem to be more stable
across more situations and more times
than others,
but there's still,
there's instability everywhere and it
makes it predicting things a very
difficult thing to do.
So,
okay,
so that's one idea about reality.
That's the idea really,
that you have,
and that's the reality that you've been
educated to have the idea of reality.
You've been educated to have,
even though we know it's wrong,
like Einstein blue,
that world in the early 19 hundreds
along with the various people that
Einstein dependable,
that's gone,
it's wrong.
And then there's all sorts of other
extremely complicated problems like how
to model positive feedback loops.
You know,
that sort of gets you into chaos theory
and it's really,
really hard to model positive feedback
loops.
And they can go wild in 50 different
ways and you can't really predict them
because they depend on initial
conditions and so on and so forth.
So,
so the deterministic world,
it's like,
no,
that's wrong.
I think part of the reason we have to
have freewill is because we can't act
deterministically.
You know,
a deterministic system is only going to
work in a system that stays the same,
you know,
so you can wind up a little clock,
one of those little clockwork toys and
it'll walk.
But you know,
if you put a cliff in front of it,
just walks off the cliff.
So in cliffs are appearing in front of
us randomly all the time.
So I can't even see how a deterministic
system could possibly work to guide us.
It would assume that our knowledge,
the knowledge that we derive from the
past is sufficiently accurate to
causally guide us into the future.
It's like,
no,
that's not right.
It doesn't that maybe that's why we have
consciousness.
No one knows.
But that's a good theory.
If there's a y
anyways,
here's an alternative.
The alternative,
this is a Darwinian alternative.
So here's the alternative.
The world's a complex and dynamic place.
It's full of weird things.
Musically.
It's made up of patterns.
It's made up a patterns and patterns of
patterns and patterns and patterns of
patterns.
And that's what it is.
And they shift and dance around and then
you throw something that's alive into
that.
It's,
it's programmed by DNA and the damn
thing has to keep up with the patterns
and they're changing all the time.
Some of them are kind of stable,
but they're pretty damn fluid.
So then you throw the DNA in there and
it goes and produces a million variants
of whatever it's going to produce.
And most of them are wrong.
So you're a mosquito,
you lay a million lay eggs.
It's like,
so that's a million
bets about how the future will causally
unfold and the bed is the future's going
to unfold.
So this egg can turn into a mosquito.
And so then you might say,
well how often is the mosquito that lays
the eggs wrong?
And the answer to that is if it,
if it lays a million eggs in its
lifetime,
I don't know how many eggs mosquitoes
late,
but they lay a lot.
All of those eggs are going to die
except one
if the mosquitoes lucky.
And you know that because we're knee
deep and mosquitoes,
right?
If,
if it wasn't the case,
then there just be mosquitoes everywhere
and there aren't.
Thank God there's enough of the damn
things.
But you know,
so basically what's the bet?
The bet is mosquito matches environment
answer wrong except once in a million.
So how do you overcome that million
mosquitoes,
million eggs.
And it'll do the trick.
And so look,
that's so interesting.
A,
because it means the fundamental
hypothesis that the mosquito structure
matches the structure of reality is
wrong at a one in a million.
It's wrong at a 999,999 level of error.
You might just think that's just
completely wrong.
You know,
that's really wrong,
but it keeps the damn mosquitoes going.
Okay,
so then this propagates across time.
You know,
and what really propagates across time
is a massive wave of death.
Virtually everything fails.
99.9% of the species that ever lived are
extinct.
It's something like that,
you know?
And we're doing a fairly good job of
making sure that a good chunk of the
ones that exist now we're going to go
extinct.
You know?
So failure and death is the norm and
it's going to happen to all of you.
So
if the underlying structure of reality
is mutable,
which it is,
and the only way that you can adapt to
it is by generating variance and having
most of them perish except for the ones
that manage more or less by chance to
keep up.
How do you define real?
And a darwinist would say,
and this would a pragmatist would say
too,
you embody real to the best degree that
real can be attained.
And it's not very good.
Your reel is only good enough for about
80 years.
But you know what else they would say is
that's as real as gets the,
the whatever reality is,
it's so damn complicated.
This multilayered pattern array that you
can't even model it without using death
as the,
as the mechanism.
You can't do it.
And even if he dual use death,
it's almost all death.
And even for the parts that aren't
death,
which is hardly any of it,
your damn solution isn't that good.
You know,
you're going to wear out in 80 years.
That's,
you got 3 billion years of trying behind
you.
That's the best you can do 80 damn
years.
You know,
maybe if you're a parrot,
you can get a 150 and apparently there's
somebody mortal jellyfish,
which fingers would be the damn
jellyfish that would be a mortal.
So real might,
you know,
that's a whole different way about
thinking about real.
Now,
you know,
Nisha said life is truth.
Truth serves life,
sorry.
And that's a Darwinian id.
Even though he didn't take it from
Darwin.
It's like there isn't anything more true
than what evolution reveals as the model
for reality.
That's as true as it gets for us.
And that's not a Newtonian reality.
It's a multilevel pattern,
chaotic reality that we're trying to
keep up with.
And that's real.
And so what that might mean is that,
okay,
the implications for action that I
derived from that phenomena
might be more indicative of what it is.
Then an objective analysis,
because your truth is the degree to
which you,
you embody truth in so far as it can be
determined within a Darwinian framework
is entirely measured by your success in
living in propagating.
And that's it.
There isn't anything under that.
Now.
Maybe there is,
but if you're a Darwinian,
that's it.
And I think Darwin's right,
all things considered and Newton is
wrong.
Plus we also know that Newton is wrong.
Now the whole Darwinian thing is more
complicated than we thought because you,
you know,
you've run,
do you know what epigenetics are?
How many of you know about that?
Well,
that's pretty good.
So your biological education,
like demolishes your historical
education,
how many people don't know what
epigenetics is?
It's okay.
It's just relatively new.
Anyways.
It turns out that your parents
experience can alter their genetic
structure in such a way that it alters
your genetic structure.
It's like,
oh,
that's something we didn't expect that
that's for sure.
And nobody knows what the final,
you know,
consequences of that will be.
But it looks like there's more to the
evolutionary story than mere random
production and natural selection.
There's more to it than that.
Who knows how much.
So anyways,
when the,
when the phenomenologists say we react
to meaning first,
that kind of opens a question.
It's like,
well,
is that,
is the meaning real?
And that opens is another question,
which is what do you mean by real?
And then that opens another question is
like,
well,
is it Newton real or is it Darwin real
Newton's wrong.
That leaves Darwin
and Darwin Real.
That's about as real as it gets.
In fact,
that might be as real as it gets.
You know,
if a partial entity is trying to model a
complex totality,
all they're ever going to be able to do
is embody a partial representation of
that and it's not going to be that good,
but it's going to be as good as they can
get.
And that's as true as it can get.
So the phenomenologists,
you know,
they have this weird idea we perceive
meaning.
It's like,
guess what?
That's how your brain is set up.
You first perceive meaning and then with
a lot of work,
you turn that into an object perception.
Christ God only knows how much
exploration you have to do before you do
that.
You know how long you think it takes a
child to handle?
It's,
it's a soother before it builds up an
accurate representation of the soother.
You know it's going to be chewing on
that thing like mad.
It's going to be taking a note and
checking it out,
turning it around and banging it against
things and it has to do all of that
including the tac kyle interaction and
the experimentation with the thing
across situations to establish say
object permanence.
It has to do all that before it can see
the thing.
You know like early Iei in early ai
researchers who were basically under the
influence of behaviorists who basically
said the object is given and so they
could treat the brain like it didn't
even exist.
You know the objects just there,
you can just see the world.
It's like that turned out to be
seriously wrong.
It's damn difficult to get a computer to
see the world.
Now.
It turns out you have to put the bloody
things inside bodies before they could
even do it because you really can't
perceive the world without a body
because perception is for bodily action
and without the framework within which
cause really what you're doing and this
is a Ph Yeti and idea to this is a
pattern,
this thing.
And then I'm,
the pattern exists at multiple levels,
including say the advertising level and
your memories of coke and all the bloody
jingles,
you know,
and all that.
But this,
when I look at that,
I map it's pattern onto my retina.
And the pattern is a pattern because
it's extending across time,
right?
So it's not like smoke,
it's not just dissipating.
There it is.
It's staying there across time.
I map that onto my retina and the retina
matches it onto my hand.
That's the coke can.
And actually the coke can is all of
this.
And you might say that's not what it is
because it's made of aluminum.
It's like,
yeah,
yeah it's made out of aluminum.
But that's only one part of what it is.
And it's not necessarily even the most
important part cause it could be made
out of plastic and you know,
what the hell difference would that
make?
You know?
So,
so it's pretty damn weird when you start
to think about it because people make
the claim that meaning is EPA.
It's like there's no real meaning of the
universe is this dead thing.
And if we all went to extinguished,
you know,
tomorrow they're just be a bunch of
meaningless marbles rotating in space.
Well first of all,
even that's not true because God only
knows what's out there if there's
nothing to perceive it.
You know,
the physicists tell us it's more like a
vast potential fluctuating quantum
field.
You know?
And maybe it doesn't even turn into
stars and planets until there's someone
to look at it.
You know?
And you might think that's ridiculous.
But if you think about it for a while,
you'll see that there's really something
to it.
You know,
because you are the thing that specifies
the level of analysis,
right?
You know,
the way you look at the world,
you don't see the atoms,
you don't see the subatomic particles,
you don't see the little rocks.
You see planet sized things.
When you look out into space and you
know,
you see it at a particular slice of
time.
That's part of,
maybe your refresh rate is something
like 60 hertz.
So what you see is the universe sliced
into 60 hertz slices and you think
that's real.
It's like,
yeah,
yeah.
So was all the rest of it,
including its huge expanse of time from
beginning to end.
You don't see any of that.
It's there.
So what's there?
All those things at the same time and
what does all that add up to?
The physicists seem to be telling us
that adds up to a pool of quantum
potential that isn't realized until
there's something that conscious,
it's conscious that interacts with it.
It's like,
who knows?
Now you've got your meaning shining
forth like mad.
And I think part of the reason that
children are so attractive is because
for them the meaning is just shining at
them.
Like Matt.
That's why they're always wandering
around like this,
you know?
And it's really fun to watch kids
because they give you a taste of that
again,
you know,
because kids have to pay you so you
don't throw them out the window because
they're very annoying.
Right.
They're always crying,
they're completely useless.
They just lay there and they don't do
anything,
you know,
and they wake you up at three in the
morning and annoy you.
And so,
you know,
because you're selfish and mean you need
some something in return and so they
smile at you and,
but they do other things.
They're really,
really,
really comical.
So there are a blast to watch and play
with.
But one of the things they really do is
they,
they remove the blinders from you while
you're around them.
Cause you know,
you go out and like a little forest with
a two and a half year olds,
very annoying cause the bloody things,
they just wander around randomly,
you know?
So you've got no goal directed,
nothing goal directed is going to happen
with the two and a half year old.
But that's kind of cool because it frees
your mind from your goal directed
narrowness and you can watch the two
year old look at all these things that
you haven't looked at for 20 years
because you already looked at them once
and now you just have to see your memory
and then you think,
wow,
that really is cool.
You know,
they'll bring you something and they'll
tell you what's cool.
And you know,
maybe it's a shiny piece of aluminum of
gum wrapper,
what you think it's a gum wrapper
because that's what you see when you
look at it.
Because you've already built up gum
wrapper representation and you just lay
it on that.
That isn't,
the kid sees,
God only knows what they're looking at.
You know,
maybe how the light reflects off the
aluminum prismatic Lee and how it
glitters and how cool it is that it can
be folded up and how light it is.
It's like,
and they're looking at it like this and
you know,
I think it's because their cortex isn't
very well developed and they haven't
built the inhibitory structures that
stopped them from seeing meaning shining
forth.
You know,
and you might think,
well,
is there any evidence for that?
And there actually is quite a bit of
evidence for that.
You know,
I mean,
one piece of evidence is that if you
take a cats brain off out and you just
leave it with the hypothalamus and the
spinal cord,
it's hyper exploratory.
It runs around like everything's
interesting.
It's pretty weird behavior for a thing
that doesn't have a brain,
you know,
you kind of think that once you don't
have a brain,
nothing would be interesting.
It depends on how much of your brain you
have.
And there are people who've experienced
that.
By the way,
there was a famous case of a conductor
who had a very serious brain injury and
it basically blew out his hippocampus so
he couldn't put any more information
from short term attention to longterm
storage.
And he wrote these articles,
these,
these massive page long journals,
multipage long journals and only,
right is it,
is that is if I'm seeing everything for
the first time,
it's as if I'm seeing everything for the
first time.
It's as if I'm seeing everything for the
And he was wandering around in a
constant state of awe,
you know,
and his wife would come to visit him.
He couldn't remember any of the things
that had happened to him.
And he'd just be blown out of the water
to see her,
you know,
because he didn't see his memories and
he'd say,
it's just like I'm seeing you for the
first time.
And you know,
he was,
he was seeing her for the first time
because the,
the access to the inhibitory structures
that were directing his attention were
gone.
He was an interesting case too,
because now,
and then he'd sit down to play the
piano,
you know,
and he'd have an epileptic seizure and
then he could play the piano and he
could play just like he used to play,
you know,
so it was like he had to switch brain
modes and the mechanism for switching
was damaged.
So we'd have to have a little seizure.
And then he could lay out these,
like Beethoven Sonata is like a mad dog.
And then at the end he'd have a little
seizure and he'd come back to,
it's as if I'm seeing everything for the
first time,
you know?
And I think part of the reason that
psychedelic drugs proved so attractive
to people in the 60s and improved
attractive to people since the bloody
beginning of time is because in some
sense that's what they do.
It's like Poof,
you're a memory representations.
They're gone and what are you seeing?
God only knows,
but it isn't what you expect.
And maybe it's what's there.
Well,
maybe not too.
Wow.
All right,
so I'm going to sum this up a little
bit.
What do you think drives to extreme
forms of pathology now that might be
your pathology,
your misery,
your suffering and all that,
or it might be your social
psychopathology,
which is your murderous desire to
exterminate.
Okay,
well here's a phenomenological theory.
The terror management theory is that you
got to build these structures in your
head to get yourself away from death
anxiety,
right?
And so really what the terror management
people are saying is the blinder you are
the better.
And that's what the pause disillusion
people think too.
Now,
the phenomenologists,
they were going at this from another
direction.
They were saying
the meaning that constantly reveals
itself is nourishing and revitalizing.
Although it's so powerful,
it can just blow you apart.
So it's a dangerous thing to be messing
with.
It's like the burning Bush and you,
you have to build this structure in
order to be able to cope with that
because you have to minimize it to what
you can handle.
But you need to build a structure
properly,
and carefully so that the meaning that
reveals itself can be shaped by you into
a world conceptual and practical.
That allows the remaining meaning to
shine through in a way that you find
sufficiently revitalizing so that you
don't become corrupt enough to become
genocidal.
Now that's a good theory and that's what
what the phenomenologists were on about.
And that's part of the reason why the
existentialists and the phenomenal,
I'll just say,
don't deceive yourself about what
manifests itself to you.
Don't use language instrumentally.
Why?
Because if you do that and twist up the
structures that you're using to
interpret the world through the world
will twist up on you.
And all live will be revealed is it's
harder.
And if horror is all that's always being
revealed to you,
you will not stay good.
Yeah.
Cause you can't,
under that sort of pressure,
you'll get bitter and resentful and
everything will fall apart around you
because you're not actually modeling the
reality in a way that the positive
meaning can shine through.
So you'll fail and you'll become
resentful and you'll become bitter.
And then you'll be looking for someone
to hurt and you'll have plenty of
justification for it.
So and worse,
and this is union contribution to this
whole idea.
This won't happen all at once.
It'll happen as a consequence of 100,000
micro decisions that you hardly even
notice where you can be truthful about
something or not in this tiny way that
hardly even seems to matter.
But that the consequence of iterating
that across time,
say 300,000 decisions is that you can
build yourself into the sort of monster
that you would never want to see in the
mirror.
And one of the things that
phenomenologists would also tell you,
and this is something you said as well,
is that is the sort of monster that you
probably are.
And so if you want to deal with that,
you have to start taking things
seriously.
And one of the things,
there's two things you have to take
seriously and one is the meaning that
reveals itself to you.
And the other is the stance of truth
towards which you were pro,
the stance of truth that you adopt while
you're interacting with that meaning.
And the final consequence of that would
be your health,
the health of your family and your
society and the health of the entire
society at large.
Pivots on that.
It pivots on that.
And that the way the world moves is a
sum total of all the decisions that are
all of us are making all those little
micro decisions and those bloody things
echo like ripples in a pond.
And so when you do some little crooked
thing that you know you shouldn't be
doing,
you're actually warping the entire
structure of reality.
And what's really interesting about that
is now we know what happens when you do
that.
What happens is that we end up with the
Nazis and the communists in the hydrogen
bombs,
and we haven't escaped from that yet,
and hopefully we will,
but we won't.
If people don't learn what the 20th
century had to teach them,
that's that.
Okay.