Yeah.
So today I'm talking to two of my
compatriots I suppose,
um,
in this ongoing discussion in Canada
about,
um,
free speech issues,
including compelled speech.
And I met Jared Brown and Bruce Party
jareds a practicing lawyer and Bruce is
a professor at Queen's University in the
law school there.
And I met them both when we were,
when we manifested a mutual interest
last year and bill see 16,
which we all regarded as,
um,
a piece of legislation that was
infringing on the rights to free speech
of Canadian individuals in a manner that
hadn't been ever attempted before.
Um,
and more recently the Law Society of
Upper Canada,
soon to be known as the Law Society of
Ontario has put forward a requirement
for all of its members.
So all of the lawyers in Ontario,
uh,
to produce a document,
a principle that we all have been
talking about,
the three of us have been talking about
that we regard as a another,
but far more egregious example of
compelled speech.
So I'm going to let jared introduce
himself and say a little bit about who
he is.
He testified with me at the Canadian
Senate last year.
Bruce Party also testified at the Senate
on Bill See 16,
and Bruce was also the lawyer that I
debated.
He played devil's advocate at Queen's
university at some of you watching this
will be familiar with that video.
So jared,
I'll let you introduce yourself.
And then Bruce and then Bruce Bruce
recently wrote a column for the,
now she'll post on this new requirement
by the law society.
And so we're going to let him begin the
discussion proper onto you.
Jared.
I'm a an everyday litigator.
I'm a commercial litigator in Toronto.
Uh,
I've been practicing for about 15 years,
um,
doing increasingly more and more human
rights tribunal work,
um,
things like that.
Um,
and obviously stepped into the breach on
[inaudible].
And as far as I can tell,
uh,
I may have been the only practicing
lawyer that actually spoke out against
the legislation.
Um,
there were certainly a lot of lawyers,
a including the Canadian bar association
that were,
uh,
arraigned in favor of the legislation.
But as far as I can tell,
uh,
boots on the ground,
I think I was the only one.
Um,
so I've got a pretty benign practice,
but,
um,
but certainly if a
taking up the fight if you will.
Okay.
Bruce.
Thanks Jordan.
Uh,
well this,
this issue arose for me a couple of
weeks ago when I received an email from
the law society and all lawyers get
these emails,
uh,
to do various things.
But this was different because it
announced a new requirement for this
year.
Uh,
jared I think was aware of this
developing,
uh,
before I was,
but,
but like many other lawyers in the
province,
this is supposed to the first indication
that,
uh,
this new requirement existed and
essentially email said,
um,
one of the things that said amongst
others was that every licensed lawyer
now is required to draft and submit what
they are calling a statement of
principles.
And that statement is,
is,
uh,
required to express your agreement and
the value you place on inclusion,
diversity and equality,
and the fact that you will actively
promote those values.
And that's me just sprung off the screen
as,
uh,
a,
an outrageous example of forced speech
out,
the same kind that we were talking about
under [inaudible] 16.
But,
but worse,
uh,
this one actually requires you to make a
full fledged statement that will be
subject to their approval in order to
maintain your license.
In other words,
this is not a matter of it being
suggested to you that you might ought to
want to do this.
This is a condition of your ability to
practice law in the province of Ontario.
So,
uh,
this district,
me as a matter that,
uh,
needed to be aired publicly,
I needed to be discussed amongst lawyers
in the province because this is a slow
march to a dark place,
I think.
And that's where it all began.
Yeah.
Well,
it was concerning to me when I
encountered this.
I mean,
I'm the member of a college as well at
college of psychologists.
And my sense of this is that if the
lawyers full and,
and,
and go along with this,
the probability that this will be
required of every professional in
Ontario and then very rapidly,
every profession in Canada is extremely
high because if some lawyers who are,
you know,
relatively disagreeable bunch and who
are very familiar with the law and with
common law in general are willing to
have their political beliefs dictated to
them by their college,
then the probability that the rest of us
will be able to withstand that I think
is extremely low.
So a strong,
a strong independent bar is always
supposed to
be the defense or at least one line of
defense against tyranny or against
government overreach.
And,
and by,
uh,
having the lawyers under the guise of
their regulatory body,
um,
being compelled to speak or,
or share opinions,
um,
it's obviously something scary and I
think it's something that lawyers should
wake up to and they need to push back
against compelled speech,
which was obviously the issue on see 16,
um,
is a particularly nefarious,
infringement and intrusion.
Yeah,
well it's,
I mean it's one thing to put
restrictions on what people say.
I mean I know you can't incite someone
to crime for example.
Um,
but it's a completely different thing to
require people to espouse a particular
political stance,
especially when the,
when,
when it's being reviewed by what's
essentially an arbitrary committee and
when the punishment is so as draconian
as,
as potentially losing your right to
practice and that that's enforced as a
mandatory,
like the first step was to make that
mandatory rather than as a suggestion.
So let's,
let's just emphasize this point that the
distinction between restrictions on
speech,
which,
which are not with things and are
debatable and so on.
But this is a different category of
question.
This is compelled speech.
This is a requirement that makes you say
something you may not agree with.
And uh,
I mentioned it'll be at the column I
statements from the Supreme Court of
Canada and maybe I'll just read out one
of those gyms too,
just to make the point.
Because even if the court has said
explicitly that,
uh,
that this is,
this is not on in a,
in a free society,
you're hear the words of the Supreme
Court,
uh,
forcing someone to express opinions that
they do not have is to tell Alterian and
as such,
alien to the tradition of free nations
like Canada,
even for the repression of the most
serious crimes,
which of course is not in Preston here.
Yeah,
I mean that was cool.
Sorry Jordan.
That was,
that was the cornerstone of not only the
opinion piece that I,
I put up on my website about
[inaudible],
but also in the cornerstone of the
presentation that was made to the Senate
is that this is a particularly egregious
infringement on freedom of expression.
Uh,
you're having to mouth opinions and
ideas that may not be your own and the
government is forcing you to do it.
And then obviously in this incidence,
so you've got your regulatory body,
which,
uh,
which holds your license,
in,
in your ability to carry on the
livelihood in the chosen profession that
you're in.
I'm telling you that you've got to start
voicing these opinions.
So,
jared,
when we talked before too,
one of the things that you pointed out,
and Bruce,
you had commented on this as well,
is that,
you know,
the,
the Law Society Administration
theoretically did some background work
before deciding that this was a
necessity.
And they produced a report essentially
proclaiming that the,
uh,
the law,
the people who are practicing law in
Ontario are essentially racist in their
orientation,
which is why this is racist and perhaps
misogynist as well,
which is why this piece of
administrative,
let's call it law or requirements,
has come into practice.
But it isn't obvious that their own data
support that conclusion.
I mean,
you can easily read what they wrote as
pretty providing pretty compelling
evidence that the legal profession,
the demographics of the legal profession
for what that's worth,
you are transforming quite rapidly.
And so,
um,
the thing that concerned me as well from
a psychological perspective about this
sort of thing is that lawyers who agree
to participate in this process are
basically admitting their racism and
misogyny on a conscious and unconscious
basis and thereby convicting themselves.
Like they're,
they're guilty to begin with.
They,
and they don't have an opportunity to
prove their innocence.
And by,
by going along with these requirements,
they're basically admitting through
their action that the accusations that
are being thrown at them both
individually and as a collective are,
are not only accurate but require
immediate remediation.
Yeah,
well,
I mean the,
the,
uh,
the rec or the requirement that's a
being rolled out right now as the result
of a,
I think it's about a 58 page report that
had 13 recommendations that were passed
by convocation,
which is the governing body of the law
society.
And the report itself,
uh,
was entitled strategies to address
issues of systemic racism in the legal
professions.
I mean,
that statement on its own is saying that
our,
our industry as well as the Law Society
Organization itself is systemically
racist.
And,
and clearly that's a to me,
I mean it's uh,
uh,
a very bold statement and one that I
think,
um,
requires some level of scrutiny.
Um,
you know,
the,
the group that came up with this report
is an esteemed group.
These are all highly respected,
uh,
well accomplished individuals.
And,
and you know,
there,
there is a body of data that they've
produced as well as,
um,
some qualitative anecdotal stories as to
some of the issues that are being faced
by,
uh,
by what they call racialized licensees.
I mean,
the data is something that a lot of
people aren't going to look at,
but I do encourage people to look at it
and see what,
what the basis on that finding that
we're a systemically racist industry
and,
and obviously profession.
Um,
I encourage people to look at it,
um,
study the report.
I can assure you that most,
most lawyers won't 58 pages,
uh,
something that happened back in
December.
But it,
there's,
um,
there's a lot of shocking,
information in there and there's a
obviously some shocking findings,
but,
um,
yeah,
no,
it's,
it's got me concerned because my,
my industry has now been deemed racist
by the body that governs it.
Yeah.
Well,
one of the things that's really
appalling about that and I think and
also about the requirements for the
statement of principles is that there's
a pronounced ideological bent to them.
Um,
and the first is the idea of systemic
racism because the way that you prove
systemic racism is,
is,
uh,
I would say,
let's say call it questionable
methodologically to say the least
because the basic concept is that you
divide the population up by racial,
ethnic and sex based identification,
which you can do in a very large number
of ways by the way.
And then you compare any organization,
uh,
to that population based division.
And if the,
the,
uh,
ratio of individuals categorized in the
general population isn't the same as the
ratio of individuals in that profession,
then you can automatically make a case
for systemic racism.
And that's a very,
very weak methodology.
No credible scientist would regard that.
And I would regard that as proof of
anything.
And worse,
I can't imagine that any,
any claim like that would stand up and
something resembling a court of law if,
if you know,
if it was possible to take a group to
court.
Cause there's all sorts of reasons why
there might be differential
representation in a group
and that,
and that is assuming that that's what
the data shows.
And in many respects that's actually
what this data shows.
So I take your point about the
methodology but but even so,
even if you like set that methodology,
it's not crystal clear that that's what
the numbers actually suggestion.
Can I get back for a moment to your,
to your implication point,
I mean I agree that the requirements to
make this statement in this context
essentially put,
be interpreted as though you were
required to make a confession about what
it is you've done wrongly in the past
and what it is you will do now in the
present to correct it as an individual.
And there is also the,
the the trouble that once you have
written a statement so as to come to
comply with the requirement,
then you have on the record a statement
of what it is that you believe and
thereafter your future actions can be
compared to that statement.
So as to show that you are not acting in
co in compliance with what you have set
you believe or that on one occasion or
the other,
you haven't been telling the truth.
So some,
some I've heard some lawyers say in
response to this requirement that,
oh well this is not a big deal because
I'll just going to write the statement.
They'll put it in a file,
it'll sit in some corner of the law
society computer.
And,
and who,
who cares,
it's no big deal,
but it actually,
it is a very big deal because they are
hurting you towards both a certain way
to think,
a certain way to express yourself and I,
and a certain restriction on your
behavior and your expression in terms of
how you,
what,
what you say you believe in the future
about this kind of law and all kinds of
other loans,
but also your subs.
You're subscribing to this idea that the
system is racist,
that the,
that the industry and the profession
themselves are racist.
And that to me that implies hopelessly
corrupt.
And I,
and that shocks me and I don't think I,
I want my industry,
uh,
advertising that unless of course,
you know,
we've got an issue here and,
and it's not entirely clear to me from
reading the report that we do.
Um,
but I,
Jordan May have some comments
obviously about writing,
writing a statement and the declaration
and what that means,
but I just find that,
you know,
having to affirm in a statement that,
uh,
our industry is,
is hopelessly corrupt,
is,
um,
it's not something I'm willing to do at
this point.
One of the things I've learned after
over the last year is that apologizing
or admitting guilt to ideologues is an
unbelievably dangerous thing to do
because all it's taken as,
as Bruce Basically alluded to,
is a statement of guilt.
And you know,
the other problem from a psychological
perspective is that,
and this,
this is a very clear psychological
literature on this.
So,
you know,
if you have a particular set of
philosophical positions,
let's say principles,
let's call them,
and maybe your principles or something
like excellence,
meritocracy and honesty,
which strike me as a better set of
principles for lawyers than diversity,
equity and inclusiveness.
Not that those aren't,
you know,
in in certain context and carefully
defined.
Also important.
Um,
if you write a statement of principle,
especially one that's going to have to
pass muster,
then what will happen is you will bring
your beliefs and your actions in line
with that statement of principle.
You'll do that unconsciously.
And there's a bunch of reasons for that.
And one reason is,
is that you've now made a coherent and
credible argument in favor of that set
of principles.
And you will find that convincing
because articulating yourself in that
manner actually changes your character.
And the second is,
is that it puts you in into a position
that's,
um,
that's often been described as cognitive
dissonance,
which is one of the most famous findings
in,
in psychology.
And cognitive dissonance is the UN on a
pleasant feeling that you get when
you're holding two opposing beliefs,
let's say at the same time.
And you notice that.
And so the cognitive dissonance here
would be,
well,
I'm just going to write this statement
of principles.
What difference does it make?
But however,
that is a statement of principles.
And so it's,
it's intrinsically dishonest and,
and character damaging to craft a
statement of Principles with which you
do not agree.
And so then you can either regard
yourself as a coward and a liar or you
bring your thinking in line with the
statement of principles and that the
latter thing is what people tend to do.
And so,
and then the idea that this is just
going to sit in some musty,
uh,
file drawer.
That's completely,
that's completely naive in my estimation
because basically what's happening,
and I've seen this happening with the
creep of ethics committees on university
campuses,
is that once you decide that you're
guilty and that you're going to abide by
a new set of principles,
it now becomes incumbent on the law
society as a matter of the intrinsic
logic of the,
of the movement to do things like check
you out on a year to year basis to see
how your attitude and behavior is.
Uh,
actually in keeping with your statement
of principles,
it's not just going to hang there in the
air,
it's going to be enforced.
And that is part of the transition I
would say from the law society,
regulating competence,
regulating values.
I mean it used to be at one point the
last study was there to make sure that
you had the skills to be able to
practice law and as time has gone on
there,
there are overseeing is more and more in
the area what it is that you sync and
whether or not that thinking is
appropriate.
And one good comparison of this is the
uh,
the case involving the Trinity Western
Law School of the,
the uh,
graduates of that law school.
So this is a private law school that
would be in bridge and they require all
their,
all their faculty and students to sign
on to a pledge that had,
contains certain values.
They promised not to do certain things
like have premarital sex and,
and uh,
all kinds of other things.
The law society on the basis,
I think that it is inappropriate for an
institution to impose values upon the
people within it have said that they
will not license graduates from the
possible.
Now you might agree or disagree with
that perspective,
but it is different critical now that
what they have done is the same thing
essentially except with a different set
of values.
They have indeed imposed instead of
values on the people within their own
institution.
It's just that they haven't chosen
different values,
which means that their objection to turn
to your question,
it was not really at all about the
position of the values.
They just don't like the values that
attorney Western chosen.
Yeah.
What,
it's pretty ironic that the argument
would be made that an organization
doesn't have the right to impose its
value.
So when it's on it's voluntary
participants,
which we should point out because you
certainly don't have to go to Trinity
Western or signed the agreement.
There's lots of law schools you can go
to where he's in this particular
situation.
You're basically,
I mean to say that a gun is pointed to
your head is too dramatic obviously,
but it's no joke to be faced with it.
With the threat of losing your license
and also to have to undergo what would
essentially be a bureaucratic
inquisition and those are not pleasant.
Those are seriously not pleasant if you,
if you fail to comply.
No.
And there's other,
there's other parts of this before we
leave Trinity Western,
can we just underline what you just
said,
which I think is very important,
which is that that the law society is
essentially an arm of the state.
It has coercive power given to it by the
state to license lawyers and it is the
gatekeeper,
so you have no choice.
Whereas as,
as you said,
Jordan,
the they association with Trinity
Western is entirely voluntary.
If you don't want to go to that school,
you don't go to that school.
And so it's,
it's,
it's ironic in the extreme that
it is the law society,
which is a,
which has imposed such a requirement in
circumstances that is much more
objectionable than the Trinity Western
situation.
And it's quite,
it's quite disconcerting to me to say
the least to see that it's actually
lawyers that are doing this and that
have that and that and that they're not
capable of seeing or unwilling to see
for some reasons that I don't really
understand why that this is an egregious
assault on the rights of,
of,
well I would say of of lawyers in
Ontario but also of individual citizens
in Canada.
It's like the fact that that,
that it's lawyers that are involved in
this is really,
um,
I find that much more terrifying in some
sense than the unfounded or likely
unfounded accusation that the entire,
um,
profession is racist,
which are also,
you know,
now what are people who are to use the
hated word racialized,
which is also an ideological term
supposed to conclude if all the lawyers
in Ontario,
um,
just go along with this whole,
they're really supposed to be able to go
into a law firm and trust that their,
um,
their claims are going to be put forward
with,
with fairness and clarity and
commitment.
If the whole society is already agreed
and the lawyers go along with it,
that it's an intrinsically racist
association and how is that going to do
anything but damage,
racial and,
and,
and sex related.
Um,
what would you call them?
Relationships in Canada.
I just can't see that as anything,
but you know,
it's supposed to be something that
brings us together with regards to,
let's call it inclusiveness,
but I can't see this as anything other
than something that's going to be
extraordinarily divisive.
Well,
interesting.
You were,
you were raising the issue of,
of why are lawyers going along with it
or why aren't they recognizing the
danger?
Um,
you know,
there was some,
some talk about this at the convocation
meeting where,
where these recommendations were passed.
There were some dissenting voices and
very,
very well put dissenting voices.
But um,
you know,
just within my own professional network,
most lawyers don't know what's going on.
They got the email.
Um,
they didn't think anything of it.
We get a,
you know,
12 of these things a month.
It's just an additional requirement,
another piece of paper.
Now,
interesting.
What the law society has done when they
pushed this requirement out is they also
said,
by the way,
if you need some help completing this
statement of declar,
uh,
statement of principles,
we're going to provide two templates
that would satisfy us.
And of course,
98% of the,
the lawyers that I practice with who are
our he time grinds,
what are they gonna do?
They're gonna file it out of their
template a or B,
get on with their life.
And,
and so it's one of those things where
you've got time pressed lawyers,
uh,
or,
or licensees and you've got a
bureaucracy adding a new law,
a level of requirement to them,
and they're just going to,
to,
um,
go along to get,
and
from what I can tell,
when I do stop people and ask them about
their statement of principles,
that's the first time they've actually
thought about it.
Yeah,
go ahead bruce.
The fact that as a template,
and you can choose between one or up to
10 points.
Yeah,
that doesn't make it less of a concern.
It's actually more,
I don't want to overstate this,
but this is,
it has a lot of similarities to
mccarthyism.
Yes.
Cause I don't statement that you know I
am not now nor have I ever been a member
of the communist party that that was the
templates in the McCarthy era.
It's just a template.
You have to say certain things and and
look how meaningless it becomes in terms
of actual substance.
If it's a template and you just sign on,
then they have literally put words in
your mouth and that is the thing that
cannot be allowed to happen.
I agree with that.
And in a couple of ways.
I mean the first thing is is that if
they were committed to this in any deep
sense,
the last thing they would provide was a
template because the idea that you can,
you can require from people a statement
of principles that's of such fundamental
import that if it is not crafted
properly,
you lose your license.
And yet that they could produce a
template of principles that wouldn't see
in some manner apply to everyone
equally.
It's just,
it's absurd.
Almost beyond comprehension.
I mean,
principals actually happened to be
important,
right?
From a psychological perspective,
your deepest principles are the axioms
from which you generate not only your
thoughts and your actions,
but your perceptions,
your emotional responses and your
motivation.
It's like there's virtually nothing more
important from the perspective of
psychological integrity then your
principles and to think that those could
be reduced to an externally produced
template and that that could be imposed
as a requirement.
So it would be easier for you is it's
like it,
it reminds me of the Soviet era where
there were templates of guilt,
you know,
if you were accused of something,
regardless of whether you were guilty or
not,
because that really wasn't very
relevant,
you'd be required to sign a template of
guilt essentially.
And that would well,
and once you've done that well you were
done.
And so it's really quite,
it's really quite amazing that that from
a conceptual philosophical perspective
that that sort of thing could even be
considered for a moment as,
as as acceptable.
And it seems to me to be a way of
sliding it in under the door.
It,
as jared pointed out,
people are busy.
And the other thing is,
you know,
when I made my first videos objecting to
bill,
see 16 last year,
part of what motivated me was a comment
by a colleague and about political
correctness on campuses.
And he said,
well,
you know,
the consequence of standing up against
it from a personal perspective is
extremely,
and the probability that your opposition
to it is going to have a broad scale.
A social consequence is very low.
And so the,
the logical thing to do,
especially if you're pressed for time
and,
and also if you want to not put your
head up above the herd where it can be
locked off is to a not notice because
you're too busy.
And B,
because you're isolated as an individual
in this circumstance facing a large
group.
Um,
the easiest thing to do,
especially when you're concerned with
other things,
is just to go along with it because
you're isolated,
right?
You don't know if there's other people
who,
who might be feeling uneasy about this.
And there's no real way of telling,
well,
particularly in our profession,
my understanding is that the majority of
lawyers in the province of Ontario are
generally practicing in a small firm
environment,
are sole practitioners.
And so you're going to have a lot of
people standing on an island on their
own,
in their own practice and they're not
going to fully appreciate that this is
an issue.
Uh,
what other people are thinking and
they're absolutely going to think that
they're putting their head above the
heard.
Um,
so it,
it,
we have a unique,
I think we have a unique industry in
that regard.
Well,
let's just make it this point at this
moment in time,
which is that all those lawyers who
think that they may be sticking their
head out all by themselves are actually
not.
Because you know,
I have certainly heard from a good
number of lawyers now who are all
extremely concerned,
shocked,
alarmed at this.
So the one thing that we want to
overcome is the possible inclination to
think that that any lawyer who is
concerned about this is an army of one.
And that in this situation is not the
case.
So there,
there,
there are possibilities here that if,
if people do act upon their concerns
and,
uh,
decline to comply with this requirement,
that the change in this situation
actually is a possibility.
Well,
bruce,
there's also the,
the uh,
the people that,
uh,
that we're servicing.
I mean,
in the private practice world,
clients,
the clients are going to watch this.
They want to know what we're doing.
I think they want their,
their lawyers to stand up on their
principles,
if you will,
and push back against something.
And I think that there's something to
be,
to be said in terms of your
differentiation in the marketplace,
particularly in private practice,
if you do exactly that.
My clients were relying on me to be this
bulwark against this type of thing.
And I think a lot of lawyers should,
uh,
should take note of that.
That,
that there might be something here worth
fighting for.
Yeah,
I totally agree.
I mean,
really your,
your lawyer credibility is at stake
here.
You can't stand up and protect herself.
When your own fundamental rights are,
are,
are being threatened,
then why should clients believe you have
the ability to do so on their map?
No,
the inclination to do so.
You know,
because by swollen we can just hook,
line and sinker,
let's say an exceeding to what's
essentially an ideological demand.
Um,
then you also brand yourself as an
Avatar of that particular radiology.
And so that's another reason to not be
trusted.
You know,
that there's the aspect of inability to
stand up for yourself or unwillingness
to,
but then the two to come out as a,
as an active agent for this,
for this particular set of,
of let's call them principles,
which,
and,
and there's absolutely no reason to make
the assumption that the whole,
the new holy trinity of diversity,
equity and inclusiveness constitutes the
highest order of moral value.
It's,
in fact,
I think it's an extraordinarily weak
argument.
If that's the case,
there's,
there's flaws in it at virtually every
level of analysis.
So,
and it certainly runs contrary to the
central themes of,
of,
of English common law,
for example.
So we make note just for a moment,
the fact that the law society is playing
a little bit close to their chest in the
sense that they have not spelled out
what the penalty is going to be for
those lawyers who declined to,
to comply with this requirement.
They've only sit and their materials
that those lawyers who are not
compliance will be advised of their
obligations in writing,
which of course leaves all the choices
open to the law society.
Well,
and that was discussed,
uh,
to some extent at the convocation
meeting.
There was concerns what happens,
what is the recourse here and,
and I,
I'm left to speculate,
but what your obligations are typically
is to file what's called the Mendel
member's annual report of which this is
going to be a component of it by not
filling out a portion of your member's
annual report.
I'm sure that you're going to face at a
minimum what's called an administrative
processor suspension.
And it may even turn into something much
larger than that.
So,
I mean,
I'm speculating,
but absolutely the Law Society did not
make clear what's going to happen if,
if somebody decides that they don't want
to go along to get along.
Yeah.
Well that's also rather troublesome in
and of itself,
you know,
because it's,
it's just not reasonable to,
to specify a requirement and then leave
the penalty undefined.
And it smacks of political opportunism
from my perspective because it means
that the law society hasn't put itself
on the line with regards to the degree
to which they're going to be draconian
about this and then can incrementally,
um,
introduced the penalties on a per person
basis,
which is where you would get the least
amount of pushback too.
Because if you're a professional and
then the board goes after you like it's
a horrifying experience and especially,
you know,
it puts your family livelihood and your
reputation online and it's very
expensive to deal with and time
consuming and troublesome and an anxiety
provoking and all of those things.
So you have someone who's immediately
put in a tremendous position of weakness
in order to to say push back against
this.
When the law society,
it's all public as well.
So I mean the,
the,
the role of the law society from what I
understand is to protect the public from
the big bad lawyers.
That's why we are a self regulating
industry.
And one of the things that,
uh,
that the law society does is it has,
it makes its disciplinary process
public.
So things like administrative
suspensions or,
or disciplinary action are things that
would be known to the public.
So you're out there potentially being
tarred and feathered on this thing and
people are going to know,
yeah,
well and to streamline important for a
professional to maintain a pristine
reputation.
And even the,
what,
what would you call it?
Even the suggestion that you're known in
accordance with even an administrative
detail with regards to the law society
is you can imagine that that's going to
put doubt in the mind of anyone who
called,
knows you or doesn't know you.
So that means the process is the
punishment.
And that's very much the case with these
mid level organizations where it seems
to me that proclivity for,
uh,
more totalitarian view of the world is
like leaping forward in leaps and or in
leaps and bounds.
So,
so,
so we consider for a moment what we
might suggest to all the lawyers who are
concerned about this and don't want to
go along with the requirement what it is
that what we wouldn't suggest that they
do.
Jared,
do you want to take them off?
Well,
it seems to be you approach that in your
article,
the national post in,
in a,
in a pretty adept way.
And that,
and my first inclination is that is that
you don't file,
I mean,
the act of filing in itself as we've
already discussed is,
is half of the admission of guilt,
if you will.
Um,
and I mean,
uh,
I think that not filing sense sends a
good,
a good statement,
but then,
you know,
you want to obviously let them know why
you're not filing.
So perhaps you have to send something
that would let them,
the law society,
the regulator know why you're not
filing.
I mean those are the things that come to
mind and you,
you discuss them I think quite well.
So it's what I do too.
For them to realize that you didn't just
forget,
you actually consciously decided that it
wasn't a thing that you were going to
do.
I think that's a very good idea.
Yes.
I'm kind of short statement but not,
I mean,
I wouldn't be inclined to suggest that
they should draft their own statement of
principles that reflects what they
actually think,
uh,
because then they are actually going
three quarters of the way of what,
of what they've been asked to do.
I mean,
there's no reason why,
even if they've been says something that
you believe that you should be filing
it.
Uh,
because it's still forced speech.
They're still requiring him to make that
statement.
So yes.
And it's not a,
it's none of their business.
And,
and I mean,
I thought about that myself.
I thought maybe you do a google memo,
you know,
Demora more Google memo,
but then I thought,
no,
you're,
you're playing the game.
You are,
you are declaring your thoughts to,
to the regulator.
And I think that's reprehensible.
Yes,
I agree.
They don't have any right to the content
of your thoughts,
not unless you're to voluntarily put
them forward.
And that's definitely a difference.
A very big difference between,
well,
the assessment of competence which has
already taken place after you've passed
the bar and you're in compliance with
the,
uh,
with the regulatory boards requirements
and the idea that they should have
privileged access to your deepest
principles is,
I agree that's absolutely reprehensible.
There's no excuse for it whatsoever.
Whether you,
whether you agree with the principles
they want you to agree with or not and
it's reprehensible.
Yes.
Oh yes.
Let's emphasize this point.
Oh,
this is,
this is essentially a debate about
whether or not those values are,
are good or bad or desirable or
undesirable.
This is about the forced speech first
and foremost.
But the idea that you can be required to
indicate how you feel about them and you
agree with some,
an endorsement zone,
even if you do agree with them and
endorse them,
the idea that you must have to say so it
is,
is just not on it.
It crosses a line into a dark place that
that,
uh,
does not bode well for the future of
freedom of speech in this country.
Yes,
the rules go ahead and drink
the rules of professional conduct for
lawyers,
um,
already have a rule that requires us to
act in accordance with the Human Rights
Code and principles of,
of uh,
um,
not to discriminate I guess is the word
I'm using.
And so clearly our actions are already
governed by a code of conduct and,
and,
and by the legislation generally.
So for them to,
to request the statement of principles,
it really is just asking you to the way
you think.
And so it's not like,
it's not like this is needed.
It's like it's,
it's the distinction between your
obligation to comply with the law and to
state that you agree with the law.
Which again,
going back to the Supreme Court of
Canada is,
is our,
are two quite different things.
I read again what the Supreme Court said
on this question.
Three court says this,
however admirable the objectives and
provisions of the law.
Maybe no one is obliged to approve of
them.
Anyone.
May criticize them and seek to have them
amended or repealed,
although complying with them so long as
there are ineffective.
So this is not a question of whether
lawyers are subject to human rights code
and antidiscrimination laws.
That is,
that is not the question here.
The question is whether or not you are
required to endorse them and say that
you agree,
which is quite a different thing.
The other thing that disturbs me about
this,
and I suppose this is a consequence of
my experience with delving deeply into
the history of places like the Soviet
Union in its early stages of development
is that there's a class based guilt
phenomena that's,
that's,
that's lurking at the bottom of this
too,
which is also absolutely I would say
terrifying.
So let's just say for a moment,
although I don't believe this,
that there is systemic racism among
lawyers defined the way that this sort
of thing is defined.
Um,
but what this requirement,
um,
implies is that every single lawyer of
that group is now guilty of that
phenomena,
merely sb and merely as a consequence of
being a member of that class of people.
And you know,
there is something,
the idea of class based guilt is,
well first of all it's the basis for
racism itself,
right?
So,
but it's,
it's a terrifying proposition from the
perspective of a informed Western
individual because one of the bedrock,
uh,
presuppositions,
let's call it a principle of our legal
structure,
is that you're judged on your guilt or
innocence as an individual,
not as the member of a class.
And believe me,
that is not a road we want to walk down
because there's,
you know,
each of us,
it might be the members of six or seven
different classes and if you look into
the history,
let's say of those classes,
whatever they are,
economic,
professional,
racial,
gender based,
whatever,
the probability that sometime in the
past,
some members of our so called class did
things that were morally reprehensible
or illegal is 100% and if we're going to
be judged on the basis of the actions
taken by people that we didn't even know
merely because we happen to be vaguely
associated with that group,
then we're all guilty of all sorts of
terrible things all the time.
And that puts us completely in the hands
of people who want to make those guilt
bay,
those group guilt based accusations and
that's,
that's a very,
very bad,
it's almost impossible to overstress how
bad an idea that is.
Yes,
absolutely.
I mean there,
there is no one that you can't identify
who in terms of group association and in
terms of of lineage as well.
I mean this is also a casting the net
back into history to see if you know,
which,
which group did wrong to,
to which group.
But of course there,
there is no one who doesn't have
somewhere in their ancestral lineage,
you know,
wrongs done by somebody you related to,
to some other person.
And if,
if that is the record is the criteria
for guilt as you have said,
then everybody is guilty and the whole
thing starts to become silicon.
Yes.
Well when everyone's guilty that means
that the people who hold the right to
punishment become all powerful.
Yes.
And all discretionary to yes.
That,
at least in Soviet Russia,
they,
they'd prime you up and torture you a
bit before they had you swear your
statement of a,
of principles or your confession,
if you will.
So,
okay.
So here's another thing that I thought I
might do is I'm going to put together an
anonymous list.
Um,
so that lawyers who are willing to
indicate their,
um,
objections to this requirement can sign
up.
And that way I can tweet and also stay
in contact with you guys on a regular
basis,
how many signatories I've obtained and I
won't make that public.
I'll make sure that it's not crackable.
And,
um,
that way it'll help people discover how
many other people are also concerned
about this and indicate to what degree
there might be strength in numbers.
And so I'll set that up very carefully
and I'll put the link to that in the
description of this video.
And so I guess we've decided on three
potential,
um,
modes of action and,
uh,
jareds fundamental suggested,
if I remember correctly,
was to not file the statement of
principle and also write a letter
indicating precisely why.
And I guess that would be,
well it
might be most effective if you filed a
piece of paper as your fitness but don't
make it a statement just to say on the
statement of principles that you object
to filing if they can or principles or
if they wish to call them.
They're more than welcome to just to,
just to send in a copy of the it from
the National Post.
Anything that,
anything that indicates that you're not
doing this,
you haven't just forgotten,
but there is a piece of paper that is
filed in place of what they've asked for
but it is not what they've asked for.
Okay,
so that can be very straight forward.
That means that it wouldn't necessarily
be very time consuming.
You could take,
you can take the time to delineate why
you're opposed to this or you could send
to in Nicola more.
You could just state that you're opposed
to this.
Yeah,
I don't think they should go to great
lengths.
I think it's very simple and they just
say something like,
this is forced speech and I choose not
to comply or send to the column or
something,
something that that stands for.
The proposition that I'm,
I'm declining this request.
And it can be very short.
It does not have to be a full reason.
Yeah.
I objected to be justifiable.
Most lawyers know how to do that if
they've been in a courtroom.
Yes,
exactly.
Yeah,
that's right.
It should be,
it should be something they're quite
accustomed to doing.
And so,
and then I'll put up this late for the
last so that we can start to collect
signatories and decide who,
and let people know how many people are
actually,
let's call it philosophically and
professionally opposed to this
particular set of maneuvers.
And to be clear,
we don't,
I don't want to know anybody's politics.
I don't want to know anything other than
are they uncomfortable with the idea of
being compelled to do something,
uh,
to speak something.
And I mean,
that's,
that's important and going to be a lot
of people who are concerned about
anonymity.
And I,
I fully respect that.
But,
but they need to know that there is
people out there that are like mindedly
objecting to this.
Now,
one question obviously that comes up
about this and I don't,
what do you want to speak to this,
but I understand if there have been
conversations between lots of various
people about whether or not a legal
action is a possibility,
uh,
on this,
you'd do you want to just make some very
general comments?
I think it's a,
I mean it's,
it,
this may come to a head and I and I have
had discussions with,
with many people within my own
professional network and I'm trying to
expand that network and I've had it at
least one person,
um,
very senior lawyer come forward and say,
I'm prepared to challenge this.
I'm prepared to be the person that takes
the slings and arrows,
uh,
through a challenging process.
And,
and I mean,
I imagine it would have to flow through
the law society initially,
but at some point you are entitled to,
to Judicial Review of,
of regulatory decisions.
So it would get pushed out into the
general court system at some point.
Um,
but yeah,
absolutely it can if,
if,
if let's say what,
there are people that are willing to,
to go to the mat for this.
And that's what I've been able to a,
to discern just within my own network.
Okay.
Well that's reassuring.
Well,
it's the way lawyers should be.
We're supposed to be objectionable,
aren't we?
Is we'll put that feature to good.
The good news.
Yes.
Well that's exactly it.
I would say from a temperamental
perspective,
lawyers are perfectly positioned to do
that because they tend to be rather
disagreeable and emotionally stable.
And so we do the rest of us and I'm
speaking as the member of another
professional,
uh,
um,
organization.
We depend on you guys to be the bull
work against any incursions into our
essential rights.
And if you guys fold and,
and,
and go along with this,
then it's really not a good day for,
for the English common law,
that's for sure.
And I think the English common law is
one of the most remarkable achievements
of civilization of world civilization.
It's an absolute gift and evolved legal
system.
It works unbelievably well.
And to,
and to not object to serious challenges
to it at a fundamental level means that
we deserve whatever restrictions on our
freedoms we accrue as a consequence of
our cowardice.
And to let that happen when we're really
just not paying attention would be the
ultimate tragedy.
Okay.