Apologies for my prolonged absence.
I've been dealing over the last few
weeks with my somewhat shaky current
health.
It seems probable that I could use a
rest if I had the opportunity and I knew
how I should probably be having a rest
right now,
but be that as it may,
I have prepared this letter
presumptuously to the world or at least
to that corner of it with which I can
communicate here at the dawn of the New
Year in these perilous times,
although I usually speak
extemporaneously.
That takes a level of capacity that I
cannot quite currently manifest,
so I'm going to read instead.
It's also a careful argument,
I hope,
and it required the editing for which
only the written word can suffice.
Dear world.
On January 16th,
I'm going to talk with Sam Harris on his
podcast,
waking up with Sam Harris.
Dr Harris is one of the so called new
atheists,
of which there are four,
like the other three,
Christopher Hitchens,
Dan Dennett,
and Richard Dawkins,
who by the way,
I always wanted particularly to debate
Dr Harris is a smart guy and I'm
certainly not complaining that or will
encounter him instead of darkens,
so I'm preparing my arguments carefully,
although I have been doing so for years.
The specific ideas I'm going to share
with you today,
we're obsessing me from the moment I
woke up somewhat fitfully this morning,
so I dictated them to my son and then
edited them with his help.
The central problem of human beings
isn't religion.
As the new atheists insist,
it's tribalism.
We know this in part because chimps,
our closest biological kin go to war and
they're not religious,
although they are tribal.
Tribalism also has a central problem and
it's not competition.
Despite the tendency of competition to
produce at least temporarily,
winners and losers.
The problem of tribalism is cooperation
because cooperation is what allows us to
exist is bounded groups.
A group by definition is a collective
cooperatively aiming at something.
It can't be aimed at nothing because
nothing cannot unite.
It only divides
thus attacks on collective purpose
because of its tendency to produce
tribalism.
Merely divide
the politics of identity which emerge
when the central purpose is criticized
to destructively inevitably produced the
situation described in the story of the
Tower of Babel,
everyone fragments into primitive tribes
and speaks their own mutually
incomprehensible language.
One alternative to fragmentation is of
course,
union under a banner,
a collective ideal cause or purpose.
The problem with uniting under a banner
as the postmodernist to push identity
politics rightly pointed out,
is that to value something means similar
caneously to devalue other things.
Thus to value isn't exclusionary
process,
but the alternative is valueless snus,
which is equivalent denialism and
nihilism does not produce freedom from
exclusion.
It just makes everyone excluded and
that's an intolerable state
directionless,
uncertain,
chaotic,
and angst ridden.
When such uncertainty reaches a critical
level,
the counter response appears first,
the unconscious,
and then the collectively expressed
demand for a leader possessed by the
spirit of totalitarian,
certainty who promises above all to
restore order.
The society without a unifying principle
oscillates unmoored between nihilism and
totalitarianism.
Human beings have been wrestling with
this problem since the beginning of
civilization when our capacity to form
large groups for all its advantages also
started to pose a new threat that the
hyper domination of the state collective
or purpose,
but without the state,
there's just fragmentation into smaller
groups.
The group itself cannot be done away
with because for better or worse,
human beings are social animals,
not loners like sharks are.
Tigers were team players,
but being on one team means not being on
others just means that any given team
sidelines marginalizes and alienates
those who cannot play their game as well
as conflicting with other teams in the
West.
Starting in the Middle East,
thousands of years ago,
a new idea began to emerge.
Evolve is not too strong a word in the
collective imagination.
You might following,
darkens.
Consider this a meme,
although this is far too weak a word
yes idea it.
Development can be traced back through
Egypt and Mesopotamia before
disappearing into unwritten history is
that of the divine individual.
Just beyond old work of the imagination
is a dramatic presentation of an
emergent idea,
which is the solution to how to organize
social being without falling prey to
nihilistic,
divisiveness or deceitful totalitarian
certainty.
The group must unite,
but under the banner of the individual,
the individual is the source of new
wisdom that updates the antiquated
nihilistic or totalitarian detritus and
glory of the past.
For better or for worse,
that idea reaches its apogee and
Christianity.
The divine individual is masculine
because the feminine is not individual.
The divine feminine is instead mother
and child.
However,
it is a hallmark of Christian
supposition that the redemption of both
men and women come through the masculine
and that's because the masculine is the
individual.
The central realization express
dramatically and symbolically is that
the subordination of the group to the
ideal of the divine individual is the
answer to the paradox of nihilism and
totalitarianism.
The divine individual is the man that
every man admires and the man whom all
women want their men to be.
The divine individual is the ideal firm
which deviations are punished by the
group with contempt and disgrace and
fidelity to which is rewarded by the
group with attention and honor.
The divine individual is not the winter
of any individual game,
but the player who plays fairly and is
there for continually invited to play.
The divine individual is the builder,
maintainer,
and expander of the state.
He who boldly goes where no man has gone
before and someone who eternally watches
over the widows and the children
is power of direct and honest
communication is that which identifies,
discusses and then resolves the
continually emergent problems of human
existence.
It is for this reason that he is
regarded as the savior of the world.
The primary image for women is not the
divine individual because of the heavy
burden they bear.
For reproduction,
it is instead the divine mother and
child.
This is not to say that man is the
divine individual and woman is not.
Although such confusion is
understandable given the complexity of
the problem.
Men like women have the divine mother
and child as an element of their
personality in man.
However,
it's in the background,
so to speak,
as the divine individuals in the
background of the psyche for women,
men by necessity play a less primary
role in the care of children.
This frees them to act as individuals in
a manner that up to now has been nearly
impossible for women.
Identification with these images is
belief in belief is not the statement of
agreement with a set of facts,
but the willingness to act something
out,
to become something,
to stake your life on something
for men and women alike.
This means voluntary adoption of
responsibility,
responsibility for oneself,
family and state.
It's in that responsibility and not in
reits.
That meaning itself resides,
the meaning that makes life bearable.
Societies that refuse to honor both of
these elements therefore doom their
inhabitants to purposelessness
unhappiness,
sterility and the aforementioned dangers
of nihilistic,
divisible and deceitful,
oppressive totalitarian,
certainty.
The meaning and responsibility is the
necessary meaning in life
which can serve as a counterbalance to
it's terrible fragility and tenuousness.
People must unite under the banner not
of their group and not of nothingness,
but if the individual.
This is a brilliant and intrinsically
paradoxical solution to the problems of
nihilistic nothingness and too rigid
group identity alike.
It's the consciousness of the individual
which transforms the chaos of potential
into habitable cosmos.
Has the greatest origin stories
repeatedly insist.
It is that same consciousness which
stands up rebellious and revelatory to
break down the pathological and too
rigid order of that cosmos when it is
become old,
infirm,
willfully blind and corrupt.
It is that consciousness which is the
image of God.
It dwells within every embodied human
form.
The fact of its existence is the reason
that the law of the land itself must be
bound by ultimate respect for the
individual regardless of his or her sins
and crimes.
It is that consciousness,
not the objective material substrate of
being which should be regarded as the
ultimate reality.
There is no self evident reason why dad
mattered should be given ontological
primacy over living spirit.
Although doing so as produced a massive
increase in human technological power,
it has left that power in the hands of
an increasingly disenchanted populous
and that presents a mortal danger.
Such power must be wielded by those who
have truly and voluntarily accepted the
responsibility of being less to prove
fatal.
The West has long been the civilized
embodiment of the idea of the divine
individual who does exactly that.
That's what the voluntary lifting of the
cross of suffering symbolically
represents.
For all its faults which are manifold,
the West has therefore served as a
shining beacon of hope
to those destined to inhabit places too
chaotic or too rigid for the human
spirit to tolerate,
but the West is in grave danger of
losing its way.
The negative consequences of this can
hardly be overstated.
A close reading of 20th century history
indicates as nothing else can,
the horrors that accompany
loss of faith in the idea
of the individual.
It is only the individual.
After all who suffers,
the group does not suffer
only those who compose it.
That's the reality of the individual
must be regarded as primary.
If suffering is to be regarded seriously
without such regard,
there can be no motivation to reduce
suffering and therefore no respites.
Instead,
the production of individual suffering
can and has
and will be again,
rationalized and justified for it
supposedly benefits for the future,
and the group
effective birth control has emerged as
one of the consequences of our powerful
technological materialism.
This has been accompanied by the rise of
states efficiently civilized so that
women who inhabit them can walk the
streets,
unaccompanied in safety.
We do not yet know how to balance the
opportunities provided for expanded
female individuality with the eternal
necessity for a woman to serve as the
mother of the divine individual.
Dividing our civilization into polarized
ideological camps of female group
identity and male group identity is
certainly not the answer.
We have to be honest,
male and female alike about what we
really want as individuals and talk it
out.
We know beyond dispute the societies who
emancipate their women are more
productive and peaceful and that the
relationship is causal.
That's not a matter of if but how
but such immense amounts of patient
places a dual burden on the now more
autonomous woman who is required to
balance manifesting the potential of
individual spirit within necessity of
desire to bear and rear the next
generation of mankind to live with free
women,
gain the advantages of their freedom and
sophistication.
Man Must therefore bring their shadowed
psychic identification with the divine
mother and child into the light without
losing their divine individuality in the
process.
They must consciously,
voluntarily,
deliberately and strategically except
their responsibility for the
relationship between autonomous female
companionship,
support,
love,
and the responsibility of producing that
next generation.
This means rejecting among other things
the misbegotten idea of casual sexual
gratification.
Sex is either the impulsive,
short term gratification of a
domineering biological instinct or the
Union of two conscious spirits taking
responsibility for what they are doing.
The former is simply not commensurate
with the demands of an advanced
civilization which requires the adoption
of responsibility above all for its
preservation,
maintenance,
and expansion.
It is for this reason that the
sexualized interactions between young
men and women in universities,
for example,
are increasingly and inevitably falling
under the harsh and tyrannical
regulation of the state.
In the West,
we are as well.
Shuttering are great cathedrals.
That was marvelous monumental
embodiments of the idea of the divine
individual on which our civilization is
based.
This is no mirror practical material
matter.
It's a symbolic and ideational process
whose importance cannot be overstated.
Without that central idea,
we will dissolve and be lost.
It is time for each of us to consciously
realize what the great symbolic stories
of the past insist upon that we are all
sons and daughters of the divine logos,
consciousness itself,
bearers of it's light,
and that we must act in accordance with
that great central fact last,
all hell break loose.
This means above all to tell the truth
and to care for one another,
starting at the level of the individual
and proceeding from that out to the
broader reaches of society itself.
The alternative,
as the same stories have always
insisted,
is the more permanent instantiation of
the horror that we already saw manifest
in multiple forums in the last bloody
terrible century.
We need to wake up individual man and
woman alike and we need to do it now.
Each of us must take the world on her
shoulders
in so far as we're capable of that and
adopt individual responsibility for the
horrors and suffering its existence
entails
in that we will find the meaning without
which life is merely the suffering that
breeds first resentment and then the
desire for vengeance and destruction.
We need to take responsibility instead
of incessantly insisting on our rights.
We need to become adults instead of aged
children.
We need to tell the truth.
We need justice and compassion,
conjoined,
not judgment in pity which crushing
devour
so in the coming year.
Plan to make yourself a better person.
Fix what you can and would fix.
Start now.
There's something right in front of you,
demanding repair,
calling out to your conscience.
If you would only attend to it for your
corrective efforts,
however primitive they may yet be.
Start small.
Have you mastered the process?
You can safely and competently expand
your reach.
You will then be able to fix bigger
things instead of making them worse and
the arrogance of your ignorance.
If you do this,
there will be less pointless and
unnecessary suffering in the world.
For all its shortcomings and faults will
be a better place
until we can imagine better than that.
That's meaning and purpose enough.
Happy New Year and best wishes to you
all.