We know that the snake is
utilized conceptually in metaphorically
as representation of transformation,
right,
because the snake is something that can
shed its skin and be reborn.
We know that a snake is something that's
innately attractive and terrifying human
beings and other primates so that if you
come across a snake,
you're likely to be at least startled,
if not horrified by it,
but also attracted to it in a way that
is underneath your voluntary
consciousness,
right?
Because snakes attract orienting reflex
isn't they activate the systems
underneath your consciousness that
actually governed the structure of that
consciousness.
We know that the snake can be well
represented as well as internal chaos,
so imagine this,
imagine that it's not unreasonable for a
self conscious mind searching for a mode
of self representation to remark on the
parallels between the structure of the
snake and the spine and the brain.
Given that a snake is essentially a
spine with a brain and then imagine as
well that the most archaic aspects of
our nervous system,
those that govern novelty and orienting
and anxiety responses are in fact
precisely those that were described by
Mclean as nested inside the reptilian
brain and then imagine along with the
Hindu Yogis,
that the purpose of Kundalini Yoga is to
activate the circuitry that's associated
with that snake,
so to speak,
to produce a permanent state of alert
wakefulness.
It's associated with consciousness.
So imagine this.
Imagine an animal like like a zebra
grazing mindlessly in the herd with no
consciousness whatsoever,
and then imagine it's relatively
undeveloped cortical structures
activated suddenly by the movement of a
lion off in the perimeter and then
imagine for that brief moment that Zebra
is actually conscious state.
That requires a tremendous amount of
energy and difficult to maintain,
but because the threat and the
uncertainty manifest itself within the
zebras mode of consciousness,
it wakes momentarily and then imagine
that human beings are like that.
Zebra always because we've become self
conscious because we know that the
unknown is around us all the time.
Even when we think we're safe,
we're never safe.
Imagine that the reason we're so
conscious because as a consequence of
our discovery,
of the possibility of our own mortality,
all this underlying circuitry that in
other animals is only apparent when
they're startled or afraid or interested
or curious.
In human beings.
It's on all the time and that's what
makes us conscious and the reason for
that is because we developed enough
cortical elaboration to note that we're
always threatened by everything that's
around us and then imagine that.
Well,
that's pretty awful,
isn't it?
Because it's at the basis of all our
innate existential terror,
but then imagine as well that without
that terror pushing us forward and and
our constant reference to the dangerous
aspect of the unknown,
we would have never been motivated to
produce the kind of societies that we've
produced,
which are essentially very remarkably
elaborated devices that enable us to
find some protection from that unknown
and to manipulate,
manipulate it effectively,
and then remembering that Surrey,
we will return to genesis young says,
snake is was regarded by early gnostic
Christians as a kind of daddy who's
faculties were more developed and
advanced than the original daddy that
actually structured the world.
The idea there being that the world
initially was a pretty dismal place.
Everyone wasn't conscious.
We all existed at the level of the
animal and then the snake came along and
said,
wake up.
Wake up.
And the movement from that state of
unsolved consciousness paradise to this
profane state of awakening can be
regarded not so much as a descent but as
an asset of sorts,
even though a painful one.
And then you have Gareth,
this commentary from Mephistopheles,
his representation of Satan and his
capacity for temptation,
who says,
follow the adage of my cousins snake
from dreams of godlike knowledge,
you will wake to fear in which your very
soul shall quake a statement,
associating the human tendency to
attribute to all revolutionary sources
of new information,
a kind of demonic being,
and then you have the problem of the
woman.
Now we know that within the context of
the Judeo Christian tradition,
women have unduly suffered for their
role in tempting humanity in the
embodied form of Adam towards higher
order self consciousness.
And then you think,
well,
let's just take a look at how human
beings and their mating relationships
differ from those of other animals like
chimpanzees to whom we are very closely
genetically related.
And if you look at the mating strategies
of female chimpanzees,
you see that they really don't care who
they sleep with,
so to speak.
Any old chimpanzee will do.
Now the last dominant male chimps to be
chased away by the more dominant male
chimps.
But if a female than less dominant chip
can get the hell away from the watchful
gaze of the dominance hierarchy,
they're perfectly happy to mate.
Human females are not like that.
There is selective maters and there's a
tremendous body of evolutionary
psychological information that suggests
that although both genders,
value intelligence and physical
appearance,
females value the ability to attain
dominance,
hierarchy status in men far more than
men.
I admire the ability to attain dominant
status in women,
which is to say that men don't care for
what a woman has with regards to
potential for attaining status.
Whereas with women,
it's one of the strong determinant of
mating preference.
So then let's say,
look,
we don't know why the hell are cortex
has expanded so rapidly,
somewhere between five and 3 million
years ago.
Let's offer this as a hypothesis.
The women started to get choosy and
because they were so damn complicated,
the whole human species had to
exaggerate it's cortical growth prior to
any even use for that critical growth,
just so that the men had an even hand in
the competition.
Right?
So women put tremendous selection,
pressure on the human being.
To develop tremendous,
tremendous cortical expansion.
Now we already know that from a
mythological perspective that women are
frequently cast into the same conceptual
domain,
the temptress domain as the benevolent
aspect of the unknown,
and we know as well from representations
of hero mythology that it is the
individual who goes out to confront
chaos,
who's most likely to free from the
dragon,
not only treasured,
but a virgin,
say in the case of mythological
representations like St George and the
dragon
in the Old Testament in genesis,
there's no.
There's this notion that not only did
people become self conscious because
they did something,
but they did this voluntarily,
right?
They,
they,
they made this decision on their own.
So Milton puts words into God's mouth
and says,
so will fall.
He meaning the human being and his
faithless progeny.
Whose fault,
whose about his own ingrained he had of
me?
Oh,
he could have I made him justin,
right?
It's efficient to have stood though free
to fall,
and then you think,
well,
maybe the notion of the heritable sin of
Adam characterizing human beings in
their fallen existential condition isn't
just the black heart ravings of
fundamentalist southern Baptist
lunatics,
right?
There's something to this.
Human beings are the only creatures that
seem to live at odds with their own
experience and it's not so unreasonable
to suppose that it's hard dawning
capacity for self consciousness that put
us in that uncomfortable position.
So why do I associate the eating of the
apple with self consciousness?
Well,
let's,
because that's how the story lays itself
out.
You have the collateral evidence of the
Buddhist story of enlightenment,
right?
His contact with death.
You have multiple media,
medieval representations of Eve offering
to animal to Adam.
Not An apple,
but a skull.
You have multiple representations of the
tree,
of the knowledge of good and evil and
medieval iconography as not containing
apples,
but containing skulls and you have the
statements that are within the context
of genesis itself
and the eyes of both of them were opened
and they knew that they were naked and
they sewed fig leaves together and made
themselves aprons.
Well,
there's a lot of information packed into
those two lines,
right?
What does it mean to have your eyes open
or half?
Your brain is visual cortex.
It's not unreal.
It's not unreasonable to presume that
that means a quick
I quit magnification of consciousness.
Your conscious during the day,
that's when your eyes are open or what
happens when your eyes are open?
Well,
you know you're naked.
what does that mean?
Well,
you know,
you're vulnerable,
right?
To social comment,
to social judgment,
to dominance,
hierarchy,
status maneuvering,
and to all the terrible things that the
unknown world can can wreak upon you.
And so then what do you do?
Well,
you create culture,
right?
And that's what this little sentence
says and they sewed fig leaves together
and made themselves aprons.
That's a pretty eventful sequence all
crammed up in two little sentences.
So then what happens?
I think it's extremely interesting.
So before Adam and eve figure out that
they're naked,
they're cruising around the garden,
having a fine time doing whatever they
want.
They don't take any thoughts for the
future.
Right now.
Don't have a prefrontal cortex.
They're living in a in a paradox lists
environment like an animal lives.
Well,
what happens after they become self
conscious?
Well,
prior to this,
Adam's walking around with God,
right,
and you think about what that means.
It means something like this.
An animal isn't in the world of good and
evil and animal nature points out is
beyond good and evil,
right?
Enraptured in entirely by the actions of
automatic instinct governed by processes
that are completely transcendent.
The animals,
nothing but a force of nature.
There no opposition between the animal
in the world.
The animal is the world,
and just as in the case of the animal,
prior to the eating of the apple,
Adam walks around the garden with God.
There no discontinuity between him and
the and the transcendent world as such.
But as soon as he becomes naked yards,
well why?
Well that doesn't need to be answered.
All you have to do is think about it.
Why would you hide if you know you're
naked?
It's simple.
You hired because you think you can get
hurt.
You think that whatever you are is so
vulnerable that if it shows itself to
the transcendent to others,
to the natural world,
that something terrible will happen.
And then you think,
well,
that's a pretty logical presupposition,
right?
Look at us.
So God comes cruising around the garden
after Adam and Eve,
the apple in the cool of the day,
and Adam and Eve hide themselves among
the trees of the garden.
And God says to Adam,
Hey,
where are you?
And Adam says,
I heard your voice.
And I was afraid because I was naked and
I hid myself.
And that story has bottomless depth
because it means something like this at
the beginning of genesis,
there's this notion that there is a
transcendent relationship between the
individual and God,
right?
The identity of logo send the
individual,
right?
I know it shouldn't by the way,
that our entire idea of intrinsic human
right,
it's predicated on is we've been at some
pains to demonstrate a relationship
between the limited and the limitless,
eradicated by the dawn of self
consciousness.
What does that mean?
Well,
let's say you have a destiny just for
the sake of argument,
right?
Because you are a being with a
tremendous history and an unbelievable
potential.
So let's say you have a destiny just for
the sake of argument.
What would cause you to hide from that
destiny?
Well,
obviously
your own reflections on your mortal
vulnerability,
right?
How could I be characterized by any
transcendent power whatsoever when I'm
susceptible to social alienation,
right?
When I have this body which is capable
of terrifying degeneration that will
eventually decay into old age and that
is bounded by death.
How could I be good for anything which
is precisely what this little story
says,
and so God figures out that Adam and eve
ate the fruit and that's pretty decisive
move because once you wake up,
sorry,
you're awake,
and he says,
and this is not an injunction,
by the way,
this is a description.
All right,
you've done it now unto the woman.
He says,
I will greatly multiply the Isaura Nih
conception in sorrow shall bring forth
children.
Why?
Well,
we have a big CORTEX,
right?
Really big.
It grew fast,
and what that meant is that there was an
evolutionary arms race between skull
size,
date of birth,
and pelvic diameter girth.
The wider the pelvis,
the less effectively you can walk a
larger the skull.
The bigger the brain,
the younger the baby,
the more dependent and vulnerable.
So what do we have?
In the case of human beings,
the female human pelvis has already
stretched to the limits of its
structural capacity.
So the hole in its center is as big as
it can get without compromising the
structural integrity of the pelvis while
still allowing women to walk and run.
So how have babies adapted to that?
Oh,
that's simple.
A mammal of our size should have a
gestation period of two years.
We have a gestation period of nine
months.
Why you got to get the damn baby out
before it's head gets too big?
What does that mean?
Well,
it means it's vulnerable,
right?
Nothing more vulnerable than a baby
human being except maybe a baby kitten
room.
Right?
But it's got a pouch to hide in at
least.
So we're born vulnerable,
right characteristic of the birth of the
hero who suffers in childbirth.
Women.
Why?
Baby?
Skulls?
Just a little bit too big,
has to be crunched and compacted during
birth,
right?
The skull bones aren't joined together
so that the baby's head can be squashed
and visibly deformed during the process
of birth.
Prior to the 20th century,
what was the death rate among women
giving birth?
One in three,
one in five.
Terrible.
Why?
That's the price you pay for
consciousness
and I desire shall be to thy husband and
he shall rule over thee.
This is not an injunction.
This is a description.
The additional burden that dependent
offspring place on women place them at a
disadvantage.
What's the consequence of that from a
historical perspective?
Well,
any feminist can answer that question
right
and unto Adam,
he said,
because you listened to your wife and
have eaten the tree of which I commanded
thee,
saying,
don't eat that cursed is the ground for
the sake in sorrow shall thou eat of it
for all the days of thy life.
Fair enough,
right?
Once you're self conscious,
you work.
Why?
Well,
animals don't work.
Why do people work?
Well?
Because we know,
right?
We know that if it isn't gonna happen
today,
it's going to happen tomorrow and if it
isn't going to happen tomorrow,
what's going to happen next week or the
week after?
The month,
after the year after,
and we bloody well better prepare.
So that's what we do.
Constantly prepare and prepare and
prepare.
So we're not bounded and motivated by
what's happening from second to second
like the animal is in.
It's still paradisical state.
We're constantly tormented by an endless
string of what if questions,
because when we look at the unknown,
we can see the possibility for
everything including our own punishment
or own tournament,
our own demise,
and so we're motivated like no other
animal to work and so we work,
but that is another aspect that
alienates us from paradise,
wellbeing,
being
thorns and thistles shall it bring forth
for the analysis.
You'll eat the herb of the field in the
sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread
til thou return unto the ground for Dust
Thou art and unto dust shall thou return
right?
Therefore the Lord God sent him forth
from the garden of Eden to till the
ground from whence he was taken.
So we drove out the man and he placed at
the east of the garden of Eden Cherubims
and a flaming sword which turned every
way to keep the way of the tree of life.
Adam and Eve,
right?
The mother and father of all humanity.
So you can give them a mythological slot
and you can say Adam is culture.
Say and Eve is nature because they're
the archetipal parents.
It's a perfectly reasonable
interpretation.
They have twin sons,
Cain and Abel,
so let's read first born creatures,
firstborn,
human creatures in the new self
conscious world,
so what are the first two individuals in
the new self conscious world like and
let's find out,
and Adam knew,
eve,
his wife and she conceived and Bare Cain
and said,
I have gotten a man from the Lord,
and again,
she bare his brother Abel,
the younger brother and Abel was a
keeper of sheep,
but Cain was a tiller of the ground and
in the process of time it came to pass
that cain brought of the fruit of the
ground and offering unto the Lord.
Okay,
so we're going to remove this from its
history,
from its entrapment in a particular
temporal domain and within attempt or
culture when to say something like this.
Well,
if you work,
you make sacrifices,
right?
That's what works all about and the
reason you make sacrifices is because
you're offering up to the unknown,
the fruits of your labor in the hope
that as a consequence of your diligence
effort,
you're going to be favored,
right?
Because otherwise,
why were the point of working is to
transform the transcendent into
something benevolent,
so your work and your work and you work
and you say,
is that sufficient?
And the answer you get from the
transcendent is the answer.
Now,
it's certainly true that lots of people
work and doesn't go all that well,
right?
They make sacrifices and they do what
they think they have to do and their
life is one string of catastrophes after
another.
Right?
So we have this situation in the process
of time,
it came to pass that cain brought of the
fruit of the ground and offering unto
the Lord and Abel.
He also brought of the firstlings of his
flock and of the fat thereof.
And the Lord had respect unto Abel and
his offering.
So what that means is that,
oh,
they able working away.
Damn things are going great for him,
right?
Fortune smiles on him.
He's doing wonderfully.
He's got everything he needs.
Well old cane.
He's scrounging away in the ground and
things aren't going as well for him at
all.
Right?
Plagues locusts.
You name it.
Farm life isn't going well.
So what happens?
Well,
Cain was very wroth and his countenance
fell precisely right,
because if you work diligently towards a
certain end and you don't get there,
then your current spouse falls,
right?
You're angry,
frustrated,
disappointed,
hurt,
anxious,
threatened,
ashamed,
guilty.
The whole panoply of negative emotions,
and that's fair enough because of course
if you fail,
that's what's going to be the
consequences.
But then there's this little twist on
it,
right?
This specifically human twists,
but it's like that kind of moral of the
whole story.
And so you find
the Lord saying,
oh well,
you know,
what's,
what's up with you?
Why are you so unhappy?
If you just got your act together,
then you'd be accepted.
If you really got your act together,
which is a statement,
something like this.
If you keep making sacrifices and the
same terrible thing keeps happening,
there's always the possibility that
you're just actually not doing it the
right way.
And if you just get yourself
straightened up,
tap together,
right?
And drop the preconceptions that you
don't really need an adjust your
behavior accordingly.
Then fortune would smile on you.
And that's exactly what the Lord says to
Cain,
right?
You don't walk around with such a crabby
look on your face.
If you did well,
you'll be accepted.
And if you don't do well,
sin lies at the door.
So what does that mean?
Well,
this is a deep motif in ancient Hebrew
thinking.
If the world isn't laying itself out in
a manner that you find acceptable,
you're faced with a tough choice.
Either the world is a terrible place
bent on destruction,
or you're doing something wrong and it
bloody well better be that you're doing
something wrong.
Because if the world is a terrible place
bent on destruction,
you've got absolutely no hope.
And cain talked with Abel,
his brother,
and it came to pass when they were in
the field that Cain rose up against
Abel,
his brother and killed him.
So what does that mean?
Well,
it's pretty easy.
It's simple.
It means this will say things aren't
going that well for you.
And it's really not because life's
unfair and everything stacked against
you.
It's because you're kind of a arrogant,
stubborn,
totalitarian,
cowardly idiot.
And as a consequence of that,
the world is turning into something
resembling a wasteland around you and
you have this option change
or continue,
or you have another option,
man,
look around.
There's all those people doing well.
The world's a terrible place bent on my
destruction.
Wouldn't it be just the most interesting
thing?
If as things are going to hell for me,
I could take along just for the ride.
Some of those successful people who are
successful just for unfair reasons
anyways.
Right?
So instead of using all that negative
emotion has a cue that there's something
about me that might need to be
transformed.
I can say,
well,
why not just eradicate the target of my
resentment?
Right?
Not only because that sort of removes
the problem of comparison,
but more profoundly.
And I think sort of,
again,
eliminate Leslie profoundly,
but say you made the decision that the
world's a terrible place and it's based
on your destruction.
And then you think,
well,
what's the logical response to that?
And then you think something like this
Girtha,
fouse,
Mephistopheles Credo,
the spirit I that endlessly denies and
rightly to,
for all of it,
comes to birth,
is fit for overthrow as nothing worth
wherefore for the world.
We're better sterilized.
That's all the tear is evil,
recognized is gained to me and downfall,
rune and sin.
The very element I prosper in
and
draws our attention to this credo.
Not once,
but twice in his writing a file.
Austin has mephistopheles say right once
again,
gone to share,
nothing passed with no made one.
What matters are creative,
endless toil.
When out of snatch oblivion ends,
the coil,
it is by gone.
How shall this riddle run?
As good as if things never had begun yet
circle back existence to possess.
I'd rather have eternal emptiness.
And so then you think about cane,
like figures like Stella and you think,
well,
what exactly was he motivated by?
And on the one hand you think,
well,
he was trying to extend his cultural
dominion right?
Played by his own self conscious
neuroticism.
He wanted to extend the,
the,
the borders of his totalitarian
certainty to every corner just to not be
plagued by the unknown and you think,
fair enough.
You know,
like we're all pretty nervous and a
little stability is a good thing.
Why?
Because they make a fundamental
judgment,
which is the judgment of Mephistopheles.
Look,
life is terrible,
terrible,
terrible.
Were self conscious.
We get sick.
We go insane.
We're going to die.
Children,
innocent children suffer everywhere.
How in the world is it right to let such
a state continue?
Maybe it would be better.
All things considered just to bring the
whole game to an end and so then you
think again with Eliana that the reason
that humans societies fall apart is
twofold.
One is things go from bad to worse of
their own accord,
right?
Thermodynamic reality,
pure entropy,
structured entities decay,
but then there's a twist.
Structured entities constructed by are
sped in their process of decay by the
participants of the individuals within
that society who have essentially
decided that the game is not worth the
price and that under such conditions the
only reasonable thing for a self
conscious,
painfully self conscious individual to
do is to work as hard as he or she
possibly can to take the maximum amount
of revenge on the conditions of
existence and to ensure that the entire
game folds up.
The consciousness disappears and that
being is eradicated.