I'm here with a couple of professors
from Wilfrid laurier to talk about the
Lindsay Shepherd scandal and what
happened with Professor Rambo Canada and
Pimlott and administrator Adrianne,
Joel,
Adrian,
right Atria,
Joel,
who I think is the Unsung,
what would you call it,
the unsung villain in this entire
process because she seems to have
escaped relatively unscathed,
even though I think her role is more
reprehensible than anyone else's.
Anyways,
why don't you guys introduce yourself
and talk about what you've been doing at
Wilfrid laurier and also just let
everybody know why we're meeting.
Yeah.
Well,
uh,
I'm Dave Haskell and uh,
I'm a prophet Laura Day.
I'm in the Faculty of Liberal Arts.
Uh,
this is my colleague.
Will,
will,
how do we come into this whole thing
like this is,
this didn't just happen with the Lindsay
affair,
like to background.
We support maximum freedom of expression
and we've really found each other along
with a few other professors who feel the
same way that we do that free expression
and free inquiry is the core value of a
university.
And but sort of how did we run out
each other business school?
Uh,
so my exposure to the faculty of Arts is
minimal and I've been really sheltered
from this professionally,
but watching what's happening in the U.
s watching what was happening to you at
uft,
I'm a Grad,
I did my phd here and um,
it was in January that our university
leadership sent out an email,
um,
explaining to the faculty how to think
about the trump travel ban and declaring
a,
its,
its commitment to diversity,
equity and inclusivity.
And I was really offended by that,
that they would see fit to pronounce on
a political issue in another country.
Uh,
offended.
Why I,
I'm,
I've got a phd.
I'm able to reach my own conclusions
about whether these things are good or
bad.
I don't need my administration preaching
to me about the,
the right way to think about an issue,
a political issue,
particularly consumer.
So why do you think they did that and
what do you think they were thinking
when they did that?
Because that sort of seems self evident,
right?
To the Snot,
the administration's role to dictate a
political stance to the faculty.
That's just clearly not their role.
So what do you think they were thinking?
It would seem like a manifestation of
trump derangement syndrome.
It seems like just the same reaction
that the Democrats in the US for having
that they lost to this horrible person
and they couldn't understand why and it
was so reprehensible and here was yet
another terrible thing that he was doing
and we must all agree how bad it was.
Well,
I mean even if the funny thing is even
if you can make that and say
personally and even socially,
the idea that you could make that case
and then be university administration
and then tell your faculty to think that
way.
I mean that's taking it in a whole
different.
That's taking it to a whole whole
different level of presump
presumptuousness.
Did that come from our administration?
From the diversity and equity from the
administration,
from the leadership,
the university leadership.
I remember the.
It's confusing because I remember we
also got an email from the diversity and
equity office when when trump won and
they said that they've created a safe
space and they were going to be open for
extra hours in case anybody needed to go
and find
comfort.
Right.
That happened a lot in the United
States.
Hey,
what do you think?
At least the Americans have some
justification for it,
given that it's their country.
I mean,
we need safe spaces because a
conservative was elected in the United
States and they're not even in our
country.
It does seem to be a little bit on the
absurd side.
Well,
it just to me,
you know,
they didn't send out an email when
Justin Trudeau won and I have to imagine
that there were some students who were
offended,
like there's got to be conservative
students at l'oreal,
but it's.
It's very much a one sided conversation.
When we talk about administration,
when we talk about the diversity and
equity office,
they talk about diversity,
but they really don't mean it because
they do not want those students who are
ideologically diverse.
They talk about inclusion,
but they purposely will exclude those
students.
And an email like that is proof positive
of that kind of exclusion.
But what?
Well that was,
that was the thing that just got me
hopping mad and I was emailing back and
forth with a colleague at Queens,
uh,
and we were talking about the importance
of free speech and this had outraged me.
And,
uh,
and he sent me a link to a star article
that David had written.
This is now maybe a month later in
February or March about a,
this guest speaker.
Oh,
Daniel.
Roberta.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And that she couldn't speak and where
she was,
she,
uh,
um,
commercial lawyer.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So merely because she served as a
defense lawyer for someone,
she was pilloried.
Well this was another,
like when people look at the Lindsay
Shepherd affair,
this is not an isolated case at Wilfrid
laurier.
This is something that is,
it is a regular occurrence and now it
isn't always as high profile,
but whether it's students in my office
saying I can't speak,
whether it's my colleagues sometimes
saying to their students who believes
that they're stifled and every hand goes
up and there have been cases of that
colleagues have come and told me,
but we've got these other examples like
when Daniel came to speak at the
Brantford campus of Wilford Laurey and
some students agitated until she was
forced not to do so and,
and my,
My President Greg,
we should provide some background.
So that was the case.
Right.
And so give me a.
She was a CBC journalist who was accused
of sexual assault and sexual misbehavior
by a number of people who was
immediately let go at CBC,
who was dragged
viciously through the press,
I would say,
and then was found innocent in the
courts now,
but,
and he had a defense lawyer.
The defense lawyer had been invited to,
to speak.
Yes.
She was part of the defense team.
She was going to speak and she wasn't
going to speak about the Ghomeshi trial.
In fact,
she was going to talk about what it's
like to be a high power powerful lawyer,
um,
in,
in the big city in Toronto.
And I mean that would have been really
valuable for the criminology students,
but the students who were agitating
against her really with the support of
several professors,
uh,
they were saying,
well,
no,
if she comes on,
it will trigger students.
It will,
um,
it will mentally harm students.
And so that was used as justification
for the act.
Interesting to,
to me to see that these claims of harm
and so forth or
generally put forth by people who have
no clinical expertise whatsoever.
And their idea is that the way that you,
first of all that,
the way to aid people's mental health is
to protect them and there's no evidence
for that whatsoever.
And the second is that in your attempts
to protect them,
the best thing to do is to shelter them
from exposure to ideas that would be
challenging or frightening,
which is precisely the opposite of what
a clinician does when he's trying to.
Or she is trying to,
um,
deal with someone who has access
anxiety.
What you do in a case where someone who
has access anxiety,
even as a consequence of a trauma,
let's say,
is you get them to voluntarily expose
themselves to increasingly larger doses
of exactly what frightens them.
That's the curative route.
So not only is it a advice that's being
disseminated,
say by people who aren't clinicians,
it's actually advice that's being
disseminated,
who are promoting the opposite of what
an informed clinician would do.
And that doesn't.
That isn't my opinion,
that's,
that's as close to a consensus as
anything you could reach among clinical
practitioners,
right?
One rules for clinical improvement is
get your story straight,
something like that.
Talk about your past,
sorted out and expose yourself to the
things that you're afraid of that you're
inclined to avoid.
That's the pathway to,
to resilience and more robust mental
health.
Okay.
So tell us the story a bit.
You guys have an inside view of what's
happened on the Wilfred laurier campus
since the,
the Lindsay Shepherd fair broke.
I should just say that,
you know,
after this rubber tie event,
I read David's piece and immediately
emailed him and just say,
and that's how we injured and uh,
we met and we had lunch and uh,
in just talked about free speech and the
Chicago statement and how can we get it
implemented the university,
but we just couldn't see any way forward
and really.
So that's another thing we want to
discuss.
You guys have rewritten the Chicago
statement,
right?
So that it's more appropriate in the
Canadian context,
right?
We call it the Laurie Laurie a statement
for freedom of expression.
Okay.
And you've been trying to convince or,
or you're trying to be in,
you've been trying to communicate the
university authorities to have that
ratified essentially adopted as a state
of principles and have you had any
success with that or what's the
consequence?
They deferred to a task force that's
going to be held and we can certainly.
Okay,
as in is that in the aftermath of the
shepherd affairs that going to be part
of it really do anything over the summer
just because it just seemed too big a
mountain a and there seemed to be no way
to introduce the idea right now you've
got your
catalyst and Lindsay shepherd becomes
the catalyst and and,
and you know what,
what a object lesson in what goes on at
l'oreal,
but also what an object lesson in how
you handle these free speech opponents.
She's really given a model that other
students I hope will follow,
but it was,
it was through this robot tie thing that
we got to know each other and,
and a few others.
Yeah,
there's a couple more of you.
And so about five I think he told me.
That's right.
So,
so the rope Italians incident really
brought us out of the woodwork.
We started a chat and say,
you know,
we see this problem on our university.
We don't know what to do.
And then when the Lindsay Shepherd
scandal broke,
we all immediately we were emailing as
it's happened again,
is essentially what we were saying.
And we said,
we've got to do something about this.
Uh,
I'd already,
I was out on a,
on a trip and I came home and I said to
my wife,
where are the newspapers?
This was a November twelfth when the
story broke Christie Blatchford story.
And I said,
hey honey,
where are the newspaper?
She said,
I can't let you see him.
I said,
why not?
She said,
you cannot read the papers.
And of course it was [inaudible]
Christie Blatchford articles in there.
So as soon as I read it,
I was beside myself.
I thought it's happened again and this
time,
this is really terrible.
They've attacked a Ta,
is what they've done.
So I contact with the full force of the
administration and claims that she had
done mental harm,
broken two laws to laws,
federal and provincial is sincerely
worried that they were going to railroad
this young lady
so they could have easily taken her to
the Ontario Human Rights Code.
The mission would have had field.
What was gonna Happen?
Uh,
I contacted Christie Blatchford.
I said,
can you put me in touch with her?
She was kind enough to do so I got in
touch with Lindsay and I said,
I know that this is a terrible time,
but you've got a professor who supports
you.
I knew that these gentlemen also would,
uh,
and then quickly I as quickly as I
could,
I wrote an op Ed for the Toronto Star
that we just again to saying this is
happening.
The world needs to be aware of it,
but it was really after that,
uh,
that Monday after the story broke on the
Saturday,
we started to talk and,
and how can we,
how can we assist Lindsey and,
and how can,
oh,
the orbit helped you.
And the fact that the star ran it was
quite remarkable as well.
So hurry to the star.
The Star really does want to do its best
to champion free expression.
Yeah.
Well you'd think journalists would
actually be concerned about that to some
degree.
Think they are.
Like,
one of the things that's happened to me
in the last year is that although the
press coverage of what I did just to
remind people.
So last year I made a video about bill
[inaudible],
which was the bill who's provisions
Lindsay Shepherd theoretically
transgressed against.
Just to be clear about that,
and when I first made the video,
I was accused by all sorts of people,
including journalists,
have,
um,
well first of all,
making unnecessary noise and being
unnecessarily alarmist,
which were the minor accusations.
And then the more major accusations were
that,
you know,
I was all the things that you'd expect a
far right.
I'm an agitator to be a bigot and a
transphobic and racist and all of these
things.
And so,
but what was interesting was that the
journalists,
by and large,
especially the main journalists,
turned around on that issue really
quickly.
It was probably within three weeks
because what happened was a couple of
them actually went and read the policy
documents that I had referred to on the
Ontario Human Rights Commission website,
which are still there and which are
still appalling and have led exactly to
this situation with Lindsey.
And as soon as they read what I had,
uh,
being uh,
what,
what outing,
let's say in my video,
then they started to understand that
this was,
that I wasn't just ringing a bell for no
reason at all.
It was actually reasonable,
I think,
of people to go after me to begin with
because Canada is such a safe and
peaceful place and our political
situation and economic situation has
been so stable that when someone comes
out and says,
look,
we're in danger of making a major error,
the logical first response should be,
no,
there's something wrong with you.
It's like we're flying.
There's something wrong with you.
Right.
Exactly.
Well in Indiana.
So it's reasonable.
I think it was reasonable for me to be
hit hard in the aftermath of doing that
because,
well,
generally speaking,
whistleblowers in Canada are alarmist in
Canada.
Have very little to be alarmist about
this.
This.
Okay.
So now,
so fine.
So this thing happened with Lindsay.
What have you seen happening on the
Wilfred laurier campus?
Things that I'm not particularly proud
of,
I would say.
I mean,
I knew that a will and some other
colleagues were going to come to the aid
of Lindsey,
but I was thinking that once her
recording became public that we would
just have a flood of professors coming
to support our cause,
which is we had a lorry,
a statement for freedom of expression
modeled on the Chicago statement.
We thought that immediately people would
just say,
of course we need to reinforce that this
needs to be the primary mission free
expression,
free inquiry needs to be the primary
mission.
And we got that a pretty fast.
We really did.
And uh,
and,
and uh,
and got it on change.org.
And then where I was emailing everybody
that I knew and trying to get people
interested and I would say out of 50
emails I sent,
I got 15 signatures from personal
relationships.
So even with personal relationships,
you could only get a 30 percent hit
rate.
So what do you think's stopping
professors from signing that say are
clambering on board,
especially in the aftermath of the
shepherd recording,
which we should point out.
This is one of the things that's very
interesting is that outside Wilford
Laurey and perhaps outside universities
that are in the same boat,
the reaction to that recording was
universal,
right?
And and national and international and
uniform.
And the reaction was,
what the hell.
This is scandalous.
There's nothing about this that is
acceptable.
Right?
And so what's what struck me is so
remarkable is that even though there's
been international outrage over this
and,
and very and not an outrage of a sort
that's only been disputed by a very
small number of people,
at least to begin with,
Wilfred laureate responded on mosques,
let's say as if this was somehow
debatable.
You know,
as if there were two sides of the story
here,
let's say.
And I thought,
well,
I thought Rambo Canada and Pim Lot who
were the professors,
did what they did.
I thought it was appalling for in
upgrading her and in the manner in which
they did it and in the language that
they used.
But I thought what was truly terrifying
was the presence of Adrian Joel at that
inquisition because she was a
administrator who was hired specifically
to do exactly what she was doing by
legislated necessity on the part of the
Ontario Liberal government.
Right.
Because it wasn't just the university
that was involved in this.
Her position was set up because of
legislative necessity,
which is something also to keep in mind
when we're going after the university's.
Okay.
So you had a hard time getting faculty
on board.
How many faculty members didn't sign it
out of,
out of how many faculty?
Five hundred and 50 full time and now.
And so you say,
well what's going on with them?
Well,
I think that some.
Maybe,
I know this is hard to believe,
but maybe unaware.
Even now there's a big proportion that
are unaware.
I unbelievable.
I think.
Okay,
well that's it's own mystery because I
don't know where you'd have to have been
in the last month to not have noticed
that this has happened,
that people perhaps in the sciences,
the computer sciences,
the math,
they,
they've got their head down and they're
doing the research and and so and so.
I don't think there's anything
diabolical there.
I think that as well.
I've got very few signatures from the
business faculty meet some,
but a lot of people just aren't engaged.
It's a bit of a commuter school a little
bit so I think people are just getting
on with their research and their
teaching.
Maybe not aware of.
Well that's a.
that's an interesting thing in and of
itself because I think part of what's
led to the occupation of the university,
let's say by the radical postmodern
types is the proclivity of the
scientists in particular,
but also I would say the more serious
scholars to be focusing narrowly on
their field of inquiry,
which is essentially what they should be
doing and not paying attention to any of
the broader contextual issues.
Which is actually a perfectly fine
strategy.
When things are going well,
but a terrible strategy when they're
not,
and what you also see,
so we've got these people who might not
be aware and we've got the,
the few who are aware and are supporting
maximum free expression,
but then you've got these other people
who are convinced that maximum free
expression,
free inquiry is not a good thing for a
university.
And,
and those people are definitely
congregated within the arts and the
humanities and they justify it because
they are applying a social justice lens
or what they would call a critical
theory lens to this entire,
this entire issue.
And,
and how,
how about a quick summary of critical
theory or critical theory?
I mean in a nutshell,
it's an idea that came from the
Frankfurt school in Germany.
It transfers over to Columbia
University.
Uh,
it is some German scholars who are
Marxists.
And what they are saying is that a
Marxism as an economic unit or as an
economic philosophy really doesn't work.
It doesn't transfer very well,
but let's change it over to a social
theory.
And it's a,
it's a theory of oppressor and
oppressed.
And it's very bifurcated,
you've,
you are either one or the other and if
you are the oppressed,
you're good.
And if you're the oppressor,
you're bad.
And it's as simple as that.
There's no nuance or okay,
I'm,
I'm being as bad as they are to to.
So I'm giving you the really broad
strokes on this,
but essentially it does set up the
villain and the victim.
And,
and it is the idea that we must do
everything to silence the villain,
the oppressor,
and to center the oppressed.
Yes.
And then we will elevate the oppressed.
And same thing happened essentially with
the French,
a deconstructionist to 1970.
It is.
So this is,
this is the motivation behind it.
But when,
when you hear them talk about critical
theory,
it is not critical thinking.
There's a big difference.
And so parents will hear while they're
teaching critical theory.
Isn't that a good thing?
No,
because critical thinking means I'm
going to show you both sides of this
argument.
Critical theory means I'm going to
deliberately give you one side of the
argument.
I'm going to tell you who's right and
I'm going to tell you who's wrong.
There's an oppressor and oppressed the
oppressors,
the bad guy.
The oppressed is the good guy and it's a
very manipulative way of.
Okay.
So,
uh,
so,
so there's,
let's say two reasons why people
wouldn't sign the,
the,
uh,
the petition one is they're doing
something else and they're just not
interested in it.
And,
and,
and fair enough,
even though I think that that's
dangerous at the moment.
The second is that they're actually
philosophically or ideologically opposed
to the proposition.
Right.
And so to what degree do you think the
ladder is the determining factor behind
the relatively small degree of support
that you,
that you guys have been able to draw
out?
The big thing that the,
uh,
a group of faculty signed an open letter
to the University of about the
violence.
Uh,
and,
and that,
the,
that the administration needed to make
the campus safe.
Yeah.
They did the same thing with me after I
made my video.
I was,
I made the campus unsafe and 200 people
signed up.
He signed a petition.
Yeah.
What does unsafe mean?
I mean this is the problem.
The the,
the left,
the far left are taking words that have
a traditional meaning,
a traditional definition,
and they're blowing that definition
completely,
completely away,
and and at one time,
harm meant that there was an infliction
of damage that would have lasting effect
and it would compromise the appearance
or the function,
right?
We can think about damage to a car,
right,
lasting and it's affecting the,
the appearance or the function.
That's what harm is,
but they've stretched that definition so
that it becomes meaningless.
That my an objectionable idea becomes
harm,
that that when you show a video,
you've made a place unsafe and that
that's the language of trigger warnings
and safe spaces,
but it's disingenuous that there was a
trans rally and one of the speakers said
that,
letting I can quote this,
apparently letting Peterson's views be
heard in the classroom is violence is
violence.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
Yes.
You can react with violence.
Well,
that's often what I think that I've
thought a lot about.
One of the tenants of postmodernism
left,
so I would say of critical theory,
but particularly of postmodernism in
it's more Marxist variance,
is that the only motivation for the
construction of hierarchies is power and
you think,
well that's.
No,
there's lots of reasons for producing
hierarchies,
right?
There's hierarchies of competence,
there's hierarchies of interest,
there's hierarchy,
hierarchies of aesthetic quality,
like there's all sorts of.
Wherever you can make a qualitative
judgment,
you make a hierarchy.
So there's the idea that power is the
only driving force between behind the
construction of hierarchies is
absolutely preposterous.
So you think,
well why in the world would anyone make
that claim that it's only power that
exists while as far as I can tell,
at least one of the reasons is that it
justifies the use of power and if you
have your position because of power,
which is basically tyranny,
then I'm fully warranted in my use of
power against you.
That's all there is.
So I think it's a great justification
for it.
Okay.
So how many people signed the petition
stating that the campus had become
unsafe?
That was like 79,
79.
Just like that.
Okay,
so you got more people signing a
petition claiming that what shepherd did
made the campus on Save,
then you did getting some.
Okay,
so that's interesting because one of the
things we're going to address later is
the president's letter as a consequence
of the inquiry into the Lindsay Shepherd
affair,
and one of the things she says,
I'm a people who've tried to downplay
what happened at Lindsay at Wilford
Laurey have said basically
two or three things.
One is that,
well,
the shepherd is not to be trusted and
she's really like a.
a,
a subtle arm of the right wing.
That's one.
One.
And that she's a reprehensible
character.
Yes.
There are Pedrosa.
I know they.
They directly went after it.
I'm quite sneaky that way.
The second is that pim lot,
ramboo Canada and Joel misinterpreted
Bill [inaudible],
which I think is absolutely
preposterous.
I think they interpreted exactly the way
that it was written,
especially if you consider the
surrounding policies and that's what I
was warning about last September and the
third is that this was an isolated
incident and doesn't truly reflect the
reality either of Wilfrid laurier or
other campuses and not stated explicitly
in the president's letter,
and so that's one of the things I wanted
to discuss because I don't buy that.
I think this wasn't an anomaly.
This wasn't people stepping out of line
and I think the proof of that is not
what Rambo candidate or pim law,
because we could say,
yeah,
they're ideologically committed
professors and they and they're.
They're not very professional in their
administrative abilities and they went
after a Ta unprofessionally and
stupidly.
That's bad.
That's not really bad.
What's really bad was that there was a
paid administrator at the meeting who
was hired to do exactly that,
and so the fact that she was there is
the proof to me that this is not only
not an isolated incident.
It's actually a logical and it logical
and inevitable consequence of
legislative moves that made these
bureaucratic positions necessary and the
practical reality that these
administrative positions do exist on the
campuses.
So there's no isolated incident issue
there.
Now,
how do you think Lindsay's been treated
at Wilfrid laurier?
Like what's your,
what's your impression of her,
of her personal situation there?
I think that,
so on the positive side,
there have been students who have
rallied to her support and that's been
really encouraging to see a,
it was some students on campus who are
dedicated to freedom of expression.
They mostly are coming from the
conservative clubs,
uh,
whether it's the conservative political
club or other conservative groups.
Uh,
although definitely invitations have
been extended to other groups of other
political stripes or other.
They really haven't rallied to Lindsey,
sadly.
Uh,
so those students have to a certain
extent,
befriended her or brought her under
their wing or just began associating
with her and saying,
how can we support you?
I think in her classes,
and I'm just going from what I've seen,
I follow her on twitter,
so I see what's been going on there
apparently,
and I don't think this is inaccurate,
the other Grad students are being quite
scathing.
Yeah,
that's what I've heard from her and from
her tweets is that at least they're cold
at minimum,
they're cold and the professors as well,
including the one who told her that she
couldn't use her laptop in class because
she didn't want to be recorded.
I mean,
you couldn't script this level of
idiocy,
but my.
My thought is students always ask me a
Dr Hascall,
can I record what you're talking about?
I say,
yes,
yes.
The answer is yes.
The answer's yes.
Because you know what?
I don't say anything in my class that I
wouldn't publicly say because I and I
want to be accountable.
I want people to know what I'm saying in
my class.
I want them to know I'm fair.
I'm balanced.
I present both sides of the argument.
I'm not afraid of that.
I mean,
why are people afraid of accountability
that that's beyond my understanding.
Yeah.
Well that's,
that's a very good,
that's a very good question.
So,
okay,
so,
um,
I think,
I think what we'll do now is go through
this letter because what happened
yesterday I guess is the president had
appointed a third party fact finder to
look into what happened with the Lindsay
Shepherd Fair.
Right.
And there were concerns about that
because many people,
including Christie Blatchford were
concerned,
and the lawyer that's representing
Lindsay Howard,
Howard Levin,
was concerned that the person who was
appointed to do the third party
investigation wouldn't be neutral
because he had tweeted his agreement
with a variety of,
let's call them politically correct
issues quite publicly,
but it doesn't look like he's done a
credible job.
That that's what it appears to me
anyways.
The president who is very closed mouth
or new assiduously neutral about this
whole affair has released a report and I
thought we could go through it and talk
about whether or not we think that it
addressed the issues reasonably so
because I think it did in some part,
but I think it didn't in others.
So this is from mcclatchy.
Deborah mcclachi,
Phd,
who's the president and new vice
chancellor at Wilford Laurey and
relatively new at it,
so she's really been raked through the
coals thoughts for sure.
She was still vice president academic,
which is the second most senior
physician for the last five or so.
She's accustomed to this.
Okay.
It is.
I believe it is time for some clarity
around the events of the past few weeks
here at Wilfrid laurier university,
stemming from the very regrettable
meeting,
so that's an interesting turn of phrase
to begin with.
That followed the showing of a TV.
Oh,
clipped by a teaching assistant during a
tutorial as the newly appointed
president and vice chancellor of this
incredible 106 year old institution.
I'm here to set the record straight and
announced some important changes.
The issue has highlighted some
deficiencies but input,
but as importantly at is created
opportunities.
Yeah.
Well to me that's a.
that's a kind of marketing doublespeak.
It's like we could just go with the
deficiencies issue for now.
Opportunities for Laurie to improve our
own performance,
to lead a broader discussion on academic
freedom and freedom of expression and
opportunities to work together as a
community to demonstrate the strengths
we have as an institution.
When the issue first broke,
I erred on the side of caution as a
person,
as a president,
as the president of Laurie am sensitive
to the viewpoints and concerns of our
students,
staff and faculty.
As an employer,
I am cognizant that the four people who
were in that meeting room,
our employees and one is also a student.
All four are entitled to due process.
I did not want to rush judgment.
Rather,
I wanted to ensure we were able to
objectively assess the facts and make
sound decisions flowing from that
assessment.
That seems reasonable enough.
And I would say the events that have
transpired probably justified her
approach.
Um,
although I had taken issues with some of
the things that she had said and not
said when she was on the agenda,
but whatever.
We hired an external fact finder with
expertise in human resources issues.
I have received the report and we are
taking decisive action to ensure these
events will not be repeated.
The report along with what we already
knew has led me to the final conclusions
following conclusions and actions.
There were numerous errors in judgment
made in the handling of the meeting with
Ms Dot Lindsay Shepherd the Ta of the
tutorial and question.
In fact,
the meeting never should have happened
at all.
Okay.
That's probably the most damning
statement and the entire report I would
say because she.
And then she says no formal complaint
nor informal concern relative to a
lorry.
A policy was registered about the
screening of the video.
This was confirmed in the fact finding
report.
Okay,
so we can take that apart a little bit.
No formal complaint.
Okay.
So Rambo Kana claimed that one or more
students had complained.
He wouldn't say how many and he wouldn't
say what the nature of the complaint
was.
Now,
what this document seems to indicate
that is that,
well,
if there was a complaint,
which it leaves vague,
there was nothing that would constitute
a genuine complaint in an administrative
sense and that's why the meeting should
have never happened.
So I guess one question would be,
um,
what if any appropriate disciplinary
action should be taken against Rambo
Mckenna and pim lot.
And I don't know the answer to that
because you know,
they're not administrative experts and I
don't think faculty can be,
but by the same token,
I don't feel like I understand exactly
what happened to bring about the meeting
to begin with.
Do you guys know?
I mean,
whatever we do know we've had to piece
together from different media reports
because as has been said,
uh,
our president is not releasing the
findings of this like this is,
this is going to be,
this is a secret.
The Independent investigation.
We will never know what it actually
says.
We don't know what all the
recommendations are.
We,
I think we can take her at her word that
she's telling us what's
and why is she making it secret or
keeping it secret?
Is that,
is that the,
this concern with,
what do you call it?
Confidentiality.
That seems to be the,
the what,
the,
the camouflage behind which these things
are always hidden.
That seems to be implied and,
or even said explicitly,
but I've seen other cases where been
disciplinary measures and,
and we,
we get more details than this.
Right?
So,
so I don't know.
I don't know the level of
confidentiality that is required under
law,
but what I can say,
and I'll let,
will talk about what the disciplinary
actions can be.
Let's keep in mind that when Ramboo
Canada said that there had been a
complaint and it says here that there
wasn't,
he then echos that in his apology to
Lindsay.
He then says,
of course,
I'm,
I'm paraphrasing here,
so I'm not being completely accurate in
terms of what he exactly said,
but he said something like,
of course there are things I can't
discuss because of the complaint that
was made by a student.
So he's echoing what seems to be an
untruth and while this is about
closest statement,
as you might imagine in a statement like
this,
stating that it was an untruth,
I mean he said,
she said no formal complaint nor
informal concern relative to a lorry.
A policy was registered.
I mean,
that's,
that's
Huh.
That's as close as you could get.
Two coming right out and saying that the
statement that there was a complaint was
a falsehood.
And I just want to follow that thread
for a second.
So here we have a controversy that was
started on an untruth and it seems to be
that this is part of the whole modus
operandi here when we're here and
there's been harm and it's unsafe
violence,
daily violence.
Although again,
when the media,
global,
National News,
Globe and Mail checked in to see if
there were any police reports related to
any harassment or any threats.
No police reports had university of
Toronto.
So.
So at some point,
don't we have to say there was a boy who
cried wolf.
Well this is even,
this is more egregious.
Even though then claiming harm,
I mean because you know,
maybe people were getting nasty tweets
and so forth and I suspect they were,
um,
but the thing is,
is that Rambo Canada and pim lot
directly claimed that there had been a
complaint.
Right?
And so that's a big problem that isn't
thoroughly addressed
well,
and in either somebody,
uh,
heard about the tutorial and the fact
that a Peterson video was shown a and
uh,
kind of found out somehow,
but he decided that was unacceptable
and that the right way to approach it
was to claim that a student had
complained because it's not a problem
that he found it.
It's not such a big problem that he
found unacceptable.
Let's say it is his class,
like he has a right to talk to,
is ta about what's going to be shown and
what's not going to be showing even
though he handled it.
I think reprehensive in that meeting,
but he could come out and say look like
that is what the sort of thing I want to
be discussed in my class.
I don't agree with Peterson.
I think he's a jerk.
And like,
here's the other things you should be
concentrating on,
but to come out and say a student
complained and then to buttress that the
accusation
that she had violated federal and
provincial law as well as the university
bring in and I don't understand why Joel
was there without some sort of follow up
paper work or evidence of a,
of a complaint.
Well,
I,
I think that the,
the,
the reason for that is that the
positions that people like Joel occupy
are so ill defined and so fundamentally
reprehensible in their organization and
their,
in their aims is that this is exactly
the sort of thing that you would expect.
And so I thought she didn't say much in
that little inquisitorial recording,
but I thought the thing she did say were
spectacularly concerning.
Let's put it that way.
The way the discipline.
What,
what,
what is the discipline?
Do you have any sense of this?
Like I,
I,
I can't speculate.
I don't know.
Communications are uh,
well what,
what happens when somebody lies or when
somebody brings forth that complaint
that wasn't a complaint.
I will.
That is that.
Well,
that's one of the things this document
does not address,
like it's a big problem.
It's a big problem.
If there was no complaint and the reason
she was disciplined was because there
were because there was a claim that
there was a complaint like that's well
we can,
we don't have to beat that to death
claim that there's harm.
What about if there's a claim that the
campus has daily violence?
What if there's a claim that such and
such area has become unsafe?
Does that need to be proven or should we
be seeking disciplinary action against
people who are making those claims?
That's a very good,
that's a very good question.
Okay,
so,
so that's,
that's a,
that's a problem that isn't addressed in
this report.
It's a big one.
Okay.
And,
and I mean the president is obviously
not happy with this because she also
says the errors in judgment.
Okay.
No formal complaint,
no informal concern was registered about
the screening of the video.
This was confirmed in the fact finding
report.
So they're not beating around the Bush
about this.
There are stating very clearly the
errors in judgment were compounded by
misapplication of existing university
policies and procedures,
basic guidelines,
basic guidelines and best practices on
how to appropriately execute the roles
and responsibilities of staff and
faculty were ignored,
not just not understood,
ignored or not understood.
Okay.
That's a pretty damn damning statement
there too.
So I don't even know how the particular
here I heard Howard levins say that she
was entitled to some sort of represent.
Lindsay was entitled to some
representation under the bylaws of our
university and she was supposed to have
had that,
that nobody offered that.
Right.
So that's an administrative followup at
the level of employee employer
relationships to say nothing of the
academic issues at stake here.
We don't have policies and procedures
about how to carry out and acquisition
and that's not what she's saying.
I think there's a med eval document that
you can use,
but one thing Jordan,
I'd want to point out here is that the
errors and were compounded
by misapplication of existing university
policies,
misapplication of existing university
policies.
At the end of this document,
she's going to say that our gender and
sexual violence policy needs to be
reviewed.
So which is,
it was,
right.
Was it an error,
an application or an error in policy
and,
and that's.
This is confusing.
Yeah,
it is.
Because my suggestion would be the
policy is terribly flawed.
We have a colleague who's one of the
free speech proponents at our
university,
Dr Andrew Robinson.
He is an expert in human rights law and
he went through our gendered and sexual
violence policy with a fine tooth comb
and he says this document is unworkable.
It makes thought a crime.
And he wrote an op Ed to that effect.
So my point would be,
and what,
and who did he,
what organization is he part of
interest?
Yeah,
but which,
which,
uh,
human rights and human diversity.
I mean,
that's exactly.
It says field.
Yes,
exactly.
And so when he looked at this,
he says,
this goes beyond what the Ontario
government was even asking for.
And it gets to the point where it
actually makes.
You can be guilty of thought crime.
You can be guilty of transphobia without
any intent if someone,
if someone says,
I've been harmed mentally,
that is enough for conviction under this
particular policy.
It's the same with the Ontario Human
Rights Commission's policies.
Intent doesn't matter.
So this isn't in this application.
I'm,
I'm saying,
did Adriana Joelle actually get it
right?
And so is that a misapplication or do so
it'll be interesting if the university
does discipline her,
if she gets legal representation,
who claimed that she was actually
applying the policies correctly because
that is the question.
Right?
So,
but it could be two things.
It can be the policies are flawed and
this is the consequence and they were
misapplied.
We don't know,
but if there's definitely ambiguity here
and that,
and that's a crucial issue.
I think Lindsay was guilty under the
gender and sexual violence policy and
she was.
Adrian was accusing her.
She was [inaudible].
Uh,
it would have been an Ontario human
rights code violation,
but GSP,
she was right if there had been a
complaint.
Right,
right.
Okay.
And how many angels can dance on the
head?
Okay.
Procedures in how to apply university
policies.
Same issue here and under what
circumstances were not followed the
training of key individuals to meet the
expectations of the university and
addressing such an issue as an issue as
such as this was not sufficient and must
be improved.
Okay.
The question is who are these key
individuals?
Do they mean Rambo cannot pim lot and
Joel is they,
are they putting all three of those in
there?
And then the next question would be how
are they going to improve the training
of key individuals?
Because that actually worries me as a
faculty member,
right?
Because whenever the administration
decides that it's going to engage in
some additional training of faculty
members,
then that raises the hair on the back of
my neck.
Like,
is this unconscious bias training?
Is that what they're talking about?
Which has been.
Well I think,
uh,
I can't remember.
I've just read recently,
no himself who developed the iat just
published a review paper stating clearly
stating clearly that attempts to reduce
unconscious bias by explicit explicit
training.
There's no evidence whatsoever that they
have any positive effect.
And that was nozick himself who helped
develop the IAT [inaudible],
the little coterie that develop that
test.
I'm a chair of the Harvard Psychology
Department.
I'll remember her name in a minute.
Green walled Anthony Greenwald and
Nozek.
What's her name?
Mazda three of them developed it.
They're starting to fragment a bit
because the thing is being pushed way
too hard.
Right?
It's not a test that's valid for the
purposes that it's being put to and they
know it perfectly well even though
they're consulting about it and have
made quite an enterprise out of it.
But no,
Zack is,
you know,
it seems to be a pretty credible
scientist and he's actually looking at
the data and it's clear that the,
these unconscious bias training programs
have zero positive impact.
There's some evidence that they have
negative impact because of course people
don't like being accused of being
unconscious racists.
Right.
So I'm wonder is that the kind of
training,
and there's nothing in here that says
this,
but this is the problem that it says
there will be training unconscious bias.
Is that the same as systemic
discrimination?
Well,
it's the,
it's the neurological equivalent of
systemic discrimination,
so imagined discredit,
systemic discrimination is built into
the structure of the system,
right?
Unconscious bias is built into your
perceptual structures.
So even before you act or think you're
biased towards against the members of an
outgroup that's the claim,
and not only biased in against the
members have outgroup,
which is a different claim that biased
in favor of your ingroup,
which of course almost every human being
is,
especially if you think about your
family,
but that,
that,
that implicit bias also manifests itself
in behaviors that would essentially be
categorizable as racist,
at least at a low level.
And there's very little evidence that
the implicit bias that this test,
hypothetically measures,
manifests itself in measurable behavior.
So
we went through a thing in the summer
where they ran a regression on salaries
at lorry and found that women were paid
a little bit less than men by about four
percent.
And so they gave all the time
include jade,
did they include age as a covariate?
The answer to that would be no.
The model was a,
it had,
um,
rank,
uh,
and I don't know that it had,
it only had four categories of professor
though when this has been done at
University of Michigan for instance,
because I looked at comparables,
they had 21 categories of professor,
uh,
or 21 departments at ours.
We had four.
So you were comparing,
for instance,
within the business school who might be
in marketing versus someone who.
Well,
I know,
I know from setting up regression
equations ad nauseum that the,
the covariates that you included in the
equation determine the outcome of the,
of the,
of the year equation,
the conclusion they reached,
the explanation for the statistical
significance of the Jenica efficient was
systemic discrimination,
right?
Right.
Of course.
Well,
that,
that wasn't the conclusion they reached.
That was the conclusion.
They stepped into the inquiry width and
they gerrymandered the statistics until
they found a regression equation that
supported their,
their initial claim.
So that was,
that's not an inquiry,
but.
So there's,
what I hear you saying is there's really
no scientific basis for this idea that
there could be this unconscious bias
that could drive.
There is evidence that were full of
unconscious biases,
I mean we couldn't even see if we didn't
have unconscious biases because we have
to use shortcuts and heuristics to just
process the world.
The issue is what measurable impact does
that have on behavioral?
That's the first thing and it's minimal
at best.
First of all,
it's not easy to distinguish between
racial bias and novelty avoidance,
right?
Because what you'd have to do is you'd
have to find a person,
interracial group,
say a white person who is just as
familiar with black people as with white
people and then show that there was a
bias because otherwise you can't
distinguish it from a novelty,
novelty aversion,
and people are characterized by novelty
aversion.
You already have developed a preference
for that cop over this cup.
I mean it happens that quickly and it's
that.
It's that subtle and great and grand,
let's say.
So the first issue is we can't really
distinguish unconscious bias from
perceptual habit,
let's say,
or from or stereotyping from
categorization for that matter,
and that literature is being under
assault in a major way in the social
psychology literature.
But even assuming that an implicit bias
does exist,
which you might,
there might be grounds for by noting
that people do have an in group
preference safe for their family members
and perhaps even for the racial members,
although it's hard to distinguish that
from novelty or from familiarity
preference,
putting all that aside,
which you can't.
There's no evidence that these courses
that are put in place to reduce that
bias have any effect whatsoever on the
bias it's complete.
Even the people who are pushing the IAT
and the idea of implicit bias are
willing to say,
well,
all these things that we're doing to try
to reduce it have absolutely no effect.
Or if anything,
a negative effect.
And again,
just we don't know that what the
training is going to be.
I guess where we went down this rabbit
hole was we don't know what the training
is going to be.
Right?
We don't know.
We have no evidence to assume.
We have no reason to assume that the
training is going to address the proper
problem and every reason to be skeptical
that it won't.
Okay.
So next,
um,
there is also institutional failure that
allowed this to happen.
Well,
we don't know what that means because
I'd like to know what the institutional
failure was,
but that's a pretty broad and she says
when,
when there is institutional failure
ultimately starts and ends with me,
well that's a nice statement and okay,
she's taking responsibility for it,
but unless it's specified what the
institutional failures are,
it's just hand waving.
Going forward,
we will implement improve training and
new procedures and engage in a very
specific administrative review.
Details would be nice to strengthen and
enhance confidence in what students and
employees can expect it.
Lori specifically,
there was no wrongdoing on the part of
Ms.
Dot Shepherd in showing the clip from
Tvo in her tutorial showing a video clip
for the purposes of an academic
discussion is a reasonable classroom
teaching tool.
While thank God for that,
given that Ti vo is a publicly funded,
a middle of the road left leaning,
liberal news media establishment,
a credible one for sure.
I wish that early on immediately
following this story breaking that
administration had said exactly that
because remember for more than a month
now the public,
the Canadian public has wondered,
can you show tv Ontario videos in
classrooms that Lori,
right,
and I'm not.
I'm not joking.
Yeah.
Like this was this and there has not
been an answer from administration on
that.
Very basic question.
Yeah,
and so people who are thinking about
sending their kids to l'oreal are
thinking,
is that the place where they didn't know
whether or not you could show public
television in a classroom?
Is that the place where it took a
independent investigation to come to the
conclusion that it's okay to play a clip
from the agenda that we still don't?
Yes,
exactly.
It is the place where all of that was in
doubt.
That is Wilfred laureate is the place
where those things were in doubt and so
they're not quite as in doubt,
but we also still don't know what else
is.
What else is still in doubt.
Right.
Because if that can be you wonder,
well,
you know,
that's pretty damn innocuous.
Okay.
Any instructional material needs to be
grounded in the appropriate academic
underpinnings to put it in context for
the relevance of the learning outcomes
of the course.
Yeah.
Well,
the questionnaire is any instructional
material needs to be grounded in the
appropriate academic underpinnings.
To put it in context,
the question there is who decides what
the appropriate academic underpinnings
to put it in context are because that's
supposed to be the.
That's supposed to be the bailiwick of
the professor period.
Right,
and with with some leeway for the for
the teaching assistance and so on.
But I worry when I hear about context
because I've seen opinion pieces from
some of my colleagues who tell me that
the appropriate context is within the
frame of social justice or within the
frame of critical theory.
Well,
that's what I'm kind of said to shepherd
was that while part of the reason you
were wrong was because you portrayed it
neutrally.
If you had contextualized it essentially
have you had connects July's Peterson
as Hitler,
which was Rambo kind of statement than
it would have been perhaps appropriate
to to to edit the video and that is
equivalent to leading the witness.
Right.
And leading the witnesses when we have a
lawyer up an authority figure telling
the person on the stand what to say,
taking my ideas and putting them into
that person's mouth.
Right.
Well that's how you produce unconscious
bias.
But.
But my point would be,
so I'm not saying that this is in here,
but we really need clerical error.
Well that's,
that's a.
that's a sentence that doesn't.
That I'm not happy about appropriate
academic underpinnings.
To put it in context for the relevance
of the learning outcomes of the course.
Jesus.
It's just administrative.
Double speak the whole way through.
You present in class in order.
The criteria for evaluating that.
I,
I showed videos all the time.
Every class says they have the adequate
underpinnings.
Yeah.
Well that's.
That's the question is who decides that
did the.
The answer to that.
There's a simple answer to that.
The professor.
That's the answer.
There isn't another answer.
There's no board,
there's no higher authority,
there's nothing else you know,
and I show I do show clips from Hitler
in my class and my personality class
when we talk about orderliness and
totalitarianism,
I show clips from the triumph of the
will and I show this other documentary
called Crumb,
which is about,
uh,
an underground cartoonist from the 19
sixties named Robert Crumb.
And it is an absolutely shocking
documentary,
like if you ever wanted to know more
than you want to know about rapists and
serial killers,
that documentary will tell you.
It's really,
it's a tough.
It's a tough watch.
No one,
I can't,
I can't imagine a like a committee
reviewing my teaching materials and
allowing those things to go forward
without challenge.
It'd be a disaster.
Okay.
The ensuing discussion also needs to be
handled properly.
Yeah.
Well,
we have no reason to believe this
discussion was not handled well in the
tutorial in question.
Okay.
So whatever handled property means
Lindsay Shepherd managed it,
which I think is a good sign here
because if we take that as the model,
Lindsay did present the information
neutrally.
Yeah.
And,
and she was not taking sides and if
that's our model,
that's,
that's a good sign.
Okay,
that's good.
So that's acceptable
by this,
because we're going to three or four
paragraphs.
Find out that we need enhanced training
for tea.
Great.
So did she handle it properly?
Why do we need to treat it?
The training?
Yes.
That's row on.
And again,
who's going to do the training because
it's not going to be the faculty because
the faculty don't have time or the
inclination for that matter to run that
kind of trains are going to be the
diversity and equity.
Yeah,
right.
Well,
that's the question.
Who's going to do the training?
I have apologized to ms dot shepherd
publicly,
as has Dr Lew Rambo Khanna,
who's supervising professor the
university has conveyed to her today
that the results of the fact report to
make the results of the fact finding
report to make sure she understands it
is clear that she was involved in no
wrongdoing.
Yes.
Well,
for someone who is involved in no wrong
doing,
she should bloody well got raked over
the coals for the last month.
So the university is taking concrete
steps to make changes to ensure this
doesn't happen again.
Yeah,
well good.
It has been made clear to those who were
involved in the meeting with Ms Dot
shepherd that their conduct does not
meet the high standards I set for staff
and faculty.
Well,
that is a big question there.
Right?
How has it been made clear to those who
were involved in the meeting with Ms Dot
Shepherd?
That their conduct does not meet those
high standards?
Because we don't know.
Does that mean that the president talked
to them as there'd being disciplinary
action like we,
we.
Because if it was,
I don't even know what would be
appropriate,
but I would say that not knowing what
was done is not appropriate.
So,
and I think it deserves specifics.
I mean that's what got me into this was
the Christie Blatchford,
his article was very accurate because
she already had the audio,
but then when we heard the audio,
it was so appalling what was done to her
in that room.
It was such horrible bullying.
Uh,
and,
and just such a violation of whether the
university should stand for.
That's what all of the anger,
I mean in Canada,
the devil's in the details.
So it's the same with the,
how it has been made clear to those who
are involved.
So because I don't mean maybe this is
something we could talk about too.
I don't know what would constitute
appropriate disciplinary measures as a
concept.
I mean,
you have here three people acting on a
nonexistent complaint who produced an
international scandal that damaged
lindsay in a real sense,
although it might have also made her
stronger,
but it certainly,
it certainly didn't have to because a
lesser person would have crumbled.
I don't know if she would feel that she,
I think she might take exception to
that.
Uh,
she certainly has not claimed any kind
of victim status through this whole
thing and I think that no,
but that's more a testament to her
character than,
than anything else because I mean she
was subject to the kind of attacks I
would say that would have snowed under a
lesser person,
but she has risen to this challenge.
Yes,
definitely,
definitely.
Well,
and,
and thank God for that.
But then there has been real harm done
to the university as far as.
I don't know how you would quantify that
and financial terms,
but I suspect it's substantial.
But reputational terms,
I mean now I would say internationally
this is what Wilford Laurey is known
for,
so maybe that's an overstatement,
but I don't think so.
As these are individual employment
issues,
I cannot go into greater detail on any
individual case.
Well that could be but know that the
university has and is taking action to
rectify the situation and send a clear
signal that this cannot and will not
happen again.
That sounds pretty forthright.
Yeah,
it is.
One key improvement highlight is the
need to enhance our faculty and Ta
Training.
Yeah.
Well,
like I said,
as a faculty member,
whenever I see that I don't see the role
of the administrators at a university to
to train the faculty.
That's not their role.
Their role is to move paper around for
the faculty.
Fundamentally it is the responsibility
of course,
instructors to develop guidelines for
the roles and expectations of their tax.
Fair enough.
The university also has high
expectations of professors.
As Ta supervisors,
we recognize the need to do more in this
area.
We wreck the university's intent is to
enhance the training and support for
both the supervisors and teaching
assistants,
making these mandatory and standardized.
That's my favorite part.
Jesus.
Dismal.
So that.
So my suspicions as a skeptic are that
the making of training for faculty,
Mandatory and standardized will do more
harm than this scandal has done over the
long run.
So we don't know what the training is.
We don't know who's going to do it.
We don't know what it's going to be
about,
but the one thing we do now,
is it
mandatory?
Mandatory and standardized,
right?
Yeah.
Mandatory and standardized.
Be Interesting to see how they'll do
that too because it isn't so easy to
make training mandatory for faculty
members.
Right?
You can't just do that by fit because
they can generally tell you to go to
hell and should gendered and sexual
violence policy.
It has become clear to us that managing
the new gendered and sexual violence
policy,
now that's the one that's mandated by
the provincial government.
So it was bill a one 63,
the provincial bill that said you need
to have a policy on gendered and sexual
violence.
According to our colleague Dr Andrew
Robinson.
He says,
we go way beyond what the province even
asked for to the point where it becomes
unmanageable and,
and you have instances of thought crime.
So.
So that's what we have like this like
this where you can claim that somebody
is transphobic for simply showing a
video.
Can I.
Can I read you?
The definition is this from the gender
is from our policies,
from our policy.
It is an action that reinforces gender
inequalities resulting in physical,
sexual,
emotional,
economic,
or mental harm.
Okay,
so what's the first part of that again?
Yes.
Yeah.
You get lost,
don't you?
It is an action that reinforces gender
inequality.
Okay,
so let's start with that.
An action that reinforces gender
inequalities.
Okay.
So the first thing we might point out is
that no one knows what the hell that
means,
right?
It's a box that you can put anything in.
So actions that's a problem because
what?
It isn't obvious to what constitutes an
action or an inaction for that matter.
So I mean,
and then that reinforces gender
inequalities,
right?
So that,
that's,
that's the sort of sentence that only
someone who's ideologically possessed to
the maximum would create because you
can't parse it.
Gender inequalities.
Like what does that mean exactly?
I don't.
Well anyways,
discrimination,
sex or gender,
it doesn't talk about discrimination.
It talks about inequality,
right?
Which is,
which is,
it would be different if,
if the,
the phrasing had included the words
discrimination.
Okay.
And the next part is a resulting in
physical,
sexual,
emotional,
economic or mental harm.
Right?
Right.
So it says broadly construed,
both,
both clauses are as broadly construed as
they can be,
and the reason for that is to allow
maximum scope per interpretation,
which is exactly what happened with
Adrian Joel.
Well,
mental harm,
again,
mental harm.
And,
and as you pointed out,
mental harm is not backed up by the
empirical evidence apart from
posttraumatic stress syndrome,
like cognitive behavioral therapy would
suggest that you actually can do mental
good by exposing someone to
objectionable ideas when they've eaten
in moderation in order to help them
become less mentally fragile.
Uh,
Scott Lilienfeld out of emory
university,
very credible scholar.
Well,
he is one of the mass.
He's written several textbooks on psycho
pathology,
right?
He knows his stuff and just this year he
put out a paper where you explored the,
the empirical evidence around
microaggressions,
and he did all of the literature and
microaggressions that are of course,
these innocuous actions that are deemed
to be bigoted or,
or somehow sexist.
It's rudeness essentially.
They are actually.
It's showing a video of from Tvo is what
a microaggression is.
And what he said was,
there is absolutely no evidence.
There's no evidence that
microaggressions,
these objectionable ideas lead to mental
harm.
He also said that the,
the concept itself is extraordinarily
ill defined,
which is also a big problem.
That was the beginning of our
conversation.
Everything is if you make the box big
enough,
you can put anything into it
and and what you see in this gender and
violence policy that will,
is reading from there,
they're actually go on to say that this
can include
Heterosexism,
like you can be your,
your mental crime can be heterosexism.
Yeah.
So what if I said something in class,
like the empirical evidence strongly
suggests that raising children in a two
parent family leads to better outcomes,
which it does by the way,
like it like and seriously it does that.
Then also that's the question of,
well arguably right?
Arguably our transcripts,
that policy.
Now here's an interesting thing too,
so it has become
clear to us that managing the new
gendered and sexual violence,
Paul's,
he has led to a confusion in its
application.
Right.
Okay.
So this is back to the issue we
described earlier.
Is it a confused confusion in the
application or in the policy?
Now you just read the damn policy.
Now it seems to me that there's no way
you could apply that policy without
confusion,
so it's not a confusion in its
application,
its.
It might also be that,
but it's a confusion in the policy
written right into it.
Okay,
so that's.
That's of crucial importance,
right?
It,
in fact,
the interviews conducted by the fact
finder confirmed that the rationale for
invoking the GSV P did not exist.
It was misapplied and was a significant
overreach.
Yeah.
I'm not so sure about that because I
know that these kinds of policies emerge
from the same sort of policy framework
that characterizes the Ontario Human
Rights Commission.
It's the same people doing it and the
Ontario Human Rights Commission policies
are written so that they can be broadly
misapplied with no significant
overreach.
So.
Okay,
so that's a problem.
To provide clarity of the policies
intent and to strengthen accountability.
We will engage in an administrative
review with the goal of finding the
appropriate structure to oversee and
execute the GSPP and its accompanying
procedures.
We will also undertake a full review of
the policy and its procedures.
Okay,
so good.
So they're.
They're saying while it might've been
misapplied,
but maybe the policy itself also has
some problem.
I think
this is really good news and we had a
meeting with our colleague Andrew Andrew
Robinson today and we said,
well,
you know,
what do you think about this?
And he was pleased.
He said,
you know,
if some good has come out of this
controversy,
this is one of those good things because
definitely the gendered and sexual
violence policy,
we haven't.
Lori isn't workable.
It is prejudiced against certain people
and certain ideas and so it needs to be
reworked because at this is not an
inclusive document.
It excludes
and so it needs to be fixed.
So this is a good thing.
Well,
and it's also a canary in the coal mine
for similar policies at universities all
across Canada.
We'd say,
and maybe broader because one of one
thing you'd hope is that the Lindsay
Shepherd affair has produced enough,
may be negative repercussions to set
people back on their heels a little bit
and make them dig into these policies
because I can't imagine that there's
another university in Canada who would
enjoy partaking in a scandal of
equivalent magnitude.
What I would hope,
and on that point,
Jordan,
if someone is a student or if someone is
a faculty member,
ask for the evidence.
That's what I've learned from this.
There are a lot of claims out there.
Mental harm.
Our campuses become unsafe.
Uh,
the ideas that are contained in the,
the gendered and sexual violence policy.
I'm saying,
okay,
what is the evidence that proves this?
Because this is,
this is what a university is to be based
on
from the enlightenment to today.
We are supposed to be able to say,
here's the evidence for why we do this.
And the further we get away from
evidence and the more we embrace
ideology,
we completely remove what the mission of
a university is supposed to be.
And the idea of evidence,
we removed the idea of evidence,
which means we remove the idea of
knowledge because there's no distinction
between knowledge and evidence.
Right?
Right.
So,
so if you are a student and you want to
say,
what can I do say,
what's the evidence of mental harm?
What's the evidence that,
that this,
that I'm transphobic.
What's the wealth?
Well,
so partly what you're also saying there
is a restatement of the old presumption
of innocence idea.
It's like,
okay,
you're accusing me of something.
Prove it.
I'm innocent.
Adi,
prove it.
Where's your evidence?
Now I know when we do it.
I know.
Well,
part of that is tied up with this,
with the sexual harassment issue,
because increasingly,
and this is,
this is this has started,
I think most particularly the United
States,
we're moving towards a preponderance of
evidence standard instead of a
assumption of innocence standard.
That's especially true with these sexual
harassment policies that are being
derived by derive from institutions and
administrators concerned with such
things as the gendered and sexual
violence policy.
And that.
That's related to the comment you made
earlier about the lawyer who wasn't
allowed to speak right,
because she had the temerity to offer
someone who is accused of a crime,
a legal defense,
right when,
when apparently what we were supposed to
do with just assume that the people who
were making the accusations were right
because they claimed that they were
wronged.
So and,
and to,
to be,
I mean,
we always have to do our caveats,
don't we?
We say,
I know that we want to protect people
who are victims like I each of us would
agree,
but it can't be done at this sac by
sacrificing truth.
Well,
you don't protect people from being
victimized by undermining the rule of
law.
No,
quite the contrary because ultimately it
comes back to bite you in the behind.
Yeah.
So that's for sure.
And very,
very rapidly.
So.
Okay.
In the interim,
we will ensure access to the existing
support and complaints procedures by
providing management and oversight
through the Austin Office of dispute,
Resolution and support.
Okay.
I'm not sure what that means.
Well,
it's actually very good news.
Okay.
Means that,
uh,
the oversight of this is being removed
from the diversity and equity office and
put under the president's direct
control.
So she doesn't think that they're
responsible.
I'm,
and I'm very worried about diversity and
equity office over
this suggests that the president should
be,
it suggests the president is also
worried about the diversity and equity
office that she has said we're not a
bit,
but the fact that she has done this is
really a strong sign that,
that she is aware that that office needs
to be needs to be right or at least that
she's concerned enough the reputation
of the university so that she's not
going to let the same mistake happen
again,
which is a good thing.
Like I don't care why she's doing it
particularly,
but it's a good thing that it is being
done.
Okay.
So fine.
So that's,
that's a,
that's good news that this has the added
benefit of improved accountability as
that office reports through to me as
president.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well you can see in those lines that
she's not particularly happy about
what's happened.
I wonder what sort of financial hit
Wilfrid laurier took because you could
imagine that while the donors are going
to be a lot more conservative than the,
than the professors and the
administrators and the students.
Well,
we have a,
we've been contacted by a group of
alumni who have now organized.
They haven't yet released what would be
their,
their press release,
but slowly they've been reaching out to
other alumni and it's the lorry,
a alumni for free expression.
And what they have said is their mandate
is one to withhold all donations until
laurie a excepts the Loria statement for
freedom of expression.
And uh,
I,
I haven't checked in.
It was just someone acting on her own.
Uh,
she's a Lauria alumni.
She has I guess,
contacts within the alumni association
and she just,
she sent us some contact information and
said,
here's what I'm doing,
wanted you to know I support your
efforts and I'm,
I'm working on this.
I'll let you know when I'm ready to go.
And so that was really encouraging.
Yeah.
I have a colleague who does a survey of
chief financial officers quarterly to
gauge their optimism about the economy
and started down at Duke and he's
starting it now for Canada and he got
responses from to a he because he sent
out an email to shortly after this
broke,
he got responses from two alumni who
just said,
you're,
you know,
why should I participate in this?
Why should I help you?
This is not so I don't have any respect
for you.
These are alumni of,
of,
of Wilfrid laurier university as well,
and I can imagine too that enrollment is
going to take a pretty vicious hit.
You know,
our business school is quite excellent.
We have a great car program.
We in the finance area,
tech,
a lot of very strong students and we
compete for top tier students in Ontario
of the entry average is like 89 or
something and,
and,
and we really could be for the,
what we call the high flyers and they
can choose any school right in the
province,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
it doesn't take much of a hit to a
reputation to give people who have
options,
the reason to go elsewhere,
right.
And then you lose the best people and
that's when things really started
the fall apart and what you might begin
to see.
And I would say that this is something
that uh,
the general public might look at,
watch what happens to the entrance
averages in the arts and humanities that
so,
so we might not take a hit,
but let's see if the average is take a
hit because suddenly and currently the
entrance average to get into our general
arts program in communications.
Let's just talk.
Communications is mid seventies with an
average of 60 in English.
So.
So I,
I don't,
I mean,
right,
basically
a failing grade because I'm just few
handy in the NASA.
In high school
you'll get 60 you really well,
right?
So it's,
it's basically the grading basically
runs from 60,
it goes zero.
You didn't hand it in 60 to 100.
You handed it in.
And let's keep in mind that the tutorial
that Lindsay was running was a grammar
tutorial.
The content of which looked a lot like
grade six curriculum.
Yeah.
Well that gets us into a discussion of
the schools in general,
but we're all ready.
I'm,
I'm thinking that maybe it's not a good
idea to lower standards any anymore.
Right,
right,
right.
Okay.
So academic freedom and freedom of
expression for those who have chosen to
use this incident as an indictment of
Wilfrid laurier university or the plight
of Canadian universities in general,
I say your assertion is unreasonable and
unfounded.
Well,
we better stop this interview.
Yeah.
Well,
you,
you can say that all you want.
I.
Well,
I would say instead that what happened
at Wilfrid laurier is a precise
manifestation of exactly the sort of rot
that both produced bill [inaudible] and
that I was warning about last September.
And so I don't think the assertion is
unreasonable in an unfounded at all.
And here's one piece of data.
Eighty percent of humanities papers are
not sighted once,
so,
so.
So let's just translate that for the
viewing public.
Yes.
That means that they're producing
scholarship that nobody looks at that,
that even their friends don't look at.
And because,
okay,
so what a citation is,
is I read someone's paper and I find a
good idea in it,
and then I use that idea to buttress and
idea of my own or to,
or to,
or to riff off or to,
or to criticize even for that matter.
And then I cite them,
I say who they were and when they
published it.
And then the paper,
the size that there's a huge bureaucracy
that keeps track of citations and it's a
major indication of academic ability to
be cited,
right?
It's,
it's,
it's the,
it's like it's academic payment to be
cited.
Okay.
So 80 percent of humanities papers don't
get cited once.
It's absolute failures,
absolute failure as a game.
If someone wanted to play a game,
uh,
I would suggest that they go and they
look at the publications of the
professors in a particular area and see
if the titles all sound the same.
And if they all say something about
intersectionality,
a colonialism and,
and these other various,
uh,
social justice words,
you might wonder,
am I going to get taught the same course
again?
And again,
by every professor in this program,
because it seems to me that all of their
research is,
is very similar.
Uh,
and,
and how can that be when there's such a
broad base of knowledge and the world
that we can have such similarity between
every publication,
which then goes on.
Why?
Why do I need to read my colleague stuff
when it's exactly like my own,
which,
which we see.
So just just as a baseline Jordan,
how many,
like what,
what would you say
is,
is someone who is doing some good
research?
What's,
how many citations would,
would they be receiving?
Maybe collectively,
like what,
what are we looking?
Thousands.
Thousands?
Yeah.
Well a good.
Like if you,
if you write a good paper then like a
great paypal,
paypal will get you 100 citations,
right?
An outstanding overwhelmingly
outstanding pay.
I'll get you a thousand citations.
Um,
10 isn't none.
You know,
if you register with 10,
but zero is that failure.
It means your work had zero impact it,
it means your work wasn't worth the
paper.
It was published on this.
This brings us to a kind of interesting
little issue with regards to the rot in
the universities,
which,
which Deborah mccloud she says does not
exist.
It's like,
here's how the game works is that we set
up a little ideological garden,
right?
The 10 of us play in,
and then we all publish in the same
journal and we peer review each other's
articles and we just published them.
There's no critique or very little.
So the,
the barrier for publication is very,
very low when it should be very high,
like a good journal,
a good journal will reject.
Ninety percent of the papers that are,
uh,
that are,
are,
are submitted to it,
right?
So rejection rates really matter.
So the question is why do the papers get
published since no one reads them and
they have nothing to offer.
And the answer to that is very
straightforward.
The journals are extremely expensive,
are way more expensive than they should
be.
So just to buy a single paper online for
the ordinary person is like $40,
which is more than a hardcover book.
That's just a download,
the PDF.
And so the journal itself,
the libraries are full of them,
are very expensive and the subscriptions
are very expensive and so what happens
is the professors pressure the
university libraries to by the journals
and the library funds the publisher and
so the publishers will publish anything.
Routledge is a good example of that,
much to my chagrin because they
published my first book but and they
used to be a great publishing house,
but they'll publish damn near anything
and the reason for that is that the
libraries are forced to pay radically
inflated prices for the publications
that no one ever reads.
And so people right to publish in
journals that libraries have to purchase
at inflated prices to produce knowledge
that no one will ever read.
And that's the little scandal that
plagues the humanities.
I think it characterizes the humanities
more than plagues them.
So the idea that there's no systemic
rot,
let's say in the universities,
especially in the humanities,
is just not right.
This is just far too general.
There.
There is rot and it's not everywhere and
this just reveals that.
I don't think she's that familiar with
the situation.
She's in and,
and I've been listening to some of your
work and Jonathan Haidt trying to
understand what's been going on over the
last two years in universities protected
as I am in a business school and
starting to realize that it's not
everywhere.
It's social justice perspective.
Fields are fine so far.
Yeah,
and the business schools,
although there are moves into the
business schools,
but they're still doing all right.
Philosophy is not doing too badly.
Like there are disciplines that have
still remained untouched and mostly
what's happened so far is that if the
discipline has a strong economic or
scientific footing,
it's proved much harder to corrupt and
empirical for my part.
So I play in the playground of sociology
of religion,
but all my stuff,
well most of my stuff is quantitative so
I actually,
I wasn't familiar with what was going
on.
I don't.
I go to conferences where everybody has
to have strong empirical evidence.
I publish in journals that are
international journals that are the
scientific study of religion is what we
do.
So,
you know,
I'm familiar with food co and that
stuff,
but that's not where I play,
so I wasn't really exposed to what's
going on and you don't and you don't
really think.
Well they kept no reason to be that
concerned about it.
Well this is it,
but then I'm trying to get into the
headspace of some of my colleagues.
So I got out of text book,
it was called race class and gender and
it's,
it's an anthology that's used in
cultural studies courses in women's
studies courses and it sorta the Goto
text.
So I'm told and I'm reading it and I
turned it and I turn to page 14 and I
can tell you it's page 14 because I was
so astounded by what I found and it
said,
uh,
we the,
Oh,
it says objectivity as found through
rational thought is a western and
masculine concept that we will challenge
throughout this text.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
And I said it's too bad.
It's too bad that you're shocked by that
because the want to go for irrational pc
types have been saying exactly that
since the 19 seventies.
Like that is exactly.
Make no mistake about it.
This is why mcclachi is wrong.
This isn't,
this isn't something they're secreting
in.
This is the dead statement.
Oh yeah.
They said,
um,
the,
the whole notion of logic and coherence
and empirical data for that matter.
The evidence.
Let's question,
let's question the definition of
evidence because the underlying idea.
Remember the underlying idea here is
that all hierarchies are predicated on
power.
So if the reason that I put forward
something as evidence isn't because it's
evidence,
it's because it's evidenced that I get
to have that position of power.
And so if you're a postmodernist and you
say,
well,
I'm going to question your evidence,
what you think you're saying is you're
going to question my claim to that
arbitrary power.
The whole idea that there's evidence
outside of claims of arbitrary power.
The postmodernist dispensed without the
19 seventies.
That's Derrida.
That's exactly what he said in all this
time.
I've been trying to get samples of
thousands so that I could say,
you know,
this is a little bit.
We can say something,
God just in generalized.
No,
no.
That just demonstrates how thoroughly
entrenched you are in the reining
patriarchal ideology,
I guess,
and I was just hoping to get beyond
anecdotal.
There's no beyond that.
There's no beyond anecdotal.
That's become a methodology.
That's odd.
It's called auto ethnography is a
technical term for it and auto
ethnography is the publication of a
journey of a,
of a private diary essentially in a
hypothetically reputable,
reputable academic journal.
It's only because of in the last three
or four years that these things have
been happening and I said,
well,
where?
Where do they get this?
How do they,
how do they find these thoughts?
Yes.
Well,
we don't.
We don't want to fall into the mistake
of making,
of making the assumption that this
hasn't been thought through.
People are just misunderstanding what
evidence is.
That isn't what's happening at all.
When they say they want to question the
definition of evidence,
that's exactly what they mean when they
say,
we want a question,
the definition of evidence because the
definition of evidence currently
supports the scientific power structure
in chemistry say,
and that's fundamentally dominated by,
let's say,
white men.
We can go after the definition of
evidence itself and that's how we're
going to bring it down,
and so the next on the hit list are
going to be the biologists that are
already under attack from the paper.
It said that mathematics is whiteness.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Definitely.
I didn't know that mathematics could
have a race.
Yep.
Thinking the thing is there's nothing
logical about these claims.
Once you accept this central axioms,
the axioms are straightforward.
The world is a battleground of power
hierarchies.
That's what it is.
There isn't anything else outside of
that,
and each power hierarchy generates its
own internal narrative including rules
for what constitutes evidence that
support and buttress the structure of
that hierarchy and because the
hierarchy's exclude,
then it's in the best interests of the
people who are excluded to invert the
hierarchy and of course they also regard
that as just even though that's part of
the incoherence of the entire argument,
that's where they have to turn to to
Marxism,
but make no mistake about it.
This isn't.
This isn't accidental.
It isn't.
People misunderstanding what constitutes
evidence.
Not at all.
No.
I've been listening to some of your
lectures on this for the last year and
thinking you sound a little deranged.
Well,
I,
I might be a little deranged deranged
about this.
And then this whole episode with Lindsay
Shepherd just proves that in every
dimension of this is about power.
Uh,
the double speak,
the,
the changing of terminology from the
expulsion.
People's ideas could be violent.
The circling,
the sacred,
circling around the victim group.
Well,
look
what happened at Wilfrid laurier.
One of the things that were so bloody
interesting that I thought was just
fascinating was the unbelievably
strategic attempt to transform shepherd
into perpetrator and
Rambo Kana and pim law into the victims,
especially Rocana as a professor of
color.
Right?
So,
so what happens,
the reverse narrative was,
well,
Lindsay shepherd was using something
like her white privilege and their white
tiers to,
to harass a poor professor of color.
Untenured professor of color.
Yeah.
And that there was every attempt made on
the part of the people who are going
after shepherd to make that the
narrative.
So
in the they started accusing everyone of
being trans phobic just right out of the
blocks.
Within days of this,
we were all tired without epithet.
Immediately labels have been just flying
and without any regard to the intent of
the person or even the content.
Here's something interesting about the
transphobia issue too,
so I've had at least now a number of
discussions with trans people by the
way,
but also a number of letters from trans
people over the last year,
about 40 of them as a matter of fact,
which is a lot of letters because there
aren't that many trans people and every
single one of them I think I got one
letter from a trans person who wasn't
happy with what I was doing,
but every single one of the other
letters said the same thing.
We are sick and tired of being the
poster child for these activists who
claim to speak in our name because
that's another thing that we should be
very aware of is just because an
activist comes out and says,
I'm a member of this minority group and
therefore I speak for them.
It's like the first time it might be
true,
but the second claim is not only just
unjustifiable,
it's actually,
I would say it's,
it's not racist exactly,
but it's groups just because it's
predicated on the assumption that just
because you happen to be the member of a
class,
that you're a representative member of
that class,
that class is so homogenous that
everyone in it is the same enough so
that all the members within it can speak
for all the other members used to call
that racism when it was,
it applied to racial category.
Absolutely.
But Lindsay has been very good to point
out and so if some of the media that
there have been a transgendered students
at Laurie who have spoken out in support
of Lindsay and we have to keep this in
mind that this is not a transgendered
issue.
No,
and neither was my comments on bill
because I mean,
all I know that Lindsey,
as she even said,
she is not transphobic.
She supports the rights of transgendered
people.
This is,
she's unequivocal in that.
Uh,
and,
and I think that that's just cover story
her for her.
True,
right beliefs,
and there are transgendered students who
have come to her support and at great
personal cost to themselves.
Like those are some brave people.
They're right there to break with that
group that the hostility in that group
is real in the activist end of the
group.
You Bet.
Yeah.
We're
so quick to take over this issue as
their own and claim that the,
the debate itself was and
that it was just cover for this
transphobic climate that existed and it
has nothing to do with transgender
people.
It's funny too.
You saw the same thing with um,
Rinaldo Walcott when he was on the
director of the women's in diversity
women's and gender studies at,
at the,
at,
at the University of Toronto.
He claimed that he claimed like four
times in that interview that the
University of Toronto was a white
supremacist organization.
And I thought I just don't know what to
make of that.
Like I traveled down to my office about
a week after that,
that,
that interview and I happened by some
students who were standing outside
waiting to write an exam.
So there's about 100 of them may,
and like this is particularly true at
the University of Toronto.
I would say that
you couldn't look at that group of
students for more than two seconds and
think that that was a white supremacist
organization.
I mean it's so ethnically diverse.
If you think that the University of
Toronto is a white supremacist
organization,
then what that essentially means is that
the most tolerant institution in the
most tolerant city in the most tolerant
province in the most tolerant country in
the world is white supremacist.
So it's like,
well then I don't.
I don't,
I don't even know what you could.
Especially when you say that,
as someone who's a full professor,
I don't know if he's a full professor
who's a professor at that institute.
It's like,
where's your evidence for this?
That same professor was using racial
slurs against Lindsay.
Oh yes.
The white tiers thing.
They're also misogynistic,
right?
Because it's white girl tears.
I could never ever
do something like that to any student of
any race.
I just don't understand how the people
on the far left can rationalize that
kind of behavior.
It,
it just,
it's so they can rationalize it with
power,
but in terms of civility,
just incivility in recognizing the
humanity in every person.
How can you resort to those kinds of
racial slights?
I just,
I don't.
I don't understand how you can say don't
be racist and then you make racial
comments terribly racist comments.
I just,
I don't under do people.
Well,
no,
there's the idea there is
straightforward.
You cannot on her racist comments
against the dominant group.
That's the rule.
If there's a dominant group,
so once you identify them as oppressor,
you can say anything you want about them
because by definition this is axiomatic
in the ideology.
You can't say anything racist about the
oppressors,
that that's like a rule.
It's a rule of discourse.
So here's where I go with this.
For self interest,
do you not realize when you say,
I don't care about your efin white
fragility?
No,
that not well cut.
Is that as I get his name right?
Walcott,
he didn't say,
but others other pundits have said that
in it's appeared on Lindsay Lindsay's
twitter page where they've assaulted her
there or that's too dramatic where
they've made insulted her.
They're insulted her there.
Uh,
but my,
my point would be,
even in your self interest,
do you not realize that you are giving
ammunition to the real white
supremacists?
Do you not realize that there are really
dangerous people on the right who are
looking for that exact kind of comment
to rationalize their behavior?
Well,
if you're trying to burn something down,
what makes you think you're going to be
so careful about how it burns down?
And I really mean that.
Look,
I mean I've,
I've,
I've had,
have interactions with the right wing
racial supremacists online.
They're not very happy with me and it's
because I called them out for the same
sort of behavior that the leftists
manifest,
which is like,
I don't,
I'm not impressed by your manifestation
of group identity,
Uber All let's say.
But I understand that the radical right
wingers are playing the same game as the
radical left winger.
So you might say,
well why would the radical left wingers
play into their hands?
I would say,
well,
if you're trying to,
if you're trying to burn the whole damn
house down,
then why not inflame the people who are
most likely to do it?
And you might think,
well no,
that,
that's not in anybody's best interest.
It's like it's the stated aim of this
ideology,
right?
They want to invert the pie.
They want to invert the Patriarchy
essentially.
Well,
what's the patriarchy while it's the
White Supremacist University of Toronto.
So who cares if you're handing your
opponents weapons,
you're hoping that it will escalate that
the people on the left as well as the
people on the right.
Yeah.
So its power because uh,
this is the same thing has happened at
evergreen state and the whole
justification there was racism.
I know when they went in after Bret
Weinstein,
who is about is,
I mean Brent is,
he's a Bernie.
He's a Bernie supporter,
right,
exactly.
They eat their own.
Last week from Mike Paris,
who is the only colleague of his that
publicly defended him and he emails me
and he says,
I've been following the story closely
and I just want to reach out and just,
you know,
commiserate with you and wonder is there
anything we can do or talk about it
together?
And I thought,
no,
you're from evergreen state,
you know,
that's a nightmare and we're not that
bad,
but it's the same pattern repeated.
It's not about transgender people and
their rights and,
and just the victim.
They didn't know the term transgender
people.
As far as I'm concerned,
we're,
we're like sacrificial animals on the
altar of bill.
See 16,
the activists have a new group that's
oppressed to wave the flag for,
to push forward their radiology.
And,
and as NSA said,
the consistent message I've got from
transsexual people is I wish they just
shut the hell up and quit putting us out
in,
in the public
eye in that guys,
because all they're doing is making our
life more difficult.
It's like,
well,
it doesn't matter.
We're trying to tear down the
patriarchy.
Who cares if your life is being made
more difficult?
It's like you.
You don't make an omelet without
breaking a few eggs.
We want to keep that in mind.
Okay.
Laurie prepares our students and
instructors for difficult discussions.
Yeah,
probably not.
We support our teachers in navigating
complex and divisive issues with care
and confidence.
That's a more credible statement.
I mean,
especially given the outcome of this is
just want to take you back to the
lessons of the previous paragraph.
Lauria has commitment to academic
freedom or freedom of expression.
Well,
that's unequivocal perfect.
Yes.
Except that they won't adopt the,
the Chicago principles.
So for example,
something else to keep in mind that the.
I think this is the first time anybody's
talked about this when we were
established in 1973.
The Wilfred Laurier Act says
specifically that this university will
be dedicated to research and teaching in
the spirit of free inquiry and free
expression.
That is the establishing act of our
universe charter statement and,
and,
and that is what it says is our mission.
So in fact,
we are breaking the law by not standing
behind maximum free expression.
And Max free inquire because it is right
in our very founding principle,
our very founding charter in the fact
that we are so hesitant to to just
embrace that and say,
we know that it's within this contest of
ideas that the best facts come forward
and knowledges advanced.
Why are we afraid of that?
Why are we afraid?
What's made made every university a
great university because we're doubtful
about the integrity of the institution
like this.
This critique that whose claim is that
our institutions are patriarchal.
Institutions are fundamentally corrupt
and oppressive is sufficiently.
What would you say makes people
sufficiently guilty so they're perfectly
willing to circumvent their adherence to
policies,
to charter policies like that.
I just think that at some point you have
to say,
this is why you were created.
Maybe we should get back to this and
maybe.
I mean maybe there's a someone who is in
the provincial parliament who's going to
say,
I'm kind of upset that you've actually
rejected the very founding charter.
I would hear,
well,
there's no one in the current in the
current legislature that would do that.
Certainly not in the current government.
Not by any,
not it,
no,
no chance at all.
Okay.
Um,
we support our teachers in navigating
complex and divisive issues with care
and confidence.
We are leaders in ensuring our students,
faculty,
and staff have the necessary supports
and tools to help those who've
experienced marginalization and
discrimination to engage fully.
Okay.
So now you see the reversal,
right?
Right away.
Here is,
and this happens every time now that a
modern university,
virtually every time that a modern
university comes out with a statement in
favor of free speech,
the next thing they do is,
is bringing this competing set of claims
like the,
uh,
to help those who have experienced
marginalization and discrimination to
engage fully.
As soon as the word marginalization is
in there,
then you know that that postmodern ethos
has,
has manifested itself within the,
within the confines of the document
property.
Grounded academic debate at laureate
occurs everyday and encourages critical
thinking and civil discourse.
Yeah,
ideas that one finds objectionable
should be challenged and debated.
The common good of society depends on
the search for knowledge and it's free
expression.
Hey,
fair enough.
Free expression and academic university
academic freedom at the university
require accompanying responsibilities
and accountabilities to be met by
members of the university community.
The other shoe drops.
Well,
even that statement,
it's not so bad.
I mean,
okay.
Faculty members have responsibilities
and they should be accountable.
I think.
I think that university should be a
civil place.
I think that it should be civil,
right?
I think that there should be tolerance,
but tolerance is very different from an
embrace and a complete embrace of what
diversity is now defined as.
Or equity is defined.
Tolerance means I disagree,
but I'm going to let you speak anyway.
And that really is the goal of the
university.
Uh,
so anyway.
Yeah.
Okay.
We,
we,
we will continue to ensure that we are
protected against protecting,
against and dealing with hate and
intolerance.
These have those have no place in civil
society.
See that I'm not so sure about that.
Hate and intolerance have no place in
civil society.
The problem with that is hate,
hate and intolerance is not defined
here.
That is the problem and the I keep
hearing hate speech is not free speech.
And then when I asked,
well,
what do you mean by hate speech?
Yes,
that is the problem.
Well,
the other thing too is I'm actually
allowed to hate you.
It's okay.
You might've done something that makes
me hate you but that.
But there are limits on what I can do as
a consequence of that hate.
And that is not.
So there's two problems.
The first problem is this is a big one
who defines hate.
That's a major problem.
And the second is,
well,
you don't limit hate.
You can't limit hate anymore than you
can limit anger or aggression,
but you can limit the manner in which
people conduct themselves when they're
motivated by those emotions.
And let's be clear,
there is really a clear definition of
hate when you look at the criminal code
under sections three,
18,
and 3:19,
it says you cannot advocate physical
violence against an identifiable group.
I am totally on board with that.
Like let's,
let's be clear.
You can't say go and hurt these people.
I got that.
But that's really clear.
Where's that?
Definitely.
I just want to see all the issue.
There is something we discussed earlier
is while then we can gerrymander the
definition of hurt,
right?
Well,
I'm talking physical advocating,
physical violence,
right?
Physical after that,
physical in there because the criminal
code also does.
I think it does it in such a way to say
we can harm what is harm.
Again,
harm is longterm infliction of damage
that compromises your ability to
function or your appearance.
It's a pragmatic definition is grounded
in common law.
So we actually have a history of
defining it so that safe and let's not
move away from these definitions because
they're the thing that allow us to have
conversations that are uncomfortable but
needed.
Okay,
good.
They,
uh,
these have no place in civil society,
let alone on a university campus.
They will not be tolerated at Lori.
Yes.
Well,
we see you.
We saw an example of that not being
tolerated with the Lindsay Shepherd
case.
I remain concerned by the way faculty,
staff,
and students involved in aspects of this
situation were targeted with such
vitriol.
Now now things are starting to get out
of hand.
I remain concerned by the way faculty,
staff,
and students involved in aspects of this
situation were targeted with what,
with such vitriol,
vitriol.
That's acid day.
So,
um,
is she,
you think she's talking about the tweets
that Lindsay has received them,
is that faculty,
staff and students.
So not just Lindsey,
but I just wonder is this,
does this apply to those who have been
advocating free speech?
And I,
I'm,
I'm just,
I'm pointing it out there.
I mean all of us who have come out in
favor of maximum free speech have been
subjected to a lot of vitriol,
both emails and it's always anonymous
emails.
It's always from people who will not say
who they are.
So,
but my point would be I,
unless there was something that simply
said,
I am threatening your life.
I just,
I deleted.
That's what I do because this is what
happens.
I mean,
I wish people were civil but they're
not.
There's no discussing heart issues
without conflict.
Like that's just not happening.
The question is how you live with the
conflict and you can't limit it to none
because then people can't have a
conflict.
They can solve a problem,
so what you do is you.
You Limited well as we've limited quite
successfully in our country to date,
right?
We use the definitions of violence that
have prevailed throughout the
establishment of English common law and
that works just fine.
My concern about that paragraph is that
she's cowtowing,
let's say,
to concerns about the way that the
people who actually,
let's say perpetrated this event were
dealt with by members of the general
public,
so member members of the university
community must be supported to work and
study in an environment free of
discrimination and harassment.
That's a tougher and they have
my commitment.
We will continue to make this a
university priority.
Yeah,
that's a sentence that worries me in an
environment free of discrimination and
harassment and they have my.
The problem is it's so difficult to
distinguish that between real dispute.
You know?
I mean if you're.
If you're committed to a line of
argumentation,
you stake your whole,
your whole life on it,
say your,
your whole academic career and you're
engaged in a dispute with someone else
who holds a contrary view point.
There's going to be heat and sparks
generated by that exchange.
There has to be because otherwise you're
not talking about anything of any
importance.
Yeah.
If we all agree,
we don't need free speech.
I mean,
that's standard.
That's the thing,
right?
But when I read this line,
uh,
members of the university community must
be supported to work and study in an
environment free of discrimination and
harassment and,
and I just wonder how equally that idea
has been applied at my university so far
because certainly we know that our
president has sent out letters of
support to the Lgbtq community,
which she was right to do.
If they are feeling harassed,
I have no problem with that.
But at the same time,
there are official bodies at our
university,
the women's center and other bodies that
are under the auspices of the diversity
and Equity Office,
uh,
if I'm correct that are petitioning to
have a,
there's a pro life group on campus and
they are petitioning to have them
defunded and shut down.
Right.
So,
so did Debra mccloud,
she sent out a letter to all the people
who are supporting the shepherd to say,
well,
we're really sorry about older
your responses.
My point,
our president is aware that there's a
group on campus that are marginalized.
These are the prolife students,
and I don't care what your position is,
pro life or pro choice,
whatever your position is,
you bloody will have to admit that
there's at least a debate.
There is a debate,
but,
and the point I would make is here truly
is a marginalized group of students who
have received no support from our
university.
None.
And I know my president is aware because
early on in this controversy I said,
and another matter is that these
students are being attacked or I'm
sorry,
I don't want to use hyperbolic language.
These students are being harassed and
they are being harassed because they
were being threatened with having their
funding removed by official bodies of
the university.
Yeah,
well there's the prolife students are
real canaries in the coal mine as far as
I'm concerned,
regardless of what you think about,
do anything represent diversity,
ideological diversity.
But we're not seeing any reception of
these diverse students.
Do they?
Are they being included in this
diversity and inclusion?
No,
they're being excluded purposely by
actual offices of my university.
So I'm saying,
yeah,
that's standard practice.
I would say on campuses
across the country,
it's just uneven,
it's uneven,
and I think that what what we need to
see a is just a policy that applies to
all students and not just those who
smell right or are orthodox to the
social justice or who were in the.
What would you call it?
Acceptable class of victims.
Okay.
It bears repeating in the current
context that Laurie is support for our
lesbian,
gay,
Bi,
trans,
queer,
and two spirited campus community and
transgender people in particular is
unwavering.
It isn't the obvious that it bears
repeating in the current context because
the issue here fundamentally is that
Lindsay Shepherd was was subject to an
administrative inquisition despite the
fact that she was 100 percent innocent
by the university's own standards,
and so it doesn't bear repeating in the
current context that is support for our
lbgt to Lgbtq campus community and pr
and transgender people.
In particular is unwavering.
It actually isn't about them.
It's not about them at all.
It's about the fact that she got
pilloried for doing something that she
was actually right to do.
So I'm not happy with the fact that this
paragraph was inserted into here.
I think it's an indication of exactly
the kind of administrative weakness that
allowed this sort of event to occur to
begin with.
Now,
this is the theme though,
right,
of the Justice Warriors,
is that this is the victim group they've
repeated over and over that there's been
violence,
harassment,
vitriol.
Everybody's picking up on that.
The union president said that it was
daily occurrence.
The president's repeated.
She's issued a campus wide email and
response to the open letter saying,
uh,
we're going to make this a safe campus.
She's repeating it here.
So the validation,
yes,
their narrative of victimization
emerging from the Lindsay Shepherd
event.
Without evidence,
we,
we actually send an email to our
faculty,
uh,
the Union president and we said,
we're concerned about this daily
violence on campus.
Could you please supply us with evidence
of this?
And she wrote back and she said,
uh,
what did she say something
as I'm telling everyone in the press,
no.
Yeah,
because it would inflate,
didn't she say because it would inflame
the situation even further with
something like that.
So how,
how in the world providing evidence that
something like that with members of the
union,
we are paying our fees just like
everyone else.
And we just,
we wanted substantiate some
substantiation to these claims that
there was violence as a daily.
Well,
the whole premise is that there's injury
happening and that's why we can't speak
about these things.
So if they can establish the violence,
then maybe we're sympathetic to the
argument that the space shouldn't occur.
But.
But that's susceptible to bogus claims.
If there's no substantiation,
you can't build policy that way.
Yeah.
Not without
getting into the kind of trouble that's
already emerged in light of recent
events.
We have added measures to improve campus
safety while it is by.
No.
See that,
that,
that actually seems to me to be the one
sentence in this article so far.
That's actually a mistake because by
going forward with what practices are
that are going to improve campus safety,
then the president is validating the
claims of the people who claim that this
occurrence produced an unsafe
environment on the campus.
It's like,
so I,
I,
I think that that was weak.
We will ensure that all students,
staff and faculty know exactly what our
commitment to academic freedom and
freedom of expression means in the
classroom.
That would be good.
To that end,
we have established the task force on
freedom of expression to take input from
our community,
which we should point out,
which won't include Lindsay Shepherd.
Right?
Because she asked to be part of that
taskforce.
In fact,
I believe that they offered it to her.
I'm not exactly sure.
Some,
some Grad students nominated her and it
was prior to the revelation being made
that it would be the position would be
filled by the president of the graduate
students association who,
and I think this was poor form,
uh,
just before that announcement was made,
the president of the Graduate Students
Association put out a statement where I,
I'm not sure if it's a he or she or a,
I'm not sure of the,
the uh,
gender pronoun use,
but um,
that they were standing 100 percent
behind the Trans and Lgbtq.
Yeah.
And the.
And that,
the fact that they were going to sit on
the,
on the taskforce would indicate that all
students would be represented properly,
but it's just the.
They showed this incredible bias.
And,
and then they said,
and we're going to be sitting on this.
I just don't,
I don't know that that does a service to
all the Grad students who they
represent.
Alright,
look at best practices beyond Lori pay.
They could look at Chicago,
that'd be good and develop a clear
tangible and you never know.
Maybe they will.
You never know.
And develop a clear,
tangible set of practical,
implementable guidelines that will bring
clarity to this issue for our own
classrooms and we'll have the potential
to serve as best practices for others.
Well that's exactly what you guys are
recommending.
That is my commitment to you.
Well,
and it's not like the University of
Chicago is a lightweight
and it's not just the University of
Chicago over 30 universities.
Many of them Ivy League have adopted the
Chicago statements to great effect.
Right?
Right.
And so,
so this is.
This is something that has worked that
is working.
It's clearly something that should
happen in Canada.
It would be a wonderful thing.
It would be a wonderful thing to do.
Would be.
It would be so wonderful.
So it's not like we're trying to
institute this policy that hasn't worked
and that hasn't been been accepted by
really prominent universities in the US
and it doesn't,
it doesn't
involve us a law or legal ease.
It is simply a statement of philosophy
about what we want and which is maximum
free expression and free inquiry within
the bounds of the law.
And I just think this task force is
going to be a disaster because,
uh,
the justice,
advocates aren't interested in free
speech,
uh,
they,
they want to forbid certain forms of
speech and it's just a question of which
topics and who's going to come
troll the lender might be enough public
screwed.
Like I don't think interest in Wilfrid
laurier.
I'm sure that the president would be
real happy if this went away,
but I think the probability that it's
going to go away is very low because I
think Wilford Laurey is now being
watched and being watched by very many
people to see what the genuine outcome
of this will be.
And I think that even if it was ignored
by the mainstream media,
which it might be,
it's not going to be ignored by people
on Youtube and the people who've been
who've been generating content
associated with Lindsay shepherd and
the,
the magnitude of that content online is
absolutely overwhelming.
I don't know if the Wilfred laureate
administrators.
No,
because you know people older than 40,
you usually don't know much about online
media,
but the amount of commentary this has
been generating,
this is generated on youtube is
absolutely beyond belief like it was a
major scandal.
Back to the task force though,
and we'll you've said this in the past,
the freedom of expression proponents,
we already are the compromise position
because we are saying we want you to be
able to articulate whatever position you
have.
We want you to be able to like we are
the compromise position.
We're not saying we want to shut down
anybody.
Whatever your position is,
let's hear it.
That's that.
That is where we are.
So we're already in that compromise
position in the boundaries of the law,
within the boundaries of the law in
respect to the university in its
operations.
Of course.
So,
so we're already saying we want all
these sides to be able to be hurt.
I don't understand.
It's already approved diversity of
opinion.
It is.
And so what I have to look at is many of
the colleagues that I have who are on
the left and are hoping for restriction
of free expression are really,
to a certain extent,
linguistic imperialists.
That's exactly why I objected to bill
[inaudible].
I said that I wasn't going to let the
linguistic imperialists take control
over my voice.
The fact that it happened to be about
transgender pronouns with.
Well that was just how that problem
manifested itself at that period of
time.
But that,
that what have you called them?
Linguistic imperialist.
That's exactly right.
And,
and these,
the,
these idiot ideologues on the radical
left who were so good at neologisms are
unbelievably good at grasping the
linguistic territory.
I mean the,
the propagation of words like cis
gendered is a perfect example of that.
So it.
Yeah,
it's just,
I don't understand how they can be so
against colonialism and imperialism and
then want to do that in,
in the sphere of language,
in
an authoritarian structure which can
only be abused.
Well,
that's,
that's part of the weird.
See there's this weird marriage between
postmodernism in Marxism.
Right?
Which makes no sense because you
actually can't be a postmodernist and I
guess you can be a critical thinker and
a Marxist,
but you cannot be a postmodernist data
Marxist at the same time because the
postmodernists hypothetically are
critical of grand narratives,
right?
They don't believe that they,
that they have in a universal validity.
Of course,
the problem with that is that without a
grand narrative you can't act,
but they sneak the Marxism in through
the back door and then the justification
I think is for these authentic
authoritarian impositions is that,
well,
it doesn't matter as long as the right
people are being hurt by them and the
right people would be the people who are
in positions of power now who,
who have no justification for being in
those positions of power.
Right?
Because they don't stable solution.
If you're making the assumption that
what's being sought after is a stable
solution,
and I think that's.
I think that's a dangerous assumption
because I think that the university
activists mean exactly what they say
when they say that we should be flipping
over the patriarch.
They've put no counterproposal forward
throughout this.
Right?
It's like they don't have a solution,
a,
they're not even talking about a list of
forbidden topics and who's going to be
adjudicated and what the appeals
process,
so that's always.
That's always done post hoc.
Yeah.
That way you can keep the level of fear
that you can keep adding to the list as
well.
Definitely that will because it's way
better.
It's way better if you.
It's way better if you want to exercise
power over people to never let them be
sure which policies they're violating
and I think that what happened to
Lindsay Shepherd is an excellent example
of that,
so it's a.
it's a canonical example of that.
If it's the Orwellian idea of freedom is
the ability to say two plus two equals
four and they want to keep avoiding the
ability to say two plus two is four by
creating new answers and moving on and
he just went through this whole process
with a statement unfree expression and
it goes on for paragraphs and paragraphs
and then the last,
nearly the last sentence is freedom of
expression does not trump all other
rights in the university community.
Freedom of expression.
Can only thrive constructively when
accompanied by other rights,
including the equality rights of equity,
diversity,
and inclusion.
There you go.
That's right.
And so now you no longer have free
expression and that's the snake in the
garden right there.
Eating that.
Yeah.
So there's,
there's this,
but how.
I mean those,
those are so complicated.
There's individual rights and group.
There's positive rights and negative
rights and they're all in this salad
with no guidance as to how you're going
to trade them off against each other.
It's,
it's like you say it just ad hoc as we
go forward.
We'll.
Yeah.
Was so funny to produce an entire
document talking about freedom of
expression and then put a sentence like
that in is a Coda psyllid if.
And by the way also this,
it's like,
wait a second,
it's also this,
it's that little admixture of poison.
It destroys the integrity of the entire
argument and,
and,
and to,
and to put all those words in their
diversity.
Okay.
What the hell do you mean by that?
Exactly.
Inclusivity or.
That's a word that really that's when I
really have trouble with because it's
very difficult to understand even what
that means and equity equity is equality
of outcome and so that's an impossible
goal to begin with because it multiplies
in difficulty as you add number of
measurement dimensions.
Right?
So.
And that's the intersectionality
problem,
so to speak.
So.
All right,
well,
well with the task force,
the interesting thing is we'll didn't
want to sit on it because having looked
at what had happened,
I,
I suppose it was the experience at UBC
that,
well I just saw big arguments happening
with no,
no possibility of a constructive outcome
and so.
But I was more hopeful and I understand
wills position completely,
right?
Yes.
Well it's easy as a faculty member to
get pulled into interminable
administrative duties that have no
positive outcome whatsoever.
In fact,
it's pretty much par for the course.
Well,
he makes the,
I mean your most compelling argument.
Well to one,
look what happened at UBC and two were
already in a compromised position.
You mean what,
what more can you want?
And I get that,
but I,
I have let my name stand for nomination.
Uh,
we'll see this week.
I guess,
whether or not I'll,
I don't know if I'll get voted.
Well,
one of the things we should find out and
publicize is whether any people who have
a strong free speech orientation will
end up on that task force.
I mean that,
that's absolutely critical.
Important.
Well,
they'll certainly get their work done
quickly if no one running the free
speech side is on it because they'll
just say,
right.
But maybe they'll have to create a list
of their own about what can't be talked
about.
Right?
Who knows where that will go.
Well,
and one thing that strikes me though is
just the disregard for history,
uh,
people who are marginalized or would be
considered in the marginalized group.
If we look at how did they get the
rights that they have today,
right?
How did that happen was because of free
expression,
right?
Actually,
the easy case to make for free speech is
left wing.
It's like powerful.
People don't need their free speech
protected.
They're powerful,
they're rich.
They can say whatever the hell they
want.
It's people who are precisely
marginalized and oppressed,
who need all the protection of the law.
Of course they want to weight it against
saying,
yes,
we want to have people without power to
have the freedom of expression,
but let's make this a quicker process by
making sure those that have power can't
speak whoever those who have power,
it's not just,
Oh,
you know,
you could say,
well,
wouldn't it be wonderful if those who
had unfair power weren't allowed to
speak?
It's like,
well,
maybe it wouldn't be wonderful,
but who the hell is going to decide who
has power and who has unfair power?
Like the devil's in the details there.
So the only fair application of this
principle is to let everybody have equal
opportunity,
not equal outcome by the way.
Well,
that's the free market solution,
right?
Because you can't determine these by
central Fiat because it's technically
impossible,
which is actually something
postmodernist should know because that's
actually one of the logical consequences
of their philosophy.
Right?
Things are too complicated to decide by
Fiat in some sense,
but.
All right.
Is there anything else that you guys
want to say that,
that,
that you've observed as a consequence of
this Lindsay shepherd of fair or that or
that you're hopeful about or pessimistic
about what,
what?
What's the,
how do we solve this?
Just the way we're solving it.
This is the way to solve it is to,
is to have W.
I think this is a textbook case of the
utility of free speech.
Shepherd was able to make her case
publicly.
There's been a huge debate about it.
There's been some moves made on the part
of the university that looked positive.
We've got ample opportunity.
Everyone has ample opportunity to have
their voice heard.
You know,
this video we're making tonight,
I'll probably be watched by 150,000
people,
so like,
and we had a perfectly reasonable
discussion,
you know,
I think we gave credit where credit was
due with regards to this document and,
and are jointly hopeful that something
positive will come of it and made some
pointed critiques about,
about what it does contain and what it
doesn't,
but we don't want to underestimate the
utility of doing these things.
It's useful and I think the fact that
you guys have this little cabal of
people at Wilfrid laurier who are
willing to speak,
I was shocked when when you wrote that
op ad and when the Toronto Star
published it,
I mean nothing like that from an
academic happened in relationship to me
last year and Bill [inaudible],
we've seen such uniformity of outcry
about this from all the newspapers,
glove star son,
which,
which really just shows you the
disconnect between what is happening in
the academy and what is happening.
It's a disconnect of staggering
magnitude.
People outside the academy say,
well,
how can you believe that they have what
they've been saying is really this
happened,
this actually happened.
That's the universal response and and
you know the response on the campuses as
well.
Yeah.
It happened and we were right.
I have a solution.
I mean it's not a solution,
but it's A.
I call it an inoculant actually.
So yes.
Let's get the statement for freedom of
expression at our university and similar
statements at all universities.
Why the federal government is not tying
funding to this.
I know that the Conservatives Med
suggestion that I made to the
conservatives,
well this is,
this is what needs to happen,
but in addition to that,
I think that young people and parents of
young people need to look at what's
happening and they need to start
educating their kids at home and they
need to start.
And I've written several op-eds where
I've said people ask me,
what is the solution that I say?
Start watching the videos of Jordan
Peterson.
Start watching the videos.
Uh,
there's Jonathan Heit,
Jonathan.
Hi.
You Bet.
Look into the Heterodox Academy.
They know what they're doing,
who,
who definitely are scholars of repute,
the,
they,
they are moderate in the,
like incredibly civil.
Uh,
there are also some people outside of
academia.
There's a,
um,
a fantastic utuber.
Uh,
my name is Josephine.
She's a Canadian political science
student who is at u of t moderate,
really well spoken,
articulate in classical liberal ideas.
My name is Josephine.
Okay.
So she's actually been the reason that I
know she knows you.
She was at one of your rallies.
I spotted a video there.
She is in the background there.
Another young lady as a woman who is her
name is roaming millennial.
Yeah.
I don't roaming millennial.
I'd been on her show.
Oh yeah,
you bet.
You Bet.
Yeah,
and she's a tough cookie.
That girl,
you bet.
And I would say start watching these.
Yeah,
well the young people are watching them
in droves.
You know,
she has a big following,
roaming millennial,
and I'm grateful for that because in
fact when these students go into the
university classroom,
if they choose to go into the arts or
the humanities,
they're going to go in with knowledge
where they can say,
I realize it's tough to challenge a
professor,
but start a facebook group and say,
Hey,
did you know that there are other ideas
to do?
You know that there's an opposite side
of this debate.
Well,
we should.
Or we could also encourage parents who
might be listening or or students
thinking about going to university who
might be listening to this,
is that check to see where the
university stands on free speech and if
they dampen down their support for free
speech and for your inquiry with
statements about diversity,
inclusivity and equity,
then go somewhere else.
It's a worry.
Another thing,
and this is just beginning in Canada,
we have a society for academic freedom
and scholarship that professors can join
if a,
if a.
sorry if a professor has joined the
Society for academic freedom of
scholarship,
you can be pretty sure they are going to
be wanting to give you both sides of the
story.
So that's not a bad check either for.
Do they have to do their research though
the students to do diligence while
that's good,
it'll educate them.
Right.
I mean Lindsay Shepherd definitely got
educated over the last two months.
No kidding.
She's got her phd thesis in
communication.
Pretty well demonstrated there is an
auto ethnography for you.
Yeah.
I caused an international scandal by
just revealing what had actually
happened.
Yeah.
Alright.
Alright,
good.
My pleasure.
Thank you guys for coming and also for,
it's not common for faculty members.
Well to talk to me first of all,
like this.
Certainly not on record and certainly
not common for them to be writing and
speaking openly about such issues.
So I don't know what the hell got into
you guys.
It's really good.
That's happening at Wilfrid laurier to
where were we realize we're finished now
by being associated with you.
Yeah.
I,
I said,
uh,
earlier good of you to offer yourself on
the sacrificial altar.
I,
you've got to look your kids in the eye
eventually.
Yeah.
And uh,
how are you going to say that you need
to stand up for truth if you actually
don't stand up for truth.
That is a problem.
Yeah.
Yep.
Alright guys.
Good.
Thanks a lot.