Dear a Dr. Harris,
please forgive me and this goes for
whatever audience this video might
attract for reading this,
but I need to make this quick and
coherent and this is the fastest way of
doing so.
I want you to address some of the issues
that I believe made our discussion both
more trying and less valuable.
That might've been a problem that many
of the people who now listened to it
rightly identify.
I think that our discussion would
perhaps would be more productive if we
started from the realization that we're
both trying to address the same problem.
What is the relationship between science
and ethics?
Okay,
you see,
ethics is nested inside scientific
realism.
Now obviously that's a contentious
claim,
which is not the same as it being wrong,
but the fact that it's contentious re
David Hume and his problem with deriving
an art from an is means that there is a
real problem there.
I see scientific rate realism is nested
inside Darwinian competition,
at least potentially,
not necessarily.
I could be wrong,
but I am trying to address the real
problem
and I think the fact that you're
addressing the science slash ethics
problem indicates that you see that
there's a real problem there too.
Okay.
I also think we only got to the problems
with my formulation,
not the problems with your solution.
For example,
the problem with measuring wellbeing,
you consider the enhancement of
wellbeing,
the proper and of ethics.
However,
the psychological measures of wellbeing
currently used are almost only trait
extroversion minus trait neuroticism.
That's happiness minus sadness.
Well that's how well being is currently
defined.
Well,
that proposition is faulty in every way.
It's a big problem.
It's a measurement problem.
It's a scientific realism problem.
You might say,
well,
we need better measures of wellbeing,
and I would say,
well exactly,
and those will have to be nested inside
the Darwinian conundrum.
How should we act in the world?
Here's an answer individually so that
the family thrives at the family level
so that society thrives at the societal
level so that the ecosystem thrives and
and not just today,
tomorrow,
next week,
next year and across time.
That's the problem.
The developmental psychologist John
Piaget was trying to address when he
studied the moral development of
children.
Piaget was interested in solving the
problem of the relationship between
science and ethics,
and he looked how he looked at how
ethics in children emerged and
transformed into adulthood.
That's what drove his entire life.
He was trying to formulate a scientific
solution to the problem and ethics,
and I've drawn a lot of my thinking from
that.
Okay,
now I'm going to jump to a level of
analysis,
and when I do so,
it will make many think I've gone off
the rails of this argument.
I ask for your indulgence.
While I tried to put things together
that have not yet been put together,
this means that I have to present many
ideas simultaneously as if looking at a
picture or as if describing a picture,
which is how these ideas have frequently
been represented.
The individual who acts in this
equilibrated manner is the mythological
hero.
It's the mythological hero who confronts
the attention,
the unknown,
with a tension and intent to
communicate.
It's the archetypal hero who obtains the
gold from the eternal dragon,
the dragon of chaos.
That's an evolved representation of the
predatory but promising domain beyond
the safety of the tree or the campfire.
Okay.
It's the archetypal hero who distributes
the goal that he,
that he obtains from the dragon to the
community.
It's him who rescues the youthful virgin
from the predatory reptile that Saint
George,
it's the oldest story.
We know it's in the Enuma Elish,
the Mesopotamian creation myth upon
which the opening lines of genesis are
founded.
Can't you see an evolutionary
relationship
that's the archetypal hero.
That's first a way of behaving.
Second,
it's a representation of that way of
behaving.
Third,
it's a way of organizing society itself
around that action and representation
forth.
It's that society that then selects
through masculine competition for the
best contender to that representation
and finally,
it's what is selected for by women who
peel off the top of the masculine
competition.
Women outsource the impossible cognitive
task of mate selection to the male
dominance hierarchy.
Hero emerges at the top of the
competition.
He gets all the girls.
It's that what's it's that which is
selected for and he human females
perform part of the selection process
there.
Mother Nature,
the selection apparatus that choosy
maters it.
Female chimps or not.
Okay.
The archetype will hero might be
regarded as a super meme in Richard
Dawkins terminology,
it's been around so long that we have
adapted biologically to its existence
just as we have in every way to the
presence of the 300 million year old
dominance hierarchy,
which is more permanent,
more real,
even from a strictly realist perspective
than such evanescent phenomena as
amphibians,
reptiles and mammals.
It's even older than trees.
Okay.
The closer you are to that article hero,
the more likely you are at least as a
male to when the dominance hierarchy
contest that makes you attractive to
women.
Okay.
If Richard Dawkins who formulated the
idea of the meme was wiser,
he would have been Carl Young.
An archetype is the ultimate meme.
Okay.
In my opinion,
we need to have a real conversation.
Not An argument.
It's not that I think you're wrong,
it's that I think that there's a real
problem here,
which we both recognize and are both
trying to solve.
If none of this makes even the least bit
of sense,
if it doesn't at least peak your
curiosity,
if you can't see that we're obsessed by
the same problem,
then we won't be able to talk and that
would be a shame.
You're very sharp and precise,
but I think in patterns somebody said,
listening to us was like the right
hemisphere of a single brain talking to
the left.
That's a good metaphor.
There wouldn't be so many people trying
to get us to talk if we didn't have
something to discuss.
The relationship between science and
ethics is vitally important.
If we had a real conversation and no
fault is employed on your part,
we might be able to further the solution
to the problem.
Thanks for listening and watching.