This is Jocko podcast number
one 46 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
And I wanted to kind of delve into and
slash explain some conversations that
I've had lately. Sure.
With a couple of people.
And actually I think the numbers
increased now cause now I've had this
conversation with a few people and I'm,
I am feeling like I need to kind of
share this idea with kind of with more
people.
I guess at this point
it's kind of a discussion that
applies to everyone at some level,
sort of about what you are and about
who you are and about where you been and
about where you're going.
So that's a pretty broad topic I think.
Suffice it to say
now in order to convey this properly,
I'm going to try and set up
some visuals in your head.
Could you kind of kind of see this right?
Graphs,
whatever charts,
all right diagrams and I'm going to try
and keep them simple but pretty straight
forward. Um, here we go. We're going
to grade things when a great things,
one to 10 because that's sort of the
stamp. Is that the standard? Yes.
I mean I guess you'd go a, B, c,
d, F, but we're not doing that.
We're going one to ten one being
the worst, 10 being the best,
one being the least, 10 being the
most, that type of thing. Okay,
so so you have a chart,
a picture in your head at the bottom of
the chart is a one that's the lowest.
That's the worst at the chop is 10
that's the highest. That's the most. Now,
the first chart that we're going
to talk about, it measures talent.
Now what's different about this chart
is this is not just talking about a
particular talent.
This is talking about every possible
type of talent that you as an individual
human being have,
and it's consolidating that.
All those different types of
talents into one giant score,
one holistic score,
10 at the top or one at the bottom.
So this is, this is everything
that you are as a person,
how smart you are.
The only,
the only thing is that everything that
you are as a person that you are given
naturally, right? Yeah. So there's
a baseline of how smart you are,
so how intelligent you are. Now
we know you can work, get smarter,
but we're just talking to baseline how
how charismatic you are as a person,
how well you read people's emotions,
how athletic you are
and that grades you can grade to all
different types of athleticism and their
strength cause some people
are naturally strong,
some people are naturally flexible.
Some people have natural
cardiovascular endurance, right?
You would get a certain
level of that naturally.
Of course we know people can work hard,
you can improve some of that,
but we're just talking your
natural talent healthy.
That's sort of a talent sort of like some
people are born healthier than others.
No doubt about it.
How good looking you are.
You ever seen those little like,
I don't know if their psychological
experiments but they put like the faces in
front of the babies and the babies
pick the one that looks nicer to them,
has to do with a symmetry,
symmetry and ratios and
stuff like that. So, so that,
that's a talent thing that
you're getting and natural.
Your natural body composition.
Right.
Some people are born a little bit
with a little bit more fat on them.
Some people are born with a
little bit more muscle on them.
Some people are born with the skin and
bones. Right. You get everything. Yeah.
Again,
I know you can work on some of those,
but we're talking about what you got out
of the gate from your Creator or nature
or wherever you think you got it from.
So at the top of that chart, I don't
know who's at the top of that chart.
Uh, maybe, I mean there's people, there's,
there's a bunch of people that would
crank towards the top of that chart.
So who's up there? Well. Yeah,
ultimately hard to tell cause you know
what you to know what was given to him or
what, but look at them, you know,
to just says someone as a whole.
Yeah,
the rock character type character,
Delaney, the Rock, he's charismatic,
he's a good athlete, really
good athlete. He's tall, he's,
he's got a good acting skill, which I'm
again, did he work hard for these things?
We better, we better give the rocks and
credit or we're going to hear from him.
But I worked for all that, but
hey, he's given some natural stuff.
That's a very good one. Uh, Tom
Brady, right? Yes. He's smart.
He's a good athlete. He's, you know,
got some leadership skills. So he's got
some, some, some natural gifts that are,
again, does he work hard? We're
not taking that away from him,
but you're born with some stuff, GSP
maybe. Right. Just be really good athlete,
smart guy, you know, level headed.
He's a very talented guy.
So there you go.
You take that chart. You look at that
chart, the one to 10 where's the,
where those, but where's the rock?
He's like a 9.6 he's up there. Yeah.
And then you ask yourself,
where are you on that chart?
Where are you on that chart?
And I'm asked quite a few people this
and we're still talking naturally.
We're just talking what you got naturally.
Where do you think most people,
where would you rank yourself
naturally? I Dunno. Five.
Oh,
most people ranked themselves.
Most people that I've asked to rank
themselves a little bit higher than that.
They've ranked themselves 6.8 7.2 in that
they're giving themselves a little bit
above average, right? Yeah.
You're going five. Huh?
We'll keep in mind we just said the rock.
So I'm like all right.
Yeah that's true.
Well you know what we should have done
is we should've said one to a hundred so
you could say the rock is a
96 it's still be a 50 okay.
Yeah. All right, so you're giving
yourself five so, so that's, that's good.
And I'm sure you know we could break
that down about where you got the cause.
Cause some people,
this is important.
Some people can be a 10
or a 9.84 their intellect.
But maybe they socially don't
have good skills about reading.
They weren't born with that little thing,
right? So they can't read people well.
So even though they're really smart,
they're not,
they're not making anything happen cause
they can't even communicate with people
well or they're just, they're not
healthy, right? They're bad athletes.
Some people the opposite, wicked good
athlete, but they're just not that smart,
right? And everything of it. So you could,
you could be a nine athlete, but you're,
uh,
a very low whatever intellect and
that's going to bring you down.
Might even bring you down below average.
So,
so he got that chart and that's
it. Okay, so now we got that.
It's the holistic talent chart.
That's what we'll call it.
You got the holistic talent sharp
on one side. Now in your head,
I want you to picture on the other side.
The other side is another chart,
also one to 10, one being
the least, 10 being the most.
And this chart is to grade
success.
Now this is not easy to do because of
course you can ask yourself what is
success, right? What is really being
successful? And this is a good question.
And I remember,
I don't know if you remember this time
when people started asking me a lot about
how to raise your kids.
And I said,
well I don't want to talk about how to
raise kids cause I don't know if I'm a
success.
I don't know if my kids are successful.
I don't know if I should be giving that
advice because what if my kids aren't
successful? And, and then when you, when
I started talking about that question,
it's like, okay, what if my kid,
if one of my kids goes and get a job
at an investment bank and he's making
$450,000 a year as a 26 year old,
is that successful?
It could be, but what if that kid is
miserable? What if that kid, you know, is,
is doing cocaine, right? That's
not successful. That's horrible.
So it's very hard to,
so that,
that makes you start thinking
about what is success.
But I think we can generally know and
understand what success broadly is when
you look at these individual
categories, right? So, okay,
good family, right? You've got a good
stable scenario going on with your family.
If you're old enough to have a family
for not old enough to have family,
at least you are prepared to have a
good family life. That type of thing.
That's one level of success.
Uh,
gratifying job meaning a
job that cause you can,
I know people that make a ton of money in
their job and they hate it. Yes. Right?
So is that successful?
[inaudible] maybe not the,
I know people that love their job,
but they don't make any money and
they're struggling paycheck to paycheck.
Does that, is that success?
I don't know. Again,
these are all things we could
kind of weigh out. Yeah.
And then you've got health and wellness
because even though we talked about what
you're given naturally,
you got to remember that you think you
could work for something and you can,
you can be successful and be healthy
and be mobile and be not worried about
getting out of breath when you
walk up the stairs or whatever.
So the overall health and
wellness and so again,
you have to take all of these
different types of success,
all of them and wrap them up holistically.
And I don't know,
could we throw,
this might be the wrong,
you could possibly throw kind of a
strange, you could possibly fill the,
just the whole word happiness onto
this situation, right? This the,
the general term happiness where I,
but I think that's a scary thing to do
because happiness isn't necessarily a
good thing in terms of you meet someone
that's had a few beverages and even
though their life's a disaster,
man,
they're having a good time at the bar
to pretty happy. Is this our goal?
Not really.
That's why I think happiness is a,
I don't know that I would
throw it into this chart.
I would call it success because it
has a little bit more strength to it.
Now you got your two,
you got your two,
your two charts.
Now on the left you have holistic talent.
Is that what I called it? Yes.
Holistic holistic talent. On the left.
On the right you have holistic success.
Success.
Now here's the question and I could ask
you where you are on the success side.
Yeah. Where are you? Oh,
seven Oh, okay, good, good.
So you were a five for talent and you're
a seven for success. That's pretty,
that's pretty legit.
Let me ask you,
this is every person that is at the top
of the talent chart holistically with
everything they've got,
is every one of those people that scores
at 9.8 at the top of the success chart,
the answer's no.
The answer's no.
Is every person that's on the bottom of
the talent holistic talent chart on the
bottom of the success
chart? No. The answer's no.
And what do we see? We
see that there's a, well,
when you put the space in between
these two, there's talent,
holistic talent,
and there's holistic success.
And there's a space in between
and that's what actually matters.
That's what actually matters.
What do you do? What do you do?
The fee and that to me,
and I hate to get,
I hate to throw this out there,
but for me,
the thing that's in between
the left and the right,
the thing that's in between towns success
is is can be summed up in one word,
discipline, discipline. Do you
have the discipline to do the work,
to make the hard decisions,
to put in the daily grind that's
going to get you from wherever you,
you started out with whatever level of
talent you had and move yourself up that
chart on the right hand side.
I think it's important to recognize
this and this conversation.
This particular conversation,
the first time I had it was with a younger
person who I could see in their eyes,
had the sense of like,
I don't know if I have the talent,
and it's like, well, you know, I don't
know if you have the talent either.
There's one way to find out.
You do the hard work,
you implement discipline on your life
and that will give you the opportunity to
see how far up that sucks.
One thing I can tell you is if you don't
have the discipline and you don't do
the work, you're not going to be above
your, your holistic talent level at all.
There's some people that make a run
for it, man. You know what I mean?
There's some people that have no
talent or very limited talent,
but they get after it and they end up way
off far on the success and or you know
what I think is good about this.
When you get some success,
you kind of compound that back into your
hard work and people start to get on an
upward spiral,
upward mobility towards the top of the
success chart cause they got a little
foothold. Once they got that foothold of
felt good, then they take another step,
they get a little bit further
and then they get a little,
a little bit more success,
boom,
and then they use that to propel
themselves up a little higher.
The problem is the reverse happens
as well. That's the problem.
People feel a little bit that
they got beat at something. Right.
The bad luck came your way because
you know what, on this in between,
there's some luck in,
in between the discipline,
there's absolutely some luck as well.
There's some luck and you can get lucky.
You can meet the right person
at the right time. You can,
you can make a move at the right
time before anyone else did. You can,
you can get discovered by someone
or some thing, you know there's,
there's definitely some luck involved
for sure. You can't count on the luck.
The luck is not the reason.
Some people like to look at someone else
and say they're lucky they didn't see
the, the, the thousands and thousands of
hours of hard work. That person put it.
They just saw that last little end
result where they got lucky allegedly.
Yeah. Yeah. The luck thing is,
is weird cause if you
can extrapolate it out,
like someone who can't want to play
football, we had to do these cool.
And they see something on the back or
the front, I don't know, whatever. Oh.
And it says chance favors.
One of them said chance favors
the prepared men. Right.
True. So it's like, same thing,
right? Chance and luck. Same thing.
So you'll like, the more prepared
you are, the more skills you have,
the more whatever they'll quote
unquote lucky you're going to get.
But really when you fit,
you switch the word luck for chance.
You just increase your chances of
success. So like, um, you know,
I dunno who got discovered,
you know, he, there,
they're going to be in a position
to be discovered, you know,
because whoever quote
unquote discovered them.
I'm sure many people have been in that
situation too. You know, like, um,
you know, some guy goes on the news,
right, with his baskets than he makes,
you know, or whatever. And boom, he blows
up because those baskets are dope. Yeah.
But Brat planning people who've been
on the news with your thing, you know,
for years, decades, centuries main
maybe, essentially, but you know, no,
for Lego to be sexual CPR
people been going on in the news
with their thing for a long time.
Same thing with American idol. A lot
of people have been on American idol.
What I'm saying, how many people
really made it? Right. You know,
as far as getting discovered,
whatever. It's like, Oh yeah,
he got lucky or whatever. Yeah, man. But
you're not going to get lucky if you,
if you're kind of whack, you know, like
if you're, you're not prepared. If you're,
you don't have the skill,
you don't have the talent talent,
you don't have the Xyz that it takes
then yeah. So it's Kinda like, yeah,
the luck is sprinkled in there
everywhere. Right. By the way, you know,
and maybe they didn't get
discovered on the news,
but maybe they went to somewhere else.
Then they got discovered, you know,
a year or two years
later, what are, you know,
so you just increase the probability
of being discovered when you have this
skill. So yeah, luck. Sure. It
is part of it for sure. But yeah,
it can propel you a little bit faster.
Or sometimes it's like one of those things
where you talk like a foothold, right?
There's a bunch of footholds everywhere
just because someone latched on to one
specific one that everyone at some point
to and say, he got lucky there. Well,
he's so good where she's so good
most of the time. All the time.
There's exceptions everywhere obviously,
but most of the time
that person is so good,
they would've got discovered somewhere
else anyway. It's just a matter of, oh,
this particular one made them get
discovered and propelled them all quick or
whatever. Well, this ties back into
something that I've said before,
and I'll say it again right now is make
your luck. You gotta make your luck.
And if you make it,
if you keep,
if you keep putting forth the maximal
effort that luck's gonna come,
you're gonna make your luck happen. You
know that. You know that actually when we,
when we came, when tasking at
bruiser came home from Iraq,
there was, there was, you
know, people were like, all,
you guys got super lucky on that
deployment because we got a lot of action,
right? And there was two like immediate
thoughts behind that was number one, like,
hey, you know, first of
all we lost our bros.
Like they're nothing lucky about that was
the first immediate thought in my head
was like,
hey man, like cause cause the bottom
line is seals want to go into combat bad.
And that's just a broad statement.
And so when we came home,
had been in a lot of combat and killed a
lot of bad guys and people were kind of
saying,
hey you guys got lucky.
And again the first thought was, hey man
you did. If this is luck, I don't want it.
The second fault was just like
the same thing. Oh we got lucky.
We didn't like crush ourselves in the
workup and try and be the most, you know,
prepared we could be and
then get overseas and,
and form relationships with all the
conventional forces and do good work for
them and continue to, you know, just get,
go as hard as we could the whole time.
No, that didn't have anything to do with.
It was just luck and it kind of fell
into our lap. But you know, of course,
just nod your head and say, thanks man.
Appreciate it. Yeah, good times. Uh,
so luck is definitely a part of it.
A little part because where we
was I lucky to be in Ramadi,
it cause I could have deployed a year
later and a year later Ramadi was passed
by it. So is there a lock
there? There absolutely is. So,
I don't want to sound arrogant,
but luck is apart.
It's like foot locks. It's like a heel
hooks. They're a part of the game.
There are not a game changer right there.
They're a part of the game.
They're not a game changer. We,
we had a group come in, this is
back in the day,
a group came in,
a guys that were known for
foot locking and he'll look,
and what they did, they thought we were
Jujitsu guys, normal dudes, you guys.
But we weren't because we were as dean.
So we were footlocker and he looking
all the time and these guys came in and
immediately they were going for,
these are the kind of guys that
would go and I don't know if you,
I don't know if you remember this time
period in Jujitsu, it was like immediate.
They're going for a full lock,
like just diving for it.
But they didn't know that we did for
alarms all the time and you weren't going
to just grab a full lock
on Dean lister or me.
Like it wasn't going to happen and it
kind of then of a sudden they didn't have
the rest of Jujitsu.
You'd have the rest of the game.
So then it was not good for them cause
they only had this one dimensional game.
And that's what taught me that
foot locks aren't important,
but they're not more important
than a choke or a guard pass.
They are definitely part of the game.
You can't leave out,
but they're not a game changer.
And you see that now,
now that you see everyone broadly
getting good at at the whole leg,
locking foot, locking, he'll hooking game.
Now you see it coming back around where
you have to have the rest of Jujitsu as
well. Like even even as much as
like a year ago, it was like, oh,
this guy got this crazy,
he'll hook and the guy tapped and
you didn't know what was happening.
That very rapidly changes into,
okay, the guy went for a heel hook,
the other guy got out and now
we've got to where we back to.
We're back to the Jujitsu, so
same thing. Luck as a factor.
It's not the factor. Yeah. All
right. Now that's number one.
This is the number one thing
I wanted to talk about today.
If you're in that position where
you're looking at your talent,
and I guess this is,
I guess it's applicable to people that
are a little bit younger because people
that are a little bit older,
they probably figured this out already.
You probably looked at yourself in
the mirror and said, hey, look, I,
I might not have that much talent, but
I can, I can, I can get after, you know,
this is something that you say about
basketball too, and I don't, I don't,
I know you want a basketball player.
I played basketball growing
up and when I was growing up,
it was like the Hay Day of the Lakers
and the Celtics rivalry and all this.
Well, the hard work,
right? Just this like, Hey,
I'm going to work harder than anyone
else to make up for my lack of talent.
And they would say about Larry
Bird. You know, Larry Byrd is, yes.
They would say this is kind of garbage.
They'd say Larry Berg was an athletic,
which is total garbage. I mean, but
people would say that, and maybe it's,
cause he didn't have the,
the biggest vertical jump or whatever,
and they'd say he was like
slower than other players,
but he works so hard that he
was able to compensate for that.
Now again,
when I heard that when I was a kid,
I kind of believe that when you see Larry
Bird now, when I watch you know, games,
he was, he's a freaking
awesome athlete, you know,
and you're not playing in
the NBA and being a world
champion over and over again,
MVP without being of an awesome
athlete. Larry Bird, how old is he?
How talk he used to call,
he's like six [inaudible] tall guy,
this guy named Spud Webb who's like five.
Spud Webb for sure there is that. But
yeah, man, I dig it. And I remember this.
These spud Webb probably had to
work harder to make, what about,
there's a guy named,
I think his name was Muggsy Bogues.
You remember Muggsy Bogues you was now
he was even smaller than Spud Webb.
But he was so small that people,
it was a different little situation
that the players had to deal with.
He was so small and some of it so fast.
You know what's interesting,
I got some friends in hockey and as a
matter of fact, the goals, you know,
the goals, the goal, the San
Diego goals. Yeah, yeah, sure.
So I went down and talked to the goals
and what's cool about what's cool
about that level of athletics,
which is the minor leagues,
the goals are a minor league team.
What's cool about that level of
athletics is those guys are hungry.
They're not prima donnas that are,
you know,
driving around in a chauffeured
car and all that stuff.
These guys are hungry
and they're playing hard.
And what's interesting is in hockey,
and this is within the last few years,
at one point a few years ago,
they were just getting the bigger and
bigger and bigger hockey players just
getting bigger guys. Cause you're just
there. Just monster guys that are six,
six and six, five and six,
four and they way I, you know,
to 60 and that was the
way hockey was going.
But then what happened was they started
bringing out these guys that were
smaller and faster and that could go
maneuver quicker than the bigger guys.
And all of a sudden hockey's going
back in that direction to have smaller,
faster guys.
So it's interesting.
And the amount of talent
that that employees,
hey, figure it out. You
can make something happen.
Muggsy Bogues Spud Webb make
it happen regardless of height.
But to my point, Larry
Bird, when I was a kid,
I would hear about Larry Bird not being
a good athlete and all you had to do was
work hard, which, which left an impression
on me as a kid. Hey look, very bird's,
not that he's not that great athlete,
but he's got to work hard.
So we asked what I'm going to
do. Work hard, work harder.
They say that about Dan Gable to
yeah, the wrestler. Yeah. Hey,
maybe not the fastest, but his thing
was I'll, I'll outwork them all.
You ever heard stories about him? Dan
Gable? Yeah. He would just run from every,
every place he would go.
He would run st near that story
from class to class in college,
from class to the cafeteria,
you'd run everywhere.
So hard work now. Okay, so that wraps
up, we got talent on the one side,
we've got success on the
other side and that's cool.
And we know that we can progress up that
chart for the young people out there
and even the old people out
there, if you, if you're,
if you're on the lower end of that
chart of, of the talent chart, boom,
work hard, applied discipline, make
good decisions, you can end up further.
You can go to the top of that
success chart. Boom. Now,
now we're going to get weight.
I guess we're going to get away from
the holistic success a little bit here.
Maybe not. Maybe, maybe not.
This is a conversation that I've also
had and it had it primarily with two,
two people that I know pretty well.
One of them very well and
one of them decently well
and this is the conversation,
these two individuals,
high talent high in the talent chart.
So what does that mean?
They're smart.
You know,
they've got that personal interoperability
with other human beings on top of
that. Super driven on top of that.
They've got the whole work thing too.
They got the discipline thing
down to they've got all that.
They're maxed out in the
game that they're playing.
So what do I mean by that?
In soccer, how many goals can you
score? Let's say you're the best team,
either best player on your team and
you're going to play a season worth of
soccer. How many goals can you score and
the whole season. Then the whole season,
I don't know how many games,
I dunno, let's call it,
let's say you play 15 games,
so you're going to,
I don't know,
45 maybe 60 goals.
Okay,
that's completely unrealistic.
Yeah.
We'll take it 15 so you say
three goals for 45 yeah,
we'll go. This guy gets a hat
trick, which is a rarity in soccer.
We'll say he gets it for every game for
15 games season and that's where he ends
up. He ends up at 45 calls.
I'll totally watch kids soccer,
so my numbers might be off a little bit.
Okay.
Now what if you were a basketball player
and how many basket, how many games,
how many goals can you make in
basketball in a game? You know,
realistically on the High
End, 21 points. Yeah.
Then you multiply that times a season
and you obviously can score way more in
basketball than you can in soccer.
Clearly this is where,
again,
I've had this conversation primarily
around the financial aspects of work for
people.
If you get in,
you have to look at the
game that you're playing.
Cause sometimes the game that you're
playing a soccer and it doesn't matter how
much talent you haven't, doesn't
matter how much hard work you, you,
you put into it,
you can only score 45 goals and that's it.
And meanwhile,
someone that maybe doesn't even have the
talent and doesn't have the work ethic
that you had, but they're playing
a different game and their scorn,
200300400 goals,
they're making two,
three times as much money as you.
Why?
Because the game that they are playing.
So you have to look at
that every game just about,
well I'll say it.
Every game that you can play has a cap
on it of what you can actually make until
you get to the top and you look at it and
you change your angle, you change your,
you change your angle of the game. You
could say, I'm gonna create a new game.
You know, you could get really good
at soccer and say, you know what?
I've maxed this game out and to create a
new game where it's a smaller field and
a bigger goal, you know, you could do that
and people do that in industry, right?
People do that in industry.
They,
they get to the top of their game and
they start a new game, a different game.
They changed the rules a little
bit where they can score more.
I'm totally supportive of that.
The problem is I just want to make sure
that people recognize that sometimes
you've put in awesome, you've got,
you're a very talented person,
you've put in a lot of work and
you got to the t, you got to the,
you kept out your game. You're going to
get as many goals as you're going to get.
That's it. Yeah. And so you can't
get frustrated. I'll tell you what.
I was in the navy, I was in
the navy. You get everyone.
I was an owl.
I retired as an old four e over 20,
which means,
which means I was a prior enlisted guy.
You can go look at what my salary was
and then you can have my little specialty
pays in for jump dive demo,
special duty assignment pay.
You can add those little things in there.
You can add my beat, uh, officer housing,
basic allowance for housing in there.
You can figure out, I mean it's,
you're going to make this much money.
That's it. That's the cap. Yeah.
That's what you're going to make now.
Now we start to talk about can you
play multiple games at the same time?
And the answer to that is yes, you
can. You can play multiple games.
Now I kind of,
I kind of said this on a
different podcast. Somebody
had talked about, you know,
having a side hustle while you're in
the military. And I was like, well no,
you can't really do that because you know
you got to focus 100% of your job and
then,
but the reality is I had a side hustle
the whole time I was in because I guess
what I was doing, how is buying
houses? I was saving my money.
I was driving a 1997 dodge grand caravan
and I was buying a house here and I was
buying a house there and
that's when you have a,
when you have a alternate
job or an alternate game
that you're going to play in
the military,
it's okay.
It just has to be on a complete not to
interfere basis so it doesn't interfere.
Occasionally if you're a pro,
if you've got a few properties and
one of them has a broken water heater,
you can mitigate that by making sure
you've got a good property manager and
making sure you know the right handyman.
I can go over and square that stuff
away and get that problem solved.
I had some kind of catastrophic
situations. I had the big flood
or the big broken no slab like well if
cracked pipe in the slab, I had a crap.
One of my rentals has flooded twice.
Once from the ceiling
wants from the ground.
How does it flood from the theme from
seeing the crack pipe in the upstairs
bathroom, crack pipe somewhere,
boom, drip, drip, drip.
Next thing you know
you've got water damage.
The other one pipes running through the
slab because something goes wrong or
whatever,
and that thing starts to leak.
Tenants don't say anything
for a long period of time,
even though hearing their hands squish,
squish, squish under the, under the, the,
the flooring, they don't say anything.
Guess what? Everything's ruined.
You got to come in. They, you know.
So what do you do with those
catastrophic situations? Well,
if you've got the right management
team in place and gets handled,
it gets handled. Make the phone
calls people, get it taken care of.
You don't have to worry about it.
So you can't do that.
It's gotta be on a not to interfere basis
with your primary job if you're in the
military. And really it's the same
thing. If you have a primary, you know,
you got your primary job,
you're working for someone
and you're doing nine to five.
You don't want to interfere.
You want,
you want your side alternative Gig to
be on a not to interfere basis with your
primary gig.
Now the other thing that you can do,
and this is where you start to look
at, okay, cause you, you, you, you,
you're playing games,
you're playing these different
games because you want to
move yourself up on the
success level.
Sometimes you have,
and I see people do this and
some people do this really well.
They have one game that
they're playing to make.
They have another game that they're
playing to be, you know, to,
to win in their health, right?
They're doing marathons there,
there Jackin steal there,
they're doing Jujitsu.
They've got another game that they're
playing to get some sort of gratification
out of life, some kind of positive
gratification out of life,
whether they're working as a volunteer,
whether they're donating time to the
supe kid, whatever you're, they're doing,
they're doing something that's giving
them some gratification that they're
moving the ball forward for humanity.
And
that's, that's, that's a
good thing in my opinion.
So sometimes I think someone's there,
they're,
they're losing their soul because
I work at a job to make money.
They don't like it. They're
not healthy. And then,
and they feel like they're just
giving all their time to the man.
What should that person
do in that situation?
Find some other games that you
can play to find some other games.
Find a game to take care of your health.
Find a game to take care of your family.
I mean, you know, for, for
family, right? How do you,
what game can you play to take?
Make sure you get the
family unity that you want.
There's all kinds of things that you
can do, right? Whether it's camping,
whether it's vacations, whether it's
going on, on rock climbing trips,
whether it's everyone going to do Jujitsu,
whether it's you're doing a 15
minute PT in the morning, whatever.
But there's things,
there's some games that you can play to,
to get that side of things.
So there's all kinds of these various,
we'll call them games that get played.
But what I find,
this is the whole point
of this conversation.
What I find is people aren't aware
that they're in a specific game,
and that game has limitations
in that game, has rules.
And if you don't recognize that you're
going to play that game and you're gonna
keep playing that game soccer game, and
you think you're going to get more goals,
they're not coming
because you can't do it.
That game is limited in its own right.
So what you have to do is you have to
either change the game where you got to
find a new game to get into.
If you're young,
look at what game you're gonna
play and figure out what you know,
how you're going to win in multiple
games so that you can move yourself up on
the success
holistic success chart.
Sure. So there you go. That's
the first thing I wanted to, um,
to talk about today.
Number one,
the second thing I wanted to talk about
is Connor versus could
beep. All right. Okay.
So Connor versus could be, and
once again, this I realized,
I think the only other time
we've talked about a fight in,
in, in, on this podcast was another
Conor fight. I think it would make,
it might've been Connor versus Nate.
So why are we talking about
this fight? Well, there's,
there's two major reasons. Well, there's
three major reasons I guess now. One is,
was it the biggest fight
of all time in UFC?
It possibly was. I don't know. What do
you think? Yeah, I mean, I don't know.
It's hard to compare now because
yeah, cause it's, I would say no,
I would say yeah, because the fan base
is probably bigger than it's ever been.
Just overall. What about the hype
behind this fight? No, I felt like,
well then again, I don't
know. That can be my bubble.
I didn't hear as much about it. I heard
a lot about it for sure. I didn't,
but I didn't wait. Which one did
you hear more about? Jon Jones?
Some of the John Jones
fights. I remember. Yeah.
And then I'm also like some of the Brock
Lesnar fights. I remember thinking like,
Dang, newsers you, here's what I think.
I don't know. No holds it. Sorry.
Josie Aldo, Jose Aldo and Conor McGregor.
He, that was a huge, that might,
that might've been, that might've been
bigger. Yeah. And they did more toward,
they did a big press thing.
Here's though I think that people had
a better handle on what could happen in
the Jose Aldo fight.
I think people didn't know what
was going to happen in this fight.
Yeah. What's funny is for me, I was wrong
by the way, but it was the opposite.
I thought, oh, Josie, I was just
gonna beat this guy up. Oh really?
And then actually this one I thought
could be, was going to win too. Yeah.
So that's, let's get to that then.
All right. Um, I sent out a tweet,
which I normally don't, and so I
sent out a her, here's the tweet,
here's the tweet that I actually sent out.
It was to the notorious MMA,
which is Connor. I said, stay
outside the first three rounds.
Don't overcommit strikes mostly jabs.
Get booed by the crowd. Doesn't
matter. Frustrate, frustrate.
Could be forced bad shots.
Tire them out in the fourth start
stepping up the striking in the fifth.
Let it go and finish him. Good
luck. John Cavanaugh at John Kevin.
I tagged his coach because
his coach, well, okay,
now people are going, okay, well why
were you rooting for Conor McGregor?
And some people went a little crazy.
Like why are you when he's a bad sets,
a bad example for the sport and all men.
So
actually the reason is because I've
communicated with coach Cavenaugh a decent
amount on Twitter and little dms
and all that and just, you know, he,
he just has been kind of like a cool guy.
And here he was going into coach
his fighter in the biggest fight of,
of Connor's life.
And you know,
just because we've had
that little commerce,
we've had conversations on Twitter a
bunch and I just threw that out there like
two hours before.
I mean we,
I was watching the first fights
when I threw that out there.
I didn't know what the
really funny thing is.
John Calvin notes texted back or he,
he tweeted back copy.
So he actually read it and responded,
which is pretty crazy.
Um, so, so anyways,
because I have had a little
interaction with coach John Cavenaugh,
I felt like, you know, hey,
I'll throw this out there
also. You know, Hans,
Hans is like boys with Connor,
right? And Hans is my boy. So I was,
you know that that association,
There's association,
you know what I'm going to be like,
Hey,
Hans is my boy and he has been for a
long time and he's Bros with Connor.
And so I just, you know, like
again, so, so people are,
why did you, why are you voting for this
guy win? So there's that whole thing.
Now, the other odd thing about this
is you have a striker versus grappler.
Who Do I root for?
And striker versus grappler crap.
I always root for the grappler and I
know that factually and statistically the
grappler has the advantage
because grappling versus striking,
the grappler wins most of the time.
How can you go the distance
with this argument?
Sure you can took it all the people
that all the Times that a striker is
actually a good grappler and then
they don't use their grappling,
but they use their grappling only
to defend from being taken down.
Chuck Liddell the,
and there's a bunch of us,
there's countless guys that you can now
name that knocked people out and we're
known for their standup.
But what they really were,
their base was that they were a good
restaurant, couldn't be taken down. So,
but generally striker
versus grappler the striker,
and this is what I talk about from a
self defense perspective, right? If, uh,
if you're a good striker,
then that means you can run away and,
and if you're a good grappler,
once you get ahold of someone,
you can defeat someone
that has good striking.
Here's the thing that people
don't understand. In order
for you to punch someone,
you have to get close enough for them.
That where they can take you down.
You have to get into their takedown ranch,
the red.
So you have to get in the red zone.
So once you're in the red zone,
you can get taken down.
So how do you defeat that as a,
as a striker,
how do you defeat a really good grappler?
Um, the way you do it is by
we'll do. And what I just said,
you stay on the outside. You, you touched
person up. You don't overcommit to sir.
Cause the, the harder you notice. How
many rounds have you done if MMA sparring?
Countless. Okay. Me Too.
So when I would be
going against extractor,
the harder they throw at you, the easier
it is to take them down all day long.
And when I'm going against a wrestler
that I don't want to get taken down
against. Like I used to do this to
dean and it just frustrate them,
not commit to any punches,
not throw any kicks it all sit there and
jab and run away for basically two or
three rounds. And even dean who's
a far superior wrestler to me,
he would have a very, very
hard time taking me down. Yeah.
So this is a strategy.
The reason I know it's a legit strategies
because people have used it against
dean.
When Dean was fighting MMA,
people used that particular
strategy against him and it worked.
And so I know the strategy works guys,
that Dean was infinitely better on on
the ground and yet he couldn't take them
down and he was infinitely better at
wrestling. Why couldn't he take them down?
Because they weren't playing that game.
They weren't playing,
they weren't even playing the MMA and
they were playing the almond a jab you and
stay away.
Now a couple of things also,
Connors attitude, Connors, what
are you want to call it? His, his,
the way he behaves right?
He's unsportsmanlike.
And he's a trash talker and all
that. I get it. Number one, he's,
he's trying to sell fights like
w w is he a very confident,
perhaps in overconfident
guide? Actually. Maybe,
but if you ever see his work ethic,
it's freaking solid.
He's always respectful after a
loss. So when he loses, he's,
he is respectful and he says, Hey, good
job. You got beat. You know, he doesn't,
he's not, he's not a poor loser. Um,
and he's a hard worker.
And do I wish that he would behave
a little bit differently? I,
I don't. Yeah. I mean
it's, it's, it's him. Yeah.
As another thing is that's, that's him.
You know what I mean?
That's him.
And you can't expect guys that are
going to do what he's going to do for a
living to behave the way
that you want them to behave.
It's the same thing with guys
that are in the military, right?
You can expect a guy that's going to
go put his life on the line to be as,
as Kipling says, a plaster
St, right. It doesn't happen.
You've got a guy that you want to go
kill people and you want him to put his
life at risk.
Guess what?
He's going to get a little crazy sometimes
and as a leader, as a even as society,
we have to look at those
guys and go, okay, look,
we'll give you a little bit of room.
We want you to stay in the box here.
We don't want you to get out of control,
and that happens all the time.
Military guys get in trouble all the time.
They get out, they get outside the box,
but you've got to give him a
little bit of room. If you,
if you didn't want that type of person,
you would have no one in a while.
You would have a very few people in the
military because you take someone that's
attitude is, you know, hey, I'm
a, I'm a saint. Well guess what?
A saint doesn't want to go
hunt people down and kill him.
A saint doesn't want to
get in the mud and blood,
blood and guts and be in that situation.
It's very similar with fighters. Now,
are there fighters that do
behave in an idealistic way?
Sure, absolutely. There are. Is that
preferred? Sure. That's great to see.
I would prefer it. I don't know, but
it's great to see. I mean probably in my,
I want to, I don't know who my
favorite fighter of all time is,
but fader is definitely at the,
you know,
he's in the top three of
my favorite writers and one
of my favorite things about
for faders, faders showed no emotions
ever at any time. Winter loose,
the same reaction. He mostly one, but
he would just raise his hand like he,
when he barely even raised his hand, be
like a half her, it'd be like half like,
Hey,
I just just destroyed this person in one,
$2 million here in Japan and I'm taking
the pride of Russia home with me.
No big deal. I'm going to
go lift a kettle bell. Uh,
Sakharova soccer.
Rob Was the same way,
very v and the thing that was
funny about Sakharova, again,
he's one of my favorite
fighters is Sakuraba. The only
thing that was, you could,
you could hold against soccer sometimes.
He would like clown people almost. Yeah.
And he was almost had some of
that professional wrestling
stuff going on. Yeah.
So anyways, uh, Conor is Conor,
Conor will mature and he'll
get older and that's fine.
He backs it up, he puts it on the line,
bro. He puts on, he doesn't avoid fights.
I can say that,
you know,
he takes the hardest fights
he can possibly find when he,
when he lost to Nate Diaz to say, I
want to fight him again next. Yeah.
You know, that's legit. So anyways,
there was a couple of people that
were like straight up, just hostile.
Why are you supporting Carter? He's a
bad sport. He just represents like, okay,
I get it. So there's why
John Kavanagh, great coach,
my buddy haunts friends
with them. Um, yeah.
Now for the actual game plan,
the actual game plan that I talked
about, number one, stay outside.
Stay outside. You stay outside the
range of that person you get just,
we can barely touch them with a jab
and you get ready to sprawl. Now,
Connor actually did a good job.
He sprawled a few times. He,
he defended the takedown
on several occasions.
He did a good job on the bottom of,
you know,
Khabib does this thing that dean does too,
which is he ties up your legs with
his legs, kind of like captures them.
And when you can't pull your legs
out when you're up against the cage,
you cannot get up. Yeah. Connor, God,
his legs out over and over and over.
That was impressive. That was impressive.
So that's number one. You stay outside,
it's really hard to take,
you know,
even even against someone
that's a great wrestler,
me and I'm not a great wrestler. I
can, I can back up and stay away. It's,
I'm really hard to take down and
so isn't it? So is anybody, if you,
if your sole goal is
to not get taken down,
it's actually not that hard to knock
it taken down now it changes when you,
when you start committing to your punches,
it changed.
When you start trying to
knock someone out, it changes.
When you start getting into a
wrestling match with people,
then it's easy to get taken
down. You know, Taylor, right?
Olive oil to take down on Taylor and
as soon as we start mixing it up,
guess what you're getting? Yeah, getting
taken down cause I play his game.
Can't play his game. Okay, next part.
Don't over what happens when you throw
strikes, your weight goes forward.
When your weight is forward
you you can get taken down.
That's all there is to it.
So you don't want to throw big heavy
punches early because that's when the take
down is going to come.
Mostly Jabs again,
that's the Lightest
Punch your furthest away.
I wouldn't even throw kicks. Maybe a
couple of kicks but I wouldn't throw him.
He's fast cars fast so he might be
able to get away with it but I probably
wouldn't even throw any
kicks in the first round.
Maybe start throwing some kicks in
the second round but kicks again.
Kicks take time and a well timed shot.
We'll take you down on a,
on a kick. Can you chop at the legs? Yeah,
you can shop with the legs.
That can have a big negative impact on
the person you're fighting. Getting booed.
Right.
Why did I say get booed?
The reason I said get booed is because
if you're doing this strategy right,
people are mad at you because they
think you're avoiding the fight.
They think that you're not being
aggressive and they're going to get mad.
The crowd is going to hate you, and that's
just what you got to deal with, right?
When your crowd is frustrated and annoyed
at you, guess what? So is your opponent.
So now your opponent starts getting
frustrated and taking bad shots,
and when that, and when that opponent is
taking shots that are outside the zone,
you basically have to be able to put your
hands on someone for the most part in
order to get a good shot and take them
down. When you're outside that zone,
it's you just, there's a, there's a war.
There's a fraction of a second difference
that it takes you to get to the shit,
to the grip on the person that you
can. You can stop it. You can stop it.
You can't,
you can't shoot from too far away.
And when you get someone frustrated and
you're touching them up with jabs and
they're getting mad and they're hearing
the boos, the crowd, they get frustrated.
They start shooting from far away. When
they start shooting from far away, yes,
sprawl on them. You put your hands on the
back of their head, you stand back up,
you walk away and you make them do
it again. You make them do it again.
You make them do it again. I said, tire
mountain. A lot of people were saying, oh,
Connor's cardio's no good, and that's
not a good plan. You're an idiot.
That type of thing. The reason I
said that is because first of all,
wrestling is for the most part,
wrestling is more tiring than striking.
That being said,
if someone's,
or if someone's a good wrestler
and not a good striker,
they're going to get more tired striking
than they are wrestling. So you take,
you take Khabib out of his
game, his game, his wrestling.
He's not getting tired wrestling and
he's getting a little bit tired. However,
when he shot four times and around
and you've defended all of them,
it is absolutely easier to defend take
downs than it is to to to do take downs.
It's a lot easier. I mean, we do
these drills all the time. In fact,
the way that we run the drills,
when you first,
when you're the first
monkey in the middle,
you're the one that's doing the take
downs and when you're more tired,
all you have to do is
defend the takedowns. Why?
Because it's easier to defend take downs.
You don't have to work as hard.
All you have to do is
counter what they're doing.
So you take him and you
tie them down and Connor,
Connor's not going to get
tired while he's striking, oh,
he's going to get less tired.
While he's striking again,
could could con or use an improve in his
cardio. Sure, sure. I've seen him fade.
We've all seen him fade. That's a bad
thing. He needs to step that game up.
I'd love to look at his training and
see where we could fill in those holes.
But the bottom line is he's going to get
more tired of which he did when he's in
a wrestling grappling scenario than he
does when he's standing up throwing jabs.
He said he looks like he's in walking
through the park when he's standing up.
So you do that, you, you,
you, that's what you do.
You stand up your tire amount and you
don't overcommit and let them run out.
You're now some people. So we use as a
congress to just trying to knock them out.
There's a problem with that idea of
is that great? It was a great one.
It happens to Aldo. Sure.
You can't count on knockouts,
you can't count on them when
you're throwing knockout punches,
guess what happens?
You're over committing.
When he overcommitting it's
easy to get taken down.
So there you go.
Now what actually happened in the fight,
Conor pressed forward almost
the whole time, which,
which when you press forward,
it's easy for a grappler to time your
moot forward movement and shoot on you and
take you down. And, and that's what
happened. Like I said, he escaped.
He escaped from the Mount position a
few times. That was impressive. He got,
it's usually the Camaro. Yes,
the attempt could be, could be,
but had a camera on him. Yes. Legit come
here. And I was like, oh this is over.
Nope. Nope. Conor got out. I think Conor
got out through brute, just like strength.
So he got out of that and he
recovered recovered guard a few times.
He freed his legs from those weird,
um,
half guard sort of leg
control things that dean does.
He freed his legs from
those a bunch of times.
He survived fairly well on the bottom
in the early rounds and that's all he
needed to do. If he would've done
this game plan of staying away,
if he got taken down with one minute left,
cause he starts doing it,
then you survived for a minute. It's okay.
It's okay. You survived for a minute.
That rounds over and then you
get to try it again. Uh, again,
the reason that I know this game plan
works is because it's been used against my
fighter dean.
And you know who did Amare sue levy.
He's a, he's a dean. Talked about him.
He's a Russian guy that ended up
like mafia dude or something hit man.
But that's what he did.
Just stay away.
The guy was a better striker and don't
overcommit and that's what happens.
And you know what's also weird is people
even do this in Jujitsu matches. Yeah.
They do this in ADCC where,
hey,
if I'm a great wrestler and you're better
at Jujitsu than me and I don't want to
go to the ground with you, I just play
the patty cake for a while and then I,
what I do is when there's one minute left,
I do one take down,
I get two points and then I cover up
and hold and I win the match. Yeah.
So people do this in,
they do this.
Another thing that did do
that they do in Jujitsu,
and this is something that you have
to work on as a Jujitsu practitioner.
Let's say you and I are training
and you get the take down on me,
what do I do? Well, I
engage with my guard.
I started looking for, you
know, grabbing your arm.
I start looking for neck control. I
immediately start doing Jujitsu with you.
What if I want to really it I have,
there's another,
there's a whole nother game I can play
with you, which is you take me down.
I immediately try and get back up. Yeah.
That's a, that's a totally different game.
This fouls up.
Like I used to not do this with dean.
I used to not do this with,
I do with Andy now because I have to
because people are going to do that.
People are going to do that.
When you're in a competition and
someone takes you down or you get, yeah,
you take someone down.
If they're not comfortable,
if they think you might be a little
bit better than normal on the ground,
they're just going to try and get back
to her feet and that is a different game
than just engaging in Jujitsu.
Yeah.
Or if they don't like their buttons, you
know, guys, they don't like the bottom of,
yeah, for sure. They get taken
down. It's like stand back.
They're just going to get back up.
And that's if you're not used to that,
that is problematic for you on top if you,
if you allow that situation to happen.
Yeah. Yeah. That's why it's good to
train with. I think I said this before,
good to train with MMA guys because
that's a lot of the time the case,
unless they're like straight up dude,
you too background guys. But you know,
you know guys who just
have essentially um, uh,
what do you call a freestyle
kind of style to them.
They and in a sense we do Jujitsu.
Yeah.
Anytime I train with them and they
don't like being on the bottom.
So you're going to get that training.
They're big time feed on the hips,
your head away and they're just
trying to get back up again. The,
the theme or the reason that all that
I have all this stuff in my head is
because it's all about what game are you
playing, what game are you playing? And,
and again, Connor, that's one of the
things that everyone loves about Connor,
myself included,
is he goes in there to fight.
And yet that instinct of going forward
all the time against a guy that's a
superior wrestler and Grappler, which
could be certainly is. And like I said,
grappling broadly stated is
superior to striking in a,
in a one on one situation.
Yeah. Do you look hesitant?
You know, I agree with that probably
more than you do. Oh, okay. Because,
and there's obviously, and I just had
someone hit me up on social media.
It was like, but what if, you
know, why don't you get punched on?
What if the striker can punch you
when you're trying to take him down?
And like that the case has
gone through and through.
Can striker knock someone
out? Yes, they absolutely can.
They have a puncher's chance. Can you
rely on that? Hell No. You can't. Yeah.
Hell No. You can't. Yeah.
What were you going to say?
Yeah, that's it. I mean, yeah,
most of the time as far
as how it has played out.
Oh yeah. You, yeah, you can knock
the guy out. Oh yeah, for sure.
Yeah. Well, yeah, he can happen for
sure, but yeah, you just do the,
you run the statistics. No, it's like
way harder to plan a knock out on a,
on a breath for grappler to plan
a submission was way easier.
Even in grappling tournaments
they've got would be like, Hey,
I'm going to go and I'm going to
get this guy in a rear naked choke.
That's what I'm going to do. And against
another grappler by the way. So yeah,
it's way, it's way easier to plan
because it's way more methodical.
It's like way less. Like, what do you call
it, like chaotic and don't get it wrong.
Like strikers know how to control
their environment. I dig it. Yeah.
But just the nature of what it is, you
know, there, there's no, there's no doubt.
And again,
broadly speaking because I am totally
pro striking and you have to be able to
strike and you're, you're more time,
your boxing kills. The better they are,
the better you are as a human
being and I don't know if, yeah,
I mean if you've ever trained,
if anyone here doesn't believe in
striking it all go and train with somebody
that's a really good high level
striker and they will jack you up. Yes,
they will jack you up.
You will be,
you will feel like a white belt
in Jujitsu on the map. Yes.
The only difference is if it's,
if you talk,
if you flip a switch and you make an MMA
and you can grab a hold of them. Yeah,
you can. You can all of a sudden
you can equalize it very quickly.
That's why Jujitsu came about that.
That's why, well not Mike came about.
That's why it came onto
the scene so strong.
It's because all of the striking stuff,
as awesome as it is,
we just saw another example
of it on Saturday night.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yeah.
And I'm not even saying
honor is a far superior.
If Connor is a phenomenal striker,
once he's on the ground,
he's on the ground in those strikes
don't mean anything anymore. Barely.
Especially these kids with like
super good grappling and you know,
they can keep going. You know,
when you gas and it was this movie,
we'll go into kind of what your
strategy was. If a grappler,
is he a grappler? Gasses. And that goes
for anyone in a fight. If you gas out,
you're essentially ineffective. So
kind of that aside, the, well, the,
the reason that p that it seems like,
Oh yeah,
all of these guys like a Leo Machida,
right?
He was a big one who kind of exploded
onto the scene and just beat up everyone.
And he was a karate guy,
black belt in Jujitsu by the way.
But no one wants to talk about that part.
Or even like a chocolate l type
character where he's just knocking,
he's straight up knocking everybody
helicopters and everything.
Superior restaurant by the way. So it's
one of those things where it's like, yeah,
if you don't know any grappling, oh
yeah, your, your chances of success,
especially as time goes
on, go, go way down. Um,
but most people if they're like primarily
striking or striking as their kind of
their, their success, you know,
that's what gives them success.
They have to learn even
like a few fundamentals in
grappling and get really good
at them. Just defensively
to start with. Start with.
But if you don't know anything, like
if you know how to defend the takedown,
that's grappling right there ready.
And if you get really good
at that, then okay, that's going to help
you a lot. But that's grappling. Now.
What if you essentially fail
at defending the take down?
Meaning you get taken down, you have
to learn to get back up. If you don't,
you'll get hell done there.
Straight up.
If you don't like take a big strong guy
and just a normal size person, one knows,
knows you to put the big strong guy
on his back. Like even in guard Bro,
he won't get up. No. If the guy's
like, Hey, don't let him up,
you won't get up straight up.
He, and the harder he tries,
the less ability he's
going to have to get up.
It's like throwing somebody in
the water who can't swim. Yeah.
And like he can't even tread water,
let alone swim.
He can't try the try as hard as you can.
And the harder you try it,
the more it's just going to not work.
But you teach someone to just
tread water or he'll handle it.
He'll handle a little bit. But you
just learned how to tread water though.
You learned how to swim a little bit.
So you've got to learn that stuff.
And what's Nice,
well you need to take this into account
is that the UFC rounds or are only five
minutes.
So they're only five minutes,
which means you could see it took,
it took time for Connor's
good enough that it,
he's not getting like just caught you
made a quick mistake and get caught. No,
he's making a series of
mistakes that take time.
And then finally they get capitalized on.
If he can make it three minutes
on the feet every round May.
And the chances of him getting
submitted in two minutes by Khabib,
especially when he was doing good
maneuvers on the bottom, bottom,
they're not really that good.
And you know,
can you make a mistake and get gay teens
that normally happens to the grappler
that's like grappler versus grappler.
I shoot on you.
You grab the guillotine or I try
and post and you do an arm lock.
That usually happens. Not from
most of those moves come out of me.
Me engaging in grappling with you,
not me getting away from you.
Me Getting away from you exposes
less of grappling submissions.
Unless you do pour mistakes, like turn
your back, then you got a problem,
you're going to have a,
you're going to have a problem.
And I suppose we should
also talk about the, uh,
the after situation after
the fight. Sure. And,
uh, you know, Khabib, who's
normally very stoic and calm,
he lost it. He ran out
in the crowd. Conner, uh,
and I was watching in detail some of
these little clips and Conor was getting
nuts too. Let's, let's not make
any mistakes about it cause yeah.
So,
and then the guy came in from Congress,
from Khabib's team and soccer
punched Connor. That was gnarly.
And so what do I think of all that? Yeah.
It's horrible. Is it bad for the sport?
Yes, it's bad for the
sport. Um, interestingly,
Joe Rogan posted that Brendan
Schaub kind of made a prediction.
The predicts. Yeah. He made a prediction
that something was going to get crazy.
Yeah. And that's, that was
accurate. What do I think about it?
I think it was a bummer. Yeah. This is
a bummer. It's a bummer to see. I'm,
I was surprised to see could be get
crazy like that. The fight was over.
You could see that Connor was pretty
humble and defeat and he was sitting there
like, hey, all right. Uh, that's a bummer.
And Khabib got nuts for those moments
and I don't know what's going to happen.
I don't know what's going to happen in
terms of, I know they didn't hate it.
I don't think they paid him yet.
They didn't pay him his $2 million purse.
Yeah. Wouldn't that be an athletic
commission thing? No. You, Oh yeah,
it will definitely as the athletic,
yeah, they'll, they'll find them.
They'll take part of his purse and
that's just money. That's like, you know,
when you pay a speeding ticket and the
state gets the money, it's the same thing.
So they,
the athlete that Nevada State Athletic
Commission could find him half as person,
put 1.5 or no, he, he made $2 million
purse. He could put a mill. They,
he could put the net.
Nevada state athletic commission could
put $1 million in their pocket by saying,
you,
you shouldn't have done that.
Were finding you were finding you half
of your purse, boom. Here's $1 million.
Let's build a new office
center office center.
So I don't know what's going to happen.
It's not good to see that.
I wish everyone would be better
sports. Uh, that would be good.
But the people are super emotional and
they haven't learned to control their
emotions yet.
Which brings me to the third point
that I wanted to talk about this week.
What are you going to say?
No, no, no. I dig it. But the,
there is like a bigger kind
of picture here with the,
it's sold anything that's quote
unquote bad for the sport. Right.
That's that that is something,
but there's two elements right there.
There's the growth of the sport and then
there's like promotion of the sport for
the people who are in the, who were in
the game in a bad press is good press.
Any press is good press.
There's a dichotomy. So yeah,
the growth of the sport to the guy who
doesn't watch MMA cause it's so barbaric.
We're watching. Okay. What will the
Pettis fight? Right. Same. Same event.
Pedis and for example, yeah.
By the way, I like Ferguson.
That dude's a hard worker. I like
Pettis too. Okay. And, and I,
and I definitely liked Duke. Roufus
yeah, my boy, my boy there was, you know,
we would be cornering people
backstage and Duke Rufus was always,
I mean he hasn't probably
doesn't know anything.
There's probably wouldn't even
barely know who I am at all,
but he would always be like, super
cool dude. He's awesome. Yeah.
So that fight Ben Pettis and Pettis is a
good dude too. You know, I liked pedis.
Yeah. Really seems like it. Um, but that
was a bloody fight. Yeah, it was. So,
and there's bloody fights every once
in all right guys with a huge gash is
whatnot, so, okay. Bloody fight. Right.
And so me, my brother and my cousin,
we were watching this fight and uh,
so these guys are just basically
punching each other in the face,
each other in the face, bleeding like
all over, you know, like super bloody.
The kind of where they got to
stop the fight and be like, hey,
check this guy that, you know,
so it gives you a, hey doc,
hey timeout while we just clean
up blood off everyone. Yes.
It'll take about a minute here. Just a
white blonde off everyone. Yeah. Yeah.
And meanwhile we're just watching it
like, oh, whatever. Like, actually,
it's like there have been more eventful
fights then this one, like it ended in a,
you know,
he broke his hand or whatever and it was,
and that was considered uneventful. I
broke his hand. Yeah, yeah, yeah. All I,
the guy in the head stopped. Yeah, they
stopped the fight and that was uneventful.
We consider that uneventful and eventful
fight is a guy who gets knocked out,
unconscious, flat out, which with which
happened, by the way, a few fights early.
Anyway, so we're watching
this blood everywhere and
meanwhile we were like, okay,
you know, like whatever. But so that,
my point is the growth of the sport.
You get a guy who doesn't watch MMA,
they only watch, you know, basketball,
football,
the traditional sports,
and they get a glimpse into MMA and
they see that all the blood and stuff,
they're like, this is a dumb sport.
This is not even a sport. This is like,
this shouldn't be illegal.
This is like two human beings.
And everyone shared meanwhile.
Okay.
So when the fight stopped that that
pet is Ferguson fight, it stops. Right.
They stop it. They, you know how
they cut to the crowd? Everyone.
So I'll just see their reaction.
There's like businessmen in their
suits drinking their drinks.
It's like the epitome of like gladiator
old school king with all the grapes and
the stuff and high fiving and stuff.
Right? Meanwhile these two guys are like,
one guy has a broken hand,
the other guy has bled off.
Well they both have blood all over.
Right? So as an outsider looking in,
you're like, it's reasonable to expect
them to be like, this is, this is dumb.
This is not a sport. I'm not going
to sign onto this at all. Okay.
Then you get these posts,
fight shenanigans could be even guys
jumping out of the ring into the crowd,
continuing to fight after
he won, by the way. So that,
and I'm not saying that this
is how I'm looking at it.
I'm saying this is how an outsider, we'll
see it. Interesting. And then you see,
you know, months ago, whatever,
Connor flying into New York
and busting up the bus.
It could be even in, and it's this
thing and you know all this stuff,
guys getting injured from
the broken glass, all this
stuff, right? It's a, it's a,
it's not cool from an outsider looking in.
It's like this is not a sport.
This is dumb. These guys aren't people,
these aren't civilized people, this stuff.
But from the inside, man, I'm really
looking forward to this fight now.
After caught, I did that then, you
know, then, uh, you know, things happen.
Connor's talking all this
trash. It's like, oh, and he's
backing it up. Oh my gosh,
I want to see this even
more now if you get,
and I like fader to or that's the fader.
I like him too.
What if everyone was like fate or though
there will be a lot of fights that you
just don't care about. You'd be
like, Hey, all right, cool. Or,
but on the flip question, cause I
would, I would care about all of them.
You would not care about you care about
them left last. I think we'll meet you.
I Dunno. I Dunno what you care
about sometimes, but the people,
the reason, fate or his fate
or to the extent that faders,
faders cause because other people are
not like for you to compare him to
everyone else,
it gets all crazy and he just sits there
and looks at him and then knocks him
out or chokes him out.
Cause when you think about it,
isn't that really the martial art spirit?
For sure.
Super Stoic and that's how it
has been. Yeah. But now, hey,
martial arts, let's face it, when
you're in the game, if you watch MMA,
especially USC, if you
watch this, this is,
it goes like the martial arts spirit
of the thing is very small, very small.
This is a show. You don't get it wrong.
This is a show with real punches,
real kicks, blood, all that
stuff. And this is all part
of the show. What happened?
I definitely think of it more as a sport
than I do think of it as a display of
martial arts for the community.
I'm not thinking of it that way anymore.
It's a sport.
But I would even go beyond the sport.
It's a show straight up
because if it was just a sport,
you know what they did for the first time.
I don't know if you noticed as you
probably did, they had like fog on the,
on the octagon explore. Yeah.
I was like only for Connor.
The dry ice dry ice effect.
Right? Yeah. Really like you.
What do you think? I give that the
Nega tron there was a while where it,
UFC was trying to lean
towards the other direction.
They took away all the show stuff and
they made it look like more like a sporty
and now graph. Kind of going
back a little bit. Yeah man.
It's because the new owners took over.
Well yeah.
And you know that was obviously like a
quote unquote branding play. You know,
we want to kind of go mainstream with
the sport edge of it and you know,
make it a kind of a wholesale. Here's the
thing Brad, it's not a wholesome thing.
Like it's totally,
there's a difference.
We need scoring a ball in a basket or
running across the end zone or the goal
line for a touchdown and all this
stuff out running guys trying to just
basically talk you to the
ground and there's a difference
between that being the
goal and the goal being to hurt the
guy as bad as he possibly can or they
incapacitate them as bad
as you probably know.
Something I said on when I was on
Joe Rogan's podcast is I was like,
if you go watch where any of those
other sports, when they escalate,
they escalate to what you actually
want to see, which is MMA.
Like what happens when a basketball
game gets a little too rough?
They fight each other. What happens
when hockey gets a little bit,
they fight each other. What happens when
football gets a little bit too rough?
They fight. Even baseball.
Someone, someone does something
out of line in baseball,
they fight each other. Yes, let's just
get rid of the ball, get rid of the net.
You get rid of the hockey stick and just
loves I get it on. Yeah. And that's, yeah,
that's why, and that's, I mean, obviously
that's a whole whole nother thing,
but if you,
and I'm not saying there's necessarily
a confusion between it like us,
the sport in the show and the
martial arts and all that,
but I'm just saying there,
there are three different elements
and they just gave me a whole like
interesting idea.
So sometimes for me,
I'm so functional,
like I operate and such a functional
mindset that it's doesn't even work,
right? It just doesn't work. It
doesn't work with normal people. Like,
Hey, just like, no, this is just going to
be, uh, we're just going to be playing.
If I was,
if I was in charge of the entire UFC,
what would it look like? And it would
probably be just be so functional.
They'd be the extreme that you would,
that you're saying people
would just be like,
I don't really know if I want
to watch this. And however,
I would say if you dug deep into the
training methodologies and you understood
the people,
which UFC does a decent job now with the,
what's it called when they're
leading up to the fight,
they embed it so you could watch the
embedded, you get to see kind of, it's,
it's not highly edited,
embedded and you get to see what,
but I would,
you know,
for me I would make the whole thing
would be like functional. It'd be like,
oh, there'll be lights that show
you everyone and we call her lights.
Why would you need color lights? You know
what I mean? You definitely fired. Yeah,
no we wouldn't do that.
You'd want to get fired up.
You see the guy walking
into the gauge that's about,
that's about to fight another human being.
It doesn't work that way though.
I know like the,
even if it,
again go back to everyone being stoic
and it'd be like it'd be reduced.
It would be less of a show and in fact
you might even argue that it's kind of
has, we've seen that before. Like in just
like other, like you ever watch like,
uh, like a karate tournament
or something like that.
It's like they don't develop characters
or nothing like that. They're just,
this is guy and hey, this
guy's good. And so like, cool.
I want to see what he's good at.
And then you sort of forget about it.
You don't anticipate that unless
you're way, way in the game. But my,
my personal,
uh,
vision doesn't always line up well with
like the drama creation that everyone
else likes. Yeah. But that's,
that's literally life. That's why,
that's why you want to
watch it because of poplar,
a big part of it is because of the
John Chael Sonnen wise man. Right?
Said one time,
once one fight ends,
that's when the promotion for the
next fight begins. So that, you know,
when he gets on the mic
after the fight is done,
he's essentially promoting the next
week. And, but, and the thing is, it's,
it's totally proven. Like even like
someone saying, why do you care why?
Like people were coming to you saying,
why are you supporting Connor?
He's such a bad role model.
All of that. That's all good
stuff. Like, well, if they,
if they were like, Oh, who's that guy
caught it, will you support this? Hey,
let me look into this guy. That's a
failure. But yeah, to love him, hate him.
The thing is if I dislike
a guy and there's guys that
I disliked, I understand.
I don't dislike them as people. I dislike,
dislike what we call the UFC character.
You don't like the guy that that's
on the mic and doing that, whatever.
I'm just not a fan actually.
I'm the anti-fat I want him to lose.
Like if he's fighting a
guy, unless I don't know the
other guy. It's interesting.
You know what I think kind of changed
my perspective a little bit is like Tito
Ortiz, he had this, he has a horrible,
his reputation was always like he was
a jerk and all this stuff. Bed. Yeah,
he was a WWE. He'll, yeah. And,
and I didn't know him well,
but I mean I trained with
him psalm and you know,
Dean Jean Dean train with them a lot.
So I kind of knew and by proxy and
Tito Ortiz as a dude, as I could,
just a dude outside of that whole world
and totally cool and totally good to go.
You know,
totally coined a Bisping is the same way.
Like this being kind of a heel.
I've met Bisman got trained with Brisbane.
Bisman is totally good dude. You know,
trains, hard, hard work, great work ethic.
Good. I, and I'm saying again,
I don't want to make it sound like I
know these guys and I'm all boroughs with
them cause I'm not, but I've trained
with him, I've been on the mat with them.
You know,
like I know I can understand
their character outside
of the character that they
play on TV and the character that they
have. And maybe that's why for me,
when I look at Conor and I see all this
stuff, I look at it and I think, yeah,
you know what behind that it's going to
be another guy that's a hard worker that
wants to win and take care of his
family. Like, oh, okay. And he's got,
he's doing some stuff and he's talking
about red panties and you know, he just,
that's what he's doing. Cause,
and I look at it the same way.
I see a guy like Bisbing,
a guy like Tito Ortiz who are behind that,
that front that they put up,
they're just,
they're just hardworking guys
that like to fight. Yeah.
But I don't see Conor as a bad guy as
the heel though. Connie was a good guy.
He's like, he's anti opponent.
Like he'll, he'll really kind of,
he'll talk bad about his opponent. Not
necessarily bad, like necessarily bad,
but you know, he'll talk himself
up over his opponent kind of thing.
But he's not like,
like Bisbing will actively just like
chill sona and just like Tito Ortiz
actively play the bad guy to the point
where they will be categorized as that.
Oh yeah.
People will make about,
this is the thing about the stuff that
[inaudible] was saying about Anderson
Silva. Yeah. You just,
yeah, that was crazy.
And chill son's a good
example even though Chelsea,
you can tell by that cause
you guys like you ever touch,
I did stuff with Chelsea video watch,
right.
And like full on accommodating like overly
polite person in ways that he doesn't
have to do that. You don't have to
do this plate stuff. So he's an,
he's one of those guys. But I could tell
like, okay, this is the show and I get it.
And actually I dig it. Um, like Bisping,
I was genuinely surprised how nice he was.
I did a video with this being,
if you want to look at it,
very funny video to by the way,
which one did you do with Biz? Bang?
His head not deliver on just show,
I forget what episode, but
we put oh yeah, they did.
Yeah he was, he played, uh,
the main guy to snatch the movie.
You're right. But didn't call,
he didn't call it snatch what you call
it snatched. He snatched. It's good.
He doesn't really get up. So it's, it's,
Michael has Bisping Kit Dale is Tommy.
And then hit not do is, let me ask you
this. Kenny Florian. Kenny Florian,
when you did the heat,
he's yeah.
That he's got some chops.
Straight up acting chops. Yes.
Kenny Florian shout out.
Yes. Yeah. Straight up acting
chops. So Kenny Florian,
not to go too deep into that,
but Kay.
So on top of that Kenny Florian
is super nice too. Yeah. Nice.
He got tested with, with us, with me, um,
on how nice he could be as
far as tolerance. So we go
up there, right? Oh this,
you have to reshoot the whole
thing. Two cameras, right.
We get and so you know,
one angle and him one ain't going
hand out to the angle on him.
The camera just didn't work.
Something with the SD card or whatever
this and we've totally had to like get
access to the restaurant after hours
and like all this stuff schedule with
Kenny.
Not to mention who is like,
this is like after he crossed
over into straight up mainstream,
you can't just get Kenny Florian off.
He, you know, he had shows in like,
he's kind of a high level guy
at this time and I get home,
like we're, you know, we're editing and
I'm like, we got her, there's no choice.
We've got to re shoot this thing. And
then, oh, we're like man, Kenny Florida,
like whatever. He's like, yeah, cool.
Let's go. Go like reshape. He had a goatee
when a dean and I were doing the trials
for ADCC in 2002 for the 2003 80 cc,
Ken Flo came out and he was one of
the competitors. And you, same thing,
like we didn't really know him that well,
but no,
we were all kind of like a black belt.
She's and all that stuff.
So actually I wasn't a black belt at
that time. I was a brown belt, but we,
you know, everyone was just like super
cool. Yeah, the dean was a brown belt.
What am I talking about? I
was a purple belt. All right.
So where this whole thing goes from,
and this is interesting that you
brought this up. There's the,
now the other thing I
wanted to talk about,
which is this idea of attack detachment,
which talk about all the time.
Yeah.
And I've seen like another
little reveal on detachment.
Maybe another angle. Okay. So picture
this black belt versus a white belt.
You're training Jujitsu.
The white belt is like
grabbing your sleeve.
Okay.
Or grabbing your belt or grabbing it,
like doing something.
Whatever he's doing doesn't matter.
And it will not affect the outcome at all.
And I see. And so what should
you do as, as a black belt, as a,
as a better grappler,
what are you gonna do when someone's
doing something that doesn't matter?
What do you do? You just kind
of ignore it. It's like, okay,
that's not gonna affect the outcome. I'm
not going to worry about it. As leaders,
I see people getting caught up all the
times in little things that will not
affect the outcome unless they let it.
So I see some white belt blow
them in the chain of command.
It's going all crazy. Grabbing their
sleeve and this leader on the top,
like gets concerned about it and puts
time and effort into something that
doesn't matter whether it's
a little personality, Rob,
a little key go uprising.
It's, should we do it this way or should
we do it that way? Doesn't matter.
That's a little sleeve grab.
It doesn't matter.
And I see people getting caught up on
things that don't matter all the time.
And what I've realized is it's something
that I figured out a long time ago.
I don't know when, but a long time
ago I figured out, you know what?
That thing doesn't matter. I'm not going
to worry about it. That's the thing.
Doesn't matter. I'm not going to worry
about it. That thing doesn't matter.
I'm not going to worry about that thing
matters. I'm going to focus on that thing
and that makes, that
makes a big a big, big,
big difference.
It's,
it's leadership capital because if I'm
investing my leadership capital and
getting your hand off my sleeve or trying
to do it my way instead of your way or
trying to keep your ego in check if
that's what I'm investing my leadership
capitalists, I have nothing left to invest
in the thing that's actually matters.
Just like if you're a black belt and
someone guys grabbing your sleeve and you
focus on pulling that and off your whole
time you're going to waste energy and
maybe even give up position cause your,
cause you were focused on
something that did not matter.
So it is important to realize and to
learn to differentiate between things that
don't matter and things that do matter.
And in order to tell the difference
between those two things,
you have to be able to detach
and step back.
And obviously this is the same thing,
not just with Jujitsu, not just with
leadership, not just with combat.
Cause it's the same thing in combat.
You're going to have things that don't,
things are happening on the
battlefield that don't matter.
Little Hey guys move in here instead
of there. That doesn't matter. Oh,
this guy's moving there. So it doesn't
matter. The is doing this. Okay,
it doesn't matter. Oh wait, the enemy
did that thing that matters. Well,
one of my guys did this
thing that matters.
So how do you learn to
discriminate between the two?
You have to be able to detach from it.
That's what you have to do.
You have to be able to detach and
okay,
if you,
if you don't learn to detach,
you're going to constantly get tripped
up on things that don't really matter.
And I'll tell you,
the more,
the better you get.
The last things matter.
Yeah.
The better you get,
the last things matter
and the better you get, the more the more
important things matter. Hmm. So you,
you end up just wasting no energy
on things that don't matter.
And focusing all your energy
on things that actually matter.
And this is the difference, man.
This is how you win in Jujitsu.
This is how you win as a leader.
This is how you're winning combat.
And this is truly how you win in life.
Think about all the things you don't,
what you used to talk about a lot.
You haven't done it in a while.
You just talk about distractions,
how things can distract you. Right?
That's totally true.
That's what I'm talking about.
The things that distract you
from what actually matters.
So you have to,
you have to figure out how
to detach from those things.
I was doing some reading as is her
norm shows a guy named Keith Douglas.
He was a British soldier, World
War II. He's kind of a bad ass.
He was stuck in an administrative position
in October of 1942 during the second
battle of El Alamein. And so he was
stuck in this administrative position,
so he just went AWOL and went to the front
line and join the fight and got after
it.
And one of the things that wrote,
he said to be sentimental or emotional
now is dangerous to oneself and to
others.
So what is he talking about?
You can't get emotional.
You can't get sentimental.
You can't get caught up in
things that don't matter.
After his return from Africa.
This Guy Keith Douglas,
he wrote a book about his experience.
Here's a little excerpt, can kind of
think about what this guy has been
through that taught him these lessons.
Here we go.
As I came up to them,
I recognized one of them as Robin,
the observation officer,
whose aid I had been asking
for earlier in the day.
I recognized his fleece lines,
fleece lined suede waistcoat and
polished brass shoulder titles,
and then his face strained and tired with
pain in his left foot was smashed to a
pulp mingled with the remainder of a boot.
But as I spoke to Robin saying,
have you got a tourniquet robbin?
He answered apologetically.
I'm afraid I haven't, Keith.
I looked at the second ma'am,
only his clothes distinguished
him as a human being.
His face had gone
in place of,
it was a huge yellow vegetable.
The eyes blinked in it without lashes
and a grotesque huge mouth dribbled and
moaned like a child exhausted with crying.
Okay.
So there's an example of a horrible
situation that you have to learn to detach
and you have to be able to focus
on things that actually matter.
Because as Keith Douglas said,
to be sentimental or emotional now is
dangerous to oneself and to others.
Now, as I was digging into a little
bit of Keith Douglas and we'll,
we'll get to Keith Douglas
fully on the podcast, but he,
he added to that line,
he added another line that
I want to hit as well.
To be sentimental or emotional now is
dangerous to one's self and to others.
And he continues to trust anyone or
to admit any hope of a better world.
It's criminally foolish,
as foolish as it is to
stop working for it.
So I, you know,
that's a little tangent, that's
a tangent, but it's powerful.
And like I said,
we'll get to Keith Douglas as book and
that book got published after the war and
unfortunately Keith Douglas never saw
that book get published because he was
killed by an enemy mortar fire on June
9th just a few days into the d day
invasion of Normandy,
which he took part in.
But again,
luckily he left us a a lesson
which is to control your emotions.
And I think as a,
as a person ended up as an individual,
if you can start trying to discriminate
between things that matter and things
that don't matter
and the way that you do that is
by detaching from everything.
And then you can pay attention to,
you can assess logically,
not emotionally what's
important and what's not and
you focus on the things that
matter and it's going to make
your entire life a lot easier.
It's a great lesson from Keith Douglas
and
I think that's all I've got for today.
I will say that speaking of lessons,
I've got a little lesson
to pass on in a book,
in a forthcoming book.
It's called Mikey and the dragons.
And
if you didn't hear about the book yet,
Miking the dragons about a young kid
that's scared of everything and that makes
his life pretty hard, pretty miserable
because he's scared of everything.
And one day he finds a book
and one day he, he scared of
everything he finds this book and,
and, and there's a book within the book
and the story and we'll go into the book
within the book right here real quick.
And then one day Mike,
he noticed a book,
he opened it up and took a quick look.
It had pictures of dragons with things
like a snake and all kinds of scary
things that made Mikey shake.
But in the pictures there was a boy too
who didn't look scared but like he knew
what to do.
And even though Mikey was scared in deed,
he decided that he would give the
book a read. He opened the first page,
which he eagerly read and this is what
the dragon book said there once was a
kingdom long ago and far away on the
kingdom had suffered a horrible day.
Their protector and leader there king,
he had died.
And when they found out the whole
village cried when the king was alive.
He was a powerful force.
Now they took the dead king
away by carriage and horse.
They knew they would miss
him and that made them sad.
But there was something else
that made them feel bad.
The king had always been so strong and
brave and protected the kingdom from the
Dragon Cave.
The Dragon Cave was just over the and
filled with scary dragons that were ready
to kill.
And the story continues from there and
explains that no one in the village in
the kingdom would stand up to the dragons
except the young prince who's only
seven years old.
And he's nervous and he's scared.
He's know if he can handle it,
but he kind of realizes
he's gonna have to step up.
So he goes to his father's war chest.
I'm so happy that I could put the word
war chest in a book and he finds the
shield and he finds the sword of his
dad and they're both super heavy.
But then he also finds a little note,
a little note from his father,
the king that explains how
to overcome the dragons.
So even though this book is aimed at kids,
I think we all know that we
all have dragons to fight.
And like I said on the last podcast,
I really wanted to get this book into
the hands of kids and really into the
hands of everyone.
But again,
my publisher told me that there was no
scenario where this book gets published
by November. So what did I do? Um,
I started my own publishing company
and the book will be out in November.
So yeah, it's, it's actually
getting printed at this time.
And in order to pull this off,
in order to actually know how
many books I need to print,
I think it already looks like I need to
print more books because you all ordered
a lot of them already. So thank you. Uh,
preorder so that I know what to print so
I can print enough of the sacred first
the dish.
If you want,
you and your kids and your family
to know how to crush their dragons.
Appreciate it. Uh, going to need
that. That's what's going to happen.
We're going to go forward together
and slay dragons in this case.
Who's the Dragon? Well, you know, big
publishing companies and sometimes,
uh,
anyways,
we all have our dragons to fight and
yeah,
when we fight our dragons, well I dunno,
maybe sometimes we could use some help.
Sure.
Echo.
Sometimes you don't even know any way
that we could maybe get some help fighting
on dragons. Yeah. So
dragons, the dragons. Sure.
Dragons. Sure. Our Dragon.
Yeah. So I'll tell you this,
this,
and this might help.
This will help actually if you realize
to the full extent that capability,
capability and knowledge that
will help you fight the dragons.
Those two things are
imperative in fighting. Yeah.
So we're staying on the path.
That's the capability part.
Actually the path is both at the street.
Half covers all, yeah. Capability,
knowledge,
always trying to improve.
So every step forward on the path
is a step forward in capability,
knowledge, check, check, as
opposed to the slippery slope,
which is a step backwards capability
and knowledge to be careful on that one.
Yes. So what, what capability, right?
This preparation, execution results,
right. Just made that up right now.
Literally couldn't, could be flawed,
but whatever. Sounds good to
me. So, so staying on the path,
what start would you do
to, of course, good place.
Did you do to good universal
kind of overarching. Yeah.
How many people hit you up a day?
That just started Jujitsu a lot.
And what I started doing,
trying to do is everyone that's,
that's indicating, they just
started. You'd get to first day,
you get to a second day, do you get
through, just got my kid into Judith.
I just retweet it and be like,
boom, you're in the game.
Just letting people know,
hey look, here's another person. All
different types of scenarios too,
by the way. Different types. Here's the,
here's what I run into his old 12
years old, 29 years old, bad back,
uh, you know, hurt elbow. I'm
a surgeon, I'm a firefighter,
I'm a police officer, I'm
a CEO. It doesn't matter.
Good. Jump in the game. Yeah.
All good. And every once in
a while we'll see this. Yes.
Got My kids into git. You
know, one of them, I hope,
I wish it was maybe a little
bit more into it, you know,
like what should I do or something
or whatever. Maybe not even that.
They just said
you jumped in there because a
lot of times it's like, oh yeah,
this is perfect for my kid. Oh
yeah. If she wants to jump in, if,
if you're, if you're taking your kids
to Jujitsu and you're not participating,
we've got an issue. Yeah. Let's, let's
at the very least just consider that.
Just consider it. Think you're saying
Japan. Yeah. Get it. Get it. Yeah man.
I had a,
a cool guy come into the gym here and
was in a police officer and he had his
kids all fired up. You know, all the
kids are into it. They're so fired up.
That's awesome. I was like, Oh, you know,
what class are you going to? He's like,
whoa. Guilt tripped him immediately.
Level seven guilt trip. I was like, Bro,
are you kidding me? Come on and get on
the mat. So he's in the game though. Yeah.
So, and, and that's not like
that rare of a story because,
and even just how our gym is laid out,
where you know the kids classes going on,
hey, just, just look right behind
you right now. Look right behind you.
That's not adults going on. Yeah. So
you can just let, let your kids go.
I know you want to watch the kids.
You want to see what up.
You want to see what's going on.
Don't worry about that.
They're going to be five of them. You
know they got it. They got it, Dave.
They got it. They got those kids on
lock unlock in a good way, by the way,
and just turned around.
There's just jumping down right there.
You're going to have as much fun as
your kid, by the way, if not more.
But the cluster, you're going
to have something in common
with your kid. Oh yeah.
In your, and tell you what, if you don't,
your kids going to be beating you
is going to be beating you up. Yuck.
Hey, the kids grow up. My
kids 15 my boy is 15 you know,
you better watch out. And we want,
I think there's a secret part of us,
if not overt part of us that wants
our kid one day to like question you,
stand up to you,
maybe confront you about some stuff,
some questions they have about you
and your whole thing is, you know,
I got to ask that the other
day. It's like, no it didn't.
It didn't really make you mad cause the
story and dichotomy leadership about the
patches, right to
patches, patches on Julio.
I told the guys no patches and Lafe and
Seth made patches anyways and brought
them in disguise like once
you like offended and weren't
you mad? And I was like,
no. Actually I was kind of
thinking to myself, wow, cool.
These guys have that little rebellious
streak that they need as leaders to tell
the man to stick to the man.
Yeah, that's fine with me.
Yeah. Yeah. It wasn't offensive.
They weren't doing some of those going
to get someone hurt or killed. They were,
they were just being little rebels.
You're just fine.
So do I want to see that with my
kids? Yes. I want to see a little bit.
Sometimes I needed to keep
that in food chair big time.
So if you're not doing, doing Jujitsu and
your kids are, especially if it's a boy,
well no girl, boy, whatever.
That the probability of them standing up
to you maybe a little earlier than you
expected is very high. That's what
I think. That's my hypothesis.
That's a good thing.
Not a bad thing. Yeah.
It will be a bad thing if you can't
do anything about it cause you're not
portraying kids.
Get good kids get good fast yet it's we,
it's funny because you get these
kids right who really get into it.
Then they grow up into adults. Sold
the belt system is kind of, it's like,
it's like planting a seed before the the,
the plant goes above ground.
There's a lot that goes on underground,
right? So some, you know, some plants,
you know the bamboo anyway,
there's a, what do you call
her? What do you call this?
Limericks I don't know.
Either way. There's an old
school story about the bamboo.
It takes like a bunch of
years when you plant it.
But once it breaks ground, it takes,
it shoots some super fast. Right?
That's all kids are what you,
so it's a put him in math and metaphors,
but that's an old common story
they say as a metaphor anyway.
So you put the kid in Jujitsu,
they really like it. And kids,
they get the belt though.
What are their belt? White.
And then you have these intermediary.
Yeah, the main ones are yellow,
white, yellow, orange. Green.
Gray has become a main one now
two grades become legit. Okay.
So you get up to green belt,
that's essentially the purple slash
brown belt of kids, the greenbelt.
Interesting. And then you can't get a blue
belt until 16 traditionally tradition.
So once you reach blue belt, you're
essentially a black belt for your body.
That's it. Your buddies like
right into puberty or whatever.
Here's the thing with, I don't completely
agree with you. Oh yeah. So yeah,
I dig it. I hear what you're
saying. But to your point,
usually 10 years to become a black belt
around if you're training hard and all
that.
And what you're saying as a kid could
start at five and now 16 gets his blue
belt. He's been trained in for
11 years. So to your point,
his skill level could be very, very high.
Yeah. So that's, yeah, you're right.
And I got into the story. So I said black
belt, maybe irresponsible. Either way.
When he hits blue belt, that's
not a normal adult blue. Oh No.
That is a kick ass blue belt to kill her.
So he's going to go, oh yeah, for, yeah,
my first time fighting his blue belt.
I'm 17 years old and he's beating
everyone super easy too, by the way.
And these are adults 25 26 years
old and he's just beating him.
So he gets his purple
belt right right away.
Unless he's in one of these situations
where they actually make you be blue bell
for two years.
He'll sometimes,
there's that like I think I'd be GGF
does that sometimes competing with anyway
anyway, when they, when they
reached ground, meaning adulthood,
when they reach above
ground like the bamboo,
they just shoot because all their
fundamentals are like, well they have,
they've developed like a
whole proprioception and
body understanding and it's
proprioception not just of their own body,
but if their opponent's body as well,
like they know where you're their opponent
is going to be. Yeah. Which is legit.
Big Tent on the path
of Jujitsu and Jujitsu,
the overall concept that we're
getting better. Yeah. Yeah.
It's very jujitsu heavy I think today,
but you know,
I haven't really been training that much
either way. Oh yeah. I'm on the path.
You're going to need a geek and a rash
guard. So people ask, where do we start?
What do I go?
Where do we go to get it?
[inaudible] go origin main.com boom.
He's, Oh, planty pick would it?
Whichever one is right for you.
They are all made in America by the way,
which you know, it seems like
common knowledge, but let's this,
this is your first introduction to
origin main.com boom. Now you know,
get a Gig, get a rash guard, jump on
the path to just to just jump in. Yeah.
Usually the first class is free
by the way. Most places. Yeah.
And a lot of people ask, Hey, I
need vice going to my first class.
Just go keep an open mind, have
fun, relax, do all those things.
Yeah.
A big one is like keep
your ears like open.
You know, don't, don't be that
guy like you always say this,
where don't be the guy. I'd be like,
what if I just do this kind of thing?
It doesn't work if you just go and
just listen, just listen in in time.
Hard to annoy.
I think that might be starting to
annoy me a little bit when people,
and I'm talking to a big group of people
that have never done jujitsu before and
someone throws out the
like, wait, what if,
you know what if they just grab your
arm right here? It's like, well,
there's 14 other moves
that you can do from that,
which I didn't get to because I'm trying
to teach you this fundamental thing
over here that you don't understand it
because you're an idiot and so yeah,
and that's the, yeah, I would say that.
Just keep that in mind. That's the advice.
If you, you know, what do I do
and keep your ears open, keep,
I don't want to discourage people
from asking questions, but let's just,
let's just think about how,
ask the questions,
right?
Yeah.
Don't ask it as a challenge to
the Canon of Jujitsu knowledge.
We're just the way some people ask it,
all you have to do is this. It's like, no,
actually, if you say like, hey,
sometimes he's doing this and
I don't know what to do yet.
That's why I'm going to tell you,
and I won't be annoyed at all,
have you tell me if you say it to me
like you just uncovered the secret key of
Jujitsu. I'm going to be slightly
annoyed. You won't know it,
but I'll just be like, oh yeah, well
here you go. Here's what you do.
So actually you mentioned the key to
defeating Jujitsu. You mentioned it.
What is times runaway you? Oh yeah, 100%
nobody can submit me if I'm running,
unless the house is true. Running is a
good self defense. He also had origin.
We got, we've got some
supplements at origin. Yes.
And we got joint warfare,
which will help you train every day.
We got
Krill oil,
which will also help you train every day
and those kind of compliment each other.
Then you have very much,
they very much to accomplish what I
didn't eat the whole mental like curcumin
and Krill oil, this big like massage
for your brain and getting everyone.
So anyways,
so try those.
Those we get great feedback on those
all the time. Also got the discipline,
which is for pre mission nutrition when
you need to do something both cognitive
and physical.
We got your back on this one.
A three scoops we've determined is
kind of the limit in my opinion.
I think it's kind of limited currently.
I would say that.
Have you ever taken like the old school
preworkout before Jujitsu? Oh No, no,
no. Don't take this stuff before. I've
done that before and it's horrible.
It's like the wrong wrong move.
I think if you, it cause your,
your heart's beating, you're all
amped up. It's just not good.
You can't think straight. You know,
discipline is not like that at all.
Three scoops. We'll get you right in
the zone where you want to be and,
but I think I haven't tried four scoops
cause I just think it would be crazy.
But I think four scoops would start to
lean towards too much either watch and
that that's the case with most things,
right? Where it's like, oh yeah,
two scoops is better than one. And it's
true. Three scoops even better than too.
Dang, that's true too. And
then that's the kind of
dichotomy you to find the balance.
The balance milk,
we got milk,
milk is milk protein,
whole milk because milk has protein in
it and we have multiple flavors now we
have mint chocolate, we have
peanut butter, chocolate,
we have vanilla gorilla,
we have the darkness,
just straight chocolate.
Which is surprisingly good by the way.
Why is that?
Are you surprised still right now?
Well, I am not surprised at all anymore.
We'll put it this way.
I'm not surprised in the capability
that it took to make it taste good.
I'm not saying that that was the hardest
one to make. It took us a long time.
We went through iteration. I so, so if it
surprise you, I guess I take that back.
Yeah, it is surprising how good
it is cause it's good. Yeah,
it's really good cause it's easy when
you think about it. You're like, okay,
chocolate mint. Okay good. I mean
as far as making that tastes good,
I'm not going to be that impressed
because come on, it's mint chocolate.
Let's face it. That's good. Good mint
or chocolate peanut butter. Same deal.
In fact, isn't it weird though,
as as good as those flavors are,
how come it's so how come it's been until
now that some going actually make them
taste the way they're supposed to taste?
It should be more impressed
than you are. Yeah. You know,
now that you break it down like that.
Sure. I think you're actually right.
I didn't think of that. I just
considered sure. So obvious,
but peanut butter in
anything in my opinion.
But it's going to make it taste good.
But if you're going to try to hit me with
a straight chocolate on something with
protein that's good for you, that
low in sugar? I'm like, yeah. Okay.
I'll give it a chance to in
one gram. Yeah. Uh, I was,
we went to, I went to
eat with my fam. Sure.
Telia and we were talking about,
we were just talking about food
and my daughter was like,
well sometimes she's like,
you just eat like one meal and then
you just have like nuts and bolts.
Cause cause I do, I eat
nuts. I get the big giant,
uh,
what do they call it?
The cans of mixed nuts that makes up
the container and I have some yeah.
Container to container. Yeah. And I
have just have like a handful of nuts.
I'm going to put some of them in a ball
and then I'm just doing that and milk.
And that's when you can't use the peanut
butter milk in my opinion. Too much.
Too much nuts get, I did
get, um, I, I don't agree,
but hey, I dig it man. Oh, you don't agree
that you can get too much peanut butter?
No. So, okay. Hey, one of the, you know,
those huge things of peanut butter,
the biggest one.
You buy it from the big box store
files. Yeah. MOCA is
good protein on Nolan.
And I'll tell you what,
now we just came out with warrior
kid milk and get the right thing and,
and truly this is awesome and I'll tell
you why it's awesome because kids need
good food.
Kids need healthy food and they're not
going to eat healthy food if it tastes
like junk.
And so we made warrior kid milk.
There's a little less protein
in it. There's only, uh,
only 11 groups because there's 11
grams of protein for, for the kids.
There's probiotics, there's vitamins,
there's one gram of sugar, which is,
which is not even sugar.
It's something else.
Whatever is one gram of sugar in there.
Um,
and it tastes awesome.
Strawberry and chocolate.
The chocolate's delicious.
The strawberry is kind of next level.
The strawberry is so good.
It tastes like someone took the ultra
high end ice cream and made you a
milkshake with it. Strawberry
style. That's what it tastes like.
Your kids are going to love it and you're
going to love it. That's the problem.
I mean the problem is
that's not a problem.
The reality is I've had
strawberry milk warrior kits,
strawberry milk like for desert
three meals in a row right now.
The last three meals I had strawberry
milk every time. Why is that?
Tastes good and it's good. It's
awesome for you. This is a revolution.
I am not going to throw this out there
like like just throw this one out there.
There's a revolutionary thing,
but can you imagine,
I think this is the first product in
the history of the world that I can
personally think of. You tell me if
you can think of something else. Okay.
This is the first product that I can
think of in the world that the kids are
going to want to have it as much as the
parents are going to want them to have
it.
I don't know of any other thing like that.
What other thing is like that big kids
want to have it as bad as the parents
because the kids want ice cream.
They want it bad. The kid,
the parents don't want to have it. Right.
The parents want the kids to have, uh,
the vitamin pill.
The kids don't want to have it.
This is a universal want.
Yeah. It's delicious
and it's awesome for the kids.
So I'm super stoked because it's cool
when kids want to be on the warrior kid
path, but they don't have
good food. Easily accessible.
This is going to replace
all them little Chocolatey,
sugary drinks that parents
had been forced to do.
Feed their young children and poisoned
them no more. Those days are over.
So get on the milk train.
Yeah.
We'll kinda get your warrior kids on
the block train as well. Yeah. The,
that strawberry one.
It's funny because I don't,
when I go to wherever to get a milkshake,
I don't get this job here. No, no, no, no.
Neither would I. But I mixed up
the street, you know, I got some,
everyone's excited. There's
been some hype and uh, you know,
so I'm like, all right, we'll see what
up. Me and my son, whatever. He's too,
by the way. Uh, so yeah, it makes
it up or whatever. And you know,
I taste it and probably date, you know
how something will bring you right back.
Oh, you're a kid, the
strawberry, whatever. That's,
I think that's the last time I really
got into a strawberry stuff back then.
Right back.
And then there's the readymade strawberry
milk that used to get when you were a
kid.
And let's face it that that is a whole
memory section in your brain that
remembers that it's looking for it.
Sometimes you go into a seven 11,
you see one of those,
you're like nick.
And now that I am straight up milk, same
the strawberry milk right there. Yeah.
It's probably tastes better
because it's got a little bit,
it's a little bit thicker, you know, it's
got a little bit more a milkshake. Yeah.
We're going to have to come
up with strawberry of Mocha
adult too with a little
bit more protein just for GP because
the GP is good. But in the meantime,
get that warrior kits strawberry
bringing you rent and the warrior kit
chocolate's good too. It's, it's
awesome. Well, I prefer the chocolate.
I'm just saying the strawberry brought
you back saying it was good. I like it.
Obviously my son, my son drink most of
it, but you know he's too, he's too.
Yes sir. How's his, what? What's his
bicep workouts looking like or a solid?
He actually has a video of him dead
lifting one of the kettle bells.
The audit was dope.
Yeah,
too good form to kids have surprisingly
natural. Good form. Yeah. What's up?
They get broken down over time by society.
Got To fight against it. All right,
let's roll. No, no. Like what
else? I'm all good. Uh, also what,
where he could monkey already said that
and that's that. We have our own store.
So that's something. Yeah. If you want
to represent, you want to get a shirt?
You want to get a Hoodie?
I'm going to get a hat. Uh,
more rash guards on there. More, more
specific direct messages on the ref.
Rash guards for staying on the
path. Go to Jocko, store.com also,
you can get tee shirts because not
everyone wears rash guards all the time.
Like John Donahoe. Yes. Let's
just wear regular. Hey, I'm down.
We gotta to send John Donner some,
some of these things. Yeah. But yeah,
that's where it is. Jocko. store.com.
Good shirts on their new shirts on there
by the way. Oh, interesting. Um, shoot,
I've been meaning to sort
of send everybody an email,
kind of letting them know cause there's
a few of them. I'll do that check.
Do that also got, uh, hats. Yeah.
For those of you that like flex fit hats
there, they're available. They're dope.
For those of you that like truckers hats,
they're also available.
And hoodies, legit hoodies, legit,
heavy, heavy. And do we,
do we have any Hawaiian on their left?
No. Hawaiian or uh, you know, hey.
Yeah, no, not as of right now. No. Okay.
But maybe in the summer we'll make
the Hawaiian one again or maybe the,
the winner for the actual light people.
Oh yeah, true. Got To get it home.
So that's good. Yeah. Some women's stuff
on there too, by the way. Some new, uh,
it's more a women's stuff
for the female troopers. Yes.
Specifically in the house. Uh,
remember subscribed to this podcast,
iTunes, Google play, stitcher,
leave review. So I can read them.
So echo can read them,
but mostly so I can read them.
I want the feedback that
goes over there. Cruz. Well,
I get addicted to reading
those when they're funny.
They're when they're interesting,
but usually the interesting ones by
interesting, I mean funny. Yeah. Good.
Very good. Uh, and also don't forget
about the warrior kid podcast.
Nothing but great feedback
on the warrior kid podcast.
People listening to it over
and over and over again.
Partially because they love it.
Partially because I haven't
put out enough episodes.
So we got a little intense time period.
Books coming out and all that.
But we're kind of getting through that.
So I'll be able to get back on the
path of making the warrior podcast.
Matter of fact, I'm almost done
with a story from Uncle Jake.
Good story from Uncle Jake. A
real big lesson learned. Oh,
that'll be on the warrior kid podcasts.
So subscribe to that one as well.
And don't forget about that.
Warrior kids soap from
Irish oaks ranch.com we've
got young aid and a warrior
kid running his own business.
Age 13 making money,
making product made in America,
made with goat milk.
What else do you need to know other
than get some soap and stay clean.
Also get the youtube youtube videos.
Now we are stepping up our game.
I know we've been talking
about this for a long time.
Some of it's just been in the form
of harassment, harassing echo,
but we actually are making preparations.
Training is underway.
People are coming on board,
things are happening.
We're moving in the right direction.
And so youtube, subscribe to
Youtube. We're going to start.
We're going to use that
platform even more.
Yeah, get it out there. Yes.
Utilizing spreading good messages
to keep people on the path.
Sometimes to get people on the patterns.
Psychological warfare. Speaking of the
path, a little help staying on the path.
These are little tracks about overcoming
your own personal individual weaknesses
at one time or another.
Yes.
So you get that album and you
press play in certain scenarios.
We're working on assembling
psychological warfare to,
yeah, probably going to be
called. All your excuses are lies
and that one will come
out before Christmas.
We'll get it to you before
Christmas. Yeah. Yeah.
We should be able to get
it to you before Christmas.
Yeah.
In time for the New Year's resolutions,
the as they develop as they develop,
she didn't know your anti
new year's resolution. I am.
From what I understand. No,
that's a just another day to
me. No, don't worry on my part.
If I was going to make a resolution,
you know, and I'd start it right now.
Why would I wait? No,
now, not even today, now,
not later today that after dinner.
No, get it done now. All right,
well it can still technically be a year's
resolution because you could just be
like boom, like from now on
for the next year again, eh,
that doesn't really fit either way. I dig
what you're saying and cool men do it.
Speaking of staying on the path on
it.com/jocko actually there it is on it to
stay on it on it. And when he,
when they named it on the path,
that's what they had it in reference to.
I know that 100% for a fact
get your fitness stuff.
That's how you stay on the path.
You bring the gym to your house. You
said this, you said this earlier,
I still have a 24 hour fitness
membership by the way. Yeah.
And I go to 24 hour fitness
every once in a while. But,
but having this stuff at home, we'll
keep you on the path like hardcore. Yeah.
So get your kettle bells when you do
kettle bells. When you do kettlebells,
kettlebells,
I do kettlebells.
Everyone that I know that's
on the path does kettlebells.
I'm not saying if you don't do
kettle bells, you're not on the path.
I'm not saying that.
I'm saying if you're on the path
and you don't do kettle bells,
consider getting
kettlebells for your house.
And when you do go to on it.com to get
them cause there's cooler in my opinion,
that's the only ones I got go there.
There's a lot of cool stuff on there.
Some clothes on there too.
If you want a lot of information
as well on it.com/and Jocko.
By the way, it's a good
spot. Also Jocko white tea.
Speaking of bringing
the gym to your house,
you better bring 8,000 pounds anyway
if you drinking Jocko white tea. Yes,
it is proven. People ask me is
that for real? 8,000 pounds a year.
A hundred percent a hundred
percent one ton is 2000 pounds.
Tonight you will be able to dead lift
and you only have to drink one too,
by the way.
I drink the camp.
Yeah. Yeah. And sometimes people say,
well I could only dead lift, you know,
four 85 and I'm like Drake, Morty. I
remember I used to be like that too.
I dig it. But yeah. Hey it even got
Jordan B. Peterson. Yeah. Office.
He was plateaued at 7,000 pounds.
God knows how long he was stuck
there that week level. I know.
Then he got right up to 8,000 pounds
t you know what the fuck?
What's funny about not what's funny?
What's interesting first episode
of this podcast.
Oh Yeah,
we talk about pomegranate Chai.
Yeah. You say pomegranate, Jada.
No, whatever tea that you're into,
cars, because that was the first one.
You made this weird kind of
easing into this podcast starting,
which wasn't really what I had in mind.
You know, I had more mine like, Hey, okay,
we press record, we start, you had a,
you know, we're cruising over here.
We'll just kind of be, well, yeah,
well the part cost has begun now,
but as a result of different mindset,
as a result,
there's that added layer for the people
that did listen to that first few
seconds of that first first episode.
You say palm or we say pomegranate Chai,
you see no pomegranate white tea.
Yeah. And then look at,
you look at, you now,
Meet Your own pomegranate white tea.
People would ask me all the time what
kind of tea and I wouldn't really be able
to tell him because I try. I would try
different ones. No one was perfect,
so I just went and made the perfect one.
I mean drill. Yeah. That's how you did.
We have it on our website too, by the
way. Jocko. store.com we offer it there,
but you can get it anywhere. Yeah.
Yeah. Amazon too. Amazon has this stuff.
Amazon prime for the cans.
Save yourself a little shipping.
You're on Amazon Prime TV. Then you've
got that also on Amazon and everywhere.
You can buy books. We got
some, we got some books.
I got way the warrior
kid and Mark's mission.
Those are part of a series and those will,
those are good books for
your children as a parent.
They want how many? I don't know
how many people have told me this.
These books have made parenting easier for
them because now they just
look at the kid and say, Hey,
what did you think this is a water warrior
kid would do you think a warrior kid
would eat that donut? Right
now? I don't think so.
Do you think that warrior
kid would leave with wood?
Would leave the room all dirty?
I don't think so. I think
it's like, no, no, no way.
I got parents and say their kids,
they don't know where your
kid wouldn't do that. Yeah.
Like when they read warrior kid,
their voice goes from like, Hey dad,
what do you think we're
going to do to like, Hey dad,
I don't think we should do that. Sounds
like weakness to me. Case in point today.
So my daughter, she's sensitive. I
wouldn't say thins getting a lot.
I don't know if it's thin skin sensitive,
whatever.
So like if you say something mean to her
as like if another kid says something
mean, that's something to
her. Super Nice to everybody.
So a kid called her a liar.
Oh,
but apparently that's this kid's thing.
He just calls people liar.
Like you've got to good
reaction out of it. Some point,
some dude ain't know he got
one each it to some point.
At some point somebody's acting all
crazy and he's like, okay, not now.
I know how to make people really not
know how to get a reaction. Yeah.
So she doesn't like that, you know?
Cause she lying was kind of the thing.
My Dad always kind of, we
would get spankings for
lying. That's pretty much it.
That's a big violation of the whole
thing sold, you know? So as a result,
not to say I spanked her for lying.
I'm not saying that,
but she doesn't like the
whole line or she gets a cute,
you know how like she'll do
something, I'll be like, hey,
did you brush your teeth?
She'll be like, yes, I don't be like,
and then you go smooth. She'd be like,
oh my gosh. She'll get devastated
if I think she's lying.
She's a good check for Rod
toothbrushes. Wet or dry? No. See I get,
I go deep. I just lie to me.
We're going to see what he did.
But see what you do though.
Like if I go and investigate
that indicates to her
she's fine. Lack of trust.
Yeah. Like, you think I'm lying and
she gets really sad. So anyway, well,
what I'm saying is she's sensitive to
that kind of stuff, just manipulating you.
That's a very possible to
do. Or if they're good, you
know, kind of watch them.
Yes you do. Anyway, so at school she
was like, Hey, that's the boy. He call,
he calls me liar. And another day
he called her a liar every day.
Like that's his name, like you're a
liar every day. So one of my things,
I have to go too deep into it. I
tell her, hey, you're a nice person.
So you'd be nice to people whether
they're mean to you or not.
So you're just a nice person.
You don't like become a mean person
cause they'd be meeting. She goes, well,
I really don't like to be called a liar.
I was like,
would you rather be called
a liar or plate face?
And then she started laughing because
she remembers that's how he gets over it.
He laughs at himself, calls himself plate
face. You know, Nathan, he's over there.
He's all kind of laughing, confused, like
Oh, that's funny. And they laugh about it.
Then they slowly become friends. So she
was like, boom, weight. Less bothered.
That was today, and I'm not even joking.
It was today when I dropped her off.
Awesome. So that's where
awarded kid and Mark's mission.
We also got discipline
equals freedom field manual.
This is the book that what's great
about this one. People tell me,
I read two pages every day.
I read three pages every day.
I wake up in the morning and
read one page. Get yourself
on the path, get your mind right
as my boy Matthews to say. Yep,
up in Yosemite, dig it. He hit
me up on Twitter. By the way,
I'm going to track him down. And so that's
just one equals freedom field manual.
Christmas time.
Good gift for someone.
You want to put someone on the
path? Cool. Give them that book.
Don't even say anything. Don't
even, don't even introduce it.
Just give them that book and just let it,
let it ride.
Because when you open it up,
you're going to open it.
You have to open it up because it looks
it's not normal, and when you open it up,
you see that's not normal either.
It's not just a bunch of like black
print on a white page. No, no.
It's different. So he started flipping
through it. Then you start saying,
wait a second, this makes sense to
me. I did. The next thing you know,
you wake up and it's not
seven 42 it's four 48
seven 42 is still pretty good.
I think it depends on who you are.
That's the discipline equals freedom
field manual. After that wealth,
not after that, but the first
book, extreme ownership.
There's a book about combat leadership
and you got the dichotomy of leadership,
which just came out dichotomy.
Leadership, by the way,
by the way,
extreme ownership number five right
now on the Wall Street Journal business
books list. The number one book on
that list is dichotomy leadership.
So thanks to everyone for getting those
books and much appreciate that support.
I already talked about Mikey and
the dragons. It's coming out.
It's coming out on Jocko publishing.
So if you want it,
order it right now, it's just
up on Amazon. So go to Amazon,
go to go to Jocko podcast.
You can click through and
get Mike in the dragon.
Some people were having a little
trouble finding it. It's there.
Get it also Ashkelon Front.
This is our leadership consultancy.
We solve problems through leadership. It's
me, Leif, Babin, JP to Nell, Dave Burke,
Flynn Cochran,
Mike's Rally and also Mike Bama.
Don't call a speaking agency.
We don't like that.
Does email echelon front info national
on front.com or check out our website
muster San Francisco, sold out. Um,
the only good news I have for you is
that there will be more musters pay
attention. I'll put the word out
through the social media or whatever.
Also EFO Overwatch.
This is connecting special operations
veterans and leaders and combat aviation
veterans and leaders to companies that
need experienced proven leaders that
understand the principles
of extreme ownership.
Go to e f Overwatch to get in that game.
And if you want to keep cruising with us,
you can find us on the interwebs,
on, on Instagram and
on Facebook. Keep well,
echo is an echo.
Charles and I am at Jocko Willink and
thanks to everyone out there in uniform.
Thanks for your sacrifice and your
vigilance here at home and abroad as well.
We know what you do every
day and we thank you for it.
And to everyone else,
remember the words of Keith Douglas.
To trust anyone or admit any hope of
a better world is criminally foolish.
As foolish as it is to
stop working for it.
Keep working for it.
Do your part every day to become stronger,
faster,
smarter,
better to try and make the
world a little bit better.
Keep working for it and
keep getting after it.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.