This is Jocko podcast number
29 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink.
Okay.
Into the midst of this war torn land
were inserted 22 able bodied American
soldiers and the platoon leader.
As I made my way to the platoon command
post c p the sun had already dropped
from the sky night in the tropics
comes fast and even as I approached the
outgoing platoon leader,
the shadows had begun to
obscure his facial features.
I found him lying on his
stomach in a depression,
situated roughly in the
center of the platoon.
As I bent over to introduce myself,
he motioned for me to get down,
assuming that perhaps I was dangerously
exposed. I laid down next to him.
Hello, I'm Jim Mcdonough. I said,
feeling somewhat awkward,
being so formal while lying on my stomach.
Tom Rolf,
he said,
are you here to take my place?
He was unable to conceal his
eagerness. Yes, I replied,
can you tell me what's going on here?
As he began briefing me,
it became apparent that the platoon
was not the object of his thoughts.
I asked questions about the
disposition of the squads,
the personalities of the men,
the tactics of the enemy,
the attitude of the villagers.
He responded by telling me
about how difficult the job was,
how much his family needed him, how he
never asked to be an infantry lieutenant,
how dangerous,
not an honorable his life had been of
late and how he did not deserve to be
wounded or killed.
Yeah.
He was overcome by fear that
on his last night in the field,
the enemy would somehow
snatch survival away from him.
As the hours passed,
we did not move from our position.
In the midst of the platoon.
I became acutely conscious
of our protected posture,
all about us.
I could hear movement.
I saw silhouettes of soldiers as they
moved about setting up their positions for
the night. I noted that at least one
patrol departed from the perimeter,
but that the orders for the patrol
did not come from the Lieutenant
Ralph lay.
They're chattering aimlessly into the
night describing again and again for me,
the wife and two children
he had left behind.
Okay.
Gradually he honed in on his point.
You've got to understand, I did
this for them. They need me.
They need me in one piece,
nervous silence followed as I tried
to find his eyes in the darkness.
What was he talking about?
The question or rose.
Even as the answer was forming all
around me, they know what to do.
They're good soldiers.
Silence again.
He was shocked by his own confession,
but at the same time he was urged
on by the bearing of his soul.
I could have been a hero
sometimes I even wanted to be,
but I had to think of my
family. You See, don't you?
Most of these men don't have
any family there. Just boys.
The shamefulness of his
words hit me like a club.
He was not the leader of this platoon.
He felt no responsibility for the mission.
He fell no compassion for his men.
In his mind.
The other members of the platoon existed
for only one reason to protect him,
to keep him alive. They
were expendable. He was not.
He had reason to live.
They did not
okay.
I wanted to crawl away, but it was
dark and I had no idea where to go.
We stopped talking.
I had nothing more to ask.
He wanted to say more about
his personal concerns.
He knew he had gone too
far but he didn't care.
His only concern in the world was to
leave that knoll as soon as possible.
The platoon and I could
be damned if he survived.
Justice would have been done that night.
Nothing else mattered for him.
His soul lay naked, stripped
of pride, guilt and shame.
They were affections of the
civilized world out here,
only living mattered,
unable to sleep,
unable to move.
I lay there wondering which I would turn
out to be the crazed killer I had met
and Q non with a blatant
coward beside me in the dark,
which one was more devoid of humanity.
I did not know.
Later after almost three months
in the field, I saw a for again
at the battalion secure behind the
battalion perimeter of Lz north English.
He had adopted an air of bravado
and the safety of the officers club.
He told me of his brave deeds,
he taught as one who had
seen it all in his own words,
he became the dashing,
fearless leader of combat infantry men.
He even had a few combat awards for valor,
the procurement of which
fell among his duties,
but the most amazing thing
of all was his beliefs.
Belief in every one of his own words as
far as he consciously knew he was all he
claimed to be.
He had forgotten how he laid,
quivering in the dark,
praying for the enemy not to come.
Okay.
From that point on,
I began to watch myself carefully.
Was I really what I thought I was or had
I deluded myself as effectively as Raul
Fad.
Okay.
In the morning,
the helicopter came to take Ralph away.
He brought himself to his knees,
which is as high as I had seen him rise
since my arrival the night before and
without a word of farewell
to me or any of the soldiers,
he made a desperate
dash for the helicopter.
Okay.
In an instant,
he was gone and I recognized with a
feeling of awe that I was now in command.
Good Evening Echo.
Good evening.
Well back in Vietnam the night.
Hmm.
And this book right here
is called platoon leader.
A memoir of command in combat
by James are make Dunno.
He served,
he went to West Point,
so four years at west point and then
he got assigned to the hundred 73rd
airborne brigade in Vietnam.
And one thing about this book,
and this is a
a fantastic book and I'll tell you there's
a quote on the back of the book here.
It's the Marine Corps Gazette wrote,
this stands alone is the finest statement
of what it means to be the commander
of a small unit.
I hope that every platoon leader reads
ponders and truly absorbs the words of
Lieutenant Colonel Mcdonald.
Okay.
So it starts off there.
That was him going to this
small little perimeter,
but platoon perimeter outside
of a village in Vietnam,
he's taking over from the outgoing
platoon commander. And again,
this is something very different than
we do in the seal teams where you just
have a random new guy show up,
it's going to take charge.
We're lucky the way we're set up.
We do like an entire workup and prepare
for deployment with the same guys we're
going to be on deployment with and
then we all go on deployment together.
We work together and when and
deployments over we go home.
It's a very solid way of running
that system. This is different.
There's guys trickling in and out all
the time throughout the entire chain of
command,
all the way up from the frontline guys
all the way up to the commander of the
platoon.
Hmm.
Fresh out of west point.
Fresh out of college. Yeah.
It's a military college, but it shows up
in Vietnam. Then here he is in the bush.
Back to the book,
I was alone.
That was my first sensation as a leader.
I gathered up my belongings,
my weapon, web gear and rucksack
and move toward the command post.
I needed a few minutes to gather my
thoughts before I made my debut as platoon
leader. I knew it was going
to be a tricky business.
I had assumed that I would ever have
a company commander nearby to give me
orders, but I had not even met him
yet. I would not meet him for weeks.
So that's the guy who was above the
platoon commanders. The company commander,
you know in his mind he thinks is
going to have this company commander or
somewhere nearby him mentoring him and
tell him what to do. Not Happening.
Doesn't have any even hasn't even met him.
He's taken over the platoon.
He hasn't even met the company commander
yet. I would not meet him for weeks.
The fact was I was totally on my own.
What should I do?
Whose advice could I ask? The platoon
sergeants, the squad leaders in time,
I would listen to their ideas,
incorporate them with my own,
but I could hardly begin with, well, what
do you think we ought to do? Men? No,
I knew that the basic
decisions were mine to make.
Now I might go in that situation a little
bit different and I wouldn't have any
problem asking platoon sergeants
and asking squad leaders, hey guys,
what's going on? Getting some
feedback from them. What's
been working, what's not?
I don't think there's any, I don't think
there's anything wrong with that at all.
He took a little different tact.
He didn't feel comfortable doing that
and you know,
one of the reasons why he didn't feel
comfortable doing that because he's young,
he's fresh out of college
and he's a little nervous.
Stepping into this combat role.
Obviously
back to the book,
the first few moments would be crucial.
Obviously I was the object
of interest that morning.
Everyone was wondering what the new
tech new lieutenant would be like and I
would be telling them with my first
words, my gestures, my demeanor,
my eyes.
So he knows that everything he does,
they're watching him
and they're judging him.
I would have no grace period in
which to learn my way around.
This was a life and death environment.
If I began with a blunder,
my credibility as a leader would be
shot and so might some of the men.
I decided to begin by giving
my attention to tactics.
In a military environment,
everything is determined by tactical
considerations where you sleep,
when you sleep, where you go, what you do,
and in those company you do it
all or dictated by underlying
tactical necessities.
I would communicate my style of leadership
through my tactical instructions.
Pretty good call,
pretty good call.
Let's just talk tactics,
something that we're all familiar with.
The first thing that occurred to me was
the necessity of sending out patrols.
If our actions were strictly defensive,
the enemy would be free
to pick their tactics.
The initiative would be theirs and this
would eventually disprove the illusion
of security that the
perimeter wire offered.
My training told me that a completely
defensive unit is a prime target for an
overwhelming attack. Boom, so he
knows that out of the gate, again,
they've got this nice little perimeter
set up. They've got 30 or so guys there.
They've got to defend this
perimeter from attack,
but instead of just staying in
a defensive position, he's like,
we got to go out on patrol.
We got to get out there.
We've got to disrupt
what the enemy's doing
and combat leadership as in real estate.
Location is everything.
I was the platoon leader and the
patrolling would be done by squad size
elements.
Normally there were 10 men in the squad
and four squads in a rifle platoon
for personnel. Strengths being
what they were. My squad's,
we're down to only six or seven men of
peace and there were only three squats.
I would be risking over supervision of
the patrolling squad who's direction was
better left to the squad leader.
If I went with it,
I would also be away from the majority
of my platoon back at the perimeter.
On the other hand,
to stay with this two squads
in the perimeter would deny
me the knowledge of the
terrain in which the my platoon operated
and the opportunity to evaluate the
quality of the patrols, the
major offensive activity
of my tactical position.
Moreover,
I would not be sharing the highest risk
operations of my men and would therefore
might lose their respect.
I also might miss my best chance to
appreciate their perceptions, needs,
and attitudes.
Finally,
I might slip into a
defensive attitude myself,
and that attitude will eventually
overtake the entire platoon.
So basically there aren't
there inside that perimeter.
He's got three squads and he's sending
the one squad out on patrol on a fairly
regular basis, and he's, the question
is, you know, where should I go?
What should I do?
And then he decides that the best thing
for him to do is rotate through and go
on patrol with them sometimes.
And I love the point of,
of moreover I would not be sharing in
the highest risk operations of my men.
So he knows he's got to take some
of the risks that they're taking.
That will also give them a chance
to appreciate their perceptions,
needs and attitudes.
So if you're in a leadership position
and you never get down to the frontline
troopers and see what they're doing,
see what they're doing on the job site,
see they're doing in the field
and see what's going on out there.
You can't understand it.
And then he says this,
finally I might slip into a
defensive attitude myself.
And that attitude would
eventually overtake the entire
platoon cause they're all
gonna turn into what he's
turned into or what he is.
Back to the book.
If a patrol made contact with the enemy
and it lasted for any length of time,
a second squad would be sent to react.
If I were inside the
perimeter at such a time,
I would move out with the reaction squad.
I firmly believed it was the duty of the
combat leader to move to the sound of
the guns,
especially when a majority
of the unit was engaged.
So he's going to be there when
things go sideways. He's gonna move.
Now,
back to his feelings on what this is like,
even more on inspiring than the scenery
was the realization that whatever took
place in this part of the world,
whatever these men did or whatever
happened to them was my responsibility.
I might describe myself
as a long for the ride,
but whatever happened here or back at the
perimeter, I would have to account for,
to my superiors,
to my men and to myself.
I felt I was living a lie.
I was trying desperately to learn
what I was already supposed to know.
So the reason he's talking about that
is when he goes out with the squads,
there's a guy that's junior to him,
a sergeant that's running the
squad that's running the patrol,
and he's not going to go out
there and and be the boss.
He's going to go out there sort
of along for the ride. You know,
he's not going to take
charge of the squad.
He's going to let them do what they do
and he's going to be more of an observer,
but he's, but that doesn't relinquish
any responsibility from him.
He still owns it. He's still taking
owner ship of the whole thing.
And this statement about,
I felt I was living a lie.
I was trying to desperately to learn
what I was already supposed to know.
That's very common for anybody stepping
up into new leadership position.
You don't think you're ready for it.
I mean often sometimes you feel confident,
but a lot of times people, when people
hit me up with questions, they say,
you know what,
I'm taking,
I've been promoted and I don't
think I'm ready to do that job.
There's some very common to feel like that
and my statement, I've said it before,
it's okay. Yup. You know,
there's a cognitive bias that
when you're a real smart person,
you don't think you're that smart,
but when you're not that smart,
you think you're smart. Oh yeah.
100% of the country just,
we had these,
we had these forms that
we used to make the,
the leaders in the seal platoons fill out.
They would rank themselves one,
you know, one being the lowest
score, five being the highest score,
and they'd grade themselves on whatever,
10 15 different items.
Tactical knowledge,
uh,
ability to lead understanding
of the troops are understanding
of the tactics and
they had to grade themselves on
everything. Yeah. And 100% of the time,
100% of the time, I don't make that
claim very often. Oh, 100% of the time.
The guys that graded them,
so the guys that were really good,
really good leaders and really stepped
up and really doing a great job,
they'd give themselves a grade.
They're great.
Average would be like a solid 2.7
day. He'd be like, Oh, you know,
I could get better at this
and I could do better here.
The guys that were not good,
they were not good leaders
and their platoons were
struggling. Literally they're,
they're great.
Average would be 5.0 they would gave
themselves a five and everything their
self,
that's arrogance just completely crushes
your ability to do a self assessment.
Yeah. Unbelievable. Interesting.
Back to the book,
back at the platoon base,
I busied myself learning more about the
tactical position and the personality of
the men. There was a distance
between us in those first hours.
I was not sure of their soldier
leanness and they were not sure of my
leadership.
Fair enough.
Little little mutual assessment
going on right there.
Now they're out on a patrol and there's a,
one of the, one of the guys
spots, a guy named done,
he spots somebody and he sorta
gets ready to engage and uh,
Mcdonald's says, what
are you doing? And He,
and the sergeants reply was short VC.
I mean,
these are Vietcong.
He says,
I felt it was time for me
to assert myself. I will
not allow the squad to fire.
I did not see any weapons.
And regardless of the political
leanings of the older man,
the boy to my way of thinking deserved
a little more consideration. Hold off.
I said to done his look,
spoke a thousand words.
He wasn't accustomed to
being second guessed.
Not only had he been a squad leader,
he had been leading the entire platoon.
And the reason he says that
is because in the, the, uh,
the old platoon commander who was weak
and was hiding this guy done was out
there making stuff happen.
And now I was challenging him.
My decision was made and I couldn't
back away. If I relinquished my command,
the squad would open fire. Both the
man and the boy were as good as dead.
Maybe done was right. What
did I know? I was a newcomer.
If I let him give orders, the
consequences were his, if I gave orders,
they were mine. No, I decided either way,
the consequences were mine.
I was the senior man.
Even if I look the other way,
I would have sanctioned the killing.
I stared back at done.
So
he's taken ownership.
One might even say he's taking extreme
ownership of the situation and despite
even if the other guy makes a decision,
he owns it because he's
the senior guy out there.
Now they're continue,
so they let those guys live and now
they're continuing the patrol and back to
the book,
I sensed a slight poll on my right
fit foot and pivoting to my left.
I took a broad step.
The roaring in my ear was tremendous as
if in a dream I began floating in the
direction of my last step. It was
still a warm, beautiful, clear day.
Yet somehow I didn't
seem to be there anymore.
I was going off into a deep sleep,
although my eyes were wide open and I
could see the soldiers in front of me
exactly as they had been a moment ago.
I continued to float,
how graceful I felt,
sensing everything in slow motion.
I saw the ground rising to meet my chest.
What a perfect landing.
It was the ground
sliding up underneath me.
Then I heard that I rose again rebounding
from the impact and a below of of soft
fine dust particles. Again,
I ease down into the dirt,
sending a second thicker cloud of
brown debris rising around my face and
outstretched hands abruptly.
The pace of my thoughts quickened as
the surrealistic affects left my God,
we've been hit. Then the pace
increased to normal. Oh No, it's me.
I felt sick to my stomach.
I thought I would vomit and I
made my first deliberate movement.
Since the explosion had gone off
in my ear from my prone position,
I jerked my head to the left
and gaped at my legs. Oh,
be there.
Please be there.
They were there bleeding and torn,
but they were there.
I was so happy. I wanted to
shout with joy. I was euphoric.
So he's walking and it's a booby trap.
That description is eerily similar to
Jody medics description of getting blown
up and yeah, I mean he, this, this, uh,
Mcdonald.
I ended up in a little bit
better situation in the
fact that he kept his legs.
But Jodi, the way Jody describes that
in his book is very similar. You know,
just boom and
horrible situation.
Back to the book.
A wounded leader is still a
leader unless so incapacitated.
He can't make decisions.
I wasn't that bad off and I found it
somewhat consoling to assert myself as the
man in charge. At the very
least, it staved off the
shock that would come later.
So they get it,
they get him out of there and
he's on a stretcher. Anyways,
lying naked on a stretcher,
suspended between two chairs,
I began to suffer the
first sensations of shock.
I began to shake so severely and I
thought once again I was going to vomit.
I was also afraid of
defecating where I lay.
I was so overcome with self pity that
for a second I caught myself starting to
shed a tear.
The morphine was having its effect and
I was not in full control of my emotions
more than anything. I was scared.
I was no longer afraid I would die.
I was afraid,
afraid because I could have died.
My heart was racing my body trembling,
the ringing in my ear confused my drug
thinking even more and I couldn't focus
my thoughts.
I only knew I had completely failed.
In my first attempt to lead a
combat action, the West Pointer,
the paratrooper,
the ranger he had lasted less than 48
hours blown up by his own blundering
footwork and ill considered decisions.
How in glorious at all seemed
lying there in my nakedness,
two ears on the ground for
48 hours and this happens.
Go in and take over the platoon calling.
The other guy a coward
basically goes out on is,
I think it's this was his third patrol.
He had done two other patrols.
Nothing happened on those other patrols
and then boom, it gets blown up.
Now he's in the hospital for other
wounded soldiers, came aboard.
One was gut shot and about
four inches of his stomach.
We're poking out of his middle.
He shielded his wounds with his hands
as he walked out to the chopper.
One American Armored Cavalry platoon had
just been been ambushed in the five oh
six valley south of bongs song and nine
bloated and charred but still alive.
Soldiers were brought
in in place next to me.
They smelled awful and their pain
was excruciating, mercifully,
some were unconscious,
but those awake we're
screaming the violent shaking.
I had experienced that to Lz.
English was rampant among the group.
I was grateful to be an infantry man.
I wouldn't want to travel in gasoline
fed machines that invariably exploded and
burned when hit.
A Vietnamese soldier had been brought
in and placed ahead of me signifying the
greater severity of his wounds.
He too had been gut shot and apparently
his stomach and intestines had
completely spilled out.
His stomach lay quite exposed,
but his intestines still attached had
been dumped into a sand bag which was tied
creek purely to his thigh.
When he was brought in,
he was unconscious,
but after a while he came to,
I saw him lift his head
and stare at the sandbag,
what he saw and made him pass out again.
The cycle of coming to looking at his
intestines and passing out was repeated
three times on the last go around.
He must have died for,
he was abruptly removed from line and
taken away from the operating room.
Okay.
Doesn't matter what war it is.
You go into that hospital where they're
bringing in those wounded soldiers
and it's grueling,
okay?
He gets,
luckily his wounds weren't that bad.
He gets healed up in a few weeks and
goes back right back into right
back into it, right back into it,
and here they're going out on patrol
and I mean,
think about that. He got blown
up. He's there for 48 hours.
He gets blown up, he gets sent to the
hospital for three weeks, heals up.
I mean you're, you're, you're, you might
as well have died when you step on an IED.
Just do some matters and how big it was.
This one of,
obviously it wasn't
big enough to kill him,
but if it would have been a
little bit bigger, he'd be dead.
Or if the shrapnel went in the wrong spot,
he'd be dead.
Or if you stand in a little bit
closer to do it, he'd be dead.
Or if or if whatever, they didn't
get it out in time, he'd be dead.
If it hit a vein, he'd be dead.
If hit an artery, he'd be dead.
So he knows that and guess what?
Doesn't matter.
Giddy up, go back out there. You're
back in the game and here we go.
They're going out on patrol. I placed
myself fourth in the order of March.
As we slid out the wire,
the first 50 yards were tolerable,
but as we left the relative security of
the perimeter further and further behind,
I began to dread that each footstep
would land me on another booby trap.
I tried not to think about my wounds and
the mayhem and Gore I had seen during
the past few weeks,
but the more I tried to forget,
the more clearly I remembered if I was
going to die and I began to grieve my,
for myself,
for my wife,
for the little boy who would never really
know his father sweat poured from my
forehead, my back, my every joint.
My stomach was as tight as it.
Not each step felt as
if it might paralyze me.
I tried hard to feel my legs so I would
remember them long after they were blown
off.
I was torturing myself.
Then I realized that the
other men must be afraid to,
yet they kept moving.
I was their leader.
I had been trained for my job in the
best installations in the U s army,
had to offer west point,
airborne school, Ranger School,
jungle warfare school.
How could I be deficient
after such an investment?
While my men wrenched from unmilitary
backgrounds into the army and quickly
processed and an in personal training
facilities continue to do their duty.
Somehow I kept moving.
I could not allow myself to appear
cowardly in the eyes of those men besides
there was no place else to go.
That IED booby trap
threat is just horrifying.
Okay.
And you know it's scary enough for,
for just being over there when you see
the destruction that it causes, but,
but getting blown up and
actually personally stepping
on an IED and then you're
back in the field three
weeks later in the same area,
patrolling the same ground.
That's courage
now is there.
Okay.
Moving into position on an ambush site.
He's getting some stuff from his gear
and here we go. Back to the book.
As I struggled through the undergrowth,
the lace called on a branch and pulled
the compass loose from its birth,
causing it to fall on the
ground where it struck a rock.
The metallic case Made
Allowed Ping as it bounced.
Without hesitation,
I yelled booby trap
lurch to the right,
threw myself to the ground,
covered my head with my arms and tried
to pull my legs up to my button brace for
the explosion that was
about to rip me apart.
Okay.
And all the other guys are doing
the same thing, diving for cover.
So if you didn't catch that,
he was just moving through the brush
and something caught on his compass and
pulled it out of its pocket and it fell
to the ground and he heard that metallic
noise and he yelled out. I
mean, here they're on patrol.
They're setting up an ambush.
So this will just be quiet and tactical
and silent and all of a sudden he's
yelling out booby trap and diving to the
ground and makes everyone okay cover.
So they come back from that and he says,
I took the time to debrief the
platoon upon reentry to the perimeter,
pointing out the strong points and the
weak points of the knights actions.
I did not spare myself in the critique.
I simply stated what had happened. I
had made a mistake, but an honest one.
There were a few subdued
comments by the patrol members,
all of whom clearly recognize the
danger of my action. It didn't matter.
I'd overcome my fear.
I was once again in control of my
platoon and more importantly myself.
So when you make a
mistake, own it. That's,
that's what you gotta do when
you make a mistake. Own it.
Back to the bulk of my
indoctrination period was over.
I had been blooded but survived.
I had been embarrassed,
but would recover.
The early shocks had been merciful
in that they were over quickly.
I could now turn my attention away from
the self conscience concerns of how I
would fit into this alien environment
and how I might be perceived by the
soldiers I lead.
I could concentrate instead upon improving
my style of leadership and fighting
the enemy,
there was much to do for too long.
The platoon had done only those things
necessary to minimize casualties and
approach that in the long road,
which surely lead to maximum casualties.
So you want to sit back, you
want to, you want to hide,
you're letting the enemy get a get a
drop on you and he knows that you got to
take some risk up front to prevent
the long term extreme risk.
Okay.
Back to the book.
An old army adage claims
that soldiers only do well,
that which their commander
checks in combat.
Everything must be done well.
Yet I realized I couldn't
possibly check everything,
but I could create the illusion
that everything was being checked,
especially if I use the squad leaders and
the platoon sergeants as extensions of
my own will.
So a little bit of
decentralized command there.
He knows he can't inspect everything.
He can't be everywhere all the time.
But if he uses proper
decentralized command,
he can make it happen cause his leaders,
his subordinate leaders,
we'll make it happen.
Back to the book.
Not only tactics,
but all matters relevant to our life
in the field had to be supervised.
For instance, health habits had to be
inspected as diligently as weapons were.
Soldiers have to be kept clean.
They have to shave and watch wash and
the squad leader has to see that they do.
Soldiers need a place
to relieve themselves.
A place secure from both
enemy and the disease.
Mesac women has to be kept clean
and soldiers need a balanced diet.
Feet must be cared for.
A squad leader is accountable for the
changing of socks as he is for the
cleaning of weapons.
Men on alert must stay awake no matter
how exhausting the preceding hours have
been.
Radios have to be monitored.
Cap dried and supplied
with fresh batteries.
Proper communication
procedures must be maintained.
Codes must not be pro compromised.
Positions must be constantly improved.
The Claymore mines have to be checked
camouflaged in re camouflaged trenches
have to be deepened. Firing positions
must be made more lethal to the enemy.
Artillery fires must be registered and
reregistered grass adjacent to the wire
must be kept cut.
The ammunition bunker has to be kept dry.
Soldiers must rehearse in
all combat situations that
the that may be expected of
them.
The functioning of the chain of command
must be clearly understood by all the
men in combat.
Leaders are quickly a traded and every
man in his turn must be prepared to take
over the mission.
Lot of stuff to handle. That's why he's
saying he can't do all that himself.
You have to use decentralized
command in these situations.
Back to the book,
I checked positions at night.
Every night I lay behind the machine
guns to the men in the strong points.
I check the frequency of the
radio carried by the RTO.
I ate my eat meals at irregular hours,
sometimes alone,
sometimes with a group of soldiers.
I sat and listened to the men.
I studied their manner of speech,
their gate,
the fact that they were left or
right handed, how soundly they slept,
how well they saw in the dark.
I listened to their stories,
their hopes,
their gripes.
I tried not to speak about myself.
They're concerned about me was whether
or not I could get them through their
tour. They might want to tell me
about their homes and their families,
but they wanted me to listen,
not talk.
They did not want to know about
my life away from Vietnam.
I was an officer in their
eyes that made me different.
I was a part of this war.
I was one of the they.
They drafted the soldier.
They trained him.
They ordered him to this God forsaken
place and they sent him out on terrifying
missions to be maimed and killed.
They did not have a life
other than the army.
They were the army.
So I listened and I watched these men
were the prime resource of the platoon.
They would fulfill its missions.
They would do their country's bidding,
but they were men first.
They were not so many boots on parade.
They were human.
They have loves fears,
futures that they hope to see.
They made me wonder,
was I coming to know them too well to
make them do what they had to do or did I
not know them well enough
to ask them to do it?
I say that all the time.
That's one of the misconceptions about
the military is that the people that are
in the military are people.
They're humans.
Not so many boots on parade.
Okay?
Now he's talks a little bit about
the enemy. The enemy were also young,
also adherence of a humanistic faith
in which killing was not the essence of
life.
Yet now we faced each other obsessed
with the idea of killing each other.
There was no risk bite from it.
Once a day I wrote a letter to my wife.
It was a moment of sanity
snatched from the madness of war.
If anything,
my thoughts of home reinforced my desire
to stay alive and my determination to
keep the enemy from killing me.
They would not kill me.
They would not kill my men.
We would kill them. First
war is the management of violence claimed
the contemporary social scientists and
military strategists. As we hacked our
way through the struggle of Vietnam,
for us,
violence was killing.
There was no management involved.
People were either dead or they were not.
I could not manage mypal tune up a hill.
I had to lead them up there.
I had a mission to accomplish and I had
men to keep alive as many as I could.
I had to do more than keep them alive.
I had to preserve their human dignity.
I was making them kill,
forcing them to commit the
most uncivilized of acts,
but at the same time,
I had to keep them civilized.
That was my duty as their leader.
They were good men,
but they were facing death and men
facing death can forgive themselves many
things.
War gives the appearance of
condoning almost everything,
but men must live with their
actions for a long time. Afterward,
a leader has to help them understand
that there are lines they must not cross.
He is their link to normalicy
to order to humanity.
If the leader loses his own sense of
propriety or shrinks from his duty,
anything will be allowed
and anything can happen.
Some men in combat will commit
war crimes just to some.
Some men in combat will fail
to take care of themselves.
They will experiment with
drugs, steal property, abused.
When this happens,
it destroys the discipline
of a unit making it easier
for others to follow. Suit.
War is at its very core.
The absence of order and the absence
of order leads to very easily to the
absence of morality.
Unless the leader can preserve
each of them in its place.
The leader has to set the standards
for morality as clearly as he sets the
standards for personal hygiene
or weapons maintenance.
He must allow no cutting of corners,
a bottle of soda stolen from an old
peasant woman leads gradually but directly
to the rape of her daughter.
If the line is not drawn in the beginning.
Yeah.
There's a lot of Deckard
dichotomy in there and,
and this is one I've talked about before.
I was making them kill,
forcing them to commit the most in civil,
uncivilized of acts,
but at the same time I had
to keep them civilized.
Okay.
Then you know, another one
that I talk about all the time,
okay.
Is the fact that you care about your men
more than anything and yet you have to
send them out pawn missions where they
can be gravely wounded or killed
until this is what a combat leader is
struggling with.
This is the dichotomy of leadership.
Yup.
This was war,
this Vietnam involvement,
and in war things tend to happen,
but the commander was the link to order
and civility and he had to be humane at
the same time. He had to be
uncompromising to protect the lives of all
the job was not easy.
Okay?
The job was not easy. No, sir, it was not.
Okay.
Now he goes into a chapter that's
called a cast of characters where she's
describing some of the people
in the platoon
who were the sons that
America sent to war in vain.
I looked for the arc,
typical platoon of romantic fiction.
The kid from Brooklyn wasn't there.
The incipient poet never made it.
The rich mom was boy out to prove his
manhood stayed home as a cross section of
America's youth.
The platoon was complete failure.
So all these care typical characters
that you see in the movies and this idea
that it's a cross section
of America. No, it wasn't.
Okay.
The military draft was
never concerned with equity.
It's sole purpose was to obtain the
required numbers of men would sufficient
mental and physical
qualities to do the job.
Since the pool of men from which to draw
as much greater than the numbers needed,
a natural selection process allowed the
educated and the privilege to avoid the
draft altogether.
The selection process continued for the
unfortunate it's drafted so that those
with some education or particular skills
would be diverted from combat service.
Even among those who made it to Vietnam,
the vast majority never saw combat.
Okay.
Only those without skill.
Without schooling and without friends or
who's or who were obstinate in the face
of ceaseless proselytizing
against their obligation to serve,
made it to the field.
Okay.
And they knew it.
Talking about some of the guys here,
he's got a guy named Jim
Barnes from Asheville,
North Carolina who is,
yeah,
good solid operator.
Got a really bad stutter,
um, guy named Corporal John
Killigan from Bakersfield,
California. And he's sort of
is the, throughout the book.
He's a guy that is sort of the,
the model soldier.
Okay.
And He's 22 years old already on
his third tour of duty in Vietnam.
And by the way, a tour in Vietnam was
a year long. So this guy's throat.
So Killigan is on his third tour
in Vietnam. Most combat experience,
soldier in the platoon,
everyone respected him,
but no one considered him a friend.
Um,
the reason was simple why
he was so well respected.
Okay.
He was the best soldier among us.
He had the reflexes of a cat.
He was a deadly shot.
And ferocious in a fight and he never
showed the slightest bit of concern for
his own safety.
Awesome.
There were so many ways to avoid
ending up as a combat infantry men.
There were so many of their countrymen
who would never see an olive drab uniform
or a drill sergeant or
the green hell of Vietnam,
but each of these men seemed destined to
end up there as if it had been written
in granted on the day of his birth.
They did not complain.
This is what those guys
live with a little bit.
I noticed one day that specialists
Barnes turned away when one particularly
beautiful girl walk close by him as he
was clearing a thicket of underbrush away
from the wire.
The girls left arm was missing her empty
sleeve folded neatly and pinned to her
shoulder.
What's the matter?
Barns I asked and his painstakingly slow
stutter Barnes explained that the girl
and her lover were among a group of
armed Viet Cong who walked through one of
our ambushes.
One night the ambush was sprung,
the boyfriend was killed and the
girl's arm was mangled by a bullet.
The girl was evacuated by the Americans,
but her arm could not be saved.
Eventually she returned
to work her fields.
What do you say to a girl who's armed?
You shot off.
Barnes asked me his stutter
clearing for a minute.
I could think of no reply.
Now
they're starting to get some intelligence
report that there's ominous forecast
that there's going to be some big attack,
some big enemy thrusts and he's
taking some time to prepare for that.
My targets for improvement,
we're disciplined and tactics.
The two are closely related
in the heat of battle.
There is no time for second guessing
the per commander and is necessary for a
soldier to develop an
automatic response to an order.
Such instantaneous obedience will
overcome all fears, all confusion,
all inclinations towards
self preservation.
Eight is the result of unmitigated daily
discipline in all things from taking
the daily malaria pill to shaving each
day to attacking in the face of an
automatic weapon.
I'm adding this to my life,
the statement of unmitigated
daily discipline in all things.
They're heading out on a patrol
and as
mcdonough heads up the line to inspect.
Some of the soldiers
here we go to the book.
Suddenly there was a hollow sounding
explosion and a whistling past my year,
followed by another explosion a second
later about 150 meters out in the bushes
I spun around to see king. It's one of
the guys king with a sneer on his face,
sorry, Lt, the words
he has from his mouth,
I dropped my weapon,
the grenade launcher dangled from his
right hand a waft of smoke curling up from
the barrel.
It was clear that he had fired
his 40 millimeter round at me
at that range he could not have missed.
So he must have meant it as a warning.
He was telling me he did
not like my attitude.
So you got McDonald who's been imposing
discipline and trying to keep the guys
squared away and this guy doesn't like
it and so he sends them a little warning
shot with his,
with his m 79 grenade launcher.
I was scared, but I was angry to
king, had not only threatened my life,
but my authority as well.
A few weeks earlier,
I might've been overcome by the situation,
but since then I had developed a thick
skin necessary for survival in Vietnam
with murder in my eyes.
I looked into king's face slowly,
deliberately.
I walked up to him saying nothing
until I was close enough to touch him.
I had made no threatening gesture.
Suddenly when I was close
enough to smell his breath,
I flicked my [inaudible] in the fire
position and placed the muzzle of the
weapon and the cavity of the underside
of his chin. He went up on his toes.
As I increase the pressure
of the rifle barrel,
lifting him up against
the bottom of his head,
the sneer was now on my face as I raised
my voice so everyone could hear you,
son of a bitch.
The eyes of everyone in the
platoon were riveted on us.
Drop your weapon again and
you better pray to God.
It hits me square in the back
because if it doesn't you bastard,
I'll blow your brains to kingdom come.
Not a man stirred,
putting down a little rebellion.
But again, this is something
where you to think about that.
I mean from my perspective,
nothing like that ever came close to
happening me at any time was it? Was it,
was there any time where I ever thought
any of my guys would do anything in any
way to hurt me in any situation.
In fact,
those guys would do
anything to do to save me.
They would never let
anything happen to me.
And here you have one of your guys that
just decides is going to give you a
little warning shot with a 40
millimeter grenade launcher. Yeah,
cause he doesn't like here
added tooth or whatever.
They're probably had a lot to do with
a lot of those guys didn't want to be
there. Absolutely. Absolutely.
Now they
are
moving forward on a patrol.
They had a little incident happen
and they find a corpse
from the book.
Now I was becoming fairly
accustomed to viewing the dead,
but this cadaver was
particularly grotesque.
It was the old woman who
had cared for the children.
Both her breasts had been
half severed from her body.
A Deliberate Cup made on
the underside of each.
Each palm and the sole of each foot had
been shot through with a small caliber
round the killing wound,
which no doubt had followed.
The earlier torturous wounds was a blast
from a weapon weapon evidently placed
inside her mouth and directed
out the back of her head.
Her eyes were open,
transfixed and terror jabbed into her
belly on the end of a street and safety
pin was a note.
Nan the Kit Carson scout
translated it for me.
Twan cow key has been found guilty by
the People's Court of aiding the American
imperialists and their suppression of
the Vietnamese people as an enemy of the
people she has been made
to pay for her crimes.
This is the justice that will be brought
to all who consort with the Americans
and aid them in the villainous
suppression of our land.
War is hell
now.
They start to get
attacked inside their perimeter
and here we go. At that moment, the
first rush was made by the enemy.
20 to 30 Viet Cong appeared coming
at the south wire to dead run.
I shouted from my men to shift fire on
them. There was no need for my words.
My men were responding well.
We were getting off a handheld
flare every 30 seconds,
which illuminated the
rushing enemy very clearly.
The two machine guns on that portion of
our perimeter barked out a welcome and
neat six round bursts.
Several of the enemy fell there.
First rush was stopped in its tracks.
Okay.
It was becoming increasingly clear that
the machine gun was going to be the key
weapon in the initial
stoppage of the fight
and I just highlighted
that because I know I get,
I hear from military guys all the time,
guys that are overseas and I just
wanted to reiterate that in a firefight,
the machine gun is the key weapon.
Now they're continuing to being
attacked and from the south east,
a woman came running toward
the break in the wire,
she was carrying a bulky
object in her arms,
but in the flickering light of the flares,
it was impossible to identify it.
Don't fire Lawrence barked.
I was not sure I agreed
if it was a Satchel charge
that the woman was carrying.
She would be able to fling it
in and us and another few steps.
The explosion would rip apart
that perimeter wide open,
allowing the enemy to rush through
unimpeded. On the other hand,
if the woman was seeking help,
it would be a tragedy to cut her down.
As I hesitated, the heavy beat
of enemy rounds forced her down.
Lawrence made a dash for the wire, got
10 steps, and then went into a low crawl,
inching his way along.
He made it to a break the wire and
came up to the woman in her arms,
was her seven year old daughter.
The little girl had taken around,
clean through the chest, along was
collapsed and she was bleeding heavily.
Her mother was trying to make
it to us to save the child.
Okay,
so again,
this is the dichotomy of war.
You got people torturing
and murdering old women,
and then you get this situation where
there's a woman who's rushing the
perimeter and this guy, you know, says
he's don't shoot her and then crawls out,
risk his life to go and try and find
out what the situation is and helper
there is darkness and there's light.
Okay.
They
beat back that attack
and the next morning
they go out on patrol.
Killigan was the point man on the first
patrol out the morning after the fight
all night he'd worked in machine gun
from the southern tip of the platoon
triangle, his steady hand
holding the enemy rushes at bay.
Early in the fight,
the attackers had recognized Gilligan's
prowess and tried their best to put them
out of action.
The sound,
the sandbag surrounding his position
were torn and poked from the bullets and
shrapnel aimed at his early retirement.
He had not flinched throughout the night
and now he took up the point with
the alertness of a well rested cat.
The man seemed indestructable.
Now he starts talking a little bit about
the situation that they were in and in
some moves that he made and one of the
things he did was he kept his forces
together at this point when they had been
attacked or he reunited as forces and
he talks about that here
had the enemy's struck.
While my meager forces were split,
they might've overwhelmed one
or both elements piecemeal,
controlling the separated elements
would also have been almost impossible.
And the subsequent coordination of outside
support such as air strike and armor
platoon would have been too hazardous had
we even survive long enough to receive
help. So he's talking about, again,
this is just going out to people that
are in the military, in the field.
Avoid splitting your forces up.
Just just avoid sweetened.
Sometimes you obviously have to do it,
but always think about it.
Think about the ramifications of it when
you're split up number one, year two,
year two elements are weak.
That's why when you do split up,
you should stay as often as you can.
Stay within position of mutual support
where your weapons can support the other
group. And you can bring
them back to your perimeter,
you can attack or you can
flank or you can support them.
The other thing that's very difficult
when you're split up is it's very
difficult to control what's
happening. Yeah. Cause you
likely out of verbal range,
you could possibly be out of
radio range. And now, now,
how are you going to control
what's going to happen?
So if you do have to split up,
make sure you have very good loss of
communication plans to, to react to.
If something happens,
we're going to go to this muster point,
here's going to be the signaling
we want to come in there.
So you've got to think about that.
And finally when you split your forces
up on the battlefield and you lose
control of them, now you can't
call for air support. You can't.
It's very difficult to get help and
bring the funder let you would want to
because you don't know where everybody is.
So when you do have to split force switch,
you do absolutely have to do
sometimes avoided as much as you can.
And then when you have to plan for the
worst case scenario so that you're ready
for it.
Now they're back to kind of sorting
things out. After this hardcore battle,
when they,
when the VC attacked,
my eyes were turned to the body's
laying so lying, so neatly in line.
Why did we line them up anyways?
Was it a pension for neatness and attempt
to bring some order orderliness to the
disorder of death?
He was so absurd.
I remembered reading somewhere
that in World War II,
the Germans had lined up the
bodies of American prisoners.
They massacred disorder and order
barbarity and Siviletti civility,
ironic juxtapositions in
the affairs of men. Again,
we're just talking about dichotomy of war.
My elation was reduced to a sense of
insignificance by the Cold Brown look of
the corpse sprawled in the
bright sunlight. A few hours ago,
each one had been a
dynamo of a human spirit,
hope and ambition.
Now they were still there,
emotion frozen at least,
and that last incident of life as if
making a mockery of the final effort.
They had become meaningless
clumps of earth forever inanimate,
no more significant than the rocks
lying to their left and right.
How fickle those human
ambitions now seemed,
how pointless those concerns
and just as the bodies had become part
of the earth on which they rested.
So I had passed during the battle from
being in the war to being part of the
war.
Okay.
Continuing on the fog of war is pervasive.
As vigilant as I tried to be,
I knew it was only a matter of
time before a mistake was made.
There were six squads to control as well
as the Armored Cavalry platoon and the
still disjointed RF gaggle.
Moreover,
Vietnamese regular army units were
infringing on my area as platoon leader.
I had the problems of the rich,
too many resources to coordinate
in a limited area of operations,
the ingredients for a tragedy or brewing,
and so he had been augmented
with more with some cavalry guys,
with more platoons or started
more squads to help mount.
So now he's got a bunch of people there.
He had 30 before. Now he's got a lot more
and there's patrols are happening.
Things are going on and we start getting
a call of potential enemy [inaudible]
outside the wire and he's checking his
map and he's giving you the going back
and forth on the radio. Hey, isn't it
we have any friendlies in that location?
Nope. No friendlies there.
Check with the other guys. Nope.
We had no friendlies there.
So no one's in that area? No,
there's no friendlies in that area.
Okay. God, he's checking his map.
He's going back and forth and
now we go back to the book.
All checks had been made. The squad
still had the moving element in sight.
The decision was now mine,
take them under fire with the sniper,
then open up,
shoot to kill.
The last statement seemed pointless.
We always shot to kill,
but it reflected my troubled
thoughts over the risk I was taking.
The enemy just did not go that way,
but no friendlies were reported anywhere
near us. It had to be the enemy.
So here's the one shot with sniper.
Go out and then he hears
massive gunfire go out.
You can probably tell
where this is heading.
And then a frantic voice scream from my
radio, cease fire, cease fire, my God,
you're killing us.
I was horrified as I grabbed the handset
and barked my order to one to one.
This is two six ceasefire over.
They had heard the original plea and
even as I spoke, the Malay quieted,
okay
again, the radio spoke you sons of
bitches, they're dead, they're dead.
So in the confusion in the fog of war,
they'd seen some guys and obviously they
turned out to be friendlies and they
engaged him.
Over the next 30 minutes they get
the debrief of what's happening.
It was an American advisor was out
there with a Vietnamese platoon,
one of his guys were dead
and two were badly wounded.
And here's how we felt about that.
I had ordered the execution of those men
because the lieutenant advisor had made
a mistake by the way,
they were 2,500 meters off course.
So they should not have been in that area.
And when they were hearing,
they were hearing on the radio, hey,
is there any friendlies out there?
And they thought there's no way that
anyone could be talking to us right now,
but it happens and a man should not
be condemned to death for it in war.
However, the price from
mistakes is dear and terribly.
Final military leaders must weigh affects
of their decisions carefully before
because usually
there is no turning back.
Okay.
Uh, that, that blue on
blue, that fratricide thing,
it's a real thing. It's a real
thing. I've lived through it myself.
I've been in charge of
when it's happening,
it's awful and it's real.
And so everybody that's out there,
that's soldiers,
marines, special ops guys,
train for that. Get that.
Make yourselves as can
make your leadership,
make everyone is confused as you can
is what's happening so that you force
yourselves to think and understand
and over communicate where people are,
what positions they're going to,
what positions they're leaving,
who's where on the battlefield.
The fog of war is no joke.
Cool.
Now there's another attack that they,
that they pushed back and they
kind of Ford it early on by,
by catching someone that was going to,
that was inside there was going to
try and get inside their compound.
They catch that person,
and here we go to the book.
They're planning must have been to rupture
our defense with a tremendous blast
from the ammunition bunker and then rush
it us from the eastern flank with the
five sappers.
While we were still dazed,
the sappers were armed only
with fragmentation grenades,
but they had plenty of them. Later we
took 49 grenades from their bodies.
One of the sappers,
a young muscular man who in life would've
epitomize the propaganda stereotype of
a revolutionary, but who in depth
appeared like so much wasted.
Clay was dressed only in a loin cloth
folded within that single article of
clothing was a small piece of paper upon
which was drawn a rough but accurate
sketch of our perimeter defense.
The first link in their plan had
been destroyed by the capture of the
infiltrator,
and it was further deteriorated by
the annihilation of the Sapper Force.
But the Viet Cong were never noted for
their flexibility and they continued to
press forward according to
their original plan. However,
instead of meeting days dying
and demoralized defenders,
the enemy rushed right
into the protective fires,
have already enabled platoon because of
a slight twist of fortune over which the
Viet Cong had no influence.
The attackers went to their death
rather than to victory that night.
So this is the second time
we've heard that is just there.
The Viet Cong not being very flexible,
not being very adaptable with their plan.
So once again,
if you're in a leadership position,
did you gotta you gotta maintain
flexibility with your plan,
whether you're in a combat operation
or whether you're in a business world,
it doesn't matter.
Maintaining flexibility is absolutely
paramount in from a leadership perspective
and from a team perspective.
Hmm.
Now they're,
after that attack,
they move out to go for a counter attack,
which is,
which is just, I mean, let's, let's think
about this. You're in your perimeter,
you get attacked their date.
They had a person that infiltrated and
almost made it into the main ammo bunker
that you have.
They almost blew that up.
And then their second thing was
to have these, these sappers,
these the soldiers crawling through the
wire with 40 something grenades with
them to go and Jack stuff up. You
push back, you repel this attack,
and then guess what? The time for
a cap type for a counter attack.
So here he is as the script back to the
book as a squad lined up for the exit
through the wire,
I looked at their young faces tightened
to stifle the fear building up inside
their bodies.
They were barely men,
yet called upon by their country and
abandoned by their more well to do peers,
about to face a ruthless enemy who
meant to put them in their early grave.
No words of complaint from any of them.
They were American infantry men and
would do the job they were asked to do.
No matter what. No matter that
it would not be appreciated,
no matter that they would be
condemned by their countrymen,
or at least the countryman with the
ability to wear with all to mold public
opinion tonight.
They would do their duty,
though they were little more than
boys though. They were frightened,
though they were most not ready to die.
They would do their duty.
Okay.
Most of them were labeled as coming
from the lower social strata of American
society as if that were
something in noble.
Yeah.
I felt proud to be with them
and glad to share their company,
their qualities of moral
and physical courage,
of unselfish dedication to each other.
Amid the difficult jobs they were
called upon to do. Mark them in my mind,
is among the noblest of human beings.
Yeah.
So they're out on this counter
attack. I mean, what a,
what a great tribute to
the American soldier.
Unbelievable.
Unbelievable dedication and pride.
Unbelievable men.
Yeah.
Now they,
they're patrolling out in front of them.
They hear some whispers and whispers
out in front of them where they're
patrolling towards and
they're trying to figure out what to do.
And it sounds like, um,
McDonald's sorta saying, Hey,
let's just kill these guys.
There's bad guys up ahead.
We're wearing out the whispering and
Killigan tugs at his arm and says,
stay here. Like I'm going to go
check this out. He basically says,
you know, um, we shouldn't, we
shouldn't kill these people.
And he McDonald gets kind of
pissed because he's thinking,
look, this isn't the time for us to debate
right now. I want to make a decision.
And he says, kill again.
In one of his rare moments of speech, he
has taught me, let me check it out first.
So Killigan doesn't talk much.
He's gets it done.
So he creeps forward, you know, and,
and he was basically saying, look,
I'm going to go on alone. Like, are
you just let me take my chances?
I'm not putting anybody else
at risk. No, just me. And so
he decides, okay, go ahead.
You want to take you
on a risk of your life.
And so he Killigan disappears into the
darkness and then a little while later he
comes back. It's cool. And
we'll go to the book here.
Then as quietly as he had crept away,
Killigan reappeared from the darkness.
He crawled up to my face and
said, it's okay. Let's move on.
What were the voices?
I asked?
Family was his one word response.
I passed the word to hold fire
and the file began moving.
We moved out of position and through the
brush to our front there huddled in a
hole that must have been used
as a household garbage dump.
We're two aged women and old man,
one young woman and four tiny children.
The elderly people had shy,
embarrassed, smiles on their faces.
The children's stared in sheer
terror. Well, they might.
I had nearly killed them.
All the side of the family was haunting.
I and others like me are trained and
commissioned to lead men into actions that
determine the life and death are authority
particularly on the field of battle
is virtually unquestioned.
We were tasked to men to lead men like
Killigan to tell them what should be done
and what they must do. We
have no obligation to listen
to their point of view.
Indeed to do so.
Might be in itself or cause to occur,
a failure of leadership.
And yet the American soldier is often
much more prepared than his leader to make
a sound determination
of what should be done.
Gilligan's approach had
been wiser than mine.
I was too preoccupied with my own safety
and the safety of my men to consider
that there might have been
a noncombatants in the area.
I had come to the most basic of
battlefields strategies shoot now and ask
questions later.
1,000 times.
I might've been able to rationalize
that course of action after the fact,
but I had gone.
But had I gone ahead this time,
the people huddled now
whole would have been dead,
nothing but rotting corpses by the heat
of the next day that they were alive was
no thanks to me.
It was to kill against credit and he
was just a quote lowly American infantry
men.
So once again,
just credit to the trooper,
to the soldier and, and,
and you can see there's,
this is some of the things that he talked
about that we have no obligation to
listen to their point of view,
that that's something that you can see
he's maturing out of, right? And He,
this paragraph is a visible
evidence of him transitioning from,
hey look, I'm, I'm the boss, I'm in
charge. Do what I say to you know what?
These guys know better than I do
in many cases. And that's from,
from a leadership perspective,
that's a very important lesson to learn.
And the sooner you learn it,
the better off you're going to be.
The people that you're leading
oftentimes know the situation, the job,
the technicalities better than you do.
So rely on them, count on
them, ask their opinion. And,
and the fact of the matter is,
when you don't ask their opinion,
it's only because you're insecure
about your leadership ability and your
position.
And by not asking you actually
you actually
develop less respect than if
you say, Hey, you know what?
Killigan you've been here,
this is your third tour in Vietnam.
What do you think we should do here?
You will not lose respect leaders.
You will not lose respect if you
asked that question. In fact,
you lose respect when you don't respect
your frontline trooper when you don't
use their talent, when you don't
take advantage of their expertise,
that's when you go backwards.
Listen to your troopers,
so he gets,
he gets pulled back to command.
They assigned him to like a mixed match
unit of a bunch of random squads because
they have a certain mission that they
want them to do and they've gone out and
they've set up a perimeter and if you
don't want a security perimeter is
basically 360 degree security
perimeter of where your,
you have guns pointed to
the outside and you have,
usually the leadership will be in the
center of the perimeter and there'll be
small teams kind of out in the
perimeter making up the progress.
That's the position that they're in.
He's got these random squads that he's
never worked with before and he's in
charge of them again. This is a,
this is something where, you know,
we we did have to work with
on my last appointment.
Oftentimes you're working with other
seals. These are the guys, you know, guys,
you know him really well.
You know everything that they're going
to do and here you are getting thrown
into a combat environment on a very
dangerous patrol into enemy territory that
you don't know very well and you've got
a bunch of guys that you never worked
with before.
So as he's in that perimeter,
he's given the guys some instructions
about something called challenge and
replies.
So it's a way of confirming cause it's
pitch black and these guys don't have
nightmares and it's pitch black. He says,
hey if you, if you hear someone coming,
you can issue the challenge for a number
of some of 10 which is like if I say
echo or if I hear you
coming and I say seven,
you would respond three if I say for
you would respond six. So they've,
they've passed that word. If you
hear noise, you need to challenge,
do that challenge and reply.
So he's out there and he's crawling
towards one of the little elements on the
outside of the perimeter so he can
find out, you know, check in with them,
see if they've seen anything,
see if they heard anything.
And here we go back to the book.
She was his only warning to the others.
I came to a complete rest waiting
for someone to issue the challenge.
The seconds ticked on,
but I heard no sound.
I began to sense there was a problem.
The next sound was the bolt and firing
pin of a rifle sliding forward in
response to a pull trigger.
Both fell forward on an empty chamber.
Terrified.
I realized that I should be dead,
that the rifleman meant to nail me.
No questions asked,
only is earlier error and not
having chambered around saved me.
Don't shoot. I shouted at
heart. It's the lieutenant,
but I was too late to stop
the momentum of events.
I heard a panicky remark from the midst
of the group get the bastards that
around was chambered.
As I flung myself at the sound.
15 feet is not far to sprint,
but the journey seem to endless.
I threw myself parallel to the ground
and lunged in the dark figure appearing
before my eyes.
As I launched through the year,
I felt round switched
by my outstretched body,
nine or 10 bullets burning out of
the barrel of the automatic weapon.
My arms circled the needs of the
fire or bringing him down in a heap.
I purse the hop barrels skyward as the
last of the rounds exited the weapon.
Although I had pinned the fire,
I had also to think about the two
other men with him. I yelled out,
don't shoot you son of a bitch.
It's the platoon leader.
There was no further firing.
Fighting my rage.
I tried to focus my thoughts. We
were in deep trouble. Don't shoot,
don't shoot, don't shoot. I shot. I hold
your fire. I shouted across the perimeter.
I could hear nervous chatter from
all around so he barely escaped.
He gets the guys to stop.
He doesn't even really,
he's mad,
but he's basically taking responsibility
in being in this situation in the first
place.
So
he says to the guys that were there,
he says,
I admonished all three men to challenge
correctly speaking to them as if I were
giving a clap classroom
instructions to a bunch of eager,
if not very bright students.
I surprised myself with my calmness.
It was when I moved back to my position
that the greatest struggle within me
began. Perhaps it was triggered by the
decision I had to make by the book.
I shifted.
I had shifted our positions by the book.
I should have shifted our positions.
We were reconnaissance patrol.
We were badly outnumbered by the enemy
and had compromised our position with all
the shooting and shouting.
There were good reasons for moving.
On the other hand,
it was pitch black night.
If the enemy was close enough
to get an immediate fix on us,
he was close enough to hit us before
we could move. Even if he wasn't close.
Further stumbling around in the
darkness might worsen our predicament.
Moreover,
to effect the movement,
I would have to move around
to regroup the disbursed men.
This was the point that weighed
most heavily on my mind.
I no longer had the heart for it.
I had come within an inch of being killed,
shot by one of my own man on the side of
an ink black mountain in the middle of
nowhere.
I knew the men were ready
to shoot anything that moves
and I didn't want to give
them a target.
I should have been ashamed of myself.
I was too afraid to move,
to implement what was probably the
best course of action for my men and my
mission.
I couldn't do it naked.
Fear stripped me of all shame or guilt.
Fear was all I knew and
I didn't want to move.
A few moments earlier, I had been an
effective platoon leader doing his job.
Now I could actually feel my chest
throbbing against the dirt where I lay.
I wanted to bury my face in my hands.
I wanted to be like the little boy.
I used to be hiding from the darkness
by putting his head under the covers.
I could not think.
My big body began to tremble than shiver,
then shake uncontrollably.
My God, I was going to die.
I could not possibly live through the
night. If anyone heard my breathing,
I was sure you'd kill me. Death
was everywhere. I had sensed it,
felt it lying down beside me.
I didn't want to die,
but death was there.
Cold and clammy,
reaching for me with his icy touch,
my pulse,
pounding in my ears and I felt nauseous.
I almost threw up the passing minutes,
hours,
whatever units of time exist in
a nightmare, brought no relief.
The fear only worsened. I would not live
through the night. I was sure of it.
With the dying hurt.
I wondered would I disappear into
when I first went, prone trying
to press myself into the ground,
I fell close to an ant hill.
A few of the ants scouts immediately
began a reconnaissance of my body,
but it was not until the ants legions
were called forward that I noticed them.
As I lay shaking on the ground,
thousands of ants began trooping
over me adding to the crawling,
feeling on my flesh.
Still,
I did not move for the move I knew
would put me in the embrace of death,
so I laid there where I was. Heart
pounding, skin sweating, ears throbbing.
While an army of ants probed
and pricked up at my will.
Sometime later that night, the rains came
in, a torrential downpour, that Santa,
a stream gushing down the mountain
side at us. I still didn't move.
My night of terror was not over yet and
when the rain stopped, after a few hours,
I still lay in the ooze and slime
firstlight brought a sense of recovery.
Darkness was ending and I was still alive.
Only then did the
beating of my heart slow.
I loosened my belt,
reached down into the soggy elastic of
my undershorts and wiped out a streak of
drowned ants.
The rains had swept them over my body
where they'd become trapped and they had
drowned.
As I removed their dead bodies,
thousands of them, I seem to rid
myself of my fixation with death.
I had lived through the
night vulnerable as I was.
The answer died imminently
adaptable as they were.
Somehow the irony of it reassured me,
one died when it was time to die.
Apparently it was not my time.
Okay.
As dawn broke,
I pulled myself together,
gathered up my makeshift patrol and move
back toward the ranger camp that night
on the mountain.
Instead of engaging the enemy,
I'd come to grips with my own mortality.
That night I had been a
terrible platoon leader,
but perhaps I would be a better
one thereafter because of it.
Little bit of an intense evening
for lieutenant mcdonough.
Unbelievable.
Now he gets some,
and throughout this book there's,
and I talked about this in the beginning,
that there's rotations of guys in,
guys are getting wounded guys,
it's time for them to go home,
so you're constantly,
he's constantly getting new troopers.
New soldiers knew noncommissioned officers
that are going to be the senior guys,
the platoon, and it's just, it's just
a constant stream of incoming new guys,
which again is very foreign to me because
in the seal teams we do very little of
that.
We do do it sometimes for guy graduated
seal training and they happened to be
assigned a team that's on deployment.
They, they might come over and join,
join us on deployment. It can't happen,
but it's not, it's not the norm.
So he's got a new guy that shows up who's
a staff sergeant and empowerment and
power admins like almost 40 years old.
He'd crossed the Canadian border,
um,
are uh,
the Canadian border to
join the Canadian army
and he'd spent time in the
British army and Cyprus.
He'd been chasing war basically,
and it's slightly under six feet tall,
not an ounce of fat on his lien frame.
Determined Look,
and this is quite contrary to the
guys he had been working with.
And here he talks about that a little
bit with Hernandez and Robinson.
I had to push to get them
patrolling with Palamon.
I had to hold him back.
He believed firmly that the only
good defense was it good or fence.
And he was ready to set
the example every day.
Not only did he take himself out on
as many patrols is I would permit.
He invariably pushed seated
to the front of the column,
eventually threatening to
displace the point. Man.
He exhibited such enthusiasm when he and
I went on longer patrols that I had to
order them back to the back of the column,
lest I find myself trailing him.
He never met disrespect. He just wanted
to be up front where the action might be.
Okay.
Newman was the perfect platoon sergeant.
You're definitely blessed when you get it,
when you get a leader
like that in your command,
and I was definitely lucky enough to
serve with many guys with that kind of
attitude that I had to hold back.
Okay.
Here's an interesting thing.
Um, he says during the war,
we lost approximately 10,000 men too,
other than enemy fire.
Vietnam was so full of treachery
danger and outright bad luck,
okay.
That he's on this administrative
mission and he just like playing it safe
because he doesn't want to die.
I want to get killed by a criminal
or getting a car accident.
But you don't think about 10,000 people
die in Vietnam just from other than
combat.
Hmm.
The heavy rain to discourage the
enemy from moving against us.
Okay.
That was some comfort.
Obviously they were human after all too
often they seem to above the constraints
of normal men, too hardened to the
rigors that wore down the rest of us.
Although it was tempting
to rest on our haunches,
taking advantage of the real
spite offered by the weather.
I knew that in the long run it would
be safer to push more on the offensive.
To lie back would only allow the
enemy to build their strength.
As I was building mine and allow them
to choose the time and place of the next
strike,
I decided to go after them in their layer.
One of the personnel changes I made was
to take Killigan out of his squad leader
position. Uh, sergeant arrived
to take over the squad.
I password to him to
keep Killigan off point.
Killigan did not like it and was
close to the point of rebellion,
but I refuse to put them back on point.
His luck was about to run out.
No matter how good he might be,
the odds are heavily stacked
against the point man. My order,
however meant little in variably
Gilligan would move up to the front,
always out there,
a little advance of the moving element.
It was a role he defined for himself.
So obviously we're going to continue to,
one of the themes of this book is be
aggressive and stay on the offense.
That's absolutely true.
The reason I highlighted that thing with
Killigan was because here you've got a
guy that's all about good
order and discipline,
but guess what he's telling Killigan
don't walk point, don't walk point,
don't walk point and kill him. Good
and goes, okay. Yeah I won't walk.
Point goes out on patrol,
goes up to point, and that's,
that's also one of those things where,
you know, sometimes I get asked, you know,
my boss is not doing this or
we're not getting, we're getting,
we're not getting clear direction,
or I don't agree with this thing.
Sometimes you've got to make
some stuff happen, you know,
especially if it's the right thing to do.
You got to make some stuff happen.
Sometimes.
Now they do some,
some operations and they're starting
to take some toll on the enemy.
And here's what the enemy does.
The enemy retaliatory retaliated with
more booby traps and other regular
attacks.
One morning,
the village chief was caught at the
well as he bathed his ever present.
40 45 caliber pistol,
left a few feet away
with his pile of clothes,
a small nine year old boy,
no doubt acting on orders from a relative.
Walked up, smiled and shot the chief
twice with a 22 caliber pistol.
Once again, however, the chief survived.
Returning a few weeks later to resume
his post specialists Barnes back from six
days in Australia, stepped on a booby
trap and lost his right leg at the hip.
Robson,
the nervous baby kid from Illinois who
had arrived with Palamon got wedged head
first and a Vietcong tunnel. As
he was clearing it, he panicked,
vomited and drowned in his own puke
before he could be pulled back out.
Another man recently arrived,
sat down beside a trail to take a break
and trip the Chinese claim or with his,
but I hope that his mother would
not ask to open his coffin.
The gruesome toll of the
booby traps war on our nerves,
no matter how many we found,
we knew there were others out
there waiting for a misstep.
The terror built it is one thing to
rush an enemy in battle and take your
chances in the face of his fire power.
The experience is frightening,
but the momentum of the
act compels you forward,
sparing you the agony of
considering your predicament,
thinking your way through a booby trap
areas completely different experience and
much more horrifying.
Moving along.
You suddenly notice a freshly
smooth spot of dirt to your front.
You look hard and see the three deadly
prongs of the anti-personnel mind come
into focus and unholy trinity extending
from beneath the surface of the earth to
greet your foot,
fall and rip you apart.
You look to your right and see
a pile of rocks are intertwined.
Twigs the Vietcong warning to their
own that this is a killing ground.
You order everyone to freeze.
As you strain your eyes to
pick out more booby trap clues,
your nerves have turned to steel coils.
Your Eyes Dart over the ground for
telltale signs of human tampering,
smooth dirt and unnaturally placed
vine attached to a pull pin.
Safety.
A thin wire across your path of
broken brush time stands still.
You're afraid to move at the same time.
You want to duck your
head and dash to safety.
Maybe you can make it before
the detonation catches you,
but one of the others you have
to get them all out. Keep cool.
That's it. Bring the others slowly
into a straight file. Careful.
Watch where you step now.
Work your way up to the front.
Look carefully before each footfall
watch for nearly invisible wires.
One slight tug could bring metal tearing
through your flesh like a frenzied
power saw. Okay, let's move. Stay in line.
Don't bench up. Can't let one
booby trap get more than one of us,
but which one? Me, him. Concentrate.
Don't think about the explosion.
Look, look, you can see them if you look
carefully enough, take another step.
We're almost out of it. Christ don't
ambush us. Now we can't move, concentrate.
Think of where you would plant them.
Look for the telltale signs and
so it went tremendous pressure,
followed by tremendous relief as
the booby trap area was cleared,
then the journey continued only to bring
the patrol to another threatening area.
It played on your nerves.
Somehow the men put on a show of bravado.
I thought that section.
Talking about forget an IED.
I mean that's like what it's like.
They was just a perfect,
perfect writing and
being on out on patrols.
Were you thinking there's going to be ids?
That's what your mind is thinking.
That's what you're thinking. You're
looking at every little thing in the road.
Every little piece of trash,
every little wire,
everything could be a pressure plate.
It could be a crush wire,
it could be an IED,
could just be anything.
And so you're just constantly in that
mode of assessing and looking and trying
to figure it out. And I thought that
that wasn't just a incredible job,
especially by a guy that
actually triggered an id on
himself and got blown up.
And so he's probably feeling
that that pressure 10 fold,
a leader who arbitrates when the laws
of land warfare overtaken by pragmatic
concern is treading on dangerous ground.
The laws exist for practical and
humane reasons and I knew that well,
but the consequences of my decisions
were immediate and I could not afford the
comfort of a philosophical
debate on issues.
I tried to behave in a humane
manner and did not intimidate,
but I persisted until I was reasonably
assured that I had the truth or that my
interviewee truly did not
know I owed my men that much.
One day a stay behind ambush element
got into a sudden firefight in the
exchange. One American had been hit
in the leg and was bleeding profusely.
As I approached the action with the rest
of the patrol intending to flank the
enemy,
I noticed that the base of the hill we
were about to send was heavily mined.
A frightened farmer crouched in the grass
nearby. Come here, Papasan. I called non.
Ask them how to get through this stuff.
The farmers shook his head and dismay.
I'll call came on the radio. Dammit. If
we don't get Archibald out of here fast,
he's going to bleed to death.
Ask them again. Nam Nan,
I ordered again.
The farmer refused his
eyes widening and fear.
I took out my knife. Nan, tell
him I'll kill him right now.
If he doesn't tell us.
I had crossed the line.
I wouldn't have killed him,
but he didn't know that and
the threat itself was criminal,
but I weighed that against the bleeding
soldier and the others who might bleed
if we didn't get through to them quickly.
A leader has no one to look to
for advice on such decisions.
He must do what he thinks is best,
but he must not fool himself as
to the consequences of his chores.
War is not a series of case studies that
can be scrutinized with the objectivity.
It is a series of stark confrontations
that must be faced under the most emotion
wrenching conditions.
War is the suffering and death of people,
you know,
set against a background of the
suffering and death of people you do not.
That reality tends to prejudice the
already tough choices between morality and
pragmatism.
The farmer led us through.
We forced the enemy away and extracted
our soldier in time to save his life.
We let the farmer go,
but not before I thanked him.
Yeah,
he looked at me as if I were crazy,
very enough to just say again,
this is another great description
of what you're dealing with in war
and the decisions that you have to
make in these horrible situations.
Back to the book,
Fricker was nervous for the past few days.
He felt his number was coming up. I don't
know what's wrong with me, lieutenant.
He had told me, shyly, I don't feel right.
What do you mean? Are you feeling sick?
I asked. No, it's not
that I just feel down
like something bad is going to happen.
Maybe you've been on point too often.
I'll tell staff sergeant Robinson to
take you off. No, no, don't do that.
I'm the best man for that.
My squad.
I don't want any of the
guys thinking I'm yellow.
Okay.
Fricker wasn't yellow.
He was scared,
but he was more scared of letting his
friends down than of getting hurt.
I urged him to take a break,
but he had insisted on staying on point.
I told Robinson to take them off.
Anyway.
Fricker heard of it and pleaded
with me to put them back.
I yielded so on a lovely evening,
Fricker was cautiously leading the squat
up a hill and the machine guns stitched
him across the chest.
Robinson turned and dash down the slope,
making it 20 meters before he
stumbled and broke his ankle.
10 meters behind Frickin nail
and a Wilson dove for cover.
Fricker went down on one knee and
spun around a phrase. His friends,
blood and air bubbled from
the holes in his chest.
He dropped his weapon and tried to rise
his arms out stretched as if reaching
for help.
His eyes opened wide and terrorist mouth
agape is blood spilled over as loose
lower lip as the machine gun
bullets tore into his back.
He tumbled face down,
arms still reaching out for
help that would come too late.
Wilson took in the scene with Har
freakers dead. My God flickers dead.
His voice rose above the clatter,
afraid that no one understood.
Wilson repeated his announcement.
Oh no, he's dead. He's dead.
He yelled with all his might
nail silenced him with a curt,
shut up, he's dead, and
that's all there is to it.
Somehow nails words cut through the
hideousness of the moment more graphically
than freakers death.
Wilson was stunned into silence.
There was a cursory exchange of rounds.
The enemy fled down the reverse slope
and freakers corpse became the and the
lame Robinson were evacuated.
Nail became the squad leader.
That was all there was to it.
Another American had fallen one of
more than 58,000 to die in Vietnam.
The action took a few minutes.
There was nothing unique about it.
A messy business to be sure,
but one that can be cleaned up by
shipping off the body and making a few
personnel changes.
But Fricker was dead
a few moments earlier.
He had been a young man with a
lifetime of experiences ahead of him.
Now he was just a memory to his family
and to us a few moments earlier.
He was afraid some of his friends
would think of him as a coward.
Soon almost no one would
think of him at all.
His mother would get a telegram
and then a purple heart.
Maybe I could write him up for a metal,
but what should I say?
That he was brave because
he was afraid to be afraid
that he saved his squad by walking
up to the machine gun first.
And what did he save them for so that
they might live a few more weeks before
following in his footsteps.
He was all too much to consider
as nail.
It said he was dead
and that's all there was to it.
And here he talks a little bit about
the morality of war.
It was not a simple matter of kill or
be killed. I had to think of my men.
I could not let them be killed because
of a rigid morality on my part.
But if I compromised with that morality
too often I would become little more
than a war criminal unfit
to lead those men's.
I had to struggle to
keep a sense of balance
that's there.
That's the crazy thing about the
dichotomy of leadership is that these,
these opposing forces that are pulling
you in two different directions,
they're both, they're both correct.
It's correct of both. Correct.
And the balance is where you need to stay.
I shouldn't say that.
They're both correct, but they're both
file bull options. You can rationalize it.
Either one of them, you can rationalize,
hey we shouldn't do anything at all.
Let's just stay inside the wire.
Let me protect my guys aid.
You could rationalize that
and you can rationalize,
hey go out and kill everybody
before they kill us.
And what you have to do as a
leader in a combat situation,
you have to balance those dichotomies and
you know you could translate that into
businesses. Cause you in a business,
you've got to take care of your people,
but you've got to make money,
you know,
so there's all these,
when you're in a leadership position
and there's opposing forces that are
pulling at you and you have to balance
them and you have to pay attention
because what happens is suddenly you start
going too far in one direction or the
other and you start to re,
you start to lose control where you
start to see things go sideways.
That's when you need to say to yourself,
wait a second,
am I going too far in one direction right
now? That's probably what is happening
now.
Here we go.
This is just a quick
little interlude they had,
they had acquired a 60 millimeter mortar
and they were training with it and one
of the guys was wanting to train it. They
didn't really let him use it too much,
even though he was excited to try it
out and they ended up getting attacked.
And the only guy that's into the vicinity
of the mortar to use it is this guy
Spangler.
And so he attempts to fire the mortar
and he screws it up a bunch of times and
the VC end up getting away
and Mcdonald's says,
dejectedly I scout I scowled at Spangler
who felt absolutely terrible about the
whole affair. I knew it
wasn't his fault, it was mine.
I had failed the train him even though
he was eager to learn more ownership
right there from mcdonough.
Now
this is,
this is just a shocker in the book and
it's one of those situations where he's
going really, this, how
does this even happen? Um,
Mcdonogh decides that they're,
they're actually by the ocean.
There are a couple of miles from the
ocean and they all have their skin.
They have jungle rot, their skin,
they get a little infections,
they got bug bites and they're
just all jacked up from this,
from just from just living
in this environment. And he
knows, he says, you know,
if we get these guys to
patrol down to the ocean,
they can take a swim in the ocean. They
get out in the sun dry. Some of their,
you know, wounds off or what
have you. So they go down there,
he puts together the plan.
He actually has to like ask the guys
to go, cause there's, they're saying,
you know what, I'd rather sit
here and just have bad skin.
Then go out and have to do another
patrol just to go swimming.
And he kind of convinced
as a couple of guys, hey,
there's a couple guys that want to go.
There's a couple of guys that say,
you know, I'd rather not go.
He convinces the guys to go.
He puts together a plan. He wants to
send some strong swimmers with the group.
He's actually pretty aware
of the danger of the ocean.
He sends the guys down there,
they get down there and to
the guy's drown and die.
And again,
we're going to hear some ownership here.
James was the guy that was running
the patrol and mcdonough says,
I could not criticize James.
He had not followed my instructions,
but the fault was mine,
not his.
I had built the idea into a plan
and then ordered its execution.
In so doing,
I had executed Spangler and Evans.
I felt a hundred years old,
no tragedy in that God forsaken
country had to hit me so hard.
It was my fault.
I was the cause of two deaths
in the name of good intentions.
I had talked those men into dying.
I staggered under the thought.
The cost of leadership had finally
been too high and I couldn't bear it.
I didn't consider myself fit to lead,
but the job was mine and I
couldn't quit for better or worse,
okay.
I had to do it.
They get back to camp and
oh Wilson,
who is good friends with the evidence
that one of the guys that had drown,
he says Wilson was
crying for loss of Evans.
His close friend had deeply affected him,
ashamed of his tears.
He hunkered down behind his machine gun
at the strong point on the south side of
the perimeter.
I spoke of Evan's goodness and try to
draw from that a benevolent interpretation
of his death.
Evans was at peace.
Now I told Wilson he was no
longer part of his nightmares war,
although I couldn't follow
the logic of my own words.
They seem to lighten the Wilson's load.
He began to talk together.
We groped for meaning and a man's death.
I did my best to conceal my own skepticism
and agreed with everything he said.
Somehow we came to the conclusion
that Evan's death was a good thing.
It must be good if God willed it.
By then I wasn't sure
who was consoling whom.
Sometimes words aren't
important for their content,
but only for there being said and whatever
we said that night seemed to be good
enough for both of us.
Although I couldn't excuse
myself for the drownings.
I realized that I owed it not only to
Wilson but the whole platoon to put the
incident behind me.
Okay.
Now the next situation that
they're in there doing an assault
and as they get through these, there's
assaulting all mine through a target area.
Then as they sold them online
through this target area,
there's a Viet Cong Penn.
His weapon had been smashed by around and
he wasn't able to fight and so he just
surrendered and this guy who I mentioned,
this Guy Nan before this Nan
is a Vietnamese guy. That's,
that's like a translator interpreter.
They call them Kit Carson Scouts.
They know that they know the area,
they speak the language and so he says,
ask him if he's got any
buddies on flank security.
I instructed Nan a rush of Vietnamese
words and sued only to be answered by know
Beck and American Vietnamese Slang
version of I don't understand.
God dammit. He speak in
Vietnamese to you. Answer him.
I shouted in the prisoner's face.
Nan asked him again,
demands face demand turned his face away.
Defiantly my anger was rising after my
worries of the night before about finding
our way to the target and the
successful attack that followed.
Everything could be
overturned by an arrogant,
by the arrogance of one prisoner.
Killigan seeing the way
my face was flushed,
made the quiet comment.
Don't be mad lieutenant.
He's just a soldier.
Same as you and me.
Damn him.
He was right.
I would hope to do the same if I were
in the shoes of a captive of the captive
Killigan. The quiet man who disavowed
all pretense of leadership. Once again,
made me aware of the fragile
superiority of my own leadership.
And then as they proceed on,
they take these captured guys
and they bring them back to the company
command post and we'll go back to the
book. At the end of the mornings fight,
we linked up with the rest of the company,
essentially a reinforced platoon that had
comp that comprise the blocking force.
I turned over our prisoners to
the platoon leader, a youngster,
and his first action, who I later found
out did not last another two weeks.
Predictably the company commander
had stayed back at the base,
bring the goat,
bring the Guccis over to the CP.
Lieutenant pastored my sergeant,
sergeant, they aren't geeks.
I said quietly,
they're soldiers just like you and me.
For a moment I thought I
saw Killigan Xyz flash.
Then we started our journey home.
They're going to go on up
company sized operation,
which means they're taking multiple
platoons of which Mcdonald's,
one of the platoon commanders and the
company commander was named Moray and
Morei calls them all
together to do brief moray.
And I haven't talked about this much,
but morays, kind of a guy that's,
he's not real proactive and
getting out in the field,
so he's sort of staying back on base.
He's a little nervous about the situation
and this is just a great example.
And then he's got the other
platoon commanders who you
kind of hear his judgment
on them, but this is a great
display of leadership of,
of taking ownership up and down the
chain of command and to his peers.
So the, here we go from the book and the
plan would put Marae who's the company
commander,
2000 meters away from our present
location and 4,000 meters away from the
objective.
I tried to conceal my disdain cer request,
permission to control the operational
movement of the maneuver forces in the
initial phase of the operation.
I spoke with what I hope with as a totally
expressionless face. So he's saying,
listen boss,
so you're going to be way over there.
Why don't I just go ahead and
control this? The boss says,
sure, Jim, I guess that makes sense.
You're the senior lieutenant among the
platoons. Did you have a plan in mind?
Marae was easy and I was going
to take advantage of it. Boom.
I briefed him on my consent to come.
My concept routes of movement where we
would set up time of anticipated contact
with the enemy and types of weapon.
Tree wouldn't carry the captain concurred
with the plans then excused himself.
I've got to get back to the CP and report
to battalion seeing an opportunity for
complete freedom of
action. I continued, sir,
I need to flesh out the details
with the other platoon leaders.
May I brief them in your absence?
Yes, certainly. Carry on.
He left as we stood up to salute.
So there you see what just happened,
how beautiful that was.
He took total control
and not only did he take
control up the chain of command,
but he's going to get some control
over the peers as well and he's,
he's judging and passing judgment on
the way the other platoons are running
their,
well,
the way the other platoon commanders
are running their platoons and he says,
observing all this,
I signed Lee Lee wrote Lieutenant
smally out of the plan.
If he could not exercise
minimum control in the defense,
he would surely fall apart in the attack.
Lieutenant Evans First
Platoon's leader was anxious.
He had been on the job only a week
and this was his first operation.
He was a tall, good looking boy from the
Midwest, but I felt he was too eager.
He was disappointed to be standing
pat for the night as the reserve unit,
but the call had been raised,
not mine.
Perhaps it was unfair of me to make snap
judgments of others and then plan my
axis on the basis of those judgments.
The fought bothered me,
but not enough to deter me.
I was in the business of evaluating
people and the traits of other men would
determine my own fate and that
of my soldiers presumptuous.
Though my role may have been, I had
to make judgments and act accordingly.
Marae was timid, smiley
was weak. Evans was eager.
I did not condemn them for that.
I noted it and adjusted.
We were in a war,
not a community social,
just great leadership example of how you
lead up and down the chain of command.
So now they're actually
about to head out on this,
on this operation about 50 meters shore
to the forward of the Stream Killigan
dog leg to the west and
brought us up on the trail.
The heavy labor and the Bush brought
beads of sweat to my forehead and I
concentrated in our present movement,
leaving thoughts of the
night operation for later,
we were assuming in the treacherous
position of doubling back on a previously
used root.
Always dangerous tactic for a second.
I considered yelling at
Killigan to get off the trail,
but we were so close to the Ford that by
the time we maneuvered off the trail we
would have been at the crossing site
as Killigan moved ahead and is stealthy
glide.
I saw him freeze momentarily and then
glanced to his left directly into a Bush
overlooking the trail.
I knew in an instant that we were
in eminent danger for Killigan.
Never made abrupt moves except at the
movement of conflict except at the moment
of conflict.
Killigan turned back to us,
his face contorting as
if to shout a warning.
I yelled ambush and dove to my left.
Killigan took a grenade blast and
the face at point blank range.
At the same time, Sergeant James went
down with this bullet in his shoulder.
The enemy was spraying us from a position
across the rice patty kill again and I
had hit a comp. Killigan had hit
a command detonated booby trap.
Okay.
I pressed my face into the dirt as
bullets wind over my outstretched body.
I calculated the best. At best.
There were only four of us were left.
I peeked out from under my helmet to see
James Struggling to get off the trail.
The red blotch widening in
his dark green fatigues.
He was moving not into the bushes,
but toward Killigan who is lying face
down in the patty with a plastic knocked
him his blood turning the yellowish
water read within minutes.
If he were still alive,
Killigan would drown.
Okay,
so they get killed or get out of that
situation. They get back to their base.
They go back again to do the ambush.
Their hit again on the ambush.
They evacuated guy,
they move again and now they're there
in the final moment where they are going
to do this big ambush
as part of the company.
So this is kind of what this last
section of the book is leading to.
It is morning until they're actually
doing their final movement into the ambush
position.
It is morning and there was a grime,
a grimness in the drizzling air.
Silent figures move to the West,
shoulders bent under equipment,
loads, buckles taped for silence,
camouflage paint on taught faces.
Google's in the night.
Young boys really from
places like Valdosta,
San Diego, boulder, Madison,
Portland out to kill Asian
boys who are out to kill them.
The gears of war grind together.
Unrelentingly mechanisms in motion that
will catch up human flesh as they mesh.
Society's clash,
politicians deal,
diplomats debate.
Young men struggle to the
death tomorrow or the next day.
Mothers will receive the news and cry,
but nothing will stop the mornings.
Killings,
okay,
they finally get to
their ambush site and now
the ambush is about to
happen simultaneously.
Another group of enemy walks
into the third ambush site.
It is tripped and all the enemy or
killed the first group of three.
Here's the melee and panics.
One Darts Back Nan,
the old scout catches him
with a round in the side.
He falls in and the old man finishes
him with two rounds in the head.
Two of the enemy scrambled through
sergeant don'ts positioned and our hit.
One falls dead.
The other scramp scampers into the brush.
Dawn pursues
the wounded enemy.
Ducks into a hole in the ground,
obviously is familiar with
the territory in Vietnamese.
Don't yells for him to come out.
There is no reply done. Yells again,
bullets spray out of the hole.
Done lobs a grenade. Dirt,
leaves and flesh fly out of the
opening in front of a blast.
Done throws a second grenade,
a death rattle.
Rasps from the whole Sergeant Dunn looks
around for the newest soldier spotting
an 18 year old.
He sends him in a safe way to harden
the youngster toward the events in store
for him during the year to come.
The youth emerges dragging
the Vietcong behind him.
It's a gruesome sight.
The man's face, nose,
mouth,
eyes are gone.
Air is sucked in and out of the hole
where the nostrils used to connect the
jelly,
like mass rising and falling in bubbles,
wounds, gape everywhere on his body.
There is nothing we can do for him.
It would be inhumane to prolong his agony.
So they accomplish that ambush and
they're continuing to press the enemy.
But something that Mcdonogh didn't count,
something that he couldn't have predicted
or that he failed to predict back to
the book.
But I underestimated the ruthlessness
of our enemy and I failed to realize the
extent to which political ideology
can displace human morality.
It was a major oversight and it costs us
the village of Trong Lam and Trong Lam
is the village that they were actually
their perimeters next to this whole time.
And I should have gone over
that right in the beginning,
but Trong Lam is the village
that they were there to protect.
They're there to protect these villagers
and keep them safe and keep the Viet
Cong and the communist out of the area.
So they're sitting in their, in
their perimeter one night, you know,
they're literally just
meters from the village.
And that's where this whole story is
taking place and as they're sitting there,
and we'll go to the book,
the first explosion ripped one of the
hots apart in a blaze of brilliant orange
and yellow flame. Another
definitely explosion than
another rip through the air,
punctuated by the Staccato
clatter of automatic weapons.
We braced trying to print,
pinpoint the direction of the attack.
My God, I explained, I exclaimed
to no one in particular,
they're hitting the village.
It would be a butchery.
The Viet Cong had pennys
traded the eastern end of
the village and we're moving
from thatch hut to thatch hut,
throwing Satchel charges inside and
shooting down anything that moved.
Sergeant Palamon
leave back third squad and come with me.
We're counter attacking into
the village and two minutes
they dashed for the village.
We dashed for the village.
As the flames burst upward,
the scene revealed before us was ghastly.
A mother ran by me with
her decapitated baby,
her own left arm hanging by a strip
of flesh to Viet cong stood behind her
trying to shoot them down in cold rage.
I fired into their faces,
their heads collapsing into pulpy mush.
Two young girls came running at me.
Tears of pain streaming from their eyes.
At a glance, I could see that both
had been disfigured by shrapnel.
The Vietcong had their mission kill as
many villagers as quickly as possible and
they were doing it well,
but they didn't expect our sudden
rush upon them at point blank range
from somewhere in the smoke and fire.
A woman emerge with her young song.
She thrust the little boy at me
begging for help in Vietnamese.
The boy was folded completely
in half at the stomach,
a deep wound across the small of his
back allowing his fat little body to be
creased as neatly as a piece of cardboard.
Surely he was dead.
I looked into the mother's eyes and
patted her on the head. Later, I said,
I'll help you later. We press the
attack back to the edge of the village.
Almost a fourth of it was now burning.
One more American fell with a
chest wound and collapsed his lung.
We broke the back of the attack.
Vc bodies late sprawled on the wire
through which they could not withdraw
the dead and dying. Lee Everywhere. A bid.
Amid the burning huts from the
glare of the roaring flames,
I could see dead and wounded Vietnamese
laying in twisted piles already.
The older women had begun their pitiful
whales of morning shrieking and tearing
at their hair and faces.
Smoke filled the air,
but it could not cover the acrid smell
of death that filled my nostrils.
Children's search for their missing elders
are huddled in groups groping at each
other for comfort there.
Eyes wide and terror.
A mother rock to one legged baby to her
breast is lifeless eyes undisturbed by
the bright flame sill writing them both
the worst had happened.
The enemy had struck directly against
the village and it most assuredly killed
and wounded many of their own families.
It was unbelievable,
but it had been done.
I knew that Trong Lam had been a defeat
like the entire American system in
Vietnam. We had fought a limited
military war with constrained objectives.
The enemy had fought a total political
war with no preordained restrictions.
We were doomed from the outset.
We were the focus of the Vietcong attacks
because we kept the village alive if
we died so with the village,
but even at that,
we were the indirect objective,
the village with the direct objective.
If the villages were destroyed,
then there would be no village,
but only now did I understand
that kind of logic.
It had not occurred to me that the
enemy could take such a step to hit.
The village would ensure the wounding
and killing of their own kin in a battle
within the confines of the village itself.
There could be no
discrimination among family,
communist sympathizers
and government loyalists.
Every day I saw the children
of the village. They were
like all children. Cute,
endearing, growing with the emotional
and physical needs of children,
the world over. I couldn't
hurt them. It was unthinkable.
The possibility was so barbaric
that it was alien to my mind,
but my mind was not the mind of the enemy
do I tried to understand them even to
think like them if only to defeat them.
I had fallen short for a few more days.
We continued to patrol the area.
It was a bureaucratic gesture,
a mere continuance of what we
had been doing for so long.
I kept to myself my own recognition
of the emptiness of our work.
It was essential for the
men to be convinced of the
importance of their mission.
Chuang lamb was no more,
but leadership must always be positive.
So he wasn't really expecting that,
that the VC would come in
and just slaughter everyone
in the village or as many
people as they good,
unbelievable savagery.
Mm.
Now, as we wrap this up, he's,
he's [inaudible]
gets his relief just like he covered
in the beginning of the book and it's,
he takes over for somebody. Somebody
comes to take his place and he leaves
and he tries to keep track of what
happened to them or how they fought and
things that occurred. And we'll
go to the book here as scheduled.
The platoon moved on and continued
to fight as long as I could.
I kept the watch on the fate of the
men specialists nail was wounded,
yet again,
platoon sergeant Palamon got out in front
of the platoon in a firefight and took
an enemy rocket propelled
grenade in the right leg.
I learned that corporate
Killigan survived his wounds,
although we lost a long and
a stretch of intestines.
Sergeant Don made it home on touch
to one of the few Sergeant James and
specialists king were killed.
Although the circumstances surrounding
their deaths were never made clear to me.
Okay.
And so it went.
An infantry man's days are numbered and
the law of attrition applied to the tune
as it always did.
In the summer of 1971 I flew out of
camera on Bay to return to my wife and
infant son.
I had just made captain.
It had been a long 12 months and I
had changed in more ways than rank.
Okay.
At National Airport in Washington,
D c a pretty young woman stood waiting
in the terminal as I walked up the ramp
by her knee, just did a 15 old
child with curly blonde hair,
barely able to keep his balance
on his chubby little legs.
Okay.
I kissed them both. Hello.
The woman was happy.
The boy was confused.
I was both.
I was also sad.
I mourn for the men I had left behind.
I grieved that their country would
never know what fine men they were.
I was proud to have served with them
and no doubt,
bye.
Absolutely feel the same way.
The amazing men and women who I saw
cut down
at the height of their lives
and our country will never really
know what fine people they were,
what fine human beings they were,
and I hope that from that,
from their sacrifice we can take and
we can learn from what they learned
or we can be inspired by them and driven
by them and become better leaders and
better people from their example.
Dan from the example of
men like Jim Mcdonald,
Hackworth and Bob Hoffman
tanned, all those other,
those warriors and leaders
that have taken point
and led the way.
And we
try to follow them down that path
as we remember those
who gave their lives
to clear that path for us.
Just so much to be taken away
from this experience.
And
it's almost like,
let's just read the whole book,
but there's so much more that I
didn't cover that I wanted to.
And you know, the fact of the matter is
you can get this book on Amazon. You Go,
you buy the book, you learn. That's
what you do. You don't have to
live through this stuff to be able to
take away some of the lessons from it.
And
because that was such a, such a good book,
and there's so much information in it,
obviously I went long.
So we're going to hold off until
next time to do a little Q and.
A.
Uh,
but
if you do want to support the podcast,
there's a couple of ways you can do that.
Number one.
You can go to
the website Jocko,
store.com. You can click on the Amazon
link and you can buy this book right here.
The book is called platoon leader,
a memoir of command in combat
by James our mcdonough,
and you should do that.
You should do yourself that favor.
Yeah.
Also,
another way it could be simpler
is just go to the website Jocko,
podcast.com and go into the books section
where it list all of the books that
you cover. That'd be on there.
You just click on the book, boom.
It'll take you right to the, to
the Amazon link even easier. Yeah.
That way you don't have to
search if you're, you know,
if you're in a time crunch.
I like that. What else? What else
can we do to support the podcast?
Um, just if you're going to
buy anything from Amazon,
go to the Jacqueline store.com
or Jocko podcast.com.
Click on the Amazon link
before you do your shopping.
It'll take you to Amazon
just like you would have gone
anyway. And then, you know,
you do your shopping. There you go.
You can support that way passively.
And then I'm also on Jocko store if
you like, you know the shirts. We got
some coffee mugs on there, some
stickers, whatever. Um, you know,
I feel like you of that stuff,
just get some gets up.
And uh,
of course if you're in to supplements
or you're running low on supplements,
go to or go back to on
it.com/jocko and uh,
and get some,
those are the good ones.
Pick up some krill oil for yourself.
Pick up some strong bone.
Pick up where your bars,
some warrior bars.
Somebody got a little low or just got a
little shit been a warrior bars in today
and I want to say thank you. It's just
a game. It's just, it saves the day.
It saves the day. Little snacky
snack. Someone asked, uh,
our warrior bars, uh, postworkout
or are they a meal replacement?
Like what are they? All the above. It's
all of that. And it's just a snack.
It's a snack but then eat too.
That's a little meal. Eat three.
That's like a full meal more or less.
Maybe with a salad or something,
but it's, yeah, it's, it's good.
As always,
if you want to kind
kick it with echo and I,
you can do that right on
the old inner webs. And I am
at Jocko Willink. Echo Charles is at
Echo Charles. That's on the Twitter.
That's on the Facebook. Uh,
that's also on the Instagram. Oh,
quick thing about the Instagram.
I just found this out not yesterday,
but the day before that there's a
like direct messages on Instagram.
You probably didn't even know that.
I did not know that because they have
it on Twitter and people send me direct
messages. Okay. So you can show me how to
check that. Well, yeah. Okay. So he was,
listen,
people sent me some messages and a lot
of people send me some and it's been,
I've had Instagram for a long time. Yeah.
So there's a lot of men. I'm like, aw man,
I got to respond. But basically
if, if I don't respond,
it's not because I'm ignoring it,
it's cause straight up.
I didn't know what was going
on. You're supposed to be
the, the, the tech guy here.
Oh Man, I know. Dang. Yeah,
I'm learning that. Hey, look,
I learned. Right. You did good.
Did learn.
Uh,
with that you can join us there and you
can join us as we continue to try and
get a little bit better and
try and do a little bit better.
And we got examples of
leadership like mcdonough,
like the people that we talk about,
the people that I admire and the
people that I look to and say, yes,
that person stepped up and led.
That's the example that I try and follow
people that stepped up and led through
hard situations,
who dealt with the dichotomy of
leadership and yet dealt with the almost
unwinnable situations, dealt with rules
of engagement, dealt with challenges,
dealt with their own
platoon leader members,
threatening them to kill them,
dealt with all those things.
And yet they still lead.
Yeah.
And so us, we got it easy. We got it easy.
So there's no excuse.
None to stop any of us from getting up.
Okay.
Then getting after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.