This is Jocko podcast number
25 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink.
And once again we have this evening Jody
Mitic and if you didn't listen to the
last podcast,
this is our first double guests.
He's been on the podcast twice.
We went so long on the first podcast
that we had to break it up into two
podcasts, but Jody had a lot
of, been through a lot of stuff,
had a lot of stuff to talk about.
Canadian army soldier sniper,
served in Afghanistan,
member of the city council up in Ottawa.
He's been on TV.
He wrote this book right here.
Boom.
It's called unflinching,
the making of a Canadian sniper
and he was wounded in Afghanistan,
lost d,
double amputee below the knees.
And uh, we talked about that on the
first podcast. If you haven't lived on,
on podcast number 24,
if you haven't listened to that one,
listen to that one first so you get the
context of what we're about to go into
tonight. But welcome to the show once
again, Jodi. Awesome man. Thank you.
Appreciate it. Echo Charles.
Good evening. Good evening.
So
or this one since we already talked
for a long time on the first one.
It didn't feel like a long time. No
it didn't. But this time we got some,
we did get some questions
from the interwebs and it
was now do you strictly pull
from Twitter or do you get emails?
Email. Get on Twitter. I get Facebook.
And what about your Instagram?
Okay.
The problem with Instagram is you
can't copy and paste from Instagram.
Oh that's on my phone into the document
that I travel with. And you're going,
so Twitter is the one that Twitter is
the easiest one. Facebook's fine too.
But I primarily use Twitter to get the
questions from all the troopers out there.
That and it keeps the questions short.
Yes. You have 140 characters. Yeah.
And we know I've got now,
so I have something called the the
question podcast question bank. Right.
Which I've caught, captured every
question that anyone's ever asked me.
They're in there and I just,
every time I, you know,
you got a chance of coming up
in the lottery every time. Nice.
Cause I go through it and I go through
all from the beginning and just look for
questions that are pertinent.
Maybe the pertinent of the topic
that I'm talking about that night.
Maybe it's pertinent to something
that's going on in the world,
but I just pick them and say,
oh yeah that,
that's a question that people have or
I'll see repetitive question people,
a bunch of different people will ask me
the same thing and then that becomes one
of the questions. But that's kind of how
we've been doing it. Right. So do you,
do you find you get, cause you, you know,
we, I don't want to hash it out too much,
but like your podcast went
from nonexistent to number
one in a boat like six
days or something crazy
like that. Like you, you left
the Joe Rogan podcast, did,
you did started your own hit number one.
And like now like do you
get too much correspondence?
Like how do you keep up like I've
noticed you are, you're like,
you must make Twitter a daily
pass out.
And I'll be honest with you,
I don't know how long I'm going to be
able to keep it up for. Yeah, because,
so you're approaching critical mass.
I'm approaching critical mass
where I'm going to have two more.
I'm not going to be able to cause
right now I read every single,
probably always read them all. I mean
unless it just gets crazy. But I,
I I at least read them and I'll try
and respond. If it's something quick,
if it's not something I
can respond to immediately,
I'll just put it in the question bank.
And
would you ever consider getting
someone to do it for, you know,
like not answer but like take it all in,
record it like,
so you don't have to check yourself
maybe. I guess that seems like something
Tim Ferris would tell me to do,
which is we just smart or
a kid in Pakistan, right?
For eight bucks an hour. No.
And maybe that's a smart thing to do.
The problem I find with
that is I wouldn't,
if I was wanting to talk to me and I was
one of the troopers out there, I'd want,
I'd rather have take the chances of
not hearing anything back from me,
but know that the guy that actually
read this thing was me. Oh,
I ran 100% with you.
I've had people,
well tell me to hand my stuff over.
And I'm like [inaudible] cause that's me.
Yeah. There one reason why I
interact with Jocko on Twitter,
it's because I know it's job.
Yeah. Yeah. And I think that's a
feeling most people would have.
I know I would have.
Yes. Who you and guess who I unfollow on
Twitter when I realize, oh that's not,
that's us of him or her. Oh, okay. So
yeah,
for me it's like if you're in a
leadership position and you lead,
you send someone else to do your
bidding. Ooh, that's to me is not good.
And I wouldn't like that if I
was a follower. Yeah. Well, yeah,
to the whole point of social media.
And the other thing is I get a lot of
good feedback from people and also people
are always like, oh you inspire me and
you when I say you would inspire me too.
Cause there's people that are out
there grinding it out in their worlds,
in their lives. And I say man the world
is filled with a bunch of [inaudible],
a bunch of Lazy slackers that I'm used to.
You get on the, you get on the Twitter,
the Jocko troopers, man, they're getting
after it. All of them are charging. Yeah.
They're not getting out there and saying
hey I don't feel like I'm going to get
after it today.
I think I'm going to say no.
They're like it's four oh seven and I'm
in the game and I go damn I got to keep
my game in check.
Yep.
I love, I love it when I
see like I'll see ya. Yah.
Cause you always put the picture of
your watch when you wake up. Yes I do.
And then I'll see like a
retweet with like, you know,
somebody else's watch and there's like a
thousand watches with like your picture
and there's right next to it.
And I'm like, oh, it's 6:00 AM where I
am all. Look at that. I love you man.
But I ain't getting up at four.
That's just me. I don't have any legs.
So I got an excuse. Right.
I don't, but uh, but it's,
I feel the same cause it's
like it's, it's a duty now.
Yeah. You, we've put ourselves in a
position where others turned to us,
so now we got to turn to them.
And if we don't show up, Oh,
who we let in down. I'm not, it's not
that I'm letting me down, you know,
it's that you're going to let down all,
what do you got?
Like 25,000 Twitter followers or
something like 40 40 40 something.
Yeah. That's 40,000 people that
are waiting for your 4:00 AM. Yeah.
You know, that's, that's
good. But it keeps you, keeps
you on. It keeps you sharp.
It keeps you on the days.
I say it,
I got days where I'll look at my
prosthetic legs and he'll be like, ah,
the last thing I want to do is put those
things on today and then I'll think
about it. Everybody else
that is my position and said,
and I get it cause I get the
same thing, right? All, hey man,
thanks for being who you are
and I'm thinking about them.
Well they're going to get
up. So who am I? You know,
and I love when I find like
when I following guys like
you though helps me go on
a lazy bitch. People see I get a
lot done. Look at this guy and then,
oh look at her, look at that kid. Oh Man,
I better step my game up to normal people.
I know a bunch of regular people with
regular lives are doing what they can to
get ahead and dig in and then something
happened and that does fire me up.
You know what? That does? Fire me up
to see people. It feels good. Yeah.
And wanting to, yeah, just had
someone today, this is this.
A woman came into the gym. To
my gym. Yeah. And she said,
they called me down. Oh,
there's someone here to see you.
I'll come down and it's a woman whose
daughter is fired up for the podcast,
fired up for the book.
They actually,
they actually named it and
I have a crossfit gym. It's
called crossfit Overwatch.
I like, yeah, you can't give me
tingles. Yeah. Yeah. And it go there.
Great Nouns of obviously because of,
you know,
Overwatch as we talk about in the book.
And so yeah,
here's this woman, she was
like, to be honest with you,
she was kind of tearing up a
little bit like that, fired up.
How humbling is it when somebody
feels like that around you? It's,
it's motivating to me.
Nobody,
it's today think that you can have that
you like in my case me that Jody Mitic,
the guy who just wanted to be a soldier
and somebody is that like fired up to
meet me, that they're shaking. Damn.
Well I gotta I gotta I gotta keep my
game up. Yeah. And it's weird too,
and we actually talked about this on the
podcast wants is like don't put me on a
pedestal as if I'm something
great cause I'm not man.
I'm not. I'm, I'm uh, I'm weak
and soft and do stupid things.
You know what I mean?
Don't put
me on a pedestal, but put
yourself on a pedestal, you know,
put yourself on a pedestal and rise
up yourself. Don't worry about me.
Spring board off my back
and go to a higher level.
That's what I want to see happen.
That's what I would want.
I don't want people to
put me on a pedestal.
I want them to stand on my shoulders and
go higher and further than anything I
could ever do.
That's what I like.
Did it, did it take you, this is
a personal question on my end.
Did it take you awhile to see
like when somebody would say,
you inspire me and thank
you for being who you are.
Did you accept that at first or did
you have to tell them like Donna,
now I don't it like you just said like,
I'm nothing special.
But how long did it take you before you
would, except that compliment without,
without dismissing it.
I literally,
right. The first person that's said that
to me, I said, no man, you inspire me.
You know, because your guess
what? I've had a great life.
I've had a great life and I'm
stoked. Right. Okay. But look at you.
You're saying I inspire you, look at
you or inspire me. You're a single mom
with two or three jobs getting after
it. And by getting after it, I mean,
waiting tables,
uh,
working in as an admin assistant and
then doing some babysitting at night.
Yeah. And helped me with homework and
making lunches and, and, and, right. Oh,
so Jocko is really, really, no, actually
you are. Yeah. You're fired up. Yeah.
I just, I asked because it
took me awhile because I, I,
I had a real hard time with people looking
at me like that and I actually would,
I would be like dismissive
of it. At first. I'd be like,
Nah, what are you doing?
What are you talking about? I'm just,
I'm nobody special. Like don't, don't,
don't say that.
And I realized I was being a bit of
a dick by completely dismissing their
feelings for, for, for the
situation. And then it was until I,
until I realize though, and then that's
when I realized I went, oh, this is,
this is real. These people
actually do feel this. And I'm,
who am I did to dismiss their feelings,
you know?
So I try to try to use it to be
stronger and realize like, you know,
like this is real.
Like people are looking up to me.
So now I've got to live up to that role.
I'll tell you another thing that I tell
people when they say something like that
to me, I tell them, look,
there's many people that have done way
more than me and sacrificed way more than
me.
100% and the fact that
you think that about me,
the only reason you think that
about me is cause you know me.
You know who I am because I
stepped out of the darkness and,
and into the public view.
But otherwise there's a bunch of
a bunch of warriors that they're
never going to know their name.
They're never going to be able
to say, hey, you inspire me.
So there's throwing that in my direction
and I tell them, look, you don't,
I don't inspire you. You get
inspired by what I stand for. And
what I represent is thousands and
thousands of servicemen seals.
Yes. Soldiers, yes. Marines.
Yes. All of them. Yeah. Yeah.
That's what, that's what you're saying.
And, and so on behalf of all of them,
I get it. Cause you know what, those
soldiers, those marines, those seals,
those guys in special operations,
they inspire me too.
And so I think there's,
that's kind of the, it's a give
and take. Yeah. Okay. Yeah, no,
I had to ask you,
because I went through such a with,
with the legs and everything, I was
just trying to accept not having legs,
nevermind that I had a woman
come up to me and say, uh,
I had to like add several actually. But
this, this was like maybe the first,
I think she said I lost a hundred
pounds because of you. And I'm like,
first of all, you don't even look like
you weigh a hundred pounds. And I'm like,
Huh, what did I do? I'm just being me.
And that was the one that really in my
mind, like at that moment I went, okay,
there's I gotta I gotta reevaluate
what's going on here. Yeah.
I can't just dismiss this as I'm
just Jody Mitic anymore. Clearly,
clearly there's something going on.
Well I think your story in particular
strikes a real chord with people because
you had to overcome some crazy adversity.
And by the way, your adversity,
while challenging as you know,
well there's guys with much
more challenging adversity
than you've had 10 fold,
a hundred fold. And so, you know,
for me it's a joke for you,
you at least get a sense.
But you and me both know and we've seen
guys and we know guys that have had it,
like I said, infinitely worse than
you. Unimaginable, unimaginable.
And so those guys that get up with
their issues and press on and drive on,
look to them for inspiration.
Absolutely look right past me.
Look right past Jodie, look at those
guys who are doing what they're doing.
And that to me is,
is where inspiration comes from.
And so I guess inspirations
around you everywhere. Yeah,
really is if you open your eyes to it
and you look at what other human beings
do, it's, it's amazing. Yeah.
It's amazing. I love, I love it.
I love humans. Humans are such, we're
such a species, that study, you know,
like, so anyway, I know we
wanted to get to the inner webs,
but I wanted to have that discussion
with you before we moved on because, uh,
it was just important to me to hear that
the discussion has been had Roger and I
think it's, yeah, I think it's a, I
think it's awesome. I think it's awesome.
And yeah, like I said,
I see why people are coming
up and telling you that. Yeah,
I agree with them actually. Well,
thanks buddy. All right. Make me blush.
We need to get to some questions from
the interwebs. No. Okay, now I get it.
All right,
here we go.
Okay.
Mental exercises to learn to control
one's pulse and breathing in really
stressful situations or when very nervous.
What do you do?
Mental exercises.
So we touched on this very
briefly in the last episode,
which was on the book and
where I talk a little bit about
sniper training.
Um,
visualization is probably
your biggest tool and in what?
In my experience, train, train
the shit out of it. Train, train,
train. And when you think you've
trained enough to keep training,
but when you're not training,
think about it.
Think about it.
The more you think about it,
become in tune with yourself. Okay?
I'm going to get a little spacey here.
Little earthy,
just sit there
because you know what you do when
your sniper, you fucking sit there,
you have a lot of time to yourself.
You can't really talk
cause you got a job to do.
And what you gotta do is you just got to,
okay,
I know my heart rate's gonna go up here,
but I got to do my best to make sure it
doesn't overwhelm my motor functions.
And you can control it pretty meant that
pretty easily if you prepare yourself
for that moment. But it's all about
preparation, training and visualization.
Um, even like even making
the shot, you know,
like Tim Kennedy was on here, right.
And you talked about dry firing,
consider dry firing that
this is your dry firing for,
for your, for controlling yourself, for
your brain, for your brain. Exactly.
And dry fire your brain
like that. And, and um,
it only comes from experience.
Now I guess there's probably
some exceptions of the rule
out there that are just
born to be cold blooded killers that
second they get behind a barrel. But,
but for me it was,
it was visualization and just preparing
to accept the feelings that were coming
and also overriding them cause
that they could still be happening,
but you can still control yourself
with the right kind of preparation.
And it's also a perishable
skill. Funny enough, I realized,
I don't know if that
answered the question.
No, I think that's, I think
that's good. And I think for me,
one thing that I, that I
know I do, and this is a,
I guess it's,
it may be considered a technique,
but it's like the technique creates the
solution. Let me explain this to you.
One of the things that I
do in stressful situations,
there's something that I always try and
do and that is no matter what's going on,
I try and remain calm in my voice.
So when things are going crazy, I try
and get on the radio and say, hey,
we need two more people over here.
Not, we need two more people over here.
So if you're gonna talk in a calm,
controlled voice,
then you can't be breathing hard.
You can't be excited,
you can't get angry,
you can't get frustrated.
You have to lock all that up and get it
under control before you open your lips
and start saying something.
And so I'm always very focused
on I am going to sound calm,
cool and collected when I opened
my mouth that way. And when,
and in doing that,
the only way to make that happen is
to do everything we just talked about.
Control your breathing, control
your pulse, control your emotions,
get all those things under
control, and then say, all right,
we need two more guys
down here immediately now.
And everybody goes, oh,
okay, let's make this happen.
And for coming from you, especially
you're the, in your, in your case,
you are the boss. So if you're, if
you're calm, cool and collected,
that translates to your troopers.
It absent. Right. So when we win,
and it would for us as well, when we were
doing Overwatch, you know, six to six,
three you move into your left.
Well, no, no, no, no. Your
left. Right. Think about what
happens. What do you do that,
imagine if I went shit six there on
your left or on your left. Right.
I'm freaking out.
Uh, they would, it would all be,
it would be lost. But you're,
that you're that voice because we're
over snipers or Overwatch. We, they,
the troops feel better when
they know, okay, there's
snipers doing Overwatch. Okay,
we can, we're going to be okay. So if I
get on the radio and talked the same way,
so you know, nope. Okay. Yet a
justifier 400 meters north, you know,
fire for effect. Roger that, you know,
like you got to, that's a good point.
I never even thought of that.
I think airline pilots trained that cause
you know when you hit the turbulence
and there, oh hey guys,
sorry about that term. Yeah,
just go ahead and put your seat and
I, yeah. Actually if you hear sully,
the guy that landed all may
river, he's like that. Yeah. Yeah.
We're going to have to write it down.
They have to teach them that because
that's where people are so apprehensive
when they're in the plane. Part
about that is he's like, yeah,
well we'll be in the river. And
the guy, he's like, uh, say again.
We'll be in the Hudson,
Roger out and like the plane,
it's like real time you're watching the
video and he's just like, yeah, yeah,
we're in the river. We're in the
room. It's like, Oh man, what? Oh,
by controlling these items,
in order to control his voice,
he's got to control his breathing.
He's got to control his temper.
He's got to control his emotions. And
so that's what I do in those situations.
And I'll tell you what,
if I haven't, if I don't,
if I'm not in a situation
where I need to talk,
I'll just talk to myself and be like,
okay, you know, just say that in my head.
All right,
what is the next book?
I know we're spending a lot of
time on the first question. That's,
that's what saved my life.
Oh hmm. Staying, if I had
gone into shock, dude,
I'd be dead. Right? Yeah.
And I say it in the book.
I say I did my best to go into the zone.
So I know I'm bleeding it and
I know this and I know that.
But in my mind it was let
the system do its job.
Okay. Everything's gonna be fine,
Jody. It's okay. And I just,
I just kept saying, talking to myself,
you know, visualizing what, okay.
So the chopper's going to come in,
you know,
and I just visualized each step and my,
my,
but the whole point to it was I
couldn't have my pulse, you know,
Jack Hammer or otherwise or bloods
lost more blood loss and then your,
and what happens,
right?
Blood gets sucked into your core when you
go into shock and that sucks it out of
your brain. I said I'd of
everywhere we were, you know,
I needed to stay conscious.
So No. Anyway, long long
answer for one question,
but this is also something, you
know, you got to learn. Practice,
keep practicing it.
You'll figure it out.
Yeah. And always, and we talk about
this again all the time on the podcast.
Inoculate yourself to these
stressful situations. That's right.
[inaudible] that's the guy's name.
Yes. Stress Inoculation. Yup.
Inoculate yourself to the stress so
that when you, you get used to it. Yeah.
The more stressful such, I mean training,
going through training, man, they,
they put all kinds of stresses at you
so that you learn to deal with it.
And if you want to learn how to cook,
that's your time to practice controlling
all those things. Absolutely.
And I'm not trying to go level
seven Zen Buddha on you all.
Like you need to get in the mind state
to control your breathing. Like no,
it's a practical thing. It's a real thing.
It's not a yoga thing. It's a practical,
real thing of, Hey, get calmed
down, take a deep breath,
get yourself under control.
Now it's time to talk and give clear,
concise orders that are calm.
Yeah.
Or make that shot or crack one
off if you're the sniper zone.
Lack of bad guy.
All right,
next question.
What does God think of the soldier first
principle in the Canadian armed forces
is expertise such as his
being lost due to this?
Oh, I think they're talking about the,
um, university ability of service,
which means, uh, everyone
must be able to deploy.
So
I didn't realize what it meant until
I lost my feet and instead in my mind,
you know, this was something else.
Okay, I can't deploy anymore,
but I can go to the sniper
school and teach the next
generation of snipers. Sure.
But you're not going to get promoted and
this and that no more. You know, like,
Huh, I was supposed to get promoted
to surgeon. Like, what do you,
what are we talking about here?
So university out of the service
says if you are not deployable,
you're not employable and you can't be
promoted and you can't get any courses in
this, that and the thing. So because of
it, we lose a lot of corporate knowledge.
Right. So I was, like I said, I was a,
what we call a master
sniper at advanced sniper.
And that doesn't mean I get access to the,
um,
Canadian temple of sniper sniper down to
see the secret 13th scroll or anything.
It just means I'm allowed to do the
paperwork and handout qualifications and
stuff like that.
Now it is a very difficult qualification
to achieve and they spend a lot of
money getting me there and that value
is completely erased with my injuries.
So soldier first is,
if you're not deployable yet,
then you're going to, you're unemployable.
Yeah. Okay. So under that system,
you get however many years to recover from
whatever your injury is at that point,
if you're not recovering
or going to recover,
they will then begin the process
to release you from the force. Acto
they're convinced that it's required
because of the size of our military.
Where my take is,
I believe that the opposite,
because of the size of our military.
You want guys like me doing the training,
the guys with the experience,
the guys who want to be there to train
the guys and can't deploy for as long as
possible.
Now,
I'm not saying put me in a spot and
leave me there for 15 years to become a
dinosaur,
but allow me to pass on the
knowledge I have and remain useful.
Right. But, but they, and
they say you can for the,
for the limited number of years,
and they,
they offer these things that
they call extensions in that,
but you're not going to get promoted.
So forget about a better pension.
You're not going to do this and
you're not gonna do that. Um,
and the dichotomy as the word that I,
I never used to use that word as much.
I used it.
I was one of the few people use it,
but not nearly as much as since I started
listening to the Jocko podcast. Um,
the dichotomy of it is that
we,
our version of the Pentagon,
and I'm going to get a lot
of trouble for saying this,
but there's a whole lot of people whose
physical fitness probably keeps them
from being able to do anything
and they're not being,
they're not getting least suited now.
And it's one of those like open secrets,
you know what I'm saying? And, uh,
and I'm sorry if people get mad
at me for that and stuff, but
I'm willing to run half marathons and,
and do crossfit without
legs and stuff like that.
And you still don't want to
promote me or keep me? Well,
I'm going to point out a few
issues with your system and I,
I don't blame the military, right? Like
in the military as a system, like we said,
the big green machine or roll on with
or without you at some point you gotta
worry about you.
And that's at some,
I just started worrying about more about
me than a boat, then the boat, mommy,
the big mommy military.
And, but then I, you know,
when I look back over my shoulder,
every now and then I go tell me
that guy over there is deploying,
show me what, show me his Med med
show. Many pull ups. Can he do? Yeah.
And so anyway, it's, um, I believe it,
I'm sure someone somewhere thinks it's
a good idea, but I think the millet,
the Canadian forces should reexamine
what it actually means because it's very
black and white. Yeah. That's, and
there's no room for, um, oh, walk. Okay.
So here's an example, real quick example
and we can move on. We used to have, um,
we're in no rush,
Jodi.
We used to have a thing
we call acting lacking.
So you are acting as sergeant lacking
qualification and it would be a way to
like promote guys that maybe
can't quite get, you know,
maybe they did have an
injury or something and um,
and they got rid of it as we
went back into combat basically.
Yeah.
So you had all these guys getting
smashed in combat now getting told like,
oh yeah, we can't make an exception
so you can't get promoted.
So I was one of them.
I was on the cusp of being promoted.
Sergeant just had to come home and do a,
what we call,
it's called a small arms course and it
makes you an expert in all small arms in
the infantry and how to train
with them to train troopers.
And then you get promoted surgeon and
when you learn some surgeon leadership
stuff as well. But um, I was number
one in my regiment to go do it.
And when I got, after I got
wounded, they're like, yeah,
sorry man. I'm like, well,
can I just be acting lacking so my
pension is better? Like, Oh yeah,
we don't do that anymore. Yeah,
that's, I can see why. I mean,
we're only in combat.
Guys are getting smashed all the time.
So why would you want to promote them
and let you know like the administrative
side of the military? It can be
very a heartless sometimes. Yeah.
I remember when I was in San Antonio
telling this to some medical colonels and
she was like, Huh. She's like, I promoted
a guy who's in a coma the other day.
We don't, we don't give a shit down here.
No. If you, if we think you deserve it,
you get your promotion because we know
it makes things better for you when you
get out.
So should I be bitter about
not getting promoted? No,
I'm, I'm, I'm over it, but I'm bitter.
You didn't get promoted how you like them
apples. Yeah. Thank you. But you know,
at the same time, there's a lot
of amazing people in a lot of, uh,
difficult spots in of
leadership and you know,
you gotta pick your battles too.
Yeah. Right. So anyway, I'll tell you,
as you pointed out,
yeah, that's really good.
What you said about the guys getting
promoted that or Tacoma. That's awesome.
I can't speak to the whole military.
I can say in the seal teams we did a,
we do an outstanding job of
taking guys that get wounded. And
as a matter of fact,
one of my guys who was real bad Ryan job,
who is awesome,
big goals.
Then he got shot in the face,
got blinded,
and he was like,
I'm staying in.
He's telling me I'm staying in. I mean,
you wanted to come back to Iraq. When he,
before he found out he was born there,
he was blind.
He still wanting to come back. But, um,
then like when we came home
from deployment and everything,
and you know, he's, he's
blind and he says, yeah,
I want to stay in the teams.
And I talked, I was, uh,
I was friends with the admiral that was
in charge of all the seals. And I said,
hey, sir, I know this might sound
crazy, but, you know, running job,
he wants to stay in the teams
and just keep being a team guy.
And he's like, we'll find a
job for him, which is awesome.
It is awesome.
But was he going to get promoted?
He would've given where he would just,
they would have put, found a job for him.
And he actually ended up saying,
you know,
what kind of became to the same
conclusion that you made, which is like,
you know what, I can't do like the
actual job of being a seal. Now.
He had tons of lessons. He
could have passed on, passed on,
which would have been awesome. Uh, but he,
he made a decision, hey, you know what,
I'm gonna move on. Okay. And
so he got out. So what would
have happened? Don't know.
There's, he, I, he have stayed
in and I would hope, you know,
that was one admiral who was a great guy,
who had a great attitude and
supporting and supporting the teas.
And that's the one thing that,
that admiral always said to me.
This is an admiral I worked
for for about 13 months.
I was the aide to the admiral in charge
of all the seals. Outstanding Guy.
But one of the things that he would
say during meetings and you know,
he'd be all these politicians
that you're talking about,
all these administrative people
all the big bureaucracy
that you're talking about.
And he would see what asked them. They'd
go through their big presentation about,
we're going to cut this, we're going
to do that, we're going to buy this,
but we're not gonna buy that.
And he'd say,
how does this affect the platoons?
Oh like,
cause cause people would forget that.
The whole reason you're there.
The whole reason to any
of that infrastructure or
anything is there is how does
it support the platoons?
How has it helped the seals?
How's it help the machine gunner?
How does it help the sniper out there?
The radio man, the guys that are
actually doing the job that we have,
and I say this to businesses sometimes
when I work with businesses and I see
that there are infrastructure's getting
super big and they're starting to impose
plans and and restrictions and I say,
Hey,
remember what you're here for.
You're here to support that this guy
that's on the manufacturing floor or this
guy that's out there selling or this this
woman that's working with the patients
or whatever business it is,
because it's very easy to
be in a leadership position
and forget about what the
ground troops are doing.
No debt and that's a horrible thing.
That's a horrible thing.
And then this thing that you're
talking about soldier first,
which sounds to me like
soldier last because they
don't want to take care of the
soldiers if they want to do that
because there's nobody better to prepare
soldiers for combat then soldiers
that had been in combat. Yeah.
If I want to learn sniper, you know
how I want to learn it from in Canada,
Jody Mitic, you know, I want to learn
it from someone that's like you.
If I were to learn how to patrol
and one wonder for someone like you,
I don't want to learn it from a guy that
theoretically understands it. Right.
That's not the same thing.
I want the real deal.
Yeah. It's, it's a policy.
Again, they defended,
they think it's necessary.
What are you gonna do?
Big Green machine just keeps on rolling.
All right.
This is a similar question
to what we've already had,
but I'm going to do it again.
How do you silence distraction no matter
how important to achieve your number
one priority.
Hmm.
On op,
when I was still a sniper, I actually
had a much easier time of this. Um,
I'm, I'm, I'm add in a lot of ways and,
uh,
whatever I want to focus on add doesn't
mean that you can't focus on stuff.
It just means like when the teacher
tells you to focus on something,
you're busy doing other
stuff. And so, right,
it's not a deficit disorder.
It's that I don't give a shit
what you're trying to show me,
but that right there, that's
what I want to look at. So I, um,
I had a way of just, I would like
if I had to watch a crossroad,
I've watched that crossroad was my whole
world and it wouldn't matter what we've
now done. It doesn't mean I
wasn't situationally aware,
but I would watch that crossroad like my
life depended on it or somebody's life
depended on it, which, which had
a lot of times it did. And, um,
if I have enough,
what I found actually,
and this is one of the reasons why
I'm starting to meditate again,
I'm seeing a therapist again.
Um,
I'm listening to Jocko podcast
and reading extreme ownership.
Um, no, I'm,
I'm being serious is that I appreciate
in my civilian post-military post wounded
post addiction,
um,
phase world. I've, I've lost
a little bit in my ability to,
to, to, to push out the
input. I don't want,
I have a hard, I used to read a
book a month at the, at the minimum,
and I'm not talking like I'm talking
like a book, you know, that I showed you,
I had the 33 laws of war in my suitcase.
I've been reading that for three
months and I'm maybe half done.
I have a real hard time now,
um,
achieving that,
that zone of zero distraction and I'm
trying to get it back because it's really,
I get a lot done. You
know, I have, I have my,
my politics, I have the book,
I do keynote speeches. Um,
I have my kids. Um, I have
all my hobbies. You know, I'm,
I'm trying to support veterans support
charities that support veterans and uh,
and I still get a lot done,
but I could get so much more done if I
could turn off some things in my mind
sometimes.
And I don't know what,
what's happened or what if this is
what an addict's brain is lake now,
or if it's just, I'm always seeking
something, I get bored easily.
That's part of the EDD.
I've always had that.
But when I found something and latched
onto it, I used to be like just,
I was 100% focused until I became,
you know,
I got as much of that as I could and
then I would move on to the next thing.
And, um, yeah, I, I, I
gotta be honest. I've,
I've visualization though,
going back to the first question
is one way that you can do it.
And I've started meditating to
get my mind back into that state.
I used to do a lot of yoga and I
used to do a lot of mindfulness, uh,
not training.
I don't know what people see now.
It's called mindfulness
training back then.
I think it was just called reflection
or something. I call it Jujitsu.
Yeah. Well, when I'm done the
bodybuilding show in November,
I will start Jujitsu. Oh, you, you might
actually be starting to do two tomorrow.
My Bro just don't hurt me.
Doesn't hurt everyone I know who
starts Jujitsu hurt something.
That's why I'm holding off.
But I would,
I will definitely come
let you a ragdoll me.
But my point is that I've lost it and
I'm probably the last guy to give you
advice right now on how to lock out
the world because I have to put on
headphones and crank music to
get through a workout right now.
And I know this, I didn't know I'm
detrimental in it and I, and I,
and I'm aware of it and I'm
trying to correct it and uh,
and it bugs the shit out of me.
They really does.
It makes me feel like less of a person.
So let me tell you about a transition
that I went through. Yes. First of all,
before the war I,
than military sent me to college.
So I had to go to college and I, as
I said earlier, or as I said before,
I was super focused.
When I went to college,
I'd been in the seal teams for 10 years.
I was a go getter. I was a hard charger.
I was like, Oh, you want
me to read this book? Boom.
I would sit down and just force myself
to read it and then got back to the seal
teams and like,
like when I went to college,
I literally read every single thing that
I was assigned and nobody does that in
college.
Nobody does that.
I read every single page of every single
thing I was assigned during college.
That's ridiculous. It's almost a waste
of time. It's almost embarrassing.
Echo definitely thinks
it's a waste of time, but,
but it was because I just could just
go lock my brain down and get it done.
Get back to the teams and the
teams officer in the teams,
you have a lot of administrative paperwork
to do evaluations and after actions
reports and all these things.
And I would do the same thing.
I'll just go into lockdown mode in my,
put my brain on it and boom,
I'd go through it and just get it done.
I would just be able to focus.
So they each thing, laser focus.
These are folks that report done. God,
give me that. Oh, come on.
Report done. Okay. Okay.
So I go to Iraq the first time, no big
deal. I go to Iraq the second time.
Do you know it's a much
tougher deployment.
It's guys are getting wounded,
guys, my guys are getting killed
and I come home and I get put into a
run in the training and with running the
training all of a sudden,
yeah,
there's administrative requirements and
there was administrative requirements
overseas as well. And you know what? We
did locked him down and got them done.
I get home and I remember
the first time I get to do,
I think it's evaluations, which in
the military and the Navy anyways,
doing evaluations is a real pain.
It's a real big administrative
administration of or a
v value shopping of all
the troops. So at this place I
was at huge running training.
I had a hundred guys and every one of
them is like a little mini term paper or
something. It has to be perfect. It's
in a person's military record forever.
That really stressful about it.
And I used to have no problem just
to hammer on those things out.
So I get back from that deployment and,
and I'm sitting down in and you know,
I start doing it. I'm like, ah,
this is stupid. This doesn't matter.
I don't know why I'm doing this.
Right. Well how do I have to do that?
Kind of started saying the same things
that I would always brag on people for
saying like, this is stupid.
Oh, now your men are stupid.
You don't want to fill out the
report and take care of your guys.
You don't want to write a good [inaudible]
career isn't worth your five minutes
or five is okay. You know? So I,
I heard myself saying this right,
and what and what,
what the constant undertone of all this
was that this stuff doesn't matter.
Combat Wolves, what mattered. And,
and when you get back from
that situation where man,
your buddies are getting killed,
you're getting wounded,
your friends are getting wounded, this
piece of paper, it doesn't matter.
And you say to yourself,
I don't care about this.
And at some point,
and it didn't,
it took me maybe two or three months.
I did what I had to do to get by.
But as I sit there and I looked at
myself and I said, you know what?
Combat doesn't matter anymore.
You're not in it. You're
not in it right now. Right.
This is now what matters. Your,
your mind was still there.
My mind was still there thinking
that that was all that matters.
And like I said on our last podcast,
actually it's in the past and
it doesn't matter anymore.
So you know what you have to do.
You have to be a man and you have to do
your job now and this is what matters
now. And that to me made a
big transition for me and it,
you know,
I haven't even thought about this until,
until you were talking about it.
Cause I remember what it was like to,
to go from when I went to college and
what I was before I deployed Romani now
would just be sold, laser focused, be
to be able to just burn through things.
And then when I got back and it was not
there and it was all because I thought,
oh, this stuff doesn't
matter. This doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter what matters you,
there's guys getting killed overseas
right now. That's what matters.
And I had to say, you know what, no,
that stuff doesn't matter right now.
And you know, and also I was in
charge of training and I said,
well what matters is doing this,
getting guys trained to go overseas.
And I became obsessed with
that and slightly psychotic
about getting guys ready
for combat. I mean I was preparing them
for what they're preparing them for,
what they're going into. And you know,
you could, I'm sure there were many uh,
seals that went through the training
that I was overall in charge of and would
attest to the fact that I was probably
pretty borderline psychopathic at that
point. But I think that that was a long
run in my training and it'll sense dude,
but I want to psycho running
my combat training. Yup. Yup.
So I go ahead. Okay. You were
just going to say you think,
I think that telling yourself
and recognizing to yourself,
why are you trying to do this thing?
Because you're trying to do something
because it does matter, right?
It has to matter in some way.
Even if it's just filling
out the paperwork to get
your license from the DMV.
Oh, that doesn't matter. Oh,
actually no. What? It does matter.
You're going to get arrested. If you
could pull it, you know, it's like, no,
it does matter. These little
things, these little stupid,
meaningless tasks in life, they actually
do matter. So you know what you do.
You line them up and you freaking
crush them. That's what you do.
That's what you do.
You line up these stupid meaningless
things and you crush them and you use them
as an exercise in discipline. They
become an exercise and discipline, oh,
this thing doesn't matter. Guess what?
I'm going to crush it now. Bring it to me.
Where's my DMV form? Watch me fill
this out. That's what I'm going to do.
So maybe I turned like some little
meaningless things into a personal
competition of discipline,
but maybe it's how consistent are
you making that happen though?
This is, I'm [inaudible] to
tell you. So for instance,
since we started the podcast,
I have to read,
you know, basically a book a
week and then once I read it,
I've got to go back into it. Yeah.
You do like a book report and,
and go back through it and say, and how
is this going to flow together? What part?
So I'm spending a lot of time on that
right now and I've been able to do it
every time so far.
Okay. Um, so I think my, cause I've
lost my ability to be consistent
and that's, that's what's really
bumming me out. Like when I, when I,
your book isn't,
I mean it's thick,
but I should have been able to read this
and two or three solid days of reading.
Yes. I told you how successful
I was. Yes. Not Very.
And that bugs the shit shit
at him and I, it's a, it's a,
it's a, uh, it's a fail. It says it's a,
you know what though? I think
this is a failure on my part. I,
I think that this is the same thing
that we were talking about on the last
podcast and I think echo said
when you say,
Oh, you know what? I'm not going to
finish this book right now. It's it.
I don't really want to. It's
sort of like when you say, Oh,
I'm not gonna quit too though.
That's what I'm saying. You say,
but I don't want to do it right now.
I can push it off a little bit.
You accept that you accept that answer.
You accept that answer.
The soldier Jodi wouldn't
accept that answer.
Would not do self-talk.
Not really.
Not really. I'm not a
guy that says, you know,
I'm going to do this or going
to do that. I just do it. Right.
I just go and do whatever that thing
is. I think because you're, you
kind of have become that.
So it's more of like an input kind of
crudely that's habitual for you to just do
it in our member hall. And it was,
I think it was kind of funny where,
where I use this example like how you
said use it as an exercise of diff
discipline.
So I said this example one time where I
was in line at the grocery store and I
had a 12 pack of beer. Do we have
to relearn this story right now?
And I was standing in line and there was
maybe three, four people in front of me.
So I'm like all right, it's going to
be a while for me to get up there.
This beard is getting you decided
you're going to hold the beer.
I remember the story. I remember
this story. Yeah. So exactly right.
But it wasn't that okay.
And the reason I decided to hold the beer,
it wasn't because that
benefited me right then it,
it was an exercise in mental stuff. But
here's the create. Okay. We're good.
Way Off the question, but
physical tasks. Sure, no problem.
Yeah, cause it's, it's visceral.
It's real. I can feel it.
But to sit down and read the report on
the sewer charges that are going to be
coming in on the tax report
for the city next year.
What's on
going on on Twitter. It all like kind
of the same thing though, really is,
but I'm wondering,
I'm wondering if my brain hasn't
replaced the oxycontin with social media.
Yeah.
Like I had to quit drinking
because okay. We now we're
way off the thing, but the,
the hardcover came out last
September and hardcover. Oh, sorry.
I've unflinching uh,
the making of a Canadian sniper by Jody
Mitic printed by Simon and Schuster and
it available on Amazon through Jocko
store.com. Click the link to Amazon.
Um, but yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Well, I already said,
I already said it. I already said it. So
anyway, the hardcover came out drinking.
I drank every day from
the date came that day.
So we had 450 people at the
event. Uh, uh, Kevin Newman,
my buddy who's, who's, uh,
he's a well known news anchor and Canada
does an interview with me on the stage
and we got standing ovation.
We go out, we celebrate me,
the president of the company, my editor,
wait, we have a good night, good night.
And the next day,
if I didn't have one drink,
I was having 10 and that
went from September to the
new year and I was getting
fat and I,
you know,
I was sleeping in because I'm hung over
and I'm not going to the gym. And I went,
oh hang on,
what's going on?
Because this is cause I have my job
as politician, I'm Daddy, you know,
I'm friend. You know, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm
advocate and then you know, the book is,
it's a job, right? You know, selling
a book's a job full time job.
I need nine days a week and
36 hours a day to do it.
And so I had to make,
that's one of the reasons why I decided
to do the bodybuilding thing cause I'm
like well you can't drink and it'll be
right until November cause I need that.
So I'm trying to figure out if my brain
is looking for a new habit because I was
diagnosed before, I was like auntie
addictive. If that's even a real thing,
but I had a doctor tell
me when she was like,
you're pretty much an anti
addictive personality,
like you won't get addicted to stuff
and narrow was addicted. Doxy cotton
even though it's a physical
thing more than a mental thing,
but I still wouldn't trust me with
a pill right now. Yeah. Anyway,
I think we go way off track,
but I just
again, and I don't know what your
therapist is going to tell you.
I'm going to tell you what
Jocko would tell you though.
These little things are things that you,
I know you know how to do them.
You've done your whole
career in the military,
you are watching a crossroad and I know
that might sound exciting to people that
are out there that are thinking
how crazy that must be. No,
there's times where Jody was walking
watching a crossroad and there was nothing
going on for four days and he was watching
that crossroad and so you have that
in you. You just got to tell
yourself that, you know what,
this stuff now this is what matters and
how are you going to tell yourself that
this is what matters.
It's because this is how it
connects to the strategic picture.
You can't say that this matters because
of what it is right in front of me.
Just like when you're looking at
the crossroads, you're not thinking,
oh this crossroads is important because
the crossroads is important. No the car,
the reason it's important is because
you are supporting keeping guys alive,
which is going to help a mission out,
which is going to help the,
the overall strategy, wind commander's
intent, commander's intent,
the whole [inaudible] the commander.
Now you are the commander and
also what's your longterm mission?
And that's what I kind of,
you just said to yourself like,
oh I picked bodybuilding cause I there
you just gave yourself a mission. Right?
So what's your administrative,
you know,
Echo made some big advances lately cause
he started freaking reading books and
he wasn't doing that before, but he,
he got the longterm mission of like,
you know what, I'm going to
learn as much as I possibly can.
So you got a longterm mission with
your constituents to be the best city
councilman and represents. So when they
ask you a question you're like boom,
that's kind of the quarter psycho stuff
that I would say is like if anybody ever
asked me a question like
when I was going to college,
if it asked me any question about any
of the reading, I'm going to know it.
That's just a bizarre p uh oh.
What's that OCD thing to be like?
I'm going to know everything.
So you have four kids,
you train every day,
you get up at four in the morning.
I've got to get up at four in the morning.
That's my answer. Sorry to riff
on you guys on that man. Like,
I know you want to do the questions.
But when that guy, when that like the,
the first question was
easy cause I'm like, oh,
I'll just talk about what I used to
do. And then that one was like, well,
if I was to try and answer right now,
I'd be lying, I'd be a liar and I can't,
I have my moments still, don't get me
wrong. I'll have moments where I'm like,
this has to get done and I'll
fire through a speech or I'll,
I'll write a report or whatever it
is and then a, and then I lose it.
And it's like, ah, ah fuck. It's gone.
And that's actually
reinforcing what I just said.
So when you have a near term mission
that you know what the outcome would you
know what the result is?
You know what the end state is.
You know what the commander's
intent is like, Hey,
you've got a speech in two days.
Okay now it's in one day.
You can sit down and
concentrate and get it done.
Which where you've missed the connection
now is the connection between these
menial tasks that don't mean anything.
And how can I put them to a long term
strategic goal and one of those longterm
strategic goals you can put into place.
If nothing else is,
I'm going to discipline my mind to
do these menial tasks like a soldier
and that's pretty cool.
Oh yeah, it's a tee shirt.
Yup.
Thank you Jocko.
Whoever asked that question
a thank you for asking it.
Although I went off and talked about me
for the most of the speaking of Tangents,
echoes can take it a little further out.
It's not attention. It's what you said,
how you said that's what a soldier does.
So that's like a little
exercise and I did this before.
I did this in a couple of times.
Okay.
Like one was how I quit
drinking was I figured out,
and you can do this
with your diet as well.
I figured out that basically through
all this stuff that I read that you're
wanting to eat junk food
or drink or whatever,
is your brain tricking
you because it's built to,
it's evolved for a certain environment.
That environment doesn't work,
isn't around anymore.
Yeah.
So now we're in an environment
of abundance has to do
with don't mean anyway,
come to the conclusion that it's
your brain falling for a trick.
Your physiology of the brain falling
for a trick makes you want this stuff.
How he says how Jocko says,
that's not what a soldier would do.
I had it in my mind, I'm not
going to for that trick. I'm
not a sucker. That's not, you know,
doing this is what suckers do.
I'm not a sucker and this is just
like self talking to yourself.
So I essentially shamed
myself out of drinking. Yeah.
Just like he's doing the,
basically the inverse into focusing,
you know, I just remember like I w
I'm the guy that we were in Kosovo,
I quit smoking in a day because I
couldn't run up the hill next to her camp.
I said, well obviously these
things aren't good anymore.
And I literally just, I just, I even
had a pack of my pocket for like a week.
I just like, Oh yeah, okay. Just
throw those out. I want that guy back.
And I'm in search. I think it's
been 10 years since I was wounded.
I think I'm going to find
them again probably on the
stage for this bodybuilding
thing or something. But yeah, I just,
I just couldn't answer that question
without talking about that because I
wouldn't have been truthful
at this point in my life.
And that's what's cool is maybe that
question right there was something that is
forcing you to face that. I mean you
might've had at the back of your mind,
but now you're going, you know what,
I can't answer that and I want to see,
cause I'm not there right now.
I'm not,
but I'm going to get back there real
quick. My moments. So standby people,
standby soldiers coming back
online. Reboot Jody. 3.0
all right,
next question.
This is all, just read it.
How you prepared mentally,
what kind of discipline you had.
Routines in and out of battle.
How I prepared mentally.
Yeah.
Routines in n out of battle.
Yup. What kind of discipline you had
and routines in and out of battle.
Um,
okay.
I'm going to fall back on
mental routine I think is probably your,
your your biggest cause the
physical one is easy. Okay. He,
he come back. So battle doesn't mean, you
know, you're in gun fights all the time,
you know, like, like we say w if first and
still we're patrolling. Right. You know,
which just a static patrol.
So you know,
you gotta make sure your gear's
good. You got to make, you know,
are your batteries changed? Right?
You guys like there's all the ways,
the checklist, checklist,
checklist, checklist.
As a leader it actually makes it easier
I found because now I have a reason to
check their stuff and check that their
routine. So my routine stayed solid.
Right. Cause I think I had
other guys I had to worry about.
Um,
so rest is a big one.
I used to have to order my guys to
go to ground because they were so,
cause there's only three of us and I used
to, my barrier, especially I'd be like,
Barry, you need to be
useful. I need you to sleep.
So my routine was like, make
sure enough rest. Make sure,
because you know that the
saying mission before man,
sure. Except when the man is the
mission. So I my man to be good. Yeah.
And I'm going to say,
if you abuse your man too much,
you won't accomplish the mission.
So like, you know, you know,
the sacrifice the body. Well, let's wait.
Let's think about that because the
body is what needs to get this thing.
There's only, there's only three of us.
And in our case, you know, of your sniper,
you're, you might be alone, you might
be with a one or two other guys.
I can't afford to have a guy run head at
first through a doorway to get through
it because I need him to be useful after,
you know, if you have a platoon, sure.
You Sacrifice Smith, he runs through the
door. Hey, okay, you got 29 more guys,
I can go through the door. Um, so my
routine was always like, you know,
make sure everything's topped up.
Keep an eye out, you know, uh,
do the, do the mental checklist
and then visualize visually,
like out of battle. I would
try to, you know, I'd be on my,
I remember I'd lay on
my bunk and I'd have my,
and I'd always ended up with my right
foot crossed over my left foot and my am I
am my arms up here on my chest and I'd
have my head back and I would be going,
okay. So, okay if we go down and you know,
and if contact left and I would try to
like, you know, visualize these things,
you know,
cause as the team leader,
I had the radio and I was security
because my boys, when they're in position,
you know, my spotter is
spotting my shooters shooting,
so like they're 12 o'clock.
So I'm now everything, everything, the
rest of the clock for them and for myself.
So I was constantly rehearsing
mentally what would, what could happen.
I'm calling and I'm
practicing a call for fire.
I'm practicing and calling in an
airstrike and practicing a nine liner.
I'm practicing, um, uh, just a grit.
What do you guys do you guys use that
turns the nine line four nine nine line is
a casualty evac. Uh, call for
fire nine line. Yeah. Um, no, no,
but grit and I group range indication
during the fire. Yup. Yup. So my first,
even with all the visualization,
my first actual grit in a battle was
did in bed to bed to, to tobacco.
There it's supposed to be six, three, uh,
300 by that tree, you know, all, you know,
um, a farm for a fact or at your
own time or something like that.
Calm, cool, collected
voice. But, you know,
the guy was like 40 meters away and
it was like in my sniper was actually
looking over him. Waveys
like, I'm, you know,
I'm looking at that stuff and I was like,
fuck it, and I just shot on myself. But,
uh, but my point is that even with all
of that practice and visualization and
training, you know, that
was my first attempt. Um,
so I was always just trying to make sure
that my routine off off the battlefield
was putting my mind back,
but in a controlled setting,
you know, and, and all. And, and then
also, like I said, make sure, okay, yeah.
How much sleep did you get? K? Good,
good, good. And that's the routine that,
you know, that you got to get the
guys to relax. Especially like for me,
I had to,
I just had to make sure,
cause I only had me and two other guys,
I couldn't afford to lose one of them,
whether it was to exhaustion
or malnutrition or
dehydration or sprained ankles
or whatever, you know. So I
just, I just did my best to keep,
keep that checklist going and,
and visual.
And I would encourage them to
do the same. I'd be like, Hey,
what are you thinking about
over there? All, you know,
whatever. It'd be like, Hey,
you want you to think about, uh, you
know, remember when you may like,
or do make making that shot and you missed
or whatever. Like, try and visualize,
try and think about what you did.
You know,
there's a lot of steps that
go into pulling the trigger,
you know, and, and, um,
and then, you know, just think about that.
Think about how it happened and encourage
that. You know, I'm, I'm a big fan of,
um,
of meditation and Yoga and all that stuff.
Like if any,
like I think an our side of the world,
we've lost a lot of that stuff.
And I know we tried to get it back and
got people that do it are tree hugging,
you know,
a spandex wearing Weirdos or whatever.
But Yoga and meditation and stuff like
that's all warrior culture from the past,
you know, you know, like
Samurai meditate, you know,
ain't warrior monks a fasted and prayed.
That's just meditation.
And they looked inside themselves
a lot to try and you know,
a Samurai's job was pretty tough.
Call him a pussy for meditating,
make sure I'm there so I
could watch. And, and I,
and I firmly believe that that type of
stuff keeps you functional for when you
hit the battlefield. You
know, that self, you know,
as Grossmann calls it the self reflection,
self inoculation as well.
So that was my routine.
It was just a constant
rotation of thoughts and then,
but the actions were always
to prepare the, you know,
the situation for what was coming.
Does that make sense?
Yeah. Okay. Yeah. The one, uh, one
thing that I, that's actually a pro,
I like a really practical thing
that I did that and that is I had,
uh, this is again, this is
just a real practical thing.
I had two cots, right? Slept
in a cot, slept in one,
caught something,
one caught the other cop was all my
gear and it was just laid out going body
armor, you know, everything
was right there. And when I,
when I got dressed to go out,
all that thing was empty and
so never forgot anything.
When I came back, everything went
right back on the cop spot. Same spot,
everything squared away.
So those, that to me was,
and I figured that out really
quickly. Okay. Just going to,
I don't want ever want to forget anything.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna put everything
that I need right here. Okay.
That I had,
I didn't even think of it around my,
you know how he said I would sit there,
right foot over the left. [inaudible]
all around me because we had a cot,
we had a cot. We didn't, we couldn't
afford to Canadian army. Okay. Sorry. Um,
but around I had, we all had two by
fours around us cause we were in like a,
a fog. We built ourselves and
each nail had it. So I had my,
my chest rig, my rifle, uh, my ammo
pouches and uh, you know, like,
and then all around and,
but that was what I would,
when I would go through my stuff. That's
what I mean. Like I would hang it up,
open up the pouch. Okay. Everything's
there, close it next pouch,
make sure top up my mags, all that
stuff. And I would make sure I'd make,
get the guys who do the same thing
and when you're ready to go out or an
operation, all your nails were empty.
That means you've got everything. Yeah.
But the biggest thing with route,
like Peop,
people call it a routine and they think
there's magic to it, right? There's not,
it's just making sure you do the same
thing over and over and over again.
You know, as, as, as magical as navy
seals and snipers want to be like,
it's not really that, it's
not that mystical, I guess.
Um, it's a, it's just a lot
of repetition, you know,
the routine is that you repeat the
same actions because that was me.
That's what makes you good
at them. Yeah. I was to,
I was telling you when
we were driving over,
here are some point how we use
to try and do everything. Yeah.
When you would fire up the hours together,
five or six Home V's lined up for an
operation, they'd all be lined up,
ready to go.
And then everyone would like get the word,
it'd be like load them up and then you
just see everyone would just get in the
zone,
boom.
You'd see them getting the vehicles and
then we'd start the vehicles at the same
time. There's no reason to
do that. No, but there is,
I know the have loves dog type.
There's no, there's no, um,
definable reason why you would do that.
But our deal was,
you know, okay. Starting up in three, two,
one start up and then you hear all the
vehicles startup wants to and it's just
like all those little things would the,
all those little disciplines would
lend themselves to the team being more
disciplined.
Those ignition switches might as well
have been the switch and each guy's mind.
Yup. Yup. As the, as
that vehicle is starting,
everyone's brain is going into combat
mode and we're together at the same time
synchronized from the word go when that,
I love it when you told me that
that was, I was like, yeah,
that'd be the most bad ass
thing to watch a bunch of navy.
Imagine what's your navy seals load up
and they have vehicles all started the
same time I'd run. I'd be like, I'm not
fucking with these guys. I'm out of here.
It was a, it was an awesome
sight of that when my guys,
when I was a task unit commander, you
know, I'd be sitting on basis, guys,
we're rolling out and I'd stand out
there and salute him like just like old
school. Right. Cause. But it's, you
know, it was, uh, and they, I bet.
And they loved you for it by, by
while I love those guys. But the,
the,
those guys,
I mean every time you rolled
out in the streets to Ramadi,
there was a decent chance you
got to quit getting blown up.
There was a,
a gunfight was almost
guaranteed to happen.
But the guys getting blown ids was
a real issue for you guys. A and,
and I was thinking about this today,
the ids there was,
we had statistically the most heavily id
road in all of Iraq was route Michigan
going from one end to the one
ended Ramadi to the other. Yeah.
And there was ids all over the
place. It was, I mean it was,
it was ridiculous.
And we didn't hit Amy.
I edis while we were there,
which I was thinking about that today
cause I was thinking about my EOD
contingent had to,
or do you guys,
and I never told them like,
hey, we never hit an IED.
Thank you. Never told him that.
So you credit them with that?
I credit them with part of it.
Yeah.
Part of the briefings that
they gave part of the,
now there were some close calls, uh,
life's platoon. And matter of fact,
it's in the book when they,
the EOD guys were watching the front door,
they couldn't quite keep an eye on it,
but they were,
they did a really good inspection of it.
When they came back out there,
like something looks different,
they would gather there's 120 millimeter
mortar id that would've taken out,
I don't know, four or five guys. Yeah. Uh,
there was a time where we went over,
we went over an IED will,
uh,
the point man navigator in
the vehicles was like, Hey,
I think there's something
specific suspicious actually
got out of the vehicle to
look at it. And we're like,
hmm. Yeah. Looking back,
what do you think about that
decision making process? You know,
maybe that wasn't a good one. Anyways,
we decided, oh, I don't think it is.
We drove over it and about
half an hour later, the IED,
a clearance team found a triple stack.
One 20.
So that's everybody in
the vehicle dead. Um, if,
uh, so yeah, ids were massive threat,
the number of guys that were killed and
wounded by ids and Ramadi was ridiculous.
There was a hole, there was a
vehicle graveyard, you know,
vehicles that had been blown up
and then drag back in with, I mean,
it was, it was massive. I mean,
I want to say 50 to 100 vehicles aren't
just piled up and including m wraps,
which are the mine resistance vehicles.
Those things are, they're broken in half.
Yeah. What kind of bombed you
got to put together to do that?
Yeah. Ooh, we got real lucky
and I know this sounds weird.
My rotation,
they had conventional minds,
so any purse and any tank and
there was the occasional IED,
but it was usually SV. Uh,
and uh, and in the city,
s v means a suicide
vehicles. So, um, our, uh,
our regimental sergeant major and his
driver were killed by a suicide vehicle.
Borne IED. Yup. And I
stepped on a landmine.
If I'd stepped on an IED,
I would've been vaporized.
But the rotation that that replaced us,
our sister battalion that's,
we lived the,
the intelligence says guys from
Iraq started showing up and uh,
we went from losing a tire,
maybe having one guy get killed through
a penetration in the hole or whatever to
a,
we had a whole laugh go up and seven
out of the 10 guys in it were killed.
And it was like,
like that's how quickly it escalated
and suddenly it was an issue for our,
for our guys as well.
Almost every vehicle we had hit a landmine
on my tour and that was the only time
I was ever really scared over there
when I was walking or in a helicopter or
even out on a four wheeler,
no problem.
When I had to drive on the roads in a
vehicle, that's when I was like, my,
that pucker factor was the highest
for me ever. Ids Man. Like the,
and the guys that would go out
every day and deal with that shit.
Like d clearance guys,
Fox man.
Like my hat always came off to those guys.
Yeah.
Like talk about a nerve
wracking job. Yeah. Yeah.
What's that movie with the,
with the EOD guy, I don't
know. Hurt, luck, hurt locker.
Everybody who does that jobs is,
it's a total bullshit movie.
But could you imagine
though that's your Gig?
Well,
like we had an embedded EOD guys with
us and those usually have a EOD navy EOD
guys that are basically like the two guys.
Our guys were like,
they go through our training with us,
they grow,
but they don't go through the basic
training, the basic seal training,
but they go through everything else. And
our guys are like supporters, the wall,
once our guys, our guys were
like other seals, you know,
they were that good. Yeah.
And but yeah, um, it's not,
it's amazing,
but in the guys that are with us that
with us and so they're not quite,
it's their primary job for us, but it's
not their primary job. Right, right.
Whereas the guys that you're talking
about, the guys that did route clearance,
if anybody's listening to this podcast
right now and you did route clearance in
Iraq or Afghanistan,
you, Jocko and Jody say,
thank you because you saved us so many
times because we drove down those roads
all the time. My guys wrote
down those roads all the time.
And you found all those bombs that saved,
saved our lives in so many lives.
Kept the
applies rolling. Yep. Even
kept the local populace safe.
And you know how much credit and
glory those guys get? None. Not a lot.
None. And there was, in
Ramadi, there would be the,
the big vehicle, like a buffalo,
buffalo is take a giant m wrap.
You have to climb a ladder to get into it.
So there'd be guys in there that would
disable the bombs from inside that a big
robotic arm and they would do that.
But behind them would be a
contingent of marines in Home Viz.
And I'd say, what do you guys,
Oh yeah, we're just support.
Get some devil dogs.
Marine Corps doesn't play around.
They're like, oh, you
need, you need support.
Cool to getting home visa role behind it,
but there's going to be big bombs blowing
up. Yeah. We're in the Marine Corps.
Yeah, no factor. We'll do you love it.
I love Marines. Marine Corps. Awesome.
Anyway, questions from the interwebs.
Questions for the Inter webs.
Can you tell us about Jody,
can you tell us about your wife,
the medic that helped save you then you
kind of talked about this a little bit
on the first podcast we did together.
So you know what I'll,
I'll tell you about
her. So Atlanta is, um,
so I say her dad was in the army
and he, he, he's from Ireland,
he immigrated to Canada,
join the military and uh,
he was an airborne commando
and Canada back in the day.
Like that was pretty much,
you know, that was our,
one of our most fierce units and he
commanded the jump school, which is like,
whoa. Wow, that's, that's pretty bad ass.
He did the American ranger course and 68.
[inaudible]. Yeah, it's an old
Vietnam Rangers were running,
run the show got old. They were young.
Sorry guys, I should have said that. The,
these fresh combat experience rangers
were running the show, you know,
they weren't playing around.
Yeah.
He got kicked in the spine
with a steel toe boot. Yeah.
And finished with a broken
vertebrae and a, but you know,
so I always say she was drafted
into the military at birth and uh,
cause she grew up on bases all
over the world. Germany, um, uh,
I think South America and stuff or is
it her dad ended up being in a like
embassy security and stuff.
Um,
she became a medic at a high school.
I think she joined at 17 as well. She's
a little bit older than me. Um, and then,
uh,
she has more citations for
saving civilians than she
does receiving soldiers.
She happens upon, she's like
one of those, uh, angels,
I guess that just won a woman.
So here's one.
A woman had a heart attack behind
the wheel, drove into a ditch.
Atlanta was right behind her, drove,
stopped her car, jumped in the car,
pulled her out dead.
Alana brought her back to life right there
at the side of the road, no equipment,
anything like that.
Just skill,
skill and determination when and kept
her alive until the paramedics showed up
and took over. She's got
a decoration for that. Um,
you know, she helped
save my life and, and,
and a lot of my friends and,
uh,
one time we were driving and
we came upon a scene and we,
uh, we were in my truck and Ayla was
still a baby still in our baby seat.
And so I look up and I,
and I see it, I think she,
she might have been on her phone,
I don't know what she was doing.
And I see scatter cars,
car parts everywhere,
and one lone cop standing in the
middle of it, like a squirrel.
And not because he's scared or
anything, he's just, he's the only guy.
He's the first on the scene.
And I look and I'm like, okay,
something bad happened here. And I see
one vehicle in the middle of it all.
And I went to Atlanta, they need
you. And she went, Huh? I said,
you see that van? They
need you. She jumped out,
jumped headfirst through the,
this van was crushed and she went in
there and there was a four year old,
little three year old little
girl, uh, that had been hit
with the car, was t boned.
She stabilized the little girl's spine,
uh,
kept her alive until the firemen
showed up. Uh, they extracted, she,
she was in command of the
scene and they were like, they,
I guess I was doing my best to help the
cop with traffic and stuff like this and
uh, and deal with some of the other
like minor injuries and the fireman,
like the first guy to put his head and
he's like, I kind of heard like, well,
who is this? And then all
I hear is Atlanta. Like, I
need this and I need like,
just bark it out, all these orders.
And they go, Oh yeah, okay, hang on.
So they run in,
they're getting all this stuff and they
get the board and they put the little,
the girl, the girl ended up passing
away unfortunately, but, um,
zero hesitation.
That's,
that's my wife fucking hero. And, uh,
you know,
she retired from the military
last year and is going through,
um, she probably gonna get mad at me for
saying this, but she's going through it.
A lot of soldiers go
through the transition.
Oh,
you mean the thing we've been talking
about for the all night and all last pod.
Yeah. She just, she's just having
a tough time figuring out who,
who's Atlanta Gilmore or if she's not
a soldier and she's an amazing mom.
Uh, she's an amazing wife and,
um, she's an amazing person.
It's just in her mind,
she needs to find the new
her and, uh, you know,
and I'm trying to help her
the best I can, but, you know,
I can only do so much and at some
point she'll figure it out. She's,
she's coming around pretty good right now.
I think she's,
she's starting to like volunteer a
little bit here and like get out, do
some stuff and, you know, I'm pretty, you
know, I'm just, I'm just proud of her,
you know, for the most
part. Yeah. You know,
that's one of the things that makes
that transition so hard, um, is that,
you know,
before I was talking about like combat
matters and then beyond that you're doing
this thing, you know, for your wife,
like she's in charge of
saving people's lives,
saving soldiers' lives, and that's going
to help this strategic mission. I mean,
what, what, what is going
to replace that for her?
And the answer, Alana, is nothing.
Nothing's gonna replace that. Yeah,
but you know what? You don't need to
replace it. You need to replace it.
A whole stock replace that thing.
That's a beautiful, beautiful
experience to have had in your life.
But don't let it turn into a black hole,
right?
Like, like the black hole, the mass
of a black hole is some insane number.
Just like the mass and the,
and the power of this combat
experience is the same thing.
It's this super powerful experience,
but don't let it suck all
the other experiences away.
Don't let it do that. Don't let
it do that. So what's the, what's,
what else?
What matters?
Now we know what mattered in the
past, right? But what matters now.
That's the question. And there's so many
things. I mean, you got two daughters,
you got your dumb ass to
take care of and I am dumb.
You can tell Ya. So what
is it? What does it,
one of those things that
matters and what's the next
mission she's going to find?
Maybe she's to end up being a paramedic.
Maybe she goes, you know, who knows?
Maybe she'll end up being an artist. Maybe
she'll end up having her own podcast.
Maybe she'll end up being a painter.
I Dunno.
But what mattered in the past is awesome,
but let's find out what matters now. Yup.
And grab hold of that baby. Listened,
listened to Jocko.
Now
hold on to that thing and let that
thing grow. Yeah. Let that thing grow.
Let that thing feed off of the
past and bring something new,
something bigger. Something that
happening. Something that's happening now.
But that's my wife. Yeah. That's awesome.
You should use the damn proud of her.
I could see it on your face.
Like I don't have any
decorations for saving.
People yelled at either
do I life, you know? Uh,
and you know,
and I think about what I,
what I saw, I saw a lot of destruction,
but honestly it was mostly the enemy,
you know, that I caused and I'm
like, it's easy to step over him.
Like he doesn't look like me. He doesn't
talk like me, doesn't dress like me.
Like I don't even know that, you know,
I didn't know nothing about that guy.
Step over him, carry on, she rolls up,
let's just take my case. She knows
me. I'm Jodie, I'm her buddy.
We watched a family guy together.
I used to, you know her,
her ex husband and I used to,
we're, we're buddies, you know,
like you know all these
things in and she would,
whenever she would roll up to a scene,
it was the clean up the mess the
enemy made of us. And she knew most.
We're a tiny army. Yeah. And our,
or were brick at brigade for
us is like 3,200 guys, maybe,
maybe,
maybe 2,500 in 2006.
So she knew most of the guys that she
put into body bags or like in my case she
says after they loaded me on
the helicopter and it flew away,
she was just sad because she knew that
what I was going home to because of my
injuries. Right. She was like, she knew
more about your future than you did.
Exactly.
She knew what a nightmare you were about.
Go through.
She knew that what I was and who I
was and what I was now going to be.
They have to become an except and
she says that she said that in an,
she had never said that to me and I read
it in an interview she gave once and
she said, yeah, I just, I,
I was just devastated for him because
of what he was going to go home to.
This big, tough, strong, proud
guy had to go home without feet.
She's just like, oh, and I guess
she said something like, you know,
if nobody else looks after him,
I guess I gotta God dammit she did.
Next question prompts to, Alana,
you love your baby. Awesome.
Kind of a next question which I paired
these two together because this one
relates here. How do you deal with
being away from family and loved ones?
Oh, I'm uh, I'm odd.
I'll always have been.
I think this might be where I
might be a little bit like you.
Do you ever like,
I just,
I don't really miss people.
Yes.
Does that make sense? Do you know what
I'm saying? I know I can see it. Okay.
You know I, I don't miss people
cause I know I'm going to see them.
Even my dog.
I love my daughters,
love my daughters and I'll walk in the
house and they're better than puppies.
Right. They jump on me
and I get Daddy, Daddy,
it's the seven year old's still
does it. I get kisses, I get hugs.
I get where were you?
You were gone so long.
But like today I haven't spoken to them
and I don't miss him.
I know that they're out there like,
but on a, on a, on a certain level,
when I do get home I'm real
happy to be home. Yeah.
Like you were saying to me on the phone,
like you just want to get home,
but when I'm away from home
you're in the game. Yes.
Especially for this I guess cause I'm
here to promote the book and I'm here to
hang out with you guys. So
I'm like, I'm looking forward.
And it's like when my dad was crying
in the parking lot before I went on my
first mission ever. To me it was
like, what's the big deal dude?
I'll be back in six months and, and
you know, my best, my best buddies,
you know, the, the guys that I
was happy didn't die in combat.
I've talked to them every
three to six months. You know,
I just talked to the leader of that Green
Brae team that I worked so much with
just the other day after two years
of not actually speaking. You know,
a couple of messages on Facebook in this,
it's weird for me.
Yeah. I'm very similar. I don't,
I don't feel the need to continually
update people or talk to people.
And my best example is the guy went
through seal training with did three
platoons within that seal team, wasn't
training cell with them at seal team one.
And he was my roommate that entire time.
So eight years or so we were, and
we, we did everything together,
drank together, hung out together,
everything we did and I got,
and then I got moved to Virginia Beach
for two years. Didn't talk to him.
Not One single time, not a letter, not a
phone on a phone call, nothing came back.
It's almost like, hey, what's up man?
Oh yeah. Hey, you want a burger with us?
You know what I mean? It was just like
nothing to write up. Picked it right up.
And that's how I always feel. So, um,
and I kind of do that with my
family, at least in it, you know,
I'm assuming that this
person is a guy that's um,
thinking about being on deployment
without his family. And so, yeah.
And again,
when I talked about earlier is I'm going
to compartmentalize and say it and I'll
tell you this is,
I didn't want to talk to my wife and
kids every day at all when I was on
deployment. I didn't want you could do it.
I mean, if you were, if you were on base,
you could do what I mean.
For those of you that don't know overseas,
most places overseas right now, you
got Internet, you got satellite phone,
you can call home.
You can,
I did not want to do that with
my wife and with my family.
When was your first deployment? Uh, 2003
2004 that was your first one ever? Oh No,
no, no. I, my first
deployment was in 92 93 yeah,
mine was a Kosovo 99 you called home on
a w you had one phone [inaudible] it was
seven second delay and
you got 15 minutes a week.
Maybe it was 42nd delay.
I just know like it sucked.
There was no such thing as email,
email and 99 first of all,
I didn't even have an email.
Yeah.
And so there's one guy on base who is
the Geek and he would go back to the main
camp where they had the Inter Inter web
and you had to give them your email and
the password and he would download your
messages onto a CD Rom com back with it
and print it off on the
clerk's computer for you.
I wonder if our type of
thinking about it is,
is a response from the fact that we just
didn't have it the first time and then
buy between 99 and 2006 and 2006 I had
a sat phone in my pocket for every,
everywhere I went. I could have
called home all day every day,
but I didn't because I was like,
well, first of all to treat.
And second of all,
I know a lot of work at a job to
do and I can't be worrying about.
I one time I was on the phone and a shot
went over my head, Hey dad, I got to go.
Hey, you know, when he's,
and then I think, uh, um,
your Guy Chris Kyle in his book,
he talks about being on the phone
and then a gunfight starts. Yeah.
And his wife listens to the gunfight
because you forgot to hang up the phone.
Are you kidding me?
Putting your family through that?
But I think maybe our situation is that
we came from the generation where that
just wasn't an option anyway.
So I would love to talk to some of the
newer guys. Yeah. About this,
about this subject. Um, my,
I did two, I did three
shipboard deployments as a seal.
So we used to deploy on ships.
And the first one I went on the,
we didn't have internet, so it
was old school. You'd get mail,
written mail,
but that was the norm.
Once every 30 days or 35 days,
it'd be like mail call.
Everyone would be all
excited. But um, yeah,
I think that that definitely conditions
you to not be addicted to having that.
And I don't think you're helping the home
front either to call everyday and say,
I miss you so much.
I can't wait to,
I don't know if it helps
the home front either.
I think it actually is a little
bit painful for the Home Front.
I was talking to one of the wives the
other day of some of our guys that are
deployed,
don't get mad at me ladies,
but I'm just saying a lot of ladies
that are deployed tents. That's true.
But I was talking to a wife of
a guy I know and she says, Hey,
I haven't heard from so and so
for, for like four days. I'm like,
Huh? I'm like, he's probably on op.
Like you know when he does for a living,
you know exactly what he does for a
living. OPS can take awhile. He's like,
it's like, yeah, but usually he
gets back to me and I'm like,
obviously he's on a long up,
but their condition now to always
hear back from you. You know what you,
you talked about this in your book,
which is life's gonna go on. Yeah.
And I think that that's something
too that will help, you know,
if you're like for this guy that's going
to be gone for a long time and how's he
going to deal with it except the fact
that life's going to go on and just be
cool with that. Things are gonna
change the things we can get remodeled.
This is going to be some
new rugs in the house.
It's gonna be a new piece of furniture.
The fridge might break and
she'll go get a new one. Exactly.
And there's nothing you can do both
and you can just be cool with it. Yeah.
If you don't like the color she picks,
say thanks for getting the new fridge.
Yeah.
Thanks for taking care of that because
I was busy doing protecting freedoms and
democracy in the world.
All right,
next one.
What are your workout
slash training methods?
I usually make it up as I'm
walking into that. No. Okay. Um,
right now because I am
bodybuilding and I'm going like,
I'm doing a, might be hearing
from echo here in a second.
He's the big time bodybuilder.
Do you buddybuild no. No. Okay.
So I've worked out since, you know, I
was 16 with weights, right. But I always,
so my first mission in Afghanistan,
because I was a driver slash bodyguard
and remember Animal Stak yes.
Supplement, which was basically
steroids. Yes. So we would order,
we ordered a shit ton of animal stack
and because we had a lot of downtime,
we watched, um, you know,
like 24 of the series on
DVD and we worked out,
I came home like bench benching,
like whatever four plates aside is
dead lifting. Like I was like
huge. We looked, looked awesome.
What did you weigh to 40 or
something crazy like that.
And then I tried to get behind my sniper
rifle because I was not operating as
this neighbor. Right. And
I was like, Oh God, okay.
Two big tried, tried rucking through my
rucksack on and tried to go up a hill.
Oh my God. Oh yeah. So I had to slim
back down. I've realized, I'm like, oh,
being a meathead is not
conducive to being a sniper. Um,
so I always tried to tailor
my body around being a sniper,
especially after that.
And, um, but now, uh,
like I said,
I'm going to be 40 in January.
It's going to be 10 year anniversary
of getting blown up in January.
And I wanted to quit drinking and I needed
a new goal to move towards. So I said,
I'm gonna get into bodybuilding and if
you know anything about bodybuilding,
I don't want to look like Phil Heath.
I want to look like a Arnold
when he was in the 70s, sixties,
when they still look humans. So you
picked a realistic goal. Yeah. Something,
something where I might not need
supplementation from another country. Um,
and not that there's anything wrong
with it. Whatever man of, to me, my,
my view on that stuff is if it gets you
to where you want to be and you're not
hurting anybody, who cares, right. It's
your body. Do whatever you want with it.
Um, so, but, but for
bodybuilding, you look good.
So I'm doing the physique class,
which means you wear board shorts and
you don't necessarily have a routine,
but they tell you how to pose.
They like, I want to see your abs.
We want to see your
glutes, whatever, whatever.
So you kind of just stand a certain way
and uh, and I take direction well, right.
I'll be on the parade square basically.
So you look good,
but you're not really good for much
know when you're in that condition.
So I want the picture of me
with a six pack. I'll be 40,
I'll have a glass of water,
it'll all go away. Um,
and then I'll celebrate
the 10 year anniversary of
getting blown up and I'll at
least I'll know that I've
got like somewhat of the
type of body I used to have
back. Okay. All that being said,
my training now is being
directed by my buddy nick.
And I do whatever he tells me.
And right now its
chest and arms one day back and shoulders
and other day and legs and other day.
Can you squat? No. How do you, what sucks?
Because that was my favorite
exercise of course, of course. Um,
but there's gotta be some like modified,
I do a hack squat. Okay. There,
you know the machine. Yeah.
So I recently discovered it,
like in the last six weeks I,
I discovered this machine hack squat,
um, before I was doing leg press and, uh,
curls.
I can't really do extensions cause the,
cause the stumps are different length
and where the pad rests across my shins,
it tweets too much torque on my stumps.
So,
but then I found this hack
squat thing and it's, it's
made all the difference. So I, you know,
slap as much weight on it as I can stand
in and I just squat cause it's almost
like a squat. Yeah, it's pretty close.
But I'm supported so my wife's has
noticed a firmer ass. There you go.
Things like that, you know.
And so anyway, my, my,
my routine is just that and you know,
the food is,
I'm a big baby when it comes to food.
Um,
I've never eaten my vegetables and I
don't care what nick says or what my mom
used to say. I'm not going to eat
him. That's what my food eats. Um,
you know, I'm a meat and potatoes guy
pretty much. Um, and that's about it.
I have the worst eater of food,
like fear factor with Joe Rogan's old
show. I would be the worst contestant.
I'll be such a low,
well I might be able to pull
it off because I've eaten
some pretty gross things
cause I had to write.
But um,
like I just don't like a lot
of foods. I'm the same. Yeah.
And I don't care what anyone tells you.
Oh come on. You just got to try it.
I'm not, I'm not trying it. Yeah, I
just smelled it. I want to throw up.
I just looked at it. It's something I
don't want my mouth. How about that? Okay.
How about you just get me the steak
without any spices or sauces on it.
Like I asked for and the plain potato
I want next to it and I'll follow some
butter and some pepper on that bad boy.
That sounds like a good,
it's like that's what food tastes like
and that's what I love. But you know,
Atlanta makes fun of me cause my
favorite ice cream is vanilla. I'm like,
my life is exciting enough.
I don't need no strawberry
sprinkle bubblegum ice cream.
It's bringing my vanilla. Maybe a Brownie
on the side. Yeah, I don't know. I, I,
I do go with the mint chocolate
chip milkshake, but Ooh,
maybe release chocolates.
What about what,
so you just literally see your
like steak and potatoes do you are,
when you go to this bodybuilding yeah.
You're gonna have to drop a bunch of fat.
Yeah. So I'm dropping the fat. You
got to do that by diet. That's diet.
So what are you going to do?
What do you know what Nick's going
to put you on for a program for that?
We start that next week.
You think he's going to go like no carbs.
All Fat.
He's a proponent of the old school
bodybuilding where you never want to be in
Ketosis really? But he's a
body builder. We're going to,
I want to get them to re look at
the physique stuff because you know,
if you read Arnold's new update,
more modern book on bodybuilding
or Encyclopedia of bodybuilding,
which he rewrote the nineties
they still went by the whole fuel,
the muscle with the carb thing.
Right. But they looked amazing.
So they,
they might have been onto something
because you've got to think about we're on
the juice.
Well,
Arnolds most of those guys and say in
the 70s they weren't juice. Actually,
you're completely wrong.
Those guys were absolutely
juicing 100% in the 70s, the 70s.
Absolutely. And it wasn't even
late today. Not like today,
but Arnold was absolutely 100% on steroids
as we're all those guys back in the
day. And they weren't illegal yet,
but they all spit in the book.
He says he didn't really, they didn't
really know what they were like,
their affect, they knew they helped. Oh,
but they didn't have it down to a science.
You know what their effect was
27 inch arms or whatever. Yeah.
They didn't have it to science,
but they were taking,
they were absolutely 100% on the sauce.
Um,
and it wasn't illegal at the time.
They know that. Yeah, that's right.
So that might be where that
idea comes from of hey,
they weren't on anything.
They were absolutely and on that.
So completely yoked nick. Yeah, they
did. It look pretty good. Pretty you,
you said that earlier. They like, oh,
you don't want to be natural like scores
and Baker the 70s I they still looked
human is my point. They looked
more human than they do now. Mike,
did you have you watched generation iron?
Yeah.
I mean what is now or just mutants. Yeah.
And that's great. Good for them. Amazing.
But I can't, I need to lose
weight to be on prosthetics.
Like I can't be putting on that kind of
way. Yeah. So next thing is, um, could,
ptosis is bad because you risk losing
muscle mass and that's kind of counter to
the whole body building thing.
So transitional period,
you do risk that if you're not in ketosis.
So there's the of,
and it varies from person to person.
Some people they go through,
they switch over to ketosis right away.
Yeah. And you know, the risk, you know,
they don't, they don't lose out, but
some guys it takes weeks and yeah.
You as Muslim that, yeah.
Like, I'm not that big yet at
all, but I mean we're still,
we've got till November and
uh, as long as it's, you know,
it'll probably be a protein
heavy. Uh, with the normal curves,
rice and potato, sweet
potato, stuff like that.
Like little bit of olive oil
and coconut oil and stuff.
You just go lots of fat.
Pretty good amount of protein,
no carbohydrates. The, yeah,
no, sorry. But this is my thing.
This is after the bodybuilding.
Yes. That's how I eat anyway. I eat,
I do love me some pasta though.
And Atlanta and I will crush a pizza.
Like whoa. Oh yeah, that's our
thing. Friday night we get a pizza,
we rent a movie on iTunes.
You know how to get the occasional pizza.
It's understood. It's a taste good.
Yeah. Yeah. Um, but occasional,
yeah.
But my,
my general rule for myself is
that it's usually a high protein,
low carb diet. And if, and I like
to eat, like if I'm not eating,
I like to be taking like
a shake or something,
like every three or four hours or I just,
you tried to intermittent fasting. Yes.
Yeah. Have knocked that. Um,
it's okay. I don't mind it.
I like it as far as convenience
goes, man, that's a convenient died.
I'm not eating today. Yeah, I'm going
to want more. And I, I don't, I did a,
I did a 48 hour fast a little while ago,
just out of randomness.
Like one day I worked all day or
traveled or something and I didn't eat.
And then the next morning I worked out
right away and then I had a phone call
and then I did something and I was
like, Dang, it's been 24 hours,
I'm just going to throw 48 on this thing.
So I went 48 it was no facts could squat.
So you have zero intake or do you have
a zero or a drink of water? Just water.
Drink water. And you know what? I
did squats, roll Jujitsu both days.
It was no factor. Okay. Yeah, I did. Um,
I did a 48 hour,
but I had coffee.
Did you feel all right? Oh,
it's fine. I feel fine. I like,
I had a little bit of tightness forbid,
but they whatever,
like in the stomach.
And I'll tell you once you read the
forgotten Highlander or any of these books
where I'm talking about these people that
are just going months without food or
they get the people up in North
Korea eating, uh, what is it?
Route and salt water soup.
That's your meal. God. Oh, we,
we found some weeds out there.
Do you ever have the dichotomy in your
mind of if I was a caveman I'd be fine,
but then you realize it's 2016 and why
are you depriving yourself of something
or why aren't you taking
full advantage of the,
of the technology available to you,
whether it's protein shakes or, or,
or supplements like on it. I feel
like, you know what I mean? Yeah, yeah.
I agree with you on those points,
but a lot of people think that the
benefits of 2016 are a twinkie,
you know? Oh yeah, no, I was
bag of potato chips or whatever.
And that's picking my kids up from
school yesterday and I was sitting in the
office waiting for me to come down and
then there's this young fella sitting
over there by the next,
the principal's office eating his lunch,
I assume because he can't be trusted
around other kids in lunch or so.
I don't know what the deal is and he
pulled a twinkie out of his lunch.
I almost fell over who gives
their kid at twinkie at lunch.
That's supposed to be Christmas, but
when we be, when we, when I was a kid,
I don't know about you. When I was a kid,
oh, you're thirsty. Here's a coke. Oh,
you're still thirsty. Here's another
car. Oh, you're hungry. Potato chips.
Like my mom would read the
ingredients on stuff and be like, oh,
there's way too much sugar in this shit.
I got cocoa puffs for my birthday.
My parents. Oh, I was, I was rice crispies
and cornflakes the rest of the time.
Yeah. Thank you, mom. Yeah,
I was lucky charms. I mean,
we just ate it and it wasn't like my
parents said, oh, this might be bad.
That was just what people
bought. Yeah. When I was a kid.
Now my mom was on top of that
stuff and I have that too.
Like there's sugar in like a loaf of
bread now I give my daughters as to slice
sandwich, that's like 12 grams of sugar.
If they eat the whole thing, I'm like,
why is your sugar in the
bread and and like I'll be,
I'm not,
I'm like an 80 20 guy,
whatever that you know the
80% like 80 hours at a time.
I pretty good 20% of the time I'm
getting after some crap. Right.
I'm a lot like that. And most of the time
it's because like the other day I was,
I was doing side was that film and I was
traveling and it, it wasn't the Pretzel
wrapped hot dogs that we
are all so fond of. It was,
but I was legit hungry and I knew I was
getting back early enough in San Diego
that I was going to be able
to get a workout in and train.
So I had,
you know,
had like a milkshake end up double meat.
Same,
which have some guide where some
random place in the airport.
Oh, the airport. [inaudible]
dog. Yeah. Yeah. It was good.
Milkshake airport milkshakes,
milkshakes or tasting
milkshakes are tasty.
So do you make,
do you make that kind of stuff at home
though? To try and trick yourself?
Makes what kind of stuff at home?
So to trick myself into thinking
I'm having a treat, right? I got,
I get my Blendtec I'll put coconut milk
in sugar-free cause you got to actually
search for that one. You
can't just, Oh anyway, so,
uh, put my coconut milk in a, I
throw in a couple scoops of protein.
I throw in a couple of scoops of uh,
organic sugar free peanut butter,
which you got a search out again.
Did you know they take the peanut oil
at a peanut butter now? That's insane.
Why did they do that?
They sell it off and then they put the
vegetable oil and so now you got to
search out real peanut butter.
Thanks. Thanks world. Anyway,
so I put it in a couple of scoops of
real peanut butter that I get to the bulk
barn and I'm in a cup, a
scoop of glutamine. But uh,
when I, and then ice it, right.
And then I spin it up and
it's kind of like a shake,
like a milkshake sent me the recipe.
If it tastes good and I'll put a shot
of espresso in often. And it just,
it makes me feel like I'm having a treat.
And so I'm like, oh, that's my sugar.
Her tooth satisfied for
the morning or my tree is,
my treat that I give to
myself is a dark chocolate.
And by dark I mean 85%.
It's,
it's almost bitter. Yeah. And I
dip it directly into coconut oil,
the Onnit coconut oil.
I dip it right in there and scoop that in.
And that is money. Yes. It's so good.
So good. And the other thing
about if you, if you and I,
we like broke out some Hershey's bars
here, milk chocolate, you take one bite,
you want another bite immediately, you
want another bite, immediately don't,
but you do. And you do it. Yeah. You take,
you take a couple of squares
of 85% chocolate and it's like,
it satisfies it and it doesn't make you
go, oh, that was good. And it takes the,
it gives you the satisfaction.
It takes longer. That's my,
that's my special
chocolate I find as well.
Don't find that it stays in
your mouth along with the taste.
It's just a little bit bitter. Get the
dark chocolate, coconut oil. Coconut oil.
Makes it a little bit, just makes it
so by not heard this on your podcast.
But I don't,
I don't know
why coconut oil,
by the way that I love on it,
but use it on it before it was called
on it. But they're cool. Coconut
oil. That's the one he does. It's
the virgin coconut oil. Yeah.
It's really
high quality coconut oil,
which is what I do.
And actually it's good
too in supporting on it.
I actually do support this podcast.
Yeah.
So, uh, whoever asked about
nutrition, it's um, ah,
you know, one thing I will,
that was me that asked about
nutrition wasn't that, no,
the question was about working out. We
kind of delved into nutrition. Okay.
Well Jocko, um, the other thing,
my guts got destroyed by the antibiotics
in my recovery and it took me figuring
it out on my own. Like why was I
constantly having like, um, diarrhea.
Why was ed constantly not like just an
upset stomach? And then I started reading,
okay, what causes it? Do I have
IBS or blah blah blah. Oh No,
I was on six months worth
of, of antibiotics, killed
everything in your gut.
I've had staph infections like
I wanted a year, one year Rad,
like for staph infections
and my stumps in a row.
And it just like just hand,
you know,
just hammers cause I was getting sick
and like, so I'm like, what's wrong?
And then I realize, oh okay.
So now every morning I like,
I keep a bottle of Kombucha in the
fridge every morning. I just shake it up,
take a Swig, have a probiotic
pill that I take with that swig.
And that's made a huge difference.
And I'm always seeking out
different ways to keep the, the,
the gut flora happy, you know,
so like apple cider vinegar,
apple cider vinegar and Kombucha and
the probiotics, those three additions,
I've made a huge difference,
uh, in my, in my system, Mike,
my immune system alone.
And then I like,
I just started jack and massive amounts
of vitamin D and C and in my body.
Um, and then I've, I've kept
a real close eye on like,
so as a kid, like, you know,
when we were eating lunch,
I didn't want onions and mushrooms
because as a kid I didn't like them and I
found out later as an adult while I'm
actually slightly allergic to them.
So whatever your body tells you,
pay real close attention, you know,
because nothing will screw with your
gains are your workout routine more than
feeling like shit. Right. And,
and so if you eat something
and you feel like shit after,
you know,
pay attention to that because that can
take a lot of energy away from your
workout and just from your date,
you know,
like you go roll into work with a headache
because you ate something that you're
actually allergic to, like that can really
mess with your mood. So I pay super.
So one of the reasons why I'm such a
basic eater is cause I've learned that
that's how I feel best and I function
best when I have minimum sub like minimum,
like additions to like, you
know, when you, when you go
to the get breakfast, right?
Nothing better than bacon and eggs in
the morning until they bring your home
fries and they're covered with Paprika,
Montreal spice shit all over them.
And I'm like,
why would you do that to my potatoes?
Potatoes are delicious
with a little bit of butter
and salt.
All they come like that.
Can I have some without it? Ooh. Yeah.
Okay. You know what, keep it potatoes. Um,
because I've learned that if
I have that go in my system,
I'll spend a good half hour on the can
and that's time I don't can't afford,
you know? So if anyone
who's like, you know,
when you're a big part of your routine is,
is the fact that you have to have the
energy and like just not feel like shit
when you, when you go into the gym.
Yeah. So that's why, by the way,
just so everybody knows
the probiotics and there's,
there's bacteria in your stomach that's
supposed to be there that's good for you.
Yeah. And that's what Jody's talking
about. That's why he drinks Kombucha.
It has the probiotic. Right.
Because it keeps those things alive.
And what he was referring to earlier than
that, that when you take antibiotics,
yeah.
It actually kills all that bacteria and
then that makes your stomach not be able
to, that's why they came out with
the, um, the yogurt a few years ago,
uh, whatever it was called, the dot. Yeah.
And I don't know,
there was that yogurt and they started
selling it cause it'll replenish your,
your good flora. Yeah.
Whatever. Whatever. Yeah. Um,
all right.
A few more interwebs.
We got one more question.
Do you ever have doubts?
If so,
how do you handle them?
Yeah,
I talked about the doubt I had
answering that second question.
Um,
if you don't have any doubt,
I'm going to be real
suspect of you as a person.
So do we all have doubts?
Hey folks,
sorry to break it to your
Jocko occasionally has
doubts. He'll never admit it,
right?
But doubts are part of being human and it,
if you're not doubting yourself,
you're not challenging yourself either.
I believe this.
This is just what I think.
So I try to approach my doubts
head on unflinching you know,
did I have doubt this third time
I got sent into battle school?
Yeah. Big Time. But
put on the best uniform. Put on,
you know, getting the best shape.
Polish your boots to the highest standard.
Be prepared to get shit on and,
and,
and bulldog your way through and smile
while you're eating that shit sandwich.
You know,
like the doubt is,
yeah.
You ever heard that?
Like you ever talked to someone
and they talk about what they want,
they really want to be doing.
Okay. So I have a, I have a
buddy of mine, he's a cop,
but he really wants to t shirts
and he's like, ah, well, you know, I'm
just waiting on, well there's, you know,
there's a time,
there's a time he even made a t shirt
for me and he's probably going to listen
to this and he knows who he is. And Bro,
I told you this at the time. He said,
Oh loud, let's sign a contract
for 12 months and this, I'm
like, you know, I don't,
um, six months tops and you know, if that,
and he's like, why? What's the
matter? I'm like, well, I just,
I just don't think you're going to, this
is it, this is where your are. He's like,
why? And I'm like, cause you're
not putting the f like you're cop,
you're not a t shirt
cellar. And he see, you see,
he's doubting himself to take that leap.
You know?
Did I have a doubt when I put my name
in for the election? Hell yeah, I did.
I've never had been a politician.
I was a gunfighter. I was a sniper,
but the ideal with doubt by
dealing with the situation.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
Because I want to know that I can
a get through this, through it.
And if I fail, I fail. It's,
hey man, I fail all the time.
I've failed a reading your book.
You know,
I failed Megan to the airport
in time yesterday, but,
and I have doubt all the time,
but I also have enough confidence in
myself that I'm willing to try almost
anything.
And I don't know if that's really
the question that was asked,
but the answer is the same because fear
is the thing that holds you back from
almost anything in your life.
That was I nervous when I put my hand
up to volunteer to go on sniper course.
Hell yeah, I was, but where did I want
to be? I wanted to be on sniper course.
Um,
it was,
I nervous the first time I was in charge
of a sniper team going into combat,
but guess what? There was
nowhere else I wanted to be. Um,
doubt is your doubt. Is your
mind telling you, you know,
to think about the things you
need to think about anyway, right?
Like the doubt is there for a reason.
It's a self preservation mechanism and
you need to use that doubt to put the
thoughts into your mind to
visualize the successful outcome.
Like we talked about earlier,
visualization, you know,
I picked your failure all the
time and then I picked her.
How will I deal with it?
Yeah,
no doubt.
Doubt to me is just a question to ponder
and then move on, you know?
So that's, that's how I do it.
I'm going to say for me,
I
agree that doubt is really how I know
that I'm pushing myself into a zone that
I'm not used to,
but like the enemy,
I respect my doubts. I'm
not afraid of them, right?
But I them
I'm going to watch them.
I'm going to listen to them.
I'm going to understand my doubts,
but I'm not going to be afraid of them
and I'm going to destroy them.
I get chills when he talks like that
and I think that's
bout all we've got for tonight.
Echo Charles, how can everybody just
step on up and support this pod?
Kashi, Bro. Huh?
Um,
well there's a few ways as we
were talking about earlier,
if you want to do some Amazon shopping,
click for a book called unflinching.
Sure. Unflinching and what,
what we do in this is no exception,
is we all the books that we talk about,
we list them on Jocko, podcast.com
we have it listed, what kind of,
what they're about and what episode
they're from and stuff like that.
There's a link on there. You Click on
it, boom. You can buy for them. Right?
That's the paper back.
Write their paper. Ben.
Also one of the coolest
pictures ever taken of me.
Yeah,
bitch.
I was checking out your picture here
and you have that little fun meter patch
you had that thing pegged.
Those of you that don't know,
that weren't in the military.
That was the one that guys were different.
Random patches and some of them are,
you know,
proud historical patches of their unit.
And some of them that if you get this, uh,
if you, if you ordered the hardcover,
it looks like that you can't see it.
But on the soft cover you can see Jody's
got the little and everybody in the
military knows what this is a little fun
meter patch and the fun meter is paved,
meaning, oh, I'm having all
kinds of fun here. Time.
That's awesome. There they are,
a paperback hardcover. I like
hardcover. Me. That's what I do.
That's good. But yeah, do that.
So I'll list Allen obviously. Oh,
I can get through Amazon.
And then if you guys like the shirts,
discipline equals freedom.
Okay.
And the one with Jack was
hit on it because you want
to, by the way, thanks. Know,
get one of those if you want to support.
And then of course,
do your shopping at on it.
In the event of you wanting supplements
that actually work because you gotta
watch out for supplements
and bodybuilding and stuff.
A lot of supplements not regulated.
They can put anything they want in them
and sell them to you. So get on it.
Supplements my opinion.
jacada.com/jocko Jocko,
get you percent off.
Get your shroom tech.
I think shrink depending on what you're
doing. If you're doing high intensity,
sustained exercise,
shroom tech, Alpha brain.
If you want to think better and Krill oil,
if you want your joints still
hold up with the passage of time.
Do they still have the
shroom tick immune? Yes. Yes.
I love that one there. You find that
one good for when you're traveling,
you are into on it. Even before. Yeah.
I forget what it was called but Andre
because he was on Rogan right like years
ago before they started on it
and he had these two supplements
because Andre used to like to party.
Huh?
Take out from that statement whatever
you want. But that's what he,
how he would put it in.
He had a supplement called roll roll on
I believe and it was meant to like roll
onto the next day. Oh you take it
when you're hung over. And I started,
I ordered it and cause when,
when I was very sluggish and all that
from the stuff from my addiction and just,
you know, the whole immune
cell, like I would look in
for anything. Yeah. So anyway,
that's why I started using it. They have
one, it's called new mood. It's for like,
Oh, I love new movie. You
know, love it over. Yeah,
yeah, yeah man. They have some,
a lot of good stuff for all kinds
of stuff. Yeah, no, yeah man.
Get on that chocolate bar or a
jacket or on it.com/jocko 10% off.
Boom. And if you want to
hit up, if you want to,
if you want to keep hearing anything from,
from Jody, you can get him on Twitter,
Facebook, Instagram, snapchat.
He's all up in the game at Jody,
medic medic,
m, I, t. I, c. O, w.
N the Jody Mitic podcast will
start being posted on iTunes.
If not today, then very
short. That's right. And today
being, what do we, Saturday,
this goes up when we're
going to listen to this.
You don't know when people are
going to listen to this, right?
You can just tell him, listen,
check out the Jody Mitic pipe,
Jody Mitic podcast on iTunes.
We'll be talking about all
kinds of cool stuff on there.
That's Jody echo is that Echo Charles
and I am at Jocko Willink on all those
things to Jody,
you got any closing words?
Once again, uh, just
thanks everybody. You know,
this is a real honor for me
to share the same space as a,
someone is as incredible as
you Jocko and echo meeting you.
It's been a pleasure. Likewise, it's
a Mike continued seek. You know,
I have a thing I call it,
I seek knowledge. You know,
I'm seeking the knowledge to continue
to grow as a human and learn, keep,
continue to learn who I am and it's
experiences like this that make it,
that make it happen, make it possible
and just thanks man. This is,
this has been awesome.
Well again,
thanks for coming on yourself
and as I said before,
most importantly thank
you for your service.
The world is a better place for what you
did in the army and for what you have
done and are doing with your life.
It's an inspiration to everybody
that hears it and knows it.
And everybody else that's out there
listening, all those troopers,
I tell you,
go do the same thing.
Go follow the example set by Jody Mitic
and so many other brave veterans and
brief people in the world
that face their demons,
whatever those demons are,
they face them and overcome them.
Okay?
And make the world a better place
by making themselves better people.
Cool.
So go out there.
Make yourself better.
Look that demon in the eye
and get after it.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jody and Jocko
out.