You discuss leading and maneuvering
up and down the chain of command.
But what about laterally within your
own peer group where the competition for
advancement is fiercest and your ability
to to set team objectives and implement
some of the tools you
discuss is limited. Okay,
so you absolutely do have to lead
laterally amongst your peers.
And since you don't have rank or position,
you have to do it another
way. But wait a second,
since you shouldn't use rank or position
to lead people below you in the chain
of command and since you don't want to
be led by someone that's throwing their
rank and position around, then guess what?
You need to do the same type of leadership
that you would use up and down the
chain of command to lead your
peers. So what does that mean?
That means you help them when you can
or you support what they're doing. You
try and build a relationship with them.
That's what you try and do. Now this,
this part of this that where we're
talking about the competitiveness.
Like if they want to maneuver and try
and make you look bad and jump in the
spotlight and try and get all the
credit, guess what? That's fine.
That's fine. Let them do it.
And everyone is gonna
see what they're doing.
And they might not see it immediately,
but they will eventually be found out.
So do your best to support them.
Do your best to help them do your
best to build the relationship.
Make the mission the most important thing,
not the little politics that you're
about to dive into and get involved.
And don't make that the primary thing.
Make the primary thing
accomplishing the mission.
Hmm.
Thinking about this, if you
start fighting with them,
you're expending energy on fighting
your own team. That's what you're doing.
Instead of fighting the enemy, it's,
this is a blue on blue situation.
This is a friendly fire. It's
fratricide don't do that.
Disengaged from the friendly fire and
focus on how to make the team win.
Hmm.
Take the high ground,
take the high ground or the
high ground. We'll take you.
Yeah. Okay.
Another one of those
points that we always say,
I know I do and I always think this
where people are watching, man,
they see that and they see
that you see all that stuff,
but let's play this game too. You
know the game where I play with it.
Like who would you hire? Who would
you rather have working for you?
Who would you rather have working
for you? If the guy, the guy,
oh you got four guys.
One guy is helping the other guys out
trying to help them with their mission.
One Guy,
the other end of the spectrum
is undermining people and
trying to make himself
look good. Which guy are you going
to promote? Yeah. All Day long.
You know who you're
going to promote. Yeah.
You're going to promote the guy that's
trying to help the team win and not just
look out for himself. Yup. Yeah. Fully.
And then sit and consider that with not
just your boss but like your peers as
well. You know, even if
there's competition, let's
say everyone's competing for,
yeah, and you're the guy who's jumping
in the spotlight always, whatever.
Versus the other guy who's
always helping everyone. Right.
Even even if they're competing with
you, for sure. I'm in the spotlight,
he's going to get ostracized if
anything is, you know, so man. Yeah,
they see that stuff, man, that goes
socially. You know what? No, no, no.
Answer me this.
When someone sees the world this way,
that means there have a tendency
to think that way. That means they,
I might have a tendency to act this way,
so they are going to be
especially cautious if you're
looking at everyone like,
well, I'm trying to compete with that guy.
I might be getting screwed
over if I don't, if I let him,
you don't get the spotlight right now.
If that's the way you're thinking,
that's the way you're acting
and if you're acting that way,
everybody can see it. Yeah. Don't
act that way. Don't act that way.
Be a good team member. Yeah. The
enemy is outside the wire. Yeah.
That's a good one too.
Where the good news about that is like
let's say you are active in that way,
as long as you can admit it to yourself,
even if you do have those feelings
inside, but you're like, hey,
I don't want to act like
that. And you start,
even if you know it's kind
of against her feelings,
and then you start acting
that way slowly and slowly.
Your feelings can accommodate where
you don't feel that way anymore.
You'll start to feel that way.
Let's start to realize how you should
act as a human being, as a team member,
as a leader, as a follower,
you'll grow up, your mature,
you'll be a good person.
Feel the benefits as opposed
to just looking out for
yourself at school and over
the other team. The ones against
me, check, kill or be killed.