Two of my bosses have told me,
I don't like Jocko.
Interesting,
interesting concept.
Without giving any value, valid
reasons. Their ego is in the way.
How do I flank them to
help them see the path?
My belief is that they're
afraid of the truth and they,
they're afraid of the truth
they see in extreme ownership.
Okay. So, uh, yeah, I mean,
clearly ego could be a problem here
as a leader who wants to constantly be
compared to some other leader.
Right.
Do you know if you were teaching a Jujitsu
class, it's like, well, the way that,
the way that Dean teaches this, you know,
that that would make you mad afterwards.
I didn't even think so. That could be
part of the problem. Oh, that's dead.
That's definitely, that's way up
there on the list of possible things.
Could be the military flavor,
right?
Some people don't like the military
flavor thing, so that's, that's okay.
It's,
it's
can turn some people off. They don't
want to hear about it. That's fine. Uh,
the reality is here's the,
but here's the reality of the situation.
Okay.
What is there to not like about
the things that I talk about.
Right? So let's say, you know what,
I don't like people taking ownership.
I want everyone to make
excuses and playing each
other, right. It doesn't even,
it doesn't even make sense,
you know, instead of,
I don't want to hear
about this cover move,
I want everyone to ignore each other
and get worried about themselves. Right.
Like that, that makes no
sense whatsoever. You know,
if a key keeping things simple,
I don't want it, hey look,
I don't want to keep things simple.
I want everything to be so complicated,
but no one knows what's going on. Right?
Like these things that they make, no,
there's no human being.
No one in a leadership position that
would want everyone or that would,
that would go against what
these simple principles. So.
Huh?
Do
you fix it then? What's the
problem? Uh, one, here's a couple,
and actually this was a Twitter thing and
a bunch of people gave great responses
on Twitter after I kind of
highlighted it. Uh, one,
one of them and my, my actual responses
like, hey, just don't, you know,
stop using my name. You know, stop saying,
well chocolates it cause you can't even
imagine how annoying that most. Well,
Jack was June. You know, when you're in a
leadership position, you know, it's like,
that's going to really great on somebody
so, so, so throw that out the window.
Don't pit it as me,
Jocko against what your bosses
are saying. No, don't do that.
You've set up an adversarial relationship
with them and you've set up or an
adver adversary relationship with me.
And I've never even met these people
before. I don't even know who they are,
even know what business they're in.
But what you've done by constantly harping
on it is you've pissed them off and
now they're saying, dude, quit
talking about Jocko. We don't care.
Because also the way that he's just,
the way he's being offensive
in approaching these
things means that he has a
little more listening and growing to do.
Because if you really want to
approach your boss or you know,
he asked about frank as possible. The
way fight someone isn't going, hey,
the way jock was says you should
do this. Like no, that's not good.
So let the principals work and another,
another person pointed out, you know,
um, hey, don't, hey,
stop trying to impose your things on them.
Like take extreme ownership. How's that
sound? You step up and start leading.
You do your thing, you
perform well. Quit talking.
Quit trying to force these things down
people's throats and give them space.
Give them room and then they'll
recognize that you're doing a good job.
If you label it with something
that you know they don't like,
well then they're going not going
to like it. No matter what you do,
no matter what you do,
that's going to be problematic.
Don't bludgeon them with with, well, you
know I've, this is blah, blah, blah. No,
don't do that.
Take let but your ego in check.
How's that sound for your
ego in check a little bit.
Make the ideas that you're
talking about their ideas.
Get them to talk about
ownership, you know, get them.
Maybe they call it something else
other than extreme ownership.
Maybe they call it, you know,
a personal accountability.
Okay, awesome. That's great.
Yeah, I really liked that. I really
like what you've come up with, boss.
I'm in with.
Oh well now they're in the game and they
don't realize that you're talking about
the same thing. That's fine. Don't
they? Don't ever have to realize that.
They don't ever have to realize that.
So I mean,
there's some people are some people
that don't like it. Even in the teams,
there's people that like, they
didn't like me, didn't matter.
It didn't matter where, what the principal
was, didn't make dog. That's the dog.
It's like, no, like, hey,
just, just, just don't,
don't attach my name to it and go and
do to be a good leader. How's that?
So those are some things I think
if you live, live, the principles,
act on the principles.
No one's going to be mad at you for taking
ownership and responsibility of what
you're doing unless you say, Ooh, you
look how I took ownership of that.
Well then you might paint yourself
into a corner where they ain't stupid.