This is Jocko podcast number
one 30 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good Evening
Caesar.
When he perceived that the seventh legion,
which stood close by him was
also hard pressed by the enemy,
directed the tribunes of the soldiers
to affect a junction of the legions
gradually and make their charge upon the
enemy with a double front which having
been done since.
They brought assistance to the one to
the other nor feared lest their rear
should be surrounded by the enemy.
They began to stand their ground more
boldly and to fight more courageously.
In the meantime,
the soldiers of the two legions which
had been in the rear of the army as a
guard for the baggage train upon the
battle being reported to them quick and
their pace,
and we're seen by the enemy on top
of the hill and Titus having gained
possession of the camp of the enemy and
observed from higher ground what was
going on in our camp,
sent the 10th Legion as a relief to our
men who when they had learned from the
flight of the horses and the settlers in
what position the affair was and in how
great danger that camp and the Legion
and the commander were involved,
left undone,
nothing to dispatch,
okay.
By their arrival.
So great.
A change of matters was made that our men,
even those who had fallen down,
exhausted with wounds,
leaned on their shields
and renewed the fight.
Then the camp retainers though unarmed,
seeing the enemy completely dismayed,
attacked them,
though they were armed.
The horseman too,
that they might buy their valor blocks
the disgrace of their flight thrust
themselves before the legionaries
soldiers in all parts of the battle.
But the enemy,
even in the last hope of safety displayed
such great courage that when the
foremost most of them had fallen,
the next stood upon those who were
prostrate and fought from on top of their
bodies when these were overthrown
and their corpses heaped up together,
those who survived cast their weapons
against our men as from a mound and
returned our dark wood,
which had fallen short between our armies
so that it ought not to be concluded
that men have such great courage,
had in judiciously dared
to pass a very broad river,
ascend very high banks and come to a
very disadvantageous place since their
greatness of spirit had
rendered these actions easy,
although in themselves very difficult.
Yeah,
so
war is eternal
and some things do not change.
And in war we see the
brutal examples of savagery
and we also see the courage
and sacrifice that's
hard to find anywhere else.
Like in that passage right there,
unarmed men attacking the enemy
and even the enemy showing courage,
climbing on top of stacked bodies of their
brethren to gain a little bit of high
ground.
Think about that.
Gaining the high ground by climbing
on the backs of your fallen comrades?
No,
that is war and that account
of war is from the book,
the Gallic wars,
which was written
by Julius Caesar himself, although he
refers to himself in the third person
and that war lasted from around 58 BC,
two 50 B c eight years of fighting between
the Gauls who were a Celtic race of
people in what is now France and Belgium,
I guess you'd say Celtic
and of course the Romans were known
for their military strength and in the
future,
I'm sure we'll go a little bit
deeper into some of Caesar's writing,
but today we're going to look
more at an overall assessment
and instruction really about
the Road Roman legions,
which as I said,
are known as an incredibly
powerful military fighting
force that conquered much
of Europe and parts of Africa
and the Middle East over time.
And the writing that we're looking at
today comes from a guy by the name of the
giddiness.
Now his full name was poo bleus,
Flavia's vagarious Renata's.
But thankfully we can just refer to him
as the Getty is not much is known about
them.
It's actually not even known.
100% if forgets.
This was actually in the military,
it, it seems as if he
was, and even if he was,
it's likely that he didn't have any
great stature or rank inside the Roman
military.
But he did capture some
incredibly important information
and he called it the Apidra,
more ray Miller terrorists,
which translate,
it's basically into the
epitome of the art of war.
Sometimes it's also
called de re militaria,
which means on matters of the military.
And the book is estimated to have been
written around four 30 a d so it's
several hundred years after Caesar's rain.
But this book that he wrote became a
guide for warfare throughout the Middle
Ages. And, and
interestingly, this is even,
it stayed even after we had gun powder
and it was carried oftentimes by general
officers and their
staff throughout Europe.
And there are even reports that George
Washington carried an annotated copy with
him, which as I dug into it may or may
not be completely true, but at a minimum,
at a minimum,
he paraphrased Vegetti yeses book in his
first address to Congress in 1790 when
he said to be prepared for war
is one of the most effectual
means of preserving peace.
So brigetta has put this information
together through at a minimum keen
observation of how the Roman legions
and the Roman military worked.
And the book has stood the test of time.
So I think we might as well see
what we can get out of it. Yes sir.
What do you think? Yes
sir. [inaudible] check.
It starts off strong.
We'll say that
starts off right here.
Victory in war does not depend
entirely upon numbers or mere courage.
Only skill and discipline will insure it.
Okay.
That's a common theme.
We find that the Romans owed the conquest
of the world to know other cause then
their continual military training,
exact observance of discipline in their
camps and unmarried cultivation of other
arts of war.
Does this mean?
I'm just gonna be talking about discipline
for the next as long as I'm alive.
Yes. It's entirely
possible, isn't it? Yeah.
It's interesting that he says it's,
it's important than just mere more
important than just mere courage.
Courage is important, but there's
something more important. Discipline. Yes.
And skill and scale. Scale it where
you liked that part. Yes. Okay.
Romans.
Okay.
They thoroughly understood the
importance of hardening them.
So when he's talking about what the
Romans do, talking about the Romans,
that's the day they thoroughly understood
the importance of hardening them by
continual practice and of training them
to every maneuver that might happen in
the line and an action.
Nor were they less strict in
punishing idleness and Slough.
See,
sometimes I stick up for like our
generation or being modern saying like,
no, you know, we're, we're
kind of hardcore too.
But then I read stuff like that and
I kind of wonder, I kind of wonder,
the courage of a soldier is heightened
by his knowledge of his profession and he
only wants an opportunity
to execute what is,
he is convinced he has been perfectly
taught, so that makes sense.
I did an interview a little while ago
and as I'm, it hasn't come out yet,
it was with NPR, NPR,
national public radio,
but he was asking me,
he had heard me saying that an interview
that like I wanted to go to war and he
was kind of surprised about that. But
that's exactly what this is talking about.
You train and you're convinced that you've
been taught well and then you want to
go get after it. Especially
when you're young, you,
you have nothing to lose.
Back to the book,
a handful of men in nerd toward
proceed to certain victory.
While on the contrary,
numerous armies of raw,
an undisciplined troops are but multitudes
of men dragged to the slaughter.
No big deal. Yeah. Multitudes
of undisciplined men.
You're just getting dragged to the
slaughter. That's life. That's life.
Oh,
and here's another point for it is
certain that the lesson man is acquainted
with the sweets of life. The less
reason he has to be afraid of death.
Interesting.
The young soldier therefore
ought to have a lively I. Oh,
this is he just talking about
what,
what the young recruits should be like,
what kind of qualities
they're supposed to have.
The young soldier therefore ought to
have a lively, I should carry his head,
erect his chest and shoulders be broad,
his shoulders muscular and
brawny his fingers long.
His Armstrong and his waist small.
Going back to posture. Remember I brought
that up with Jordan B. Peterson? Yes.
He's got the in his book.
Stand up straight with your
shoulders back and I'm like,
that's how you get
indoctrinated in the military.
That's been going on since the Roman
times. There's something to it.
I'm here to tell you,
talking more about the recruits.
He says they should be taught the use
of their arms by constant and daily
exercise.
But this essential costume has long been
abolished by the relaxation introduced
by a long piece.
Can't accept that when things
get easy. And you know, again,
working with businesses all the time,
it's,
it's real easy when the times are good,
like the economy's good right
now. The economy's good, right?
So people are just kind of
making money and everything good.
And then we'll train as hard. They don't
prepare as much happens in everything.
Yeah.
Because we kind of subconscious will,
it seems like you need any with sub
constantly rely on that kind of push.
Like the, you know, the stress
will push you, you know,
like if the economy is not good, it's
like, oh, it kind of pushes you to like,
oh we've got to, sure we don't work or
whatever. And it kind of, okay. Do you,
you know, some people, I
think you actually do this,
some people perform better under pressure.
Yeah.
The reason I say you because you'll,
you'll have a video to make let's say,
and if there is no deadline,
let's just say there's no real,
there's no real urgency.
Urgency. Like I'm not, I'm not,
I'm not expecting to see that.
But then sometimes there's a deadline
like for a muster video. Yeah. And,
and there comes the deadline and boom,
there's the video midnight,
one o'clock in the morning into
my email. Yeah, you need that.
You need that structure and discipline
younger. It does help for sure.
100% yeah. Even even time
stuff, like if you're like, hey,
meet me at around seven. Well
that's not correct. Yeah.
Well it'll be more, it'll be around
whatever time you might as well.
I said show up when you want.
I rolled the dice a little bit today cause
I said 1230 ish. Did you notice that?
Yes. To me when you put a number that I
just assumed that's the norm. That's how.
Yeah, that's probably good. Yeah, you're
right. I think you're right. You're right.
I think, yeah, you do. You do pretty good
with being on time for me actually. Yeah.
Yeah. Well I'm gonna say your bat
and I'm pretty good average. Yeah,
sure. Did you see someone asked how
they could get your job? Yes. Yeah.
Yeah. I told him to kill me and
kill you. Yeah. There you go.
I guess we know the price on your head.
Someone else.
Maybe they can be on time
because really that's all it required.
Press record beyond time ago.
We'll money
right now. He's talking a little
bit about initial training.
Going back to the book,
the first thing the soldiers are
to be taught in the military step,
which can only be acquired by constant
practice of marching quick and together,
nor is anything of more consequence either
on the march or in the line than they
should keep their ranks with the greatest
exactness for troops who march an
irregular and disorderly manner are
always in great danger of being defeated.
And I read that part so
I could read this part.
They should march with
the common military step,
20 miles in five summer hours and
with full step, which is quicker,
24 miles in the same number of hours.
So these guys can march,
you guys can march and we've talked
a lot about foot patrols and in the,
it's in the seal teams,
there's something called a forced march,
which is like you're on a road,
there's no threat,
you're just marching and you're trying
to move from point a to point B.
Don't do a lot of that in the seal teams.
You don't even do that really much
in the, well, I can't say that,
but there's a difference.
That's a forced march.
We called it a forest road march and then
there's patrolling where your tactical
and you're scanning your field to fire.
These guys are talking about a forest
road march and you're just on the road.
It's basically,
or you're going as fast as you can,
so you're just like maybe what, you don't
have a ride if, I mean in your case,
yeah, we'll never ride
for whatever reason. Well,
in the seal teams we usually had to ride.
Gotcha.
Oh, here's a good one. Learn to swim.
Every young soldier without exception
should in the summer months be taught to
swim for it is sometimes impossible
to pass rivers on bridges,
but the flying and pursuing army both
are often obliged to swim over them.
A sudden melting of snow or fall of rain
often makes them overflow their banks
and in such a situation,
the danger is as great from ignorance
in swimming as from the enemy.
It's, I kind of take it for granted
that people know how to swim,
but it is not true. And when I figured
that out when I went to Navy boot camp,
because you'd think if you are joining
the navy navy, you'd know how to swim. No,
not true.
Not True at all.
People did not know a decent amount of
people did not know how to swim. Yeah.
I'm with you. Student come from Cli where
you know everyone knows how to swim.
Even at two years old,
you know,
you know how to swim because you're
on the island and it's all, but yeah,
there's people, yeah, straight up. Some
people haven't even seen the water,
like the ocean or whatever.
Well,
there's definitely people that haven't
seen the ocean. I mean, when I went to,
when I went to seal training,
there was guys that had never been to the
ocean before. Yeah. They were from Iowa,
you know? No, they're just salt.
Why is the water tastes salty?
So yeah,
parents teach your kids how to swim.
They have those good programs now where
they do the little floating program.
So like even a little baby can
float themselves and stuff.
But you can look that up on youtube and
learn how to teach your baby to swim and
be careful. Effective. Yeah. It'd be
throwing the, uh, what's that called?
The safety. The safety tip. Yeah.
That's, you got to, you know,
when you're doing anything in the water,
you gotta be careful. Really careful.
Even when you're training in the,
you gotta be really careful.
One up one down is the rule. Like if
one person is doing some trainings,
someone's got to stand there and watch
them, make sure that they're safe.
But yeah, if you don't know how
to swim, I learned how to swim
back to the book.
No state can either be happy or secure
that is remiss and negligent in the
discipline of its troops.
Four is not profusion of riches or
excess of luxury that can influence our
enemies to court are or respect us.
Okay.
This can only be affected
by the terror of our arms.
It is an observation of
Cato that misconduct in the
common affairs of life may
be retrieved,
but that it is quite otherwise in war
where errors are fatal and without remedy
and are followed by immediate punishment.
Okay.
For the consequences of engaging in enemy
without skiller courage is that part
of the army is left on the field of battle
and those who remain received such an
impression from their defeat that they
dare not afterwards look the enemy in the
face.
That's powerful stuff right there.
Okay.
This can only be effected
by the terror of our arms.
That's underlying,
there's a little underlying threats
of violence and everything that,
I shouldn't say everything, but
dad, they're just, let me, let me,
let me break down a little bit more cause
I don't want to make a broad statement
about the whole world, but when I was
a young guy and it's the whole platoon,
it was definitely underlying
threats of violence.
I mean even with a big smile on your face,
even amongst total bros, like the, the,
the thing that's underlying it
was like, well, you know, yeah,
if this escalates down, you
know, we know how that could go.
So yeah.
Have the discipline train.
Yeah.
I don't know why I'm finding this book
like almost comical in how on point it is
with everything I think about, I
kinda noticed that or yeah, I'm just,
I mean the whole opening thing,
the whole opening,
the opening on slot of discipline,
you know,
I was straight up into it.
So back to the book, too.
Accustomed soldiers to carry burdens is
also an essential part of discipline.
Okay.
Recruits in particular should be obliged
frequently to carry a weight of not
less than 60 pounds exclusive of their
arms and to march with it in the ranks.
This is because on difficult expeditions,
the often find themselves under the
necessity of carrying their provisions as
well as their arms,
nor will they find this troublesome
when a nerd to it by costume,
which makes everything
easy. Boom. There you go.
Where the gear that you wear,
the gear that you're gonna fight with,
get used to it. These to, I used to, I
used to talk about this with
like discipline equals freedom.
The whole idea of it.
I'd say if you have the discipline
to wear your gear all the time,
then you'll have freedom of
movement when you need it. You know?
I kind of felt like that was a stretch.
Does that seem like a stretch? Well, no,
not anymore. Not Anymore. This kind of
back into the non stretch zone. Yeah.
Yep. For sure. Because like, yeah, okay,
so you have all your gear on,
right?
Jody Mitic was kind of talking about
this I think when he was like, Oh man,
you know, like it was just a pain in
the ass to wear and all this stuff.
That feeling, and that's a
real feeling. What is it, man?
This is a painted all this gear.
This is digging into my, you know,
I'm not used to it or kind of thing,
but man,
you get a guy who's really used to it,
but that's not even a factor factor.
He's free and it doesn't take, there's
two things that happens. Number one,
you get used to it.
Number two,
you figure out your gear so that your gear
works properly. Yes. So it's like, yeah,
you can cause cause your gear when
you first put it on, no matter,
you could go to the best gear store in
the world and you buy gear and it's not
going to fit you quite right. You're
gonna have to make little modifications.
You'd have to adjust it.
You have to put the weight somewhere else.
Now in football you wouldn't always
wear your gear and practice ride. Um,
it was pretty designated, like depending
on the day, you know, so you know,
two days you have full gear,
you know,
two days you have just
helmets and shoulder pads or
whatever. But yeah, you were,
you were when you were supposed to.
Some guys would like,
maybe not where their mouthpiece
or something like that,
but it'd be rare I think in the NFL.
Like they won't wear their
iPads or their hip. Goodness.
That's just cause it's a pain. I don't,
I dunno, I can't really speak for that.
I think I know the guys who run a lot
and if you take out your thigh pads and
you're like hip protectors and stuff,
it helps you run for sure.
But you run that risk and you should
train with it. You should train with it.
But here's the thing though,
if if there's a rule,
because some guys even in the
game they just won't wear it.
They just simply won't work.
But you do run the risk of like if
you get what's called a hip pointer,
there's an injury called a hip pointer
is basically your external obliques.
They kind of overlap your hipbone,
right?
And when a helmet or something hits
that and crushes your excellent,
our old bleak against your hipbones
called the hip pointer and it's,
it's a debilitating,
painful injury that kind of where even in
everyday life you were out of the game,
out of the game. And I've had it before.
So hip protectors will help against that.
So you run that risk, you know?
So it's up to you, man. I mean,
I think in college, I know in high school
it's like it's a rule you got to wear,
but um, I think in the NFL you
don't have to. That's good.
I think the overall point is,
and it sounds like the football was on
board with it and train how you fight.
Yeah. We are the gear train how you
fight, but it's tough to though in,
and this goes for any context
situation even obviously,
and really in the military,
but it's a,
it's almost like so obvious
in the military that's a
given where you can't train
exactly how you fight, you know,
so you can shoot each other. Yeah.
And exactly right. Like I
said, I used to tell guys that
I used to be like, hey, unfortunately
I'd, you know, I'd be like, unfortunately,
I can't put guys out here
to actually kill you.
You do the for for football.
As it turns out,
where you can't just have
guys going in life as a week.
Do you know somebody's hip pointers
already be all day? Yeah. Actually you,
so he goes on to talk about,
it,
talks about some slack here
going back to the book,
but negligence and off having by
degrees introduced a total relaxation of
discipline.
The soldiers began to think their
arm armor too heavy as they sold him,
put it on.
They first requested leave from the
emperor to lay aside the curiosity and
afterwards the helmet.
In consequence of this,
our troops and their
engagement with the goths,
we're often overwhelmed with
their showers of arrows.
So there you go and start
taking that a little shortcut.
And I like how he says it's by degrees.
Like no one just wakes up in the morning
and says, I'm going to be weaker. Now
they just, they just start to decay just
a little bit. Take a little shortcut,
you know, here's, here's a,
here's a, here's a workout,
a workout tip. Jockos
workout tips. I'm serious.
This is,
this is like something that goes through
my head when I'm doing some exercise.
Let's say it's squat day and let's say
it's, it's, I'm doing the 20 rep squats,
which is just painful.
Yes.
And I have that thought in my
head where sometimes, you know,
I'll be like, oh man, you know what, just
I'll just do 16 today. Cause you know,
like, I mean I worked really hard
yesterday and I'm kind of tying,
you're still doing it and I'm still doing
it. At least I did over there, no auto,
you know, Blah Blah Blah Blah. And
when I hear myself saying that,
I always think like that's the big,
that's the first step down
down the slippery slope. K
and I'm not going to do it.
I'm not going to do it.
Have you ever, have you ever
skipped it? Come on, be real.
Have you ever skipped it? Like you know
what those doubts, not doubts, but those,
those thoughts of, Hey, let me let me
slack. Not skipping a workout. I mean,
have you ever given you the only time?
The only time where I've been like,
you know what,
I'm not finishing this workout is like
I'll hurt something offer and this way
and I've done it where I've done it,
where I haven't done that.
That's a lesson learned.
Like I've been like,
I remember one time I was squatting
and I like felt a little, you know,
you get a little twinge in your back.
I got one of those and then I kept
going and then I was debilitated.
I was like eight. I was like not
good. But generally if, yeah,
no, when I, cause it's this,
that's why I'm saying this,
like that little conversation right
there is a good conversation to have with
yourself because I think about,
I think about that little,
you just give that little
bit of slack that time. Yeah.
And it's not good.
We know that.
Just in my mind I'm thinking that leads
to more slack right there. It does.
That leads to a little bit more next time
because next time you're to feel that
way at
15 reps instead of 16 yeah. Because
you've, even if it's subconsciously,
you established a new
little pres a precedent,
which is kind of just the standard
give a little bit. Yes, exactly.
So it's like it's different if you're
undefeated, right? If you're undefeated,
you either undefeated or
you not undefeated kind of
thing. Once you're defeated,
then you're kind of like, okay,
you know, let it sneak in there.
It's part of you now. I gotta say
I'm defeated trade. I'd call my car.
He ended the kind of at the end, you know,
I live and do metcon and it's, you know,
good.
And I will also straight up,
I'll be honest that it doesn't
happen very often. I mean,
I talk a lot of trash water, but it
doesn't happen very often. But Oh yeah.
There's times where we'll be like, ah,
well that workout was pretty solid on me.
I'll do, I'll make deals. That makes me
mad that, that, that makes me mad. And I,
and I,
I don't like that actually
hanging with you made me get,
gave me that mindset, which is a mindset
I simply did not have go deaf Koran.
No, but you know how you said it makes
you mad. Like I never had that feeling.
Never had the feeling
like, oh, I'm making it.
I just never thought of it that way ever.
Like not even a little bit,
didn't even consider thinking it that way.
But now, yeah, when I feel it like, oh,
maybe I'll do it tomorrow.
I really don't feel I actually have that
response where you kind of get mad at
it, at yourself kind of thing. It's like
you're split into two people. It is.
It helps.
It helps so much
check. All right. Let's
see. Going back to the book,
it was a constant custom among the old
Romans to exercise both cavalry and
infantry three times a month in
by marches of a certain length,
the foot.
We're obliged to march completely armed
the distance of 10 miles from the camp
and return in the most exact
order and with the military step,
which they changed and quickened
on some part of the march,
they made these marches not
in plain and even ground only,
but both cavalry and infantry were ordered
into difficult and uneven places and
to ascend or descend mountains to prepare
them for all kinds of accidents and
familiarize them with the different
maneuvers that various situations of a
country may require.
Guys put some miles on foot.
Again, the reason that I wanted to
mention that part is it's not just,
it's not just about wearing the gear,
it's drying to simulate as closely as
you can to this situation that you're
going to be in. Same thing with
anything. Same thing with sports.
Same thing with business.
When you're training,
when you're training someone for business,
put them in that situation that they as
close as you can to what they're going
to be in.
Yeah.
Here it continues to enumerate
the different nations,
so formidable of old, all which now
are subject to the Romans would be.
So he saying like we
beat down so many people,
we can't when I'm going to take
the time to talk about them all.
But the security established by long
piece has altered their dispositions,
drawn them off from military to civil
pursuits and infused into them a love of
idleness and ease.
Okay?
Again, this guy's writing several
hundred years after Caesar,
so he's talking about the, you
know, the, the, the slippery slope,
okay.
Hence a relaxation of military discipline.
Insensibly ensued then a neglect of
it and it's sunk at last into entire
oblivion.
So he's watching the
fall of the Roman Empire
and where does it start? Lack of
discipline. When the troops boom,
I'm getting a kick out of this boat.
The necessity therefore of discipline
cannot be too often inculcated as well as
the strict attention requisite in the
choice and training of new levies.
Don't, you can't ever let
up the slack. You can't,
can't ever say it's
okay not to do that rep,
uh,
that that's in the book,
he goes into a long sort of a long,
long description of how they
were organized like man by man,
truth by troop. Uh, not going to
go too deep into that, you know.
Well one of the things he does mention
in that section is as about how when they
stopped doing a good job replacing the
soldiers that were leaving, you know,
you're,
you're not keeping your,
not keeping people coming in and
not keeping them trained up and he,
this is a good thing. I think this
is good for any team situation.
The expense of keeping up good
or bad troops is the same.
Okay.
But it depends wholly on you. So I
think that's a good statement. No,
you got,
you got some good members on your team.
You got some bad members on the team.
It costs you the same to keep him. Yeah.
You got to decide how you're going to,
how are you going to
manage that situation?
Back to the book in former times,
the discipline was so strict that the
Tribune's or officers not only cause the
troops under their command to be
exercised daily in their presence,
but we're themselves so perfect in their
military exercise as to set them by
example.
Nothing does so much honor to
the abilities or application
of the Tribune as the
appearance and discipline of the
soldiers when they're apparel is neat and
clean,
their arms bright and in good order and
when they perform their exercises and
evolutions with dexterity,
no big deal
more.
He's talking about just
keeping the elements
organized in a combat situation.
Less the soldiers in the confusion of
battle should be separated from their
comrades.
Every cohort had its shield painted
in a manner peculiar to itself.
The name of each soldier was also written
on his shield together with the number
of the cohort and century
to which he belonged.
I liked that.
I had a note in here about how we,
we would name our vehicles so he'd know
what vehicle to get into. You know,
like the Harvey's piece would have names
so you'd know which vehicle is yours?
Well, the one called Zev, so they
had all kinds of names for him.
My first deployment to Iraq,
my first deployment to Iraq,
they were named after the movie.
Oh,
movie, right? Yeah. They were named
after a movie. It's about bowling,
but it's not the big Lebowski. Kingpin.
He was a kingpin. That was the name.
It was one of the Humvees
was called big urn.
Now What's interesting is the
humvees originally were not named,
they were numbered one,
two, three, four, five,
six and that seems like
a pretty squared away.
Like I joke would be good with
that just to give him a number.
Here's a problem with it.
When you're going on an operation,
you'd go into a building to do
uh, uh, a take down of a building.
The vehicles move around, they get, they
got to adjust. And when you come back out,
they might not necessarily be
an order numerically. So guys,
but guys would go one, two, three,
oh that's my vehicle. Gotcha.
So they get in the wrong vehicle,
which might not seem like a big deal.
But then when you're trying to get a
head count and someone is not the right
vehicle and the vehicle
commanders like I'm,
I'm supposed to have eight
guys and I only have seven.
Now we're trying to sitting on
the x trying to get a headcount.
And that's problematic. But if you
know what your name of your vehicle is,
you confirm it and they're
written on the side.
Nice big letters looking for big
urn. You see it, you jump in.
That make sense with the,
with the numbers.
Cause I think just by nature we assign
numbers to things for all kinds of weird
reasons.
You know,
like where if there's three things that
are like if I see okay there's three
bottles in a row mean you don't even
have to know each other. And I say, Hey,
grab the third bottle. It's
kind of, there's a shirt,
there's a kind of a ambiguous
understanding. Okay.
Then went the furthest one on the
right. You know, it's like that.
So the numbers can jam you. We
numbered this podcast. Yeah.
Cause it's like chronological.
So,
but interestingly they could've
had just names. Yeah. In fact,
maybe they should have, remember when
the UFC, she used to be numbered.
They're numbered and then
there's all know what it was.
This is what I was thinking.
They used to give them a number and then
they would have like a crazy name. Yeah,
yeah. The title. I'd
like glory or whatever.
And then they just started just calling
them the names of the guys that were
fighting. Yeah. Which
makes sense once you have,
that's kind of what
I'm thinking right now.
Like someone that's looking
for a certain episode. Yeah.
They, they would, they might
not remember the number,
but they remember the book or
they remember the person. Yeah.
That's kind of interesting.
But we couldn't,
but we do kind of do it like that kind of,
but what is,
is there value to having a number
aside from keeping a count of how many
episodes there are? Well I
think, I think someone now can,
if you know what one you're
looking for and then you find it,
then you can go and find it
easy in your platform. Yeah.
But the easiest way if
you want to know what,
cause sometimes I don't
remember what a particular,
if you Google Jocko podcast and then
whatever thing that you're looking for.
Yeah. It'll take you to
the youtube video. Right.
It'll take you to the youtube video. Yeah.
Cause the youtube videos that put the,
somebody just told me on, on, somebody
said, hey, you should review this book.
Marise Stratacon strategic
comms strategic on. Yeah.
And I said,
he said,
you should really read this book and
this guy has like been in the game for
awhile. And I said, you
should check out podcast.
And I didn't run a one number was I
googled Jocko strategic con and I found 57
boom. Done. So now, or you can say 57 C's
to go back in there and look, right? Yeah.
Check.
Yeah.
All right. Talking about drilling
the troops back to the book,
the younger soldiers and recruits went
through their drills of every kind,
every morning and afternoon, and the
veterans and most expert regularly,
once a day length of service or age
alone will never form a military man for
after serving many years.
And undisciplined soldier is
still a novice in his profession.
By practice only can be acquired agility
of body and the skill requisite to
engage an enemy with advantage,
especially in a close fight.
But the most essential point of all is
to teach soldiers to keep their ranks and
never abandon their colors.
And the most difficult evolutions thus
men thus trained are never at a loss
amidst the greatest confusion of numbers.
The recruits likewise,
are to be exercised with wooden swords
at the post to be taught to attack this
imaginary antagonist on all sides
and to aim at the side, feet or head,
both with the point and edge of the sword.
It sounds,
I think some of those movies that came
out because this isn't sound glorious to
me, that maybe it doesn't to
you, but to me that awesome. Mm.
And then like movies like Braveheart
where they're showing kind of the sword
battles. Yeah. And how
just psycho it was. I mean,
that's a good reminder.
Yeah.
Big Time.
Back to the book.
In short,
both legionaries and auxiliary troop
should continually be drilled in cutting
wood, carrying burdens, passing
ditches, swimming in the sea or rivers,
marching in the full step and even
running with their arms and baggage.
So in there,
so that a nerd to labor in peace,
they may find no difficulty in war.
Okay.
For as the well trained
soldiers eager for action.
So does the untaught fear it
in war?
Discipline is superior to strength.
Okay.
But if that discipline is neglected,
there is no longer any difference
between the soldier and the peasant.
The old maxim is certain that the very
essence of an art consists in constant
practice.
Yeah.
Discipline is superior to strength.
This is a solid book.
The Art,
the very essence of an art
consists in constant practice,
so whatever it is you want to be good
at. Yeah, that's how you get good at it.
Lafe and I just wrote another book.
We've been writing a lot.
I've been writing at a ton.
Sure.
And you can see the first draft was
probably five times better than our first
draft of our first book.
And you know,
we both have done a lot of
writing in the military, you know,
in college and all that. But your
practice, you get better. Yeah.
Jujitsu, guess what? You practice,
you get better. Yes sir. He do
pull ups. You're going
to pull ups. Do pull ups.
Okay,
here we go.
Yeah.
The last Simonian's made war.
Their chief study.
Yeah.
They affirmed to be the first who
reasoned on the events of battles and
committed their observations.
They're on to writing with such success
as to reduce the military art before
considered as totally dependent on
courage or fortune to contain to certain
rules and fixed principles.
As a consequence,
they established schools of tactics for
the instruction of youth in all of the
maneuvers of war.
Okay.
How worthy of admiration are these people
for particularly applying themselves
to this study?
Evan art without which
no other art can exist.
Boom. That's interesting.
Hmm. It's interesting.
Can you imagine it? Well for me, you know,
actually I can't imagine when
you're a kid you think like wars,
just like Ah, just charge and then
as soon as you get into the teams,
sure.
Like all there's maneuvers you can do.
There's things you need to make happen.
There's ways you can get advantage.
It's not just what they call it, courage
or fortunate. It's not just that at all.
There's a whole lot of things involved.
And it's also interesting
that they were doing,
they were doing studies
and debriefs on the war,
on the battles. Hmm. Cause it sounds like
people weren't. And he says, hey look,
they were the first two reasons on the
events of battles and committed their
observations they're on to writing with
such as the sec success to figure out
that there's a military art
and how,
you know, what, how fired up is it that
to study this art of war without,
without which no other
art can possibly exist
too strong for you, I don't know
for is too strong. I can see you.
That's a bold statement for sure.
It's a real bold statement.
I don't think I've thought about it
enough to offer any sort of an opinion on
the deal, but hey man, I dig it.
Kinda like Kinda like exercise in life
or health in life. Yeah, that's true.
But yeah, sure. Cool. You
seem pretty fired up about it.
You do.
And this is where George Washington
statement kind of paraphrased from back to
the book. He therefore who desires
piece should prepare for war.
He who aspires to victory should spare
no pains to form his soldiers and he who
hopes for success should fight
on principle, not chance.
Yeah,
no one dares to offend or insult a
power of known superiority in action.
Do you get bummed out that you
didn't learn this in third grade?
Like this whole thing? Uh, yeah, yeah.
Yes. Right. Including Jujitsu
for sure. Yeah. Well, yeah,
I feel like it.
And you can,
I learned this kind of from you in the
beginning where you know how you have
this kind of big picture kind of mindset,
the long game. You're always like,
you always correct me when I have
this like short sighted. Yeah.
That's what I wish I understood
slash even. I don't know,
off kids even capable really?
Well, no, you're 100% right.
And I've actually said this many times
that kids have a hard time connecting
what they're doing now with where
it puts them in the future. Yeah.
And I, I say kids and kids, I mean
me, everyone, I mean I'm better now,
but when you're, when you're a
kid, like it made it and kids,
some kids are different.
You know, like some of my,
some of the kids that my
kids hang around with,
some of them are dialed where
they've just got a vision.
They know where they're going,
they know where they're
going to be an eight years,
they know what they want to do.
That's not a majority of the kids.
Most kids are, you know, like, well, Hey,
I can get this right now and that's cool.
And they don't think about how it's gonna
affect him when the future. And that's,
that's,
that's just really problematic.
Not Understanding that long game is
really problematic and I think we do a bad
caught a bad job of teaching it as
parents and as teachers and as a society.
Yeah, yeah. Agree.
Well, I mean there's,
cause you have, you don't,
like JP says this and Lafe said this
where they are like when I was a kid even
you say you want it to be some sort of a
commando, at least you had like an idea,
you know, so there was at the very least
somewhat in your mind it'd be like,
hey for sure if I do this, that
was, that was a savior. Yeah.
So I think some families just through
tradition and stuff like that,
they'll have that structure like,
hey, you're a, I don't know,
you're a Johnson so you do this x, y, z.
And it's just a matter of
getting the kid to embrace that.
Which is really kind of like,
either they do or they know. Yeah.
I mean I think if you're fair
to your kids, because the law,
I think a lot of times like we get caught
up in like our own feelings, you know,
in this thing like, well
you know, I don't know,
your kid's not listening to you or
something like that. You're like,
oh my kid's not listening to me.
You know,
you get caught up in the feeling
that emotions, yeah. You know,
that we're rather than,
hey, you know, that's,
it is a problem that needs
to be solved kind of thing.
So I think that's the way you
can alienate your kids real easy.
And it's a common thing
I think, where, you know,
we'll alienator kids and then
they won't embrace the, the,
the pride and tradition of your family.
Cause they're like alienated.
You alienated him in one right now that
sometimes you don't even know that you
alien. You know how they're like, oh
he's in a rebellious phase. You know,
like sure there is such thing as a
rebellious kind of phase because they know
certain kids,
they gather this or they gain the sense
of like empowerment in certain ways,
you know,
so we want to test it out.
They want to test the
boundaries and all that.
Unconsciously they know they've got to
break away from their parents and they
got to start practicing that.
It seems, it seems natural,
but if you have successfully alienated
your kid when that rebellious phase
comes, they're stepping right outside the
game. They're starting their own thing.
In fact, they'll give, they're going
to have some resentment against dad.
Who is this unfair tyrant
who lame heaps of this stuff.
The kids never think their parents
know anything. As a parent,
I understand why I totally don't like,
ah, I get it now. But that is funny.
That really funny actually.
I mean we just don't,
it's not just parents like your
teachers don't know anything.
I'm not speaking for everybody,
but like when I was a kid,
my parents didn't know anything. Teachers
didn't know anything. I knew everything.
Dorks, budget, idiots. God, I'm stupid.
So if you're listening to this and you're,
you know,
under the age of 40 you
might want to listen to your,
all right,
that's good stuff.
He who desires piece should
prepare for war. Remember that one
back to the book in army to numerous.
So now he's talking about the size of
the army and the army to numerous is
subject to many dangers in inconveniences.
It's bulk makes it slow and unwieldy in
its motions and it is obliged to march
and columns of great length that is
exposed to the risk of being continually
harassment, assaulted by
inconsiderable parties of the enemy.
The encumbrance of the baggage is often
an occasion of its being surprised and
its passage throughout
difficult places or over rivers.
The difficulty providing forage for such
numbers of horses than other beasts of
burden is very great.
Besides the scarcity of provisions,
which is to be great,
carefully guarded against in
all expeditions soon ruined
such large armies where
the consumption is so great that not
withstanding the greatest care and filling
the magazines,
they must begin to fail in a short time
and sometimes they unavoidably will be
distressed for want of water.
But if unfortunately this
immense army should be defeated,
the numbers last must
necessarily be very great.
And the remainder who saved themselves
by flight too much dispirited to be
brought to action again.
And I read that whole thing so I
could read this, which is saying, hey,
like do you get too many people? I read
that whole thing so I could read this.
The ancients taught by experience,
preferred discipline to numbers.
Like we'd rather just have a small
squared away group then a ton of guys.
So where I see this with businesses,
this is what businesses is.
As businesses grow,
it becomes harder for them to turn,
right?
It's harder for them to pivot.
So you get big companies
that when they were small,
they were all agile and they were
making things happen and they can change
direction and then as they get
bigger and bigger and bigger,
they lose the ability to do that.
And so you've got to pay attention
to that and what you have to do,
there's a couple of solutions. It's like
the solution is, yeah, you can stay small,
but you don't want to spend it.
Stay small as a business because
you can't just like, you know,
it's cool to stay small as an army,
but there's only so much you can
do with limited number of people.
So what you have to do is you have to
start to become more aware of what's
going, what's going on, what's
coming down the pipe in the future.
Because it's gonna take
longer for you to pivot this,
this big monster you've got.
So you've got to do it.
You got to pay more attention. So when
you grow in size, this is classic.
When you grow in size a a business.
If the leaders of the business continued
to focus down and in to the company,
they won't see what's
coming over the horizon.
And that's when I get caught off guard
and now they don't have time to pivot
because there are a lot bigger.
But they used to get away with it cause
they were a little small company that
could come into work on Monday and they
could talk to everyone in one sitting
and everyone gets on
board and we move forward.
You fast forward that and you go from
50 employees to 500 that are now,
you know, spread out over a large
geography. You can't make that quick move.
And so what you have to do as a leader,
as as you grow,
you need to adjust your frame of vision
from looking down inside your company to
looking up and into the
future. If you don't make that
transition, you can't, you,
you think you can turn things
quickly, you can't. You can't.
It's a big army and a big army has to be,
it's hard to control a big army
and it takes more lead time. Yeah.
And so that's the focus that you
have to adjust to as you grow.
You know? That's a good way up. So how do
you do it then? Like you as the, well you,
what you do is you have people
underneath you if you're making widgets.
And I was,
when we started off,
we had eight people and I was in a factory
all day checking out your widgets and
making sure that they were good to go.
And I was testing them myself and I was
making little adjustments. That's cool.
That's fine. It works when we had eight
people. But now when we get 40 people,
I need to start going,
okay, echo, can you,
can you pay attention to the widgets in
here? And then when I get to 300 people,
I need to have four or five echoes that
are down there that are watching this
stuff. So, so that's what you gotta do.
You gotta adjust your field of vision.
You've got to adjust. Your focus
are all too. And what fools people,
what fools people,
what catches them off guard is that
they think they can still pivot quickly
because they were able to do
it when they were smaller.
When they had 30 or 40 people,
they were able to pivot quickly.
They've got 300 they can't do it
and they get caught off guard here.
Watch out for that. Kind of
like a big cruise ship, right?
Come talk to like a little speed bump.
Of course like this.
Of course those things take miles to
turn miles. Those big oil tankers,
they take miles to stop back to the book.
The excellence of their discipline made
their small army sufficient to encounter
all their enemies with success.
Now this is something else I see a
lot in business world and this is very
common, right? You get the, you
got the big, the big business,
the big gorilla in the room or whatever
and they can't pivot very quickly.
Well then you get the smaller companies
that are very agile and they start
picking away at the big guy. That's what
he's talking about right here. And like,
just because you're small
doesn't mean you can't,
you can't take a shot at the title. You
know, you could, you could move quickly.
And if there's chaos going on,
that's when you can adopt.
Now are there advantages to being the big
company with lots of money and lots of
people and you're very stable?
Oh yeah, absolutely. So,
and are there advantages to
being small? Yes, there are.
The mistake that people on both
sides make is they view themselves,
they don't understand what their strengths
and weaknesses are and they don't
understand the strength and weaknesses
of their opponents. Right? Okay.
So they say if there's someone
that can move quicker than them,
they all don't worry about them
were bigger and more stable.
All those people are maneuvering on you
and they're sticking the needles in your
feet and eventually those little needles
get infected and there's a problem.
Yeah. Got, you know, situation
going on. So you have to constantly,
as a leader, and again, this is why
leadership is important. You have to,
as a leader, need to assess
what's the strength of that group,
what's the weaknesses? What is,
what are our strengths? Right.
We keep hearing this again over and
over again throughout all these ancient
military leaders. Know Yourself, know
your opponent, know your strengths,
know your weaknesses.
For sure people fail to do that.
Problematic.
Hmm.
Here we go.
Uh,
famine makes greater havoc in an army
than the enemy and is more terrible than
the sword. You know, I, every time I,
we've read that in the last couple books,
people talking about how it's
better to starve your enemy.
It just makes me really,
really thankful that there's abundant
food in this country right now.
It really does. I mean, I,
I've never been starving.
And can you imagine starving to death?
It's gotta be absolutely heinous.
Yeah. Worse than the sword.
According to the Getty's
and army drawn together from different
parts sometimes is disposed to mutiny and
the troops though not inclined to fight,
pretend to be angry at not being
led against the enemy such seditious
dispositions.
Prince Burley's principally
showed themselves in those
who have lived in their
quarters and idleness and a feminist.
See these men on a costume
to the necessarily fatigue
of the field are disgusted
at its severity.
Their ignorance of discipline makes them
afraid of action and inspires them with
insolence.
So you let your,
it's one of those, it's
one of those dichotomies.
That's what it is. And if you let
your people do whatever they want,
they get soft and then they
start to rebel. You want to
talk about kids, you know,
let your kids do whatever you want,
whatever they want,
and see how that works out for you.
Lack of discipline of your kids.
You're gonna end up with some
rebellious kids. Yes. Now,
am I saying that you need to beat them
like a dog? I was into submission. No,
I'm not saying that at all because then
you don't what that dog is that dogs
crazy. That dog will bite
you at some point, right?
Or somebody else or somebody
else is problematic.
So you have to find the balance
between those two things.
He says there's,
there's several remedies for this evil.
Let them be constantly employed either
in the field days or in the inspection of
their arms. They should not be
allowed to be absent on furlough.
They should be frequently called by role
and trained to be exact in observance
of every signal.
Let them be exercised in the use of the
bow and throwing missile weapons and
stones both with the hand and sling and
there and with the wooden stored sword
at the post.
Let them be,
let all this be continually repeated and
let them be often kept under arms until
they are tired.
Let them be exercised in running and
leaping to facilitate the passing of
ditches. And if their quarters
are near the sea or the river,
let them all without exception be obliged
in the summer to have the frequent
practice of swimming.
Let them be accustomed to march,
March through thickets and closures and
broken grounds to fell trees and to cut
out timber to break ground and defend a
post against their comrades who are an
endeavor to dispossess
them and in the encounter,
each party should use their shields to
dislodge and bear down there antagonists,
all the different kinds of troops thus
trained and exercised in their quarters.
We'll find themselves inspired
with emulation for glory
and eagerness for action
when they come to take the field.
In short,
a soldier who has proper confidence in
his own skill and strength entertains,
no thought of mutiny.
That's awesome.
Yeah. These guys were doing force on
force training. He's saying, look,
you're not going to use stores,
but you're going to go against each
other with your shields and fight for it.
And, and this is, again, I've,
I've answered that question a bunch
of times where people, you know,
how do you build morale and your team?
It's like make them train hard,
make them work hard. Now the real
trick is to make them train hard,
make them work hard.
But at the same time,
what you do is you give them
ownership of that training.
So they're running the training.
Yeah.
They come up with the ideas at you just
respect the hardcore training that their
debt they're doing and you do it with
them. Yeah. You don't just inputs.
It's different than just
imposing on the team.
Like we're going to do this hardcore
training that will create a mutiny if
you're not careful.
Yeah.
Especially if you're not out
there doing it with a more,
if you don't explain why it's
important. Yeah. I read this thing.
This is to kind of add to that. Well,
I think so anyway. They felt, was it,
I forget what it was, but it said and
allow for success. So like when you train,
you know, you train our train hard, train
hard, but allow for success for sure.
Because if there's no success,
it's like morale goes down
after awhile and whatever. Yeah.
Something like this for sure. You can't
just, I just said can't beat that dog.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You can't beat that dog.
It is much more to the credit of a general
to form his troop to submission and
obedience by habit and discipline than
to be obliged to force them to their duty
by the terror of punishment.
So he's making the reason I pointed
that out because it's making a clear,
a clear delineation between
discipline and punishment. Discipline,
good punishment, bad. And he's saying
those are two kind of opposite things.
So I think that's very important.
I think so too.
And it's important to remember that
you're treating your people good,
you're taking care of them,
that's what you're doing.
And you don't necessarily take care
of them by making their life soft.
You take care of them by making their
life disciplined and hard not to beat them
down. There's a balance, but
that's what you got to find. Yeah.
Back to the book.
It is essential to know the character
of the enemy and of their principal
officers, whether they be rash or
cautious, enterprising or timid,
whether they fight on
principle or from chance.
And whether the nations they have been
engaged with were brave or cowardly.
So again,
know your enemy.
You must by no means venture to lead
and irresolute or different army to a
general engagement for soldiers unused
to fighting for a length of time must be
considered in the same light as recruits.
So He's saying if you've got people that
haven't fought in a while and they're a
little bit nervous, then you got to
figure that they're just like recruits.
You can't always trust them.
Then he talks about the general and says,
if he finds himself in many respects
superior to his adverts adversary,
he must by no means differ
bringing on the engagement.
So if you're in a better spot than
the enemy or you can take them go.
But if he knows himself inferior,
he must avoid general actions and
endeavor to succeed by surprises and
stratagems.
This when skillfully managed
by good generals have often
given them victory over
enemies, superior, both in numbers and
strength. So this is common sense stuff.
If you think the enemy is better than you,
don't fight them head on.
That's guerrilla warfare. If you think
the enemy is bigger and stronger than you,
you don't fight them head on.
Hmm.
All Arts and trades,
whatever,
are brought to perfection
by continual practice.
How much more should this maxim true in
inconsiderable matters be observed in
affairs of importance and
how much superior to all
others is the art of war by
which our liberties are preserved,
our dignities perpetuated
and the provinces and the
whole empire itself exists.
You don't really like that,
you're suspect, I think. Do you,
do you like it enough for both?
Okay. We'll take that. That's true though.
Yeah. I actually, I can dig it. Yeah.
I mean, let's face the facts here.
If it wasn't for,
if it wasn't for war, well then you'd
just be enslaved by someone. I mean,
I'd love for it to not be that,
that for that to not be the
case,
but if it wasn't for war,
you would just be enslaved by people
or someone else that was someone that
believed in war would, you'd be the slave
of them. Yeah. That's how it would work.
Sorry, I'm sorry. That's, that's,
that's the nature of the world. No, no,
you're actually right.
Yeah. Cause it's like,
it's like the hope or wish that
everyone was just perfect. Of course.
That'd be great. Or actually
in a way would it be great
though? You know how like,
sure, that'd be great. Everyone got along,
everyone singing Kumbaya but isn't isn't
like stress or imbalance or whatever.
Isn't that the catalyst for any
kind of progress of any kind?
What do we do if everyone was just happy
and it's just all good, satisfied, right?
I don't know man. I think we'd be in the
stone age. I just think it's bad. Yeah,
we probably would be.
But guess what?
If we're in the stone age and I see that
you got a piece of whatever piece of
meat or a rock that I want,
guess what?
I know best scene that you
were talking to reality. So,
but I mean I guess the question is not
to go off on too much of a tangent,
but the question is,
would you want it to be all peaceful
all the time with no progress?
Would you want that good theoretical
question? Kind of know, right?
I mean, cause you're kind of thinking
that you're going to think of,
do you like doing graphic
design on a computer,
which wouldn't exist if it wasn't
for war? Nope. Who would not say
point taken. But even like
even like competition. Right.
You know, it's like, yeah,
competition is good. Healthy
competition is good. It's good for you.
It makes you be, it doesn't feel like
that. Even when you're in the moment,
it's like, let's say you're just
dominating and whatever. I don't know,
you play tennis, I don't know. And you're
killing everyone. You're number one,
you're breaking world records your money
and then you kind of notice this new
young, hungry guy coming in. He starts
breaking your, some of your records,
you're like, you don't like that
you, that makes you kind of mad.
You kind of wish that never happened in,
but at the same time,
that usually is a catalyst for
you to start working harder. Sure.
In preparing for that young,
I'm all about it. Yeah. So,
but you're going to cut and you like
the, the head to head, you know,
like you'd like that. Yeah.
Like the competition. Yeah.
You like directly though,
you know, like when you say
when I think anyway, it wasn't,
when they say healthy competition is good,
it's the result of healthy
competition is good.
You get the best products right in the
market or whatever and that's a result.
That's why it's good. That's why it's
kind of empirically good. Ultimately.
I agree. Sure. It's not a
perfect process. You know?
And I know you're on the fence of,
I know, but, but you, you like,
like if I came up and you could tell I
was feeling good, that would make you,
that wouldn't make you nervous.
You'd be happy. You'd be like,
you like that head to head. It felt you
were feeling good about what? Come on.
Let's face it on the mat.
Oh, on the mats of justice.
If you come up to me and
you're all excited or even
give me the Echo Charles Kao.
Okay. Cause I just played
that through my mind. Yeah.
When I see you like that, I'm
like, oh yeah, it's even more on.
And so I'll even put it more accurately,
more extreme,
more understandable as far
as what I think you're like,
so let's say we went enrolled in, I tapped
you out all right. For the first time.
Sure you wouldn't like,
you wouldn't like that specific thing,
but when we roll again, that's when
you'd be at your happiest right there.
That's what I think. Like I think most
of us, you, you want more of a challenge.
Yeah,
like all of that.
It's really on now that moment to you
is a very pleasurable moment is what it
seems like. For some people,
like from, I don't know.
I would even argue for like
a lot of people like that.
I mean maybe that's a good example,
maybe not,
but that moment usually is a very
stressful moment. Like, Dang,
I know I got to deal with this now.
You know,
and sure it will result in
the way better stuff for sure.
But the moment is less embraced men on
normal people people should pay attention
to too is
the thing that bothers people. Again,
topic we've talked about before.
The thing that bothers people is
the anticipation of the situation.
But most people like you,
you like we were talking about you
making videos earlier when you know,
like there's a muster
common in your by like, oh,
I got to do this video that
I would imagine hangs over
your head more than when
you actually are all right,
now you're doing the work and
you're putting it together
and it's getting dialed.
Yes, true. That's how I feel about
things. You know, I'll be like,
there's something that I got to do
and I'm like, oh, it's like, ah,
you know what you do,
you attack that thing.
And now when you talked to me earlier
about working out and like, Hey,
do you ever just call it? What I
will do, which is major weakness,
is I'll, I'll like, I'll like,
wait, I'll, I'll, I'll pace, I've,
I've posted this on Twitter
before. Like, Yo, I hemmed and
Hawed, I, I re I, you know,
redid the weights,
I vacuum whatever.
I'm taking all kinds of reasons
to not start procrastinating it.
I'm going to do it, I'm gonna
make myself do it. But I'm just,
I'm just like being such a baby,
but I do that 200% and
I'm not talking hours,
but it's there in 20 minutes,
you know, 20 minutes of like,
you don't want a better stretch out
more. Yeah, yeah, exactly. That's weak.
Weak. Do it. Just do it. That's the
thing that you know what you don't want.
That's one thing I'll tell you.
Two Little Wah.
This is a workout tip from Jocko Day.
You Do,
you put a stopwatch on stuff. Even when
I'm doing something that's not really,
even when I'm doing something that's
not really focused on the time,
I at least put a stopwatch on it so
that I just gotta keep, you know,
you just keep,
it just keeps it on paceman cause
otherwise that feeling that I just talked
about, we'll, we'll start
finding itself in between sets.
You know what makes it good?
Yeah. It's weird thing.
I'd mentioned this workout that I started
a long time never really deviated,
dealt with for it's, it has rest
between sets as part of the workout.
The time designated times.
Designated time. Yeah. It was
always, I don't think, man,
I it,
I cannot think of a time where it ever
worked out where the time between the
sets was just like ambiguous or something.
It was always a specific time.
So that little procrastination thing
would creep up between exercises or,
or before my first set,
you know your warm up and the first
sets of usually the heaviest for me too.
So I'm like, all right, all right. And
that'll happen. But you're right though,
like if you watch on it,
I have this one workout that I do where
I do like it's Elsa's pull ups and then
talk pull ups and then dead hang pull
ups and then kipping pull ups and then
Chin ups.
So it's like those five and you do as
many as you can in each and then you,
then I do something else in that
I'd come back and do it again.
I do like five rounds of that. So
they're like burnout sets each one. Okay.
And like the first time I did I was like,
oh that was cool.
And so when the first time I did
it, you know, I was kind of um,
let's just say motivated to do it.
That was kind of fired up and
this was years and years ago.
And then the next time I did it,
it took me a really long time and I
realized because I just was taking a long
time between sets,
that's not the purpose of it.
So now I always put a stopwatch
on that thing. Yeah, keep, keep,
keep the clock ticking and that's it.
And you feel it because you feel the
clock ticking, you know, you're like,
oh my God, I guess that that would apply
to everything. Huh? Like you'd like,
if you, and you know, that's why like when
I write, I do a thousand words. You know,
why? Cause it get thousand
words done in an hour.
Sometimes I'm always shooting to see if
I can get it done in 50 minutes. Wait,
wait. So you will, let's say when you
write, you do, boom, you set the clock,
your time, your watch. I
don't set my watch. Yeah,
it's, you know, eight 48. Okay.
Nine 48 I'm going to be done.
I'm gonna wrap this. I can,
because that's even worse.
You sit there and stare at a blank screen
or you click on that little on that
little internet browser
thing at the bottom.
Then there you go. You're going down
that slippery slope. Don't do it.
I'll do it.
Check
talking about the general
a little bit more.
If therefore he finds his army composed
of raw troops or if they have been long
on, long been unaccustomed to fighting.
He must carefully study the strength,
the spirit,
the manners of each particular legion
and of each body of auxiliaries,
cavalry and infantry.
He must know if possible,
this is good. He must know if possible,
the name and capacity of every count,
Tribune,
sub alternate soldier.
He must assume the most respectable
of fordy and maintain it by severity.
He must punish all military crimes
with the greatest rigor of the laws.
So there's a dichotomy there.
He's saying you should know the name
of every single person on your team.
At the same time,
if they get out of line,
you maintain by severity.
Hmm.
For troops that have never been an action
or have not for some time been used to
such spectacles.
Been used to such spectacles are greatly
shocked at the site of the wounded and
dying and the impressions
of fear they receive,
dispose them rather to fly than to fight.
That's again to me is how to you train
people and get them used to what they're
going to be facing in the real world.
Always keep that in mind as a leader,
and I was about to say, almost keep,
always keep that in mind as a trainer,
but as a, as a leader, guess
what you are. You're the trainer.
Hmm.
Having explained the less considerable
branches of the art of war, the mill,
the order of military affairs naturally
leads us to the general engagement.
So now he's up to this point.
He's only been talking about
how to get ready for war.
This is a conjecture full of uncertainty
and fatal to Kingdoms and nations for
indecision.
In the decision of a pitched battle
consist the fullness of victory
troops must never be engaged in a general
action immediately after a long march
when the men are fatigued
and the horses tired,
the strength required for action
is spent in the toil of the march.
What can a soldier do?
Who charges when out of breath?
Sure, everyone's going to hit
me up. See, you need more rest.
Hmm hmm.
And he goes on to a little,
a little get after it right here.
The sentiments of the troops
should be determined before battle.
It is necessary to know the sediments
of the soldiers on the day of the
engagement.
Their confidence or apprehensions
are easily discovered by their looks,
their words, their
actions, and their motions.
No great dependence is to be placed
on the eagerness of young soldiers for
action,
for fighting.
Has some thing agreeable in the idea
to those who are strangers to it.
So he's saying the young soldiers that
hadn't been a war that are all fired up
the fight,
don't listen to him because there's some
agreeable in the idea of fighting to
people that haven't done it before.
And then he says, on the other hand,
it would be wrong to hazard into an
engagement if the old experienced soldiers
testify a discussion of a declination,
a disinclination to fight.
So if the,
if the old guys are like, Hey, this boss
not a good idea, pay attention. A general,
however main courage and animate his
troops by proper exhortations and
harangues, especially if by his
account of the approaching action,
he can persuade them into the
belief of an easy victory.
With this
view,
he should lay before them the cowardice
or unskilled fullness of their enemies
and remind them of any former advantages
they may have gained over them.
He should employ every argument
capable of exciting rage, hatred,
and indignation against the adversaries
in the minds of his soldiers.
Now this is something I disagree with.
I disagree with this idea.
I disagree with the idea of telling the
troops that it's going to be an easy
victory of telling the troops
that, hey, they're cowards.
I don't agree with that.
And because when you do that,
there's a lot of things that
can go bad. Uh, number one,
when you go against the enemy and you
face him and they start doing good against
you because they're more skilled than
you expected, that's a problem. Yeah,
I can jam up your morale. All that
can jam up your morale really bad.
So I don't recommend ever
disrespecting the enemy.
I recommend you give them a full,
not to mention if hey,
this can be an easy victory. What's
your mindset going into it? I mean,
first of all,
you're not training hard for it.
You think you're going to win and easy
it's called. Yeah, don't do that. No, you,
you,
you respect the enemy.
I think the point that he may have been
trying to make is like don't be afraid
of the enemy. I get that. Nothing
to be afraid of, but respect him.
Didn't Frederick the great say
something like the last last time,
like something about remind them of
how lame they are or whatever. Um,
he did say something like
that and actually it just,
the thing that he was saying,
what was it that he said
he,
he was saying no.
What he was saying was only talk
about the enemy with total score.
That's what he was when we talk
about the enemy with total score,
and actually he was also saying like you
shouldn't even hate the enemy but don't
let anyone know that you don't hate her.
Which was kind of interesting and he's
saying the same thing like rage and
hatred and indignation. That's how you
want them to be thinking of the enemy.
So they both agreed on that point,
but I disagree on the point of tell the
tell your men that this is going to be
an easy fight because there's not
going to be an easy fight. Yeah.
Back to the book.
It is natural for men in general to be
affected with some sensations of fear at
the beginning of an engagement.
But there are without a doubt,
some of a more to Morris disposition who
are disordered by the very sight of the
enemy to diminish these apprehensions
before you venture on action,
draw up your army frequently in order
of battle in some safe situation so that
your men may be accustomed to the
site and appearance of the enemy when
opportunity offers,
they should be sent to fall upon them
and endeavored to put them to flight or
kill some of their men.
Okay.
Thus they will become acquaintanced with
their customs arms and horses and the
objects with which we once familiarized
are no longer capable of inspiring us
with terror.
It's amazing how good you get at something
like if you've seen it one time. Yeah.
You know, and just, just think
about any situation. Think if,
if like if you scare someone,
which I enjoy scaring people sir.
But if you scare someone and then they
come back in and you try and do the same
thing, it's like they're not
scared at all. It doesn't work. So,
so that's what, that's how you want to
prepare your people. You get them used to.
Those seeing what they're
going to see. Yeah. Good.
Generals are acutely aware that victory
depends much on the nature of the field
of battle
when you intend therefore to engage
endeavor to draw the chief advantage from
your situation.
The highest ground is reckoned the best.
Always take the high ground
talking about reserves,
the method of having bodies of reserves
in the rear of the enemy army composed
of choice,
infantry and cavalry commanded by the
supernumerary lieutenant generals counts
and tribunes is very judicious and of
great consequence toward the gaining of a
battle.
Some should be posted in the rear of
the wings and some near the center to be
ready to fly immediately to the
assistance of any part of the line,
which is hard pressed to prevent.
It's being pierced to supply the vacancies
made therein during the action and
thereby to keep up the courage of
their fellow soldiers and check the
impetuosity of the enemy.
Okay,
so always have reserves.
Don't overextend yourself.
The post of the commander in chief is
generally on the right between the cavalry
and the infantry.
Fraught for from this place,
he can best direct the motions of the
whole army and move elements with the
greatest of ease wherever
he finds necessary.
It is also the most convenient spot to
give his orders to both horse and foot
and animate them equally by his presence.
So position yourself in a good spot.
Okay.
And able general never loses a favorable
opportunity of surprising the enemy
either when tired on the march
divided in the passage of a river,
embarrassed in a morasses,
struggling with the Dick
clarities of mountains,
wind dispersed over the country,
they think themselves and security
or are sleeping in their quarters.
So just take advantage of your enemy
whenever they let their guard down.
In all these cases,
the adversaries are surprised
and destroyed before they
time to put themselves
on their guard.
But if they are too
cautious and you and give,
yeah,
but if they are too cautious to give
you an opportunity of surprising or
ensnaring them,
you are then obliged to engage
openly and on equal terms.
So whenever you get the chance,
you, you sucker punch him.
Right. You know, is that the,
is that, am I encouraging you go
out in soccer punch people know.
But if you're going to fight,
take advantage of the situation,
you've already determined that
the enemy that needs to be fought,
you're going to do everything you can to,
but isn't that you've got going anything.
I just started a rash of sucker punches.
No,
I feel like you misused the expression.
That's what I think from cause sucker
punch is more of a waging of war or a
certain level of war. When someone, and
you're saying these are already at war,
they're already at war now it's like it's
Kinda sucker punches the kind of, hey,
we're just going to go invade
this country. They have no
idea that were, you know,
they don't know kind of their citizens
said something bad about our president or
something like that.
But if you guys are in war and they
are sleeping or something like that,
oh no man.
That's good. Okay. I agree. No, I
actually agree with you very much.
Very strongly. I think you're
correct. Yeah. In fact,
I don't think you should soccer
punch anyone. Yes, I agree.
You shouldn't soccer punch someone, but
if you are at war with someone, yes,
then you're trying to get them at their
least prepared situation. Yes, I agree.
Thousand percent all
right. This is important.
The flight of an enemy
should not be prevented,
but facilitated generals unskilled in war,
think of victory,
incomplete.
Unless the enemy are so straightened in
their ground or so entirely surrounded
by numbers as to they have
no possibility of escape.
But in such situation
where no hope remains,
fear itself will arm an enemy and despair
inspires courage as powerful as you
think about that fear itself, alarm the
enemy if you surround them completely.
When men find themselves,
oh sorry.
When men find they must inevitably parish,
they willingly resolve to die with
their comrades and with their arms,
their hands,
the maximum that a golden bridge should
be made for a flying enemy has much been
commended for when they
have free room to escape.
They think of nothing but how to save
themselves by flights and the confusion
that you might think that you might
think by that statement. He say, hey leg,
you build the Golden Bridge
for them to get away. Yeah.
You might think that that's
sort of a a merciful to do,
but check out this line and
the confusion becoming general.
Great numbers are cut to pieces.
The pursuers can be in no danger when the
vanquished have thrown away their arms
for greater haste. So an area guys are
dropping their swords, they see an escape,
they dropped their swords and
they run for it. But you got them,
you're waiting there for him.
In this case,
the greater number of the flying enemy,
the greater the slaughter.
Yeah.
Numbers are of no signification where
troops once thrown into consternation are
equally terrified at the site
of the enemy as their weapons.
Yeah,
so that's good advice.
And that's,
this is something as well, you
know, I, it's not the same thing,
but man, when you, when you do,
when you're dealing with another
human being and let's say,
let's say you and I are talking about
something and I know I'm right and I know
you're wrong,
but you kind of planted yourself into it.
You kind of painted yourself
into a corner. Yeah.
I'll give you a little out and
give you a little while. You know,
I don't want to like,
I want to do that to you.
I don't want to do that
to be hard work with, no,
let me give you a little out like oh yeah.
It's probably the way it used to be,
but you know what, hey, you know, it's a
little subtle where you like, yeah, yeah.
You know, definitely I've done it before
I call. That's cool. I'm glad it worked.
You know, we think of this so
it gives good a little out.
That actually is very, very, um,
it's not, it's a nice thing to do,
but it feels very smart.
Very smart.
It's very smart to do you give people a
little out. Yeah. I have to do that with,
I have to do that with a, I
have to, my kids, you know,
I'm a little out cause
they'll paint themselves in a
corner because they're kids,
you know? That's what they did. They just
ask what they do. Yeah. Yeah. It's, uh,
when you embarrass somebody,
cause that's kind of embarrassing,
especially when you get into some
argument where it turns into me and so you
kind of thing, then you realize
you're wrong and you're like, Oh man,
I have to basically wow. I, yeah, give
them, let me give out. So we're kind of,
we're both winters can be good cause
my ego's not involved over here on this
happy that we can get along and
moving forward. Yeah. Good with it.
Back to the book in the first place,
your men must not imagine that
you retired to decline in action,
but believe you retreat and artifice to
draw the enemy in to a more advantageous
position for you where you may more
easily defeat them in case they follow you
for troops, you perceive their
general despairs of success are prone,
prone to flight.
So what that saying is,
and I should have given
this introduction before,
is that if you feel like
you have to retreat,
you don't say, hey, we're, we're,
we're getting crushed here and we're
going to retreat. What we say is, hey,
we're going to bait them,
we're going to move back and we're going
to draw that men. So the guys go, oh,
okay, I get it. If you're just like, hey,
we're getting our asses kicked
and we need to get out of here,
you're going to lose. Your
people are going to run away.
But if you're like, hey,
we're doing this maneuver,
we're going to fade back a little bit,
we're going to set him up and he'll go,
oh cool,
I'm gonna get an opportunity for payback.
So that's a good point.
Very good point.
It seems like their mindset would
still be in the fight in that case.
[inaudible] versus [inaudible].
Exactly.
You keep them in the
fight. It's exactly. Now,
once people once it,
once the enemy is fleeing and you
chase them, you gotta be careful.
Back to the book,
a ration inconsiderate pursuit exposes
an army to the greatest danger possible.
That a falling into ambush and
bushes and the hands of the troops,
enemy troops ready for their reception,
for as in the term temerity of an army
is increased and their caution lessened
by the pursuit of a flying enemy.
This is most favorable
opportunity for such snares.
So when you get somebody running after
you, that's when you can catch him.
The greater the security,
the greater the danger troops
when unprepared at their meals,
fatigued after march when their
horses are feeding. And in short,
when they believed themselves,
most security,
the most secure are generally
most liable to a surprise.
All risks of this sort are to be avoided
carefully and all opportunities taken
of distressing the enemy by such methods.
So that mindset that people get,
like you just said,
when they're running away is one thing.
But also when they think they just one,
they get the mindset of like,
oh,
we don't need security anywhere anymore
right now. We don't need it. We're good
there. That one little line,
the greater the security,
the greater the danger that that line
right there, it doesn't make any sense.
The greater the security, the great
danger. What he's saying is when the,
the greater the security is the greater
the danger of being susceptible to
letting your guard down.
Yeah.
Like if it name MMA situation,
they got the idea we talked about
before, but yeah, you've got them days,
days and they're like, well I'm going
to go either to the finish all crazy,
not like as cautious as maybe they should
be. Kind of that situation for sure.
He's talking about the greater of
the security. So the better you feel,
right does it, your said,
I keep losing that line.
The greater the security,
the greater the danger that the security,
the greater the danger. That's what it is.
So when you're feeling secure, watch it.
Watch yourself
resources in case of defeat.
If while one part of your army is
victorious, the other should be defeated.
You are by no means to despair.
Since even in this extremity,
the constancy and resolution of a
general may recover a complete victory.
So just cause you
take a little loss doesn't mean
you're going to lose completely.
Yet not withstanding an entire defeat,
all possible remedies must be attempted.
Since many generals have been fortunate
enough to repair such a loss so you can
always come back and army after
a defeat has sometimes rallied,
returned on the enemy,
dispersed him by pursuing an order
and destroyed him without difficulty.
Nor can men be in a more
dangerous situation.
Then when in the midst
of joy after victory,
there exfiltration is suddenly
converted into terror.
So same thing,
you're joyous cause you one and
all of a sudden you're the tables,
turn whatever be the event.
The remains of the army must
be immediately assembled.
Reanimated by suitable exhortations
and furnished with fresh,
fresh supplies of arms. That's what
you do when you get a good victory.
You're like, all right, reload.
That's what we're doing right now.
And in this last section of the book,
he,
he kind of just breaks down and sums up
the rest of the book that we just read.
Hmm. So these are all pretty
familiar. Most of them, cause we,
I covered most of them.
Okay.
It is the nature of war,
that what is beneficial to you is
detrimental to the enemy and what is of
service to him always hurts you.
Okay.
That seems like common
sense. Yes. The more troops,
the more your troops had been accustomed
to camp duties on frontier stations and
the more carefully they
have been disciplined,
the less danger they will
be exposed to in the field.
Yeah.
Train them hard.
Men must be sufficiently tried before
they are let against the enemy.
Train them hard. It is much better
to overcome the enemy by famine,
surprise or terror.
Then my general actions
for in the latter instance,
fortune has often a
greater share than valor.
I like the idea of overcoming
the enemy just by terror.
Just just, I wish there was like a, a
full chapter about that. That's legit.
Those designs are best,
which the enemy are entirely ignorant
of till the moment of execution.
Opportunity in war is often more
to be depended on than courage.
Okay.
To departure to the botch
the enemy soldiers and
encouraged them when sincere in
surrendering themselves is have a special
service for an adversary is more hurt
by desertion than my slaughter.
So if you get the enemy to
like come over to your side,
that's even worse to the enemy then
when you're just killing him because you
think about when you're
getting your friends killed,
you have some kind of vengeance.
Yeah,
but if they just take your friends and
then like all in the, in the back room,
having them having a glass of wine with,
you know, you're like, okay, I'm going.
If that sounds better than the deal I got,
it is better to have several bodies of
reserves then to extend yourself too much
to the front.
There you go.
A general is not easily overcome who can
form a true judgment of his own and the
enemy forces. We've been hearing
that one since Sun Tzu art of war.
Valor is superior to numbers.
Okay?
The nature of ground is often have
more consequences than courage.
These guys talking about terrain,
that's what he's talking about.
So everyone that's in the military, listen
to this right now. Terrain, terrain,
terrain.
Learn to read the terrain.
Okay,
this is a good one. A few men
are born brave. Many becomes.
So through care and force of discipline,
great dichotomy there.
Care for your people and through force
of discipline is what makes people brave.
Hmm.
In army is strengthened by labor
and weakened by idleness.
Don't sit around, don't
sit around. Keep moving.
Troops are not to be led to battle
and less confident of success.
Novelty and surprise.
Throw an enemy into consternation,
but common incidents have no effect.
Learn new moves.
That's some advice I need to take.
I always do the same moves,
not good.
He who rashly pursues a flying enemy
with troops in disorder seems inclined to
resign that victory which
he had before obtained.
So if, if you go pursuing the enemy
when your troops aren't organized,
you're basically trying to
give away your victory. Hmm.
So be careful when you pursue
an army on supplied with grain and other
necessary provisions will be vanquished
without striking a blow. I need
to, when do you find, sorry,
I looked around and looking for like a,
like a Roman soldier and they
find some letters and stuff.
But these guys must have been hungry
talking about all the talking about the
hunger.
Okay.
On finding the enemy has
notice of your designs.
You must immediately alter
your plan of operations. Check,
consult with many on proper
measures to be taken,
but communicate the plans you intend to
put an execution too few and only those
of the most assured fidelity or
rather trust no one but yourself.
Hmm. Interesting. Consult many people.
Yeah. Get some feedback from everyone.
Next punishment and fear thereof are
necessary to keep soldiers in order in
quarters,
but in the field they are more
influenced by hope and rewards.
Okay.
Oh,
dichotomy for you.
Good officers never engage in general
actions unless induced by opportunity or
obliged by necessity.
Okay.
To distress the enemy more by famine
than the sword is the mark of consummate
skill.
And this is actually the last one here.
Dispositions for action must be
carefully concealed from the enemy,
lest they should counteract them and
defeat your plans by proper expedience.
So those,
again,
I didn't cover all the maximums and the
reason I didn't is cause some of the
maxims that he talks about are,
are legitimately ancient
war tactical warfare,
but it's worth getting the books so
you can read those and understand them.
And he,
he kinda ends this book with a little
note to the emperor of Rome at the time.
And this is how he wraps it up,
how glorious it is.
Therefore for Your Majesty,
with all these qualifications to unite
the science of war and the art of
conquest and to convince the world that
by your conduct and courage you are
equally capable of performing
the duties of the soldier.
Yeah.
And the general.
Okay.
I think that's
actually a cool statement to end on
capable of we performing the duties of the
soldier and the general. So he wraps
up the book with that last dichotomy
and I think that's one of the,
really one of the most important
qualities for a leader to have.
And one of the most important
qualities to be able to balance.
And that is to be able to maintain
and lead from the highest position.
And at the same time, never
forget where you came from, right?
You've heard that expression.
You don't forget where you came from.
That's what he's talking about.
And I think for every leader,
what that means
is recognize that you still
have more to learn that,
okay,
you can still grow, you can still
try and get better. And obviously
that's what we're doing here
is trying to learn
and trying to keep learning. Sure. He,
and I think that wraps this
up and obviously we make
this podcast so that we can
learn and other people can
learn if they want to join in.
If you learn anything and you want to,
you don't give this podcast some support.
There's a great ways to do it.
And the goal when you support the podcast
is that you also support yourself.
That's, that's, that's the goal.
Mutually supporting situation is
what we're going for. So first off,
we got our company up in Maine,
up in New England origin USA
in Farmington, Maine. A hundred percent
American made products products.
Okay.
It's a Jujitsu company, first and
foremost, right? That's the foundation.
These yes, and rash guards. Interestingly,
gies one of the hardest things in
the world to make from scratch,
and we make them here in America for sure.
A lot of people think they're the best.
That's actually what I think. Yeah. Well,
so it depends on what you mean
by the best. So if you think
that the ones that fit the most
appropriately for Jujitsu [inaudible],
then yeah, then they're going to
use your g, two g for Jujitsu.
Then another basket of the
best concur if you want.
Various different weaves, various
different options that happened to me,
made it in America,
and various perfect blends for washing,
drying antimicrobials, stuff, you
know, and yeah, they're the best. Yeah.
When you see, what do you remember
the first time you saw dragon?
We've like with your own
eyes. Yes. Were you impressed?
I was like, it's legitimately, it's,
it's legitimately impressive.
I actually,
this is one of the dumbest things I've
ever thought of in my life. All right.
Lay It on me. When I first saw
dragon, we've, I thought to myself,
it would be cool to get a legit,
cause you know,
sometimes I got to wear a suit because
I'm going to work with a company or
something.
I thought to myself,
it would be cool to get a legitimate
suit made out of this dragon dragon we've
seen. Yeah. It took me about 20 minutes
before I realized I was an idiot.
But it's that cool looking. Yeah. Yeah.
And it's that practical. That's
the thing. Yeah. So anyways,
you can get geese, rash
guards, origin main.com.
What else joggers show? Well, okay,
so you wanted the sh the suit. Sorry
Brad, you said it. So you know, let's say,
let's talk about it at least a little bit.
You said the soup soup dude,
and you know, okay. You know,
hey, give me dragging. We've suit.
But they had,
I've talked about this before where my
favorite shorts are dragging. We've short,
they were, they don't make
them. Sorry. Not yet. Well,
so I was talking to Pete about, I don't
know about them and I was like, hey,
you know, like you should make the jegging
waist and I forget why, but you know,
not,
not now there's other shorts which are
actually could prove more dope check.
You see the Buffy, like
you saw the buttons, right?
Like for the shorts are these by
that, by their dope. Anyway, so yeah,
there's some joggers, some, you
know, some shirts and whatnot,
some regular apparel or athletic wear.
But I'm super comfortable.
I'll tell you that as the,
the self slash whatever proclaimed
Kunstler of comfort I can say is the most
comfortable stuff you're
ever going to put on.
If you find anything more
comfortable, let me know. We'll see.
Compare apples to apples, but yeah,
some, uh, some good stuff there.
Also some supplements.
Mm. And you know, speaking
of this, uh, so you know,
you know who doctor
Rhonda Patrick says yes.
She'd been on Joe Rogan a couple of
times. Yeah. Probably even more than that.
Anyways,
she just tweeted out this thing
talking about curcumin and,
well, what is it like, no kidding.
Double and triple whatever. Sure. Tests,
Ucla.
Um,
curcumin is awesome for you and,
but do you remember like what this
is? This is the thing, it blew off.
The article actually blew off,
wouldn't you?
Like it was like Yacker Q and keeps
down inflammation. That was no big deal.
But actually that's a huge deal. That's
one of the reasons clients enjoy warfare.
But then they did like a test and it
improved memory and like cognitive
reaction, 28% this is in a lab. And so,
and then they referred to people in India
that people in India who have a high
level of curcumin in their diets.
That's why Indian food,
it looks yellow is because of that.
There's one not just like direct,
but they're saying that's really a
interesting fact. Right? So anyways,
that's in there.
It's in joint warfare.
It's enjoy more than just
joint the Super Krill,
which is Krill oil.
As we all know by now,
Krill oil is pretty much the best source
of Omega three better than fish oil.
Yes. And we all know fish oil's
good. Krill oils, even better.
Super Krill oil even better
than regular criminal.
What the big difference between Super
Krill oil and Krill oil? I do. Yeah,
it's super.
No,
but there's been some actual technical
beneficial super stuff and it's like Zen.
It's something,
but it's an [inaudible] not a no.
It's like Xanthan [inaudible] or
something. Sorry I'm saying it wrong,
but it's an antioxidant, which is
a big deal. You know what? Rust,
rust, rust, oxidation. Yes.
All that is oxidation of metal.
So when you cause some I didn't,
well I knew for a long time,
but before I knew it, this is
what it is. You know? Well,
how my brain was as far as antioxidants
go, my mom's like, hey, antioxidants.
I'm like, wait, oxidants, oxygen, oxygen,
oxygen. Oxygen is good. We're like,
why is it anti oxygen kind of thing.
It's like, no, it's not anti oxidant.
Oxidant meaning it fights oxidation,
which is rust of your body.
So your body technically is
kind of rusting. You know?
Antioxidants keeps it from rusting.
So now that you,
when you hear a loyal on your ears,
you hear antioxidants,
that's what you're hearing.
It's going to keep your body from
rusting straight up. So krill oil,
Omega Three's better uptake than fish
oil. Um, and we need to make many things.
Just know that you need them in this
case for your joints. In other cases,
for your eyeballs, your brain,
your Oregon's, all this stuff.
But know that, just know that it has many
uses plus antioxidants, boom, supercrew.
That's what makes it super. Then
joint warfare, as we mentioned. Yes,
that's for your joints. Curcumin, not
just curcumin. Glucosomine can drain.
These are things, man, I'm telling
you. If you have bad joints, boom,
joint work. Get some
discipline too. But yeah,
by the way. And so now what we have, as
it turns out, according to Doctor Rhonda,
Patrick, as you said, we have so that
triple stack to each other. Yeah.
So joint warfare,
Krill oil is the joints,
but joint warfare also has
cognitive enhancements,
which as does the discipline,
the discipline is like a, what'd you call
it? A powder drink. That's what it is,
right? Yeah. That's,
I mean, you mix it up.
You put a little on your water bottle
and then it gives you a little bit. Yup.
It gives you that mental edge, uh,
advantage. Uh, Dave Burke sent me a text,
he said, quote, best quote from
the last podcast. Dave Berg.
Cause like a crackhead or something
like that. Sorry Dave. No offense.
Yeah, I know. You're just like
the discipline. Yeah. Hey Man.
Did you see someone posted a picture of
like a guy with like cocaine powder all
over his face? Yeah, the Dave Chappelle
situation. It's a good marks on
that discipline. Cool.
Well, so mark, okay,
so that's a little bit of a shifting
gears scenario in regards to supplements.
Milk. Okay. I'm gonna say the
word protein. I said this before.
I'll say it again cause it,
to me it's appropriate.
I'm going to say the word protein
powder, but I'm not going to say, hey,
mo is a protein bar.
I'm not going to say that it's not,
it's not appropriate because it's
different. This is how it's different.
It's milk. I just had a
guy hit me up. He said,
I don't drink protein powders, but it
sounds like this is just dessert. Yeah.
And I hate to say it, it's kind of
true kind of things like that too.
But dessert kind of has this like
kind of guilty kind of feel to it.
This is guilt free dessert. Here's
what I did though. I was pushing,
now I know and I was going to kind
of let you know, but I was like, hey,
you know it just let me just
have it be funny for me.
So I'm thinking literally thinking
of mark while I'm shopping.
So when I shot,
I don't know how much you shop,
but I go in next question and my go tos,
right to get red leaf lettuce,
eat a lot of red leaf lettuce
for whatever and they get milk.
But this time I'm thinking of the milk.
I don't know why. It was just in my head.
I wasn't going to go drink
some milk at that time.
It was just my head for whatever and
my eyes shifted to chocolate milk.
So I'm like, Hey, what if I
mix the chocolate milk with
the milk? I know, right?
It might be too much do it. No, I didn't
do it. You don't need to. Then again,
why would I knock it before I try it?
Because what if I discover something?
See what I'm saying?
I didn't do it yet.
I'll report back button on
the less it is like a desert,
but it's one of those beneficial desserts
like not like dark chocolate like you
know, considered dark chocolate. Right.
I mean it's a certain percentage rate or
something where it's like good for you.
Yeah,
got drink and that was kind of like that.
It's like a big milkshake but an egg
in there you really want to get, we'll,
we'll have some milk for sure.
At the immersion camp,
which is by the way,
August 26 that's the one it is.
Last year we didn't have more milk
wasn't even invented yet. Yeah.
It was like straight up.
Didn't exist. Didn't exist.
It was like then all of a sudden you
cracked an atom open and they had to add
milk to the periodic table. That just
happened last year. I had to drink.
I do drink chocolate milk because they
had it at the camp. Oh, right, right.
You have to deal like the old school
cafeteria chocolate milk. Just, just,
it's just not, it's just horrible.
You don't like it. I mean,
I think I'm addicted to the experience
because that's what would it had east not
good. It's not good. So
yeah, immersion camp,
August 26 in September 2nd that's the
last day about this two sessions in there.
I would say, uh, you know, I can't speak
for anyone else. I would say, yeah,
go to booth because that's good. But
you know, go to one but a two, whatever.
For those that are wondering,
and this isn't confirmed yet,
but we pretty pretty much
had the talk Pete, me and,
and be little and the conversation is
looking like one morning tea afternoon,
Nogi evening, whichever choice. Yeah.
That's like a dream,
isn't it? I think so too.
And I don't have any
complaints from the last one.
Literally I have no complaints.
But I do remember thinking if
there was some Nogi mixed in here,
this would really, this would make me
kind of not really want to leave you ever.
Yeah. Yeah. This is worth pointing
out. This is the kind of thing that I,
you, you ever think about
like people that are OCD? Yes.
I think about that all the time.
Right? Obsessively compulsively.
So sometimes I have a little bit of that,
but one of them is,
is like I want things to be squared away.
Right.
And so when I was going to the camp,
I was kind of like,
how has this whole laundry thing going
to work? Like what's going to happen?
This was before. Yeah. Well the
thing is just to let everyone know,
if you come to camp, they, they do
laundry, there's like a laundry service.
It pick it up,
they pick it up and they wash all your
clothes and then they bring back in all
your clothes nice and clean.
And that's a huge,
so you think you could basically get
away with two D's? Two Keith? Yeah.
Well maybe three. I, yeah, I
would say, wait, I only had two,
probably three days. I didn't
bring any geese. I got origin,
I'll bring it to and bottling
them to get there. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm saying to rotate
them through properly,
but they're pretty fast on its turnaround
anyway. So that's the deal. But the end,
but that's a, that's a, that's
kind of a big deal. The logistics,
cause there's a difference between,
hey, there's the laundry service, um,
walk across camp to the laundry mat
and go handle your business. Well,
and actually the campus at a
different same lake, echo lake,
but it's a different lake. But, and I
don't know what the exact laundry service.
I think it's gonna be the
same exact thing though,
because the service didn't come from Cam.
I somebody that does
laundry for geese makes it,
there should be people in the world
that just geeky laundry. Keala yeah,
they come and grab it though. They knock
on the door. Like room service. Yeah.
Really? It's a huge deal. I think it's
very convenient. Great. Nice. But yeah,
emerging camp,
August 23rd,
August 26 through September 2nd
two sessions. I'm gonna be there.
Jocko is going to be there.
Rolling.
Rolling to fulfill your curiosity
of how it is to roll with you.
Um, I'm not going to say it'll
be a good time rolling with jock.
I'm not going to say that like my down my,
yeah,
you might get let down as far
as pleasurable experiences go.
Might let you that mind to bs.
Everyone thinks all he's gotta be stolen.
Believable? No, it's to come.
Not that good at Jujitsu. Yeah.
I wasn't really thinking that.
I was thinking more. Um Oh yeah,
that'll be fun and pleasurable.
Meanwhile it'll be like,
like 90% painful and then like
5% embarrassing and you know,
and various other negative emotions.
But yeah, he can, you know, whatever.
If you wonder about that kind of stuff.
I Dunno, maybe you don't, but yeah,
that's in origin also.
We have a store,
actually Jocko has a store
and it's called Jocko store.
Who made that name up? I did
keeping it simple. Anyway,
this is where you can get the rash
guards that we make get after it.
He'll trooper rash guards where
your kid rash guards too by the way,
if we're youth or your
kids getting into Jujitsu,
boom and for surfing and for whatever,
running, cycling, all that stuff. Um,
and uh,
what other rash guards are there at five?
I was going to make it make sense to
yeah. I stand by it. Get some rash guard.
That's what I'm going
to make stand by to get.
So check I was going to make a good
rash guard but then I thought, hey,
what's the message of good isn't it isn't
standing by to get some too close to
get after it? No. Okay.
Because Stan but now you stand by to get
something is when you're standing by to
get some getting after it is when
you're actually getting after it.
So when you're standing by where you're
getting after is two different things.
Completely back to the good rash card is
important I think as far as the layers
go. Okay, good. Is like when
something quote unquote bad happens,
there's always something good to come
from it. So what you sit to direct quote,
so you can't make him put on a rash
guard that's based on something bad
happening as far as losing goes or
something like that, right? No. Okay.
I guess you could technically,
if it looked dope, I dunno.
Jury's still out. Anyway,
back to the tee shirt. There's
some corns on there, right?
I just put that diff core on the
tee shirt def. Yeah. Good idea.
I think you're, you're right about
the, a lot hats on there as well.
Two kinds of hats as a, right. Actually
three technically three types of headgear,
trucker hats, flex fit hats, beanies.
Just in time for summer.
It's actually been,
he's been out for awhile and things
was go give yourself too much credit.
But speaking of summer and winter hoodies,
you'd get hoodies on there too.
Legit hoodies, non Hawaiian hoodies.
You know you're going to make,
you're going to make a Hawaiian
hoodie apparently. Yeah.
I think technically there's no
such thing as a plain Hoodie,
but I will have a lighter weight Hoodie
for when you go to Hawaii and it turns
nighttime and the wind, the breeze
kind of blows and you're like, Dang,
I wish I had my long sleeve shirt on.
You know, and it'll look kind of don't.
That's what I think.
That's my whole approach in my opinion.
It's a women's stuff on there too.
Um, you know, for the lady troopers,
some tank tops and v neck type t shirts
made specifically for the ladies.
Solid discipline equals freedom go down.
Also other ways to support.
Another way to support
subscribe to the podcast.
If you haven't already on iTunes and
stitcher and Google play or wherever you
listen to podcasts,
whatever platform you choose to use.
Also Youtube.
Yeah,
you should subscribe to Youtube.
The reason is so you can see
echoes legit videos. For instance,
you just rereleased one thank God.
Yes,
echo had made a video for
warpath and he put Christmas,
which we all love,
which it was during Christmas time.
And the thing is,
the video is so graphically intense and I,
I could tell and you had actually
told me that it took days,
days to put together three worth of yeah.
Film.
And so when you showed it to me,
I was super pumped and then I heard
the music that was super unpolished.
Yeah,
it was on pumps and anyways,
he's redone the warpath video
now as good music behind it.
Not Christmas music. We'll
just say revised, revised.
Did you pull off the old one broke
down. I left it man. That's for us.
You know folks who like Christmas,
all of the Grinch over here. I know.
But yeah, it's good. Youtube yet.
Subscribe to the Youtube and leave a
review on the, on the iTunes thing.
If you're in the mood. That's
my opinion. There you go.
Good way to support to also if you are
looking to improve and increase your
supply of fitness gear.
I just got a few things from my,
my bicep brats.
You don't,
when you kinda choose to embark
on a different type of fitness,
I dunno, you stick with the same thing. I
get it. No, but getting different things.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You get fired up. But
anyway, no, I don't want to go into that,
but I got some new stuff anyway. Where
you get it is in my opinion, could on it.
So on at Dotcom. Slash. Chocolate you can
get some good stuff on there including,
but not limited to kettlebells.
Maces and we get battle ropes.
I just read some really good stuff
about battle ropes. I've done them,
but not with any kind of regularity.
Yeah, yeah. Like I want to,
I want to do a battle rope
program. Hmm. Yeah, man.
I hope I don't go in too much, but it's
like, you know, like if you're trying,
it's like for metcons and you can dump
your full body, boom, boom, boom. Yeah.
It's like it burns a lot of calories.
Get to in a muscular muscular conditioning
and stuff like that, but really good.
I was like,
after you read it,
it's like you want to do battle
ropes from that one inquiry. Anyway,
go ahead on it. Dotcom. Slash Jocko.
I got the mace from
Jocko today as fired up.
Heavier than your saw. Yeah. So and
I knew it was going to be happy.
That's the thing like I know because
that's only a 20 pounder and lucky if
you're one of those things.
I think you know when we talk about
kettlebells and people will say like what
size kettle bell do you start off with?
It's hard to narrow that down.
That thing is heavy.
There's not too many people that are
just getting all over that 20 pounds.
This is like too heavy. I've never
done a workup before. By the way,
this is too heavy for me to
do like a workout. I'm like,
even even like it's so, it looks
like a big, what do you call it?
Not a bowling pin,
but you know the juggling pins,
you know like the people in the jail.
So it looks like that,
but it weighs 20 pounds.
It feels like it weighs like 50 pounds.
Literally feels like that because
it's all big anyway, but I'm going to,
I'm going to work it in and I'm going
to report back and I feel that suit.
I'm going to be a lot stronger
than you son like it. That's good.
Speaking of that, if
maybe you're thinking, oh,
instead of working out
I'm going to take a break.
You can get the psychological
warfare album that has tracks,
it's on iTunes, Google play
MP3. Whenever you get mp3s.
Just a little bit of guidance on how to
overcome situations where maybe you're
not going to get after it and you know
you should. Yeah. So there you go.
Working on psychological
warfare two at this time,
so that'll be coming in the future.
All your excuses are lies
going to be the title,
psychological word for it to
all your excuses are lies. Yeah.
See that kind of came well that's good.
I like how you do that.
I'd call it like a spot, like a spot. Like
if I'm going to go psychological spot.
Yeah. That's what it is. Cause all of that
though because not everyone thinks of,
when you say spot you're thinking of
1994 weight lifting bodybuilding. Sure.
Oh No, power lifting. Yeah, I
guess you can't really spot on a,
on a power clean like Olympic lifting.
Nonetheless,
it is a spot nonetheless regards
to what an analogy you want to use.
I think the band, the spot is the best
because you don't need a spot necessarily.
Most of them, you don't
need it most the time. Cool.
But if you've got a spotter there
and you need the spot, boom,
there it is and he's in a spot you
and he's going to bring you through.
You're not going to let the barberry
you understand. Fair enough. Also,
Jocko has some tea.
It's called Jocko white tea.
Interestingly enough, uh, dry tea,
which is tea bags and in it can,
which I've been popping every day.
By the way,
I'm not going to say it's an anti nausea
medication. I'm not going to say that.
But as it turns out,
it's kind of an antinausea medication.
Super refreshing because I can't,
by the way,
it's also anti weakness because
once you drink Jocko white tea,
you can deadlift 8,000
pallets automatically. Hey,
it's available in Canada too on
Amazon in Canada. That's new.
So checkout Canadian folks up there,
hanging out with Jody Mitic somewhere.
Sure.
Then you can get it there too.
Also got some books where the
warrior kid and Mark's mission,
those are for children.
But I think everyone that reads
him get something out of him.
He's so check them out there. Might like
them. That video you did with Brian Rose,
right? The lending area one. Um, some
of my brothers watching the video,
I don't know why he's all like surprise,
like he's impressed. Okay, I get it.
But like he's all surprised, impressed,
you know the difference. Right.
So he's watching the video, the, you know,
how you basically the part where you
were explaining where the work here,
part two marks mission, where are you
like okay, this psychological bully,
you know, did this thing and no mark
wants to fight. I mean you can fight now,
no Jujitsu. So he kind of wants to fight
him. So uncle Jake psych, you know,
comes in and he's all, hey
cool, you can fight them.
So I was like, Oh Jake, you know, getting
nuts, whatever. Okay, you can find them.
But first you got to do recon or Intel
right until gathering or whatever,
see what up.
And so he does and he finds out all this
stuff you and through like finding the
stuff or whatever,
he gains like a little bit understanding
or whatever and so instead of fighting
them,
maybe you should help them kind of thing.
So it's like this little
curve ball. It's like, man,
it's like kind of taking the high ground
when you don't expect you to just kind
of liked that he liked down. He's all
impressed. Impressed with it. Not Bad on,
let them read that thing, still
reading it until my girl little girl.
That's Jack's kind of the ethos, right?
The way that where he kid eat those,
you just read it. You just keep
reading when you're done reading it,
you read it again. Start all over. Yeah.
Yeah. She likes it. She liked the paper,
Mashiach pumpkin situation.
She really liked.
That part was actually pretty fun.
It was good and all are shining
through. Oh yeah. Big Tech.
Also the field manual,
discipline equals freedom field manual.
Best Book ever written. Best
Book. Physically look at
my opinion. Black on black.
But do you think of that front cover
for a photograph? You like that? Yeah.
It's very iconic photograph.
Yeah, that's a good,
that's a,
it's like what do you call like a manual
for if you make it a manual for life in
general, I think you'd be on
the good path right there.
I agree.
If you need a manual for some leadership,
you got extreme ownership.
That's the book that I wrote with my
brother Leif Babin and it's about combat
leadership and how you can apply the
lessons that we learned on the battlefield
to everything you do in your business
and in your life and your relationships
with people and also coming pretty soon.
What actually is the follow on to that
book that are also wrote with leaf,
the dichotomy of leadership.
It is, you know, you,
you've heard us talk about
dichotomy all the time.
It's actually the last chapter of extreme
ownership and this is the trickiest
thing about leadership is trying to
balance this dichotomy so we talk about it
and do a deep dive and get granular
on how to balance that economy of
leadership.
In that book,
which is titled The dichotomy of
Leadership. You can preorder it right now.
It comes out September 25th if you don't
want to get a copy when it comes out,
then don't order it now and you won't
get one cause it's gonna sell out in.
The publishers are slacking as usual
and they'll be like, wait, wait, wait.
But there's probably a part of town,
a few of these because
they're projected numbers are off
always and you want to get the,
you want to get the first edition.
That's my opinion,
so do that and for all for for leadership
training onsite beyond the books,
beyond the podcast,
I have echelon front.
It's our leadership consulting company.
We solve problems through
leadership. Also, we have the muster,
which is a leadership conference.
There's only one more this year.
It's in San Francisco.
Muster zero zero six it's October
17th and 18th you have to register for
that@extremeownership.com every
muster we've done is sold out.
This one will sell out to and also
for current military law enforcement,
border patrol, firefighters, paramedics,
first responders. We got the roll calls,
zero zero one September 21st in Dallas,
Texas.
It's a focus one day leadership training
seminar for people that are in uniform
handling stressful situations
and you can also register for
that@extremeownership.com and until we
are live at the muster in San Francisco
or at the roll call in Texas or
at the immersion camp in Maine.
Until then if you want to
cruise kind of hard with us.
We are on the interwebs,
on Twitter,
on Instagram and yes on that
baseball game. Echo is adequate.
Charles and I am at jockowillink and
thanks to all the people in uniform out
there, military police, law enforcement,
firefighters, paramedics, border patrol,
all first responders.
Really we won't be able to do what
we do without you doing what you do.
So thank you for protecting us and
taking care of us and also thanks to your
families who support you while you
support us and to everyone else.
Everyone else.
Thanks for listening and
remember what the Getty is said
that it isn't just sighs or numbers or
even courage itself that will ensure
victory.
Instead,
it is exact observance of discipline.
That is what it takes.
That is what you need.
So go out there and get after it.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.