You discuss making sure your teams have
the freedom to make strategic changes to
the plan if needed.
What if you're developing a system with
your team and you begin to get push back
from them before you fuel the
core values are established.
So this is a really good question.
Once again,
you start calling up with your plan
and you're already starting to get some
pushback from the boys on what it is.
Well, what do you do? Listen to them.
Listen to them. Why are they
pushing back? You know what I mean?
Why are they pushing back? Maybe they
have some good points. Is that possible?
Maybe you're a little bit off base on the
plan that you're coming up with her in
the strategy that you're coming
up op with. Maybe you're not.
Of course that's always possible to,
maybe they're wrong. You're right,
but hear them out. You
know, if I say, hey,
we're going to hit the target
from this direction here,
and my team disagrees with
what I'm saying, well, why
are the disagreeing? What's,
what's the reason for that? You know,
how do they think we should do it?
They should think we should come
in from the, from the south,
and I think we should come from the north.
Why do they think that now?
If I know something is right
and I am right, then guess what? I can
explain it to them and they'll say,
oh, Jocko, we didn't know that.
We didn't know that there was defenses
that we hadn't been told about to the
south and why. That's why we
should come into the north door.
We didn't know that the sun would
be bad or back from the north.
And that's why we didn't
know that at the time.
So you're right now,
if I can't explain it to them for,
can't give them a reason why my
strategy or my plan is better,
then there's something wrong with my
plan or there's something wrong with my
ability to explain it to them,
right?
So if you're doing the right
things for the right reasons,
you'll be able to convince your
team of the strategy or of the plan.
And if you can't,
it's a hint that maybe you need to
adapt your strategy or maybe you need to
adapt your plan. Now be
advised, this is not easy.
This is not easy to do. First of all,
you have to get your ego in check, right?
Because you think you've come up with a
plan and you think it's the master plan,
so you, you, you have to put
your ego in check is secondly,
you might actually have the best plan,
but maybe you don't have the ability
to articulate the nuances of the plan.
And so your guys,
you get a guy that's a really articulate
guy that's arguing with you on his plan
and he's actually winning the argument,
even though your plan might be better.
That's a,
that's a tough situation to be in.
So that means you've got
to really get in the weeds.
Now, one thing that you could do in that
situation, they say, Hey, I'm in charge.
Shut up. Listen to me. And again,
this might be a situation where
you're right and they're wrong,
but if you can't articulate that properly
and now you only way to do is to pull
rank on them, hey, you're
going to go backwards, right?
You're going to go backwards. So you
have to be very careful that, again,
this is why it's important to,
to have good command of
the English language.
That's why it's important to listen.
That's why it's important to take people's
ideas and that's the thing with being
a leader.
Okay,
have an open mind, have open ears, listen,
communicate and lead
your team not by rank,
right?
But by being able to,
to discern and uncover and mold and
shape the best possible plan in the best
possible strategy by and through
understanding everyone's perspectives and
ideas,
and then taking all those perspectives
and all those ideas and coordinating them
into a unified fought that
leads the team to victory.
That is hard.
That is hard to do.
But the minute, again, the minute
that I'm telling somebody, hey, no,
just do it my way.
I know that there's,
there's something wrong here
either I'm not articulating right,
which means I should take the time
because if I'm right and you're wrong,
we should be able to get there
to where you see that. Yeah,
we should be able to get there.
We could also get to a point where it's
six in one half dozen. The other right.
We could get to that point too, and at
that point, you know what I'm going to do.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm going to use your plan.
If it's six one half dozen, the other,
I'm gonna use your plan. Echo says,
come in from the north.
I say come in from the West.
We look at the pros and cons of each.
I'm going to go with your plan.
What'd you want to come in from
the West? Yeah. Okay. If it's,
if it's 50 50 I'm going
to go with your plan.
I'm going to give it to you
and give you the ownership.
That's what I'm going to do.
Even I'll tell you,
even 60 40 I'm probably
going to give it to you.
We get to, you know, 70 30
now you're going to see it.
You're going to see the light.
If you have any brain now,
you could also be an EGOMANIAC, right?
Who's like my way? My Way, my way.
Now we've got to break through that.
How do we do that?
It's not by attacking your plan,
which you're going to defend because
you're an EGOMANIAC. Instead,
I'm going to say, well, tell
me the benefits of your plan.
Let's wait it out between
your plan and my plan.
Maybe we adapt your plan a little
bit. Oh, I like what you did here.
I see where you're coming from.
That's a really good point.
I didn't think of that, but also we
need to consider this that I didn't.
You know, we, we didn't know before.
So now we're going to adjust.
So those are the things that are hard.
Those are things that are
hard about being a leader.
But the best thing you can do,
open your mind, open your ears,
listen to what people are saying.
Take it onboard.
If their plan is better than yours, great.
Use it. If it's not better than yours,
okay, articulate the reasons why.
Have the conversations with them.
Don't be scared. It's a slick move. I,
I didn't think of that for you.
Got to build up their ego.
If they got the big ego,
we've got to flank them blank yet.
So yeah,
that's good.
Get other people's perspectives because
it can seem like a 50 50 or it can seem
like 60 40 you know,
but it can also seem like a 64
or 70 30 year plan is better.
But to them 70 30 they're plan is
better because of their perspective.
Let's say they, they, there's rats drawing
down this trail. Yeah. I don't like rats.
But if you didn't know that, you know,
you're like frats who cares kind of thing.
Yeah. Yeah. Dang girl, you're advanced
dogs would be a better thing. Sure.
To say rats aren't going to interfere
with your mission. Dogs start barking.
And maybe they had,
they had somebody,
they read an Intel report that said there
was a bunch of dogs up in this, this,
you know, residents to the north.
So we want to come in from the West.
And I didn't know that. I didn't
do a good enough. So now it's easy,
easy thing to convince me off.
Right.
But all we have to do is
have the conversation. Yeah.
I understand the perspective. Talk and
communicate those dogs with three teeth.
Put your egos in check.
Yeah. Or snakes, by the way,
if you're Indiana Jones
or something like that.