The w when you, what you
mentioned about bravery, this,
how you were talking
with Sam Harris about it,
where braveries only present
if you are scared of something.
Because if you're not scared of it,
you're not being brave to overcome
anything or to to go, you know,
to do any kind of activity that's um,
you know, they, that you're scared of.
So the very,
although I don't know if I necessarily
agree with that because there's guys that
are, you know, he's says he's never
seen anyone that's not not afraid.
I seen some pretty cool,
I mean it's almost the word he uses our
crazy guys that are just so brave in do
you look at them and they, you,
you go, this guy is going to sky.
I had guys with me, you
know, in my task unit and
some of those guys were sole brave
that I didn't think they were going to
Megan home. And is it,
cause they were like, um,
it's like they, they weren't scared
to die at all. Like you didn't, yeah.
And,
and
you see the,
almost a lack of self
preservation. Right. You know, not,
not stupid, not, not
suicidal, but like, oh,
this guy doesn't think he can be killed.
You know,
we were talking about that
on the last podcast on,
and I forget the name of the major
that was on the beach landing at Toro,
I think. And he's up and he's like, Hey,
look, they can't hit me. Come on. Yeah, I,
I've seen guys do that.
Yeah.
So
as far as actual bravery goes though,
so would you consider that.