It took me a long time to
understand what sacrifice meant. Um,
because on the surface of it,
especially the way it's acted out,
like burnt offerings and that sort
of thing, it just seems like, well,
it seems so archaic and, and distant from
us that it's not really comprehensible,
but partly from reading John Piaget,
I started and neat you for that matter.
I started to understand that people
often acted out conceptions before they
understood what they meant.
You know,
when we act out a lot of things we
don't understand because we're much more
complex than we can represent.
So we're always acting out
things we don't understand.
But so there's this idea in Cain and
Abel that you have to make sacrifices in
order to stay on the good side of
God. And so I thought about that. Um,
practically say not so much
metaphysically but practically,
and realized that that was equivalent
to the discovery of time of the future
because we do,
we do act and that,
and this is a peculiar
discovery of human beings,
may be a consequence of our expanded
intelligences that we're actually aware of
the future.
And we actually treat the future as if
it's something that you can bargain with.
Now, partly it's because the future
is other people and they remember your
reputation, they remember your past
actions. And if you do someone a favor,
then that favor is in some
sense stored up in the future.
So you can think about the future as
a place of judgment about your moral
actions.
And it's not that far from
that to imagining a god
who's keeping track of that
or who even is that.
But in any case,
the idea of sacrifice emerges in the
story of Cain and Abel and Cain and Abel
both make sacrifices to God in order
to stay on his good side, let's say.
And what a sacrifice means is that you
give up something of value in the present
so that you can be so that you can
improve the future. And you know,
that's no different from what we call
discipline. It's exactly the same thing.
It's just thought that concretely acted
out version of that. And so, you know,
the idea basically was that,
well God was in the transcendent heavens.
And,
and the first question would be, well,
why is that when it's like, well,
if you go out and, and really
dark night and look up at the sky,
you have a sense of what's
beyond you, what, what's
transcendent, what's infinite?
And,
and so to associate that with the highest
of values is a reasonable association,
right? From, from a say, from
an emotional point of view.
So it's not particularly
primitive. It's a smart, um,
metaphor or it's a smart intuition
that, that, that, and it's above you.
And you know, we tend to think of
when you're moving towards an ideal,
that you're moving up,
that you're moving above,
you're moving to the mountain top,
right? You're, you're going up, not down.
And so it all sits within
that same framework.
And it's partly because when you go up,
like on a mountain,
you can see for long distances,
right?
So those are all those things
are tangled together. So anyways,
so the idea is that you have to give
up something of value now, so you,
so that you make the future better.
And sometimes it's even
something you love now.
Now that's a good example too,
because often the things that
stop us from moving forward, our,
our attachments to things that we
should no longer be attached to. Right?
And in fact,
you can almost make that definitional if
you're not moving forward in your life.
There's a high probability that you
have some idea or some mode of action or
some habit that you're so in love
with that you won't let go of it. So,
all right,
so Cain and Abel,
Cain and Abel make sacrifices and there's
kind of a hint in the story that it's
just a hint that came sacrifices.
They're sort of second rate.
But in any case it's
ambivalent tay. But, but Abel,
he just does wonderfully well
and everything works out for him.
And everyone knows people like that,
you know?
And so God accepts his sacrifices.
But for some reason he rejects canes.
And maybe it's the arbitrary Agnes of
God or maybe it's cause Cains heart isn't
in the right place when he's making
his sacrifices, which is more likely.
And so Ken goes and has a
chat with God and he says,
basically what he says is something like,
how in the world can you possibly
justify this universe that you created?
You look at me and I'm breaking myself
and half trying to adapt and to make
things right and it's not working.
And then there's this able character and
things come easy to him and everything
is flourishing for him.
And so like what the hell?
And if you don't understand that question,
then you're not thinking
because it's very,
very frequently the case when a serious
catastrophe besets you in life that you
essentially ask exactly that question.
What's the meaning of life?
What's the purpose of the world?
How come there's suffering?
And it's easy to become resentful and
vengeful as a consequence of that.
And so you got to think about what state
of mind having your sacrifices rejected
puts you in,
especially when you see someone who's
successful because that's where the
jealousy and resentment starts to starts
to what faster is probably the right
word.
And so God says to Cain exactly what
he doesn't want to hear, which is,
well, yeah, okay,
but you have made lots of mistakes
in your life. So he basically says,
sin is at your door like a predatory
and sexually aroused animal,
and you've invited it into your house
to have its way with you and produce
something creative as a consequence. So
he was used as sexual metaphor, you know,
and so that you've willingly gone down
the negative path and you've allowed that
to enter into you and,
and to operate in a creative manner
and you've spun off all these terrible
thoughts and, and this justification
for not acting properly.
And that's why things
aren't going well for you.
And so don't lay that at my feet,
which is the most brutal possible
message he could have got.
And so then he leaves the presence of God,
let's say.
And it says in the story
that his countenance fell,
which meant he was basically enraged.
And so what does he do?
It goes out and kills Abel.
And then that's,
that's a very fascinating idea
because Abel is his ideal.
So kills is ideal. And when you
kill your ideal, you're lost.
And then he does that to take revenge on
Abel, but also to take revenge on God,
which I think is extremely interesting.
And, and a deep, deep idea.
Like these kids who shoot
up high schools for example,
you cannot understand what they're doing
unless you understand the story of Cain
and Abel.
You cannot understand what possesses them
until you can understand that someone,
even someone who doesn't
believe it doesn't matter.
It's the psychological
state of mind that matters,
is they're out for
revenge on being itself.
And that's why they produce as much mayhem
as possible in the shortest period of
time.
That's why they sacrifice in innocent
people because it's much more vengeful
and, and demonstrative to kill innocent
people than to kill guilty people. Right?
Cause it's a worse sin,
so to speak.
And then they killed themselves and
they killed themselves as a final
demonstration of their belief in,
in nihilism and the horror of existence.
Because you might say,
well,
why don't they just kill themselves
first and save everyone the trouble?
You know?
And there's narcissism in that too,
because they know their names are
going to be splashed across the page.
That's their notoriety instead of
their accomplishment. And of course,
the media is unbelievably
complicit in that. Um,
but well, so when you're talking
about motivation for evil,
then you have to understand
what it is that's driving it.
And it is a deep resentment about the
structure of being for being what?
Saturated with suffering,
but also for rejecting.
You're rejecting your sacrifices and that,
you know,
that produces the bitterness of failure.
And I'll stop with this.
One of the things that's
really interesting about
the old testament is that,
and the Jews in the Old Testament is that
they don't take the path of cane every
time they're walloped by God, which
is like fairly frequently. They say,
we must have done something wrong and we
have to set ourself right. And that's,
uh,
an unbelievably heroic attitude because
that's the alternative to cursing fate.
It's like you take the responsibility
for failure onto yourself.