This is Jocko podcast number
one 18 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
I need a mission.
We all need a mission.
That's what life should be is a mission.
That's what gives your life purpose
and focus and drive and ultimately
satisfaction.
Now that mission can
be the job you work at.
It can be providing for your family or
it can be getting better at Jujitsu or
stronger at Olympic lifting or starting
a business that you want to grow and
build and take over the world.
And sometimes people ask me what to do
if they don't know what their mission is
or what their mission should be.
And I tell them if they're in
that situation to go help someone,
go help someone else.
Make that your mission because
that will make you better.
It'll make the world better.
And eventually from that you'll
see what your mission is.
Now I was lucky because from
a young age I had a mission.
I want it to be some kind of commando.
And eventually I ended up hearing about
the seal teams and decided that that was
the best place for me.
And that's where I went.
And once I got to the seal teams,
I had a new mission,
which was to prepare for war.
And that's what we did.
And then eventually
war came.
And then that was the mission
to take the fight to the enemy to close
with and destroy them through close
combat.
And that's what we did.
But eventually
for me
and for everyone in the military,
it ends
maybe because of retirement or maybe
because of family obligations or maybe for
medical reasons, but for
every warrior, eventually
the war ends
and that career ends.
And that mission ends.
And I've talked a lot on this podcast
about how important it is to find a new
mission.
Once the war is over for you
and you've done your part,
you have to find a new mission.
Well
tonight we have a guest on
who pursued much the same mission as me
for as long as he could and who has
now found a new mission that he is on.
So
Dan Crenshaw, welcome to the
podcast. Thanks Jack. [inaudible].
Pleasure to be here with you.
Real honor. Thanks for coming on.
And let's just start at the beginning
a little bit for people that don't know
who you are. Let's talk a little bit
about, I guess we'll talk about Katy,
Texas and at the same time also
include Ecuador and Columbia about your
childhood. Absolutely. Well,
like you said, I grew up in Katy,
Texas,
um,
at six generations of and flowing through
me and my dad's side of the family.
And, uh, my dad was in the oil
and gas industry our whole lives.
So when you hear the things about a
Ecuador and Colombia and even Egypt in
Scotland, that goes all the places
we lived over the years. Um,
because it is a cause of his career.
Everybody and anybody in the oil and
gas industry in Texas knows that it's,
it's a pretty common theme. Um, you know,
I like to talk about some
of the challenges that I
went through from an early
age and uh, what kind of, what drove
me or it may be, and maybe drove my,
that, that get past that mental capacity
that you need to become a seal. And um,
that started with my mother
and my mother got, um,
diagnosed with breast cancer and I was
five years old and she fought it hard for
five years and she never quit. She
never complained. I never saw it.
And if she did, I never saw it. And um,
and she just took care of me and my
brother every day right up until the end.
Man. Now she eventually lost that
battle when I was 10 years old, 1994.
But she instilled in me,
you know what I,
what I think are American and
Texas values of integrity,
respect and it just never quit.
Never quit no matter what.
And don't feel sorry for
yourself. Um, cause she never did.
She truly never did.
And she asked where she told me before
she died that I would sort of great
heights and I don't know what that meant
at the time. Um, but I think we know now,
and I'm not long after that,
you know,
when I could start reading
books and m and uh,
in grabbed the first navy seal Dick
Marcinko novel rogue warrior that I could
be, your book wasn't out yet,
taco otherwise maybe I'll, yeah,
rogue warrior that, that, that came out
when I was already in it. Matter of fact,
it came out right as I
showed up at the teams. It,
I'm pretty sure that's right when it came
out and obviously created some turmoil
and the teams,
but it was pretty interesting,
especially because I knew
guys that had worked for,
for Dick Marcinko and that was pretty
interesting to talk with them. And,
and to be totally frank with you,
most of the guys that work for
Dick Marcinko loved him. And,
and as a matter of fact, one of them, a
couple of the guys that I respect, my,
there's one guy as a matter of fact,
that that I work for.
And this was a couple of years later.
It's a matter of fact,
it was around 1994 because I was in a
seal platoon and I was talking to this guy
that had worked for, for Dick
Marcinko and I said, hey, you know,
how was Dick Marcinko? I wasn't to work
for him. And he looked at me, he said,
best CEO ever. Yeah. And this was from
a guy that I have utmost respect for.
So I thought that was pretty cool. Even
though you know his book, you know,
the book is, it's, I'd say
it's a Hollywood ish book. And,
and you know the,
the statement in there that everyone
always laughs about in the teams is the
statement that every seal on his
team could bench press 500 pounds.
The number game. We're not going, we're
not even going to make it realistic.
We're not going to make it realistic.
And we're just going straight to
500 pounds, everyone on the team.
And that's just a patently untrue.
And what sucks is when you do that
with that thing, well then you,
then people start looking
at the book and going, well,
what is true and what is not? Right. So,
and although from the way it's been
described to me, the events in that book,
a lot of them are compiled.
So like this little thing happened on a
training event and this thing happened
on training event and this thing
happened on a training event,
but they'd all be compiled
into one big story. And yeah,
so it's kind of like a Hollywood,
it's a book.
It's a nonfiction ish. 10 year old
Ben Crenshaw. I didn't know that.
He was like, I'm going to bench
500 pounds. No problem. Yeah,
I wouldn't, I wouldn't be here without
the, that series of books, frankly.
I probably still have two eyes,
but no, nobody. That's a luxury
that we'll get to that in a little, in
a little bit. Um, so yeah, I mean that,
you know,
once you've,
once that and you know this and most
seals operate this way or at least they
have this same story of we had,
it was from a young age I had a mission.
Um, I knew what it was and
every decision I made from,
from then until the moment
I got into Bud's was, was,
was just to prepare for
that. Now when you, did you,
I know you lived overseas, what,
where'd you go to high school?
So most of high school and Columbia.
Okay. What did you play sports down there?
I played soccer. Okay. Yeah.
Cause you were in Colombia have kind
of like what they had to play soccer or
volleyball. I played volleyball.
And then you applied from college?
From Colombia, yeah. Okay. This is,
this is kind of an important question
because a lot of people ask me this
question all the time.
You were definitely want it to be a seal.
What made you make the decision between
going to college and you ended up going
to Tufts? Yeah. Ended up in Massachusetts.
So at some point you said to yourself,
okay,
I could enlist tomorrow and
go to bootcamp and you know,
be a seal within the year,
or I can go to college for four years
and then apply and I'll be in an officer
in a leadership position. I could ask
that question all the time. For me,
when I was 18 years old, the
answer was real easy. Like, oh,
I can be a seal of in a year, sign
me up. And, and that's what I did.
And for you,
you obviously took a different approach
and people ask me all the time,
which one is better?
And I think I tell them that there's
advantages and disadvantages to both of
them. But what made you decide you're
gonna go officer style from the get go?
Um, maybe along with my mission
of being a seal my whole life,
the a similar mission of I
wanted a college degree as well.
I wanted to knock that out.
And um, and then, you know,
I wasn't well informed enough to,
to really speak about the difference
between officer and enlisted back then,
like I am now. Um, but I
did want a leadership role.
It was important to me
based on what I'd read.
And based on the movies I'd seen
that I was in a leadership role.
Did you see navy seals?
Was that, that's nice.
That's Lafe baboons answer to why you
became a seal straight up. He's like,
Oh yeah,
Charlie Seals Charlie Sheen gets out
of, I'd be that, didn't just see it,
you know, we had it on all the time.
Greatest movie ever. Um, it, you know,
it was so a combination of wanting a
leadership role, um, maybe knowing too,
was I really ready at age 18? I
knew I wanted it, but I am also,
I also wanted to be prepared and it was
able to think ahead enough to know that
maybe I can't swim all that great just
yet. We might need some more practice.
Um, but uh, but it was mostly like, it was
mostly, I'm going to go to college first,
then my life path, that's what I'm
going to do. And so that's what I did.
And I ended up at Tufts University mostly
because of its international relations
program. I was that, that was my
focus. It was foreign affairs,
international relations,
politics and a,
and I did a minor in physics just because,
why not?
Cause that sounds like
fun. Yeah, it's awesome.
Speak Spanish obviously from,
from growing up in Columbia too.
Are you fluent in Spanish?
Pretty fluently.
It's kind of a little rusty but
we're weak. And you did ROTC at? Yes.
Was there any seals?
They're like a prior seals that were
instructors or anything like that? No, I,
well no, there, there was at Harvard.
So a lot of these guys doing master's
programs while we're doing ROTC,
they're not attached to the unit.
But I did have the opportunity to
work with some guys and um, you know,
just get that mentorship. You just, hey,
this is the kind of workouts you
might want to be doing. I mean,
just the basics cause you just
have no idea going into it.
Do you think kids over
prepare for buds now? Um,
I think it depends on the kid.
I often mentor guys who want to go through
and you know that sometimes they do
focus a little bit too much on,
especially things that are good at,
like I'm running 10 miles a day. It's
kind of like a five minute pace. I'm like,
stop running, never run again. You know,
you're good at that and move on
to the next thing. Uh, you know,
focus on your weaknesses. It, look,
guys just don't understand
the little little basics.
I don't know if they overtrain I haven't
worked with enough to really know,
but I talked to people and they send
me messages all the time and they're on
this two year training program to
get ready for buds and I'm like, hey,
train for two months and then go,
don't,
it's not that hard if you played a sport
in college or have you played a sport
in high school and you can run like
you'll get in good shape there and it's
going to be a challenge.
But waiting around,
especially when there's a war going on
that you don't really want to miss. Yeah,
that's a big deal to me.
You know,
and I told these guys this war's not
going to last forever. And you know,
I showed up at the team in 1991 just
missed the first call for it. And it's,
you know, we, I,
I didn't shoot my weapon at the
enemy for 13 years and that's a long,
dry hard 13 years. And so, yeah,
you don't wanna miss out on that snow.
You don't, one of my old team guy buddies,
it was like 1971 and,
and he loved,
he thought the Vietnam War was going to
end and he's down at the Marine Corps
Recruiter Tang. I want to
be a door gunner. Huey.
It's interesting that there's the,
you know,
you always hear about the
protesters and whatnot,
but there's kids that want to fight.
Oh yeah.
We do have,
there's a warrior class in America that
I think we should be proud of and it'd
be proud to be a part of because it's a,
they're good people with good values and
they want to do the right thing for the
country. So you show up the buds so
you get to be good done with college.
College is college,
right?
Is there anything particularly you want
to say about college? No. Okay. Well cool.
We want to hear about
college happened college.
And so you show up at buds
and any issues at buds.
Yeah. Um, you know, I started my,
I started with class two, six,
one about Tuesday afternoon
of my first hell week. My,
I stress fractured, developed into a
pretty noticeable fracture. And uh,
I got the old question, are you
hurt? Are you injured, Mr Crenshaw?
And you really want to be
injured because you better not
just be hurt because then you're
just quitting. And uh, I was,
I was injured pretty substantially.
I mean, you know, I mean,
we stress fractures are pretty
normal injury in buds. Okay. So you,
so when I'm sitting here talking about
people don't prep enough, you're like,
actually you should prep more.
Do you think you could have run more
preparing for bucks? I would have.
I ran plenty. I would've, uh,
I would've focused a little bit more
on strength and conditioning. You know,
something I just didn't know
how to do back then. Right.
Because what happens in buds as you,
I mean,
you're going to go to failure and w you're
going to go to failure no matter what
you're in. It's going to happen on the
hour, every hour, maybe every 10 minutes,
all the time. So the guys
who overprepare, they,
they can't understand why they're
failing so much. Right. And that,
that messes with their heads.
So maybe that's what you mean
by overpreparing cause that,
that's what I mean by like,
I think,
I think guys get too confident in their
abilities and they just don't understand
why they're hitting a wall all the time
where it's like guys like me are just
like, I just, I just, I expected to
suck, so it's really not a surprise. Um,
but we're just going to keep trying
no matter what and just never quit.
And quitting is never an option.
The other problem is if you over prepare,
it may be, it becomes an option.
This isn't the case for everybody,
but I see some of the best in shape
guys quit because it was just,
they were like, maybe it was an option
for them. Like maybe I'll make it,
maybe I won't. But if you, you should
never go into bud's thinking that way.
And um, that's why a lot of
guys who make it through,
I think have this story that, well, I
wanted to do it since I was 10 years old.
So it was just never an option
for me to ever quit. So yeah,
you do need prepare
enough to make sure your,
your muscles when they do fail aren't
putting all the strain on your joints and
your knees.
And that's what happened to me because
it just happened over time and over time
you're limping a certain
way and that just,
that causes a fracture eventually cause
there's too much pressure being put on
your bones. So, you know, or
I just had a week genetics,
which is like one story where
likely answer, I got rolled back,
I came back again with two, six, four.
And um, you know, you know, you know,
there's the two mile
run you do in hell week.
It's like Tuesday or so if how we can,
it's a time you went
through a long time ago.
Well it's like a Tuesday or something
and it's a time to run and if you,
and if you get in the top five,
you don't have to do it again and then
everybody else has to do it all over
again and you get to rest under a boat
and you know, eat sand or whatever.
They let you do much on
that sand over there. At,
uh,
my first hell week I was dead last.
I mean just we'll way be
like not even close. Right.
Cause I was limping the whole time
and my second hell week I was,
I was first placed by maybe five minutes,
you know,
and maybe cause I knew what the game was,
but everybody does actually because the
word gets around it, you know that it's,
but it was, it was, it was a message
maybe to myself of like we're gonna,
we're gonna not only do this but we're
going to crush it and I'm going to feel
good about it and I'm going to rest
under that boat and eat my sand
while everybody else is running
the, frankly, it was really cold.
So I kind of wish I'd been running
at the time, but whatever I want,
the closest store I have to that is we
got done with a four mile time, Brian.
And when we got done that people
that failed and I didn't fail,
but there was a bunch
of people that failed.
And the instructor who is a
really a perfect instructor,
meaning that his attitude and the way
he carried himself was epic for buds.
And he was the senior chief of the phase.
It was dive phase.
And the guys come across and he's
collecting the guys that fail,
which was probably at least half of
the class and then, you know, he says,
you know, because I'm fair, I'm gonna
go ahead and let you do this time.
Don't again get on the line, ready, go.
And everyone had to run another four
mile time to run. Right. Well not us,
but the people that,
the people that passed got to not be,
but the people that didn't pass,
which was half the class,
had to go and just run another form of
time to run right then to see if they
could then pass it.
Much easier to pass.
Eighth Mile.
You're definitely doing a lot better
after you've put out as hard as you
possibly good for a four mile run,
which I actually had to do every time
I failed to run and I failed one run in
bugs. I paced myself. I said, well,
you know what? I'll just pace myself.
I'm not going to put out as
hard as I as a kind of, I'll,
I'll save a little bit for
later and that didn't work.
I failed because I'm not a fast runner.
And so from then on it was just a sprint.
As hard as I could go for the
whole damn time, unlike you,
I didn't win any races in buds.
That's literally not.
So you get done with and you show up.
So now it's 2000 and what?
What year is it a,
this is 2007 2007 yeah.
Finishing bugs 2007 and I'm
moving in SQT Oh, that's right,
Leif Babin putting me through
[inaudible] nice. You know, I was,
I was, I was indoctrinated
early on bruiser stories.
Jack, Jack, and that's awesome.
And then from there you rolled
two team three, team three,
team three with collusion in 2008 and
then I'm back in Ramadi in 2010 with a
tribe platoon, you know, your little
troupe, you know, going back to life,
running that course.
It was interesting because what that
course used to be was almost like an
administrator course, hey,
here's how you write evils.
And they had a little tiny bit of dashing
of, of, of tactics in it, but it was,
here's how you read,
right evils,
here's how you write navy messages
and just that kind of stuff. Yeah.
And you know, we knew that these kids
needed to train because I, in Ramadi,
I had guys that were the
first platoon guys out,
ground force commanders and we wanted to
make sure these guys knew what to do on
the battlefield and it was awesome
that lake and went there and started
rehashing that program and the, and did a
great job. I think it was very valuable.
Yeah. Yeah. And yeah, so
then you got done with that,
then you showed up at team three and you
went right on deployment. Right. I mean,
the three was already on deployment,
so they had just deployed, you know,
and you know how that goes. Um,
the cycle of graduates.
So we met up with team three.
I was in Fallujah for a little while.
Uh,
it was done in Bosnia for few months and
actually stayed on deployment to meet
up with team five and, and, um, and,
and help them transition. You know,
as we were setting up another, uh,
uh, debt out there and Bosnia, um,
great,
great first deployment and learned a
lot and got to work a little bit and uh,
then came back to Iraq in 2010 and another
great deployment for me because I was
able to take over as platoon commander,
uh,
when my platoon OIC had to go
to relieve another platoon OIC.
So we were going through
the entire targeting cycle,
working with multiple Iraqi partners
throughout Ramadi and throughout all,
all of Al Anbar.
We got to operate throughout the entire
province even a little bit in Baghdad.
So,
uh,
just an amazing experience for young
Jio who wouldn't normally be put in that
position. And, uh, working with some of
the best people I've ever met. You know,
we've talked about before. Uh, I won't
name names on the, uh, on the podcast,
you know. Well, your OIC was, it
was a great guy that got moved.
That's why he got moved and obviously
they had confidence in you too,
to move you up in to the
platoon commander position,
which is an interesting thing.
I had a group of business people and they,
they, there was a guy that kept saying,
well, no one can take my place, you know,
and then he was surprised that
he wasn't getting promoted.
And you explain to people,
if you don't have a person below you
in the chain of command or two or three
people below you in the chain of
command that can take your job,
well then you're going to have to stay
in your job and you're not going to get
promoted. So that, that's, that's
proof that you're OIC. Like I said,
he's a great guy, actually. He's supposed
to come on the podcast at some point,
but he's a great guy and he had groomed
you and taught you everything he could
do and, and made you ready and
trusted you to say when the,
when the boss came to him and
said, Hey, I've got to fire a guy.
I'm going to move you over to Afghanistan.
Is Your,
is your AYC ready to take
over? And he could constantly
say yes, he is. And that's,
that's awesome. And that shows
that he was a great leader too,
to kind of prepare you
properly for that situation.
That's a good point. I mean, that is,
that is part of leadership and management.
It's making sure that below you and
above you is squared away. Yeah.
And I would do that when I was running
training, I would always kill, you know,
theoretically or what does it
virtually kill the commander's. Yeah.
All of us. The 10 sometimes I'd
kill all of you that I remember.
Yeah.
There'd be some,
some somebody carries happening
for extended distances.
Uh, yeah, I was a little bit,
I was a little bit crazy at that point
and, and you know, I was good training.
Yeah. Yeah. You know, it's, uh,
I was coming home from Ramadi and I
wanted to make sure you guys were ready to
ready for the worst
possible case, you know? Um,
so then you get, so you do that,
you finished out that deployment.
That was a solid deployment. You were,
you were running a bunch of stuff that,
that sounds like a good deal then
what'd you do when you came back?
So he came back, um, moved
over to support activity one.
And as you know,
they,
they run intelligence support
operations for the seal teams. Uh, it's,
it's a fairly normal transition to make
as an officer and for a lot of guys too.
Um, but what that ended up w would really
what that translated into his back on
deployment 2012 with my platoon again,
seal team three Charlie Platoon, uh,
in Kandahar province. So
on that deployment, uh,
this was one of our more
kinetic deployments. I mean,
it's, it's Afghanistan,
it's Kandahar's IED is everywhere.
I mean everywhere.
I mean to the point where, you
know, our, our TTPs are, are,
are sparse or our sop is our standard
operating procedures where, hey,
we're on patrol, were getting
shot at, don't even move.
Don't even go look for cover. Because
as soon as you move, you hit an IED.
I mean they're,
they're,
they're just there that prevalent
throughout the entire ground,
not just on pathways, not just in
doorways, in the most random of places.
These guys are just burying these
things at a one, at a win, you know?
And then it's,
then it's chaos out there.
And we know they're not that
great at shooting at us.
So we'd rather just take it.
So I'm going to take a moment just to
emphasize what you just said because it's
really important and not everyone
will understand it the way you,
the way you went over it quickly,
almost from a tactical mindset.
So I just want everyone
to understand what he's,
what he's saying is when at this point,
the ids were so bad that if you
started getting shot at by the enemy,
the obvious and common and practice that
everyone in the world instinctively and
by training has, is you immediately
hit the ground and seek cover.
And you get behind a log.
You get behind a piece of terrain,
you find somewhere to hide from
the bullets that are coming at you.
And what Dan's saying is
during this deployment,
the IED threat was so high that when
the enemy started shooting at them,
instead of finding cover
to hide from the bullets,
they would rather just stay put,
probably take a knee but not dive behind
something because of the likely there
was a likely chance that there was an IED
there. Yup. That's, that's crazy. It is.
It is. Um, you know, we've,
I've seen multiple guys get,
get blown up and, um,
usually our partners,
our Afghan partners who were patrolling
with us, I, because, you know,
maybe they don't, they're just not
as careful or maybe they're there.
The equipment they're using
to detect ICDs in the ground,
they weren't using it properly,
whatever the case may be.
Or maybe just cause it's bad luck and
they're just everywhere. Um, you know,
it's more, you had more Afghan
partners than Americans. Oh, by far.
We would sometimes go on operations with
about a hundred Afghans and maybe 12,
15 seals. Yeah. Because there were, were
doing entire clearance operations
through villages. You know, we're,
we're going house to house,
we're shaking hands.
It's a little bit of shaking hands. It's
a little bit of on security, you know,
either defending ourselves or
going on the offensive. It,
it depends on the situation. But,
um, you know, we round everybody up,
we talked to them and we have, we meet
with village elders. So it's, it's,
it's, it's a little bit
of your, your, your,
I guess your more typical unconventional
warfare tactics of we're trying to meet
and greet the population,
um, while also, you know,
being prepared for
battle and, uh, and, and,
but the hardest part of that was
certainly the IED threat. You know,
only single file lines.
Everything we ever learned in
training of different formations and
staggered actual on whatever it is,
it doesn't apply at all.
It all gets thrown out the window because
it's, it's only about single file.
What has been cleared, what hasn't
been cleared. And you could,
you could veer from that a little
bit depending on what area you're in,
in Kandahar and went more mountainous
areas, less ids. But even then,
I've got a story, you
know, these guys, uh,
some of our guys take a take a point to
take out on the high ground and a little
hilltop. I mean, just in the middle
of nowhere. I mean, middle of, no,
I can't emphasize this enough. It
is the middle of nowhere, right?
And they sit down in this pop goes off,
it was a blasting cap that went low order,
which means it didn't blow up the main
charge, like a 15, 20 pound charge.
It would have killed all three of them
right then and there. And, uh, I mean,
I want to say that again,
middle of nowhere.
There was no reason for there to be an
IED right there. But there was this one,
this was out in the mountains and this
wasn't even in the, the pen, you know,
the southern Kandahar district,
which was,
which is truly just a minefield
everywhere, you know, so, you know, the,
I can't emphasize how bad the threat is
there. And even, even, even taking that,
even taking a small high ground
position behind a rock, like, you know,
this is what we, the kind of
things we ran into. And, um,
so that was that deployment. It was a
lot of fun. And, uh, um, but it was,
it was a hard one for us. Uh, you know,
on month six,
that's six months in
is June 15th, 2012. Um,
I was hit by an IED blast by one of these.
Again, they're everywhere. And it was,
it was the one day we spent in Helmand
province. So we went to Helmand on a,
on a last minute mission,
uh,
to support some marine special
operations forces out there. And,
uh, as, as the early, I know we, oh,
we always fly in about the middle of the
night and we do that so that the enemy
can't arm the ids. The Ids are
everywhere, but they're not always armed.
And if they,
if they keep them arm,
they run out of batteries and they
don't work anymore. So they, so there's,
there's a little bit of tactical
consideration there. But, uh,
you know, in the early morning hours come
and the, and the daylight starts to hit,
we start to move around and we start to
clear out this one compound and hadn't
been totally clear jet.
And one of my Afghan interpreters
was responding to a call,
runs in front of me and completely
gets dismembered by about 15 pounds of
explosives underneath him. And, uh,
all I know is I got hit with something
and it feels like you're getting hit by a
truck while a bunch of guys in the
truck or shooting you with a shotgun.
That's sort of what it feels
like. And um, you know, immediate,
my immediate reaction
was feel my legs right.
So I feel my legs and everything
is still there. Um, you know,
I know something is wrong
distance from the Iud, a couple
of feet. I mean, it's so,
I mean, cause I would,
aliyah a few feet were,
you and me are probably is about it.
We're just across the table
and uh, you know, lots of pain,
pain everywhere, but not in my eyes. So
that was completely blinded. But, uh,
you know, uh, totally under the assumption
that I just had dirt in my eyes. And, uh,
I remained under this assumption that
there was really nothing wrong with my
eyes for frankly, for weeks to come.
And we'll talk about that. But,
you know, I, I was, I didn't lose
consciousness. I knew what was happening.
I could hear the moans.
Everybody thinks that when somebody gets
their legs blown off, they're screaming.
Like in the movies. It's just never
the case. It's a very different,
like visceral sound of pain. Um, and it's,
and I've heard it many times now because
this happened to us a couple of times.
And, um, so I heard that. I knew,
I knew that Rockman had been hit
because I could hear him. And, um,
you know,
one of our,
one of my teammates tells a story where
he got hit with the foot in a building
next store. I mean, and it was,
and that's how they knew something
had gone terribly wrong. And, uh,
you know, the medics come to me,
there's nothing they can do for me.
They sorta just wrap up my eyes. They
know something's wrong. I really don't.
Frankly,
I was just,
I keep assuming there's just dirt in my
eyes and that it'll be fine. And, uh,
eventually we get taken out of there
and I was able to get up and walk to the
Hilo because you don't let somebody carry
you when they've got a fire fight to
finish and we get on and uh,
as soon as the medics on
the helicopter see me, they,
they put me out right away
and I don't wake up for days.
So when I do wake up, I'm in
Germany. They told me my ride,
I had been removed and I'd probably
never see it again out of my left eye.
But there's a chance and again, kind of
self deception kicks in and I'm like,
so you're saying there's a chance that
we'll be fine, just get the surgery done,
get me out of plane to,
to back to Maryland,
to the Walter Reed Hospital where these
surgeons are and well, let's do this.
And they're like, it's going to be a
day or two. I argue. We argue, you know,
that's how it goes for the next
couple days. I can't really move.
I can't get up to use the bathroom. My
body is completely swollen and, and, and,
and shredded really.
I mean there's no real permanent injuries
to the rest of my body, but it's,
it's in such a state that like I just,
just shockwave from
the blast,
I think shock and I was,
I had a ton of shrapnel just throughout,
I think I was swollen,
um,
might've been muscle atrophy from being
in a medically induced coma for so long
because I'd been there,
been that way for five or six days,
but really couldn't move. Um, and,
and just wrapped up really
tight cause I mean there's,
you can see the scarring a
little bit. Um, I was just,
it was kind of been through a meat
grinder a little bit. And uh, I was also,
I was hallucinating wildly so I,
everything I saw was Afghanistan.
I was lucid,
I understood what was around me,
but all I could see was an Afghan guy
sitting next to me or an Afghan village.
It was, it's, it was,
it's almost like phantom pain but with
your eyes and there's a medical term for
it that I can't remember.
Um,
but it was just an odd and
terrifying experience because it was,
I knew it wasn't real, but it's
just everything I saw. And, um,
eventually got back to Maryland,
um,
on a one on one of our medical
flights. And, you know,
my wife was there waiting
for me and you know,
we began to have that conversation
about, okay, what's the next surgery?
Cause I had to remove the cataract
and then that was, that was the issue.
There was a lot of shrapnel in my left
eye. The eye that was still there.
And you know, the, the, the
issue was, could we came,
we were safely removed the cataract
and will he ever see again?
And if you have to be,
we do do that.
What are his chances really of
having decent vision and um,
you know, we, we prayed and we,
I and I look back on it and again that,
you know, we call it self deception,
but it was really the
strength to stay sane and,
and believe that it was actually
going to see again. And you know,
I truly believe that was God. Strength
is working through Migos, allowing me to,
to believe in something impossible,
um,
because otherwise I would have gone
nuts because people sometimes ask me,
what's it like not knowing if you're ever
gonna see again. And I always answer, I,
I don't know. I don't know what
that's like because it was never,
that was never my mental state. My
mental state was always, it'll happen.
It's just a matter of time. And then
I can finally get back to my platoon.
You know, the, the, the, the issue for me,
it was like, when are we going to do this?
You guys told me six weeks.
All right, let's schedule
it. Inhale. It was insanity.
Obviously when a, I hear
this story, I think Ryan Job,
who was with me in Ramadi and he,
and he got shot in the face and you know,
it was a similar situation
where, you know, clearly his,
his eye,
one eye was gone,
but his other eye appeared to be intact.
And he could actually
see after he got wounded,
then he got put into a, uh, you know,
he could see what was happening and,
and walked into the CAS
evac vehicle. Uh, but,
you know, they put them into
a medically induced coma.
And when he woke up he couldn't see and
then it was the same type of thing that
they were, you, they were
telling him which is look,
well there was some nerve damage,
we're not sure.
And his attitude was very similar of
like, well, it'll be okay and you know,
it'll come back. Um, but you know,
what didn't take very long
before the doctors were like, no,
um, it's, it's, it's not coming back.
And, and I forget the timeline, you know,
I forget the timeline cause
it's, it's kind of a kind of, uh,
a blurred together. Um, but yeah,
for him it was, he had a
great attitude, but, um,
you know, at the end it
didn't happen. And you know,
and that's a guy that was still like a,
he also still wanted to come back and
get back with his platoon and was telling
me, you know, don't worry, I can smell
the enemy and I'll know where to shoot.
Let me back, sir. So, yeah, uh, the,
the fact that you were able to
recover is awesome. Awesome.
And you know, it's, uh, it, it shows,
it should show people that, you know,
even though you had a great attitude,
the threat of have never been able to
see again was very, very real, very,
very real.
Oh yeah. And, and it truly was amazing.
We had miracles occur in the operating
room multiple occasions and, uh,
doctors are just amazed that not only
could I see again, but see, well again,
um, it, it was because they're at,
in their minds they're like, well,
if we do the surgery and his
retina, doesn't it detach?
Like, we think it might, um,
he'll still have, you know,
crappy vision, you know,
cause this is corny as all destroyed. I
mean, everything's a mess in this eye and,
uh, you know, we'll get them some decent
glasses so we can kind of live his life,
but he's, he's pretty much permanently
disabled and I'm, I just didn't listen.
I don't even remember these conversations.
It's like I like I blocked him
out and, um, and it's just,
cause the first surgery was we've
got to remove the cataract. Okay.
That went well. All right. We removed
the cataract. Great. You know,
and the next step is to put a
lens implant in your eye. Like,
like anybody normally would
only have cataract surgery.
That's just the normal thing to do.
Um,
we ended up never doing that because
it's kind of like replacing a window pane
on a normal line,
but if the frame of the window is
completely destroyed and you have to,
so the window pane to curtains and
that's never a good policy. So, uh,
they, they eventually refused to do that
on me even though I was demanding it
constantly. Um, but because
I wanted to see again,
I wanted to get back and I didn't
want to have a big thick glasses,
which is what I have to wear now or,
or this specialized contact.
But then another problem occurred,
which is a hole in my retina that was
expanding and event. And this is again,
it's kind of a normal, you
know, I, if if you're over 50,
this might be a normal thing that occurs
and then you have a pretty routine
surgery to get rid of it and to stop it.
But for me it was incredibly fragile. Um,
but we had to do it.
So I went blind again for six weeks
recovering from the surgery. So, you know,
I was, I was, I was truly living in
darkness for a long, um, you know,
and not always thank God I wasn't
hallucinating the entire time.
That stopped after about
week one. Um, you know, just,
or just after my major surgery,
my first major surgery. But, um,
I went blind again and another miracle
happened because they truly thought I
wasn't going to make it through that
surgery either. So after when they,
when you were blind to again for six
weeks going into that, did they tell you,
okay,
you're going to be buying for a period
of time and it's going to take time to
you eat just yet, because of
the recovery process. You,
they put a gas bubble in your eyes so
that it puts pressure on the back of your
retina and you would have to be face down
for six weeks. It's just the weirdest,
what the hell did you do for six weeks?
I down my bed,
I get one of those massage chairs
where you put your face down.
And I had audio books going all day
long. I mean, it was great. Yeah.
And by great, I mean, not great at
all. By great you mean awesome. Yeah.
You know, uh, yeah, Starbucks and uh, you,
you had to stay face down
all the time. Are you? Um,
and that six weeks goes by and then they
eventually remove the gas bubble and
dissipates. Yeah. So there's eventually a
point where you're like, okay, it's gone.
Now I can, I'm allowed. I'm allowed
to look straight again. And then,
and then it's just, you know, refitting
your eye with the right eyewear, you know,
like glasses and contacts so I can
actually get back to her normal life.
And in frankly, that took
years. Uh, it, you know,
it's w I eventually, I'll
just, I'll skip to the end,
about two and a half years,
then I finally got,
got referred by the Navy to an
outside clinic that does these,
these amazing contacts.
Um,
there's only one company in the world
that does it and I can see 2020 with it,
you know, not up close. You know,
my vision is complicated
because I have a cataract, but,
but I actually see 2020 vision at
distance, which is, let me just,
not even close to what they thought was
possible. So I'm in. But despite all that,
I mean,
before that two and a half year mark,
I still had decent enough
contacts to survive. I mean,
they just weren't comfortable. They kind
of drove me crazy. And, um, you know,
all I cared about was
getting back to the team.
I was almost going back
to team three. The, uh,
command wouldn't let that happen in
the end just because I couldn't get the
medical waiver to do it.
So I stayed at what was now it's called
special reconnaissance team one. Again,
we do Intel support for the seal teams
and uh, did a troop commander there.
So in charge of about 50 personnel,
mix of seals,
intelligence specialists, um, all sorts
of really great people that you know,
as you know,
support the teams and intelligence
matters and deployed to Bahrain,
uh, worked with, uh,
joint special operations task force
out there working in all throughout the
Persian Gulf, uh, working
on classified programs.
They're working in Lebanon as well.
And uh, coming back from that,
I'm told I had to eventually
get out. I mean, I,
I had to start the medical
retirement process, but before,
before I did, I, I truly, I wanted
to serve again. I mean, it was,
it was extremely important to me. So this
deployment to by rain was about 2014.
By the time I was really told I had
to medically retire was around 2016.
But you know,
this process takes up to a year.
And I asked that I be able to serve
again in some capacity. Let my, let my,
the specialties that I had that I had
acquired over the years at SRT one,
um,
be put to use in the Pacific.
So they deployment to Korea for my last
deployment in the end of 2016 and as
soon as I got home from that, I was,
I was medically retired and, uh,
had to find my next mission.
You know,
like you talked about the earlier
on in the podcast. I mean, it's,
it life truly is about
mission and, um, you know,
I'm getting into politics now running
for Congress and in Houston, Texas, uh,
for the second district.
And I talked about this a lot and from a,
from a political philosophy standpoint,
if you don't give people a mission or
you don't encourage people to find their
purpose and their dignity, you,
you have a failing society. Uh,
it's so important and you're
not, you know, even even
think tanks, talk about this,
like American Enterprise Institute,
like our policies need to promote a sense
of mission for people and help people
understand that they
have value in this world.
They're here on this earth for a reason.
And if you're not constantly seeking out
what that value is that you contribute
to society, you're not doing your job and
we need to help you do your job if, if,
if, if need be, but you, but
you do have value and you,
and you must find that purpose
in life. Um, and guys like us,
I think can't survive without
that constant mission. And uh,
well we see it all the time with,
with all vets. And when they,
and I talk about this all the time,
the vets that get out,
that have a note on newt,
another mission,
they focused on that mission
and they go kick ass.
The vets that get out and don't
know what they're going to do,
that flounder around without a direction.
Those are the guys that end up in trouble
because they don't have a mission.
So they go and drink a beer,
then they have another beer and then the,
they could get prescribed
pain medicine for their back,
which hurts which socks and,
and they go down this bad road.
And I believe a lot of it is because, you
know, they just need that next mission.
But you got done with,
so 2016 you didn't roll right
into politics. You rolled to you,
you went back to college.
Did that become,
doesn't 16 did that become you?
You looked at what you're going
to do next and you said, okay,
well how else can I serve?
How well it's going to move forward?
What's my next mission going to be?
And you decided you're going to
go back to school, back to school
for, I knew it was going
to stay in public service.
So I knew my next mission was
going to still be government.
I wasn't exactly sure what
I knew I wanted to do.
I wanted to be able to implement
policy and strategy and,
and take that tactical experience.
Um, cause I had to have, you know,
cause I that built an understanding of
what policy in d c looks like on the
ground.
Um,
and actually because the reason I was
hurt that day in 2012 was because of an
Obama administration's
policy of always wanting boots on the
ground battle of damage assessments for
any, any close air support. So
because earlier in that day,
marines that called in close air support
on a compound they were taking fire
from,
for some reason they wanted guys to walk
across minefields and go take pictures
of it. Right? That's not good policy.
Now it's not a victim hood story.
Don't get me wrong. I mean there was
a battle going on. We want it to go,
I don't care really what the reason is,
but from a policy perspective, that's,
that's concerning that,
that,
that kind of pressure has being
put on our two star and our,
and that's what drove that mission. That
doesn't make a whole lot of sense. Um,
so it's great to see somebody like
General Madison right now who says the
opposite. I will not waste my troops
time with these kinds of things.
And he's on record. Um, you know,
after we dropped the mother
of all bombs while back,
he's on record saying I will not waste
my troops time going to count the dead
bodies out there. That's just
good policy. So, you know,
a wanted to take that
experience to Washington, um,
the natural and the national next
step was get the right education.
So the Harvard Kennedy School
of Government is where I went,
got a master's degree in public
administration focusing more on national
security issues, economic
issues, um, and, and,
and a little bit of political us politics.
How long was that school?
I just did a year when your program
and, um, you know, it's kind of the, uh,
accelerated executive style program
that you can apply to if you're,
if you're older and you actually
have some, some life experience,
the intensity level of that, uh,
it's tense as you make it. I took,
I took about four extra credits
more than I needed to. Uh,
so I was busy cause I, you know, it's,
it's not like going to college
where you're just getting
through it. I think, uh,
I would highly recommend anybody,
you know,
you do a master's degree later on in life,
you're really going to get
the most you can out of it.
You cause you care about learning.
You're there for a reason
because you have purpose and,
and you know why you're there. So I got
a lot out of it honestly. And it was,
it was quite, it was really
an amazing year. I mean,
you hear from the greatest
people had, you know, bushes,
deputy national security advisor
teaching us. Um, I had, uh,
you know, the, the premier experts
on counterproliferation policy, uh,
teaching us in classic Reagan's
Chief Economic Advisor is
my economics professor.
I mean, you just can't, you know, the,
these people don't speak in terms of like,
this is what we think happens in the
White House there. No, they're like,
when I was in the White House,
this is how it got done. I mean,
that's the kind of the, the level
of instruction that you're getting.
So it was really happy to, to get
that education. And it, it, it, it's,
it truly applies to, as in the hood. My
current role is as running for office.
Um,
I'm glad it was there,
but what I hadn't necessarily thought
about running for office even after I
graduated, uh, I was looking at more
policy jobs, you know, cause I didn't,
I don't have the political connections.
I don't have the background and money
and the donor networks to really to,
to jump on a campaign,
uh,
right away we've thought about it in the
longterm sense, uh, for sure. But, uh,
but not in the short term. And a,
I was working with Pete sessions,
Congressman Pete sessions and
Capitol Hill for a little while,
getting legislative experience
there and I'm working,
doing some consulting and uh,
eventually came to a head where I was
about to take a job that they're doing
counter weapons of mass destruction
policy for Department of Defense or go run
for office because my congressman,
Ted Poe had just announced
retirement and we prayed about it.
We thought about it. We, uh, had
the right backing from, you know,
some well connected people that I think
God just put in front of us at the right
time. And my wife and I went for it.
You know, she was, uh, she was all in,
who was all in and, uh, and that
was it. I mean, I've already,
I'd already come back to Texas,
but at this point to help with
hurricane Harvey reconstruction was out.
Volunteering were my old
hometown of Katie. Um, my
parents didn't flood. They were,
they were living there.
They've been living in spring,
which is just north of Katie for the
past 13, 14 years. But, you know,
neighbors needed help. They
were still need help. Um, it's,
it's still pretty devastated in Houston.
And you know,
I think the decision became easy that
we knew this was the right choice.
Like this was the right mission. If I
cared about nuclear proliferation policy,
what better place to affect
it for them from Congress.
If you care about helping flood victims,
no better place than elected office. Um,
if you care about border security,
which Texans do no better place
than public office. You know,
if we care about protecting Americans
and protecting the sanctity of the seal
teams and, and pushing the right policies
from the defense level, then you know,
elected politics is
where I can do it from.
And so the decision was easy was it was,
it was the right choice for us.
We knew we were doing it
for the right reasons.
We know we are still doing it for the
right reasons and we're not going to quit.
So with all those things
that you said that are,
are real positive about
having a political career,
yeah.
You must have also been looking at the,
the nightmare gut check,
just mudslinging that you're going to
have to go or that's going to be thrown at
you and all that and,
and your family getting a microscope
on him and watched all the time and no
privacy and all that. How did you
weigh those things out and that,
did you think about those things as well?
Absolutely. Uh, it's,
it's by far the most concerning
thing about politics. I
mean, if anything drives,
drives you out, it's, it's
that, you know, and frankly,
the experience hasn't been too bad yet.
I mean, I get attacked for silly things,
uh, here and there. I've got a, you
know, one of, one of my opponents,
I what I would call one of his
cronies there. There's these,
there's these corrupt,
um,
they called them the slates in Harris
County, which is Harris County is Houston.
Um,
and these three slates are essentially
three political mailers that go out and
they, they make, they target
senior citizens especially,
and they make it sound like there's these,
these um,
these conservative review
type of magazines. You know,
these something with authority behind it.
But really they're not really,
they're pay to play and it's just one
author and they pick who they like based
on what kind of money they were able to
get out of the deal. And then the trash,
everybody else. So, you know, they
put mine, they put my bio on there.
It doesn't say anything
about who I actually am.
It just says I'm homeless and don't
have a job and would like to be gone.
I mean it's, it's absurd, right?
And most people read it and they think
this is this, this can't be serious.
So it actually,
it got me a lot of votes because people
would look me up after that. It's like,
oh well this is, this is who this guy is.
Maybe I will vote for him after all. Um,
but, but unfortunately that's politics and
that's, that's the world we live in. Um,
even though the,
you know,
the Harris County Republican Party has
publicly denounce these so-called slates,
um, cause they send out these voter guides
and you know, they just announced them.
But people don't always know.
People aren't, you know,
sometimes a lot of folks still rely on
those so that you're battling this kind
of corruption. You're battling this
establishment. I mean, you know,
we always talk about the establishment
and politics and I never really knew what
that meant.
I think until I stopped behind the curtain
and now I truly understand and it's
this class of politically connected
people in the donor class that really just
stick together and it has nothing to do
with policy or doing the right thing for
the American people.
It's just how much money do you have?
That's all that matters. And it's
not, it's not all that matters. Um,
we made it into the runoff after last
week's election, which is March six.
I was nine candidates in my primary and
on and on election day I came out far
and away first place.
Um,
we beat out overall in the election.
I was second place, but we beat out.
So just to again,
explain that a little bit for people
that aren't paying attention to the
election, you were in the, in the fight,
you're going against nine other
candidates going into the election.
Obviously there's some people that vote
early through mail voting and they just
vote early and you were behind there.
But then as your campaign picked up and
people started to actually see who you
are, when people came to vote on
election day, you, you won election day,
but you didn't win all the votes combined
because the people that had voted
early and got it correct.
And it shows the trajectory and the
momentum of what you're doing. Right.
We've got some great momentum that
we're excited about and even put in,
he would paint a broader picture.
You know,
we started this late November and
the election was march six. That's,
that's a very little time for anybody
to get a campaign together. So,
and we're going up against, um, you know,
one of my opponents had s probably
all ended up spending the,
when the numbers come in
between six and $7 million,
which is a record for self funding
for a campaign like this. Um,
another opponent in a similar,
similar or very high spending,
very much self funded.
And it was already state representative,
so had had some kind of campaign machine
in place. You're trying to catch up,
you're trying to build a campaign team
and an an a message within almost no time
at all and no money whatsoever.
That's, that's not an easy task.
And it only a couple of months.
Usually you start like a year out if
you're going to run for Congress. Um, but,
but this,
that just wasn't the case here because a
typo announced retirement and about mid
November. So we had a lot to overcome.
Um, we built that momentum quickly.
We worked hard, worked
hard, got the message outs,
met as many people as we could. And
you know, in, uh, worked, uh, we, we,
we've snuck by, uh, was snuck out of that
third place spot because as you said,
so we were behind during early voting
and mail and voting because that,
that stuff happens so early.
There was just no way for my momentum to
catch up in time. But by election day,
we were far and away first place and,
uh, were able to sneak into the runoff.
So now we're in the runoff
and that's a May 22nd.
So we've got another two months to,
uh,
to really prepare and get our
message out there. And I think we're,
we're excited about it and I
think it's going to go well.
So you talked about this a little
bit. You talked about money, right?
Money and as disturbing as it is,
what's driving so much of who wins these
elections is who has the most money
because that's how you get
the advertising. That's
how you get the mailers.
That's how you get the word out there.
I mean,
if you don't have the money to pay for
advertising than no one knows you the
yard and you don't get any votes.
So as disturbing as that is you
without money, you, you, you,
you have a real hard time.
I mean,
you've done an amazing job with
the limited amount. How, I mean,
how much money did you go into
that last election? Spending
ended up spending total about $200,000.
So we were outspent in a 30 over,
over 30 to one easily.
I would say.
You could say more if you count
what everybody else, you know,
first and second place also spent
against me. I mean, you know,
it's something to be proud of,
but uh,
so I,
I think if we can raise $200,000 and you
went up against somebody that spent $6
million sprite and yeah,
like I said,
unfortunately money drives so much of
these elections and that's why you end up
with those people that,
I mean,
I know you can't technically or possibly,
but you're not supposed to be able
to buy an election. Right, right.
But I mean, the, the,
the person that you talked about that
spent 6 million without that money,
I mean we're where wood is a female.
Right?
Where would she have been without
spending that money? I mean,
I'm assuming she wouldn't
have been anywhere. No.
So she was able to by herself
at least third place. Right.
And maybe if she had another more money,
she would've been able to buy
herself first place. That's
a scary thought. It is.
I mean, it, you know, I, I, I
don't like the way campaign finance works.
I don't think he should be able to self
fund that much for a race. And you know,
I understand that there's some good
arguments to make that you can sell fund
over what the individual limit is.
But, but to that extent, I mean it's,
you know, it truly creates a, a donor
class of politicians and like that's just,
I don't think that's what we want as
American people and it's, it's up.
But it's up to voters
in the end to decide.
It's up to voters to see through that.
And you know,
I always encourage go out and do
your research. You know, just,
just do enough to go on the websites of
each candidate and get a feel for who
they are, watched them, watch
their videos, see how they speak,
see how they would represent you,
see how they would articulate your values.
You know,
we put up youtube videos all the time.
You can always wash me and
interviews. Um, you know, we're,
we're coming to or listen to podcasts,
listen to Jockos podcasts and uh,
you know,
cause cause you want people to get to
know you and you need to be out there with
folks. You need to be meeting people
everywhere you go. And that's how we won.
You know, that's how we built
that connection with the voter.
That's how we built momentum.
Just getting out and meeting people and
inspiring them to connecting with them.
That's, that's, that's still works.
And we proved that that's one of the
things that you did while your opponents,
we're spending a bunch of money
you put on your running shoes yeah.
And ran through your entire district.
Right.
I did lift a lot of the way to cause uh,
we talked about overpreparing well
sometimes you can under prepare and a,
when you're running a campaign there's
not a lot of time to get your running in.
And so I started at a hundred mile
run and um, it was going well.
And so I want to back up a little
bit. We, we planned this awhile out.
It was going to be five days
run across the whole district.
Really show that dedication. I want
to, I want to get on the ground.
I want to show the dedication to every
inch of this district and I'm with,
with whatever publicity we get out of it,
we're going to use it for a good cause
and we, we set up a go fund me account.
It's still active if you
want to donate to it,
let's go fund me.com/rebuild Houston
with Dan Crenshaw and that money goes to
three particular volunteer groups that
I was able to identify and vet that are
still out there everyday
rebuilding people's homes. Is that,
I mean that is still going on.
I always try to let everybody
know if you're a contractor,
if you've got any expertise,
please come volunteer in Houston.
We are backed up into, you know, it is,
it is tough to find a
contractor these days.
Even if people have the
money to pay for it,
they still can't get any availability.
The demand is so high that the prices
have gone way through the roof.
We need more people. They're nationwide.
So, you know, police come to Houston,
there's work for you and
there's good work. Um,
and there's a lot left to
do when people need it.
So in these volunteer groups are
out doing it, you know, for five,
$7,000 between five and $7,000,
they can rebuild a whole home
because all their labors free, right.
It's volunteers and they may do a great
job and they're working in a lot of
these neighborhoods where we're
individuals just can't do it themselves.
And it was,
it was,
it was just great to see that a lot of
church affiliated groups always out there
helping and um,
you know,
it makes you proud to be a tax and
it makes you proud to be an American.
So we finished that run,
you know,
by by day three I was certainly
limping through most of it. Um,
it changed out my shoes day five or
we're running pretty well again, but um,
it was tough, but it was, it was fun.
It was great. It was a great experience.
You see people honking at you
maybe because you're in their way.
Maybe because maybe because they're
supporting you. I don't know, but, uh,
I mean it was just,
it was,
it was pretty credible experienced to
see the supporters out there to see just,
you know, it was, it was great.
Um, we went and that was,
that was one early voting started. It was
a, we voted on day one of that run. And,
uh, and, and, and, and, you know,
two weeks later on election day,
we wrapped it up and it was,
it was a good night. It was a,
we're on pins and needles.
It wasn't until 2:00 AM that we knew
that we'd actually come that come into
second place by 155 boats.
Oh,
so you think anybody says
their vote doesn't count,
doesn't matter. That's wrong.
It, it truly matters. I mean,
every single vote mattered.
I can't thank every volunteer enough.
Can't think every supporter enough.
Cause a lot of people went out and
they maybe got 10 votes here and there,
maybe a hundred votes here and there.
You know,
individuals were able to do that and put
us over the top because they believed
in the message they believed in our
candidacy. And it was just, you know,
it's humbling. It's, it's almost,
you feel a weight of responsibility when
people put their trust in you like that
as you should feel it because you don't
want to disappoint them and they know
you.
You can't let your supporters down.
And I truly feel that way about every
vote. So what's so what's next right now?
Well, it's the runoff, the runoff.
It's just me and Kevin Roberts
and I'm just, you know,
it's May 22nd early voting starts
again a couple of weeks before that.
And it's a lot of the same, you
know, we, we, we stick to the basics.
We professionalize our organization.
Uh, we asked for more money.
Please donate a Crenshaw for converse.com
and at noon. And we, and we, we,
that's actually real
though. Like you, you Kinda,
you Kinda joke about it
and I know you're like,
like most good human beings,
you feel uncomfortable saying,
hey, give me some money.
But the reality is for you to take
this to the next level that you need,
you need money. And, and so when
you say that kind of jokingly,
the reality is if you
don't get that money,
it's going to be really hard to
swing it upset. Right. And so,
so that's what's the,
what's the website?
It's Crenshaw for congress.com c r e n
s h a w for congress.com you can donate
there. You can check out the
canyon to see there. You know,
see our interviews here, youtube videos
or commercials, my bio, everything.
It's all in one spot.
Follow us on Facebook.
We've got a pretty exciting
social media presence.
That's how we get a lot of our word out
because you know it's cheap and it hits
the right people. So Crenshaw for
congress.com and you know that money,
we spend it wisely. It doesn't
go to anything silly. It's,
you know, we need it to,
to send mail to, to, to voters.
You know, to get our message out.
We needed to put out radio ads,
we needed to buy tee shirts for volunteers
and to buy yard signs so that people
can put them in their yards and
create that upwelling of support, uh,
where everybody's got to Dan Crenshaw
sign that. That's, that's how we
do it. And, um, it's, it's, but
it's, we work our butts off,
I promise you that we work for, we work
for every vote out there and I'm, I,
I truly believe that's how it should be.
Um, and that's how it'd be in Congress.
Yeah. That's awesome. And I
know you're on a kind of a,
a time schedule today and I know you've
got some other things that you want to
do here while you're out here in sunny,
Sunny San Diego,
which isn't too sunny today,
but I think we just hit everything of
how people can best support your cause.
And obviously I'm in Crenshaw
for Congress on Twitter.
You're Dan Crenshaw, Texas, TX, correct.
So at Dan [inaudible], Crenshaw, TX,
and then on Facebook it's pretty easy
to find you is just Dan Crenshaw,
Crenshaw for Congress at Crenshaw
for Congress. It's pretty easy. Yeah,
I just searched Dan crunch on
you. Pop right up. So that's a,
that's it. Well, you know, obviously I
just want to say before you take off,
thanks for your service.
Thanks for thanks for your sacrifice,
for this great country.
Thank for what you've done for what you're
doing and thank you for what you are
going to do and appreciate everything.
I appreciate that Jocko, you
know, the search services
and over, um, you know, we,
we find our purpose, we find
our new mission and this is
it for me. You know, it's,
it's helping Texans,
it's given.
Texans are representative I
think they can be proud of.
We are so often just disgruntled and
ashamed of our politicians and we don't
really think they're working on our
behalf because we don't always let people
who truly put service before self and,
and you know,
part of this campaign is it's convincing
those that we do have a future and we
do have a future of leaders that will
attract people to conservative values and
um, and, and keep those
values alive and, and,
and again give us a leader that
we can be proud of. Awesome.
Well I think they'll definitely find
that with you. Thanks for coming on.
And it's an honor to be
here until you come back on.
Once you get the w,
once you get the wind come back on and
you can explain to us where you're going
from there. Absolutely.
Tell you how we did it.
Get Out and vote May 22nd
everybody. Thanks Dan. Thanks
for coming on. Thank you.
So Dan has left the studio,
but he's also left some very good ways
to support him and what he's doing.
And
Echo Charles.
Speaking of support.
Yeah.
Maybe you could tell the troops how
they can support this cause sure.
If they want, if the
course, if they want and,
and while they're supporting this
cost also support the to themselves,
which is important. Tiffts if they
want, you know, did you hear what I just
said? Yeah. Very important.
I said important. Yeah.
You said it correct. Yeah.
Two t's in that one for sure. Normally
there's no t's in it for me. Yeah. Yeah.
Important.
Kind of like the British accent.
Sometimes they don't say the [inaudible]
and sometimes the same, really solid,
you know,
like they say snap back to reality e they
don't say the reality or reality and I
see it nonetheless. Back due support.
Yeah. If you want to support,
support your joints.
Okay.
This is how you support your joints. If
you didn't already. Jock was supplements,
good supplements, Krill
oil, Super Krill, Jocko,
Super Krill oil and joint warfare
supplements for your joints.
Maintain them.
Also discipline
preworkout pre mission
cognitive enhancer plus physical
enhancer force multiplier.
Wholesome Force multiplier. Yeah.
There's layers. Yeah. Actually, yeah. It's
like a blend. It's a good blend. Yeah,
I am running low on the Krill oil.
I did not take my own advice for the
the restrictions subscription. Yeah.
So I had to manually get some more,
but hey man, that's life sometimes. Uh,
if you want to get on
the subscription thing
re up every, what is it month, right?
Cause it's a month supply. Yeah. Yeah.
However much you take and
that's the smart way to do it.
Totally is joint warfare to did you
mentioned drone warfare? Yeah, fully.
It's the one, I think the Combo
is the best way to go. For sure.
Recommend the Combo. Nonetheless,
you get them@originmain.com.
Good way to support and support yourself.
That's a big one.
also@originmain.com they're Giza and
rash guards for you. You Jitsu journey.
If you have chosen or will choose
to go on that Jujitsu journey,
there's no reason why not.
You should go on the Jujitsu and if
you're going to ask, what if I'm small,
big, large, overweight or
your older, younger, young.
The answer is start Jujitsu. Yeah. How'd
you get in shape for Jujitsu? Jujitsu.
Yeah. That's what you do. Yeah. You
know, Tim, Tim always says like, Oh,
you know how t he's been out
of the Jujitsu for a long
item forward. Yeah. Yeah.
And he'll be like, Whoa, I gotta
get back in shape to go. No,
you're looking at the wrong layman.
Oh yeah. You go back to Jujitsu,
the Gds to get you in shape. You'll
be, you'll be fine going to me, shit,
you can suffer a little bit, but might
even suffered a lot and probably a lot.
It's hard to gotta be hard mentally for
a guy like Timbo because he's a purple
belt. Yeah. And so he's going to come
and get beat by some white belts. I mean,
not wipe outs by some blue belts.
Yeah.
Cause you know some blue
belts and they bring it. Yeah.
And the key and they
can keep bringing it up.
They been in there because it got the
Kadesh. Yeah. Yes. Tim would be like,
come back in then. And it adds that
level anxiety because you know,
when you feel yourself gallon,
well you probably don't know this boat.
If you feel yourself
gassing and you're like,
should I knew I was going to gas now
you're really gassy and now is the anxiety
goes up and yes, some more. There's a how
it is. He'd want to avoid all that stuff.
That's what I think.
But you know,
that's when you put all
these weird expectations and
yourself. That's my opinion.
And the Jujitsu. So just go into Jujitsu
and learn Jujitsu. And when you do,
you're going to want a Ge if you do
geek cause he can do no g as well.
But when you choose a g I
recommend you recommend.
I think there's only one recommendation.
I agree. In all seriousness,
there's only one recommendation. Yeah.
And I've been through a lot of geese.
I have a lot of key experience.
We'll see a significant amount
of gay experience and the origin.
He has proven legitimately to be the
best one. Kind of by far too. Yeah.
There's this one that I used to use it to.
Dell's good was fine and it was like
good. Yeah. There's a difference though,
when there's a difference
between this skis. Good. Yeah.
And then you get an orange and gay. Yeah.
Right. Yeah. You know, it's funny like,
you know how like when you get a new ghee
and rash guard or whatever and you're
kind of fired up and go train because
you got your new gay, you know,
it's that faster.
That feeling didn't wear
off like for a while.
Did you feel that like when we rolled,
when we were both wearing you origins?
I did. Where are you fired up?
Yeah. Yeah. Cause like, yeah.
Did you think maybe it was
going to be the day? Uh,
for the record, I always think it's
going to be the day. Always. Yeah. Dang.
Because maybe one day there will be that
they just think it's going to be the
day to, maybe it's not though.
Maybe it will. I don't know.
Could be the day she anyway,
origin main.com get your g there
when you choose to get a g,
there's compression gear too.
Rash guards. If you do know, gee,
there's rash guards there too.
All made in America. Yeah.
I was gonna say all made in America,
which is like, it's no big deal. No,
it's a huge deal.
It's a huge deal made in America,
in Maine and our factory
by awesome workers.
And it's not the kind where by crafts
cross people, crafts, craftsmen,
crafts person, crafts people. Cause
people, man, there are more females. Yeah.
But they're craftsmen. Yeah. Men doesn't
mean you're a man. It means you're human.
Yeah. As far as I know, like modern man,
like mankind, mankind. Yeah.
Yeah. There you go. So,
so crossman kind of craftsmen kind
nonetheless. All made in America. Yes.
And that is a big deal. And it's
not the kind where it's like, yeah,
let's import all our things or whatever,
and then we'll quote on quote,
make it in America where you tick the
one checkbox that it's like, yeah,
technically it's made it,
it's not that kind.
It's the kind where they grow
the continent in America, they,
what do they do after they grow the
content and the harvest? The harvest,
the cotton. They, well, they could die the
cotton and they weave the cotton. Yeah.
Yeah. There's a whole bunch of steps all
done in America. The land of the cotton,
because it's not just cotton.
It's an athletic,
that's one of the problems with the old
geese is they're all made just with,
with cotton. They're
like, like crap. Yeah.
And then why would you not get
modern technology? Well why?
Because they don't have, they don't do
Jujitsu where they're making the geese.
Yeah. Now, so like little
issues that come up in you,
just little ones or big ones or whatever.
When they come up to
what's going on and put it,
you put an origin g in the
dryer it's dry like quick. Yeah.
And because it's not all cotton. Yeah.
Cause if you remember in the teams,
cotton kills.
Sure.
Cotton Kilz because it gets wet and then
it's heavy and makes you cold jams you
up. Yeah. It doesn't dry quick
enough. Get the blend going. Yeah.
Then you're good to go. And there's
all kinds of different leaves too,
which is cool.
Now let's go to,
or did you mean.com you can check
out with whichever one you want. Hey,
if you want something,
get something.
Also what you want to do is go to
the immersion camp if you want.
So did you see any emerging camp? It's
not like a training camp for ADCC. No.
It's an educational experience.
Like you immerse yourself in that you can
modulate to the level of your personal
commitment to getting after it.
Yes.
So some people will be there and they're
going to be really sore every day.
You're gonna be getting after it hard.
Some people are going to be brain,
their brains going to be some more sore
than their body because they're going to
be more looking at it from the education
that they're getting of learning new
moves and techniques.
So that's what's cool about the,
the immersion camp or some of us,
nothing's going to be sore because maybe
it'll be sore for a little while and
then we're just going to cruise a
little bit of exercise, the brain more,
and then the button he has to go back
and forth, do whatever you like. Yeah.
And there's a lot to go on and it's
kind of fun too. That's the thing. Yeah.
What's cool to hang out with just a bunch
of people that are going to do Jitsu
for seven days.
Yeah.
And then then they get
like five tons of lobster.
You don't have to stay there the whole
time. Yeah. There's a, there's a,
there's a first part in a second part,
you know,
it's like the first few days and then
you can do this the second few days and
then you can do all of them if you want.
So August 26 through September 2nd,
we're going to be there. You know who
else is going? No big deal. Dave Berg.
Dave Berg got the bug. Oh yeah,
no, he's got the bug. Yeah,
he'll call me for just like verbally,
like, so he's db texted me about, uh,
about like guard passing.
I'm like, Oh really?
Hey, let's do it. Let's communicate
about guard passing that via text.
Amen.
People with Americana and it's good.
It's an interesting conversation
because, you know, he says,
oh well the American is like what
I use the most right now. And,
and I told them like, the
American is actually not a
really effective move, right.
Against anyone that has trained for
a little bit. Right. Purple Belt,
you're not going to,
you might catch an him,
a blue belt in and Americana and purple
belt. Probably not going to happen.
I did catch a black belt in
America under the other day and,
and it was like shame.
Yeah.
I got caught with the Americans in this,
this particular black belt was like shame.
He hung his head in shame. He was like,
you need to go South America Honda.
But I explained to Dave the,
the reason that the Americana is effective
for him right now, the most effective.
I'm like, is it the first submission
that you learned? Yes, it is.
So he's practiced at the most than he's
figured out all the little nuance things
that you have to do right in
order to make the move, a move,
work and the American work.
So he's figured out some of those
things cause he's tried it a bunch.
Even when he missed it,
he learned something.
You didn't even know he learned something,
but he learned something.
So he keeps trying and
he got good with me.
So He's good at the Americana.
Yup.
He's not going against people
that know how to defend a yet,
which is going to be a problematic.
So you got it. You got to,
that's what happens. Isn't that part
of the whole learning process though?
Cause yes. Same thing.
I mean remember when a,
I mean I'm assuming you had
similar experience where yeah,
you sure you do Americanos and you'd
get them certain moves for years like,
like, like for when I first started,
my first good move was the keel.
In fact, I used to call it the easy
kill, the easy keeled, easy kill.
That's what I thought it was.
That was wonderful. It was,
I learned it like one of
the first submissions I look
and then I just tried it
all the time and I got pretty good at it.
But then you realize that it's
not that hard to defend the Zeke.
You'll eventually,
when you start going to get better guys.
So then you got to move to the,
I think the next move that I
actually started doing a lot of that,
the camera and I spent a couple of years
at com era and then I still spend a
couple of years at crucifix.
Then I spent a couple of years at the
straight foot lock than it, you know,
so and alluded to those positions.
That's how,
but Dave Burke, back to
my point, he's coming,
he's coming to the camp and you
know who else is? I will see you.
I'll just get a call.
We'll see if we'll see if Lafe yeah,
hopefully you know we all have to work.
Sure. Yeah. We block this off though.
Just sweet. That's really good fun.
Yeah. Cool. Go Man. If he can make that,
make that, uh, what's
the date on them again?
August 26 through September 2nd oh yeah.
And if you want it,
if you do want to come,
you can go to origin main.com and you
go to emerging camp and you can sign up.
You can come and hang out. Eat lobster
if you like lobster state steak. Yeah.
Hang out in Maine, visit our
factory, you know, which is awesome.
I think you can go like paddling, stand
up, stand up paddle boarding and stuff.
All kinds of stuff. Yeah. Also
good way to support yourself.
If you choose to vary up your workup,
make it a little less boring.
You always make it sound like I do these
boring workouts and I just realize I've
been taking that abuse for for quite some
time. My workouts are not boring. Well
yeah, in fact they're boring and hard,
so they're hard. Here's the thing where,
well, boring is like just a complete
matter of opinion, you know?
So to me,
if you're going to do 20 rep squats,
Bra breast, 20 reps, rest
20 reps until you're like,
that's kind of boring.
And have you ever done it before?
Yes. You've done that work
your exact one. But yeah,
I did do 20 rep squat,
some in fact don't.
20 rep squats that you
can only squat 10 times.
Well that's physically impossible,
but you know, yes it is.
If you could only do it 10 times,
you can only do it 10 times.
You can do it 20 times. You can
do it 20 times. No, that's it.
That's not how it works. I bet.
Hey, look, take my word for it.
You can physically do it 10 times.
Mentally, you do it 20 times.
Imagine you do the 20th okay.
It's a look.
You can physically do it 10 times.
I guess.
Technically you're right, and I don't want
to listen. I don't want to split hairs,
but you're still not right. If you can do
it 10 times, but you can do it 20 times,
because look, if you can do something 20
times, you can do it 10 times. So yes,
but what you're seeing is something that
you max out at 10 times the weight you
use to Max out at 10 times.
You do it 20 times physically impossible.
10 Moscow apparently for
Echo. Oh Man. See, anyway,
back to the workout.
Maybe that's where them skinny me calm
maybe. Anyway, if you want
to vary up the workout,
go to audit dotcom. Slash Jocko.
Get some cool kettlebells. Yeah,
get some battle ropes.
Get a mace, get to Macy's,
a heavier one and a lighter one. Boom,
formulate a more end and I use them so my,
my workouts are interesting.
All right, well there you go.
You have any interesting workout.
We'll do it that way. That's what I,
that's what I would would, what
do you say? Suggest. Okay. Anyway,
dot com good stuff in there.
Don't get addicted to the website because
there's a lot of good information too
on there cause you could nonetheless
also good way to support when you get the
books that Jocko sometimes reviews on
this podcast I organized or we organize
them on Jocko podcast.com and click
on the top to the books from the,
from the episode I got
all the books listed there
including little articles that
you know how sometimes you'll cover
article. I'll list those on there.
How much research would you have to do
if you knew nothing about this podcast or
me? How much research would you
have to do to figure out that
we read books on the podcast and that
they're all on Jocko podcast.com the
reason I ask this is because I've had,
I've had people ask me on social media
like a week ago, like on Twitter,
like do you like to read? Yeah. Right.
Like that's a cre. You don't have to
dig very deep to, to know that answer.
Yeah. Right. Do you like to read, right?
That this is a really low level question
that doesn't take a whole lot of
research to figure out, right? Yeah.
I guess is that laziness or is it like,
Hey,
this guy seems pretty accessible.
I'm just gonna ask him areas.
I wonder if this guy likes to read.
I don't think the likelihood of it being
laziness cause I'm just going to be
different for different people,
but thought the,
the likelihood of it being
laziness is pretty low I think.
I don't think it's lazy laziness at all.
I think it would be a mix
or one of these things.
Yeah.
They just want to ask you a question that,
that you know that you're
going to have an answer to or,
or maybe they're just new or maybe they
know you from extreme ownership and you
know, I know you wrote
this cool book, Hey,
do you like to read in
general kind of thing.
Maybe they don't listen to the being
harsh, being too judgmental on my part.
If you're,
if you're jumping to that conclusion
that it's laziness tend to read.
Like we literally have a podcast
about books that we read and,
and then people say, do you have
a list of books? Do you rec?
Do you have any books you recommend?
Yeah. Do you have a book list?
Do you have a reading list? These are all
things I could ask on a regular basis.
Is, is this kind of like the time I asked
you, Hey, do you know of any gun ranges?
I said, yeah, Google, go on Google
and search done. Re kind of like that.
So yeah, I feel the same tone. Here's
the thing, you never know really know,
uh, when people were coming into the
game, you didn't know what, you know,
what their deal is or where they're
coming from. So yeah, like maybe,
or maybe maybe they just heard you on
Tim Ferriss or Joe Rogan and was like,
boom, this guy, super interesting.
Let me go straight to them and start
talking to them kind of thing or start
asking questions rather
than going on the Internet.
Let me research who this guy is and
what he likes and doesn't like to do,
et Cetera, et cetera. Am I,
am I lazy in the fact that when I want
to know something, I'll Google it?
No, that's not lazy. I don't
know. I don't think so.
All right.
As opposed to what I dunno.
Saying going to school and
studying at first, you know,
alternative nonetheless,
if you were feeling not lazy,
actually this has nothing
to do with laziness because
this is more a convenience
that I think would be benefit or I thought
it would be beneficial for people who
are looking for the books that
you cover and ways to get them.
That's why organize these books on, talk
about gas.com the website are all there.
They're all there by episode and by
chance they're kind of in order of
preference in order of the way you,
almost the way you should read them.
Maybe I'd have to shift some of them now.
Yeah.
Put them in a different order because
there's some books that I read again.
I was like, man, this should
be, this should be near the top.
I mean about faces as the number
is a number one. Yeah, right.
You should read that book
first. Yeah. People ask me
that all the time. Well, what,
what's your favorite,
I've already read extreme ownership.
Is there another book you recommend I
read? Well, and I've read all your books.
What books should I read next about
face by Colonel David Hackworth.
Yeah. So anyways. Yeah, makes sense.
I mean, I organized them by episode.
Yeah, most recent episode. Right, with
book. But if you go back to episode one,
which there's no book,
but two, there's a book,
and if you go in that order of reading,
that's a good progression to get rid
your books properly. Gotcha. So if you,
if you, if you want to read your book
Jockos Book list in order of importance,
order importance, you go in
chronological order per pod cast. Yes.
With books that's recommend not all
podcast. That's recommended. Cool.
Well there it is again. Just click on the
books and boom, it takes you there. Boom.
Click through there. Get your book.
Easy way to good way to support.
Takes it to Amazon. All good. Continue
shopping if you feel the need to,
like if you're shopping for Vat
Ellington's Day. Now that already passed.
What's the next one? Easter.
Hmm? Carry on Easter gifts.
Sure. Good. Those chocolate Easter
bunnies in the, and the eggs. You know,
you go Easter egg hunting, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Well my kids do.
Sure. Well, my youngest kid
does. Yeah, there you go. My,
you can shop for that compare. Yeah. Yeah,
it makes sense. You know, they're older.
After a while, you kind of figure
it out. Kind of still fun though,
can be nonetheless click through.
That's good way to support. Also,
subscribe to the podcast if you
haven't already. Leave a review.
If you're in the mood, leave a review.
Here's the thing, I'm not saying, hey,
leave a review. I'm not saying to leave
a review, but I think sometimes people,
they want to leave a review, but they
don't like think about it. You know?
And then when let's say I
get reminded like, oh shoot,
I wanted to leave a review and
I get reminded me like, boom,
then I'm going to leave a review. That's
a good one. I read all the reviews. Yeah,
and I've read them on the podcast
before when they're really funny or I've
quoted them on social media.
Yeah, so there's that too. Yeah.
Yeah. If you write an awesome review,
well, it doesn't have to be awesome,
but if it's funny or it's
good or it's a creative,
what's the, that's what I should've
said. It is a creative review.
There's been some really good ones too.
Same thing with Amazon reviews for tea
and books and there's a lot of people
that get after it. I think it colorful
for sure. I would say colorful.
They put the main thing is
layers put a lot of layers. Yeah.
Some people are real good at the layers.
Very impressed with that on many levels.
I see what you did. Nonetheless,
subscribe if you a, you know,
if you want us to wear it that way,
that's a good way.
Thanks for the people who have subscribed.
That's, that's a good, good deal.
Too much. Appreciate it. A big deal. Also
on Youtube. Subscribe to that. If you,
if you like the video version of this
podcast or if you want to watch and or
share excerpts of this podcast.
Three minutes,
one minute sometimes. Do you
haven't made any one minute. One,
six minutes sometimes. Some one
minute ones. Okay. That'd be good.
The one you just made is good.
Thanks. The time's running out. Yeah.
That's like a woody code. He was
settling. Enhanced, enhanced,
I think it's called enhanced excerpt.
Enhanced excerpts,
which means that echo has gone
and put his cinematic flair.
No, I would say I put some music on it
and it put some text on it. There it is.
Cinematic hats. It's enhanced it a little
bit of salt and macro flare there. Yeah.
All right. Well there it is. There's some
of those on there as well. By the way.
No big deal.
I I when I got to the gym today,
Carl. Yeah Carl, he says,
Hey I saw you on Worldstar.
That's when, you know,
made it straight up in popular culture.
Popular Culture.
We're on Worldstar Worldstar
if you don't know what world star is,
it originally was for fights.
That's what I knew at
four. Yeah. That's how it,
I think that's how it gained game
cause it just scraps it was for,
it was for like music videos I think
pop music videos and stuff like that.
Then you get, you know, I
would watch it because they,
cause people would film street fights
and I like to watch street fights. Sure.
Learn a lot from street fights.
And what's funny is it became such a
popular culture thing that when people
would be recording the fights that
they're gonna then put on Worldstar.
They would be saying worldstar
during the fight.
Someone refilming and saying
Worldstar this is going on.
Worldstar well now guess what's on
Worldstar that goes video we made.
It just goes on with star World Star.
That's good.
Nonetheless.
Cross cultural boundaries.
Okay.
Worldstar worldstar maybe it happen.
You did 100% but yeah, youtube,
we'll talk. We'll start.
Thanks for putting me on there. Yeah,
it was good. That is good. Awesome.
Youtube. Good one good way to
support also, Jack was a store.
It's called Jocko store.
Obviously chocolate store.com obviously
that's where you can get shirts,
tee shirts, some travel mugs on there.
Some rash guards, more rash guards.
This is like Jocko gear rash guards.
So compared to,
how would you compare them to the
origin because actually there may their
religion. Yeah, they're similar.
They're more like geared tour light
toward like Jocko. Well, let's,
yeah, let's say this, that from a,
from a visual perspective,
there's a way that Jocko gear looks and
there's a way that origin gear looks.
There's some areas that overlap.
There's some areas that don't
overlap on over there. Some of the,
let's call them color combinations that
my brother Pete Robert's puts together.
They wouldn't be allowed in the Jocko
store. They wouldn't be Jocko gear. Okay.
And there's some things that Jocko gear
does that wouldn't be appropriate for
origin because origin is a little
bit in the other direction.
Sure. The overlapping
areas, all good. Yeah.
But if you want your gear made in America,
there's one place to get it done,
right. That's our factory up
in Maine. It's your story.
So yeah, boom. You can get rash guards
there as well. Uh, some patches,
those are restocked. A lot of people were
hitting me up. That's slide for patches.
Yeah.
It's weird that people have to hit you up,
that you just don't pay attention to the
stock and say, wow, look running low.
I should order more. Yeah. Maybe
it's not that important to you.
None of that's important.
So I got a handle on it and I think
I have a solid system where you know,
we're going to run into way less
of that, if any of that. Okay.
The less the women's stuff on there, some
hats. Cause it does mean a lot to me, eh.
I'm saying that's cool.
So maybe I should be more,
I should do a better job of expressing
how important it is to me for people if
they want patches to be able to
get one. Yeah, maybe I haven't,
I obviously haven't done a good job. Yeah,
it's your fault. It's your fault. It is.
So yeah. [inaudible] dot com that's
good. Good, good way to support.
Also psychological warfare. If you didn't
know what that is, that's an album,
an album, not a music
album. It's a spoken word,
spoken word with tracks,
chocolate tracks.
And each track is designated,
formulated, engineered,
engineered is what it is to help you
through little points of weakness that you
might run into on your
campaign against weakness.
Like if you want to skip I s I always
say if you want to skip the workout,
if you're like, Hey, I'm too tired. I
don't feel like it. I don't feel like it.
I start with Alan because
that's essentially why this
whole thing exists because
that that was the issue that was the
genesis of this album was echo questioning
how he could overcome these moments of
weakness or how I do and the nights kind
of answered one of them and
we do record those things.
You know what's funny is that I asked
you that before and it wasn't that
specific question, but it was essentially
that question and be like, Hey,
what do you do?
And then you look,
he kinda gave me a look in more like as
if your feelings don't matter kind of
thing. Basically pulled the
jockey and I was like, dude,
your mood or if kind of the day I got
asked this similar, you know someone said,
Hey John, can you tell us a little
bit more about your morning routine?
Like what you just want, you know
your camp, I know you got up early,
but can you tell us more about your
morning routine? I was like, yeah, listen,
my morning routine is extremely,
extremely important.
So here's, here's the steps of the
Jocko morning routine. First of all,
you set your alarm clock,
you set all your alarm clocks,
you set the first one at four 30
you set the next one at four 35
you set the next one at four 40 and
you have your backups. By the way,
you don't set your backups at the same
time cause you want to be fumbling around
with three alarm clocks in the
morning. It's a good tip. I said,
then you get done with that. Then when
the alarm clock goes off, you get up,
you get out of bed,
then you go.
And it's important that you get your
toothbrush out, isn't that brush.
And then I use it 46 brush strokes
on each side of my mouth and no more,
no less. And then I spit three times
to city. So yeah. And I'm like,
oh good. Here's the morning routine.
Dude, you get up and you go,
well then again, no, I know, I know.
But it's like the reality is,
is someone gonna write down my morning
routine and then follow the exact same
thing and would that be good
for him? Maybe, I dunno.
Well here's what their morning routine
then get up and go get up and get it.
Yeah. But here's the, like
some people they, they,
they focus on in this
can be beneficial from,
from what I hear they focus on or I they
identify certain things they do in a
morning routine that helps them,
that like sets them up or whatever.
Morning routine. And I've, I actually
wrote about in the, in the field manual,
it's like the morning routine
starts the night before. Yeah. Yeah.
The morning routine starts when you get
your gear ready cause you want to be
fumbling around in the morning.
Don't wake,
don't set yourself up to fumble around
with things in the morning. Right.
That's just a bad thing. Don't do that.
So you have your gear ready. You know,
for me,
I mean I'm very systematic in pretty
much the way and throw at you.
You know, I have like all my workout gear
is in the bathroom on hangers, you know,
pair of shorts, shirt on each hangar,
there's six of them. They're all the same.
There's no thought process that's needed.
They're all matching and I
have the same kind of socks.
All my socks are the same.
I do have black socks and white socks,
but one girl or is just completely
white sox. All the same.
You grabbed those, you put those on, boom.
You brush your teeth, boom, you take,
I take my supplements in
the morning and at night,
but I take my micro oil and my,
my joint warfare boom,
and then I go hit it. How much
water teaching? It's it's,
I drink when I'm thirsty,
I drink and then if I'm, I
don't measure it. You don't
be like, okay, no, let me dig.
I drink when I'm thirsty.
I eat when I'm hungry.
But if you drink water
when you're thirsty, you're
already 2% dehydrated. Okay,
well I drank a little bit more.
I drink about 3% more than all right.
There you go.
So you 1%, uh, over, over
hydrated or hydrated now less. Uh,
but well, you know like all drink
a whole thing like the, you know,
the mugs that we have to travel
there three ounces by the way.
I'll drink a whole thing of that just
routine. That's kind of the routine.
But what's it like in the morning?
You had to pound it.
Sure.
If you want to call it pounded and the
drink it cause you want to stay hydrated.
Get the water back in there man. Get
it. Okay. That sounds good for you.
Water is good for you by
the way. Yeah, no doubt.
It's better than soda in the morning.
You were drink a coke in the morning.
No Bro.
It's like the worst we did these
monster mash is back in the or,
so my son was doing the monster mash
with us when he was like six or c.
What's the monster? Mash is like, Yo,
you do rope climbs that you
do a sprint workout swimming,
that you do pull ups in the EU and they
put little things in there sometimes.
So one of the things that they had to
do was drink a coke through a straw.
So you're like doing pull ups in a rope
climb in the coke. Yeah. And so he uh,
he, he, I think that was the first
time you ever tried soda. [inaudible]
nasty. Well there's of
wanting soda though. Yeah.
The,
there's two elements to drinking a soda,
especially for the first time
is okay. It tastes weird. Sweet.
Sugary and carbonated.
Carbonated will burn your mind.
It feels like it's burning your mouth.
Yeah. He's like, yeah, you can't do that.
That's up right in the middle of the work,
not to check and do that.
You keep in mind,
you just described your morning routine.
You answered the question that they were,
I know you didn't answer.
That's why I said,
look,
I'm not trying to be negative against
morning routines and there's pretty much
what I do. But the reason
is I think people think, Oh,
if I have, if I knew your morning
routine, then I'd know what the secret is.
It's like, hey man, the secret is get up
and go do something. That's the secret.
Yeah. I'm not going to say,
here's the deal. Here's the deal.
I'm not going to sell you my morning
routine as the solution to your problems.
Now I will say that if you
fumble around in the morning,
it's going to cause you
problems throughout the day,
so I don't fumble it on in the morning.
Set your,
set your life up correctly so that
you're not fumbling around. That's good.
I'm not going to sell you my morning
routine as the solution to your problems.
I'm not going to do that,
but I will say that if you do have a
good system that you go through in the
morning, it will set up
your day correctly. Yeah.
That's why I think people ask why
people want it and I get it. Okay,
so I'm not trying to be
like a jerk. Right. I'm not
trying to get that negative.
I guess I'm kind of making five boy,
you're making fun,
making fun of morning
routines a little bit,
but at the same time I have
one tonight and I stick to it,
but I think that's a thing.
I don't,
I don't actually have something and I
stick to it like I do. This is what it is.
I follow the functional thing
that works and you stick to it.
Yeah and I stick to it.
So that's that. But I do,
I did like designed my morning routine.
I didn't see who I'm going to
design this program. No know.
It's like I know what works.
It's functional and that's what I do.
I do things that work and everyone else
wants to know what works well there you
not everyone figured out on their own
what works. I guess. Here's the thing.
Your morning routine,
your,
you're ultimately right and I think this
is super important not to forget or not
to like miss interpret where
you don't use just quote.
You just said like your morning routines,
not going to be the solution
to your problems kind of thing.
I think that's what people do think.
I think that here is someone with
a level hate in my opinion.
I don't, I don't know,
but this is what it seems like where
someone with a level head and they want to
look for just that. Just, just,
just that one thing that's going to
help them just a little bit, you know?
So they're going to be like, Hey, let me,
let me formulate a good morning routine.
I don't know that much about effective
routines, so let me look into that.
Just has a little helper,
not the solution to my problems,
which I think some people may kind of
miss. No, you're right. You're right.
And that's why,
like I said,
I'm not belittling the idea that a
morning routine is helpful because it
certainly is. Yeah. It might add some,
some tiny bit of help to your desk
if you're doing the right thing.
Some benefits. Thank you. It might
benefit your day, which is positive.
Will it cure your overall problems
of life? No, but you know what?
It's a good place to start. That's
why we say wake up early. Right? Yeah.
That's part of the routine, but even
how you, I guess I am being a jerk.
Yeah. But here's the thing. Let
me, let me, let me just like, yeah,
get on a good morning routine. That's
a good idea. I like it. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm not trying to make fun of
it. I was, but I'm not anymore.
It seems like you're making fun of it
for people because this is what it may be
sounded like when someone asks you,
what's your morning routine?
It sounds like you,
you're kind of with this presumption,
like you're presuming or assuming that
they think it's going to solve all their
problems. That's kind of
what it's saying. Yes.
But in that very specific direction,
like if someone says, Hey, look,
I'm always looking for things to benefit
my day and my effectiveness. You know,
I've, uh, you know,
I do this and do that and I found that
this helps a little bit here and there.
Hey,
what's your morning routine?
Maybe I can incorporate one or more
of your reading maybe into mind.
That'll give me a little bit of help to,
I don't think you would have came off.
Yeah, definitely. That would have been
a very good question. Here's what I do.
So there you go.
So you get how you said the question
like you were kind of impersonating
watch her morning routine, like making
them sign off. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Everyone. Not, not so good. So
good. We got to the bottom of it.
You can have your drinking water.
Another drink you can drink is you can
drink something called Jocko white tea.
It's available on Amazon.
Now this is the only tea available,
not only in America,
but in the world that comes with
an 8,000 pound dead lift guarantee.
So there's no other tea.
I never send something out there that are,
that are they say 6,000 they say they
can get your 6,000 pound deadlifts. Yeah,
there's,
I've seen,
I've seen 7,272 some teas.
Some white tees say they'll get you 7,200
and there's only one white tea that'll
get you the guaranteed 8,000
pound deadlift. Good. There's
some layers on the tea,
which I kind of remembered last time. I
didn't want to interrupt, interrupt you.
You, you're talking his first
episode of this podcast.
Absolute first one.
Oh yeah.
I think the only one that doesn't start
with this is Jocko podcast number.
That's cause you had a different vision
of the at the time with no we, yeah.
And then the last it started with you
were thinking of this podcast is to be
100% that's what it felt
like. That first one.
That's what it felt like in your
mind. Yeah. In my mind, if you listen,
yeah. Now you can see I was
not, I was not ready to Cruz.
I came in there with a game plan.
The game plan did not say cruise on it.
He became friends and get after it.
It's funny as you shut it down so quick,
right when you heard it you were like,
hey,
you know you want to cut it at
this point, not the, not the,
the little car like we just
rolled into a conversation.
But here's the thing with that
conversation, as far as the layers go,
we talk about white tea, Chai. Yeah, no,
cause I was trying to remember
what kind of tea that was.
I don't know about the tea,
especially back then. Nonetheless,
you are always on the pomegranate
that started when I was in the dirt.
So anyways,
you can get that,
you can get it on Amazon and
then you can start dead lifting
properly. There's some books that
you can get way the warrior kid.
I get questions all the time about
how you should raise your kids and,
and, and, and not just how
to raise him cause he'd,
people know how to raise him but they not
how to raise him, but how to raise him.
Like they know what they want the kids to,
they know the values that
they want the kids to have,
but they're not sure how to give them the
values. They don't know how to do that.
So it w real simple, get them this book
way of the Warrior Kit that that's,
you know, discipline, eating
habits, working out, dealing
with bullies, how to study.
All those things are in there. These are
the things you want, not just your kid,
but the children of the world
to have these type of qualities.
And now on top of that,
we have way of the warrior kid too,
which is called Mark's mission.
Just talks about some important lessons,
controlling your temper,
overcoming fear of failure,
working hard, saving money, being frugal,
dealing with verbal abuse,
helping other people,
starting businesses. Yeah, I said that.
And becoming a leader again,
all the,
there's no human being that would look
at the lessons from way of the warrior
kid and say would say, I don't want
my kid to have that quality. No,
the qualities are in there.
So there's that.
And if you want a good
example of a warrior kid,
checkout Irish oaks ranch.com
where you can get soap.
That's a handmade by young Aiden who's
12 years old. But he has a business,
no big deal. He's making
soap. Yeah. Goat milk soap,
that's soaps actually good like to
use. So for sure, let's face it,
you know how you have your
friend and his wife makes
soap on the weekend sympathy
purchase scenario and it's beautiful.
It has the little packaging and then
you say, all right, it's soap. Um,
let me go ahead and use some
soap. And you're like, pride.
This isn't like usable soap.
This is the novelty decorative item.
It was a cool little educational
experience because he asked me, you know,
he was making soap and he's, and he
reached out to me. His Dad is, uh, uh,
a farmer, also a firefighter,
but he's a farmer. Anyways,
his dad and I were connected.
I buy meat from his dad and you know,
he said all my son wants
to get in touch with you.
But as we're going through the process,
he sends me like his label for the soap.
Yeah. And you know, it looked nice,
but um, went back with, you know,
this needs to be an OCR
standard. Yeah. So anyways, yeah,
it's cool little learning process
and yeah, you can get that soap.
You could support a kid that's a
warrior kid. And the Jocko soap motto,
which I give aid, no credit for.
Sorry Aiden, you're a good kid.
But you didn't think of this.
It took the,
it took the masterful marketing mind
or Jocko to come up with the motto for
Jocko Soap,
which is stay clean.
It's good. And you know, there's
some layers on that too, right?
Like a Motorhead song. Oh,
all right. There you go.
And you like Motorhead and I am a huge
fan of Motorhead and you don't do any
drugs.
So there's the kind of the reason that
whenever I talk to people or people talk
to me on the,
uh,
through social media or email and
they've had a drug problem or an alcohol
problem and I always kind of sign off
like, Hey, stay clean, stay clean.
So cause that's also what Lemmy from
Motorhead was saying. Stay clean.
Like don't let this kill you.
Now,
let me from Motorhead was a rare dude
who did a lot of drugs and alcohol and
somehow was able to survive very
well up to up to when he died,
drinking incredible amounts
of Jack Daniels. Yeah.
Those are some legit layers, but he
always would say, don't do it. Yeah.
He's a guy that would say, don't
do it. It's done. Don't do it.
Don't do what people do. Don't
do drugs. Stay clean. Stay clean.
There you go. Uh, in addition to that,
I've got another book called the
discipline equals freedom field manual.
And if this is, this is a good point.
If you know someone that's off the path,
right? Like people go off the
path in life and it doesn't take,
we talked about this last time, it
doesn't take, but one step off the path.
When you're on a slippery slope,
it's a slippery slope when
you step off the path.
So if you know someone that has taken a
step off the path and they're starting
to slide down, get him this book to
get them on the path, the right path.
And there's also a chance
that the person that
stepped off the path is you.
So get the field manual.
It's got the faults and actions
that are to be on the right path.
Make yourself better,
faster, stronger, smarter,
anything else,
more physically fit and healthier.
The audio version of that is on
iTunes, Amazon music, Google play,
other MP3 platforms.
It's not on audible because then you
can't have it as an album with tracks,
which we obviously
support extreme ownership.
The first book I wrote with my brother
Leif Babin over a million copies sold.
There's a lot of copies sold.
Yes, that's a lot of copies sold.
You know how many copies they told us
would be successful because we didn't know
any Lafe and I didn't know anything
about the publishing world. Wait,
what do you mean?
When we were getting on the book was
getting ready to come out and I would talk
to the point where we're
talking to a publisher.
Lafe and I were talking to the
publisher and he says, you know,
if this is a successful book, then
you know it'll, it'll really be,
it will be good to see blah blah blah.
And I saw like the standard, like a myth,
like a certain amount. That's the
socially no. So I said, hey, what a,
I don't know anything about this. What
is considered to be a successful book?
You know what the number was? 20,000
bucks thing. He goes, yeah. He goes, hey,
you know, we're, we're printing 12,000
on this first round and if you sell,
if you don't, we'll print some more. But
if you can sell 20,000 books, that's,
that's going to be, that's a huge
success. And it will be. We'll be proud.
So here we are. We're 1 million.
Dang. It's pretty cool. Yeah.
Good Job Leif. Babin good job. Both. Yeah,
they've tells a story that we got home
from Ramadi and the only time I ever told
him anything positive
was when we got home.
We'd been home for like two weeks
and I told him that the Delta platoon
commander, Hey, good job. Over there.
So yeah, we're keen. I likes to keep
it real. Yeah, man. And actually,
you know what though?
Good job over there seems real simple,
but I'm sure in that context he
was probably the most loaded. Yeah,
good job anyone's ever heard. Yeah,
yeah. I believe you're correct.
Beyond the books and beyond
the podcast also echelon front,
speaking of life and me,
this is our leadership and management
consulting company. This is the thing,
every, this is a bold statement, right?
Every problem in every
organization is leadership problem.
That's a bold statement to make.
Yeah. And I'll say it again.
Every problem in every organization
is a leadership problem.
So if there's a problem in
an organization, the problem,
it boils down to leadership on some level.
So what we do is we fixed the leadership
and thereby we fix your problems.
It's me, it's Leif Babin, it's
JP Denelle. It's Dave Burke.
Good deal.
Dave Burke till Dave,
if you want to get in touch with us
to have us come out and work with your
company, get your
leadership aligned, go to
info@echelonfrontdotcomoryouemailinfoonfrontdotcomoryoucangotothewebsiteechelonfront.com
and of course we are
approaching the muster,
the leadership seminar.
Be Learn,
you learn tactics of leadership,
you learn strategies of leadership,
you learn pragmatic techniques.
You can execute as a leader that will
make you and your team when we already
expanded the floor.
So we expanded the four as much as we
could already because the ticket sales are
going quickly. And so we've got both, uh,
places that we're doing the muster.
We've got an expanded as much as we can.
It doesn't matter.
They're both,
both of them are going to
sell out doing two this year,
only Washington DC May 17th and 18th
and San Francisco October 17th and 18th.
The whole team will be there and
we will be with you. If you come,
we'll be hanging out. We'll be answering
questions that we'll be talking,
we'll be eating lunch.
We'll be,
we'll be hanging out working
out with all of you that come.
There's no green room.
Yeah,
there's no backstage where,
where life is sitting back there in the
backstage with cucumbers on his eyes to
relax. That's not happening. No,
no. We're hanging out all of us.
So you can register for
that@extremeownership.com
we'll see you there and until
the muster you can find us by interacting
and conversing and cruising with us on
the Inter webs on Twitter,
on Instagram and on that facey Paul.
Okay.
Echo is at echo.
Charles
and I
am@jockowillinkandonceagaindancrenshawisatcrenshawforcongress.com
his Twitter is at Dan Crenshaw,
t x and his Facebook is Dan Crenshaw
and
like to thank everyone for listening
thanks to all the men and women in uniform
or across the globe with sword
in hand and heart at the ready
to fight and die for what we hold
sacred and to police, law enforcement,
firefighters, paramedics and all first
responders. Thanks for being prepared.
Okay.
And thanks for being there when we call
you in our time of need and to everyone
else out there.
Thank you for listening and thank you
for sharing and thank you for supporting,
but more important.
Thanks for finding your mission
and executing your mission,
whether it's your job or your business,
or a charity or your family
or whatever your mission is.
Thanks for getting out there,
getting after it.
So until next time,
this is Dan Crenshaw
and echo and Jocko out.