Jocko.
I've got a question regarding the quote.
If there is a doubt, there is no doubt.
Oh, right. I remember that from last time.
Okay. This would seem to indicate
avoiding taking risks. Many,
many businesses or many
business decisions involve risk.
Often there can be a doubt
about either of two options,
doubt that you should maintain the
status quo and doubt about pursuing a new
opportunity to frequent or you
frequently talk about dichotomies.
Would you mind sharing your
thoughts on this principle?
Yeah,
this is,
this is a classic thing in and it's a
great point and that's why these little
sound bites can be a little bit dangerous.
Sometimes we use a little little power
soundbites because they are that simple
and of course I've loved, I
like things to be simple, right?
That's the number two law of
combat is to keep things simple.
But sometimes things like this need a
little bit of amplifying information and
yes,
this could be construed as being
extremely risk averse and like,
hey,
if I have any doubt about the safety of
success of this mission that we're not
going to do it.
Which if that was the case,
then I would have done a zero missions
during my deployments to Iraq.
Uh, same with business. Never
would have started victory.
MMA never would've started echelon
front cause there was risk involved in
starting those things.
Never would have done anything really
because there's always going to be doubts.
So this is a accurate statement and
of course every business has risk.
And so, so I guess that idea
that if there is a doubt,
there is no doubt is not to be taken
literally when it comes to risk,
when it comes to risk,
don't take it literally.
But what it should be I think
is like a a warning, right?
Like a little warning that's in your head.
If there's a doubt like,
okay, we need to think about what's going
on here. We need to understand what,
what is at risk here
because,
and I just had this conversation with us,
CEO of a company. As a matter of fact,
I was talking about the dichotomy of
leadership and I was talking about how,
you know, giving him examples.
I was like for instance in,
and he was in a technology
company and I said, you know,
if you didn't take risk you wouldn't,
you wouldn't make any progress,
but if you took too much risk you wouldn't
be where you are right now because
they're dominating. So
it's like, oh you're,
you're balancing that dichotomy all the
time. So if he would have said, hey,
if there a doubt, there is no doubt he
never would have gotten off the ground.
Now,
where I think it becomes a more solid
statement is from like a moral or an
ethical standpoint.
And that is if you think that something
is wrong or that it probably is,
if you think you're doing something
that you probably shouldn't be doing,
then there's doubt and you
probably shouldn't be doing it.
I think an easy way to keep yourself in
check and these days it's a very real
possibility. It's just if you think
that you're being recorded at all times,
like if you just think,
oh, I'm being recorded,
which probably somebody is recording you.
Like if you decide you think
you can get away with something,
you're probably not going to get
away with it. Look at all the,
just go watch youtube,
don't caught in the act or whatever.
People get caught all the time.
So whenever you're doing,
think that there could be somebody there
with a phone recording you and I think
that's keeps you a morally and
ethically in check. You know,
I used to tell my guys that you could be
getting watched by CNN or Al Jazeera or
some report. You know,
whoever you, you know,
you could be getting watched and if you're
doing something that you shouldn't be
doing, you're, you're gonna
get caught. So don't do it.
Not to mention these days we
got the aircraft overhead,
they can see everything.
So do the right thing.
That's what you do.
You do the right thing.
Yeah.
If you have any doubt that what
you're doing is the right thing,
then you should probably shouldn't do it.
A lot of those,
a lot of the horrible
police actions, yeah. Are,
you know, recorded by some random
person with a phone. Now, of course,
I always need to point out that there's
all of these good actions that take
place every single day. Millions and
millions of police doing the right thing.
No one publishes those. No one uploads
those on to youtube or Facebook.
But the bad acts that are caught, they're
caught because someone has a camera.
And so like that's great advice for a cop.
Hey,
act like you're being recorded
all the time. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's interesting. Well, it may cause
you very well. Might be. Yeah. Yeah.
So do the right thing.
Next question.
Thank God I didn't have cameras when I
was a kid for all the dumb stuff I did.
Yeah. Uh, yeah. Well, I,
I always want to make sure that
I'm not sitting here saying like,
everyone out there should
do the right thing like me.
I'm not saying that if you
thought I was saying that,
I'm not saying God that apologize
for even sounding that way.
Like I was as dumb and stupid as the
next person and still do dumb stuff.
Try not to get a man you don't
do dumb stuff. Right. You know,
it was bad when, when, uh,
when we had Charlie plumb
and Jim conch on. Yeah.
And I'm like thinking they're like, you
know, hey, this is the way to act. Right?
And I'm like, don't put me in
that category, but you guys,
you guys are awesome heroes
and I'm just over here. Yeah.
Don't say that about me. You guys can
say like, Hey, talk about character.
You have character.
I'm just over here trying to do
shit.