This is Jocko podcast number
100 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
And we have a guest with us tonight who
is in large part responsible for this
podcast existing in the first place,
who has provided massive support behind
pretty much everything I've done,
including books and podcasts and events
and all this other stuff that I've been
getting after for the last couple of
years since I departed the shadows and
stepped into the normal world.
In fact,
this is the person that pulled me from
the shadows into the normal world.
Mr Tim Ferris. Tim, welcome to the show.
Thank you for having me Jack
off. And we have, you know,
an interesting state right now
you do because you just
got done with a 10 day
silent retreat and a five day
fast embedded in there somewhere,
right? I did. So it was my first 10
day. You know what? Like you know what,
my notes weren't here after I said that.
My notes are dude question mark like,
dude, cause that's what that
makes me think. Just like,
dude, okay, tell us about it a little bit.
And I know you'll probably cover it later,
but
it was in retrospect,
probably layering a few too many
things on top of one another.
But it was my first meditation retreat,
also my first silent retreat combined
and consisted of 10 days of waking up at
five 30 and I support that part beginning,
I know it's sleeping in,
but starting at five 30 I hadn't woken
up with the stars in a while and then
sitting for 45 minutes of meditation,
walking for 45 minutes of meditation
and doing that until 9:00 PM with the
exception of meals.
But as you mentioned,
I fasted for the first five days out
of 10 because I wanted to see how that
affected my state and I sat
during meals effectively,
meaning meditated during those times
as well. And it was a, an intense,
unexpectedly intense experience because
it unlearn is your psyche in a fashion
that I hadn't experienced before.
Since you have no distractions
and you're not permitted to read,
there's no music,
there's no talking,
you're discouraged from any writing.
There are no devices and that means
there's no real escape from whatever is
ricocheting inside your own head.
And uh,
as you go through the passing days,
you drop into deeper layers of your
personality and the stories that you've
constructed for yourself as well as
direct experience and memories that you
haven't thought of in my
case. 20, 25 years, 30 years,
35 years in some cases, very vivid,
intense memories that come back.
And so people have
a very difficult time at points and the
teachers are there every other day to
interact on a one on one basis to
ensure that people don't have a complete
psychotic break.
I suppose.
Did you hear random question,
but would you hear people like
crying in their rooms or whatever?
Heard people crying? Uh,
definitely hurt people crying.
People went through a lot of
pain and there were sublime experiences
as well in moments of deep clarity or,
uh,
alleviation of suffering.
But I think that I was actually just
looking forward to describing the
experience to our mutual friend,
Dr Peter Attia,
who may be the most like cerebral,
intense,
impatient analytical person I've
ever met to a degree that even I find
hilarious, which is difficult to
achieve in this world, in this world,
in this life.
Uh,
and his level of obsession
and perseverating on diff,
on concepts endlessly,
uh,
makes me want to do a second retreat with
Peter when he's not allowed to tell me
how he's feeling.
Because I think the more you have run
your life through your prefrontal Cortex,
the harder you fall. And, uh,
I would not recommend it for most people
because I would have left the retreat
three or four times,
probably were it not for one particular
teacher who had decades of experience
with tens of thousands of retreatants
because I felt like I was going to leave
in worse shape than I came in.
That I had regressed to a very reactive
emotional state and that it was going to
be a huge handicap when I left.
I felt like I was regressing tremendously
and he was able to right the ship a
little bit along the way.
But if,
if he had not been there and I had left
even on day nine, I remember I was like,
people are supposed to be
in this deep state of bliss.
Or at least that was my perception.
I feel like I've just been rubbed raw and
all these nerves that I've numbed from
difficult experiences in childhood and
so on have just been exposed at the
surface. Uh, so I think it's a, I think
it requires a high level of supervision.
And this may not be the,
the forum for discussing
what I'm about to say,
but for those people who have the
experience, it might make some sense.
It had the characteristics of a very,
a very strong psychedelic experience,
but laid out over 10 days
where there's no escape.
So instead of ripping off the Bandaid,
you are being exposed to
facets of your life and
character that perhaps you
have not faced in decades.
So yeah,
it was a fun 10 days.
We get when you do,
when you get sleep deprivation,
which I've gone through some
insignificant sleep deprivation, you know,
you have those kind of um,
you know,
you take a trip without leaving
the farm type situations. And,
and for me it was nothing, nothing
crazy or anything. You know,
I remember seeing stop
signs in the ocean and uh,
traffic lights in the ocean and
stuff like that. So not crazy crazy,
but it's not,
it wasn't some psychological sort of
unpacking where I was meeting my former
self or anything like that. Um,
but yeah, you definitely that,
that's when I hear,
cause I've never tried psychedelic
drugs and when I wouldn't,
people talk about them. To me it
does not sound fun to me because I,
I think that where I think that where I
would end up would not be a happy place
and I don't really need to
hang out there very much.
And I should, I should also say that I
don't, in the case of the silent retreat,
or in the case of Psychedelics,
do it for fun and in,
I've had a few people ask me,
did you enjoy your experience?
I had a few staffers afterwards. They're
like, oh, did you enjoy your treat?
And I'm like,
I found it valuable.
I wouldn't use the word enjoy.
Yeah, yeah. Well, you, you, obviously,
you're going to unpack this thing and I'm
sure you'll do awesome episode talking
about it. As you look back on
it right now, your brain is
still, it's still 70% there.
And they told us at the end,
which I thought was very appropriate
because it applies to so many things.
They said, uh, or one of the
teachers said, you're, you,
you think you're normal right now and
you're not. You've very hypersensitive.
You're retreat is half done.
So it'll take 10 days,
the equivalent amount of time to
reintegrate and get re tethered.
And I remember thinking to myself,
I have fucking book launch calming.
I don't have 10 days to gingerly
walk my way back to reality. But,
uh, nonetheless, uh, that's true
for so much, right? I mean, it's,
if you have a book and your book
is 90% done, I remember I told, uh,
a more seasoned writer when I was writing
my second book. I said, I'm 90% done.
They said, oh,
congratulations. The only 50.
That's the trim work.
It's just like building a house.
They stayed trim work that all that
little stuff that takes longer than you
think it's going to take. Well, so to
just set the stage a little bit, um,
number one,
you are on this podcast before,
which was an awesome episode
and you talked about some
of your heart experiences
growing up and going through college and
actually having suicidal thoughts and
beyond suicidal plans.
That was podcast number 50 and it
really helped out a lot of people.
I got an immense amount of great feedback
from people and so thank you for doing
that.
And on that podcast,
we also briefly discussed
a novel called Musashi,
and it's just this incredible
book that you'd read.
And I had read and the ending of the
book is just full on epic and it's also a
thousand page book and it takes
the, the whole, the, the, the,
the ending of the book is literally
the last page and a half. So that's it.
You have to read a thousand pages
to get to this thing, this ending.
And we decided on that podcast that we
would do, do that book for podcast 100.
So here we are and we're going to
talk about the book Musashi by Eeg,
a Yoshikawa Agee,
Yoshi color.
And I'm just going to accept the fact
that I will be getting my Japanese
pronunciation corrected all day long.
I won't correct it unless
you want me to correct. Well,
maybe after I'd get done with something
you could tell me it's just going to
suck.
That's all there is to it.
Now the book, so if you don't know
anything about it, Miyamoto Musashi,
great Japanese swordsman and he wrote
the book, the Book of five rings. Um,
and I actually covered that
book on podcast number 80.
So if you haven't listened to 50
and if you haven't listened to 80,
go listen to those too.
And it'll give you some background,
which I don't want to spend a bunch of
time on there cause he's spent a bunch of
time on it on that podcast.
But here's the basic
understanding of whom we saw.
She was born into a Samurai family around
1584 fought his first dual at the age
of 13 against a grown man who he killed
by throwing him to the ground and
beating him with a Bokken, Boykin, Boykin,
Boykin. Oh, this is going to get them.
But I wouldn't sort of see, I
should've just said wooden sword.
And we would have been good in
that, in, and then through his life,
he traveled and he did all kinds of
things and he fought 60 sword duels.
I used to think that they were all to the
death, but they actually weren't right.
There's some of them were just like,
if you could submit you, you know,
the opponent could just say, Yup, you one,
and you could agree you beforehand what
the rules of engagement would be. Oh,
okay. So they could have a discussion and
determine the extent to which you could
inflict damage on the other person.
So they weren't all to the death.
They could have a, basically
a gentleman's agreement, like,
let's not kill each other today.
It's only do this one,
two broken bones and handicapping.
How do you gotta do you gotta
that's a hardcore conversation.
Yeah. But how do you, how do you
come off not looking like the wolf?
You don't want to be the first one to
say, hey, let's just break it down.
Let's just break bones. You know,
you should just be like, no,
we'll go to the death. That's it.
That's weird. Uh, but yeah, so,
but a bunch of them war to the death,
a lot of them were to the death and again,
um,
that then he got done with that,
all that fighting and he
wrote the book of five rings.
He also wrote a book or up
like steps called Dual Dakota.
Close Japanese has this,
this stuttered content.
And for people who were wondering,
why am I the Japanese conciliary
it's because I lived in Japan.
It's my first trip overseas ever,
uh,
from 15 to 16 as an exchange
student where I was the only knot.
I was the only American
in a a 5,000 person,
Japanese high school where I also wore
a uniform and did judo and lived with a
Japanese family for an entire year.
So that is why I'm commenting
on Japanese dope. Godel dope go.
[inaudible] is a alone coal is to walk,
let's say Dole is wage.
It's the same goal from judo
or [inaudible], which is way,
so it's the way of walking alone.
Yeah.
And I should have said that.
That's the reason why I thought it would
be awesome to have you on here because
you do have this knowledge not only
of the language, but of the culture.
And you did this, you've done a
bunch of weird stone. Cool. Yeah.
Y'All was [inaudible]
Japanese horseback archery,
which by the way also pretty dangerous.
Turns out. Yeah. And so that's what,
that's why I wanted to have you on here
because you've got massive amount of
knowledge that I don't have.
So again in that,
that Duco close enough. We're
going with it. Let's roll with it.
This is covered in podcast 80 as well.
And also this is a spoiler alert and I
guess I should do this every time I do a
book cause I do books on here a lot and
I always tell what's going to happen.
But for this one,
this is a spoiler alert because the book,
it does have the most epic ending.
I think it most be,
it might be the most
epic ending of any book.
I honestly think that it might be
that and we are going to cover it.
So if you want to read this book then
and we gave you about a year to read it,
but if you haven't read it yet,
maybe you're not going to read
it and you should just listen.
But if you do want to read the book
and get the full satisfaction of it,
then stop right now and then go read
Musashi. Take another year to read it,
which is a thousand pages long,
and then come back and listen to us.
So can I say one thing?
Absolutely.
This book
and way we can get back into some of
the history, but I bought this book.
I have a paperback version decades ago
in Tokyo at a bookstore called Kinokuniya
in Shinjuku. It's a huge bookstore.
It's, I want to say at least four floors,
maybe six or seven.
And I carried it around giving myself
scoliosis for years and years because I
was so intimidated by this thing.
It's, it's a few inches thick.
The paper is like onion skin. And
I was like, Oh God, I just can't.
Every time I pick it up, it's, Oh God,
I can't get into this. Once I started,
I could not put it down and I finished
it in a couple of days. I mean, it's,
it's that
good. So it's don't be
intimidated by this by the size.
It's not, it's not as much of a, a
slog as you would expect once you,
once you get into it, you just
get sucked in. And the reading.
The writing is beautiful. It's
very clean, very clean writing.
And the story is, that's another
thing I should say too, is that,
so there's a bunch of intertwining
narratives in there about a bunch of
different people and
characters and the AA.
They all are interesting and impactful
and they all add to the story.
Obviously for a couple hour podcasts.
We can't get into all of those. And,
and really we'll be hitting like this,
this the main plot line I guess. But
there's all these other things that are,
that are going on that we're just
don't have time to touch on that are,
that are really great to read about.
And there's so many,
if this guy would have been
a screenwriter, oh my God.
Yeah. The dialogue alone.
The book worth it. Yeah. It's,
it's just a great book and
that's that.
Um,
I guess we might as well get into
it a little bit. And when we did,
when I did podcast 80
with a book of five rings,
I started with the beginning of this
book and I said, when I did that,
that when we do this book,
I'm reading it again cause it's so legit.
Uh, so he Rigo Taqa Zone.
Alright, Tuck Hazel,
Hazel [inaudible] lay among the corpses.
There were thousands of them.
The whole world's gone crazy.
He thought dimly a man might as well
be a dead leaf floating in the autumn
breeze. He himself looked like one of
the lifeless bodies surrounding him.
He tried to raise his head, but could
only lift it a few inches from the ground.
He couldn't remember ever feeling so weak.
How long have I been here?
He wondered,
flies came buzzing around his head.
He wanted to brush them away,
but couldn't even muster the energy
to raise his arm. It was stiff,
almost brittle like the rest of his body.
I must have been out for quite a while.
He thought wiggling one finger at a time.
Little did he know he was wounded with
two bullets, lodged firmly in his thigh.
Low dark clouds shifted ominously
across the sky the night before,
sometime between midnight and dawn,
a blinding raid had drenched
the plane of Second Shahara.
It was now past noon on the 15th of the
ninth month of 1600 though the typhoon
had passed now and then fresh torrents
of rain would fall on the corpses on the
tick. Asos up turned
face. Each time it came,
he opened and closed his mouth like a
fish trying to drink in the droplets.
It's like the water they wipe a
dying man's lips with he savoring
each bit of moisture cause head was numb.
His thoughts,
the fleeting shadows of delirium,
his side had lost.
He knew that much.
How do Yaki?
Supposedly an ally had been secretly in
league with the eastern army and when it
turned on Mitsunari
his troops at twilight,
the tide of the battle turn to
okay,
he then attack the armies
of the other commanders.
You Kita Shimazu Konishi and the collapse
of the Western army was complete and
only half a days fighting.
The question of who would henceforth
rule the country was settled.
It was Tokugawa Ieyasu the powerful,
he dies demo images of his sister and the
old villagers floated before his eyes.
I'm dying.
He thought without a tinge of sadness,
is this what it's really like?
He felt drawn to the piece of death,
like a child mesmerized by a flame.
So that's how the book kind of kicks off.
And
this guy was just born on the battlefield
basically and is fighting in these
savage battles as, as, as a kid,
as a kid. Um, and I,
I think it's interesting that you start
the book where a guy's about to die,
you know,
and I think that's,
there's something significant to that
and it's not the only time in the book
where he's about to die. He,
he faces these bad situations
over and over again.
And
again, we just have to fast forward
through massive chunks of this book.
And I was just going to make one comment.
Absolutely.
There's people who are wondering
why we're saying Tuck Zol.
So talk is all is,
is represented by the same two characters
that can also be read as Musashi.
So there are different
readings for characters and
Japanese depending on if they
are adapted Chinese readings
or native Japanese readings.
So Musashi is the,
what would be called the,
the [inaudible] or the Japanese
reading and talk is all same.
Two characters would be the
Chinese reading basically,
I mean the Chinese origin reading,
which is called on Naomi.
So it's the same person talk,
Gisele and then Musashi,
the Japanese and Chinese
characters related linguistically,
they are very, very similar. So the uh,
the Japanese took Chinese characters,
which they call congee and they converted
them into to what are referred to as
silver berries. So we have an alphabet,
a, B, c, d. We have vowels and consonants.
In Japanese,
they have what are called silver.
Barry's meaning they are syllables instead
of individual letters to have cocky,
Kooky, cool mommy, mommy
mill saw sheet. The so,
and uh,
which is part of the reason why Japanese
have so much trouble with almost every
language. They kinda got robbed
when like the gods were handing out.
Sounds so they have trouble with a
lot of languages, including English.
But nonetheless, uh, the, uh,
those were simplified
versions of the characters.
So for instance, the character for, uh,
that you could say represents peace in
shine is which is an, so if for instance,
like, uh, east, the word in
Chinese would be untrendy.
So I've spent time in China as well.
In Japanese, it's unzipped, it's,
it's very similar.
And then the character for [inaudible] is,
has a roof and then a woman under a roof.
And that represents peace.
That was then modified into
the sound op, the vowel. Ah,
and uh,
there are fewer strokes in that.
So that's some of the framework
for the Japanese writing systems.
If two syllable trees and then the
Chinese characters that they use,
the languages are not mutually
intelligible though, are they? Not at all.
Now there are certain words that are
not terribly close,
but maybe what you would find say
between Portuguese and Spanish and drive,
for instance. So you would
have a word, like a telephone,
which is literally a electric
talk, which is, you know,
and even electricity as cloud. And a
dragon underneath. It was kind of cool.
But anyway,
the,
that's they wa in Japanese Dm Guac and
Mandarin and then Joan Quad Korean,
because a lot of the words in Korea,
we're also borrowed from the Chinese
characters. Uh, but beyond that,
the grammar, everything else is
completely, completely different.
And W I think are actually
in here cover where he gets,
where he comes up with a new name or when
he decides to take the new name. Yeah.
So the guy that I'm talking
about in the beginning,
as Tim just pointed out
that his Musashi Tuck,
Hazel Hazel, it's a tough one.
The zone, the zone is a long,
so tuck, Tuck, Azule Taco zone
there. We got his Musashi. Exactly.
And you'll find that out shortly for
those people who are watching the video.
That is talk,
Gisele and Musashi,
those two characters. Okay.
Anyway, what, so what does that,
what does the rest of that thing and
say it's a bookmark. What does this,
this is the wrapping that was put around
the cover of this book in the English
section in Kinokuniya bookstores so
that people could figure out what the
content was without, without having
to read the back jacket in English.
So this is, you know, Musashi, Loomio,
orthotic coke, honeymoon, got glue,
so on and so,
and then Miyamoto Musashi and
then Yoshikawa age is all here.
And then a little description on the back
are there just copies of this everyday.
Everyone read this in Japan.
This,
I mean
he misremembering this,
but I remember at the time looking
at this book and reading about the,
as they would call it, on the back
cover of the best selling Samurai epic.
And somewhere reading this
book has sold something absurd,
like 20 million plus copies in a
country of a, whatever it might be,
150 million people.
That seems now that I've been
through the book process a few times,
like it cannot be true,
but it is a very, very,
very famous book in Japan. And
everybody's going to know who, uh,
they would say Miyamoto Musashi.
They would give the last name first.
Everyone is going to know who this guy
is and they have hundreds of comic books
and so on.
Historical comic books,
fictional comic books that
have been written about
Misashi.
Yeah.
And this thing originally came
out in a series, I think in, um,
1939 or 1933 or 1935
or something like that.
And it originally came out as a series,
I think in like a magazine or something.
You're going to get it right. Quite
possibly could be the case. I don't know.
I'm pretty sure.
So we'll go with it.
All right. Now we are going to
get to a point where, again,
we're fast forwarding it
and at this point, Musashi,
she's been accused of murder and he's
been hung from a tree and Tequan Tequan
yeah.
Pakwan yes.
Talk one is sort of this kind of traveling
priests on any sort of counseling and
advising and yeah,
just sort of counseling and
advising Musashi that at this point,
and he's kind of wandering around as
Musashi has now been accused of murder and
hung up up in this tree where they're
gonna eventually kill him. And here we,
here we go, go into the book, Talk One,
save me techie.
Zos Cry for help was loud and plaintive.
The branch was beginning to tremble as
though it as though the whole tree were
weeping. I want to be a better
man. I realize how important it is,
what a privilege it is to be born human.
I'm almost dead,
but I understand what it means to be
alive and now that I know my whole life
will consist of being tied to this tree.
I can't undo what I've done.
You're finally coming to your census
for the first time in your life.
You're talking like a
human being. I don't want
to die. Taka Zilla cried.
I want to live. I want
to go out. Try again.
Do everything right this time his
body convulsed with is sobbing on.
Please help me. Help me.
The monk shook his head.
Sorry, Taco zone. It is out of my hands.
It is the law of nature.
You can't do things over again.
That's life.
Everything in it is for keeps everything.
You can't put your head back on
after the enemy's cut it off.
That's the way it is. Of
course, I feel sorry for you,
but I can't undo that rope
because it wasn't me who tied it.
It was you.
All I can do is give you some advice,
faced death bravely and quietly say a
prayer and hope some someone bothers to
listen and for the sake of your ancestors,
tech azo have the decency to die
with a peaceful look on your face.
The clatter of Taco Juan's
sandals faded into the distance.
He was gone and talk as
though cried no more.
Following the spirit of the monks advice,
he shut the eyes that had just
experienced a great awakening and forgot
everything you forgot about living and
dying and under the myriad of tiny stars
lay perfectly still as the night
breeze side through the tree.
He was cold,
very cold.
I mean obviously wrote a book called
extreme ownership where you're responsible
for your actions and you need to take
responsibility for things in your lives.
But this thing where he says, I can't
untie the rope because it wasn't me.
That was that tied it.
It was you.
You put yourself in this position and
that's, that's the way it is. You want,
your head is cut off.
You can't put it back on Musashi or Tuck.
Azul gets, he does crazy
stuff too, right? He's,
he's young and he does crazy things.
And one of the crazy things he does is
his sister's in some kind of jail or
something and he just like a
tax it and any loses and he,
they gets arrested and he gets
put in prison for three years.
And at this point he's getting released
from jail after he's been in jail for
three years. And again, obviously I'm the,
I just skipped three years
of this guy's jail time,
which actually is pretty
short in the book.
They don't spend a lot of time in jail.
Uh, but he's been in jail for three years.
He gets out and here we,
he's,
he's having a conversation and here we go.
[inaudible] smiled silently.
I want to wander about on my own for
awhile and then talk. Juan who's back,
that's where he's having the
conversation with. Sorry.
He says you should change your
first name to Tacoma interjected.
Why not read the Chinese characters of
your name as Musashi instead of Taco?
You can keep writing your
name the same as before.
It's only fitting that everything should
begin anew on this day of your rebirth.
Miyamoto Musashi. It's a good name, a
very good name. We should drink to it.
The following day, they both left
the castle. Musashi was talking,
Musashi was taking his
first steps into a new life,
a life of discipline and training in
the martial arts during his three year
incarceration,
he had resolved to master the art of war.
Okay.
Explain the, the first, the first,
last name thing. [inaudible] motors.
That that's a place, right? Or
is it, is it a, in this case,
in many cases it refers
to originally a place.
So my understanding is that Miyamoto
refers to whether it's a town or a village
or pro, not province, he would be
smaller where his family originated from.
It's not always the case,
but even if you look at English names,
you find the same thing,
right?
So it could have been an English
end in a lot of languages.
It often relates to an early vocation.
So Ferris for instance, comes
from Ferris, like f e r r o,
u. S like Ferris oxide iron.
Because way back in the day,
at some point my family worked with metals
and that's where the name comes from.
Uh, is Miyamoto the first name or the
last name? [inaudible] is the last name.
So similarly, the authors of this, the
author of this book, Agee Yoshikawa,
the Yoshikawa is the last name.
Yeah.
And why do I say Miyamoto Musashi.
Okay.
The Japanese always say
the last name first. Okay.
They say the family name first, except
for in this guy's case, eg what the,
so this is [inaudible] got it.
Yeah,
that makes sense. Yup. Making some
progress. So for instance, in jail,
very slow progress.
Intellectual Capability maxing out.
Yes.
In, in, in Japan for
instance, even as a young kid,
when you're talking to your friends,
you,
you would never, I can't recall even
once saying someone's first name,
you would just say, uh, boy, you know,
Yamamoto Polaka like you would,
so I'll call you Ferris. Yeah.
You called me with my case because
Ferris was psyche. Not Confusing,
but they knew I was American and
Tim like Teemu as they would say,
uh, we shorter. So they just called
me teemu. Yeah. Tim was on the team.
Can you get that in the military too,
where everyone kind of gets introduced
by your last name and everyone for a
while. Everyone just kind of calls each
other, you know, Willink, Ferris, Charles,
you know. Right. So, but that's how they
address each other pre, normally. Oh yeah,
the all the time.
Yeah.
With the exception of saying
my host family where I'm
dealing with everybody who
has the same last name, you
can get very, so then I'll
call them by their first names.
Check, check. All right, now
this book does have a
romantic interest in it.
I hate to inform everyone
and it's so it's,
it's absolutely worth coming
covering because it's the,
the way it gets handled
throughout is just freaking epic.
So his romantic interest is a woman named
Oh yes. See, um, Osu and he's,
again,
we can't cover the whole story,
but this is his romantic
interest and we will ease he's,
she's in and out of the story.
And the main point is that even though
he's desires her and wants to be with her
at the same time,
there's something that's more important
to him and that is the way of the sword.
So here we go. Back to the book,
Musashi covered her small white hand,
which was resting on the railing
with his own. Listen, he said,
plaintively I beg of you. Just stop
and think. What's there to think about?
I told you I've just become a new man.
I stayed in that musty hole for
three years. I read books, I fought.
I screamed and cried.
Then suddenly the light dawned.
I understood what it means to be human.
I have a new name,
Miyamoto Musashi. I want to dedicate
myself to training and discipline.
I want to spend every moment of
every day working to improve myself.
I now know how far I have to go.
If you choose to bind your life to mind,
you'll never be happy.
There will be nothing but hardship and it
won't get any easier. As it goes along,
it'll get more and more difficult.
When you talk like that,
I feel closer to you than ever.
Now I'm convinced I was right.
I've found the best man I could ever find.
Even if I searched for
the rest of my life.
He saw he was just making things worse.
I'm sorry. I just can't take you with me.
Well then I'll just follow along.
As long as I don't interfere with
your training, what harm would it do?
You won't even know I'm around.
Musashi could find no answer.
I won't bother you.
I promise he remained silent.
It's all right then,
isn't it? Just wait here.
I'll be back in a second and I'll be
furious if you try and sneak away.
Oh two ran off towards
the basket weaving shop.
Musashi thought of ignoring everything
and running too in the opposite direction
though the will was there.
His feet couldn't move.
Otu looked back and called remember,
don't try to sneak off. She smiled,
showing her dimples and
Musashi inadvertently nodded.
Satisfied by this gesture.
She disappeared into the shop
if he was going to escape.
This was the time his heart told him so,
but his body was still shackled by Otsuka.
Pretty dimples and pleading eyes.
How sweet she was.
Okay.
It was certain no one in the world
would save his sister or safe.
His sister loved him so much and it
wasn't as though he disliked her.
He looked at the sky.
He looked into the water,
desperately gripped the railing,
troubled and confused.
Soon tiny bits of wood began floating
from the bridge into the flowing stream.
Okay.
Oh, to reappeared on the
bridge in new straw, sandals,
light yellow leggings and a large
traveling hat tied under the Chin with the
Crimson Ribbon.
She'd never looked more beautiful,
but Musashi was nowhere to be seen.
Okay.
With a cry of shock,
she burst into tears.
Then her eyes fell upon the spot on the
railing from which the chips of wood had
fallen there.
Carved with a point of a dagger was
the clearly inscribed a message.
Forgive me,
forgive me.
I love how it measured.
His emotions are in the pros.
He clearly did not dislike her.
Yeah, that's heavy. That's like,
that's like, I love you. And
is it the speech? It is. It is.
But yeah, that is the, that is the
nightmare scenario for women right there.
That is it. That's an abandonment issue
is number one. And having spent, um,
you know, quite some time in the, in
the seal teams, you know, this, this,
this is a real thing. You know, guys,
they have to choose between
this girl and their job.
And of course some guys can
make it work and blah blah blah.
And I did a pretty decent job of making
it work. But I'm telling you, it's a hard,
there's a 90% divorce rate in the
seal teams in the military tie.
So this is a real choice that guys had
to make and it's, it can be really hard.
And that's just a nightmare scenario.
And,
and honestly what's jacked up is that
the guys are actually trying to do the
right thing. They're actually trying,
they're, they're looking at a girl saying,
look, you don't want to sign up for
this. Like this is not going to be fun.
And you know,
of course people fall
in love and they goes,
emotions start to take over ridiculously.
And,
and you know,
it's one of those things,
but that's a nightmare
scenario for a girl. Yeah.
And for a guy, I think this is the
weird thing, I can't speak guy girl.
I can't speak for girls cause I'm not one.
But for most guys,
they read that and they kind
of go, yeah, at least I do
get it. I mean, I'm, I'm echoes a softy.
He does. I've, I've been drinking the,
the Japan and Samurai Koolaid for so
long that I'm just like, oh, I get it.
Yeah. I bet. If we had, you know,
those little alum like meters
where people can vote. Yeah. Or,
or like this spike on the presidential
debates where things would be like,
people really agree with this thing.
If you had that right there,
and males between the ages of 18 and
35 we're hearing that. They're like,
yeah, yeah. Walkaway, dude.
That's what they're thinking.
Wouldn't surprise me.
Yeah. For the seal teams,
that's totally normal culture. Oh
yeah, Bro. You got to choose the teams.
You gotta choose the teams first, you
know? Oh, you didn't, you don't want to,
you know, don't want to put her through
this. So that's kind of messed up.
But it's the reality. Sorry.
Well, especially imagine if your,
your intention is to go dual
people to the death repeatedly.
I mean, the odds are not in
your favor. You eventually,
someone's going to be better than you.
What was that?
Do you have that section mark,
that you were reading about how he felt
about people that had gotten the upper
hand on him because that was
pretty epic. Ah, let me find it so,
and that way people don't have to listen
to 'em bad Japanese premise. Let's see.
Let's see. All right, here we go.
The adversaries he hit, I'm not going
to do as good a job of reading is Jocko.
He's bad. He's well-practiced. Plus he has
the audio book, Voice of Jocko Willink.
The adversaries he had defeated,
even the ones he had killed her half
killed always disappeared from his mind,
like so much froth,
but he couldn't forget anyone who got
the better of him in any way or for that
matter. Anyone in whom he sensed an
overpowering presence. That was the line.
I underline it. Anyone in whom he
sensed an overpowering presence.
Men like that dwelt in his
mind like living spirits,
and he thought constantly of how one
day he might be able to overshadow them.
Yeah, that's, that's deep right there.
Drive. And that's also ego issues clearly.
Oh yeah.
Those are people are hard to deal with
and when and unless you recognize that
it's your own ego that's causing these
problems cause a lot of people are so
intimidated by,
I've seen that many times where you know,
you get like a young seal that's a real
bad ass and he's coming up and they're
some of the, some of the senior seals
maybe that are also bad ass. You know,
basically you get two alpha males
in a room and it can be problematic.
And unless one of them real,
as the old guy realizes,
usually it's the old guy that realizes,
hey this is a young buck coming up.
What I should do is try and
help him instead of try and
keep them down cause I'm
jealous. And that's what Musashi's
has that attitude of, you know,
he does, he didn't care about the people
that are, that he beats. Yeah. Yeah.
He's like the Steve Jobs of Samurai.
Yeah.
Actually I was thinking
about this on your podcast.
It would be awesome if
you did. Like, if you,
if you did like the job's book and you,
you read parts of it and you've
thought about it, I thought,
I think that'd be pretty cool.
Yeah. You know, I've, I've, I've,
I've considered it because I've,
I've listened to
a lot of your episodes,
uh,
as you're going through books
and I have all my highlights.
Furthermore,
and you saw this earlier,
I showed you my index that I
created for your book field manual.
And I also have,
I noticed this is what I was looking at
is you're reading my own index at the
beginning of Musashi with the page numbers
and things that I found interesting.
So I have everything locked and loaded
and ready to go for all of these books
that I've read. I think it'd be awesome,
especially because like, for instance,
you know,
I do books about war primarily because
that's what I can relate to them the most.
But you know, if you were reading business
books and, and you were talking about,
you know,
what these people went through and,
and then you could relate it to what
you did and how, you know, it's just,
I think it'd be, I liked, I liked the idea
of biographies. I, because I recently,
not to digress too far,
but I interviewed Walter Isaacson who I
know actually who wrote the job's book
and because he just finished a new
book on Da Vinci, which is spectacular.
And Yeah, I actually noticed that book,
um, because it was out selling my book,
whatever. Walter, well
good for you all to,
we're going to go off the
rails for a second, but,
so every year or every time
I have a book come out,
there's unit Garton who writes cookbooks,
barefoot Contessa,
who for whatever reason always
comes out in the same week.
And then he's just like lining the wall.
She has her own walls from the bookstore.
So I'm like,
how am I going to compete against walls?
I'm trying to get an end
cap and then also on Amazon,
every time I have a book come out,
literally every time I took a screenshot
of it a couple of weeks ago and I said,
man,
this book is so hardcore,
it's so undefeatable giraffes
can't dance to children's book.
And it's, it's uh, it is,
it is always just slaying
my books on Amazon.
Fortunately not the same category for
the best seller lists, but uh, yes,
biographies and uh,
and going through those to tie in pieces
would also be fun because I could,
I could compare my mindset in state.
Uh,
my development at the time that I made
the highlights with my observations now
100%. And I think again,
I think that would be,
I think a lot of people would get a lot
out of it because you got something out
of it and then you get to look back on it.
You get three perspectives,
you get the person's
respected perspective,
you get your old perspective and
you get your current perspective.
That's pretty legit. Yeah, that's a lot
of growth and knowledge coming from,
you know,
pretty quick statement.
So I just want to read one more since
it's right across from what I just read,
the anyone in whom he sensed
an overpowering presence.
And I don't have the full context here
because I'm just looking at independent
highlights,
but
it appears that Misashi has
been approached by several
men in some environment
and they're asking him questions,
a small talk,
Musashi wondered why
they were taking up their time and his,
with their small talk,
it became apparent that he would
not find out unless he asked.
So the next time there was a break
in the conversation, he said,
presumably you came because
you have some business with me.
These lines of dialogue is awesome.
They feigned surprise at the very idea,
but soon admitted that they had come on
what they regarded as a very important
mission. And it goes on and on.
There's so many good lines in there.
So many good lines. Here's
a good, here's a good part.
Moving along in the story here. He
has throughout this thing. It's,
uh,
when,
when I was a kid and you remember you'd
watch what was the Saturday morning or
one day they'd have Kung Fu theater,
I think it was actually called Kung
Fu theater and on Kung Fu theater,
it was always these, you
know, my school against your
school and, and, and you know,
he got all that. That seems
neat, but that's real. Like
that stuff really happened.
And he had these feuds with
various schools of martial arts,
like you'd seen Kung Fu theater.
And in this particular one he had gone
and kind of whooped up on this one school
and then,
but like the leader wasn't there.
And so he writes a letter and here's
the letter that Musashi rights,
which is to
Yoshioka Yoshioka beautiful
name,
Yoshi, that isn't Yoshi, call it
character. What does Yoshi mean,
Yoshi? I'd have to look at it
saying, I, I, I don't recall off him,
but Yoshida Yoshida, this Yoshi that
Yoshi, no ya all that same Yoshi,
and this is Yoshioka. So here's what
Musashi writes the letter. He says,
I am told that you and your disciples
are searching for me. As it happens.
I am on the,
I'm now on the Yamato High Road.
My intention being to travel around in
general area of Egan [inaudible] for
about a year to continue
my study of sorts and ship.
I did not wish to change
my plans at this time,
but since I regret as much as you do
that I was unable to meet you during my
previous visit to your school.
I should like to inform you that I shall
certainly be back in the capitol by the
first or second month of next year.
Between now and then,
I expect to improve my
technique considerably.
I trust that you yourself will
not neglect your practice.
It would be a great shame if Yoshioka
Kempos flourishing school were to suffer
an a second defeat, like the one
that sustained last time I was there.
In closing, I send my respectful
wishes for your continued health.
Mostly Musashi,
so I love the little jabs.
You're flourishing school, wink. Ha Ha.
It's so jacked up, but yeah, that's
the old school talking smack, right?
Respect let's I kind of what they
do in the British parliament, right?
Or Hamilton if you see the play thing.
I haven't
seen it like with kindest regards,
after you basically say,
I want to meet you and do with you
and shoot you in the face with kindest
regards and wishes for your continued
health. You know, we've lost that.
There's something to that,
isn't there? You know, like,
can't you just have a feud and
still be respectful to someone?
I respect your intellect and your
capacities and yet I will stop at nothing
until I destroy it.
So this is another, a
dojo storm, which again,
this is a modern term that I think Jiu
Jitsu people created. I don't know,
did you ever use the term
go to heard that before?
I've never heard Dojo storm before.
Oh,
Dojo storm is when you take your
Jujitsu guys and you go to another,
and this happened it again in San
Diego, San Diego. Where we live is,
is it's gone through the phase
already of all the schools being all,
all, uh, uh,
battling against each other
and, and really the battle,
there's multiple reasons.
One of them is because back
in the day before youtube,
you could actually have moves that you
could keep contained in your school and
you could say,
hey look,
don't show anyone this because we're
going to use this in the next tournament
and we want to, which is exactly what
happened in Japan too, by the way.
So what's the school with these schools?
So you'd have secret moves will now,
honestly with youtube and
every competition is on
youtube and you can watch
anybody from any school and you can see
what moves they're doing and there's all
this online so, so basically
there's no more secret school. Hey,
you can knowledge anymore.
The other thing is economically at one
time it was don't leave my school cause
you're my student.
You're giving me 150 bucks a month
and so don't go to another school.
And what that did initially it worked.
You could keep your students,
but people realize that
if you want to get good,
you have to get out and train
with other people sometimes.
And so if you weren't going to let
me go and train it, other schools,
sometimes I'm not going
to train at your school.
And so they would actually end up losing
students by trying to keep the students.
So I think that's it kind of leveled San
Diego out and other areas that are high
concentration jujitsu because yeah,
it's because now it's, you know,
people will come and go and train at
different schools and everyone's cool and
it's,
it's just a much more mellow atmosphere.
And they'll last December in 2000 when
I first moved to the bay area and it was
training in Jujitsu and I walked into the
school to take my first class and they
had, it wasn't very well
written from a legal standpoint,
but they hadn't NDA a
nondisclosure agreement that
they had people sign so that
they would not teach the, the inner
workings and techniques of Said School.
Yeah,
exactly.
Has it used to be a lot tighter and I
think youtube pretty much is the thing
that destroyed that. Uh,
but, but back in the day,
the Dojo storms would take place,
which was we would go from one school
and go to another school that was,
let's say a school is saying,
oh, we'll beat these guys.
Are we have better Jujitsu? Oh really?
You got Better Jiu Jitsu? Cool. Hello.
How are you doing?
We're here to see who did.
Jujitsu is better and it's a Dojo storm
and show up and, and you, you know,
everything is determined on the mat.
That's a beautiful thing about, uh,
so this is old school,
a Dojo storming and this is
against Jose [inaudible].
Jose [inaudible]. I'd have to see you.
How's it spelled? H. O. Z. O. I. N? Yup.
That's right
here we go for a Dojo storm and
he's, he's, he's showing up.
They're kind of looking
for where the school is.
He's kind of like a little bit lost
looking around for where the actual school
is and there's a priest that he's
working with. When he reappeared,
the priest handed him a
registry and inkbox box saying,
write down your name and where you
studied and what style you use.
He spoke as though instructing a child.
The title on the registry was list of
persons visiting this temple to study
steward of the holy zone.
Musashi opened the book and glanced over
the names each listed to under the date
on which the Samurai or student had called
following the style of the last entry.
He wrote down the required information
omitting the name of his teacher.
The priest, of course, was especially
interested in that Musashi.
His answer was essentially the one
he'd given at the Yoshiko school.
He had practiced the use of the truncheon
under his father without working very
hard at it.
Since making up in his mind to study
an earnest he had taken has his teacher
everything in the universe as well as
the example set by his predecessors
throughout the country.
He ended up by saying,
I'm still in the process
of learning learning. Hmm.
You probably know this already,
but since the time of our first master,
the Joseon has been celebrated
everywhere for it's lance techniques.
The fighting that goes on here is a
rough and there are no exceptions.
Before you go on,
perhaps you better read what's written
at the beginning of the registry.
Musashi picked up the book,
opened it and read the stipulation,
which he had skipped over before.
It said,
having come here for the purpose of study,
I absolve the temple of all responsibility
in the event that I suffer bodily
injury or I'm killed. I agree to
that said Musashi with a slight grin.
It amounted to no more than common
sense for anyone committed to becoming a
warrior. All right. This way.
So that's the introduction
and that's actually cool too.
That's an old school Jujitsu
thing when you'd come in for the,
the other thing that would
happen is challenge matches.
And I don't know if you've seen videos
from the old school Gracie Academy at the
challenge matches, but those guys would
come in and sign a waiver like, Hey,
if you die, we're not really, we're
not liable. So the uh, the old, uh,
the gray market, black market copy
over copy, VHS of Gracie in action.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We had my,
my old teacher, Fabio Santos,
and he had videos of himself doing Gracie
challenge matches at the Gracie school
up in Torrance and he would play him
for us. And it's the same thing. Yup.
Sign your waiver and then you're going
to get your arm broken. By the way.
First I put Aql Lik Deanna [inaudible].
So if this point he goes into the
school and there's some bad ass,
he's not the head of the school,
but he's like their best guy and
he's up there kicking everyone's ass.
You say next and he's roughs
the guy up and kicks his ass.
Then next roughs that guy up next and
finally no one else wants to fight him and
here we go. This guy's name is og.
I gone a g o. N. O Gorman. Yeah,
I'd gone with an unusual, he's the guy
that's been rough and everyone up, is it?
Or is there no one else build are
gone now holding his practice.
Lance horizontally.
The brawny steward was comparing his
registry with the faces of the weighting
men. He poured at one? No, not today. I'll
come again some other time. How about,
you know, I don't feel quite
up to it today. One by one,
they backed out until Musashi Musashi
saw the finger pointing at him.
How about you? If you
please, if you please.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means I'd like to fight.
Um, yeah. And so he, he's going to go,
and I'm going to pull a couple highlights
out of this thing, but, but, but the,
this guy, if you, if you please.
So this guy had gone, he,
he immediately does like a practice run
at some board that he puts his lance
right through. And it's sort of like
an intimidation tactic, righty. Oh,
you want to train? Cool. Watch this.
He screams and he puts his lance
right through this, this, uh,
right through this thing.
And it's actually, there's a,
there's a, the old guy that had
brought him into that, it broadened me,
saw she's looking at him and saying,
Hey, don't be a fool. You look stupid.
That's not a board you're
about to take on. Meaning like,
you just killed the board,
the piece of wood. But that's,
this guy is not just a board.
Um,
but it's don't hit back. Yeah. And, and,
and paper targets don't shoot
back and they don't move.
That's something I've
said many, many times. Um,
Musashi then says after he does this,
you know,
like this crazy scream and puts his
glance through the wood. He says,
are you ready?
Now
back to the book.
This solicit to you drove a gone wild.
His muscles were like steel when he
jumped. He did so with awesome lightness.
His feet seem to be on the floor and in
the air at the same time quivering like
the moonlight on ocean waves.
Musashi stood perfectly still or so it
seemed there was nothing unusual about
his stance. He held his sword
straight out with both hands,
but being slightly smaller
than his opponent and not
so conspicuously muscular.
He looked almost casual.
The greatest difference was in their eyes,
Musashi's were sharp as a bird.
Their pupils,
a co clear coral tinted with blood at
gone shook his head perhaps to shake off
the streams of sweat pouring
down from his forehead,
perhaps to shake off the old man's a
warning wards. Had they lingered on,
was he attempting to cast him out
of his mind? Whatever the reason,
he was extremely agitated.
He repeatedly shifted his position
trying to draw out Musashi.
But Musashi remained motionless at God's
lunch was accompanied by a piercing
scream in the split second that decided
the encounter Musashi parried to
encounter attacked.
Yeah.
What happened at God's fellow priest
hastily ran over and crowded around him in
a black circle in the general confusion.
Some tripped over his practice and,
and went sprawling.
A pre stood up his hands and chest
smeared with blood shouting medicine,
bring the medicine quick.
You won't need any medicine.
It was the old man who had come in the
front entrance and quint quickly assessed
the situation. His face turns sour.
If I thought medicine would save him,
I wouldn't have tried to
stop him in the first place.
So that's it.
Musashi one shot,
one kill takes the dude
out. And um, interestingly,
here's the advice.
So that guy that had taken him in
is the actual master and he says,
uh, is your name Miyamoto
Musashi? That's correct.
Under whom did you study the martial arts?
I've had no teacher in the ordinary sense.
My father taught me how to use the
challenge in when I was young. Since then,
I've picked up a number of points
from the older SAML and Sam Rhine,
various provinces. I've also spent some
time traveling about the countryside,
learning from the mountains and the
rivers. I regard them too as teachers.
You seem to have the right attitude,
but you're so strong, much too strong,
believing he was being praised,
Musashi blushed and said, oh no,
I'm still immature. I'm always making
blunders. That is not what I mean.
Your strength is your problem. You must
learn to control it, become weaker,
which also fun to do. And I'm
thinking about doing this, uh,
when I reread this book in full again,
is to spend some time on
youtube watching yeah.
A high level Kendall competition
to see how fast it is. Yeah.
Just to get an idea of the,
how much can transpire
in the blink of an eye.
Is there a referee that calls
it as a kill shot? How does it,
how does it get scored?
There are referees. So
I had a chance to, uh,
to train in Kendo when I went back
to Japan about eight years ago,
something like that,
eight or 10 years ago.
And I trained at this place called the
Qa Kang and I still have the armor still
have everything. And you, you have too
much like calling your shots and pool.
You have to call your target a split
second before you hit it or as you hit it
and see what's it like
men, his head, uh, Dole,
his abdomen,
Colt is the gauntlet or the arm.
And then [inaudible] is a jab to the
throat, which is pretty nasty. Uh,
and you line up in such
a way the sword is,
the tip of the sword is basically pointing
at your opponents throat as you track
them.
And you can see,
but there are referees
in cases of any type of,
they're definitely referees
in cases of any dispute.
They're very rarely disputes,
but it's so subtle and the,
the,
the misses are so close, much
like really maybe high, really,
really high level boxing.
I mean when someone Perry's,
it's not like it's traveling a
foot to the side of their head,
it's just grazing the side of their
head and then they counter punch.
Then you see it in Kendo, the movements
just faster. So it's really wild to see,
get your bell rung when you get hit.
I expected because I saw the armor,
the armor seems pretty hard that you
don't, you absolutely get your Bell Rung.
Especially I remember my
first class and you know,
I'm bigger than a lot of Japanese guys.
Not all.
I mean there's certainly
some big Japanese guys, uh,
and I was more heavily muscled and
they're like, oh, okay. And there's,
and most of the, Jeff, this has been
my experience in Japanese schools,
whether it's judo, Jujitsu, Ken know,
otherwise spend some time way back in
the day with the pancreas guys and so on
before.
And then they really came to
the u s is generally speaking,
everyone's pretty cool.
I suppose this is true in the u s two
then there just one or two guys were like,
oh, foreigner in my school.
Okay, I want to ring your bell.
And, uh, there was one guy there who
wanted to, wanted to fight and I was like,
okay, because I figured like
my reflexes are pretty good.
But the reflexes of head
movement in Kendo, bad idea,
you always want to have
the sword in between, uh,
you and your opponent and
to protect the center line.
So if you start moving your head or your
shoulders in such a way that you might
say of Aveda Punch, you really expose
yourself. So I ended up getting a whacked,
not just on the top of the head but
behind the armor because your back is open
in the back of your head is open.
And so I ended up getting whacked like
on the upper traps and neck with these
Shinai, these bamboo
swords, which hurt I, those,
those absolutely will ring your
bell. So yeah, you feel it.
You're familiar with the dog brothers,
right? Yeah. Those, they bring it,
they really bring it, they're awesome.
I have nothing but respect for the dog.
But if you don't know what they are,
you can check them out on youtube.
But they do full contact,
simulated knife and stick.
And I think it started with stick
fighting started with stick. Yeah.
Start with a screamer. And my
understanding is they have the gathering.
I haven't see,
I was watching these videos at the same
time as watching the Gracie in action
videos. And I remember like, oh,
people were just learning what a
triangle choke was. It's like, Ooh,
I can show people in my legs.
I was a new thing.
And I remember thinking this video of,
I think it was the gathering where
you have salty dog and so on.
And the participants who come just have
to mutually agree on which weapons are
acceptable.
See definitely one guy with a garden hose.
And then another guy was like,
I Kendo sword with like the tip cut offs.
It's splayed open.
And then they would go at it.
And I remember this one point
I saw this guy pull guard.
You know the people are just going nuts.
Some people have lacrosse helmets on.
I mean it's like, it's
just bonkers, Mad Max.
And these two guys are going at it and uh,
one's clearly a wrestler.
He takes the guy down and gets caught
in a triangle and I'm like, oh,
I guess that's it. I was like, no,
that's not it. And the guy took his,
his escrima stick and took the end of it
and just shoved it right in between the
guy's ass cheeks. Great Way to
break the triangle. It turns out.
And then just getting,
then just proceeded to beat the living
shit out of him with a stick on the
ground. That's not fun. I don't
like that. Trying to offense at all.
Don't like that at all.
Um,
I think we're getting
into another just good.
He's,
he's about to meet up with these more,
more of these hustling
guys for some battle.
All the priests carried Lance's
blacks leaves, talked up,
they were ready for action,
apparently set upon avenging the death of
a gone and restoring the temples honor.
They looked grotesque like
so many demons from hell.
The Ronin formed a semicircle so they
could watch the show and at the same time
keep Musashi from escaping.
This precaution, however,
proved unnecessary from Musashi,
showed no signs of either
running or backing down. In fact,
he was walking steadily
and directly toward them.
Slowly pace by pace. He advanced looking
as if he might pounce it any moment.
For a moment there was an ominous silence
as both sides contemplated approaching
death.
Musashi's fleece face went deadly white
and through his eyes stared the eyes of
the god of vengeance
glittering with venom.
He was selecting his prey,
okay?
Neither the Ronin nor the
priest wears tents is Musashi.
Their numbers gave them confidence
and their optimism was unshakeable.
Still no one wanted it to be attacked,
wanted to be the first attacked a priest
at the end of the column of the Lancers
gave a signal, and without breaking
formation, they rust around to Musashi's.
Right Musashi, I am in. Shawn
shouted, the same priest.
I'm told you came while I was away
away and killed a gone that you later
publicly insulted the honor of the ozone
that you mocked us by having posters
put up all over town. Is this true? No.
Shouted Musashi. If you're a priest,
you should know better than to
trust only what you see in here.
You should consider things with your
mind and spirit. It was like pointing,
pouring oil on the flames, ignoring
their leader. The priest began to shout,
saying, talk was cheap.
It was time to fight.
They were enthusiastically seconded by
the and who had grouped themselves in
close formation and we saw
she's left screaming, cursing,
and waving their swords in the air.
They Egged the priests on into action.
Musashi convinced that the road
and we're all mouth and no fight,
suddenly turned to them and shouted,
all right,
which one of you wants to come forward?
All but two or three fell back a plate.
Taste each sure that we saw she's evil.
I was upon him to the two or three
brave ones stood ready, swords out,
stretched in issuing a
challenge in the wink of an eye.
Musashi was on on one of
them like a fighting cock.
There was a sound of a popping
cork and the ground turned red.
Then came a chilling noise.
Not a battle cry, not a curse,
but it truly bud blood curdling howl,
Musashi sword,
screeched back and forth through the air.
A reverberation in its own body.
In his own body telling him when
he connected with human bone,
blood and brains spattered from his blade
fingers and arms flew through the air
most of the time. Musashi wasn't
really conscious of what he was doing.
He was in a sort of trance,
a murderous dream in which body and soul
were concentrated in this three foot
sword unconsciously.
His whole life experience,
the knowledge his father
had beaten into him.
What he had learned at the sec of Jara,
the theories he had heard at the
various schools of swordsmanship,
the lessons taught to him
by the mountains and trees.
Everything came into play in
the rapid movements of his body.
He became a disembodied whirlwind mowing
down the heard of Ronan who buy their
stunned bewilderment,
left themselves wide open to his sword.
I'm trying to think of why
these particular passages,
but one of the things know
this disembodiment which
I talk about all the time.
Being able to be detached from what's
happening is so important as a person,
as a leader and as a, you know in
martial arts you have to do it too.
If you're getting so wrapped up around
the fought of what's happening you,
you won't make good decisions. But
this actually goes beyond it. This,
this is like getting in the
zone. This is, you know,
when you're not thinking anymore, and
I always say in Jujitsu, if you're,
if you're thinking about your next move,
it's too late.
That person's already
doing something to you.
But that idea of being disembodied and
being detached and not thinking about
what you're doing but just doing it is,
is epic if you can do it.
And, uh, we were, we were
chatting a little bit, uh, Echo,
you and I before we started recording
about Marcello Garcia in New York.
And I've spent some time with Martin
Marcello and rolled with Marcello and
I'm not by any stretch,
I would say good at Jujitsu,
but nonetheless had a chance to spend
some time on the mat with him and a
handful of other guys,
sweetest guy you could ever imagine.
For people who don't know the name,
I suppose it's fair to say that
Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson,
Wayne Gretzky of Jujitsu wrapped
into one. He's, he's just, uh,
kind of like the, the Kimura
after which the camera is named.
So who was a very famous judoka
and also really good at Jujitsu,
fought Helio Gracie people in Japan used
to say before Kimora know Kimora after
crew after Kimora, no, Q Moreau,
like a nonrecurring phenomenon and uh,
Marcello's I mean gotta be close to
that. I mean he's, he's really good.
And one of the things that you observe
with Marcello and Josh Waitzkin who cones
the school with him was very close friend
of mine and also considered a chess
prodigy. He was the basis for searching
for Bobby Fischer. He says that, you know,
Marcel was a nickname is the,
I think the king of the scramble,
but he doesn't view it as a scramble.
Uh,
and what,
uh,
what Josh was telling me is that
Marcello can basically see a move in and
movement in general in more
frames per second. So we're,
most people see position a transition
that is kind of undefined to position B.
He sees 30 positions in between a and B.
And you see that when a,
if you,
if you want to really see some wild stuff,
you can check out just to
look up the Marcello teen,
which is his brand of guilty
in which is really, uh,
it's,
it's so technical for something that
can be so sloppy when people don't know
what they are.
It's so tactical and he can catch people
in a guillotine from any conceivable
position that most people wouldn't even
consider a position. I've seen him,
I seen him catch people and Guillotine
people who weigh like 300 pounds and not
fat, 300 like big, big, big people.
And then they try to come around his
legs into saying north south position and
he gets them to tap when they appeared
to have him in a north south position.
Um, but he seems to be able to access this
same type of mind state at will. Yeah.
I mean obviously it has to do
with these training all the time.
I mean all the time and yeah,
all the time.
And he just has turns his mind off of
it and his body's working without them.
I bet you,
I bet you if you hooked up like brain
scan and you see what he's thinking about,
he's probably thinking about like
chicken for dinner or whatever.
You know what I mean?
Like these thoughts are just not there.
But that's how I feel when I have good,
when I could do good Jujitsu,
I come off the mat and I
don't, someone will say, Hey,
what was that move you did on me? I'm
like, I have no idea what I just did,
you know? I just have no idea.
I don't know what happened. And,
and sometimes if you're
thinking about something,
you might remember bits and pieces,
but that's what he's talking about.
And that section is like, hey, it's
not even, you're not even there. It's,
it's all the trainings there,
the things you've been instructed,
the practice that you've done,
that's what's there and that's
what's executing the movements. Yeah.
It's a beautiful place to be. Whenever
people talk asking me about meditation,
like do you meditate? Jocko
Mcgee do Jujitsu, you know?
Oh, I agree with that. Yeah.
I think of the brain. Yeah. I mean it's,
it's just present state awareness and
not endlessly thinking about whatever it
is that might occupy and distract you.
Otherwise it gives you that.
Actually somebody asked me that the
other day and I was doing an event.
The guy says, you know, how do you,
how do you recharge your batteries?
Like it just seems like you're
going hard all the time.
How do you recharge your batteries? And my
initial, I, I actually responded. I said,
look, I don't, to be honest with you,
I don't really recharge. I'm going,
I'm just going and there's this. And then
as I thought about it, I said, actually,
no, I'm wrong. I recharge all the
time. I'm solar powered, solar powered.
I moved myself to get energized, right?
And look the windup watch or whatever.
But no, the reality is
is I recharge myself, um,
through physical activity.
That's where I recharge myself is by
surfing in Jujitsu and working out.
That's the recharge.
So just to build on that,
because I think it's really important
people think of recharging as,
as physical rest,
but a lot,
if anyone has really gone through a very,
very stressful period in their lives,
whether that's the death of
a loved one or a breakup,
anything that you obsessive Lee,
think about you can not move for most
of the day and feel like you've run five
marathons.
So by getting out of your head and into
your body saying Jujitsu or surfing,
you're taking a break from these leaders
that we can replay that are what?
Drain the battery.
Yeah.
Yeah. I think it's, I,
you know, again, uh,
luckily the guy asked me that question
and I realized as I was answering it,
you know, first I sounded like
an arrogant jerk. I was that guy.
Although he's on auto need no recharge.
No, that's not true. Actually.
If I go days without training
or without working out,
I start to feel like crap and I, and how
do I recharge? I get home and I'm like,
oh, there's my squat rack and or there's
the mat and you can get on it and train.
So yeah,
that's
totally true. Totally true.
One quick story of that
Marcello, which also makes me,
you can tell Marcel was
20 for the rest thing.
Think about Musashi is a,
he's famous for being hard to find when
he gets called to the mat when it's his
turn to compete even at a
world championship level.
And he is almost always found because
Josh has had to track him down a few times
asleep like in between the
bleachers and Vic Marcella Marcella,
you're up and be like, oh, okay, cool.
And he'll like get up and stretch
and literally walk 50 feet,
like seven seconds later on to the
mat for the finals and the world
championships and just turn
it on and then destroy people.
And that's cool too. And I, I
don't know if I hit it in the book,
but that's one of Musashi's things
is Musashi would show up late,
he'd have duals and he'd show
up hour late, 15 minutes late,
20 minutes late and have that
person getting all frustrated.
Yeah, no, it's, I mean it's, I
was thinking about this because I,
I was,
uh,
I remember this about Musashi and I
was trying to think of how to explain
in a culture like in that period what's
showing up an hour late might equate to
in the US it would be like coming
over to meet someone at their house,
shaking their hand,
sitting down at the dinner table than
like getting up on the dinner table and
taking a shit right on there.
It's like,
and then asking them to clean it up
cause it smells bad. Like it would be,
it would be that rude. So of course,
and it also made me think of this book,
I think it's called winning ugly.
It's about tennis,
but it relates to this form
of psychological warfare
and like taking too much
time,
like in between serves and making your
opponent unnerved so that even if they're
technically superior, you can end
up beating them. And Soon Musashi,
it's the simplest trick in the book,
but he would show up late,
late and these people would
lose their minds. And uh,
and then if they're like, oh,
this guy always shows up late.
And then he'd show up three hours early
and scout the whole place out and then
kill everybody.
Good. Um, this was an interesting piece.
Here's another weapon and he's working
with this guy who designs weapons and
it's called the chain ball sickle.
So it's like the sickle and then a
chain and then a ball. But again,
this is reminds me of Kung
Fu movies when I was a kid,
but he's seen this and hear
this guy's name is bacon be a I.
K. E. N biking. Biking. Did you just
chime in over there at Aqua Charles? Yeah.
Why is that? Cause I know, but not on
letting you guys do anything. That's good.
Good.
Just be Japanese or something that you've
been holding out on me a little bit.
Yeah, I do like the idea of
calling him bacon though.
I might not have another kid.
I might even baking
in Hawaii. The pronunciation is
very similar. Biking, biking,
biking,
insisted.
You said you wanted to hear more
about the chain ball sickle.
I'll tell you everything I know, but let's
have a few drinks while we're talking.
When he will return with a Saki bike
and poured some into a heating jar,
put it on the fire and talk
to great length about the
chain ball sickle and ways
to use it to advantage in actual combat.
The best thing about it he told saw she
was that unlike a sort of gave the enemy
no time to defend himself.
Also before attacking the enemy directly,
it was possible to snatch his
weapon away from him with the chain.
A skillful throw up the chain,
a sharp Yank and the enemy had no sword.
Still seated. Bacon, Dem
biking demonstrated a stance.
You see you hold the sickle in your
left hand and the ball and you're right.
If the enemy comes at you, take him
with, take him on with the blade,
then hurl the ball at his face. That's
one way. Changing positions he went on.
Now in this case, when there's some
space between you and the enemy,
you take his weapon away with the chain.
It doesn't make any difference
what kind of weapon it is. A sword.
Lance wouldn't staff or whatever bike
and went on and on telling Musashi about
the ways of throwing the ball about the
10 or more oral traditions concerning
the weapon about how the chain was like
a snake about how it was possible by
cleverly alternating movements of the
chain and sickle to create optical
illusions and caused the enemy's defense
to work to his own detriment about all
the secret ways of using the weapon.
Musashi was fascinated when
he heard talk like this.
He listened with his whole body eager
to absorb every detail, the chain,
the sickle two hands.
As he listened,
the seeds of other thoughts
formed in his mind.
The sword can be used with one hand,
but a man has two hands and that's
where he gets this idea of uh,
for using two sorts when he fights.
And I'm sure you know more about that.
So yeah,
so he
originated as style that
has many different names.
Uh, I think, uh, there, there
are a few different of it.
I'm probably going to get this incorrect,
but there's like Nita Nietzsche I think
is one way to say it, uh, but the,
the form of having one long sword
and then the equivalent of say,
I would imagine in the military of of
uh, like a side arm, uh, like a pistol.
So you have your primary and then you
would have your, whatever it might be,
you know,
a Glock 19 or whatever.
And Typically Samurai would use their
primary and then failing that if it broke
or if it would, if they were disarmed,
then they would use their shorter sword.
And he would in some cases utilize
both simultaneously, which was very,
very highly,
highly unusual and requires a completely
different method of fighting because
the grip on the sword is very,
very particular.
When you look at say at Kendo Sword
and how it's positioned. Uh, if you,
uh,
if you have then two swords,
it requires a completely different
repertoire of technique. And I don't know,
I don't recall offhand if
they get into it in this book,
but we saw she was also an expert in,
in weaponry throwing.
So there were instances,
and I would have loved to have seen this
and I'm sure there's a video on youtube
of someone trying this,
but he would routinely throw his shorter
sword and also later on because he was
in a,
I don't want to skip too far ahead,
but he would also instruct in the use of
shooken, which are the throwing stars.
So he was an expert at throwing
weapons as well as wielding the sword.
Uh, and uh, it's,
it's a completely different school of
training that some people still use.
And Kendo at the highest levels.
I haven't seen it very much because I
think there aren't as many teachers.
Is that legal? It is legal
as far as I can tell. Yeah.
There were people who I've seen
demonstrated and you can find some video,
not much, but a little bit of video
of using one short and one long.
Uh, and it's, it's, they're
not a degree of difference.
They're different species all together.
Yeah.
That's weird.
Sometimes when I'm rolling Jujitsu and
you get sweaty enough and slippery enough
and it's, it's a, it's a little bit
of a different sport. Oh totally.
Like it's like you are not going to be
able to do this to me right now because
I'm just too slippery. And, and same
with g and Nogi and it's weird, you know,
of course I always tell people like GE
and Nogi they're different but they're
the same and,
and then it goes one degree further.
Cause when you get just
super slippery Nogi it's,
it's about the difference between ghee
and Nogi. Maybe not quite as much,
but another Marcello
story. Yeah. Can't resist.
So I trained with Dave Camp
Maria for a period of time.
Who is one of my favorite human beings
and just a sweetheart of a guy and a hell
of a competitor and also high level judo.
Yeah.
And so when he competed in Jujitsu,
most people were terrified of his standup
and they would kick their hips back
and then he would do a flying arm bar
and routinely used flying armbars on.
Everyone here uses a total beast to just,
I was on the competition circuit around
the same time as him and some of the
other guys we were talking about earlier
and they, yeah, they were killers.
So Dave went to New York and trained
with Marcel for a period of time.
And to me, I mean, Dave, he's a
high level competitor. Like I've,
I've never seen Dave thrown
around or anything like that.
And so he's telling me about his
experience and he's friends with Marcel,
but the experience of, of rolling Nogi
and I was like, oh, well that makes,
I suppose that makes sense.
I've heard so much about Marcello,
but once you put on the
gear was different game,
I assume because of all your experience
that you had. And he's like, no,
it was even worse. Yeah.
I find that with Dean,
my buddy dean, who is, you know,
world champion multiple times with no
[inaudible] and everyone thinks, oh,
well if you put the key on, maybe you
can neutralize them and stuff. No,
it's worse because you can't
move at all and he doesn't.
And it's not like he doesn't know
Jujitsu with g, he's savage is there.
Someone's really good.
It gives them more control.
They already have control over you.
Now they have even more control and
now they have handles. It's not fun.
Uh, do you got one you want to read?
You know? Yeah. I want to just,
these are,
these are things that I highlighted
when I was really just coming into the
professional world and felt like I
needed to toughen myself on a number of
different levels.
And this is one that I highlighted.
This is from fairly early in the book,
which means it's like the end of a
normal book early in the book and it's
talking about a period of
his traveling and he says,
or I should say it reads,
he stopped along the way to look
at several well known temples.
And at each of them he bowed
and said two prayers. One was,
please protect my sister from harm.
The other was,
please test the lowly
Musashi with hardship.
Let him become the greatest
swordsmen in the land or let him die.
Please test the lowly Musashi with
hardship. That's what he's praying for.
And that's what you'd think when you
were getting into the professional world.
You're like, all right, bring
it because you were scared.
You think you were scared
about what was gonna happen.
I knew that I had relatively
high pain tolerance and uh,
I could handle a lot of workload.
So I was,
I was preparing myself for several years
of being lowest on the totem pole and
suffering.
Got It.
But making up for our lack of experience
by just absorbing more punishment in
the form of just working longer
hours, work hard, doing more,
always doing more. And uh,
served me well at the time.
Got An idea for a book anyways,
I guess. Yeah, exactly.
And then when I disintegrated in self
imploded, I had an idea for a book. Uh,
yeah, there's a go. This
is another one. And uh,
it's referring to I believe
Musashi's writing and it says, well, his
writing has a certain childish quality,
but there's an appealing,
what can I say directness about it.
If I had a swordsman in mind,
I would say it shows spiritual breadth.
The boy may eventually be somebody.
I just liked that.
The childish directness.
Yeah.
Yeah. The good stuff. And again, that's,
that's what you were thinking
about yourself. Like, Hey,
at that time you were the young swordsman
coming up in the business world.
That's right. Having to
make things happen. Um,
there's a,
there's another fight scene here.
He called him fight scenes cause I
don't know, that sounds like a movie,
a Kung Fu movie.
Not that there's anything wrong with
Kung Fu movies cause some Kung Fu movies
are awesome, but some of them
are also cheesy. Sure. Um,
the, you're a movie professional
there. Echo Charles. Yeah.
I don't think he'd be called the scene
if it's in a book. Okay. I Dunno.
I Dunno. Is it not a scene if
it's in a book? It could be,
we could do this. It reads like a
screenplay. So if it were a screenplay,
we could call it a beat or
a scene. I think. Here's a,
here's a scene after an inner,
this is a fight with a guy named Dan Chin.
Shiro.
After an interval of two or three breaths,
Denson Chiro shouted Musashi.
He was well aware that the man standing
several feet above him was in a very
advantageous position. Not only was
he perfectly safe from the rear,
but anyone trying to attack him either
from the right or left would first have
to climb up to his level.
He was thus free to devote his entire
attention to the enemy before him.
So he's about to fight this guy. And
as you said earlier, sometimes he
shows up late. Sometimes he
shows up early. In this case,
he showed up early and he got an elevated
position, and so his enemy, Daesh,
Charo is sitting there looking,
going, oh, this sucks. I'm below him.
And he's protected from the
back and left and right,
and then Musashi says,
are you ready?
Musashi's question was calm,
but trenchant falling like so
much ice water on his opponents.
Feverish excitement.
Denson Searo.
Now God has first good look at Musashi.
So this is the bastard he
thought his hatred was total.
He resented the maiming of his brother.
He was vexed at being compared with
Masashi by the common people and he had an
ingrained contempt for what he regarded
as a country upstart posing as a Samurai.
Who are you to ask?
Are you ready?
It is well past the hour of nine did I
say I'd be here exactly at nine don't
make excuses. I've been waiting
a long time. As you can see,
I'm fully prepared now
come down from there.
He did not underestimate his opponent
in the extent of daring attack,
daring to attack from his
present position in a minute,
answered Musashi with a slight laugh.
There was a difference between Musashi's
idea of preparation and his opponents.
Denson Shiro though physically prepared
had only begun to pull himself together
spiritually,
whereas Musashi had started fighting
long before he presented himself to his
enemy.
For him,
the battle was now entering
its second and central phase.
At the Geelong Shrine.
He had seen the footprints in the
snow and at that moment is fighting.
Instinct had been aroused knowing that
the shadow of the man following him was
no longer there.
He had boldly entered the gate and
made a quick approach to the kitchen.
Having waken the priest,
he struck up a conversation suddenly
questioning the man as to what had been
going on earlier in the
evening edition sharp,
disregarding the fact that
he was a little late. He had,
he had had some tea and warmed himself up.
Then when he made his appearance it was
abrupt and from relative safety of the
Veranda he had seized the initiative.
So I guess I was wrong in this section.
He doesn't show up late but he or he
shows up late but he like gets to an
advantageous position without the other
guy realizing it, which is just as cool.
Did you find one? I've got so
many but this one, this one.
This one is good because it highlights
how profound is maybe
too strong a word but a
deep, some of the characters in
the book are besides Musashi,
because there are quite a few characters
in here and this is a teacher.
This is an exchange between
is as far as I can tell,
he's Imo and who's one of the teachers
or a PR prospective teacher and Musashi
and Musashi
has brought a letter that he
wants. He's, I'm wonder read,
which is some type of request
for instruction and cause
I'm on is ignoring both
Musashi and the letter and he says,
but just please read the letter.
I don't want to just
please read the letter. No,
I'm not going to read your letter. And
then it says, please read the letter.
I don't need to. And then massage.
She says, what's the matter?
Can't you read cause I'm an snorted.
And then massage. She says, well,
if you can read, read
it. This is what he says.
You're a tricky brat.
The reason I said I don't need to read
it is that I already know what it says.
Musashi says even so,
wouldn't it be more polite to read it?
And this is how the teacher responds.
Student warriors swarm here
like mosquitoes and maggots.
If I took time to be
polite to all of them,
I wouldn't be able to do anything else.
And that he continues.
I feel sorry for you. However. So I'll
tell you what the letter says. All right,
this piece right here, ah, it's just good.
This is the continuation
of that fight scene,
which actually goes on for multiple pages.
His technique is better than mine.
Musashi thought candidly,
he had the same feeling
of inferiority at Cole.
You Guy who castle when he had been
encircled by four leading swordsmen of the
Yazoo school.
It was always this way when he faced
towards men of the north of the Orthodox
schools for his own technique
was without form or reason,
nothing more really than a do or die
method staring at dead Chinchero.
He saw that the style Yoshi was you
Kempo had created and spent his life,
had both simply simplicity and complexity.
Complexity was well ordered and systematic
and was not to be overcome by brute
strength or spirit alone.
Musashi was cautious about
making any unnecessary movements,
has primitive tactics or refuse to come
into play to an extent that surprised
him.
His arms rebelled against being extended.
The best he could do is maintain a
conservative defensive stance and wait.
His eyes grew red searching for an
opening. He prayed to hace man for victory
and then they go through and it's just
dead silence. Snow accumulated on Musashi,
his hair, and then he kind
of breaks him down mentally,
um,
destined charros feet inched
forward at the tip of his sword.
His willpower quivered toward the start
of a movement to lives expired with two
strokes of a single sword first.
And we saw she attacked who his rear.
So a guy had snuck up behind him,
Musashi kills that guy and then
kills it's just another, um,
another great battle scene.
And the, uh, the eyes, they talk about
the eyes quite a bit in this book.
And I'll come back to Kendo where you,
something that's very uncommon in
Japanese culture, which is really intense.
Direct eye contact doesn't happen
a whole lot in Japanese culture.
Even in the martial arts.
In judo it's more of a relaxed gaze.
And you might come out first
and there's some yelling.
So you'll hear that quite a bit.
I don't know if non Japanese do it,
but in Japan when I was watching certain
people compete or competing myself and
you'd hear people and they come out and
after they bough they'll let out a bit
of a scream. But then it's,
then it's down to business.
And in Kendo you hear a
lot more vocalization and
really intense eye contact.
Are you trained to look at their
eyes? Yeah. Okay. So would you,
where do you look in wrestling?
In wrestling, and I should say,
I mean I was,
I was a decent high school restaurant,
had a good competitive record, but, uh,
I wouldn't consider myself
anywhere like a d one restaurant,
just mop the floor with me.
Uh, but I would typically
have kind of more of a soft,
uh,
I can hips type of,
I mean I'm always looking at
people's chest in every sport.
I'm looking kind of like naval and chest,
usually kind of watch it in the hips,
in wrestling. But in Kempo they teach
you to look at the eyes in Kendo.
Kendo, they teach you to look at the
eyes and are you looking for like,
to see what they're going to do? That's
where you're going to see their movement.
You know, there isn't any
explicit instruction and why,
but you communicate a
lot with your eyes and a,
so you can tell if someone's intimidated.
You can tell if someone's
angry, you can tell. Uh,
you can also throw people off.
So for instance,
I mean you have Mendel Colt Day and all
this stuff. You have the targets, right?
And what I realized pretty
quickly is that much like in say,
boy ty on Thai kickboxing,
one of the oldest tricks in
the book, which is really,
really unpleasant if you
happen to get caught with it,
is particularly since I ball up to say I
got caught with it when I went to Japan
because I want it to also
cross train in striking.
And so I went to a number of schools
including place called [inaudible] and
kindness is, it's at the end of it like
Coldwell [inaudible], this, this con,
whatever it is, that sort of
place of practice, right? And,
uh,
first time I sparred someone in the,
in the karate schools in Japan,
like Gilchrist g and, and so on,
they don't have head contact with
the fists, but it's bare fisted.
So you're punching each other
in the chest and body and so on.
And this guy was wailing on my legs.
He was just like hitting me with these,
these,
uh,
roundhouse kicks to the legs and I
had never even seen like kicks before.
So I was punching him right in the chest,
just below his collarbone,
right his throat.
And then punching him in the stomach
and he was kicking me in the legs.
I was like, hey bro, like I'll do this
all day long. And so punching the Jasmine,
I had to skip school the next
day cause I couldn't walk.
But the trick in Moy Tai that you see a
lot is like, look at the leg low kick,
look at the leg, low kick, look at
the leg, low kick, look at the leg,
low kick and still it until it really
starts to hook hurt and then look at the
leg head kick. And you see a lot
of people get knocked out that way.
So when Ken know you can do something
very similar where you're sort of
telegraphing deliberately with your
eyes and going for a certain target,
you get parried you do that four or five
times and then you telegraph the same
way and go for a different target. Yeah.
Uh, but yeah, the eye contact is, was,
it's really, it's really
intense. And if you watch,
Kendall won't say youtube and
imagine what the eye contact is like.
If their eyes are like wide
open staring at each other,
it adds another layer of flavor
to the entire experience.
And then you can read a passage like this
and you're like, Oh God, I can see it.
And it's opposite of Jujitsu where you
don't really look at the person. Yeah.
It's almost like the little unwritten
rule. Like don't know why contract. Yeah.
Those gazing lovingly into someone's
eyes like purposefully when I'm trying to
really mess with someone,
you know,
I just look right at him like
and shake my head very suddenly.
And you probably noticed that they never
really look at you unless you do it
super deliberately.
Like if you try to roll with
someone when you were with someone,
try like notice where they're looking.
It's almost like they're just blank.
The blank. Yeah. Just,
I mean that's a weird thing too is with
Jujitsu you don't even have to use your
eyes. Like I used to notice, I
don't notice it so much anymore.
I used to notice if someone
was in a good position on me,
I would actually close my eyes. I started
viewing it like I was not, it was,
it wasn't smart like I was
doing it to relax myself.
Someone gets in a good position.
I just close my eyes cause you,
you know where they are.
They're freaking, you know,
on your back or they're across the side,
you know exactly where they are.
But I would just close
my eyes to kind of relax.
I don't do it anymore cause it
seems like a bad idea. Right.
Why would you close your eyes? Stupid.
It burns a lot of energy though.
I remember doing training with Laird
Hamilton who's one of the most famous big
wave surfers of all time. If anyone
hasn't seen the documentary riding giants.
Oh my God. Yeah. Go see that.
The invention of tow in surfing,
holy God.
And he leered is a beast.
I mean he's one of the most incredible
physical specimens I've ever seen.
He's in his fifties and just wipes the
floor with like first round draft picks
routinely, uh, in terms of workouts.
And he likes to do a lot of
underwater training with weights.
And he's devised all of
these original exercises,
like there's one called ammo
boxes where you hold a Dumbbell,
he holds a 50 pound dumbbell to his chest
and then swims across the surface of
the pool or just slightly
submerged with one arm. Uh,
and then does all manner of
different exercises. And his
wife, Gabby, Gabby Reece,
who is also a world class athlete
of her own right, said to me,
relax your eyes because under water,
when I'm holding like two 50
pound dumbbells, understandably,
my eyes are bugging out
of my head and she's like,
you're burning too much energy.
She's like,
try relaxing your eyes and I could
hold my breath for another 10,
15 seconds just by relaxing
my eyes. Uh, and just,
just another side note that's related
and I think relates to a lot in this book
also, not just Jujitsu
is in, uh, in tango.
I'm making it a point to bring up tango
every time we talk publicly about cool,
let's be the best female dancers very
frequently close their eyes because if
they try to read the males movement in
order to respond, it's already too late.
If they tried to do it visually,
it's too late.
And I think that with
a lot of martial arts,
certainly that in
particular with grappling,
I mean your body is always going to sense
it before your eyes can interpret it.
And that's why I was doing it originally.
Yeah. Much like the female tangle.
I remember Greg had a drill where you'd
start back to back and said, okay,
you've got to close your eyes.
Just kind of trust you gotta
close your eyes and then grapple.
And I remember doing it and think,
oh, that's not that much harder.
It's like as long as you're
already connected with the guy,
it's not that much harder.
Yeah.
So speaking of tango dancing and women,
here's, uh, he, he again,
Ohsu is in and out of the book and at
this point he is heading to a battle and
the odds are against him.
And Ot wants to go in with him and
she actually wants to die if he dies,
and so he's having a conversation
with her and here we go.
Don't be a fool oh two he
suddenly blurted. There's no
reason why you should die.
The strength in his own
voice and the depth of his
feeling surprised to even him.
He's one thing from you to die
fighting against the Yoshi.
This not only is it right for a man who
lives by the sword, die by the sword.
I have a duty to remind those cowards of
the way of the Samurai your willingness
to follow me to death as deeply touching,
but what good would it do?
No more than the pitiful
death of an insect.
Seeing her burst into tears,
he regretted the brutality of his words.
Now I understand how over the years I've
lied to you and I've lied to myself.
I didn't intend to deceive you
when we ran away from the bridge,
from the village or when I
saw you at Hunada bridge,
but I did by pretending to
be cold and indifferent.
That wasn't the way I really felt.
In a little while, I'll be dead.
What I'm trying, what I'm about to
say is the truth. I love you. Oh Tzu.
I throw everything to the four
winds and live out my life with you.
If only after a moment's pause,
he continued in a more forceful vein.
You must believe every word I say because
I'll never have another chance to you.
This I speak with neither
pride nor pretense.
There have been days when I couldn't
concentrate for thinking about you nights.
I couldn't sleep for dreaming
of you. Hot, passionate dreams,
Otu dreams that nearly drove me
mad often have hugged my palate,
pretending it was you.
But even when I felt like that,
if I took out my sword and looked at it,
the madness evaporated
and my blood cooled.
Her face turned toward him. Tearful
boat as radiant as the morning glory.
She started to speak,
seeing the fervor in his eyes,
her words caught in her throat and
she looked again at the ground.
The sword is my refuge.
Anytime my passion
threatens to overcome me,
I forced myself back into the world of
swordsman ship. This is my fate. Ohsu.
I'm torn between love and self discipline.
I seem to be traveling on two paths
at once. Yet when the past diverge,
I invariably managed to keep
myself on the right one.
I know myself better than anyone does.
I'm neither a genius nor great man.
He became silent again despite his
desires to express his feelings. Honestly,
his word seem to be concealing the truth.
His heart told him to be even more candid.
That's the kind of man I am.
What else can I say?
I think of my sword and you disappear
into some dark corner of my mind.
No disappear altogether.
Leaving no trace at times like that.
I'm happiest and most
satisfied with my life.
Do you understand all
this time you've suffered,
you've risked your body and soul and
a man who loves his sword more than he
loves you.
I'll die to vindicate my sword,
but I wouldn't die for
the love of a woman.
Not even you as so much as I'd like to
fall on my knees and begged forgiveness.
I can't.
Yeah.
Another speech.
You another scene that most women
would rather not go through. Yeah.
And it's another, I, again,
I know I don't relate to every normal
person at all in very little ways,
but like when I read that, I'm always
like, yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
And I've been married for 20 years to
an awesome woman. And uh, but yeah,
when I hear that, I just think, yeah,
that's how you do it, right? Hey, look,
every time I would start thinking about
you, I just look at my rifle and be good.
I want us, I want to, I want
to chime in and get something,
another one that is not chronologically,
yeah, sorry. We're out. We're out of sync.
Oh, it's okay. But the ones that I
underline tend to be universally,
I think universally applicable in
some ways. Yeah. So to the four,
this is a apparently a discussion about
some type of battle and they're going
back and forth.
Uh,
all right, so this is Musashi then.
What else can I do? But challenge him?
I realize of course that even if I do,
he'll probably refuse to
come out of retirement.
So I'm challenging this whole
castle to a battle instead.
A battle of course, the four. Uh,
and then here we go.
So his,
his arms still held by cause
Eiman and Deb Uchi and massage.
She looked up at the sky,
there was a flapping sound cause an eagle
flew towards them from the blackness
enveloping Malka soggy,
like a giant shroud.
It's silhouette hid the stars from view
before it glided noisily down to the
roof of the rice store house.
And then this is the part that I
highlighted to the fore retainers.
The word battle sounded so
melodramatic as to be laughable,
but to Musashi at barely suffice to
express his concept of what was to come.
Yes, yes. This part. So,
so Musashi's it had this,
another clan,
another group that he's
been battling with and the,
the senior guy in the family,
the senior guy from the school died or is,
yeah, he's died. And this 13 year old
boy is now the senior guy in the family.
His name is again judo
and he shows up.
So he's challenges of,
again,
he challenges all these people to a fight
and he shows up and they show up and
he gets there.
It's by some tree
and of course it starts off Musashi.
You're late. Cried a horse first. Pride,
a hoarse voice.
You took a shit on my dinner table.
Many took encouragement from Musashi's
declue declaration that he was alone
believing it was a trick. They started
looking around for Phantom seconds,
allowed twisting off to one side.
Allowed was followed.
A split second later by the glint of
Musashi sword flashing through the air.
Oh,
someone had shot an arrow.
The Arrow aimed at his face broke
half falling behind his shoulder.
The other half, the other half
near the tip of his lowered sword,
or rather where his sword
had just been from Musashi,
was already on the move.
His hair bristling like a lion's mane.
He was bounding toward the shadowy form
behind the spreading pine getting Jiro
hugged the tree trunk.
Screaming help. I'm scared.
Ghazi Moan jumped forward. A howling
is though the blow had struck him,
but it was too late.
Musashi sword slice to two foot
strip of bark off the trunk.
It fell to the ground by can gyros,
blood covered head.
It was the act of a ferocious demon
Musashi ignoring the others had made
straight for the boy and it seemed
he had had this in mind from the,
the assault was of a
savagery beyond conception.
Can Gyros death did not reduce the Yoshi
goes Yoshi oak is fighting capacity in
the slightest would had been nervous.
Excitement rose to a level
of murderer's frenzy.
And so that's how he kicks off the battle.
There's the 13 year old boy and he goes
right for him and cuts off his head.
So, um, and this is the
first time he starts using,
uh,
both sorts.
I think this is the first time onlookers
who had a clear view of him covered
their eyes and horror. This
is, as this battle continues,
most more ghastly still was the site of
the dead and wounded left in his wake.
As he continued his tactical
retreat up the path,
he reached a patch of open land where
his pursuers surged forward in a mass
attack. In a matter of seconds, four
or five of men had been cut down.
They lay scattered over a wide area,
more urban testimony to the speed with
which Musashi struck and moved on.
He seemed to be everywhere at once,
but for all is agile shifts and Dodgers
Musashi clung to one basic strategy.
He never attacked a group from
the front or the side always.
Oh bleakly add an exposed corner whenever
a battery of Samurai approached him
head on,
he somehow contrived to shift like
lightening to a corner of their formation
from which he could confront only
one or two of them at a time.
In this way, he managed to keep them
essentially in the same position,
but eventually Musashi was bound to be
worn down eventually to his opponents
seemed to be, seemed bound to find a
way to thwart his method of attack.
To do this,
they would need to form themselves into
two large forces before and behind him.
Then he would be in the
in even greater danger.
Okay.
It took them all Musashi's resourcefulness
to stop that from happening at some
point.
Musashi Jew,
his smaller sword and started a fight
with both hands while the large sword in
his right hand was smeared with blood
up to the hilt and the fist that held at
the small sword in his left hand was
clean and though it picked up a bit of
flesh the first time it was used,
it continued to sparkle greedy for blood.
Musashi himself was not fully aware
that he had drawn it even though he was
wielding it with the same
deafness as the larger sword.
So he's just getting after it with two
swords, you're going to eventually run.
Crowd cried a thousand voices,
you fighting by herself.
Ron Run while you can,
so he just crushes everyone.
There's another weapon that I don't know
if they talk about this book that he
was quite adept at using
as I understand it,
before he began fighting with two swords
and it goes by number of different
names in English. Sometimes it's
called the juts or a jetty. J U, t,
t, e in Japanese. It's the
Damian's 10 hands literally.
And it was a baton basically,
if you could imagine,
this will make sense in a moment.
If you could imagine a half inch thick
iron rod that's about 18 inches long or
12 inches long,
that then has what looks like
the clip of a say ballpoint pen.
Uh,
that is a little,
that is pulled away from that,
uh,
rod so that you have a space in between
this hook effectively and the rod palace
guards and so on would use these as the
equivalent of a police badge because
they were forbidden from having swords
in certain quarters because they could be
used to assassinate higher
ranking officials and so on.
And you could use that in
combination with a sword to,
uh,
effectively Perry or catch the bleed in
between those two prongs and then toss
it away or a twisted away or just use
it to temporarily arrest to the use of
that bleed and then pull your own
long sword and cut someone down.
And we saw she was very
adept as I understand it,
at using the day before he
started using two sorts.
You could also just use,
it just didn't like clubs.
It's a big, which I'm sure this
is exactly what it was used for.
Now, as the story progresses, you know,
he matures and and starts moving into a
little bit of a different phase and this
is kind of where the first time he starts,
he's,
he's wounded and he's traveling and
eventually he lays up for the night
after they had said good night.
Musashi went to his room where
he lay awake in the dark,
his eyes glistening
the way of the Samurai.
He concentrated on this concept as it
applied to himself and to his sword.
Suddenly he saw the truth,
the techniques of a swordsman.
We're not his goal. He sought the
all embracing way of the sword.
The sword was to be far
more than a simple weapon.
It had to be an answer
to life's questions.
The way of [inaudible],
Kenshin and dot j months master Nami
was too narrowly military to hidebound.
It would be up to him to add to it.
It's human aspect to give
it greater profundity,
greater loftiness for the first time
he asked whether it was possible for an
insignificant human to
become one with the universe.
So he's starting to uh,
like I said maturity.
Do you got one? Yeah,
I have one which I think is
philosophically very similar
and brings back one of
the characters that you
will about earlier. Uh,
and uh, refers to a lesson that he
learns from head learned from Taco on.
And here's how it goes.
It wasn't that he,
that's Misashi had forgotten the
lesson talk one had taught him.
The truly in that is the truly
brave man is one who loves life,
cherishing it as a treasure that once
forfeited can never be recovered.
He will knew that to live was
more than to merely survive.
That's the one that I highlighted.
The problem was how to imbue this life
with meaning, have to ensure that he,
that his day would cast a bright ray of
light into the future even if it became
necessary to give up that
life for a cause. If see if
he succeeded in doing this,
the length of his life,
20 years or 70 made a little difference.
A lifetime was only an insignificant
interval in the endless flow of time.
I think I've heard you say that quote
before like I'm to just surviving.
Living is not just surviving. That's kind
of wild and maybe this is where I got,
maybe this is what I think
I've heard you say the quote,
but I think I've heard you say that
concept before. Yeah, I have and maybe,
I mean this is where it incepted me
20 years ago. It was in massaging.
He ends up with a guy named EERE who sort
of a student of his and they're living
in the mountains and again,
I think this is, this is as,
as they,
as he's starting to mature and grow in
this area where he's going to where he is.
It's a mountainous area in Japan and for
those of you that haven't been in Japan,
it's got some incredibly beautiful,
beautiful mountains and incredible, yeah,
beautiful.
Even right outside
of Tokyo for people who are
ever thinking of going, ah,
there's a place called [inaudible] goal,
which is n I k k o and the o is long,
but Nico and they have
beautiful temples and mountains.
That is where I did the Japanese
horseback archery. Just as a,
as a side note on the Japanese horseback
archery. It was so great. So there are,
there are not, as you would imagine
in many schools for horseback archery,
but one of the s, one of the families,
one of the clans that still exists,
the Ogasawara.
So the Ogasawara as the family and then,
or do like Yeu is the school.
And that,
that do you comes up a lot in Musashi's
life. If you look at the history,
it's like such and such,
do such and such.
Do you like the school of
whatever and Ogasawara or do you,
uh,
Japanese horseback archery is what I
ended up studying with one of the members
of the Oga.
So out of family and we did it in Nico,
which a stunning place to train.
And, uh, just as a little,
a little, a little bit of context
on what exactly this means.
So the ceremonial version of Japanese
horseback archery entails a straight away
that is marked off in,
in the,
in my case with a metal rods like rebar.
So you effectively have these stakes
in the ground that are about three feet
high of rebar and like every five feet,
two parallel lines running,
let's call it 300 or 500 feet.
And you get on a horse at the very
beginning of this track in there,
three targets laid out,
uh,
equally distance over that 500 foot space.
Uh,
the first one probably comes up at about
a hundred meters and they're about the
size of a big dinner plate
and you're on the horse.
The saddle is wood, so you
don't sit on it. A, you do,
you squat above it and you have Tabi
on which of these splits socks and you
don't have shoes on in these,
uh,
stirrups that actually do not
enclose the foot, uh, around.
They didn't circle the foot.
They,
you stick it in kind of like a slipper
and you have a really wide stance.
And then you have a bow,
which is about six feet long,
in my case, in my left hand.
And the bottom of the bow,
you keep inside your thigh and then you
have arrows that are stuck into your
belt on your lower back and
your first Arrow is knocked.
And then you pull the line slightly and
lock it down with your index fingers so
that there's tension on him.
And then you have the reins and you,
you take off at a full gallop and then
you throw the rains down and you fly with
you gallop with no control.
The horse and these rebar
that are set every five feet,
keep the horse galloping in a straight
direction and you fire the first hour of
the first target,
and then you have to reload your
Arrow by reaching to your back,
pulling their hair out. And
there's a really tech, technical,
somewhat complicated way
of knocking the air very,
very quickly while you're riding a horse.
And then you intend to hit
the next two targets. Uh,
while you're yelling,
there's certain things you're supposed
to yell as you shoot at your target.
And Ah, it's, it's an incredible,
incredible demonstration.
And they do this at the temples in Nico,
which to me is what comes to mind in
terms of imagery when we're talking about
his experience in these
mountainous regions. And A, yeah,
lesson number one,
or you do not want to fall off and people
do fall off because if you fall off
your horse, you get trampled by
the horse and you hit the rebar.
Uh, but, uh, the reason I
brought this up is that,
uh,
everyone has seen restaurants say that
say established 1946 established 1987
established whatever.
And The Sun Pretty Young
Guy in his mid thirties,
really strong.
The bow I shot had maybe like
a 60 pound or 65 pound tension,
which is surprisingly difficult for
people who have not done much archery to
hold that at full extension
for a period of time. Uh,
especially on a horse,
it's like 65 is,
is 70 pounds is quite legit
on a longbow or recurve bow.
And he was pulling a bow that
was 120 pounds, like nothing.
And his jacket,
he had what,
what might look like a sort of a shiny
like 1980s like breakdancing jacket is
kind of what it looked like with like the,
the t like the elastic tube
portions on their wrists.
And on the back it said Olga
Sawada Yob Oussama established 1157
let's just like,
yeah this goes back away.
Did you hit the targets at the very end?
I did. Yeah. You got them. Cause you know,
shooting from vehicles is really, really
hard. Shooting guns from vehicles.
I mean it's just hard.
I can't,
I can't even imagine trying to do about
Arrow horseback on a wooden saddles.
Yeah, it's a, it's
definitely a different thing.
I was very surprised that I actually ended
up hitting the targets. But uh, yeah,
at the very end.
How long did you train it for?
Another thing I would not recommend a,
I crammed it into a week. I had a week,
I have a week to train and you know
how to ride a horse before I had some
experience.
On a horse,
but western and western
style for people don't know.
If you think Rodeo, uh,
where you're, you're,
you're effectively seated in the saddle.
It's kind of like the Harley
Davidson of, of horse riding. Thanks.
Your feet are out in front of you
or you hear your heels are dropped,
you don't post.
And uh,
Japanese is somewhere between, it's, it's,
it's closer to English where you'd be a
more elevated and the position is very,
very different. You're, you're effectively
an, almost a sumo stance. Like you're,
you're very much abducted,
like your, your groin is very,
very open.
So I was extremely sore.
I felt like I was doing like suspended
squat practice for hours every day.
So after a few days of that,
uh,
pretty uncomfortable and we'd lost three
days, I want to say to rain when we,
we couldn't,
it was too dangerous for the horses and
the humans to train doing anything in
those conditions. So we had about four,
I'd say four days of real training.
So speaking of rain there, up there, uh,
Musashi and EERE are up there and
well here we go into the book.
As autumn waned,
the insect voices faded into silence,
leaves withered and fell Musashi and at
Yorie finished their cabin because they
built a cabin and address themselves to
the task of making the land ready for
planting.
One day while serving the land we saw,
she suddenly found himself thinking it
was like a diagram of the social unrest
that it lasted for a century after
the own in war. Such thoughts aside,
it was not an encouraging picture.
Unknown to Musashi hot too hot Hotan go.
Hodra had over the centuries,
been buried many times by volcanic
ash from Mount Fuji and the tone river
had repeatedly flooded the flatlands
whenever when the weather was fair and the
land bone dry,
but whenever there was heavy rains,
the water carved out new channels
carrying great quantities of dirt and rock
along with it.
There was no principal stream into
which smaller ones flowed naturally.
The nearest thing to this being a
wide base in that locks efficiently,
sufficient capacity.
Artists are lacked sufficient capacity
to either water or drain the area as a
whole. The most urgent need was obvious
to bring the water under control.
So we've got this big piece
of land and he thinks, okay,
I'm gonna turn this into a farm.
He doesn't really know that there's no
pathway for the streams that when the
water comes down out of the
mountains and when it rains,
he doesn't know that there's
nowhere for it to go.
It doesn't make sense to the water.
So it just kind of floods everything.
I'm still,
the more he looked,
the more he had questioned why the area
was under undeveloped. It won't be easy.
He thought excited by the challenge posed,
joining the water and earth to create
productive fields was not much different
than leading men and women in such a
way that civilization might bloom to
Musashi. It seemed that his goal was in
complete agreement with his ideals of
swordsmanship.
He'd come to see the way of the sorta
new light a year or two earlier,
he had wanted only to conquer all rivals,
but now the idea that the sword existed
for the purpose of giving him power over
other people was unsatisfying
to cut people down to
triumph over them to display
the limits of one strength
seemed increasingly vain.
He wanted to conquer himself,
to make life itself submit to him,
to cause people to live rather than die.
The way of the sword should not be
used merely for his own perfection.
It should be a source of strength for
governing governing people and leading
them to peace and happiness.
He realized his grand ideals were no
more than dreams and would remain so as
long as he lacked the political
authority to implement them.
But here in this wasteland,
he needed neither rank nor power.
He plunged into the struggle with joy
and enthusiasm day in and day out.
Stumps were uprooted.
Gravel sifted land level,
soil and rocks made into dykes Musashi.
Ori worked from before dawn until after
the stars were shining bright in the
sky.
Now as he's doing this,
the villagers keep coming by and they say,
what do they think they're doing and how
do they think they can live in a place
like that?
And you're wasting your time.
That's what all the villagers are saying
to them. They've seen this for, you know,
since 1100 or whatever, they've seen this
place get flooded and he keeps going.
He keeps, you know, trying. And
every time he makes some progress,
he the,
it'll rain and everything gets washed
away or it'll get flooded and then he
thinks he's doing okay. And it's a big
snow in the mountains, so everything,
but then it falls
into every,
all the water comes down again.
So he goes on, he keeps working the
land, he keeps trying to make it work.
Back to the book.
Musashi carried on in his stubborn
struggle throughout the winter,
into the second month of the new year.
It took several weeks of strenuous labor
to dig ditches, drain the water off,
piled dirt for a dyke, and then cover
it with heavy rocks. Three weeks later,
everything was again washed away.
Look,
you already said we're wasting our
energy on something impossible.
Is that the way of the sword?
The question struck close to the bone,
but Musashi would not give. In only a
month passed before the next disaster,
a heavy snow fall followed by a quick
fall EERE on his return trips from the
temple for food inevitably war along
face for the people there rode him
mercilessly about Musashi's failure and
finally Musashi himself began to lose
heart for two full days and on into a
third he sat silently brooding and staring
at his field than it dawned on him.
Suddenly,
unconsciously he had been trying to create
a neat square field like those common
in other parts of the plane,
but this was not what the
terrain called for here.
Despite the general flatness,
there were slight variations in the lay
of the land and the quality of the soil
that argued for an irregular shape.
What a fool I've been,
he exclaimed allowed.
I tried to make the water flow where I
thought it should and force the dirt to
stay where I thought it ought to be,
but it didn't work.
How could it water's water.
Dirts dirt.
I can't change nature.
What I've got to do is
learn to be a servant to the
water and a protector of the
land in his own way.
He had submitted to the attitude
of the peasants. On that day,
he became nature's man servant.
He sees trying to impose his will on
nature and let nature lead the way,
while at the same time seeking out
possibilities beyond the grasp of other
inhabitants of the plane.
The snow came again and another fall, the
muddy water. Ooh, slowly over the plane.
But Musashi had had time to work out
as new approach and his field remained
intact. The same rules must
apply to governing people.
He said to himself in his notebook,
he wrote,
do not attempt to oppose the
way of the universe, but first,
make sure you know the
way of the universe.
As I was, uh, telling one of
my seal buddies about this,
we were talking about that you
can't, you can't, as a leader,
a lot of times people want to
change people. You want to change
and you, you just, you can't
change people. Right? I mean,
you can shift them and
vacant change themselves,
but when you try and
impose change on someone,
you try and make someone what you want
them to be. It's very difficult to do,
if not impossible.
I was talking about this one had a guy
in a seal platoon and he had potential,
right? But he had some flaws, you know,
he was a blowout mouth in that kind of
thing and just wanted like to bring them
along and tried everything. Beatings, um,
counselings, um, you know,
befriending, um, more beatings,
did everything and,
and you know,
he would like make slight adjustments
for a little while and then he'd go back
to just being the way he was. And
eventually I said, okay, well we have to,
that's the way he is. That's the
way this person is. And you know,
how do we work with him?
So he's working within the confines
of things that he can do and do them
acceptably.
But I think people get caught on the
idea that they're going to change people.
And it's really hard and you see this,
especially with people getting involved
in relationships with people that they
think they're going to be able to change
and you're not going to be able to do
it. I have a question for you. Juggle in,
in your own life experience.
How do you separate
the way of the universe?
Meaning in you personally,
the things that are just you that you
shouldn't try to change versus the things
that you should try to improve these?
I think that there,
there's the temptation for a lot of people
to say, well that's just the way I am,
but it's, it absolves them of the
responsibility of doing the work.
I got asked a similar question and it'll
tie into it, but I got asked by, um,
I was working with a company the
other day and a guy asked, you know,
if I've got a guy that's really good at
something but a person that's not really
good shit,
should I just give up on trying to get
the person that's not good at that job?
Give up on them and just let the
person that's good at it. Do it.
And I said, well, yes and no. I mean,
if we have somebody that is a really
good shot, like he's a sniper,
but we've got a guy that's
not a good shot. Okay,
so we're going to give the sniper all
the good missions and he's going to go do
all the tough shots. Okay.
Yeah, that makes sense.
That doesn't mean we just let the other
guy never learned how to shoot. No,
we actually continue to train him and
make him better and I think it's the same
thing with your, your your individual
self. Right? If I've got weaknesses,
I don't just say,
well,
I'm just going to avoid being
in those areas where I'm weak.
I'm going to actually go and
try and get better at them.
Now I'm not going to make that
the focus of my life. Right.
I'm not going to try and
become a ballerina. Right.
What I like to be more flexible.
Absolutely. Do I need to
work on that? Absolutely.
But I'm not trying to become a ballerina.
I wouldn't focus on that because it
would be a significant waste of my time.
End of my entire life in a
very fruitless situation.
But that doesn't mean I shouldn't try and
be more flexible. Right? So I think you,
you, you still apply time too to try and
improve it, but you don't waste, you know,
you don't waste a valuable energy.
You'd still look at what you're
good at and say, you know,
I'm better at doing Jujitsu,
I'm better at whatever.
Can I tell you,
uh,
one of the thoughts that for whatever
reason consumed my mind for about an hour
and a half during my
silent meditation retreat,
I was thinking about giraffes
can't dance this book,
this, this demon slayer
that crushes me on Amazon.
Always buy like five spots.
When I launch a book and I
started thinking about how
incredible it would be to
take Jocko the cartoon character,
uh,
as seen in the Jocko approved logo on
your t and to have a parody of that book
called Jocko,
can't dance with like thought bubbles
of what you're thinking throughout the
book. In any case, for whatever reason,
that is what my mind decided to settle on.
And, uh, I'm sorry. Uh,
so confession over confession.
Consider do you find that
yourself that you say like, Oh,
I'm not good at this Roman to avoid it?
Or do you find yourself getting focused?
Cause you know,
you're talking about what Musashi's wha
what they described Musashi do and as
earlier, which is I only worry about
things that are beating me. Right?
I only worry about the opponent,
the baby,
just like the only book you think about
as this book, giraffes can't dance,
which is the one book that
beats you because, and that's
what you're focused on.
Your worry about these other books
that you kicked the crap out.
I also just like talking about it
because I love the fact that it's called
giraffes can't dance
and it kicks your ass.
Do you think you get
focused on things that are,
that you shouldn't be focused on or
that you're wasting time on? Uh, I, I,
you kind of know what
you're good at. I do. Uh,
I think that I've become better at
working on or distinguishing between
low level weaknesses in high level
weaknesses.
And what I mean by that is if you imagine,
say a people have seen like a champagne
pyramid where sometimes built at
weddings where you stack up all of these
champagne glasses and you pour into one
or it could be any type of glass and
it cascades down into the others. Uh,
where you could think of it
through a domino analogy.
I use this analogy a lot
looking at lead dominoes.
Like what can I do if I have a task list,
let's say,
which of these five tasks we'll make
all of the others easier or irrelevant.
And that'll help me sequence things in
the right order so that I'm not wasting
energy. Uh, if I have 10 units of energy,
I'd rather focus on identifying at
least to begin with the lead dominoes.
And so a high level
weakness would be a week.
A lead domino is something that has
downstream negative effects on many
different areas even, uh, that
can compromise your strengths,
right? Uh, so for me, for
instance, I think, uh,
for a very long time I viewed,
uh,
I only viewed impatience through the
lens of the benefits of aggression.
Because having a good,
authentic has always
been my model ever since.
I became fascinated by Dan Gable who
is about as close to a hundred percent
offense,
legendary wrestling a
competitor and coach,
uh, ah man, I have a lot of stories
about Dan Gable, uh, incredible,
incredible guy. But uh, I,
what I've realized in the
last few years for instance,
is that there are low level weaknesses.
Let's say I am not a programmer.
I am not good at a, B, c,
d or e skill that is more of a,
a technician's craft.
I will not spend time on those things
if I can delegate it or outsource it.
But if there are core psychological
traits that are higher order that can
negatively impact other
things, then I've realized, uh,
for the long haul.
Uh,
I do want to at least experiment with
developing those capacities.
I think has helped me a lot is I'm always,
and I was,
when I was in the seal teams,
I was always looking at other people.
I was always looking at their leadership.
I was looking at what they're doing
and I was looking at why they weren't
getting along. I was looking at
what was wrong with the platoon.
And as I would sit there and watch these
people, I would learn from because,
and I'd say, you know, I'd see two people
that didn't get along. And I'd say, wow,
why don't get, why can't these guys
get along? What's wrong with them?
And I'd watch him and I'd see that, you
know, this one guy has a giant ego. Oh.
And so is the other guy.
And instead of one of them
disarming the other guy's ego,
they both can't figure that out. And so
they're just battling and it's, you know,
you got that in inside of a seal
platoon. It's a horrible thing. And,
and so as I'd watch them,
it allowed me that,
then I could see it in myself where
I would see, oh, I like, I've,
I've got frustrated with someone I'd say,
or I'd get,
I have a negative thought about someone.
I think,
why do I have that negative thought about
that person that's actually a bad ass?
Or it seems like a really strong
personality or a strong presence.
Right. Why do I have that? Oh,
I have that cause that's my ego.
And it's the same thing with when
I see people getting excited, um,
I don't think excitement is usually
a positive thing. I mean it's not,
it's not a negative thing,
but sometimes people in a meeting,
someone just immediately has
an opinion and, and I think,
and I watched their,
their opinion fall apart because
they didn't listen long enough.
They didn't assess things long enough.
And so I hear them state their opinion
and they stayed it with vigor and with,
with conviction. And then you listen
to it and all of a sudden they, they,
they can't help but look bad
because what they thought was wrong.
And I probably had the same thoughts as
I sat there and I kept my mouth shut and
I listened. And, and so I'd see people
do that. And I said, you know what,
when you're in a meeting and there's
people talking about things, do,
you don't need to say anything.
You don't need to appear
stupid or whatever it is.
He better do appear stupid,
then open your mouth and remove
all doubt, right? This is just,
but I would learn these things
about people, which I think were,
were helpful to me just by watching an
and seeing people and being really, uh,
really kind of a jerk in my own mind.
Like I watch people like a jerk. Like,
why would you do that? What's wrong with
you? Very accusatory tone in my own head.
But then it was really easy for me to
flip that back on myself all the time and
say, well wait a second. You do that too.
Wait a second. You make that same mistake.
So I think that from a
psychological perspective,
I think what's given me a good perspective
of my own psychology is watching
other people intently
and closely with the,
with the goal of actually helping them
correct that of bill going up to the guy
and say,
hey man,
this is your ego versus that guy's ego
and you're either going to want to,
you is going to have to disarm the other
one or your guys are never going to go
along and this never do a move forward.
And so I think that really
helped me out a lot. I'm sure
it,
and I have found certainly that there
are many benefits in my case of being a
solo practitioner, so
to speak, uh, being, uh,
unemployed slash self employed
for decades now. But the,
one of the clear downsides is that I
don't have that in person peer group to
observe or superiors or subordinates to
observe it with the rare exception of a
handful of employees now.
But the,
what I ended up doing for myself to
try to improve because I didn't have,
I assumed, and I think this is good for
a lot of people, do assume that you,
you may not have sufficient self
awareness to accurately self diagnose your
weaknesses and strengths.
So I would seek out environments
that made it very obvious.
And the way I did that,
and I think we saw,
she in a way alludes to this,
uh,
is if you say are on the battlefield
in massage case,
your strengths and weaknesses or at least
your weaknesses tend to become clearer
or magnified.
So if I could put myself into a really
intense training environment like Aka in
San Jose, a lot of professionals
there, uh, at the time,
Cain Velasquez and a number of others
and training with Dave in a handful of
folks, I could watch my response
to increasing levels of stress.
Like how did I respond to extreme heat?
What was the self talk when
I wanted to quit? Did I, uh,
at what point was I inclined to try to
find someone easy to roll with? Like,
how many rounds did it take?
Right? Wasn't it? And uh,
and then could I then I would note that,
and I would actually take notes.
I bring my notebook and just you can see
I have notebooks everywhere here and I
would note the, not just the technical
learnings and what I wanted to approve,
but the,
the,
the decisions and the self talk that
I made that I want to improve upon and
experiment with that.
So I used the physical arena as a
way to try to identify the high level
weaknesses that I could
work on because uh,
everybody has a plan until they
get punched in the face. Right.
So it's all great and theoretically
academically beautiful to sit down and try
to self analyze when you're journaling
in the morning, which I also do,
but it's quite another thing
to be like, okay, tough guy.
Yeah. Even with that long
explanation, I just gave it,
look in all these people, I didn't
care. I wasn't consciously thinking,
actually it wasn't even consciously
thinking about it from a psychological
perspective. I was just thinking it
from a pragmatic, here's two guys,
why don't they get along? And then when I
would see myself, dude, I go, oh, you're,
you're like, you're doing the same
stupid stuff. It wasn't like this,
um,
you know,
this idea of I was looking at myself
and I was just doing what I had to do.
Right.
I guess there's always the subconscious
feeling of like trying to do better and
trying to self improve,
but I'm not a person that has the,
the constant like, um, I'm trying to
self improve. I think it's just a,
it's just a natural thing. Yeah.
I'm trying to get better of course,
but that's not, I don't think about
it. That's, I guess that's my point.
I don't think about, I'm not
focused on it. I'm just doing it.
I'm just doing it and living it
yet. Well, I think in [inaudible] in
your case, and uh, I have,
well we have some mutual
friends, I mean from the seals,
but also a force recon and a number of,
of friends who have,
uh,
been engaged at very high levels
in elite ranks within the military.
And I think that in my
experience thus far, uh,
most of them have,
whether it's by virtue of the filtering
that their careers impose on them,
right? I mean you have thousand
people start at step one.
How many make it to step
a hundred? Uh, that they,
they self select an are selected to have
a high degree of what I would consider
or what you could consider mindfulness,
which is usually associated with like
hippies and San Francisco with Didgeridoo
is and burning man and so on.
It's, it's a buzzword there.
But I think the ability to detach
in that way comes naturally to you.
And to many people I know who
also have made it to step 100,
they just seem in a military context,
if you don't have that you and certainly
you can get killed or get washed out
for many different reasons.
But I think if one of them seems to be,
if you no self awareness,
you just, you get broken or you
get disqualified at some point or,
or you, you get as good as the machine
can make you. And I think that's,
that's the real difference.
You get as good as the machine,
the machine's going to make
you good. Right? Right.
But you the only person that can take you
pass what the machine can make as you.
And so if you're not self aware, if you
can't, if you can't figure that out,
if you can't look in the mirror and
see like things that you can correct,
then you're, you're just going
to be what the machine made you,
which is a high quality
item. I mean, you know,
the military is filled with some
high quality guys, great guys,
fabulous guys that perform outstanding.
But then there's like this one more
little level of guys that are where you,
you look at him and you go, man, that
guy is really good at what, why is that?
That's because that guy,
the machine got him to here and
he's looking at myself going,
what can I do better? He's got that
detachment and that's definitely,
definitely important. I got to
introduce somebody in this book now,
um, that there's, his name is Sasaki.
Could Jiro Gun Room? I'd have
to see the last part. Yeah.
He got the first g. A. N. R. Y you
got new you guys to be a hard to say.
Come to, I guess I'm going to go
with what I'm calling. So this guy,
and he dances the in and
out throughout the book,
but this is Musashi's uh,
archrival the other swordsmen that's
got this incredible reputation only.
He's been a little bit more,
he stays on the scene more.
Musashi is going in trying to
farm and doing other things.
And this guy's kind of
on the scene and there's,
there's one part where these elderly
gentlemen are talking about who is truly
the best swordsman Slash Samurai in Japan.
And here we go to the book.
As he compared the two,
he had to admit that the most
Daimiel am I saying that right?
The time you meal would prefer could
he came from a good family and he had
started the art of war
thoroughly despite his youth.
He'd developed a formidable style of his
own and he gained considerable to fame
as a fighter.
The story of his brilliant defeat of men
from the old Bata Academy on the banks
of the Sumida river.
And again at the dike on the condo
river was already well known.
Nothing had been heard
from Musashi for some time.
His victory at each show,
each GI Joe Gi had made his reputation,
but that had been years ago and soon
afterward had spread this story that the
story was exaggerated,
that Musashi was a seeker of after fame,
who had trumped up the fight, made a
flashy attack, and then fled to mount. He,
every time we saw she did
something praiseworthy,
a spate of rumors followed
denigrating his character and ability.
It had reached the point where even the
mention of his name usually met with
critical remarks or,
or else people ignore them entirely.
As the son of a nameless
warrior in the mountains of me,
Masaka his lineage was insignificant.
So he kind of faded and he does
some dumb stuff too, right?
Like he does dumb things
like he's a young,
you didn't come from that from the ranks
that have people that were counseling
him and keep him in line.
So he did dumb stuff like have battles
against whole castles and attack people.
He was kind of crazy. Yeah. Right. And
so his reputation and then of course,
you know this is like a, I guess
ancient social media, right?
There was rumors and they would post
signs about people and they would do these
things to denigrate people's
reputations and such.
And they had done that
considerably to massage it.
Just thinking about how
labor intensive it would be,
you're talking about spreading posters
like to hand create piles of posters that
you then go post to denigrate someone.
Like the equivalent of a tweet was
like sitting down for a week and a hand
making posters to put around town
and they do it in this book that you do.
I mean it's full times.
They go on both sides. People write sign,
Musashi does it, the other people do it.
It's um, yeah, it's, it's crazy.
And we're getting toward getting closer.
Closer.
We saw she's wandering
in the mountains and
here we go back to the book.
At times he was so
tortured with his sword.
Okay.
It seemed like a weapon
that turned against him.
Among the possibilities he
considered was choosing the easy way.
If he could bring himself to live in
a comfortable, ordinary way with Ohsu,
life would be simple.
Almost any fife would be willing to
pay him enough to live on perhaps 500,
2000 bushels.
But when he put it,
but when he put it to himself
in the form of a question,
the answer was always no.
An easy existence imposed restrictions.
He could not submit to them.
Okay.
Three's get, he got the idea, you know,
I could just marry to get a good job,
make a hundred k a year,
we'll call it good.
He doesn't like that though,
doesn't it? Not like it.
The easy path has restrictions. It is
the discipline that provides freedom.
Apparently for Musashi
done as a contemporary example, uh, one
of my a, I would consider him a teacher.
He certainly become a friend,
but a political originally at least when
he came to the u s a Polish political
refugee named Jersey Gregorich.
He's now in his sixties lives in Woodside,
California,
and he's a world champion and world
record holder and Olympic weightlifting.
Yeah, as is his wife. He, he, that was a
good podcast by the way. Oh yeah, he's,
he's awesome.
He's so salty.
And to give people a little bit of
back on the first time I met him,
I was just at the time suffering from
a malaise in a general fatigue with the
hypersensitivity of the bay area.
And I walked in to meet him for the first
time to get an assessment and we sat
down and we drank Marco Polo black tea.
It's the only tea that he drinks
and he's like, have a seat.
So I sit down and we're talking,
he's asking me about my goals,
about my athletic background,
past injuries and he's sitting across
from me is ease in great shape.
He's in his sixties he,
he can still do well as an example,
I've seen him on an endo board. You
know, those aren't some balance boards,
like a wobble board on top of a
cylinder with a loaded barbell.
He's holding a loaded barbell
in a position like a hand
clean on an Indo board.
Uh, he's in his sixties throw
it up, you know, for like 150,
200 pounds and land in
a full ass to heels,
snatch on an Endovar that is legit.
And so he reached across sipping
tea and then he stopped mid,
mid thought and reached across and sort
of pit pinched my right to and just said
you owe to fat. So I just loved this
guy. Like after that I was like, yes,
we are going to work together.
But his one of his mantras that he
uses for everything is easy choices,
hard life, hard choices, easy life.
Discipline Equals Freedom for sure.
That's awesome. That is awesome.
Did you like get on the program with him?
I did for quite a period of time. Yeah.
And where you were you traveling down?
I mean,
how does do following instructions and
trust me coaching you are traveled down
regularly and um,
made excellent progress.
It's very to do Olympic weight lifting
the way that Jersey would want you to do
it. Uh, and which is the
way I would want to do it.
You really need hands on
instruction. It's highly, highly,
highly technical. And, uh,
also you need a logical progression
because most people who just want to do a
weekend course and figure out the snatch,
they do not have any of the
ankle or shoulder mobility,
thoracic spine mobility to even perform
the right movement regardless of who the
instructor is.
They could have a 500 time world
champion teaching them and doing video
recording,
but if they had don't have the mobility,
there's going to hurt themselves. So
I went down regularly and then, uh,
when I was traveling with,
sent him video and he would
reply with video commentary,
a great experience.
I mean,
I still think the Jersey style
relatively narrow stance as to the grass,
uh, overhead squat, one of
the best movements. What, how,
why does his grip when he does that?
It's a snatch grip. So it'd be a wider,
wider grip, but he can, there are videos
of Jersey people can look them up.
J E R Z y Gregorich Gre,
g o r e.
K a.
Their videos that he is one of the most
flexible mobile humans I've ever seen
any strong as an ox.
But he can with his feet together,
uh,
holding a say 35 pound plate overhead
with his hands flat underneath it.
Like he's holding a dinner platter,
go down into a perfect
squat with his chest up,
asked to his heels,
holding that overhead with his
fingers, basically touching. Yeah.
Which people might say, Oh, I could do
that. Trust me. You can't like, trust me,
you cannot do it.
That's, that's awesome. So
we're getting towards the,
towards the end here,
this again, this, um,
rivalry is brewing and finally there is a,
speaking of social media,
there is a command issued by the castle.
And here's what it says on the 13th day
of this month at eight o'clock in the
morning on Fukushima in the
Nevado straights of Buzan Sasaki,
could Jiro gone through a Samurai of
this Phif will add his lordship's bidding
fight about with me.
You motto Masashi Masana,
a Ronin from the province of Nema Soka 80,
strictly forbidden for supporters of
either swordsmen to go to his aid or set
forth on the water between the
mainland and Fushi Nama and Funy Shama,
sorry until 10 o'clock on
the morning of the 13th.
No sight seeing vessels,
passenger ships and fishing boats will
be permitted to enter the straights.
1612 that, that, that, that document
right there. So there you go. It's on,
they're going to fight.
And for people wondering what Ronan is
that as a master list warrior that is a
Samurai without a Lord
floating a floating person,
Nin person.
And uh,
you could think of them in some cases.
I mean they would either be freelance,
self directed learners,
an autodidact like Musashi
or they'd be mercenaries.
So ruined in, we're also swords for
higher negative connotation to it.
Negative connotation.
God,
I would say for sure a
negative connotation, uh,
simply because,
uh,
the lineage and association in Japan,
Japanese culture is so
important that if you,
if you don't have a master or a particular
fif that you're associated with a
particularly if you come from,
you are born of unknown origins
are from a no name at warrior.
It is very much a,
an important class distinction.
And Saki also as I understand it,
and this may come up later, but
used a slightly different sword. Uh,
and yes and
uh, we we can get to that. Do you want
me to hold it? No, no, it's cool. He,
he uses a sword called the drying pole.
And for years until I was actually
prepping for this podcast,
I thought that that was a bad
ass name for a sword of course.
But what I thought I
was thought to myself,
that means like drives you have your
blood. That's what I thought it meant.
It drives you have is of your blood.
And then as I was researching
for this podcast, it's actually,
and correct me if I'm wrong, but from
what I found, there's a method of Clo,
of drying your clothes on a stick,
a long stick,
and his sword was longer than most swords.
And so the full name of it
was the closed drawing sword.
Did I get all that right?
That part,
I'm not sure if it makes sense to me.
And I remember when I was in
Japan a number of years ago,
I go back as often as I possibly can and
I'm still in close contact with my host
family. I've been to my brother's weddings
and so on. It's just been fantastic.
And I went back and I went
to a Japanese Sword Museum,
which was incredibly hard to
find and it was empty. And the,
I'm decent at a,
still decent at reading Japanese,
but it's been a long time and
it's been almost 20 years,
more than 20 years since
I formally studied it.
So given there are
thousands of characters,
one gets a little rusty and I went
into this Japanese sword museum and the
displays and everything you can imagine.
I mean it's Japan, things are clean,
meticulous.
And I went in and it was just walls and
walls of displays with different sorts
from different areas.
So I mean swords were talking
about swords from these arrows are,
they're preserved and they look brand new.
And I was walking around and there was
a gentleman who is cleaning and I asked
him a question at one point about how to
pronounce a character and he proceeded
to pause his cleaning and walk me through
the entire museum explaining how each
of them was used. And one of
them, or one type I should say,
which I believe is what Sasaki used.
It is long and it's called the Daci.
I think it's Dutchy and the difference
of the most remarkable differences. A it,
yes,
it's very long and it is curved and it
would be used very often by horsemen and
it was curved so that
they could strike down,
uh, their opponents without getting
the blades stuck in their bodies.
Because if you have a straight blade or
relatively straight played like a Katana,
it's almost like having a straight bladed
hatchet that you swing into a tree.
It's like fuck. And it gets stuck.
Well if you're on horseback,
that's a big problem.
You lose your sword,
you're in a very bad position.
And so it would,
it would be more of a slicing motion
as opposed to a chopping motion and the
Daci was very effective for that reason.
It's also another reason that
it tended to be longer. Yeah.
Cause you're fighting from on top of a
horse, so you've got to reach down. Yeah.
Apparently they're saying that this
sword was about nine to 12 inches longer
than the normal sword and they gave
it this name, that drawing Paul,
which again I always thought was about,
that's the way my mind works.
Echo Charles, don't be laughing. Oh.
Then it turned out it's just trying to,
everything's there,
were outside on a broom handle.
Everything is cooler in my brain.
Uh
Oh two who by the way, this whole time
that she's been in and out, she's, she,
they've never actually
like gotten together as,
as whatever mates or as
permanent partners. Right.
It's always just been this kind
of thing. Very Japanese. Yeah. Um,
oh is that very Japanese?
Yeah. Yeah. I would say so.
Just this a very what we would consider
sort of awkward tension that never has
some resolution. Right then that's
then that's exactly what this is.
And that's exactly where they've
been for 962 pages of a book. Right.
Awkward tension for 962
pages and God bless her,
she's still like saying,
Hey, I'm here for you.
Even if even though he told her
I love my sword and not you.
Well now to be fair, he said, I love my
sort more than I love you. No, he said,
I don't dislike you. Which
in the Musashi speak. Yeah.
It's like I will love you
until my dying. True. True.
So she is going to say goodbye
to him because there's, you know,
this is, this is, uh, does it match
where someone is going to die and it's,
I guess I'm looking at it,
it's a little bit,
the older guy that is been out of practice
against the young stud that's in the
game fully.
So it seems like people are thinking
there's a good chance he's going to die.
So He's having that final conversation
with her. Ohsu, please forgive me.
I may seem harmless, but I'm not,
not where you're concerned. I,
I know that. Do you truly? Yes,
but I beg you say one word for me.
Just one word.
Tell me that I'm your wife.
Okay.
It would spoil it if I told
you what you know already,
but,
but
she was sobbing with her whole body,
but with a burst of strength.
She seized his hand and cried. Say it
Sam, your wife throughout this life,
he nodded slowly silently.
Then one by one he pulled her delicate
fingers from his arm and stood erect.
A Samurai's wife must not weep and go to
pieces when he goes off to laugh for me
out to send me away with a smile.
This may be your husbands last departure.
Both knew the time had
come for a brief moment.
He looked at her and smiled.
Then he said until then,
yes.
Until then she wanted to return to smile,
but only managed to hold back the tears.
Farewell.
He turned and walked with firms.
Strides towards the water's edge.
A parting word rose to her throat,
but refuse to be uttered.
The tears welled up irrepressibly
she could no longer see him.
The strong salty wind ruffled Musashi
sideburns. His Komono flapped.
Briskly saw Suki bring
the boat a little closer
though. He'd been waiting for over two
hours and new Musashi was on the beach.
Suzuki had carefully
kept his eyes averted.
Now he looked at Musashi
and said right away, sir,
we're the few strong rapid movements.
He pulled the boat in
when it touched the shore.
Musashi jumped lightly into the
prow and they moved out to see
oh to stop the south.
The shout was too Taros.
Another guy that's there on the scene.
Oh two was running
straight toward the water.
He raced after her startled to
Suki and Osu be joined the chase.
Oh Sue, stop. What are you doing?
Don't be foolish. Reaching her.
Simultaneously they threw her arms
around her and held her back. No,
no, she protested. Shaking
her at Sarah had slowly,
you don't understand what,
what are you trying to do?
Let me sit down by myself.
Her voice was calm when they released
her and she walked with dignity to a spot
a few yards away where she knelt
on the sand, seemingly exhausted.
But she had found her strength.
She straightened her color,
smooth her hair and bowed her head
towards Musashi's little craft.
Go without regrets.
She said,
that's how you do it right there.
So again,
it was mentioned or if,
if I didn't explain that well enough,
this battle is going to take place on a
little island in the middle of a stream
and I'm straight. Yeah.
Or is it a straight,
what's the difference between those two?
Um, well actually that's a great question.
I, the way I said this, this is fun. Okay.
So I mean a novel like this is
created in your own head, right?
It's an active experience of
creating, right? So in my head,
and maybe I don't know what a straight is,
but the way I envisioned a
straight was almost like a uh,
small or extended so long,
but narrow sand
bank in the middle of say a river or a
but a wide river like Mississippi type.
Yeah. That's kind of what I
pictured. I pictured a wide, a wide,
wide river that has a,
a little uninhabited sorta strip of
land in the middle. Yeah, exactly.
That's what I picture.
And that's what you picture too.
So I guess we created the same thing.
So he's in this boat and he's headed,
obviously he's running late
and as per usual, as per usual.
And here we go to the book.
So Suki may have this,
what is it?
This broken or in the bottom of the boat?
I don't need it.
Why do you want it?
It's about the right size.
Musashi said cryptically he held the
slightly waterlogged or out with one hand.
And squinted down at to
see if it was straight.
One edge of the blade was split off.
He placed the order on his
knee and totally absorbed,
began carving with his short sword.
Suzuki cast backward glances
toward Shimo Sechi several times,
but we saw, she seemed oblivious
of the people he left behind.
Was this the way a Samurai
approached a life and death battle?
Two towns,
men like Suzuki.
It was cold and heartless,
so this is important.
He picked up this old waterlogged or from
the bottom boat says, can I have this?
The guy says, yeah, sure.
And now he starts carving it.
So Suki was growing more and more
nervous with each stroke of the skull.
He had broken out in a cold sweat.
His heart was palpitating.
How could a man going
into battle be so calm?
It would be a fight to the death,
no question about that.
Would he be taking a passenger back to
the main land later or cruelly maimed
corpse?
There was no way of knowing Musashi
thought Suzuki was like a white cloud
floating across the sky.
This was not opposed on
Musashi's part four. In fact,
he was thinking of nothing
at all. He was, if anything,
a little bored.
He looked over the side of the boat at
the swirling blue water. It was deep here,
infinitely deep and alive with
what seemed to be eternal life.
But water had no fixed determined form.
Was it not?
Because man had a fixed determined form
that he cannot possess eternal life.
Yeah.
Does not true life begin only when
tangible form has been lost to Musashi's
eyes. Life and death seemed
like so much fraud off.
He felt goose pimples on his skin,
not from the cold water,
but because his body felt a premonition.
Fruit though his mind had
risen above life and death,
body and mind.
We're not in a accord when every
pore of his body as well of his mind.
For God,
there would remain nothing
inside but being inside is being,
but the water and the clouds.
So he's going into a full on like trans.
Yeah,
full on. Transcend. Skipping
ahead a little bit here.
They arrive at the island, go straight
in Musashi, flew off the quilted quote,
the bow advanced at a very
restrained pace. Says you could,
could not bring himself
to stroke with vigor.
His arms moved only slightly
exerting little force.
The sound of Bulbous was in
the air. So Suki, yes sir.
It's shallow enough here.
There's no need to get close.
You don't want to damage your boat.
Besides,
it's about time for the
tide to turn silent.
Lisa Zukie fixed his eyes on a tall,
thin pine tree standing alone.
Underneath it,
the wind was playing with
a brilliant red cloak.
Suzuki started to point,
but realize that Musashi had already seen
his opponent keeping his eyes on God.
UNRUH Musashi took a Russet
hand towel from his Ob,
folded it in four length wise and
tied it around his wind blown hair.
Then he shifted his sort of short sword
to the front of his ob taking off as
long sword.
He laid it in the bottom of the boat
and covered it with a read Matt in his
right hand. He held the wooden
sword he had made from the broken or
this is far enough. He said, this is Suki,
so
he's going to fight the best
swordsman in the world. He carves a
wooden sword out of an or on the way
leaves his long stored in the boat and
there is a,
this is a novel,
but there's also some
historic precedent for this.
So he would routinely use wooden swords
when dueling with opponents who are
using live blades.
Okay, back to the book at that
moment, Musashi, his Hakama,
which is uh, pants. They're like,
yeah, it's kind of like a judge.
Japanese kilt, let's say, very, very long.
Usually it comes down to the ankles, has
it comma hitched, high on both sides,
jumped lightly into the sea landing,
so light be he barely made a splash.
He strode rapidly toward the
waterline is a wooden sword.
Cutting through the spray,
five steps, 10 steps.
Suzuki abandoning his goal, watched in
wonderment, unconscious of where he was,
what he was doing
has gone rouge street away from the pine
like a red streamer has Polish scabbard
caught the glint of the sun.
Musashi gone through,
planted his feet and resolutely in the
sand, unwilling to give up an inch.
We saw, she stopped and stood, still
exposed to the water and the wind.
A hint of a grin appeared on his face.
[inaudible]
he said quietly,
there was an unearthly fierceness
in his eyes are forced pooling.
So irresistibly,
it threatened to draw Kuduro inexcusably
into the peril and destruction.
The waves washed his wooden sword,
gone.
Roos were the eyes that shot fire,
the bloodthirsty flame burned in his
pupils like the rainbows of fierce
intensity seeking to terrify
and debilitate Musashi.
No answer.
Musashi,
the sea rumbled ominously in the distance.
The tide lapped and murmured
at the two men's feet.
You're late again, aren't you? Is that
your strategy? As far as I'm concerned,
it's a cowardly ploy.
It's two hours past the appointed time.
I was here at eight just as promised.
I've been waiting.
Musashi did not reply.
You did this at Ici Joji and
before that at the [inaudible].
Your method seems to be to throw your
opponent off by deliberately making him
wait. That trick will get you
nowhere. We've got Unruh now.
Prepare your spirit and come forward
bravely so future generations won't laugh
at you.
Come ahead and fight Musashi.
The end of his scabbard rose high behind
him as he drew the great drying pole
with his left hand. He slid off the
scabbard and food into the water
waiting just long enough for a
wave to strike the refund retreat.
Musashi suddenly said in a quiet voice,
you've lost code.
Jiro what?
Gone Rue was shaken to the core.
The fights been fought. I say, you've
been defeated. What are you talking about?
If you're going to win,
you wouldn't throw your scabbard away.
You've cast away your future,
your life words nonsense.
Too Bad could ready to fall.
Do you want to get it over with?
Fast come, come forward. You bastard.
Oh Musashi's cry in
the sound of the water.
Rose to a crescendo together
stepping into the water,
the drying pole position
high above his head gone.
Rue faced Musashi squarely align of
White Foam Street to cross the surface as
Musashi ran up on shore to gone,
Roos left,
gone root pursued Musashi's feet left the
water and touch the sand at almost the
same instant that gone roos sword,
his whole body.
Hurdled Adam like a flying fish when
Musashi sense that the drying poles coming
toward him.
His body was still at the end of the
motion that had taken him out of a water
leaning slightly forward.
He held the wooden sword with both hands
extended out to the right behind him
and partially hidden
satisfied with his position.
He grunted and almost noiseless sound
that wafted before gone years face.
The drying poll had appeared to be
on the verge of a downward slice,
but it wavered slightly then stopped
nine feet away from Musashi.
Gone route changed directions
by leaping nimbly to the right.
The two men stared at each other Musashi,
two or three paces from the
water had the c two is back gone.
Rue was facing him.
His sword held high with both hands.
Their lives were totally absorbed in
deadly combat and both were free from
conscious thought.
The scene of battle was a perfect vacuum,
but in the waiting stations and
beyond the sound of the waves,
countless people held
their breaths above God.
UNRUH hovered the prayers and the hopes
of those who believed in him and wanted
him to live above Musashi.
The prayers in hopes of others
of Sado and Iorio on the island of Ohsu
and Ohsu got oh Sugi and Gono Sooki on
the beach of academy and
Mata Hace on their hill.
All their prayers were directed to heaven.
Here hopes,
prayers and the gods were of
no assistance nor was chance.
There was only a vacuum in
personal and perfectly impartial
is this vacuum so difficult of achievement
by one who has life the perfect
expression of the mind that has risen
above fought and transcended ideas.
The two men spoke without speaking.
Then to each came the unconscious
realization of the other,
the pores of their bodies stood out
like needles directed at the adversary.
Okay,
muscles, flesh, nail hair.
Even I browse all bodily elements that
partake of life for United into a single
force against the enemy,
defending the living organism
of which they were parked.
The mind alone was one with the universe,
clear and untroubled like the
reflection of the moon in a pond,
a midst the ratings of a
typhoon to reach this sublime.
A mobility is the supreme achievement.
It seemed like he [inaudible] but
the interval was in fact short.
The time required for the waves to come
in and recede a half a dozen times.
Then a great shout more than vocal coming
from the depths of being shattered.
The instant it came from God Unruh and
was followed immediately by Musashi
shout.
The two cries like angry waves lashing.
A rocky shore sent their spirits skyward.
The challenger Sword raised so high that
it seemed to threaten the Sun Street
through the air like a rainbow
Musashi through his shoulder,
his left shoulder forward Jew,
his right foot back and shifted his
upper body into position half facing his
opponent.
His wooden sword held in both hands,
swept through the air at the same moment
that the tip of the drying pole came
down directly before his nose.
Okay.
The breathing of the two combatants
grew louder than the sound of the waves.
Now the wooden sword was
extended at eye level.
The drying pole high above it's bearers,
head gone.
Rwe had bounded about 10 pieces away
where you had the seed of one side.
Though he had not succeeded in
injuring Musashi in his first attack,
he had put himself in
a much better position.
How did he remain where he was the s with
the sun reflecting from the water into
his eyes.
His vision would soon have faltered than
his spirit and he would have been at
Musashi's mercy
with renewed confidence gone.
Rue began inching forward,
keeping a sharp eye out for it,
Chink and Musashi's defense and stealing
his own spirit for a decisive move.
Musashi did the unexpected.
Yeah.
Instead of proceeding
slowly and cautiously,
he strode bold boldly toward gone.
Rouge has soared projecting before
him ready to thrust into gone years.
Eyes be artlessness of this approach.
Brock gone route to a halt.
He almost lost sight of Musashi,
the wooden sword row straight
in the air with one great kick.
Musashi leapt high and folding his legs
reduced his six foot frame to four feet
or less.
Okay.
Yeah. God, Woo stored. Scream
through the space above him.
The stroke missed,
but the tip of the drying,
Paul cut through Musashi's headband,
which went flying through the air.
Yeah.
Gone Rouge mistook it for his opponents
head and to smile flooded briefly across
his face.
The next instant his skull broke like
gravel under the blow of Musashi Sword.
Yeah.
Has Gone Rue lay with a sand,
met the grass.
His face betrayed no
consciousness of defeat.
Bloodstream from his mouth.
Yeah,
but his lips form the smile of triumph.
Oh No,
gone through.
Yeah.
For getting himself.
You warm a Kabuki chumped up and with
him all his knew their faces distorted
with shock.
Then they saw the Goda Sabu and EERE
sitting calmly and sedately on their
benches. Shamed. They somehow
managed to keep from running forward.
Yeah.
They tried to regain
a degree of composure,
but there was no concealing
their grief and delusion.
Okay.
Some swallowed hard,
refusing to believe what they had
seen and their mind's went blank
in an instant. The island was quiet
and still as it had ever been,
only the rustle of the Pines and the
swing grasses mocked the frailty.
And the impermanence of mankind.
Musashi was watching a
small cloud in the sky
as he did his soul return to his body
and it became possible for him to
distinguish between the cloud and himself
between his body and the universe.
Sasaki could Jiro gone.
Rouge did not return to
the world of the living
lying face down.
He still had a grip on his sword
is tenacity was still visible.
There was no sign of anguish on his face.
Okay.
Nothing but satisfaction at
having fought a good fight,
not the faintest shadow of regret.
The site of his own headband lying on
the ground sent shivers up and down
Musashi spine.
Never in this life he thought would
he meet another opponent like this?
A wave of admiration and
respect float over him.
He was grateful to [inaudible]
for what the man had given him
in strength in the will to fight.
He ranked higher than Musashi and it was
because of this that Musashi had been
forced to excel himself.
What was it that it enabled
Musashi do to defeat?
Cause she could Jiro skill,
the help of the gods,
while knowing it was neither of these
Musashi was never able to express a reason
in wards,
certainly was something more important
than either strength or godly.
Providence Koichiro had put his confidence
in the sword of strength and skill.
Musashi trusted in this sort of spirit.
Okay.
That was the only difference between them
silently. Musashi walked the 10
paces to Kuduro and knelt beside him.
He put his left hand near the nostrils
of could euro and found there was no
trace of breath
with the right treatment.
He may recover.
Musashi told himself and
he wanted to believe this,
wanted to believe that this Moza Vallian
of all adversaries would be spared,
but the battle was over.
Okay?
It was time to go
farewell.
He said to [inaudible] then to the
officials on their beat benches,
having bowed wants to the ground. He ran
to the reef and jumped into the boat.
There was not a drop of
blood on his wooden sword.
The tiny craft moved out to sea.
Okay.
Who's to say where there is no record as
to whether gone rue supporters on Hiko
Jima attempted to take revenge.
Okay.
People do not give up their loves
and hates as long as life lasts.
Waves of feeling come and
go with the passage of time.
Okay.
Throughout Musashi's lifetime,
there were those who resented his victory
and criticized his conduct on that
day.
He rushed away.
It was said because he feared reprisal.
He was confused.
He even neglected to
administer the coup de Gras.
Yeah.
The world is always full
of the sound of waves.
The little fishes abandoning
themselves to the waves,
dance and sing and play.
But who knows the heart of
the sea a hundred feet down.
Who knows?
It's depth.
The end.
That is
how the book finishes up.
Who knows the heart of the sea,
who knows its depths.
And as I read that,
I wondered to myself,
are we just the little fishes?
Yeah.
Abandoning ourselves to
the waves to sing and dance
and play.
Is that what we're doing?
And I'm not saying don't have fun.
I'm not saying don't
sing and dance and play.
Enjoy life of course.
And relish the joy of life.
But I think you have to make sure
you don't dance your life away.
Yeah,
don't be one of the little fishes.
And in Docauto that final writing
of Masashi before he died,
the last thing he wrote,
okay,
was never stray from the way.
And I think that that's
what this is about.
All the fun and the singing and the
dancing and hold the play. It's okay,
it's good.
But all those things
can be distractions
because there is a path,
there is a way,
and you know what that way is,
you know what you should be doing.
And it's hard to stay on that path
because it is the path of discipline
and discomfort,
but it is the right path.
And did you know that?
And it is that path that will ultimately
lead you to where you really want to be
so that you can live
and you can die
without regrets.
I think a lot of times,
okay,
people are trying to find the path and
they're looking all around different
places and different people in
different influences. But man,
I think so often that path.
Do you know what the path is and people
know what they're supposed to be doing,
but they just don't get on
the path and stay on the path.
Yeah, I agree. Word, something they
felt when they were eight or 12,
and they s they traveled the world or
travel through life's experiences trying
to find the answer that was in
front of them the entire time.
And so they come back to see what they
knew with different eyes and to recognize
that they knew the path all along,
which is something that,
uh,
I so enjoyed about this
book and the character both
real and certainly presented
by the author of Musashi who is using
his experiences in this domain of the
sword as a means of a
thematic interconnectedness.
And so unlike sus, uh, Cojito at the end,
he is not just a
technician with the sword,
although he is a brilliant technician.
He's tilling the soil,
he's constructing buildings,
which later he did quite a lot of,
uh,
in terms of architecture and overseeing
the building instead of destruction of
things and finding at the highest
levels of performance with the sword in
felling opponents, the, the principles,
the first principles that
he can apply everywhere.
And that's part of what fascinates me so
much about Musashi or anyone who's the
best at what they do is that it could
be anything. It could be pottery,
it could be sniping,
it could be calligraphy,
but like the best they see the depth,
they see the,
uh,
yeah,
the interwoven web is that can expand
from that one fine focus into everything
that they do.
And I think of that for
me at least is the path,
and maybe it's just coming off of a silent
retreat that I want to talk this way,
but it doesn't strike me as something
that is cleanly expressed in an Instagram
post or a quote necessarily.
It's more of a feeling like,
you know,
okay,
if you're sober and take a moment to
sit in the stillness and that stillness,
I don't mean sitting on a mountain top,
it could just be
five minutes of silence.
You first get up in the
morning and observe your own
mind and how you feel like
you know if you're on the path or not.
Or at least you know when you're not
totally agree. You know, you
know when you're not on it.
And I think that the feeling of
being on it when you're on the path,
it has that beauty of
mindlessness or no mind is
what they would say in say zen.
The state of no mind, and it sounds
like unconscious, but it's different.
It's not unconscious,
it's not subconscious.
It's something else where you feel that
you are exactly where you should be
doing exactly what you should be
doing and you're not planning,
you're just putting one foot in front of
the other on this path that you didn't
have to find it because in a way the
path was seeking you the whole time.
And it's just a feeling.
It's a really,
it's a feeling I think
that everyone can have,
but they get so caught up,
we all get caught up.
I don't want to speak for you to
find, so I'll speak for myself. It's,
it's easy to get caught up in the noise,
in the shiny objects and just like
the little fish you were talking about
earlier,
it's like what you see that lure
to recognize it as a lure
is sort of the first step.
And then to realize that when you
look past the lure, all right,
there's a lure 16 inches in front of
you and then you're in an ocean that has
endless fathoms of death.
What a journey. Yeah. I the same,
the line that says the world is
always filled with the sound of waves.
It's like,
yeah,
those sounds are going on and the waves
are out there and there's little fishies
swimming around in the waves.
You, and I think you've
experienced this type of,
that type of clarity in
many different contexts. Uh,
I haven't surfed much,
but I have done a bit,
certainly not as regularly as you have,
but the feeling of when I've been
out in surf that suddenly exceeded my
capacities,
which is also not necessarily
something I recommend,
but I've had this harrowing experience,
particularly as someone who didn't
learn to swim until I was in my thirties
which is a whole separate thing that
I think we covered in episode 50.
I have fear related to the ocean,
which I think is healthy on,
on a lot of levels.
When you're out there and suddenly sets
come in that are 70% of 102% bigger than
what you went in with the feeling of,
or just sitting calmly on your board
waiting for a set and looking out over the
water.
The sense of insignificance
that you feel is not a,
at least that I feel.
It's not a negative thing.
It's a very, uh, hesitate to use the word,
but I can't find a better one spiritual
experience where you're like, oh yeah,
that email,
that comment on social media,
that commitment I made to go to an event
that I run now really six months later,
don't want to go to who gives a fuck?
It's like we're a bunch of monkeys on
a spinning rock in the middle of this
whole thing.
Whatever this whole thing is.
And all that thing is singing
and dancing and playing it.
It's like compared to the depths of
the ocean, it means nothing. Yeah.
I think, yeah, it's, it's, uh,
it's,
I just, I love the purity of, uh,
despite his stupidity, let's be honest.
Right? We already talked about it. Like,
he made us a lot of stupid decisions.
Storming the jail. I mean, what do you,
what do you think's going to happen? And
so on and so forth. Despite all that,
coming back to what he knew,
one of the few things that he felt, I
shouldn't say no, felt to be true to him,
which was this commitment
to the way of the sword.
And it doesn't have to be a
commitment to the way of the sword,
but I've always had a certain envy,
uh,
for people including yourself,
who from a very,
very early age just felt
okay.
Ebay beacon for a direction that
called them. Yeah, really lucky.
I feel like I was really lucky in
that aspect where you meet people.
I've met for instance, Laird Hamilton,
I mentioned him earlier. He's like,
he still surfs every day,
wakes up at four,
stoked to go out and train
and uh,
he's on the path.
He's on the path and I mean this is a guy
who
he was with, I mean he's out
there with large tiger sharks,
which are routinely out
where he surfs in Hawaii,
where he spends a good portion of the
year and I've heard stories and these are
real,
these are not several hundred years later.
And Baelish storage is a real stories
where someone was bitten by a tiger shark
bleeding out. He went back
to a jet ski, they had a, Oh,
it took off at some piece of clothing.
He had put in makeshift tourniquet on
this guy who's bleeding in the water with
tiger sharks. Keep, mine's
already been bitten.
The key has been lost to
the jet ski hot wires,
the Jet Ski and brings the
Guy Back and saves them and,
and I'd say every few months he saved
someone's life in the water and he's in
his 50s and you're sitting in a,
in a steam room at one point.
And uh, I, I,
I in retrospect realized not a good idea
to try to outlast layered and the steam
room, but he was saying roughly
along these lines, like 20
once it's 20 feet, you can start to
have fun. Start to play around. He goes
20 to 20 to 30. Yeah,
you're really jamming.
It's like 30 to 40 you can definitely
get into the zone and he's like above 50
are not allowed to fall.
And that's his day and he has kids.
But as far as I can tell,
Gabby, who's just incredible,
incredible on so many
levels in her own right,
she understands like this is his path.
He's still chasing giants and he's
not going to stop. How could he,
like that's part of who he is.
What do you think draws people like
in the wrong direction in their life?
I think it's just a little
distractions as you talk about.
It's a little distractions,
little things that just
pull you off.
And I think,
I think maybe people don't want to accept
the fact like they know what the path
is, but they want to deny it for what?
For whatever reason. Like I think that's,
I think that can be part of it. Uh, the,
the distraction of the path.
I mean,
I will say for those people out there
who were like, oh, for God's sake,
like I don't know what my path is. I
can't define it. I don't know if I could,
if I could say to someone
with absolute conviction,
my path is x,
but I can tell when I've strayed,
if that makes sense.
There's a certain agitation,
there's a certain scattered feeling that
I have and as to reasons people get off
the path. And I think people may have
multiple paths, but you are going to say,
I was going to say,
because I've been,
I'm trying to formulate what what we're
talking about because I know exactly
what you mean. Like like the
path is, it might not be like,
Hey I want to do this thing. Like there's
something else and, and I think it,
I think there's something else is
the path is how you are going to live.
Yeah.
That's not necessarily a
destination that you could,
you could follow the same path and get
to a bunch of different destinations,
but the path itself of
how you're going to live,
how you're going to go through life,
how you're going to do things,
that's,
that's what I'm talking about.
And even the path that I'm on could have
led to other things and in my life and
even though you know,
I was in the military for 20 years,
I'm not in the military anymore,
I'm still on the same path.
Like the path is the same of the way I'm
trying to live my life. That's the same.
And if I'm in, when I'm in business,
the way I, the way I run my business,
I'm Trump. I'm just on the
same path. It's the path.
It's like the way you're living
your life more than anything else.
And it doesn't matter if you're in
college, if you're starting a business,
if you're working for someone,
are you on the path that you're supposed
to be on? Are you living the way that
you feel you're supposed to live,
that you know you're supposed to live?
I think people get off that.
They get off that and then not living
the way that they know they should live,
regardless of circumstances. You've been
in horrible circumstances before we all,
we all go in situations where
things just went sideways and,
and you can either have stray off the
path and turn into something that you're
not, or something that you know you
shouldn't be or you can stay on the path.
You can continue to do the things that
you're supposed to do and do and live the
way that you want to live.
And really lately I've been talking about,
because I've been trying to explain this,
you know what the right thing to do is,
right?
You know what you're supposed
to do as a person, as you,
you know what you're supposed
to do. Do it, do that thing.
What is that thing that you spent?
You know,
you're supposed to live a certain way.
And, and when you don't live that way,
like you said,
there's,
there's friction and there's tension and
there's disruption and it doesn't feel
right. And when you live the
right way, it's often harder.
It often is less immediate gratification,
but the,
but the internal gratification that you
get from living the way you're supposed
to live is very satisfying.
And another thing I need to absolutely
point out is I am by no means sitting
here trying to say that I've always
maintained the worst human ever.
I'm horrible. And, and
you know, I was on with a,
with a guy named Charlie plumb came
on the podcast and a guy named Jim Jim
Conkle. Charlie plumb was a Vietnam,
uh, fighter pilot shot down,
spent six years in the Hanoi Hilton.
And another guy named Jim [inaudible]
uncle who was a fighter pilot in World War
II. And, and we got in this conversation
like about, you know, doing good and,
and these guys are just levels,
infinite levels above me as
far as being good people. And,
and I kind of went along
with the conversation almost
as if I was one of their
like had that level of goodness, which
I don't, you know, I mean I'm trying,
but you know, when I was a young
seal has a maniac, you know,
I made Musashi looked like
a brilliant saint when his
youth, you know, I was like,
how are easy maniac kid filled
with just mayhem in my brain and,
and all my friends, we were all the same
and we got after it. And so believe me,
I'm not trying to say that, but I
will say that as I've grown up, I've,
I've think I've gotten myself closer to
living the way that I know I'm supposed
to live or I the what I believe to be the
right way and the right path to be on.
And you know,
so I just wanted to make that quick caveat
that anybody that's listening that's
like, Oh wow, jack was really
just a saintly person. Go wrong.
I'm not even remotely making that claim.
Um,
but I am trying, I'll give
myself at least that much credit.
I think that everyone is
a work in progress and
the path so to speak is
okay
illustrated for me in this book and I'll,
I'll get into a couple of specifics.
It might be helpful for people to think
about or at least had been helpful to me
as I think through
what distinguishes the relative lack
of friction and the scatteredness and
agitation versus states
without those things.
Because being on the path
is not necessarily for me
a feeling of overwhelming
joy and happiness per se.
It's,
it's a lack of
excess agitation and distractedness
and I think that what,
what I've found for myself is that as
I get older and feel more at peace with
what I'm doing and how I'm
behaving, like you said, it's,
it's having certain first principles in
mind that transcend any given project,
any given conversation, anyone
relationship. And early on, it's
as you're hoping to define yourself
or find yourself or build yourself,
you all,
he very often succumb because how could
you not to pursuing shiny object after
shiny object?
And in the beginning I think that's fine.
And even for a very long period of time,
you throw a lot against the wall to see
what sticks and to discover what you're
good at, what you're terrible
at, where your weaknesses are,
what your strengths are.
But over time,
whether you're looking at some of the
most successful investors in the world,
like Ray Dalio of Bridgewater associates,
they manage $160 billion at last count.
And uh,
or athletes like Marcello Garcia who
will not train a technique that he cannot
use on a 300 pound muscular opponent.
He just will not train. The ITI did not.
He does not drill techniques that he
cannot apply to someone twice its size.
And these are principles,
right? Whether it's safe and it,
and you can take principles from
one domain and transplant them,
which is why I think this book is such
an excellent illustration of the value of
becoming exceptionally,
exceptionally good at something in a very,
very narrow band.
Because when you do that,
the constitution and the frameworks and
the principles that you developed for
yourself can then be applied everywhere.
So in Jujitsu, let's just say,
and I'm talking out my
ass a little bit since,
I certainly don't feel qualified to speak
to too much on Jujitsu at this table,
but if you take something like
position before submission,
right?
Let's just say for what,
for whatever reason you adopt that
and that's worked very well for you.
You can apply that to a lot,
right?
You can apply that to a lot of things.
And uh,
when you start to really think about
precepts and principles and the Docauto
that last a short book or
treatise of Musashi is,
is in a fact, uh, a
bulleted list of precepts
and pretty tough to follow all of them,
all of them at the same time.
By the way if you read them,
but if you just have a few, I
ended a, they can be very plain,
very much plain speech.
I mean let's just say it's say what
you mean mean mean what you say
do what you say you are going to do
on time. I mean very simple, right?
Then you have a recipe book, you have an
algorithm which is really just a step,
a set of steps that produce a
given no and predetermined outcome.
Usually
if you follow those you,
you can start to mold
and define this path,
your way of moving through the world
and interacting with the world,
but if you're stuck in say
the weather patterns of the world instead
of looking at sort of the tectonic
plate level and you're focused
on these things, it change very,
very quickly like the news cycle,
like what your friends are saying
on social media at all times.
The fear of missing out in
social expectations that are set,
that make you want to posture because all
of your friends are putting highlights
of their lives on the Internet,
which makes you feel like a failure
because it's not all glamour shots.
Those are all just shifting weather
patterns. They mean nothing and you just,
you should let those pass
as they say in this book,
it comes up a lot.
Uh,
as much as froth froth that comes
up a lot in Musashi and flies,
right?
Froth and flies and insects.
He's passing phenomena
versus thinking about,
in his case he uses the
mountains and so on,
but the lower levels that tend to be less,
they're less sexy, they
don't move as quickly. Uh,
but if you understand those slower
moving and by extensions a timeless
principles and you can use those
to carve and form and find,
rediscovered your own path than I think
it just gives you a much greater level
of peace in part because it gives
you a much greater level of agency.
You feel like you can craft
your experience of life
as opposed to being tossed
back and forth by the vagaries of fast
changing factors you have no control over
man. Well I suppose we
could talk about this, um,
indefinitely,
but we're using up too
much bandwidth already. Um, Echo.
Speaking of the path,
do you have any recommendations of maybe
how people could stay on the path and,
and, and, you know, maybe even
support? Sure. Real quick though,
as far as pronunciation goes,
when there's like a double consonant,
you kind of say I'm both. Huh? Like,
like this Dakota, you say dope.
Cotto yeah,
there's a little stutter in it.
Cause it's almost like you got to finish
the first K and then start the second
kid. Yeah. It's, it's, it's,
it's, yeah, it's kind of a,
I think it would be considered
what they call it. Glottal stops.
So like Hokkaido in Japan is
actually Ho guy though. Right? Right.
But if there was only one kid be
Hokkaido. That's right. Yeah. Yeah. We're,
school took me a long time, which was
really embarrassing in the beginning,
working on my pronunciation.
Uh,
I had to say the word school a lot. I
was going to school, walking to school.
When are you going to school and its goal,
which has that little stutter and man,
did I mess that up?
Well,
I certainly uh,
cast a broad apology to all of
my Japanese friends especially,
they're going to be going crazy.
I'm sorry.
It's interesting that you care because in,
in,
in the Hawaiian language they put a,
it's actually considered another
letter. It's, it's called the Oak Kenai.
It's basically an apostrophe. In Hawaii
there's a lot of vowels go together,
right?
So when you want,
when you want to do that little function
to separate them, you put the Oak Ina,
they're like, like the word Hawaii,
Hawaii. There's two eyes at the end.
So you say Hawaii, you remember you
were asking me, Oh, I just say call.
How do you say quiets it quiet?
[inaudible] I think technically it's cool.
I typically don't say cola anymore.
That's a whole nother theory. Very similar
but similar deal, right? Similar deal.
Like, this is with consonant, straight A,
and I don't want to take
us too far afield, but you,
there are some really weird similarities
between Japanese and other languages
where there may have been trade roots
established before the dawn of man in
weird places.
Uh,
so there are some commonalities
in Polynesian languages
and then you also find
incredible commonalities with
Turkish of all languages. Yeah.
Nearly identical grammar.
I remember when I was taking
linguistic classes and their,
what they would point out these weird,
weird commonalities that you say, wow,
that's, you know, like things that like
the number one things like the sun,
things that it,
you know,
everyone kind of has to have
created a word for it some point.
The other is definitely some
strings and I forget what they are.
I didn't study hard enough. I wasn't
on the path fit and closely enough.
But a lot of these languages like that,
you know,
even the pronunciation of like a is
Ah, you know, Japanese Hawaiian, yeah.
You know, all these very
soft bowels. Typically.
Yeah. Uh, a e O Ooh. Yeah.
And then that I is like e yeah.
Japanese people can handle Spanish is
probably the closest that I've seen
language that they can handle.
Any language that ends on consonants,
a lot is going to be so right. I
remember. They've such tough time.
They add the you at the end. Yeah.
The teams and Tim, Tim or Jeff,
the same mcbeaty or yeah, be it
a nub. I beat her. Mcdonald's
is Monica Donato. Yay.
And then they have a tough
time. Uh, but the, and the,
for those people wondering,
the reason they can't or have
so much trouble distinguishing
between r's and L's,
which many other Asian people do not.
But in the case of Japanese is because
they have a blended phoneme of blended
sound. It's a, it's a combination
of our l and d. So naughty you dude.
It is how they say it.
So that do that like sound is not clearly
distinguished into multiple consonants
in Japanese, which is why they have
so much trouble with r's and L's.
But you can teach them to
fix that in a few minutes.
If you explain how the
tongue is positioned.
And I remember at one point I give
credit to my first Japanese teacher,
Mr Shimano,
who was fantastic because we would
hit a sticking point in class,
we'd be going over some concept that was
really difficult for a native English
speaker,
his brain to wrap itself around,
like they have subject markers and the
difference between why God and if it's
known to the speaker, it's
this, if they're not known
to the speaker, it's that.
And you're like, what's like,
what does that even mean?
And he could sense because,
uh, I, I transferred
from a very weak school,
very bad school on long island to a
very highly competitive school in New
Hampshire that had classes six
days a week, mandatory seated meal,
like dead Poets Society,
Mandatory Sports classes from 8:00 AM
or so to about 6:00 PM and the Japanese
class was very often the class after
sports. So people were wiped out,
hadn't had dinner,
and we'd be struggling in getting agitated
with some aspect of Japanese and he
could tell that we were,
we were, we were losing it,
but we still had 45 minutes to go.
So it's all right.
Had a really strong Japanese
accent and he'd be like,
we're gonna stop for a minute and I'm
going to attempt to say this word for you.
And you would write squirrel
on the blackboard if you
want to talk about a word
that would be designed to be Kryptonite
for Japanese person. And so he would,
he would take like five minutes for just
comedic effect to just go scar scorer,
screw. I need to do that for like two
minutes and we crack up and loosen up and
realize, okay, everyone is
learning a new language,
has some type of sticking point like
this. And then he'd be like, okay,
enough fun and games. Now back to
the hard stuff. He's an excellent,
excellent teacher. Yeah,
it's legit. Speaking of hard
stuff,
speak quick,
my brother please for
the love of God all good.
I was going to talk more about your
retreat, but we can talk about that later.
In the meantime,
wouldn't take care of her joints or gin.
main.com is a good spot to
get these joint supplements.
Chaco supplements, Super Krill
Oil, not just regular Krill oil.
Supercar Krill oil. Yeah, clearly. All
upstairs actually. Boom. There you go.
Also another one called
Jocko joint warfare.
It's a blend of joint degeneration,
warfare,
weapons check technically also
for some legit fitness gear.
If you're in the kettle, you into
kettlebells. Yeah, I have some in my, uh,
my garage here.
It's the only,
the only fitness tools I have right now
are two kilovolts. Boom. There you go.
So boom, I got mine from
on it. Yeah. Squat rack.
I go to a gym for that right now,
but yeah, yeah, yeah. I'll get,
I'll get kettlebells are
dope. Yeah. Especially the
ones from audit, by the way.
Werewolf gorilla,
bigfoot chimp.
I'm just listing the ones. Oh, I
thought you were calling me names.
The thing you're trying
out new names for me.
Those are the kettle kettlebells I
have, you know, the autistic one,
the dope months. Did you say artistic
or autistic artists? I'm just curious.
Just messing with and I don't
think they're up to stick at all,
but they are dope though. My opinion,
you're the regular ones. I have the ISO.
We're, we're sitting
here in Austin, Texas.
Not too far from Vaughn at HQ and I
actually bought two of the standard issue.
I know you're like me. Yeah. Just cut,
not cut the decorations and just go.
I click got training in star
wars ones though. They do. Yeah,
the Darth Vader one and storm trooper.
The Darth Vader once. Cool. Yeah,
I've seen it. You got to kind of admit
it after awhile. You're like, okay,
I mean me, I don't care. I'm
like, Hey, come to my house.
See my kettle bells. Yeah,
they're dope. But some people
Jocko, they're like, no, you know,
wants to say hardcore,
but you got to admit it.
I'm more of a Boba Fett guy myself.
But yeah, I do like Darth Vader. Yeah,
check those out anyway on it.com Mecca.
And they got other stuff on there too. Um,
pretty much for any kind
of workout other than what,
like your typical gym workout,
like they have maces and whatnot.
So anyway, go down on it. Yeah. And just
as a side note for people listening,
don't, alright. I've had enough caffeine.
I've been off of caffeine for 10 days.
So we do a lot of personality
right now. Uh, all good.
Don't let perfect be the enemy of good
when it comes to working out or home gyms
or anything like that.
Don't say I can't start because I don't
have these seven pieces of equipment for
two years when I had very little money
and was training in Jujitsu when I just
moved to the bay area,
which is stupidly expensive.
I had roommates and no space whatsoever.
I had one 53 pound kettle bell and I did
everything with that kettle I did and I
got into that combined with Jujitsu,
that's all I had space for.
It was one kettle bell. I got into some
of the best shape of my entire life. Yeah.
You're like kettled off 53 pounds.
That's nothing. It's like, okay,
do 20 pistols with 50 pounder. Yeah. Yeah.
Let's see if you can do one
review the three pounds.
Cause a lot of people couldn't even do
one pistol with a 53 pound kettlebell.
Yeah. That's like the goal.
Yeah. Yeah. And I'll say,
I don't want to say I was
against kettlebells before,
but you know when they first kind
of came on the scene here. Yeah.
And then people were like, yeah,
kettlebells and look how cool we are.
You know how like when people do that,
you kind of build this kind of natural,
not resentment, but just
some resistance. Like,
I'm not going to jump on your little band.
Like I see what you're doing, you know,
I'm a stick to this.
Or,
and then finally I got on the boat and
kind of shit it got on that earlier man.
Kettlebells and you don't need to be,
I will say not a doctor,
don't play one on the Internet,
but just to uh,
to keep Jockos liability
insurance premiums,
low kettlebells.
Don't get too fancy.
Kids with the kettle bells.
Don't pick up a kettle ball for the first
time and tried to do snatches. Yeah,
it's a good way to, uh, get
reconstructive shoulder surgery.
You don't need to do a whole lot if you
just do two handed Kettlebell swings
properly, which I would not in my
book would not be above the shoulder.
And you do,
let's just say some Turkish getups,
even partial Turkish getups and
a handful of other exercises.
I'm particular wind mills
in caustic squads and so on.
You really don't need much and you,
you don't have to do potentially dangerous
ballistic movements to get a lot out
of kettlebells.
Yeah.
And I personally would even go further
and say don't do much like especially
like the like Turkish get the snatch too.
Like these ones where snatch beautiful
color. Yeah. If you're trying to like,
let me get that big one.
Cause it's cool.
You look at them and this one's like
obviously bigger than the other.
I'm going to get down mean the
last time you were at my house,
I was over there dude. Every exercise
with the biggest kettlebells I asked me.
Yeah. So I dig it man. But man, if you
start doing these snatches or the man,
I had to have this big foot one,
it's 90 pounds and me.
So I can, I mean now I can boom, clean,
impressed one hand I'll go like, oh, go
to this side to this, that in to this,
you know, I'll do that.
And it wasn't like,
I don't know if I wasn't warm or
I just hit it at the wrong angle.
I got it up to here and
then when I pressed it up,
I think he was too far back. So it went
like when I press it was weird. You know,
kettle bells are they big tank back there.
So when I pressed it up it's
almost like it went backwards.
Messed up my shoulder a
little bit. Yeah. Yeah.
You will be able to press
as well as you can clean.
So if you cannot clean a weight
extremely smoothly to your side,
do not try to press it. Yeah. It had
been, just be careful. Start Light.
That's the point,
right?
Yeah.
Unless you're Jocko,
I'm not saying anything over
here because of liability.
I know I give the worst advice on this
kind of stuff, so sometimes yes, for sure.
Also if you don't have a copy of Musashi,
yeah,
I'm going to list it on the website,
a Goto Jocko podcast.com.
Go to the books section right there
on the top menu. Boom. Click on there.
It will be actually,
it's been on there.
It's been on there since you mentioned
it. It's been on there for a year. Yeah,
I'll put it right at the top. Don't even
have to scroll down. Boom. Click on it.
It is good.
I had another book to the page
or Cortland thousand percent.
That's a lot of percent. I'm on it. Uh,
so I have a brand new book that is out,
which Jocko is a part of as a,
as a continuation of our
lifelong partnership.
Jocko has a reappearance
in tribe of mentors,
which is I think the easiest to read
book that I have yet put together.
It is a brand spanking new who has 130
people all asked the same 11 questions
that were most burning for me.
And uh,
is that a thousand page book because it's
this thick. It's shorter than Musashi,
which isn't saying much.
It is a about 650 pages.
Each profile is ranges between two in
10 pages and a number of the people who
came up in our conversation,
like Dan Gable who won a gold medal in
the Olympics for wrestling without having
a single point scored on him.
Ridiculous.
It's like winning Wimbledon and
that having a point scored on. Yeah,
it doesn't happen. People, uh,
and many, many, many others.
So it covers every possible
facet of human performance,
whether it's a physical
training, uh, expert meditators,
worldclass investors, the founders of
Facebook, Twitter, salesforce, linkedin,
you name it. If you want super,
super tactical and nuggets of advice,
including some from our
good friend Jocko Willink,
then Sharben mentors is a easy to digest.
Choose your own adventure book.
That would be a nice nonfiction
compliment to our friend Musashi. Yeah,
I'm put it up there right
next to it. Boom. And so what
that does is you click on,
it takes you through to
Amazon. Boom. What was the,
what was the website again for
your book page? Jocko, podcast.com.
I think it might be slash books maybe,
but easiest way,
you know the top menu on the website,
but it just, it looks from the pot,
from episodes, whatever I am. Yeah. Click
on there, boom. Click through there.
And if you're doing any other Amazon
shopping, you know, hey, carry on.
No one's going to stop you there.
Also subscribe to the podcast.
I was just going to say,
they may have already removed this,
a little glitch in
the system, but I used to be
able to buy trap bars and so on,
on Amazon prime with
no shipping trap bars.
So hex bar. Oh right,
right. It's like a hug,
like 60 pounds to a hundred
pounds of metal. Uh,
so while you're picking
up your brain food,
you can pick up your body
tools. Boom. Eventually dig it.
Amazon. Yeah, Amazon is pretty
good with their shipping situation.
I gotta tell you, even if the, you want
it, like whatever the next day, you know,
we were like good additional shipping.
It's like four bucks or something. Oh,
it's amazing. Yeah. He got something
right on that one. You know,
I also subscribe to the podcast if you
haven't already on iTunes and stitcher
and Google play and Spotify.
I think,
I think real confident that
whatever you're listening to,
the podcast on, boom, subscribe. Also
on Youtube. If you haven't already,
there's more than just the podcast I
needed to. It's excerpts on Youtube.
What are you going to put some,
some takeaways or what did they call it?
Outtakes from this because there
were some pretty funny ones.
They were, but we were all
laughing. I think so. In fact, yes,
that's exactly what I'm going to do,
which is one of the many reasons to
subscribe to the Youtube Channel,
in my opinion.
What is the Youtube Channel?
Jocko podcasts do your big role,
the ubiquitous,
so make sure we spell it out.
I'm so bad at this.
I'm just the hand wavy PT Barnum
guy gets technically were true.
When we say subscribe to the podcast,
technically we are asking them to go
on Youtube, search for Jocko podcast.
Make sure it's the correct one. You
know, sometimes there'll be like jock, go
see Tim adding tons of, yeah, you
could just get, you could get,
and, uh, since this will not be
published for probably a few hours,
at least you guys could get a URL like
Jocko subscribed.com and then have it
point to a page on your website where you
have all of the links where people can
click for different services to subscribe.
Man,
I wish I had somebody that worked with
me that like did computer type stuff and
stuff like that because maybe they would
have done that at the beginning when we
first started this stuff like that.
I was thinking of all of these things.
This is what I'm going to buy
Jocko, podcasts, this and all this.
Then we can have them all and we'll,
I'll do this stuff. And then, um,
like your whole attitude.
You didn't tell me not to do it.
I'm not blaming this on you.
I'm just saying that that's
what I was real fired up to
do. But he's like, no man,
that's it. Jocko store. That's
it. You know, like super
simple. So I'm like, Oh yeah,
that's, that's cool right there. So like
all the cool little thing. I will, I'll,
I'll, I will jockos defense, you know, say
I see tears welling up in the
eyes. Uh, in Giagos defense,
I will say that a lot of people who try
to start podcasts or do x get caught
with the obsession on new tactics.
And then above tactics you would have
strategy and the most strategy would have
principles.
And so if,
if you're constantly focused on
optimizing for an additional 1% with these
tools, you get nowhere. On the
other hand, if I would say,
like you guys have done with
this podcast to focus on
exceptionally high quality,
that fixes a lot of problems.
And then other people use tactics on
your behalf and you don't have to be as
concerned with the ebb and flow
and expiration dates of said tools.
So there's always a good time.
Always a market
uncrowded market is great.
That's the only uncredited market.
Dang. See. And just to be
clear, when you were like that,
it wasn't that you were like
influencing me not to do it.
You just like the way you were was cool
to me. I was like, Dang, that's cool.
So I'm going to just keep
it super simple to me.
Just kind of trying to be like you.
But yeah, I thought of that same thing.
I'm going to have the thing and
it'll have all the links. Aw Man.
That'll be great. Then meanwhile he's
like, let's record a podcast, so, okay,
let's do that. You know, so we
let that other stuff go. Anyway,
Youtube, back to youtube,
Jocko podcast, regular logo,
black white letters. Boom. That's it.
That's the one that you want to
subscribe to. Also, Jack was the store.
It's called chocolate store and I see
that. No bells, no whistles. Jocko,
store.com t shirts, travel mugs,
bumper stickers, all that stuff.
Some rash guards,
new rash guards,
hoodies, picker, hoodies. I got
people sending Marines, thermometers,
Nebraska actually. Yeah,
someone did that to me
too. What about your, uh,
your crop tops with the discipline equals
love on them for those out of stock
still.
Those are out of stock broker
actually, but the women's stuff is back
in stock as well. That was out for awhile.
Luke girls, you know for the
girls, for the ladies, boom,
back in the game, big time.
Some patches in there. And again,
the rash guards where your kid,
I think that's the one. Yeah,
actually there's another one. Yeah,
you or got them around.
Any question about rash guards?
I always assumed because I had never seen
rash guards until a few years into the
Jujitsu game,
I guess or observing that I assumed
that rash guards became part of Jujitsu
because Brazilians also surf a lot and
would then just use them in the gym.
What is the function of the rash guard?
I've never understood that.
I knew that because let's say versus
wearing a tight fitting like sweat wicking
shirt. Well, I mean it's not going to
be as tight fitting as a rash guard is,
right? A rash guard is
as tight Vinnie's, uh,
piece of garment can be and therefore
your fingers won't get caught in it.
Your toes won't get caught in it,
it won't get in the way. And that's,
that's why now you can also just go
shirtless, but when you go shirtless,
now you've got ringworm and,
and all whatever other heinous forms,
diseases that live on the mat. And so
that's, and it's just Kinda, you know,
it just takes it one,
one separation away from pure nastiness
when you're rolling with everyone.
But you guys should make,
maybe I'm the only one with this issue,
but I always find,
I feel constricted at the neck and the
hot in certain rash guards so that all
rash guards, but if there were one
that gave some space to the neck,
that would be,
yeah,
I think some brands
will have a wider neck,
wider know some brands will actually on
purpose have like a higher neck. Right.
Some people want full coverage in the gym.
They want,
they don't want to make
human contact with anyone.
It's just the Spiderman outfit while
they're trying to throw it out.
There's people that were in a little
hoods, I'm not kidding. So yeah,
it's getting crazy. People with
like hair or something like that,
they'll do that hood thing.
That's cool. But I can get you,
I can give you whatever kind of Roger
you want to loose neck, rash, guard.
I'll get your loose. Recommend
that rash guard. No one piece.
Say Discipline Equals love. If you
could get me a discipline equals love.
UNITARDS for my reentry
to the Jujitsu world,
that'll go over good.
Just before I tapped at t Ferris out,
I commented on his garment,
but yeah. Hey Jocko, store.com that's
where you get them. They're cool.
Also psychological warfare,
if you didn't know what that is,
it's an album with tracks.
Tim Ferris that if
you're on the path Foley,
but you find those days or those moments,
whatever,
that maybe you might
want to get this store.
You feel like you're going to
choose to step off the path.
That's what it's for really. It's not
like when you suddenly get distracted,
it's like I'm going to wake up at
what? Five and um, just to, to,
I'm not going to wake up at five.
I'm gonna Sleep in.
He listened to one of these tracks.
This specified tracked though.
Wake up and get a, what's it called?
Wake up and get her fruit wake up.
You can get after it.
What it is is you play it and it's Jocko
telling you why you should wake up and
get after it pragmatically in
his own Jocko away. But there's,
there's tracks for everything. No
waking up, slipping on the diets,
skipping the workout, blah,
blah, blah. All that stuff. No,
let me interject here or actually
take over if you don't mind please.
Because the psychological
warfare, tra, uh,
album on iTunes was a number
one spoken word album for about,
I think nine months straight.
And unfortunately, good
news and bad news,
it was just taken down for I,
we just got beat out as the number one
album. There's now a new number one album.
Giraffes can't dance is not,
you're asking the new number one album
on iTunes spoken word is discipline
equals freedom field manual. Now it
was number one. Did you share that?
I get the report every day.
So if you've been looking for discipline
equals freedom field manual in audio
form yet formula,
it's not on audible because then
you couldn't put it in your alarm.
You couldn't listen to tracks
whenever you want it to.
That's why we didn't do it that way.
We put it is an as an album
with tracks on Amazon music,
Google play,
Spotify apart everywhere.
I think you can ask Alexa, she'll deliver
it. Alexa, like boom, you're there.
Uh, so that's out. Also
on Amazon Jocko white tea.
Most people think it's the best tea that
they've ever had and it's guaranteed,
um,
and scientifically proven to increase your
deadlift to a minimum of 8,000 pounds.
We have all backed up data on that. A
little blind, double blind, Quik trip,
quadruple blind other books to get on
Amazon and we might as well just put all
these books on our website.
Uh, so first Tim, Tim,
obviously four hour workweek,
four hour chef,
four hour body tools of titans.
Those are all books,
awesome books.
And I was thinking about four hour work
week and what I was thinking about for
our work week that I think when
I read it for the first time,
which was before I knew you what it did,
I didn't follow anything in your
book for our work week. I didn't,
I don't even follow one
thing. Maybe May, I dunno,
maybe there's two or
three things in there.
What it did though is it made me look
at things in a different way cause you
were saying, look, here's this and
you looked at it from over here.
And what it showed me was like I can
look at things differently and you know,
like I said, I probably grabbed
a couple things from there.
But the most important thing
that it gave me was like, okay,
you don't have to look at this the way
everyone else is looking at it and that's
the,
that's the best damn drill you can get
from somebody or the best advice you can
get somebody who's like don't look at
things the same way. Everyone else.
There's a whole nother angle.
And once I saw what angle you were
looking at it from, I looked at,
I started saying,
well let's look at it from my ankle.
What does this going to look like from
over here? So that's a great book.
And again, the four hour chef,
which is, it's about cooking,
but it's really about learning.
It's really about learning for our body.
All kinds of good experiments
that you did on yourself.
You're similar to me in the fact that
I'm always chasing some different goal.
I'm either trying to do Max pull ups
or I'm trying to do a Max deadlift for,
I'm trying to cut down
my one mile run time.
I'm always got some random thing
that I'm trying to do. And I, and,
and I explained this,
I'm actually,
I actually explained it when
I was just on your podcast. I,
if I'm not going to get to a 600 pound
dead lift because my whole life would
have to be different and I wouldn't be
able to do other things that I to do.
So I get to an 80% or an 85% of what
I'm actually humanly capable of.
And then I'm looking for that next
goal because I'm not going to change my
entire life. Uh, but what, what the,
what the four hour body is good for is
you've got a lot of different things that
you can bounce from thing to thing and
they're all going to improve some aspect.
So I thought that was awesome.
Tools of titans,
obviously tons of of good information
from all a lot of different people and,
and now you've got tribal mentors
and it's interesting because
you know when we talk about for 20 minutes
or however long we were talking about
the path for, well for people
out there that are saying
like, well what, what path?
And I'm sitting here trying to explain it,
it's hard.
I don't think I did a good job.
I took a swing at it.
But what's cool is you get a book like
tribe of mentors and you can kind of get
a feel for what other people's paths are
and how they stay on them and way they
live their lives.
And then you can at least at a minimum
get a different perspective from
different people,
which just like four hour work week for
me is very important to see different
people's angles on the way
they look at things. It's,
it's like it's an eye opener at a minimum.
Yeah,
the Lens. I mean, if you,
if you have a set of different lenses
that you can look through to evaluate the
world and make decisions,
evaluate yourself and make
different decisions, it's,
it can really change your life and
the lives of those around you very,
very quickly. Uh, what's,
what's been fun about putting
together in this case,
tribe of mentors is that I'm asking
people the same 11 questions.
So for instance,
I might ask,
what do you do or what do you tell
yourself when you feel overwhelmed or get
distracted? As we were talking about
staying on the path, and I asked I,
that was one of the questions that I
sent to everyone and people were able to
pick and choose their questions.
But when you see that across disciplines,
and so you have everyone from say
David Lynch,
where Darren Aronofsky,
who were incredible
directors to the Dan Gables,
the, uh, Kelly Slater's most
decorated surfer of all time, uh,
to artists and investors and so on.
There are commonalities so you can spot
patterns and then assemble your own
toolkit of these first principles we've
been talking about. So, for instance,
one that I've been applying,
there are many that I've been
applying myself from the book. Uh,
you may have met Kyle Maynard before.
I know who he is, said I have better.
We have. So Kyle, incredible
guy, uh, congenital quad amputee,
that means he was born without arms
or legs, became a wrestler. I mean,
among many other things.
I mean, became a wrestler,
lost every match is for a season in his,
uh,
his dad supported him throughout it all.
They were accused of child abuse. He kept
competing and then he started winning.
And the same people who said it was
child abuse were like, oh, he isn't. Now.
He has an unfair advantage. Just people
can't grab his arms and legs. I was like,
really? Wow. What a world. And uh,
just a fascinating guy who has done a lot,
climbed Kilimanjaro.
I think he was the first
person ever to do so.
A quad amputee without prosthetics
carried the ashes of a, uh,
a fallen,
a member of our military to the top,
which was there one of their dying wishes.
And he gave a piece of advice that
he learned from a business icon,
which was you can't answer seven and
what that refers to is any time you are
rating for yourself,
say how important something is or how
much you want to do something on a scale
of zero to 10 you can't use seven.
If you're asking someone for feedback,
they can't use seven. Why? Because
all of a sudden now they can't choose.
What I realized after
reading it and is a safe,
comfortable, nebulous number,
and that's always seven.
Now you have to choose a six which is
barely better than 50% or an eight and
you,
you get to,
you accelerate your path
to better decisions almost
immediately just by adopting
that or the way that, say
Daniel Negreanu, fader Holtz.
These are two of the biggest
winning poker players of all time.
One in live, in person
tournaments, the other online,
and to look at their decision frameworks,
how they decide, how much to bet,
how they stake other people.
These are all tools that you can apply
everywhere. It's really cool stuff.
Uh, so yeah, travel mentors has been
a very, very fun book to put together.
Yeah, it's a, I've been on the road,
but one of your people sent it to me,
so I think it's waiting for me
at my house when I get back.
So I'm stoked on that one.
And what you showed me that flip through,
that's kind of why I know it's,
I'm going to be cool for people
to get again, find, find,
find the path, find various paths and,
and help them, guide them towards, there's
also run it a couple other books. One of
them is called way of the warrior kid.
It's about a kid who
turns into a warrior kid.
Best book ever. Uh, extreme
ownership book about leadership.
It's
combat leadership principles from war and
how to apply them in your business and
life. The discipline equals
freedom field manual. Um,
once again, to everyone that got
this book, including Tim. Yes.
Thank you for supporting it. Uh, also
the, the book because of your support,
it made the on New York Times bestseller
list, which is, which is pretty awesome.
Thank you everyone. Thank you, Tim.
Course. Um, that's awesome. And,
and you know the book,
it doesn't follow any formula really.
It's not normal. It's kind of
like this podcast is not normal.
It's not [inaudible] not everyone's going
to get it. Some people going to turn it
on this podcast and go eat. I don't
think I can listen to that. That's okay.
Same thing with the book.
That's okay too.
I'm not here to write things
that everyone likes him.
I'm not here to record a podcast and
everyone listens to, wants to listen to.
I'm okay with that. Um,
those of you that do get it,
thank you for forgetting it.
For those of you don't get it.
Why are you still listening?
Three and a half years later,
it's not punishing yourself there.
They're imposing discipline on themselves.
I can make it this guy's annoying
voice for another 20 minutes.
Like I said, the Audio version
is on empathy MP3 platforms.
I've been asked that 5,000
times on social media.
I've answered everywhere by the
way, everywhere. So that's good.
If you need some leadership support for
your team or for your business echelon
front, that's our leadership consulting
company. It's me, Leif, Babin,
JP to know Dave Burke,
info@echelonfront.com.
If you want to get it echo,
you got any clothing songs. That's
it. Thanks Tim. Again. Yeah.
Thank you gentlemen.
Then I use the word gentlemen loosely
if you want to keep this conversation
going.
We are actually on the interwebs
fairly heavily on Twitter,
Instagram and a face, a bulky,
um, echo is an echo. Charles.
I am at jockowillink and Tim
is at t Ferriss. Two R's,
two s's on Twitter,
on Instagram at Tim Ferriss.
Two R's, two s's on Facebook.
Tim Ferris, you got it.
Did I miss anything else? All right.
Tim, any closing thoughts from you sir?
Any closing thoughts?
I'll share one quote if people like quotes
that I think relates well to a lot of
what we talked about and certainly
Musashi and this is a quote from RK locus.
So by the sound of the name
you might guess it's very,
very old and it is,
we do not rise to the
level of our expectations.
We fall to the level of our training.
Hope is not a strategy as
James Cameron would say.
Train hard, train, train hard. Uh,
Tim as always,
thanks for everything.
I literally would not be sitting
here right now if it wasn't for you.
Um, and what's cool is you've helped
me out a lot, but more importantly,
you've helped out all kinds of people all
over the world. I think that's awesome.
The content that you put out,
the advice that you give to people.
And so thank you for what you've done
for me and thanks for what you do for all
kinds of people everywhere. Thank
you John. Much appreciated. Uh,
and while I'm thanking
people to close this out,
I'm want to thank the real warriors out
there better in uniform on the front,
holding the line against evil.
Thank you for what you do.
And those of you that are back
here in uniform at home, police,
law enforcement, firefighters, paramedics,
all the other first responders,
thank you all for keeping our homeland
safe and to everyone else that's
listening
this,
remember that the world is filled with
the sound of waves and the waves are
filled with little fishes.
Let them play,
let them dance.
Let them sing you.
You get on the path and stay on
the path and keep getting after it.
And until next time,
this is Tim Ferriss and echo and Jocko
out.