Jocko, you've talked about how getting
into into adversarial relationships is
pointless, but people always get into
adversarial relationships with me.
I've been told them scary
before but never understood why.
My question is how do I maneuver on this
without acting like a little weakling
bitch for lack of a better term,
to appear less threatening.
Do I just accept that I
rub people the wrong way?
So this is a question there.
I'll do my best to answer cause it's
time for definitely time for some self
awareness here for the
individual asking this question.
It sounds like you are,
you know,
a big abrasive person that is aggressive
and intimidates people and I know what
it's like to be that
person because I could be,
I could come across as intimidating.
I know that um,
I can definitely come across as
aggressive. I can be aggressive.
I am aggressive in many ways, abrasive.
I don't know that not necessarily uh,
um,
categorizes me because I'm very cautious
about not being abrasive because if I'm
being abrasive with people, am I building
a relationship under, make any progress?
The answer's obviously no.
So something,
the thing is when I hear
this type of question,
okay,
I, I think that there's some little bit
of insecurity going on here, right? Some,
a little bit of, hey that's not
an insult. That's what I sense.
Cause everyone's got insecurity's I do.
Everybody does and but,
but the fact that you asked this question,
I'm hoping that that means you want to
make some kind of improvement. All right.
Do you want to get better? And you know,
I'm a little worried that you might just
be looking for like reinforcement cause
people think jock was big and aggressive.
So if I say I'm big and aggressive,
I'll, you know, jock, who
was just going to say,
hey those people are just scared of you
and they don't deserve your mercy or you
don't. You Do, you use your intimidation
factor. Overrun those people. Right?
That might be what you're looking for,
but you're not going to get that here.
And the reason you're not gonna get that,
here's cause that's not going to help you.
It's not going to help
you achieve your goals.
Can you talk about people
being scared of you?
But the fact likely is,
is that you're the one that scared.
Okay.
In, in, you actually said it yourself,
that you don't want to appear to be weak.
You don't want to appear to be a bitch.
Yeah.
That is that feeling.
That's fear.
That's fear. It's fear of looking
weak. It's fear of looking wrong.
It's fear of failure and
it's fear of vulnerability.
And those are, those are, those are real.
And if you're, you know, everybody should
be feeling those fears. I at some level,
but you have to overcome those fears.
If you don't,
then how are you ever
going to step up if you're,
if you're too afraid to be wrong, how are
you? You're going to answer a question.
If you're too afraid to
look weak, how are you ever going
to exposures? Any weaknesses?
And if you don't expose any weaknesses,
well just build a bunker around yourself
and sit in there by herself. You.
So as a leader, we know that up
and down the chain of command,
you need to develop
relationships, right? That's what,
that's what you're supposed to do.
That means you need to
communicate with people.
That means you need to talk and you need
to listen and you need to develop trust.
And one of the best ways to develop trust
with other people is by exposing some
vulnerability, by saying, hack on,
I'm not quite sure how to do
this. Or Hey, echo, hey, can you,
can you help me with this
issue I have going on here?
I don't know how to solve it.
That's ways that you build trust
and thereby build relationships.
And it's hard to do that because
you don't want to look stupid.
You don't want to look weak.
You don't want to admit you don't know
something because you want to be Mr.
Strong and know everything
in.
So you're probably putting up a front.
Yeah,
an aggressive front and abrasive front.
It's a wall to keep people intimidated.
And then in your mind you
think it's not my fault,
it's their fault because
they're scared of me.
It's their fault because
I'm so intimidating.
So that is not good. And then you get
the you're kind of closing statement.
Should you just accept that I rub
people the wrong way. You can.
You can't accept that you
rub people the wrong way,
but then you might as well accept right
then and there that you're never going
to be a true leader.
That's,
you're never going to build
any relationships that
you're never going to inspire
anybody and you're never going to
be the leader of a bad ass unified,
high performing team,
probably not worth it.
And the, the better thing to do
is to humble yourself,
is to open yourself up to the pain and
the discomfort of displaying weakness and
error and failure
and open yourself up to try
and be nice to other people
instead being scared of what's going
to happen if you expose yourself.
Go ahead and throw it out there,
act
pleasant to them so they
talk to you without fear.
And in doing those things,
you can overcome whatever
these under insecurities are.
And I dunno what the insecures you have.
It could be any number of things.
Maybe you don't think
you're smart as they are.
Maybe you don't think you're
as well educated as they are.
Maybe you don't think that they have,
you have the strategic vision that they
have. Whatever those insecurities are,
it's all good. We all
got them. No big deal.
But if you stop hiding
them and you own them,
hmm,
you will become not only a better leader,
but to become a better man.
So
take a breath
and get home
and take another crack at this gig.
You know,
I think losing your
temper is a huge red flag.
Like I've always said and always will
say huge red flag if you ever lose your
temper. And I'm nothing screaming, yell.
I'm just saying you're getting
mad and displaying that
anger. Well, what's really,
what's really what's really bad is when
people utilize their temper as a tool to
scare and intimidate people.
So they go, all, man,
I don't want to say anything to Jocko
on this cause you got to go loses,
loses temper, whose mind
go crazy like that. That's,
that's me using it as a tool,
which is not good because you're
not building any relationship too.
You're not getting any input from people.
You're, you're not respected by the way.
People might fear you if you have a
bad temper, but they don't respect you.
They're not calling you up
and asking you for advice.
They're not wanting you to run
their, their project. Yeah.
No. And they're not motivated to do
good by you when you're not around.
They are definitely not motivated to
do good by you and you're not around.
In fact, the only reason they do
anything is out of fear, you know?
Whereas if you have a
relationship with them,
you could leave for six months and the
people that know you and respect you and
care about you and have relation to,
there's still busting their ass to
do the best they can for you. Yup.
Glad when you come back to yeah.
Yeah. In, in a lot of times,
like,
so the adversarial relationship thing,
there's a way to look at it is
it kind of takes both you to,
to kind of cultivate an
adversarial relationship. It goes,
goes for any kind of relationship, but,
well, yes and no, it will. Okay. So,
um, you, you keep being
a dick to me, we'll say.
And if I just keep being nice to you,
even though you're being a dick to me,
even though we have a job to do what it,
yes, all in all that and we're
maintaining the integrity of that.
But I'm keep being nice to you.
You keep being a dick to me.
I keep being nice to you after a while.
The way that shakes
itself out is I'm be nice.
You know the next person. Yeah,
no. Well, here's the thing.
We're still getting the job done and
whatever, but my re, my response to you,
if you'd be a dick to me is not be a
dick back or defend. You know, it's,
it's just be nice. Oh, you know, it's a,
where are you going to say it
shakes out as it shakes out.
The one guy who's a Dick stands out.
Yeah.
So everyone's being cool and
when all is said and done,
we're just dealing with one
guy is a dick. So if you, if,
if you cultivate the adversarial
relationship, it's like, okay,
you have this competitive situation
now to people that, you know,
or Dick or guys that are jerks,
which ended up with, yeah,
and let's say you were a
nice guy to begin with.
Don't become a jerk now.
You know, it's true. So,
and I'm saying that because a lot of times
if you're like gay people were Crete,
uh,
creating adversarial relationship with me,
you're going to play a part in that
relationship, you know? Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. And the thing with this
question, and you know, I mean,
even the terminology used,
which, which is, you know,
how do I maneuver on this without
acting like a little bitch? Literally.
So you gotta figure, not, not, you know,
not the most mature person. So I'm,
I'm guessing, hey man, you're probably
22, you know, 24 something like that,
or you're haven't matured a lot and you're
27, but you're still caught in that,
in that game. And I think a
lot of times, you know, uh,
people when they,
when they meet me or they,
they learn about me or I
show up at their business,
they think I'm going to
be that guy that's like,
we're going to just come in here and,
and it's,
it's always really cool
when people go, man, yeah,
I didn't think of that. It's, Oh, you
have this approach that we didn't expect.
And I'm like, yeah, you know, and by
now most people kind of, you know,
at this stage and echelon front,
and when I show up some work,
people have listened to as they know
where I'm coming from now, but you know,
two years ago,
you know,
they expected this big sergeant slaughter
type thing to go down these folks to
whip these people in shape.
And,
and my guess is that the individual that
asks this question was kind of thinking
he would get some moral support from me.
And I'm trying to give them moral support
because I want her to be successful
because I want him to go out
and dominate in the world.
But to go out and dominate in the world,
you have to be a a chess player,
not a checkers player.
You gotta,
you gotta think you gotta
use the relationships.
You've got to use indirect warfare
to go out there and be blunt,
force trauma and everybody, it'll
get you, it'll get you, you know,
it'll get you a, a quarter of
the way there if you're lucky.
And then it'll, it won't get you
the rest of the way. So just, just,
it's no big deal, man. You're young. You
got some learning to do. That's awesome.
I wish I would have been smart enough
to ask this question when I was a young,
stupid 23 year old. You
got some, you're thinking,
you recognize that you're in a situation,
so all you gotta do is just, uh,
just start taking a different approach,
a little bit more of an indirect approach,
a little bit more of an open mind,
a little bit more humility.
Don't worry about looking weak when you,
the people that are scared to look weak
are the people that are weak. Right.
The people that are okay being exposed
are the people that are strong.
Like I'm totally comfortable
in my leadership capabilities.
So when I have an issue, I'm like, Hey,
I don't feel comfortable with this.
I'm not worried that somebody
is not going to say like, oh,
well we don't think you can
handle this, that, no, no,
no. I actually, I know I can.
I've been in worse situation.
So what he got. Yeah.
So if you're paranoid about looking weak,
it means you probably are weak.
If you don't care about
being looking weak,
it probably means that you're coming
along, you know you're doing pretty good.
Yeah.
Check.
So you don't need a hard
shell if you have a hardcore,
but you need art shell. If you have a
softcore yes. That is true kind of thing.
Yes. Did you just make
that up? Yeah, but I mean,
I'm not looking at it like, Dang, that
was deep. I'm not, I'm not thinking that.
But that is a true statement.
If you're,
if you're fundamentally sound on the
internal and the meaningful structure of
your, of your being, then
you can withstand attacks.
So you don't need to put up a
big wall. Right, right. You know?
But if you're fundamentally weak
internally and the fundamentals of your,
of your being are weak, then you need
to put up a big wall of protection.
You need to go round
and blow up to people.
And he made me weapons up there
to really keep him away from guns.
Some of the,
some heavies.