This is Jocko podcast number
one 59 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good evening. Good evening.
Okay.
There's a
a terrible feeling in the
gut that I've only felt
while I was overseas in Iraq,
and it's,
it's this deeply distressed
kind of sick feeling
and it literally feel it in your gut.
Literally feel it in your stomach,
in my stomach. And it's not.
It's not the fear. It's not fear.
It's not.
It's not the fear of death.
Because when you get to a point,
when you kind of accept that death is
a possibility and you're okay with it,
then that fear kind of goes away.
And it's not the fear of one of
your guys being wounded to kill.
It's not that either,
because even that fear,
even that fear you,
you,
you kind of get a control of that fear
because you know you can't dwell on it
because you know,
if you dwell on the fear of one of your
guys getting wounded or getting killed,
then that's going to detract from the
very thing that you're supposed to be
doing. That will most likely prevent
your guys from being wounded or killed.
If you're dwelling on that fear,
you won't be doing the things you should
be doing like planning and training and
preparing and inspecting
and reviewing and leading.
So even that fear,
wallets persistent and heavy and potent,
it's you have some level
of control over it.
But
when something goes wrong,
when something happens
and
you're responsible and the burden of
command settles down with its mantra,
mantras,
monstrous weight on top of your shoulders
because there's no one else to blame.
That's what I'm talking about.
It actually,
I felt it for the first time really a
little bit during my first deployment that
I did to Iraq and my platoon, we,
we did what we were supposed to do.
Some things didn't go right now,
nothing crazy,
but mistakes were made and it was actually
back to back to back missions with
related targets that we're going after.
And I was the assault force commander
and I think one of my might've even been
the ground force commander.
So I was clearly responsible for these
missions and there were some mistakes
made.
And
my commanding officer came
and spoke to me about it,
you know,
pulled me aside to point out the mistakes
and the resulting impacts that these
mistakes we're going to have. And
he wasn't happy. I mean he wasn't,
he wasn't mad because we had a good
relationship and he was talking to me just
straight,
but he wasn't happy.
And you know, I kept a calm face
and I took ownership and said,
hey my fault, this is the things
we're going to do to fix it. You know.
But even though I kind of kept a calm
face in front of him when he left eye
again, I felt like this retching in my
stomach debt that I had made some kind of
mistake. And, and one of the worst things
about it is there's nothing you can do.
Like the mistake happened. You
can't go back, you can't fix it.
And I can't compare that feeling to
anything else really that I've felt cause
cause I've never felt anything else
that feels like that. And I've,
I've talked about it with my friends
and leadership positions overseas and,
and like, actually the first time, uh,
it was actually stoner that
talked to me about this,
this gut feeling and he had
something going on and you know,
he's like, he's like, you know, that
feeling? And I was like, Oh yeah,
I know that feeling. And
like I said, I've never,
I've never felt this feeling,
this gnawing feeling in your gut
that's eating you from the inside.
I think you see it sometimes.
Um,
if you watch,
you know,
some movies try and capture this feeling
of where it's basically where someone's
life is falling apart,
but they're trying to keep up a facade
up that everything's going okay.
Have you ever seen the movie Fargo?
No. Okay. I got you on this one.
This movie Fargo.
There's a guy and he's,
he's a car salesman and he's been
fudging the numbers and then he's,
he's,
he's trying to kill someone.
There's all these things are happening and
it's all, and he's a very, I would say,
a very naive person.
And he's married and he's got kids and
he's trying to do this stuff that's not
right and he knows it and it's starting
to come apart and that that's the kind
of thing we, you can see it's
just eating him from the inside.
So I think it's that,
that type of gnawing deep feeling where
everything is going wrong and there's
nothing you can do about it. That's the,
that's the closest I, I think I can call,
is it just when things are going so wrong
and there's nothing you can do about
it?
And I think that that feeling,
that feeling for me, I think
that's why, number one,
that's why I always
say combat is humbling.
It's because of that feeling right
there where you, something went wrong.
You couldn't stop it, you couldn't
control it, you can't fix it.
It is what it is and
okay,
that makes it humbling.
Extremely humbling.
And because of that,
it made me want to make sure that I did
everything humanly possible to prevent
from that, to prevent that feeling
from grabbing hold of me again. If,
if I could help it. It opened
up my mind. It made me,
it made me always want to
listen to other people's input.
Cause I always said to myself, wait, if
I didn't see what was going on over here,
how do I ever know where
my blind spots are?
I always think I must have blind spots
somewhere. There must be something.
I see something I don't understand.
How can I listen?
I need to make sure I listen to other
people's viewpoints and perspectives so
that I don't, so I can
cover and, and yeah.
Covers many blind spots as possible.
Hmm.
Review other methods and other ideas
and other principals to see what I could
learn from them. And when people
raise opposing points to me,
I don't object to them.
I don't bristle up and it's,
I, it doesn't offend me when
somebody says something that isn't,
that I don't agree with. It
doesn't offend me at all. In fact,
I want to know more about it.
And
as I, as I go through my life,
I try and continue to listen.
I try to absorb opposing
opinions and process them.
And I want to just understand them.
I want to understand the context of him.
I want to understand the
perspective of them. It's,
it's how I think I'm going to eliminate
as many blind spots as possible.
So when someone would
tell me like a new tactic,
right when new tactic, when I was in
the, in the teams and someone say, Hey,
we're doing this now and there's of
course when somebody tells you something
new, there's always a part of you
that says that bristles up to it.
And I again,
those humbling situations,
that feeling in my gut that I didn't
want to feel it, it pushed that,
that ego down because I actually
want to hear what your ideas,
I want to hear if this is a blind
spot I haven't noticed I want,
I want that idea to work.
I want to see how it works.
I want to see if it works and sometimes
they would work and it's any and I would
learn something. Sometimes
they wouldn't. You know,
sometimes it would reconfirm the reason
and then that person would learn, hey,
the reason we don't do what you're
wanting to do is because of this.
And so now I'm helping them with
a blind spot that they might have.
But either way,
my goal was always to learn
to hear other people's viewpoints
and that's the way I remain today.
Eh, those other viewpoints are
going to make me sharper, right?
I'm going to read things so that
I can see them from other angles,
understand things from other
ankles they can strike.
When you understand
something from another angle,
you can strengthen your position
or you can leave your position.
If you realize that our position is wrong
and I,
and it's going to make me better,
and it's made me better not from me,
not because I want to be better,
but for the people that are around me,
the people up and down
the chain of command,
that I'm trying to support them so
I can do my job better as a leader,
as a follower and as a person and also
so that I can as much as humanly possible,
avoid that wretched,
seizing,
miserable feeling in my guts.
So I was thinking a lot about that.
And tonight we're going to explore
some principles of war actually called
general rules by this
individual Machiavelli.
This is the good Machiavelli,
Niccolo Machiavelli.
This is the guy that wrote the prince.
He's
got all kinds of great quotes out there.
It's better to be feared than loved
if you can. If you cannot be both.
He's got never, never was anything
great achieved without danger.
Here's one. If an injury has been done,
if an entry has to be done to a man,
it should be so severe.
That is vengeance need not be feared.
That's pretty ruthless.
Here's another one,
a hence it comes about that all armed
profits have been victorious and all on
armed profits have been destroyed.
Okay.
In one more quick quote as you,
you can,
you can just Google Machiavelli and quotes
and you'll find a bunch of great ones.
Men rise from one ambition to another.
First they seek to secure
themselves against attack.
Then they attack others and
that's actually from the prince,
which is his most famous book.
And if you think about the
process of being a human being,
that right there is very accurate and
you can really see that with accuracy.
If you overlay that on Jujitsu,
first you seek to is secure yourself
from attack and then you attack others
right when you're rolling at first,
when you first start,
you're just trying to defend, just
trying not to get choked. Yeah.
And then eventually you can stop from
getting choked and you can stop from
getting arm locked in and you start trying
to attack those people in arm locked
down.
So that's Machiavelli and a,
if you don't know anything about them,
he was an Italian, really a politician.
And a diplomat. And, but on top of that,
this was during the renaissance period
and he's an actual renaissance man.
So he was a poet. He was a poet,
philosopher. He was a playwright.
He was an author of books born in 1469
died in 1527 from 1503 to 1506 he was in
charge of the Florentine militia.
And when he was in charge of that militia,
he didn't like mercenaries because he
realized that weakness of mercenaries is
that they, they're, they're getting
paid. That's why they're fighting.
They're not fighting be from
their true belief system.
So he raised and recruited a citizen
army and they were well respected on the
battlefield and they fought in some
pretty good battles and one but it didn't
last forever. Florentine was
eventually defeated and dissolved,
and Machiavelli was accused
of conspiracy and tortured.
And I, of course, whenever I, I
go down a lot of rabbit holes,
but I went down that torture rabbit
hole for a little while yesterday.
And they were pretty brutal about it,
but he,
they thought he was a
conspirator or whatever. And
he did. He even after torture,
they couldn't get it out of him.
They eventually just exile them.
And that's when he wrote
his book the Prince,
which I'm sure we'll cover on here at
some point. This is where you are here.
This is where the word
machiavellian that's kind of,
it usually refers to his book,
the Prince and,
and usually that word nowadays is used
to describe someone that's kind of
scheming and unscrupulous if like if you
look it up in the dictionary, that's,
it'll give you a definition
along those lines.
And like someone that's trying to
snake and make things happen happen.
But, and like I said, I'm sure we'll
cover that book at some point. But um,
after that he wrote another book,
which is called the art of war.
And it's, it's definitely a
really good book. It's Anna.
We will probably parse through
the entire thing at some point.
But one thing that's good about
it is in the end of the book,
he part seven of the book and
there's, we have this, the last,
the last part of the book,
he basically breaks out the most
important principles from the book,
which makes it pretty easy and
straight forward to uh, talking to, uh,
to explain them and, and then
you can get the details. And I'm,
like I said, I'm sure we'll get
granular at some point on it, but
here's what he says in this book,
he's,
and it's bare with me a
little bit only because the,
the translation is old.
I know that I've told you many things,
which by yourself you
might have understood and
considered, not withstanding,
I have done it as today.
Also I've told you for to be able
to show you better meaning thereof,
the quality of this army
and also to satisfy those if
there be any whom have not
had the same commodity,
do understand them as you nor me thinks
that there are other to tell you.
Then certain general rules,
the which you should
all have most familiar,
which bvs which is his way of saying
lesson. I wrote a lot of stuff.
I'm glad you understood it
or at least you say you did,
but just in case some other
people can't understand it.
I'm going to break it down for you very
simply in these general rules and like I
said,
the translation,
the translation that I read of this book
is called the tutor translations by ag
and it's translated by a guy named Peter
Whitehorn in 1560 so we're talking like
somewhat archaic language and it's a
little bit tricky to get through bone.
I'll talk through them and we'll
get it into an understandable format
and there we go. So like I said,
he says, hey look, I wrote a lot of stuff.
Here's the general rules that you should
be most familiar with. Here we go.
Number one, the same.
That help if the enemy,
her teeth, the and the same that
help if the hadith the enemy.
That one's pretty straightforward,
right?
What benefits the enemy harms you
and what benefits you harms the enemy
straight forward. I think, you
know, that's one of those common,
uh,
principles that across
the ages everyone says it.
And the reason they say that
is because people forget it.
People forget that if, if, if we're,
if we can hurt the enemy in any way,
it's helping us and anything we do that
benefits also is going to hurt the enemy.
Yeah.
So sometimes we forget that that's
why many of these various canons of
principles on war remind us of that
because it's an important fact.
Number two,
he that shall be in war most vigilant
to observe the devices of the enemy and
shall take most pain to exercise his
army Shalon [inaudible] least perils and
may hope most of victory.
So what does that mean?
That means pay attention.
That means be vigilant in observing
the methods and plans of the enemy.
And when you're in war,
number one,
pay attention to who
you're fighting against.
Understand who they are.
Andy Burke,
he was going to do and Ebi,
I think it was an match. You know where
he was going against yeah. Craig Jones.
Yeah. You only thing about Craig
Jones. Greg Jones is savage.
Andy, you know, he's, he's
awesome. But we're in a, we're up,
we're training,
we're training hard.
He goes and competes against
him and loses fast. Yeah.
Why do you lose?
He lost because Gwelf number one,
cause Craig Jones is awesome and
you know what Andy's real good at.
He was good at all of Jujitsu,
but he's got real good foot locks.
Got Real good heel hooks. He
likes to play that game. You know,
it's training with me,
trading with Dean list
and so he's rolling in. Didn't know
much about Craig Jones. In fact,
he didn't know anything about Craig Jones.
Oh Dang. They just, Oh yeah, he's good.
Whatever. Yeah. Not, not,
not in a disrespectful way.
But you ever heard somebody say, um,
like when they say, Hey, w w what?
What do you think about your opponents
left hook or whatever. When they say,
what do you think about your ponens
ground and pound? And they say,
I'm not worried about my opponent,
it's what I'm going to do is not what
they're going to do. You know what I mean?
And I don't mean that in a bad way.
I'm not trying to say Andy was cocky,
but Andy, his thing was like, look
God, you know I do Jujitsu. Yeah.
That was his approach.
Like I do Jujitsu and Hay and also
there's a little bit of like, Hey,
well you might go against this guy,
but he might get her,
you might have this or whatever. You
know what I mean? So, right, right.
And it was a tournament as well. So you
can't really get focused on one guy.
You're going to be fighting three or four
guys and one night you just got to get
your Jujitsu game up.
Yeah.
So Andy Rolls in and he goes,
he went right into Craig Jones,
his game in seconds. And,
and the other thing was Andy
super relaxed. Like, I mean he's,
he's relaxed anyways, so he's like,
oh, okay, this is, do you know,
we're just going to do some Jujitsu and
it'll escalate over time and eventually,
you know, it's something we'll, you know,
we'll get to that point and whatever and
he goes in and boom and it goes right
in to one a crack. Jane Craig
Jones is like really good moves.
Just goes right into it for him.
And she know I was bombed then obviously
Andy's bumped but didn't do any,
you know, we me, I should have been like,
hey man, let's look at your opponents.
Let's check out their game. Because
if you just know, you know how it is.
If you're aware of someone's game,
you can definitely mitigate it.
You can't defeat it. I'm not
saying he could defeat Craig Jones,
but he would've been, he wouldn't have
fallen into that in a matter of seconds.
He would have been, oh, this
is his move there. I need,
I know what to do to at least mitigate the
first attack, the second attack. Right.
If you don't do that, you're going to,
you're going to have problems. And, and,
and he got and then he came back and
read that. He's like, he's like, yeah,
that guy's good. So props
to my board, Craig Jones,
you beat my, my boy. Uh,
hopefully you guys will meet
again one day and you're going to,
he'll get another go and he'll
know your game a little bit better.
But bottom line is study your opponents,
study your opponents. Now can you go
too far with that? Yeah, you can. Yeah,
because some people think, oh, I wish
that happens sometimes when the UFC,
someone will Ms. Wade or they'll get
hurt and they'll throw a new opponent.
Madam though wasn't ready for that guy
had been training for a strike or now
you're putting me up against grappler or
whatever. Yeah. So you know, uh, Sarge,
this is pretty cool.
Sarge who was a really good,
who was and is a really good
wrestler and he's also Jujitsu now,
but he was, he said when he would
train for wrestling, you know,
cause he was a high school restaurant.
Poway,
which if you know anything
about wrestling and California,
we're actually in America,
you know,
Poway high school has it like
real dominant wrestling program.
And he was a wrestler there
as well as his brother.
But he said when he would train,
he would,
he would picture someone with no face.
And it's because,
you know,
when you were in the high school
wrestling scene out here in California,
you know the people that you're gonna
come up against, right? Tournament,
you're going to come up against these six
guys and you know that two of them are
good or whatever, but he just say nope.
And when he would look at him, he's like,
when I would look at them before a match,
I wouldn't even, I just see like a blur,
just fog in their face.
And then he said once he would knew
he was going to go against that guy,
then he'd look at him in a,
calculate their face and be like,
I'm gonna kill this guy. But
that's the why. What would it be?
His point in that was he
didn't want to get, uh,
like his mind offset by, oh,
it's not who I expected it to be.
Right, right. So he wouldn't have any
expectation on who was going to be,
he was just going to get in
the murder mode. And then when,
when he finally realized that
they're walking out of a map of then,
then he'd look at their face and go,
okay,
this is the guy I'm going against and
I'm gonna kill him. Which for Sarge,
you know,
that means the actual,
so observe the methods
and plans of your enemy.
Absolutely.
Next part of is you,
you have to endure much
hardship and training. Of
course, you got to train hard.
So observe your enemy, know what
they're doing, and then train really,
really hard and you're going to have a
greater chance for victory. Of course,
common sense. Next one. Number three,
never conduct vie men to fight the field
if first thou has not confirmed their
minds and know it's them to be without
fear and to be in good order for though
for Thou oddest never to enterprise
any dangerous thing with by soldiers.
But when Thou seest that
they hope to overcome.
So again,
we're dealing with some middle
English or I think you English, um,
linguists,
people can get at me if I'm wrong,
but we're pretty close to middle English.
Maybe it's a little late middle English,
but we're in the ballpark.
So what is he talking about there?
Never lead your soldiers into an
engagement unless you are assured of their
courage. Mm hmm. And
then he actually says,
unless you know them to be without fear,
which is a stretch in my mind,
cause you're going to have people that
are gonna be afraid. In fact, we, you can,
you, you're gone. People are going to be
afraid when they're going into combat.
90 something percent.
A high percentage of people are
going to have some level of fear,
but you do need to make sure that they're
going to be able to overcome that fear.
So if you got people that are shaking
in their shoes and they feel, you know,
you think they're going to, they're
not, they've not been tested at all,
well then that could be a real problem.
Okay.
Then, and then the question becomes, okay,
well how do you test if
someone's gonna be afraid or not?
What do you think they do in the military?
Yeah,
with people. What do they do? Want to make
them not scared? Yeah. Test their fear.
How do you test her fear? Put them
in scary situations, which is scary.
Situations in training.
Make them repel off the high tower,
make them send to airborne school.
Hey, airborne school, I would say,
you know,
of course there's,
there's some level of some things that
you need to learn in airborne school,
but you're basically,
I mean,
you can literally throw a sack of potatoes
out of an airplane with a parachute
on it and it's going to land up
pretty much. Okay. Most of the time,
and that's what you do
when you go to the school.
You learn the proper exit procedures.
When I went to airborne school,
it's a Kz. Here's the extra
procedures. Here is how you
land. You're floating down.
You don't have much control over your
parachute. So there's not a lot to learn.
Technically. It's not like a major
skillset. I mean it's a three,
let me put it this way, it's a three week
school, right? It's not like it's on a,
it's not a long intensive school about
learning how to pack parachutes or even
how to maneuver yourself through the air
because there's only so much you can do.
Yeah. So what is it that's
important about airborne school?
What's important about airborne school
as you're going to overcome the fear of
jumping out of a damn airplane,
that's important.
That's why an airborne or you'll go go
talk to the 82nd airborne division or the
hundred first airborne division.
Those guys are awesome and they have
that little thing that they've all done
that has put them,
they've been screened out a little bit,
cause some people are going to be
afraid. So yes, that's what you do.
You make people do hard,
scary things. I mean,
in the seal teams it's the same thing.
What do they do?
You're going to learn how to parachute.
Then you're gonna parachute at night.
They're going to parachute
at night into the water.
Then you're going to jump out of a
helicopter at night at, you know,
20 feet into the darkness and with a boat
and you're gonna rig that thing up and
you're gonna dive at night and you're
going to swim at night in the open ocean
or you're,
or you're just going to go ghost.
That scares some people off for some
reason. It never really scared me. Yeah.
I have no fear of sharks up.
Let me rephrase that.
I have no fear that a shark
is randomly going to bite me.
If I was in the water and there
were sharks, I'd be scared. Yes.
And I know that there are sharks in the
water so that your guys should be scared.
But I dunno. I feel lucky. Yeah.
I feel like sharks really want
to eat me and that very much.
They'd rather eat like someone like you.
Well I guess if you're on a surf board,
I guess that increases the chances
from what I understand. Yeah.
Cause you look like a seal, like a sea
animal seal. So that's what you do.
You put people in situations where
they're going to be afraid. You know?
And this is something that I think
everyone should do.
If you have a job that's
going to cost stress,
you want to put people in
stressful situations. So
that's how you test that fear.
And again, you're not going to go
to remove the fear from people.
What you want to figure out
is can they overcome the fear?
That's what you want to figure
out. Um, what else he say no,
that they're organized.
Never make an attempt unless you,
unless you see they hope for victory.
So you got to convince, if you're
telling your guys like, Hey,
we're probably gonna lose
you. Won't say that. You say,
look, it's going to be hard,
but there's a chance we can take this.
And you know what I mean?
You got to get them in that attitude,
not the attitude of like, oh,
we're just going to lose what's
going on here for no reason.
Don't let that happen.
Number four,
it is better to conquer the enemy with
famine than with iron in the victory of
which fortune may do
more than Valliant ness.
That one's pretty self explanatory.
It's better to defeat the enemy
by hunger then steel, you know,
it's better to let them starve. Then have
to go and fight him and then he says,
in such a victory,
the fortune,
like your luck counts
more than Valeant ness,
which is cool.
Understandable.
This is one of those things where
you've heard me say before he,
the best victories are the victories
where the person doesn't even know that
you're fighting them. That's the
best victory. And then if you can,
if you can maintain your ego
after you win and you don't gloat,
then they never even did it. Even register
it, right? They didn't know they were.
They didn't know they were
in a fight. That's what you
want. This is very similar,
but this, this part, I'll throw a
little back at it in such fortune,
victory counts more than Valeant nus.
Yeah.
Good fortune is going to help. But guess
what? We're going to make our own luck,
right? We're going to make our own
luck. That's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna and we're gonna
make bad luck for the enemy.
We're going to dry up rivers. We're going
to damn river so they can't grow food.
That's what we're going to do.
So when it cut off supply chains,
that's what we're gonna do. We're gonna
make, we're gonna make fortune favor us.
Number five,
no purpose is better than that,
which is hidden from the enemy
until you've executed it. Boom.
Pretty straightforward.
No plan is better than that which you
have concealed from the enemy until the
time you execute it.
No doubt.
True in life. True in
business, true in Jujitsu.
That's what the judge essentially the
element of surprise, surprise. If you,
if you,
if your enemy doesn't know what you're
gonna do and then you're done and they go,
oh,
that was a nice arm walk or wow,
you really took over that market
share and I didn't see it coming.
If you don't see it coming, that's really
it. We see it coming from a mile away.
It's like, ah, yeah. You can still do
that sometimes dean does that. Yeah,
but we do. Yeah, we talked about that.
What he does different things though.
Like yeah, he, he'll like
many, many steps. Yeah.
He'll tie up your defenses while it's
when you, when you see the incoming,
he ties up all your defenses
like as it gets close.
Number six to know in the war,
how to understand occasion and to take
it help if more than any other thing to
know one war,
how to understand occasion and take
it help if more than any other thing.
What does that mean?
That means you,
one of the best skills you can have
is knowing how to recognize a good
opportunity in war or in life and take
advantage of that opportunity that is
more beneficial than anything else.
And you know,
the biggest and most Blakeman
example where you see this,
well your kids aren't old
enough, but with kids, just kids,
kids have so much opportunity in life.
Yeah.
And they just don't take advantage
of it. Like they should. Right. Yeah.
Yeah.
I could see how that can be for sure.
But I think that's because they have life
is connecting now and then the future.
You know, I guess that's the thing.
Yeah. There's no doubt that they have,
there's no doubt that they have that
athletes. Yeah. Real good athletes.
Same thing. They have
all this potential. Yeah.
Any time someone, well not anytime.
Oftentimes somebody that are,
some people that are given a gift,
it's just given to them.
They don't have to work for it.
They don't want to take advantage of it.
They don't see the opportunity.
They don't take advantage
of the opportunity or that
skill set is, yeah. Cause.
Yeah, almost like, um, you know,
when you give a kid a gift verse
or money versus if they earn it,
I think you covered that in a way
of the world kid. Yeah. That's,
that's way covered on way of the warrior
kid. When you earn it, it's like,
you know,
the hard work it takes and you kind of
appreciate it and then whatever comes out
of that. But yeah, if it's
given to you, you just,
you run the risk of
squandering it for sure.
Especially when the going
gets rough, you know? No, no.
Next
nature breed.
If few strong men,
the industry and the
exercise make with many,
what does that mean? That means,
you know, nature makes very
few strong brave men,
but hard work and training
makes many boom. Yeah.
That'll work for it. Yeah. You want people
to be brave. You want people to be, uh,
have courage. Make them
strong, make them work hard.
Yeah. That will absolutely
increase their bravery.
And remember that question we got asco
a while ago about how do I make my unit
guys in the military, military
you, how do I make them proud?
How do they increase their level of pride?
Train hard.
They will get physically stronger.
They will get mentally stronger and from
that they will start to take pride in
themselves and pride in
themselves as a unit. Eight
discipline may do more in war than fury
figured you'd like. Yeah,
I kind of liked that one.
Discipline counts more than fury in war.
Discipline counts more than fury in life.
I'm not discounting emotions.
I'm not doing that because
you can't cause sometimes man,
people's emotions they get,
they will carry them through
a really tough time period.
That's why in discipline equals freedom.
In the field manual,
I talk about how you got to use both
logic and you got to use emotions and when
sometimes when emotionally it doesn't
make any sense or you're going to break
emotionally, you got to go with the
logic of the situation that I got.
I got to drive through
this and vice versa.
Sometimes the lodge cause like
this makes no sense whatsoever.
Turned to the emotional
side. Yup. But discipline,
he says may do more and he's right.
It's not 100% is like discipline
because if you have people that are just
discipline, but they have no
heart, they have no emotion.
What I, how good are they?
They're not that good. Yeah, they're not,
they're not as good as
the person that has both.
There's not as good as a person that
has discipline and a little bit of fury.
They can kind of get crazy when they
need to button in MMA. You see this,
you'll see someone when they're young and
they'll lose some fights cause they'll,
they'll sit someone down or whatever
and then they'll just go crazy trying to
catch them to get Connor triangle.
Yeah.
You have to maintain your
discipline even during the,
the actual battle.
You have to maintain your discipline.
You can't let the fury get ahold of you.
Yeah. Too much discipline,
fury, discipline. Fear. Yeah.
Once you watch the Cyborg fight, right.
The reason why I had Amanda Nunez. Yes.
So this is what it seemed like.
He's fast,
but this is what it's looked like where
cyborg landed like a solid one and
Amanda Nunez as a response unleashed fury,
like some legit fury fury,
but it was disciplined fury because
when she started landing hard ones she
didn't like overcome it. It was
like really balance. You know,
she looked great but there was some,
there was a lot of fury.
So fury like it wasn't like
all just spoken calculated like punches
who was there was fury and Tim Kennedy,
someone's like Ah,
do UFC tweeted out like she's throwing
haymakers and Tim Kennedy's like those
aren't haymakers cause every
single one of them hit,
they were full punches from Amanda that
we're nailing Cyborg right in the head.
Yeah. Most of the time, like in
five times in a row you don't,
you don't normally see five punches land,
especially not punches that
are thrown with that much fury.
He can kind of tell when
like you see like their,
their feet when they're
throwing punches like you get,
there's like a huge forward lean.
If they,
if they're haymakers there's like this
huge Ford liens and they usually pressing
forward like fully. But when they're like
disciplined, there's like that you see,
you can see the balance. Like they'll
back up just a little bit. You know,
it's good. So good. Yeah. That was crazy.
Discipline may do more then fury.
So you know what, make sure you have
some discipline it. All right. Next one.
Number nine,
when any depart from the enemy's
side for to come to serve the,
when they be faithful,
they shall be unto thee.
Always great gains for that power of
the adversaries are more diminished with
the loss of them that run away then
bone of then those that be slain.
Although that the name of a fugitive
be to new friend suspected and old two
odious, too old odious. So when
he's talking about traders,
there three is talking about,
so when you say when any depart from
the enemy side to come serve you.
So when when people leave the enemy
and they come to serve with you,
they're going to be more loyal
and they're great.
They're great acquisition.
And actually he's saying that people that
leave the enemy and come to your side
are more powerful for you. Then
people that, that you've killed
and there they have more value.
The,
when they come aboard your team,
they're going to be suspected.
You know that the old,
that your team is going to look at him
with like a cautious eye and the team
that they left are going to hate them.
Yeah. They're going to hate them.
That was weird when Solzhenitsyn was
saying that when they would capture the
Russian turncoat soldiers that
were now fighting for the Nazis,
as soon as they spoke any Russian,
they'd kill him. That was,
that was a pretty scary thought. So this
is very accurate from that perspective.
Yeah. Like if you're a trader, we're
not even going to give you a chance.
We're just going to kill you.
Yeah. Wait, so who, wait, who?
So the Russians, the
Russians didn't kill him. No.
So there was a whole group
of Russian soldiers, yeah.
That turned against Stalin and turned
against Russia and started fighting for
the Nazis.
Yeah.
And so when the Russians
would capture those,
what they consider to be traders,
as soon as they heard a soldier speaking
Russian, they'd kill him. The Nazis,
you mean they were, they were Russian
soldiers fighting for the Nazis.
Was it fossil? That was the guy's
name. So there was a German or, sorry,
a Russian general that was the
leader of that whole group.
The Vos alarmy I think was the name.
Yeah.
And so when the Russian Stalin's Russian
actual red soldiers would capture these
traders that were fighting against them,
now they would,
if they heard them speaking Russian,
they'd kill him. Hmm. So this is
from that perspective.
It's accurate. Yeah.
I wonder why they're more valuable,
you think? Because what cause or what,
or loyal, he said loyal,
right to, well, the,
the jerk, the Russian soldiers that
were now fighting for the Nazis,
they would fight to the death because
they knew that they were dead anyway.
Right. That captured, yeah. Like if
they got, yeah. So yeah, they were,
they would fight even harder.
Uh,
the thing that I'm not sure about this
is, well, I guess I agree with it.
I do agree with it. When someone's a
trader, you're suspect of them, right?
You know, you're just,
you're just like, Hey,
are you get to your attorney or
you're a trader, I'm suspect to you.
So it's going to take a little time for
me to actually trust that you really
came to Mizade.
But I guess like when you think about,
just like how you said that,
you know,
they know they're dead anyway kind
of thing where it's like, okay,
let's say mean you were enemies,
whatever.
And one of my guys goes to you and
says, Hey, I give up, I'll help you.
I give up. You're like, okay, he gives up,
I get it and let's see what he has to
offer kind of thing. But I suspect. Yeah,
but your suspect,
but let's say
a guy in your team used to be on my team
and I know that I'm pissed at that guy.
And then he gives up now to me,
to my guys like Mike,
I see him or whatever and he's like, Hey,
I give up. I'll help you. Oh No, no, no.
You don't give up your debt. Yeah. So
it's like that. Like how you see it,
they know they're dead anyway. What the
Russians did to the vasile soldiers. Yeah.
So you, oh you traded. Okay, cool.
You're dead. And that makes sense. Right?
So that's probably why they have to be
loyal because it's either loyalty or
death, you know, they can't give
up anymore. If I am not a trader,
I can give up and get beat, pow
be whatever I can, I can give up.
I have that option trader
who already made the trade,
he doesn't have that option.
That's why he's loyal.
He has to be looking at a minimum.
He's going to fight to the death.
And it's interesting too that
traders are, you know, in the business
world, because in the business world,
you know, there's, everyone's always,
recruiting is limited number of the
human limits in the world and we can only
get so many people that can do this job.
And if you have skills in that job,
you're getting recruited all the time.
And so that's,
that hurts when they leave.
And that's why. And, and just to
kind of close the loop on this,
when they leave almost all the time,
the reason,
the reason that they're leaving is because
of leadership or I should say lack of
leadership inside their organization.
So if you have a,
if you have a problem hanging on
to people in your organization,
it's most likely a leadership problem.
Not a comp problem,
not a midlife crisis problem for the
employee. It's a leadership problem.
Hmm.
Cause good,
good people will stay with good leaders
and if there's not good leaders,
they're looking for another job,
they're looking for another way,
they're looking for another
opportunity. Makes Sense. Leadership,
leadership, leadership. Get some
number 10
better.
It is in pitching the field to reserve
behind the first front aid enough then to
make the front bigger to
disperse the soldiers.
Okay.
What that's saying is it's better to keep
your reserves just behind that to keep
some reserves just behind the front lines
rather than spread out your reserves
and take on a bigger front trying to
hold more area. It's editing, you know,
this is prioritize and
execute, right? Keep your,
keep your focus of effort even with
your reserves. Keep focus of effort,
keep them consolidated so
you can utilize them well.
Next up,
number 11
he is difficultly overcome,
which can know his own power
and the same of the enemy.
Okay, let's, that was
almost like a a Yoda type.
He is difficult to overcome.
So what we're saying there is it's hard
to overcome someone who knows how to
recognize or knows and understands his
own power and the power of the enemy.
So does that mean know your strengths and
weaknesses? Right. That's what it means.
Yeah. Since he says that, right. Is
this something about winning the deal?
Definitely.
Number 12,
the Valliant ness of the soldiers
available more than the multitude.
Sometimes the situation help
biff more than the valueless.
Okay.
So what we're talking about there is
that the bravery of the soldiers is worth
more than the number of soldiers you have.
Makes Sense.
If you have brave,
courageous soldiers,
they can take a more,
they can do a lot more than people
were soldiers that are afraid.
So you want brave soldiers
and then it says the site,
what does it say that
sometimes the situation help
if more than the voluminous.
So even that,
what trumps the courageous and what
trumps the bravery is what's the,
what's the terrain situation? You know,
what's the environment that you're in?
What are the rules of the game? One of
the rules of the game that you're playing.
Cause if you,
if you know the rules,
you're going to be in a a
much better situation. The uh,
this happens in Jujitsu, right? Yes.
Because the rules are always
a little bit different.
There's no unified set of rules and
Jujitsu. Yeah, there's some clothes,
but there is no unified set of rules
and sometimes someone will lose simply
because they don't know the rules.
And then once you know the rules,
you've got to train to
the rules. Like Ebi, Ebi,
you have those positions that you
start up in. If you're an overtime,
you start in spider web, you start on the
back, right. If you don't, if you don't,
if once you know those roles,
then you've got to practice
those positions so you
can finish the emoc so you
can finish from the back offer. You can
escape from either one of those too.
If you don't know that and you're gonna
practice it. Because like for instance,
I'm pretty good at finishing on our lock.
Pretty good at finishing an arm lock.
Sure.
On the back I normally transitioned
from the back to another position.
So I would,
if I was going in Ebi Tournament,
I'd have to go and focus on what that
rule set is and make sure I know how to
win from that position. Yeah, yeah. Fully.
Yeah. Big One is the
submission only versus points.
So if people like let's say they spend
10 years competing with points in the
tournaments,
you know,
then they go to submission only with the
guy who is only trained in submission
only he's going to, you know, going
to have an added advantage. Yeah.
In all of these different, yeah, different
ways cause certain rules don't apply.
Some do.
Yeah.
Terrain Park, man Ed, this is, this is,
it took me a while to understand
this in my navy career,
how important to reign is
and now it's so obvious,
but when you're maneuvering
on the battlefield,
if you know how to read terrain wealth,
you have a complete advantage over the
enemy. Complete advantage over the enemy.
You should be paying attention
to that terrain. Studying maps,
looking at it and now they have all these
you can, you can simulate the earth,
right?
It's a Google maps like a high speed.
We can get down at eye level and you can
walk the terrain and really understand
what the visibility is like. That's
the kind of, that's that's you should,
you got to take advantage of those tools.
You got to understand the terrain,
you got to understand the terrain that
you're going into in the business world.
You'd go, got to go into a company
understanding what the situation is there.
When you get hired into a new,
you want to know the terrain,
you want to know who's got the clout.
Yep.
You want to know who the
movers and shakers are.
You want to know what things are
off limits and whatever. Yeah.
I don't know who's buying.
Okay.
Like, you know how the, you know, people
always say this is $1 billion industry,
right? Like that kind of stuff.
Like, Oh, you know, how's the,
what's the need for a year
product? Um, remembering, because I watch
shark tank, this is what they always ask.
What was the, uh, was
this a particular product?
No, no, no. Everyone, like pretty much,
that's one of the things like they ask
or they say, there'll be like, oh yeah,
this is like a million house, you know,
a million people own pets, you know,
and all of these pets need this, you know,
so, yes. And you see what I'm saying?
So they kinda, they got another
terrain in that way. Yeah, that's true.
They don't know how many
people have pets then.
They don't know how many people
going to buy that shampoo. You know,
you gotta know that one dude shark tank.
We maybe we should just do a
leadership show about shark tank.
What you've learned from
shark tank. Sure. Next up,
number 13 new in sudden thing.
Make armies afraid.
Slow and accustom things
be little regarded of them.
Therefore make thy army practice and
to know with small fights a new enemy
before thou come to
fight the field with him.
Oh,
middle English coming at
you. So what, what is that?
What it basically what we're saying
here is a number one new and surprising
things. Frightened armies. Hmm?
The new and surprising things.
Frightened people.
So on the opposing to that customary
and expected things they can handle.
So what do you do? How do you do? How do
you, how do you properly mitigate that?
Therefore you practice and you fight
small engagements to get them experienced
before you go to battle on the big
battlefield with them, with the enemy.
That's what you do. Train
hard, don't dive right in.
Get them used to the new technology.
That's what you do.
This is another good one with kids,
right?
You throw your kid into this scenario
that they haven't been into before.
You give him a little taste of it. Mm. Oh
yeah. This is a, this is exposure therapy.
Once again,
I get asked on the warrior kid podcasts,
I get asked every like every day I get
at least one question from a kid that's
I'm afraid of. What do I do? And I,
I usually wait two or three podcasts
before I answer the same question again
because it's kids. They got to get the
reputation they've got to get the reps in.
Yeah. But it's exposure therapy.
You're afraid of something cool.
Do a little of it. They do a little bit
more and that's unknowingly what I did.
And where the warrior kid one with
him overcoming his fear of the water.
I didn't know that that was a real thing.
Not until Jordan peers.
This is called exposure therapy.
Yeah.
I guess I need to talk like Kermit
the frog to imitate Jordan busters,
but he's like, yeah, that's
exposure therapy. Yeah. Oh, okay.
Next. Number 13 I'm going,
I went on to number 14
she that with disorder
follow with the enemy.
After that he is broken.
We'll do no other than to
become of a conqueror. A loser.
If you pursue a routed enemy
in a disorganized manner,
victory will be lost and you'll
become a loser. Keep it under control.
All the Amanda Nunez, right?
Sure. She had the victory and the,
you ever seen that?
That one real quick clip and I
forget who the fighter is. It did.
It is the UFC.
The guy takes a body shot and he keels
over like he's about to like go down and
the dude comes running in swinging.
Yeah.
The dude that's killed over like
he's hurt just Barak. He wasn't hurt.
He was just faking it.
Yeah. I think he was hurt
talking about Scott. Yeah.
Maybe he was hurt but he wasn't hurt
as bad as he right cross functional.
Apparently fairly cause he
knocked the dude out. Yeah,
it was the last thing is his
nickname is Drago. I know that
it's interesting that that
stuff doesn't happen more often.
It's like trick football plays.
Yeah.
How come more trick football
players don't happen
because they'd lose their
trickery element of it.
And sometimes there's
a lot of risk involved.
There's more risks than like a traditional
play a lot of times. Yeah. Yeah.
And it's like the, like the rope a dope.
Remember that? The rope a dope. Oh yeah.
Yeah.
You essentially like act like you're kind
of hurt or tired or whatever and then
they punched himself out. They
need get them, but yeah, yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You gotta be careful in that canned stuff.
So when you do have your enemy
on the run,
okay.
Don't go after him crazy. Okay.
Keep it under control. Yeah.
There is a play in football called the
reverse. Right. And I thought that,
cause you just said, why don't they
run? No, I didn't play football. Yeah.
And when you see that trick
plays, yeah. Then you think,
well that seemed to work pretty good.
Why don't they do that stuff more often?
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So here's the
common trick play, right? The um,
the quarterback does this,
so sweep right through.
They got to the running back there, runs
the outside and then the running back,
oh, he stops before he reached
the lightest scrimmage.
He stops and he throws the
football not to a receiver,
but to the quarterback who ran a
route on the other side of the field.
And cause no one's going to cover the
quarterback. He's not a receipt Reno.
And that was wide open to pass.
Oh, he's wide open. So called, ah,
we called it passed back to
the quarterback. So good.
Like 38 sweet pass back to the quote.
Okay.
But I can see where there's
risk in that one. Yes,
because that's the running back back.
So he got to nail that throw,
which is really hard for running
back typically. But I'd say the,
the one that would always
work is in pop Warner anyway.
It would always work is the reverse.
It's essentially like you do a sweet,
everyone's running this way to block for
this writing back everyone except for
the one tight end or the why do you see
where water of who's coming this way and
the running back hands it
off to him going this way.
So he's full speed running this way.
So everyone has to change
direction to chase him.
And usually that set of fields wide open,
um,
it works way better in pop Warner and
younger teams because they don't know like
these, these situations.
Like they don't know.
They just see everyone running there
and they're just sort of go, you know,
more than a professional. They're going
to be like, wait, I shouldn't just be,
you know. Um, but that was one I was like,
why don't we just always run the reverse?
Because every time this is this
team that we played against,
they'd always run it.
And it always will.
I understand why. If you ran
it every time, well then,
then the regular reverse or what are the
regular play would become the surprise.
But it seems like,
it seems like you could keep
people guessing a little bit more.
Those trick plays always see,
I was looking at him going
how I was pretty creative and
pretty good. Yeah. Yeah.
I think you see it like, oh, kind of
like I said, like when you go up in,
um, like skill, like you can
go on to the pros or whatever.
Trick plays don't work is good. They
have to be really advanced trick plays.
That's when you,
have you ever seen like the
trick play that like where
day, like almost walk off the field? Yeah.
And then they like walk over like
there's something wrong with the ball or
something like stand up and they'll
be like, no, something's wrong.
And they will and then they just start
running. Yeah. Yeah. So even that,
and then those can backfire
too because there'll be like,
if all it takes is one defensive
person to know that hey,
that ball is in play right now.
So they can just sort of walk
over and hit it out of the hand,
grab it from whatever they want because
no one's blocking them. You know,
no one's like everyone.
It's Kinda,
it's just risky check and get more people
doing that. They're going to be like,
oh, they're hip to it and
it would never work after
awhile. Um, number 15,
he did prepare if not necessary victuals
to live upon is overcome without iron.
So,
um,
whoever does not prepare
food and provisions necessary
to live is going to be
overcome without any weapons at all.
So what does that mean?
Take care of your people, take care of,
make sure you take care of your logistics.
Logistics wins,
wars and people need to survive.
So do that. Number 16, he,
that trusteth more in horseman than
in footmen or more in footmen than in
horseman must accommodate
himself with the situation.
So in the ancient times you had cavalry
on horses and you had the infantry men
on the feet and he's saying if
you prefer one over the other,
then you have to put yourself in the
right situation where it's advantageous.
Yeah.
So that's why it's good to
be well balanced and not
really prefer one over the
other.
But if you do,
then put yourself in a situation that's
most advantageous to your style or
preference of fighting.
Hmm.
Okay.
Make sure you learn how to wrestle
because if you don't know how to wrestle,
someone else is going to dictate to you
where that fight is going to go. Yeah.
Okay.
17 when vow.
Right?
See if in the day there be coming any
spy into the camp because every man to go
into his lodge.
Yeah.
Okay,
so what we're saying is this pretty
straight forward basic headcount or if you
want to see if there's a spine of the camp
average, send everyone to their place.
You know, get a head count. No
big deal. 18 change purpose.
Windau perceives that the
enemy half foreseen it.
Okay.
Does that mean if you,
if you think the enemy or if you perceive
that the enemy knows what you're doing,
didn't change your plan, that's, that's
what that means. Pretty straight forward.
Now where we don't do that or the reason,
most of the time we don't
do that is because our ego,
we got our plan and we're going to
stick to it. Now this is a total,
this is why leadership is hard because
there's a point where your plan,
you got your plan, and if you stick to
your plan, you can, it's going to work,
right? And then there's a point
where you could stick in your plan.
You're sticking with the plan and it's
going to fail because it's not working.
So as a leader, this of the hardest
thing to do as leaders to recognize,
like you know what? The plan that I came
up with, it's not going to be perfect,
but it's still going to work
and where to go with it.
Because to try and change the plan
halfway through is really hard to do.
Even if you were hearse,
the contingencies. Now,
if you are the contingencies properly,
you're probably gonna be ale to
execute your new plan pretty easily.
But if you didn't,
it's going to be a problem.
So this is one of the hardest
things for a leader to do,
is to pay enough attention and
then weigh the risk versus reward.
Because if you're coming up with a,
if you have your plan and you're
executing the plan and all of a sudden
something changes,
not quite what you thought and you decide
you're going to try and do something
completely different,
what your changes that you make on the
fly are going to cause as much confusion
as what the enemy's doing. And it's
going to be a real problem. However,
like this says,
if the enemy sees what you're doing and
now the reacting to it in a proper way
and your plan is no longer effective,
you have to be able to,
you have to be able to comprehend that
and discern whether you should change or
not. And that's one of the
hardest things for Lee, uh,
hardest decisions for a leader
to make as it's happening.
What's worse than that is we have a
long of time when you start talking
about strategic plans,
this is where ego gets more involved.
Because when I have this plan and this
is what we're going to do and I'm just
going to stick with it, and if it's
not working, I'm going to do it harder.
So that's what you want to watch out for.
You know, there's like some of these, um,
companies being taken down
by online companies, right?
You got to have change your game
plan. You know, you got to adjust.
You've got to look at them and
say, okay, what are they doing?
Where are they going? We know blockbuster.
Like, like I've said this before,
blockbuster could have,
could have completely dominated Netflix,
but what did they do? Nope,
we're just over here. Hey,
people are going to keep coming
to our stores. Yeah. You know,
there's a certain feeling that you get
when you come into a store and you get to
look at on browse with the movies.
It's something exciting to get to pick
up popcorn where you can to get popcorn
at your house. You know, people are gonna
want to keep coming in to these stores,
right? No, actually they're not. They
already have popcorn at their house.
Amazon delivered it yesterday in an hour,
by the way up and then
your terrain to an Allen.
And yet they had all the
relationships with the movie places.
What are those movie companies called?
[inaudible] of the production companies.
What is it like? What's Warner brothers?
What does that production studio.
They had studio, they got the
relationships with the studios.
They could've been like, hey, we're
gonna start selling this stuff online,
and they would have said, well, that
doesn't make any sense because the,
it's going to be all jumbled up
when it gets downloaded. Yeah,
but it's going to get better. We're
just playing the long game. Yeah.
It's weird that blind said
they were thinking, you know,
it's too hard to download a movie on
the Internet is going to be jumbled up.
There's going to be buffering.
No one even knew what Bob did.
Netflix and event buffering.
Buffering is just the Internet situation.
Yeah.
When it has to catch up.
Do you remember five years ago there
was buffering on all kinds of stuff.
Now there's hardly any buffering.
Barely any buffering.
I've met my littlest daughter doesn't
even know what buffering is using.
They're just streaming.
I'm sure she knows what it is,
but she has never witnessed it.
Yeah. Well then again, you know,
you get bad service somewhere,
get some buffering. They
weren't wrong. They, I mean,
they were on blockbuster, but
they just, the whole idea of like,
people like coming into blockbuster and
browsing the movies and buying the thing
is, that's true. Like we
did like doing that. Yeah.
But it's because we didn't have a better
option. You know, like when you go,
like even going to the store sometimes
it's kind of cool and fun, you know,
sometimes. But most of the
time at the end of the day,
I'd rather press a button
and go to the store.
to every single time. Yeah.
And there's also that thing where you,
you're, it's a positive feedback loop,
right? It's an echo chamber. I liked going
on, you know, two of those people in the,
in the c suite of blockbuster
and account and you know,
my wife loves going down and picking out
a new movie with the kids and they love
doing that, you know? And this was like,
yeah. You know, my kids love that too. So,
and my teenage daughter likes doing it
too with her friends. And like you said,
that's cause there's no other option.
Your teenage daughter would be rather
be in a room alone in her room clicking
the next Netflix
movie. Yep. Popping their popcorn
that got delivered earlier. Yeah.
So if you,
if you are on a strategy
and it's not working,
you got to recognize that you need to
change it no to self everyone in the
leadership position. Pay
attention to that one. Next up.
Number 20 soldiers when
they abide at home,
are maintained with fear and punishment
after when they are led to the war with
hope and with reward.
What's it saying is when soldiers
are confined to their quarters,
they're kept there by fear and punishment.
When they're led to war,
they're led by hope and reward.
You know,
fear for me is just not a good
tool for a leader to use period.
I'm not saying you never, this is, I'm
not saying you should never use it, right.
There should be some element, a
little element of fear. Right.
And does the element of fear,
right. Let me ask you this.
Do your kids have any fear of you at
all? Cause you seem real nice. Uh, the,
they do. Yeah. There's, there's just
enough, a healthy element. Yeah.
I mean, I would say a
healthy, but I dunno.
I don't really know what the standard
of healthy fear levels are. But yeah,
we agree that there is a healthy
level of fear. Even with your kids.
Your kids shouldn't just think that,
that there's going to be no repercussions
for anything that they do. Yeah.
Your troops should also feel
a healthy level of fear.
And it's hard to even use that word
because that word is so negative. Yeah.
But there should at least be a level of
like, you know what, we want to do that.
No, there's a line with Jocko
and you don't want to cross.
It does align with Dad Echo and
he seems real nice and all cruisy.
I think I am a little
bit too cruisey though.
So sometimes you do have to make sure
people understand that if they cross the
line,
there's going to be a problem.
And my kids definitely understand
if they cross the line,
just gonna be a problem. Yeah. That
makes sense. Yeah. It's a real product.
Doesn't surprise me and it keeps
them in check. Yeah. Next Up,
20 and I'm pretty lenient.
I'm pretty cruisy.
You're actually surprisingly
Cruzee and lenient.
Everyone thinks I want
to be the Great Santini.
You probably never seen that movie.
Yeah,
but you don't want to raise your
kids like that. Who was the girl?
You don't want to be all militant and
impose discipline on your kids and make
them number one reliant on your
discipline instead of their discipline.
I don't want to,
you don't want anyone like that.
You don't want your team to be like that
where they're reliant on you barking at
them to tell him what to do.
You don't want that,
then they can't function for themselves.
You don't want your kids to be that
way either. When your kids to think,
you know what,
I need to make a good decision.
I could slack off or I could
do what I'm supposed to do.
I'm going to do what I'm
supposed to do because I know
it's gonna be beneficial in the end as
opposed to I'm gonna do what I'm supposed
to do only because I'm afraid that my
dad's gonna yell at me or ground me or
take away my computer or smashed
one of my favorite toys. Yeah.
Yeah. You don't, you, I
mean the, the assumption,
I think anyway would be that
you're like more drill sergeant.
I'm not even drill sergeant.
I'm never, I know you're not,
but I think it's like when you look
at you or maybe what he just said,
like one or two sound bites and you're
like, oh, he's Joseph. There's recordings,
many recordings of when I used to debrief
seal platoons and I'm going to try and
get some of those. And what is it?
They're just, well, it's, it's definitely,
I could see it's not
drill sergeant. He, yeah,
but it's definitely direct and can
be pretty harsh. Yeah. At the time.
So like that's what I understand people
would probably, but, but that was usually,
it only be that way if somebody really
did something egregious because most of
the time he'd be like, Hey,
what do you think? What do you,
what were you thinking about over here?
Debrief me on that. You know what I mean?
So yeah. And it's all
contextual to like, you know,
I guess it's kind of natural.
Like let's say I heard that right.
I didn't really know you or nothing
and I heard that and be like, okay,
he's real direct and real,
real strict in like all this stuff.
So it's just natural to be like, oh
cause he's that Kinda guy, you know,
rather than kind of understand
the nuance like okay,
he's talking to these people
the time. Yeah. And then versus,
but then again, then that opens it up.
Who knows that and how that you'd be,
so you just eat. Mine just sort of wants
to just attach what they have witnessed,
you know, to everything. Yeah.
Well even drill instructors
aren't like drill instructors.
Yeah. I mean it's a, it's a
training methodology. Yeah.
There's see purpose for the Mac that way.
See,
and you know that because you've been
around that type of leader isn't,
doesn't function,
that type of leader is not good.
That type of person isn't going
to function within the team. Yeah.
So you can't,
you just can't be that way.
Is there a level of intensity? Sure. Do
I bring a level of intensity sometimes?
Yes. Absolutely. Yes sir.
But that's not the way to go through life.
Imposing discipline and
fear into your team.
You'll end up with
either one of two things,
a broken team that relies on you for
their discipline or a team that mutinies
against you and comes up and
kills you. Yeah. Frags you in the,
as they did in the nom.
Alright,
next number 21 good captains.
Common never to fight the
field except necessity.
Constrain them and occasion call them.
Yeah.
So what that's saying is good. You
know, good captains, good leaders,
never enter into the engagement
unless it's completely necessary.
Okay.
That's it. That's a great point. And
this is one of those things where
if you're in a leadership position,
you shouldn't be doing the,
you shouldn't be shooting
your gun at the enemy.
You should be observing your team shooting
the gun and looking to see where the
enemy's maneuvering to. Yeah. This is, uh,
this is about detachment right here. Yeah.
Don't get in the mix.
Stay detached,
decentralized command.
Let the team maneuver,
let them understand what the commander's
intent is and let them maneuver towards
victory.
You stay back a little bit and monitor,
go dive in in there.
Does that apply to,
cause you're the one who kind of
said this example to me one time,
I forget if it was on here or
not, but you were like, um,
it was about you when your kids tying
their shoes, you know, let's say like,
I don't know,
you're late for school or we're running
late or whatever and they're having a
hard time tying the shoes. Yeah.
You're like, let them tie the shoes.
Don't jump in and be like, oh,
I'll do it. You know, kind of,
I did say that and I've
said it a bunch of times.
That's a real simple example that's a
little bit more towards the last question
to or towards the last discussion that we
just got into them and if you let your,
if you tie your shoes for
your kids all the time,
they don't know what amount of
time. Yeah, and furthermore,
you literally are taking
away their opportunity to
learn some fine motor skills
at that moment. This is not
the same as that. This is,
this is on a broader perspective.
Your team is doing,
your team is in a firefight
and you pick up your gun,
you go on the front line and
you start shooting at the enemy.
Well now who's leading right now?
I'm just looking around.
This is the same as you know,
you're in a business situation and your
team is trying to come up with a plan
and they're arguing amongst themselves
and you jump in there and start arguing
too.
Now you don't have a good perception of,
you should be just standing back listening
to the various arguments take place.
And I'm not talking about arguments
where people are yelling and screaming.
I'm talking about uh,
a discussion where they're arguing
different possible courses of action.
If you dive right into those and you
start becoming involved at point blank
range, you lose all your perspective.
So instead you step back and you don't,
you don't, you don't go
into the field. Yeah,
you don't dive into the argument. You
step back and you watch the fight unfold.
And then as the fight unfolds,
you see the best options because you're
at altitude and you're not at point
blank range. One foot
from the enemy fire. Yeah.
This is just detached,
decentralized command.
Next up 22
cause that enemies caused
that the enemy's no,
not how thou right
order vie army to fight.
And in what? Soever manner.
That vow ordained stint.
Make that the first band be
received of the second and the third
middle English. Get something. What
are we talking about here? Well,
cause your enemies no knots.
That means you don't want your enemies
to understand how you're going to
organize your, your army to
fight. That's what this is.
You want to confuse you mean you don't
want them to know exactly what you're
gonna do.
And then the second part,
make it make that the first band may
be received. The second and third,
I'm pretty sure I'm not
a hundred percent sure,
but I'm pretty sure that
that's just talking about
mutually supporting positions.
So you want to set your team up so
that they can support each other.
So confuse the enemy.
Don't give up the plan and set your
teams up so they can help each other.
Once your tea, once a team is alone
and unsupportable there alone. Mm.
Try not to let that happen.
in the fight.
Never occupy a battle to any other thing.
Then to the same four which thou
hast appointed it, if thou will,
to make no disorder.
It's a good day. It's modern English
appreciation. Well, it makes it hard too.
They spell even words that, you
know, they spell them all day.
And just so you know,
you're looking at this,
I actually tightened up some
of the spelling and made
some of the spelling more
modern because I just couldn't, it was
harder to track man. It's hard to attract.
Again,
this,
this thing was interpreted from Italian
in 1560 by Joe was it George White head
was getting after the
translation. Yeah. So um,
it just, it's, it's interesting
and this is the same thing.
You know I said that when
we did Shakespeare don't
need to do more Shakespeare,
but people think,
oh I should just understand Shakespeare,
you're not going to understand stage.
It's almost a different language.
So you need to actually break it down
like we're doing with these various
statements.
So what this one is saying is
don't use a company,
don't use a,
don't use it a unit for a purpose
other than what you've assigned it.
Unless you want to cause disorder,
unless you want to cause chaos.
So you got your team, they're assigned
to do this. Let them do that. Now,
obviously that can be problematic.
And so we need to mitigate that because
there's times when team is going to have
to do something that
you don't want it to do.
And so I'll give you a little example.
When you're doing an assault on a target,
you have two elements,
the base element and the maneuver element.
The base element is going
to stay in position.
They're going to sneak up on the target
and then the maneuver elements going to
sneak over to the flank.
And then the base elements
going to start firing.
Massive firepower at the target.
And then the maneuver
element after a little bit,
we'll stand up and start
to go through the target.
They shift fire off the target
and then you clear the target.
So when I was a young
gun jury,
so we would, we would, you
know like let's do this. Yeah.
So we're going to hit this target,
we're going to do a fire and maneuver
on this target base and maneuver.
So what we would do is say,
okay,
let's take all of our heavy machine
guns and put them in the base element.
And then the guys with the little pea
shooters, the little m 16 shooters,
all those guys will be on the assault
because they're light and they'll be able
to maneuver really quickly through the
get to the target and then go through the
target.
Makes perfect sense.
And I remember the first time I presented
this type of plan to one of the old
guys from nom, he's
like, no, don't do that.
Why not master chief?
This way we have more firepower in our
base and our maneuver guys can maneuver
more quickly.
Here's the problem.
When that maneuver element
is going towards the target,
what happens if they get compromised
and contacted? And now they're that?
They're the ones that have
to lay down their base.
They can't get up and move
because they're being shot at.
So guess who has to move?
The base element has to move and they
can't move very well if they're only
getting a cover fire
from little pea shooters.
So you keep your integrity of your squads
and you utilize them that way and it's
like,
oh,
so what you want to do in this situation
is you want to make sure that your
elements can,
are capable of doing each other's jobs,
maybe not to the fullest extent, but they
at least need to be somewhat capable.
So maybe you put one machine gun and the
expected one extra machine gun and the
expected base element and now you only
have a couple of machine guns in the
maneuver element, but you
got him if you need them. So
I don't 100% agree with that.
That being said,
you definitely want to let people do
the job that they were signed to do.
Make sense? Right? You've trained
them, you've assigned it, let's,
let's try and keep the plan
as it's supposed to be. Yeah.
To the best of our ability, but we're
thinking we're not black and white here.
Leadership is not easy. Um,
uh, you know, another thing is
when you establish your teams, you try
and use those teams for everything.
If you can't,
and again this is a dichotomy because
as much as you want to keep your teams
together,
you also have to train them to be
split up and broken up and combined and
mismatched all together. And I would
always do this with all my fire teams.
So the fire teams would stick
together as much as humanly possible.
But guess what? I would also train them
that if they were all scrambled up,
someone would step up,
take lead and that'd be a new fire
team and we'd start making stuff happen
next up 24
the,
so dean accidents with
difficulty are remedied.
Those that are thought upon with faculty.
I had to look up.
So Dean,
cause I couldn't even get a
clue on what that one was,
but it's some sort of leader or a ruler.
It's actually a ruler.
And this is, this is a, this is a,
so he's saying the soda in accidents,
the leadership accidents with difficulty
are remedied, are hard to fix.
When leadership screws up,
it's hard to fix.
Those that are fought a
pound are with difficulty,
are remedied if you use your head quickly.
So yeah,
there's going to be leadership problems
and they're hard to fix unless you think
and think quickly.
How do you,
how can you improve
your speed of thinking?
Do you know how you can do
that? Practice. Practice? So
let's say get experience to ray cause
experience gives you the practice. Yeah,
it's experience. If I've
seen something before, it's,
I'm going to know a thousand times
faster how I'm gonna react to it. Yeah.
If I haven't seen it before I did.
It takes me a while just to comprehend
what's in front of my face. Yeah.
So that's why when we train,
we train to throw things.
Okay. So first of all,
when we train, we want to throw things
at people that, different scenarios,
different things happening, where they
start to get pattern recognition. Oh,
I've seen this type of thing before.
On top of that,
you also want to train people what to do
or how to react when they've never seen
it before.
Never seen anything like this before.
Because if I show you,
let's say I'm training you for,
well I guess we might as well just
use a Jujitsu tournament, right? Did,
you did too. I'm training you for
Jujitsu situ situations, right?
I teach you how to defend this and I
teach you how to defend that and I teach
you how to defend this and I teach
you how to defend that, right?
And she's Yada Fan, 10 different
things and you get pretty good at it.
I also have to teach you a broad concept
of what to do when there's something
that you don't recognize. So
hey, if the guy grabs your arm,
I want you to pull your arm here. Hey,
if the guys starts to go for your neck,
I want you to swim your arm, your
hand underneath, and Tuck your chin.
If the guy starts pulling
towards your back,
I want you to shift your leg up
and so he can't move around there.
So I'm going to give you exact
steps to execute.
If you see these things,
and then I'm going to say this,
if he's doing something you don't
recognize, here's what I want you to do.
I want you to Tuck your elbows in.
I want you to posture and I want
you to control his hips. Oh, okay.
And then you'll start to be able
to recognize what's going on.
At least you're going to survive. I want
you to detach and step back and say,
what's he attack? Same thing with
combat. I'm going to train you like,
Hey, if he does this, you do that.
If he does that, you do this.
If you have no idea what's happening,
here's what I want you to do.
Get into a 360 degree perimeter.
Listen, right? I mean,
whatever that that
situation's gonna call for.
If you don't know what's happening,
like if I don't know where I'm getting
flanked from or if I don't know where I'm
getting shot at from, hey,
everyone, take a knee, get cover.
Don't just start shooting because
that's going to cause confusion.
It's also going to give away our
position. Yeah. So we're going to do,
when a go into a 360 degree perimeter,
we're going to hold what we got.
We're going to listen. That's
our, that's our, that's our,
if we don't recognize what's happening,
that's what we knew.
So we have standard operating procedures
for things that we recognize and we
actually also have something to do if we
don't recognize we have a procedure for
nonrecognition which
is, which is important.
It's kind of like,
I mean it's different I guess,
but it kind of maybe fits in with,
you know,
help people say expect the unexpected
kind of thing. So it kind of fits in this,
you're essentially trained for
unexpected stuff. Like I would say,
I would say go one.
Yes.
That's the important part is
not just expect the unexpected.
It's have a protocol for when
something unexpected happens.
Here's what we're going to do.
Yeah.
Cause a lot of times when something
unexpected, and I'm thinking,
do you use to two right now? It's
because that's on purpose. You know,
like these guys with these weird games,
this weird tall,
flexible guys or something like that.
They have these weird games and they'll
do stuff that they know or they kind of
rely upon. You not have seen it
before, like you didn't see before.
So they can capitalize when
you start to panic, you know,
or when you can, you know, if, let's
say your arm is out here, like, um,
like there's some leg
locks that, that, uh,
require you to kind of try to spin out
of it and then they'll catch you with
something else. Right. It's kind of that,
so if you have a protocol
that's just like, I don't know,
whatever the protocol is,
safety protocol, you know,
it not only keeps you safe
just statistically speaking,
you know, chances are it'll keep you
safe, but it'll jam up their game. Yeah.
Overall, you know, especially
these people that, that they, they,
they capitalize on you panicking and not,
yeah. Do you want to have
some kind of a reset position?
And I used to use this with
fighters. Like, Hey, here's
your reset position. Like,
just get to hear, cause you're
comfortable there. Get them under control,
control their hips, whatever. Combat.
Same thing. Oh, you're, you're, you're,
everyone's confused. Everyone's mixed
up. Guys are all over the place.
Let's get to a reset position
in a building and now
everyone knows where we are.
We get a control of results.
Business. Same thing we got.
We got scenario that we
don't know what's happening.
You know what general corridors like,
Hey,
we're all going to go
to our normal positions.
We're going to stand by cause we
don't know what's happening, right?
So you've got to have not
just to expect the unexpected,
you've got to have a protocol to follow
when something is occurring that you
don't understand yet.
Some kind of a reset position.
Put that in your world.
Next up,
number 25 men,
iron,
money and bread be the
strength of the war.
But of these four,
the first to be most necessary because
men and iron find money and bread,
but money and bread.
Find not men and iron.
Yeah, that one's pretty, pretty cool.
Pretty self explanatory. Now let me,
let's go to a business perspective here.
A business perspective here,
because this is a, this can help people
make decisions in the business world.
When you're going to
make expand expenditures,
when you are going to invest
in something in your company,
it is important to assess whether or not
you are investing in something that is
going to help you build
is going to help you grow.
Or if you're investing in something
that is not. So for instance,
let's say let's say hey are are
we could either take you know,
$50,000 and remodel our current office
or we can take $50,000 and we can rent
this new sub office in an area
that we don't have any, um,
presence in.
So which one is a better investment?
Like we don't really need
that remodel of our office.
This other thing is going
to help us actually grow.
So make sure that the
investments that you're making,
the first thing you want to
invest in his men and iron, right?
You don't want to invest in money and
bread, money and Brad's going to be gone.
Yeah. And it doesn't reproduce.
It doesn't reproduce itself.
Whereas men and steel is going to get
you more of that bread and iron in the
long run. Or sorry. Bread and money.
Okay.
All right.
Number 26
okay.
The unarmed rich man is a
booty to the poor soldier.
What does that mean? It means
that the unarmed Richman
is the prize of, of course,
ultra. That sort of means
it means, it means be armed
and this is the last one.
Number 27
a costume vice soldiers to despise
delicate living and luxurious apparel.
I liked that one. Mm hmm. What
does that mean? Get your people.
Get your soldiers to
despise delicate living.
Despise Comfort,
despise luxurious clothing.
That's what I'm talking about.
They'll be better soldiers.
They'll be better people. Understand you
feel like I'm talking to you right now.
What the Connoisseur of comfort,
comfort is in my firing line
right now. Yeah, I dig it, man.
I think obviously I can't disagree
with that because Dang me.
Yeah. When you've been uncomfortable
for an extended period of time,
does it not make you a better
person? A little bit. Yeah,
it does. There we go. Yeah.
You know the whole idea of be comfortable.
You've told me the story of you,
because I know it doesn't rain a lot here,
but you used your kettle bells in the
rain and the other day you told me that
story two times, two days in
a row now. Sure. Right? Yes.
Yeah.
Today you told me that even jade,
your brother came out and was
impressed by your determination
commitment.
So what is it,
what is it about that that made you
feel compelled to tell me about it?
And B, you know, for
lack of a better word,
pretty damn proud that you went out in
the rain and did a kettle bell workout
and the cold. Uh, yes.
Well, yeah, it's Straw it.
And how did you feel inside strong
when it was over? It felt better. Yeah.
This is it. Well, yeah,
it makes it stronger.
I'm asking you real questions right now.
It might seem like I'm joking,
but it's actually real. You know why?
Because this is a little step for you.
And there's other people
that are listening that would
benefit from hearing how
taking this little step
away from comfort really,
truly made you mentally
and physically better.
Go Echo Charles.
Well, the, wow, what can I
start on that one? Okay. So,
okay. Yes. I go outside
out of workout planned.
It's raining, raining kind of hard
too, by the way. And it's kind of cold.
The kind you got to wear like a
lot of clothes, you know? So yes,
I go ahead and do the whole workout hard
too. And yes, my brother was like, Dang,
that's some dedication and whatever.
But yes, the, so the feeling is yeah,
that I'm actually strong now. You
know, it's like basically when you,
when you break it down, it's like
now you're strong, you're not weak.
So weak would be like, just the littlest
thing will throw you off your plan.
You know,
the littlest thing because you can't
because you're so used to comfort where
you're still used to like the
clothing thing. I mean, yeah,
that's kind of weird too. Like if you
always gotta be wearing nice clothes,
otherwise like you're kind of, you
don't go out or something. I Dunno,
but it's Kinda the say seems
like the same concept. But yeah,
if you can endure that stuff
and then how do you feel when
you're done better? Yeah.
Did you feel better after a workout in
the cold rain where you went and got
after it then you would have had it
been just normal 70 degrees and sunny.
So cow.
Yeah, a little bit, but
I feel like, um, it's,
it was just more of a psychological thing,
which does help big time
because now you know that rain,
you just proved to yourself that rain,
cold, whatever, is not an excuse.
How old are you for two years?
Rain and cold as an excuse. No more,
no more. Well, here's the thing,
going to battle. You know, it's funny.
Here's a good, here's a good expression.
You used to saying that derives peregrine
occurred when it was raining and cold.
You know, we'd say good weather,
but it was like a, it was kind of,
it's true.
It's definitely true because when it's
raining and when it's cold, guess what?
The people that are, you know
on watch your enemy, guess
what they're doing there.
They're hiding. They're all bundled up
and warm, so that makes it easier for you.
Plus there's noise from the rain,
which camouflage is the noise that you're
making walking through the j or the
woods or whatever. But that's
always a good one. Whenever it's,
whenever it's crappy weather.
I was, I was say to myself,
good operating whether kind of smile, but
we used to say two genders, that's like,
you can't complain about it. You just
look at your buddy. It's like when you,
when the door of the t of the Hilo truck,
you know to Hilo truck is no,
back in the day we didn't have a lot
of money for budget and so we'd pretend
that we were in helicopters and we'd be
in the back of big trucks and they just
drive out in the middle of the desert or
open up the Hilo truck and open it up,
open up the door, and we jump out. Like
we just got out of a helicopter, right?
Little did we know that
when the war actually came,
we would be using vehicles. We used
vehicles all the time. We, Bree,
I rarely,
rarely used helicopters
in Iraq and Afghanistan.
They used helicopters a lot more,
but for me and Iraq,
foot patrol and he load trucks,
but we didn't have to call
them Hilo trucks anymore.
Now we just called them
trucks. Sure, sure.
But when you're in a Hilo truck in 1994
and you get driven up into the wherever
and that door of the Hilo truck opens out,
opens up and it's raining and it's cold.
And as you're getting out of the truck,
your last moment to communicate
out loud to everyone,
you hear someone go good operating
other and you're like, yeah, it is.
This is going to suck. Yeah. And
it makes sense. So like, yeah,
if you're used to being uncomfortable
or if you like despise comfort,
however you put it, it's not me. They,
Machiavelli said despise comfort,
despising comfort.
Essentially. You're getting
comfortable with being uncomfortable.
You know how they say that, right?
They do. They do. Man. So yeah,
that's what they're doing.
So that's why, yeah. Yeah.
Just improve it basically at the end of
the day improves your chances of success,
you know, may, uh, roadblocks of
discomfort come about in the future.
That's what happened. Indeed. And I,
I think that not only will the rejection
of comfort make better soldiers,
it'll make better people. So yes, as
you said, get out of your comfort zone,
impose discipline and discomfort on
yourself and you will become a better
person.
And that wraps up Machiavelli for now.
But Echo,
speaking of,
I'm getting out of our comfort zone and
this is going to be a little dichotomy
here,
but getting out of our
comfort zone to become better,
what recommendations do you have for
us to make that happen? Like I said,
there's gonna be a dichotomy here.
Okay. Cause what do we have? Well,
well, there's a lot of things
you have, but, but yes, so, uh,
being the connoisseur of comfort.
And so you're kind of the kind of
of discomfort really, in a way.
I don't know about that.
Here's the thing though,
I don't think about it much though.
You know what I mean?
I'd have to be like actively thinking
about it. Discomfort, just about anything.
I'm just over here doing what I'm doing.
They know what I mean with discomfort,
just capability. I don't
care. I don't care.
There's that old viking saying
he's like the rain is cold and old.
Viking says,
how can the rain be cold?
Right. The rain's not cold. Yeah,
but I don't know. I don't get it.
How can the rain be cold if
it's cold, Ben? It's cold. No,
it's cold to you when it hits you.
The rain itself hasn't called.
That's a play on words.
Little plan word.
That's another good
thing to think yourself.
Another good thing do you think to
yourself, you only get wet once. Yeah,
I've talked about that before. Yeah, you,
you're waiting to go across the river.
You're looking for the best spot.
You're like, oh nope. Just get wet.
You only get one at one time.
Once you're wet, you're wet.
It doesn't matter if it's true, so
like suck it up. The comfort thing is,
it's all,
it's like context is a huge,
has a lot to do with it. Remember how
I told you that time where it's like,
you know, sometimes you can
just fall asleep on the floor.
I know we're in the beach,
but then sometimes you get in,
you're on your couch or wherever
and you just can't fall asleep,
can get comfortable and stuff,
you know,
because you expect that
comfort is what I'm saying.
But if you don't have any comfortable
expectations, it's like you just be,
you're just comfortable.
It's almost like you're just
appreciative for any kind of comfort.
But if you expect mass comfort, it's like
you can't get enough comfort, you know,
cause you just expect more. It's
weird. So like, like, um, okay, so you,
you know, you have experience with
cold water, right? Getting it nickel,
hit the surf. So when you're
there, how hard is that?
Just not, not right. You're just
like, we're just doing it. Yeah.
This is what we're doing. This is, we're,
we're whatever, it's cold. It sucks,
whatever. Even if it's, but in
the, this is me keep in mind,
but still I think it holds true. So I'm
getting in the shower the other day.
It's cold here, California,
whether it's, go tell that to Pete.
Well Pete's gonna understand because he,
this probably happened to him too.
So listen, you know how you're cold,
you know like it's just sort of cold.
So someone had to take a shower
and you know the kind of,
when you turn on the shower
it's not just doesn't come
out all warm. It got it. It takes
a few seconds or whatever. So,
so I turned it on and hits me.
Oh cause you take warm showers
that day. I should do a warm
shower. Anyone understood. Anyway,
the cold water like kind
of hit me and I was,
oh there's no way I could bear going
underneath that showered like before it
gets warm. No way man. No Way. But
then, and then whatever it heats up.
But I'm thinking like,
no,
like Jocko guys go in that
cold surf like for a long time.
And so then I'm thinking, oh it's
totally in context. You know, like if I,
let's say a minute before I
walked in the shower, I was like,
I'm going to take a cold shower right now
doing it literally the same exact time
I can do it. You see what I'm saying?
So it's like a mindset kind of thing,
Jack, even aside from
the training, of course,
I would say this and the reason that
I can't me, it's just like blank.
No, it's not here. Maybe it
is real, but no, I dunno.
Thinking about this when you get
out of bed, right? Well then again,
your routine's different, but yeah,
let's say you're just sort of,
I have an actual ice bath.
Yeah, but that's different
to a bright, he said, Dick,
I spent the whole time. Okay.
But that's the what I'm saying.
Like what if you get out of no out of
bed or you're just cruising at home,
which you probably don't do, but let's
say you were, and it was just cold.
The kind like heart and
pretty cold right now.
I shouldn't put on a jacket right
now. Let's Hoodie. Whatever.
That's how cold it is right here, right?
Not Freezing, but just I'm cold right now.
Uncomfortably cold.
And then let's say your son comes with
a cup of ice water and dumps it on you.
Right? How'd you sneak up on
me? It's like you're saying,
okay, maybe it didn't sneak up
on you. Maybe he was, I dunno,
but let's say he poured ice water idea.
Okay.
You're just telling me that you're
like whatever. That wouldn't,
you'd be Viking like can be like whoa.
Like I dunno, it's not cold. Well,
I tell you, if he was looking for a
reaction from me, I wouldn't get it right.
Which I dig.
I dig it.
There would be a grappling match
happening real quick though. Yeah. Yeah.
And I understand is an
attack. Okay. So that aside,
I'm talking about the actual
cold water, but it's, so,
it's not nothing, but it's
something, but it's something.
But that compare that experience
to, if he came up to day, Hey dad,
I have this cup of cold water.
It's kind of cold right now.
Do you think you can like endure this?
Right? And you were like, Oh yeah,
I can endure it, do it. And he did it.
I'm not saying now it'd
be nothing or something.
I'm saying that those two experiences
are different. Okay. Yeah.
See what I'm saying?
So this is the element of surprise
is that we're talking about one year.
Was his surprise wonder or not?
If your surprise it going to
throw you off a little bit. Yeah.
If you're not surprised, your brace
for it, you're good to go. Yeah.
I mean as surprise.
That's just one element of a different
context where you don't necessarily exist.
It's surprise and mental preparation.
Mental preparation is,
I think the overarching cause surprise
would fall under the mental preparation
stuff going on in your head,
telling you that shower experience kind
of in linkedin being a little bit anyway.
Okay. Be comfortable with being
uncomfortable. That's a Jujitsu sang too,
by the way.
Is that where you heard him mainly?
Maybe that's where I first heard it.
Yeah, because that's a good thing to have.
Oh yeah,
that's the,
that's the backhanded compliment that
Hixon Gracie told me when I rolled with
him back in the day that
you were comfortable. He
goes, he said, you're very,
you're very comfortable when
you're in a really bad position.
And I was all happy. There you
go. Seems good at Jujitsu. Yes.
So that's what I heard too. Um, but
yeah, so that's what you did to saying.
So that means dude,
you did to kind of really yes.
Last strategy or or what,
what do you call it? Rules.
General rule is essentially
despise delicate living is Jujitsu.
Delicate living and then we'll, it is not,
it's not delicate, but it's not brutal.
It depends where you roll with.
Yeah, that's true. That's very true.
There's some blood on the mat last
night, boy, I believe. Anyway.
Did you get to ifs?
If we're not in Jujitsu already,
we might not agree on the different
mindsets for cold and all that.
But we do agree. Do some digits. Do just
some judges too. And when you do it,
you're going to need a g and what grade
you get none other than thingies that
are made a hundred percent in America
from top to bottom, from origin, origin,
main.com.
That's where you get them.
You can get whatever you want on there
and you can get a rash guard so you can
do no gay as well.
And then you can get a tee shirts
and hoodies which are comfortable,
which,
which are the antithesis of what we're
talking about because you have claimed
and now this claim has been supported
on a social media sites around the world
that the origin jogger pants,
which I don't,
where are universally the most
comfortable pants of all time. Yes,
there are still,
I mean,
and I went on searches like my son got
a pair for Christmas cause you know when
you're in my family,
guess what you're getting for Christmas
products or just stuff.
So he got a pair and I tried them on and
he was like, you got to take a bottle.
They were like, cause how they looked
because they just don't, they're just not,
they're not, it's not me. Yeah.
Cause joggers as functional as they are
because they're super functional as far
as jogging and running as
functional as they are there.
That's a style thing.
Like they're in style right now,
but they're somehow
related to skinny jeans.
Are they not there? At least that's
the look. Yeah. Related. So you,
yeah, you can't wear
skin. That kind of stuff.
Used to issue when I was at seal team
two seal team one we didn't have at seal
team two they issued us joggers,
but this is back in the day.
They were basically like,
they were basically like the same thing
because it was cold in the winter time
and guys would want to run
with those things on. Yeah.
But I didn't wear those either.
But everyone else more weight and their
outer where they weren't underwear where
I'm like over your running
shorts. Oh, okay. Yeah. Cool.
There you go. Yeah. But these are,
these are probably going to be way
more comfortable going from origin. Um,
and they're made in America by the way.
I don't know if I mentioned that,
but yeah, those are good geography. Here's
the thing. You despise come for a while.
I don't think you despise come.
Not as much as I showed the, okay.
That makes sense to me. I don't
despise comfort. Just like,
I don't despise the rest between sets
because comfort is there for a reason when
you're kind of cold. I guess that's
what I was gonna say earlier.
You enjoy comfort more when you
have discomfort. Yes. Right.
Oh, you don't want to be the person
that's constantly in a feather pillow
temperature controlled scenario.
Right?
You want to be in like the tough
environment and then you're like, oh,
this feels good now.
Like when you get out of the one
you've been surfing and it's cold.
I went surfing the other
day with no wetsuit on and
it's winter time here by the
way. But one of my, uh,
to actually have my toes
were numb straight white.
So how cold does that? Maybe like
what, 55 something like that? Yeah.
I mean I only went for like 45 minutes,
but yeah,
it was cold when I got done and
then I went in the Jacuzzi it,
it felt good to see it
not despise that comfort,
but it felt even better than if it
was just a normal day and I wasn't,
didn't have a num two toes.
So really it's more about the
ability to endure discomfort.
That's really what it is. So the light,
the less time you spend uncomfortable,
the less used to it, you'll
be. So Lamar or like, you know,
the less capable you'll
be of enduring it Kinda,
that's kind of the thing. Yeah.
Check what they're going for anyway.
[inaudible] guards, tee shirts,
joggers, uh, supplements,
supplements of course,
joint supplements,
which have shaken up to be the most
important supplements there are per day.
It's true indeed for a semi to
moderate to highly active person.
That's it. Yeah, I know this firsthand.
Definitely. Uh, so joint warfare,
Krill oil, those are for your
joints and for your whole life.
Like this stuff that's in joint warfare,
Tumeric, it has all, all kinds.
It's not just like, yeah,
it's good for your joints,
but it's good for a little, it's good
for everything. Yeah. Which is, as I was
reading more about it or no,
there was an article that spring up,
that's what it was. And I was like, wow,
I didn't know that. Did all of this.
No wonder. I feel so good. Anyway. Joan,
where for Krill oil discipline, there's
also so discipline comes in lemon lime,
which is tasty.
There's also the new
tropic thunder because I couldn't call it,
we couldn't call it Pina Colada
cause that just not happening.
That was just a big negative.
And then there's milk of course,
additional protein,
additional protein that tastes delicious.
It tastes like a dessert.
A for real dessert.
And if you have kids or if you just,
well if you have kids you
get them a warrior kid milk,
which is the best possible thing you
can buy a child for food in my opinion.
Yeah, it tastes well. I
guess if you give him steak,
I think vegetables are good too.
I didn't even like steak when I was
a little kid. Yeah, you like burgers.
I like Burgers, but yeah, you're
more refined now. It's luxurious.
No though is an acquired taste getting
into the steak thing, Huh? Yeah.
Interesting. Plus I had to learn
how to cook it better, so yeah,
warrior kid milk and all that stuff
from origin you can get it. Origin,
main.com.com also,
chuck was a store,
it's called Jocko store,
so you go to [inaudible] dot com and
this is where you can get shirts that
represented the path. I want to
represent discipline equals freedom.
This winning equals freedom shirt here,
and this is what I realized this cycle.
I know, I know. I think maybe
a little bit too much into it,
but this happened though when you were a
discipline equals freedom shirt to work
out you like won't skip the work. You'll
be more into the workout. I noticed that.
Yeah, because you look at it and says
discipline equals freedom. You know,
it's like you're representing
what it's actually saying.
It's not one of these
deals where it's like, Ooh,
a cool star on your shirt or something.
Which is cool.
There's people that have taken that
idea to the next level and gotten the
discipline equals freedom.
Tattoos see,
same exact concept and yet I've seen
it in like a one dude has the desperate
goes freedom. I think it's, it's basically
on the inside of his wrist. Yeah.
Try eating a doughnut with that hand.
It's not exactly that. Just no way.
That's exactly. If that happened,
you'd be in serious violation,
like you couldn't do it.
You'd feel it.
You'd be doing burpees for like
45 minutes after that. Yeah.
You see an I posted a picture of the
guy with it on the inside of, yeah.
No. Well there's one guy
that has an on subs arm.
You're talking about the one guy. There's
a guy that has one was wrist. Yeah,
but that's the one stamp. It was
that roll call. Yeah, that was put,
I took the picture, but yeah,
I saw that. It was good. See,
same exact concept because yeah,
you can't not represent.
Now you know that the shirt
on, boom, you got the tattoo.
Now you can never know represent or are
you going to pay the price to yourself
by the way. So it's like a thing. I
dig it, man. I dig it. Respect. Also,
we get that tattoo.
I think you should only
get that tattoo if you,
if you're, you need to
commit first, right?
Then you commit first
and then get the tattoo.
Don't think that just the Tattoo's going
to push you over the edge even though
probably will,
even though it probably,
maybe that's not the best approach for
a tattoo. Uh, decision making is that,
that's what you're saying anyway. It's
called Jocko store.com. You can get your,
uh, you know the shirts and,
and before you get the tattoo,
get the t shirt and a hat.
A hat has it first.
There's a lot of fear in the game.
Cool.
Then you can step it up a little bit
more. Hoodies. Yes. Women's stuff.
I'm going to have some new stuff on
there too. You keep saying that. I know,
but I'm going to do it.
Meanwhile,
there's their patches right now or are
we out of patches? Oh Wow. I don't know.
Let me,
let me double check and the check.
Let me check with the guy that's in
charge of an, Oh wait, that's you.
Well, rest assured. Hey, if you
see something cool, get something.
If something's sold out or something
like that, I don't know. Let me know.
I guess it won't be, or it'll be on
the way. Either way. It's called Jocko,
store.com.
A lot of cool stuff on there.
If you want something you
want to represent in the
wild in the wild by the way,
get something also Jocko white tea on the
story that we saw that on the store to
buy the one. Um, but you can
get this. Yeah it's good.
Can get it from Amazon as well.
Where else?
Guess what I'm drinking right
now. Hot Tea. Yeah. You know why?
Comfortable cause concept a
little bit cold down in Boston.
Yeah, it makes sense. You're no stranger
to the discomfort so I think you can,
you know, whatever. But yeah,
it's one of those deals where even
if you don't like tea that much,
you'll probably like this was doesn't
it tastes like tea but it doesn't taste
like tea. It's can I say that? Does
that make any sense? If you drink it,
that makes it a dichotomy. There's
a condom, Jocko, white tea.
There's no dichotomy in the fact
that you can be teaching the, the,
the Jujitsu class at the muster.
And he used the word dichotomy and
then everyone started laughing.
Cause the way he says it is like directly
Tz directly mocking me isn't the word
dichotomy. Yup. So yeah,
Jack White outstanding,
uh, stuff makes you dead lift 8,000
pounds, but we already knew that. Yeah.
Everyone knows that worldwide dead lift
has increased a lot also it's in cans,
which is good for me because
the whole brewing tea, uh, uh,
sequence uncomfortable. I'm very
uncomfortable for me. Yes. So you know,
Ken seems more cool, but
whatever, whatever you like.
Also subscribe to this podcast if you
haven't already, uh, on, you know,
wherever you listen to
podcasts. There it is. I know.
I don't think we even need
to say that anymore. Okay.
Well I've said that for like a,
or maybe even three years that we don't
need to say to subscribe to the podcast,
but we do need to say subscribe to the
Warrior Kid podcast. Yes. Check it out.
Check it out.
Even if you aren't a kid and check it out.
I use a different voice in that podcast.
Dave Burke was talking about it.
He's like, I even like that different.
I use this voice right here.
It's a little bit more aimed at kids.
This is just the way I
normally talk when I do,
cause I'm kind of uncle Jake in that
and he nickel Jake is a little bit more,
he's not, you will, not Dorky,
but he just doesn't have his little
bit of a dark side. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah. That's a good way of putting
it. The dark edge. He's just good.
He's like uncle Jake is just good
across the board. You never know what,
I might have a little,
I might have a little issue with
something and get kind of crazy on it.
Jake's not going to let that happen.
So check out the warrior kid podcast if
you want to get some more information to
your kids about being on the path and
you can hear me talk and tell stories in
this voice from Uncle Jake.
Yeah.
Actually sounded exactly like how you
sound on it, which is good. In a way also,
yes, youtube as well, so we do have a
youtube channel. If you didn't know that.
It does have the video version of this
podcast and also little excerpts and
enhanced excerpts. By the way, I was
noticing some of your recent excerpts.
You can't make excerpts that are 12
minutes long. That's not an excerpts.
That's just like a video.
Well,
technically that's not correct because
an excerpt is just a part of this with
the 12 minutes is long, man. I know and
sometimes I'm going to be 12 minutes.
There is no way that everything in
that 12 minutes is important kind.
Yeah, that's true. Okay, but then
you pick out your editing scissors.
Depends on how you look at it though.
These things are supposed to be an expert
should be like, aw, you know what, boom,
two minutes and 28 seconds later you're
like, yeah, I got this. Oh, I dig it.
I agree,
but not a lot of time.
You want people to pull up
and couch and he even for
some of us are on the computer
doing other stuff and then boom,
they're, the expert comes
up, you know, about maybe.
Or maybe it's like you saying something
in me disagreeing and then you saying,
well this is this. And I'm saying,
well that's true, but what about this?
And you're like, oh, okay. Or whatever.
You know, it's like a little list.
So like a little conversation that's
not two hours. See what I'm saying?
So it's presentable. It's good.
It's due. Okay. So there's,
there's on the youtube channel,
there's the long and short excerpts.
That's a good way that's digestible and
there's a little bit more like, you know,
mealtime conversational, uh, you know,
cause it's less about like the
shortness and share ability necessarily.
It's more about like, Hey,
remember this share ability? Oh,
like I can sh watch it come in it.
Yeah.
They're more likely to watch the
minute video then the 12 minute video.
But the 12 minutes,
like the kind of like if you just want
to hear about like the specific topic
that happened to take 12
they're not all 12 minutes.
This may be like eight minutes or so,
maybe six either way.
Psychological warfare too. Speaking of
little excerpts, those are just short,
short,
one to two minutes of how to overcome
some type of momentary weakness that you
might have. If you don't have a discipline
equals freedom tattoo on your wrist,
that's going to keep you in.
Check that.
This is another thing you can
do prior to getting that tattoo.
You can just load up your
psychological warfare on iTunes,
Google play at MP3 platforms,
whatever, and listen to those. Yes.
Which is chocolate telling you how
to overcome the weakness. That is,
that's that tattoo on your wrist is
living equals freedom is like the ultimate
psychological warfare. It is a weapon.
Your weapon. Boom. Discipline. Oh,
what if you put discipline on one
wrist and freedom on the other wrist?
I actually might do that. That's pretty
good. That's pretty good. Discipline.
Freedom at origin. Uh,
I've been talking to Pete,
we're trying to buy a machine that
can make sweat bands wristbands.
Right. And then once we have that
power, two things, number one,
I'm going to make the best wristbands
cause I wear wristbands every time I
workout. Yeah. And, but there's
no good risk bands in the world.
There's none of them that meet the
standards that I would like them to meet.
Why do you where we spent
a sweat primarily. Oh,
so it doesn't go onto to run right
down my arms and my hands and I'm just
dropping everything and
it sucks. Yeah. So, uh,
I'm going to make wristbands that
are super long really. Right.
And really like just
I told Pete and like we can put discipline
a one and freedom on the other one.
Right. And you can buy little
set. Yeah. So anyways, peach,
peach shopping for the machine right now.
Good. [inaudible] yes, it can make socks.
Pete sent me a picture of a machine and
he goes, what do you think this makes?
And I looked at it and I don't know,
I just kinda like logically
it was sort of like a um,
you could see stuff 360 degrees around
something else and I was like I bet you I
said socks. And he goes day on,
cause I'm not in a good district.
He was impressed with my logic.
Deductive skills. It's
good. I'm impressed too.
Speaking of being impressed,
go to on it. So on it,
the company I'm impressed with
always have been by the way,
so go to [inaudible] dot com slash
chocolate this is where you can get kettle
bells,
all kinds of cool workout equipment that
you can just slowly add to your arsenal
at home. You've got a home gym,
whatever. Really good stuff on there.
Also good info on there.
So you know,
if you want to educate
yourself a little bit more bull
Nessa play signal on at.com/jocko
really good stuff on there. Really good.
We got some books.
We got Mikey in the dragons,
which is fully in stock. Lily.
Yeah, it w it ran a little low.
We almost didn't make Christmas,
but we made it. Thank God. Cool.
Thanks to everyone on the team that
helped us in all the printers around that,
that printed us copies and we got a
bunch of copies and everyone got them by
Christmas that I know of.
Everyone that's reached out on Twitter
that said it's not here yet on December
19th or 13th was like we still don't have
it. I ordered October. I was like, hey,
it's competent. Please come. And uh,
but as far as I know
everyone got them when they,
they got them in time for Christmas.
So um,
now we have a lot. So if you
want to get Mikey in the dragons,
best children's book ever. Ever. Yup.
Yeah, yeah. Disagree with me. No.
Well I think just by nature I'm like,
well we use made a claim like refute it.
So I'm all thinking, but because
obviously I want to be like, Hey,
what about this way of the word kid?
Cause I thought that was what
age group for which, okay,
best young,
best.
Was it a toddler that reads
Mike and the dragons toddler,
Mike Todd, best toddler.
Someone they can walk.
Well some toddlers can understand invest
children's book picture book with for
ages five and under
seven and six and under.
Sure Mike and the dragons there cause
you broke that down water that way the
warrior kid when the kids get a little
bit older order way of the warrior kid in
Mark's mission book
three has been written.
I got pictures from John Bozak today via
text. You saw him right? Witnessed. Yes.
Yeah. How do you like him?
We like him a lot. I showed,
I showed Danny Reinhardt to my youngest
daughter and I've been, I've been,
I've been telling her about Danny
Reinhardt for a long time cause Danny
Reinhardt does everything perfect.
And Danny Reinhardt does everything good.
And Mark's kind of jealous of him
and I shoot and she was, she's been,
she got all into the name Danny Rhyne.
She's annoyed with them.
She's already doesn't like him but the,
the interesting twist on the story as
Danny Ryan or it's actually a good kid and
he just happens to be talented and he
happens to work hard and he's actually
nice but Mark's and jealous.
So where your kid three coming out in the
spring and right now we've got warrior
kid one and warrior con two marks.
Mission all got discipline
equals freedom field manual.
The manual for getting
after it. Yeah, in life.
Super stoked on everyone that's posting
pictures and I'm actually most stoked
when somebody posts a picture that
they've lost a 162 pounds in 14 months or
whatever. Completely
changed their lives. Yeah.
Why discipline equals freedom.
So you can get that book for yourself.
That's also pre tattoo.
Maybe before you get the tattoo,
you just leave this out on
Europe coffee table. Right.
You just have it there cause it's looking
at you. That book is looking at you.
I've got a stack of them in my room.
I feel they keep me.
So if you want, if you want the audio
version, it's on iTunes, Amazon music,
Google play, other MP3 platforms.
Obviously extreme ownership.
The first book that I wrote
with my brother Leif Babin,
taking the lessons that we learned on
the battlefield and explaining how they
can be applied to your
business and to your life.
And that was the followed up that was
followed up by the book that we just had
come up out called the dichotomy of
leadership and this is getting granular in
how to apply those leadership
principles into your world. Also,
we have echelon front,
which is uh,
my leadership consultancy and what we
do is solve problems through leadership.
If you have any kind of
problem in your organization,
it is a leadership problem.
It is a leadership problem.
We will help get your leadership fixed,
get them aligned and get them working
and get the team functioning properly.
We also have a leadership
conference that we do.
It's called the muster in
2019 there are three monsters,
May 23rd and 24th in Chicago,
September 19th and 20th in Denver
and December 4th and fifth in Sydney,
Australia.
Checkout extreme ownership.com for the
details and to register all of them that
we've done have sold out. This is,
and what I'm saying, they sold out.
This is when people call me up and say,
or like people that I know say,
hey, hey, I know what a little late,
just want to, can you just, um,
can you just reserve three seats from me?
And you know,
these two other people that I work
with and I'm like, actually no I can't.
You cannot come to, we'll,
we'll just end it back. No,
there's fire codes that you
can't come. Everyone thinks
you all just, you know, no,
it's sold out. So you
can't come. The, the, um,
the live podcasts we're doing January 9th
sold out immediately. He was like,
sorry. Gotta be quick on those. Okay.
So there's that, that we do
have this key f online. This is,
this is the interactive training
leadership training that we put together.
And okay, so there's several
places where this stem from.
One of them is the monster itself.
Cause guess what the muster is
great foundational information.
It's a great foundational leadership,
um,
instruction that you're
going to get when you go.
Not everyone can make it to the muster.
So what we did is we took the content
from the first like two monsters that we
did, and this is the fundamental
principles from extreme ownership,
from the dichotomy leadership.
We took those and put them
into interactive online
training so that people that
couldn't make it to the muster
could still get that training.
We also did it because
companies that we work with,
sometimes they have 10,000 employees,
20,000 employees,
100,000 employees, and all the
employees are not all in one place.
They're all over the place.
They're all over the country
and they're all over the world.
How are we going to
train all those people?
W w what we needed to do was figure out
a way to scale the training that we did.
There were so many requests from the
larger companies we work with to get the
training to all their employees.
How do we do that?
We had to scale it so we put it online
and then once we put it on mine for
companies, we figured, okay,
let's get it out there.
For direct consumers that
want to take the training,
they can't come to the monster,
what have you or they want to get
reminded what they learned at the muster.
Same thing.
So that's online training.
It's available now@fonline.com
also we've got,
yeah,
Overwatch where we are taking leadership
gaps in the civilian sector and we are
filling those leadership gaps with
trained and experienced and tested leaders
from combat aviation and from the SPEC
ops community go to e f overwatched.com
regardless of which side
of that equation you're on,
whether you're a company
that needs leaders,
whether you're a event that seeking
a leadership position in a company,
go to Yaffe,
overwatch.com and fill out the
information that applies to you.
And if you want to continue
this conversation with us,
we can be found up in the
inner webs on Instagram,
on Twitter and on the Facebook
you bought echo what's at Echo Charles
and I am at Jocko Willink and finally to
all our military personnel out there.
Thank you for protecting freedom around
the world and to our folks in uniform
here at home. Police and law enforcement
and firefighters, paramedics,
EMT is correctional officers,
border patrol, all first responders.
Thanks for protecting us and our families.
Okay.
And to everyone else out there,
remember that discipline
is stronger than fury,
okay?
You need a little bit of fury.
You need a little bit of discipline.
You need to combine those things,
but you take that discipline and you
impose discipline upon yourself and reject
and refuse delicate living
and the luxuries that are
available to you in life.
And
Yeah,
get out of that comfort and
make yourself better, faster,
smarter and stronger by going
out there day after day after day
and getting after it.
Until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.