What is the difference between
an excuse and a reason? Hmm.
Kind of a good question, right? Sure.
Okay. And the reason it's a
good question because there's,
there can be legitimate reasons
why things happen. Yeah. Right.
And so for instance, you're in a,
in a sailing race,
right?
In a sailboat and the mast snaps in half.
Now you don't win the race. Yeah.
But I mean you didn't, you know,
the mass snapped.
What can you do about that?
Or the weather's horrible
weather rolls in.
You can't launch your aircraft
so you can't go on your mission.
Well you can't control the weather. So
you know like what's up, how could that,
that's a reason. Or you get really sick
so you can't compete in a competition.
That's a reason you know you were sick.
Oh you do bad because you were sick and
yet there's a reason could be called
now. Now you could look
at the situation and say,
okay,
if I'm going to take ownership of this,
did I properly test the mast? Sure. Did I,
let me ask you this.
Did we have a ground based plan for the
operation in case the weather came in,
we were going to take vehicles instead.
Hmm. Right. Yeah. That would work.
If you get sick before the competition,
maybe you ask yourself,
were you resting properly?
Where you eating properly going into the
competition so you wouldn't get sick.
You could address that.
Correct.
So you can still take ownership of things.
Even if the initial reaction is like,
oh there's, you can't control that.
Well then you can influence it.
You can mitigate it right now.
Can there still be legitimate
reasons? Yes, there can. And for me,
the difference,
the line between an excuse and a reason
is a reason you have zero control over,
right? You have zero. You just have
zero control over something happening.
Well that's a reason.
Did I tell you I was almost late
the other day for something? Uh,
cause this is borderline.
This is borderline.
I had an appointment at 10 o'clock.
I left is a 20 minute drive.
I left
an hour. I left at all.
I left about nine 10.
I left 50 minutes to drive 20 minutes.
Just so gonna make it on time. Yeah. Yeah.
I get on the road basically a couple of
roads out of my house and the one entry
way to get on the freeway is locked down.
Locked down,
like incident,
like isolate some incident incident on a
guy trying to kill himself on a bridge.
Shut the road down. Yeah. So no one's
going on the highway. So what is it?
Everyone's being channelized into
marginal, what are they called?
Back side streets rerouted.
The clock is ticking and,
and I made it right. I made
it. I was four minutes.
I had four minutes to spare. So instead
of it taking 20 minutes, it took whatever,
46 minutes,
took more than twice as long
that that could be,
you know,
fairly legitimate reason.
Now Luckily I had, I always, you know,
I had planned that there could
be something out of my control.
It might take even longer and that's why
I leave early to go to an appointment
or a situation like that.
So I could have also checked the
traffic prior to leaving and taking a
completely different route. That
would have been, I blame myself.
So even in that situation I'm kind of,
I was thinking the whole time, what?
Why did, why didn't I check
the traffic before I left?
I knew this could have happened.
So anyways,
in my opinion and excuses when you
blame something that you could have
controlled in a reason is something
that you have absolutely no control over
whatsoever. You think like a legit
disease. I mean sometimes people have,
they just don't, you can't control
that. It happens. But I think,
and I think this is the important part,
I think that what you will find,
especially when you approach the world
with an attitude of extreme ownership and
that's that you're not
going to make any excuses,
you're not going to name him routes,
is that you actually have a lot more
control over things then you think you do.
We've talked about this before.
When I go to the airport,
I get there really early because it's
something that you have no control over.
You're going to stand in that TSA line
and those people are going to take
forever and that's the way it is.
And if you want to get mad at them,
it doesn't matter. You can't, you can't
control, you cannot control it in any way.
You can stand at the back of my flight's
leaving in 30 minutes and they'll be
like, whatever. You should have showed
up earlier. You can't control it.
So in those situations, how do
you control it? You show up early,
you take ownership of it, you
show up early. You don't just, Oh,
I don't know what happened. The
traffic was bad. I mean it's,
there's a million excuses you can give.
If you get that attitude where
you're not going to make excuses,
you'll actually take ownership of the
things and then you'll actually solve
problems before they even happen.
If I'm going to an appointment and I have
the excuse of my back of my head that,
you know what, if I'm late, I'll
just say it was the traffic.
I have much more increased
chance of being late.
All right, so what's what, that's,
that's one of the things
that makes extreme ownership
hard is it hurts your ego.
It hurts your ego.
It hurts your ego to admit that you have
control over things that went wrong.
That's
that there.
It's your fault that hurts your ego.
It's also effective because of that.
It's effective because you solve problems.
Like I said before, they even happen. You
solve them because you take ownership.
Your man.
Isn't this just a bunch
of semantics though,
like excuses and reasons re cause
really when it comes down to it,
excuse is like an excuse.
Like you're excused.
Like the reason is a reason for sure.
But it's like well that's
what this whole conversation,
yes it is about semantics
and the semantics are for me.
And excuse is something that you could
have controlled and a reason is something
that you could not control. Aren't
they all reasons. So it's up to,
I mean again look, you say
tomato, I say to I get it,
but come on. Hey you brought it up so
you get, okay. So I remember when I,
when I was in elementary school,
you get, you come late to school,
you get in trouble unless
you have an excuse.
Now with it's, there's a
difference between, and I'm
saying in the, in the field,
in, in class, right? You come,
you come into class if you
have just your own excuse,
like oh my, you know, dog ate it or
know that's for homework, but whatever.
That's different than if
you have an excuse slip,
which is an official slip,
you know,
your parents or your whatever you
into the office and all this stuff.
Your movement to get excuse, slips,
change to reason slips. Cause that's what,
it's still legitimate reason. Exactly.
Kid had chicken pox can't come to school.
Yeah. So you can't come. Yeah, there's
nothing. You got chicken pox. That's what,
that's what, that's how, yeah.
That's how so but now given that now
aren't we just talking about a very split,
like a standard from case to case. So
like let's go back to La to school. Bret,
bear with me. You want to get to the
bottom of this. I'm telling you if you,
if you're paired by the thread by thread,
if your parents had car trouble, right?
Yeah.
Is that an excuse for a
nine year old for a nine
year old? Yeah, it is.
It is a reason for a nine year old that
falls on the hierarchy of standards,
but within the standards of being
a quote unquote legitimate excuse.
Right. Cause that's really what it
is. So a reason in your case, I mean,
you're a reason,
is language a legitimate excuse?
That's a reason as far as this
question goes. Absolutely. In fact,
I think I use the word
legitimate and yeah, in this
one, let's talk about it. Yeah.
Yeah. And so using the word reasons
rather than excuse is just like, okay,
let's make the language more simple rather
than, because if you have an excuse,
if you have an excuse that's an by its
very nature, by its very definition,
you're excused. It's an excuse.
You're excused from for me,
late or being linked to your
blog, whatever. But if it's,
it's weird because if someone else
gives it to you, gives you the EC,
like you're excused, Da, hey, the guy was
about to commit suicide. I get it, man.
You're excused kind of thing.
It's like that's an excuse in this case,
a legitimate one,
but if you give it to yourself,
that's the excuse that nobody
likes. Right. Like, hey man,
traffic, all you should have prepared
for that. Hey Man, my, you know,
whatever was going on and this and that.
Aw Man, you got to prepare for that.
See what I'm saying? Yeah. I guess
they're off of, there you go.
So reasons and legitimate excuses.
Same thing. Yeah. I'll give you that.
You could have said that
like four minutes going.
I'm just saying you got to explain these
things because sometimes the hard to
understand. I'm telling you no.
See, the more you talked about it,
the less I understand. [inaudible] said
the last thing I had to sum it up. Okay.
What I'm saying, the summary was great.
I'll give you a a B plus on the summary.
All right, pat, thanks.
I'll take it. Thank you.