This is Jocko podcast number
one 22 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening
and if you have not listened to episode
one 21 the previous episode to this one,
go listen to it before listening to this
web episode or even the next episode.
They are all linked together and that's
why we released them all at the same
time.
This episode picks up where
the last episode left off.
This episode is about the story of chesty
puller son Louis B polar junior and we
will be learning about Lou polar junior
from his audio autobiography which is
entitled Fortunate Son.
It is a Pulitzer Prize winning book
about his life growing up with his father
and his experiences when
he joined the Marine Corps,
served as a platoon commander in Vietnam
and about his life upon his return from
the war and the struggles that he faced.
Let's go to the book.
I first noticed my father's tattoo this
summer. He returned from the Korean War.
We had just moved from Virginia to the
Marine base at Camp Pendleton. California.
Mother had asked me to awaken him from
an afternoon nap and as I entered their
bedroom and stood beside
his sleeping figure,
my eyes were drawn to the Blue Globe
and its anchor on his right upper arm.
When I extended my hand to trace
the outline with my finger,
he awakened and acquiesce and acquiescing
to the curiosity of a five year old.
He playfully flexed his bicep and
tussled my hair with his free left hand.
I had no idea that the object of my
fascination was the emblem of the Marine
Corps,
the organization to which my father had
already dedicated more than 30 of his 53
years.
I did know that it must be important
because my mother had a piece of gold and
silver jewelry in the shape of my
father's tattoo and she wore at frequently
when she got dressed up.
Later I learned that mother loved the
Golden Silver Pin and despised the tattoo.
There were other things I noticed about
my father and the summer and fall of
1951 a time during which he made a special
effort to be accessible to his only
son and to make up for his
absence during the war.
My father had been promoted to the rank
of brigadier general after leading the
First Marine regiment of the First
Marine Division in the retreat from the
chosen reservoir through Cotu re just
before Christmas 1950 the breakout came to
be regarded as a classic in the annals
of modern military modern American
military warfare for his role in holding
together the rear guard during some of
the bloodiest fighting of the war.
My father was recognized for his heroic
leadership and his elevation to flag
rank was assured
after the engagement ended.
Mother told me father had escaped
from a trap set by the red Chinese,
but I could not envision his being
caught in a device similar to the one I
baited with lettuce and the apple
orchard behind my grandmother's home in
Virginia where we waited out the war.
He had sent me warm a mentos to Korean
swords and enemy helmet and Bugle and
several metals which arrived
in silk lined blue boxes,
affectionately known among his beloved
Marines as the old man or chesty for the
way he carried himself when marching.
He must have known that combat taking
place on the frozen waste waste in ridges
of Korea would be his last and even
then he was passing on to me the proud
traditions of his profession.
For my sixth birthday,
near the end of the summer,
he gave me a 22 caliber single shot rifle,
which he had modified by sawing the
stock and half to accommodate my narrow
shoulders and short arms on the butt.
He had stencilled my name Louis
be polar jr and added the end.
The added touch filled me with pride of
ownership and a certainty that I had the
best father in the world.
After we had practiced on
paper targets and tin cans,
he took me into the Brown hills around
our home in search of California Jack
Rabbits. At first I struggled
to matches long legged gate,
but after he realized
that I could not keep up,
he slowed his pace and began
circumventing the steeper hills.
Even then I tired easily and my aching
legs diverted my attention from our
elusive quarry throughout the several
months that we hunted together and Camp
Pendleton countryside. I never once
came close to hitting a rabbit,
but my father puffed silently on
his pipe pipe each time I missed.
And on those occasions when he bagged
game, I was allowed to carry our trophies.
The last hundred yards back home
in early February is my twin sister.
Martha and I were beginning
of the second half,
half of our first year of grade
school and our older sister,
Virginia was seemingly
an adult sixth grader.
A parade was held to honor my father's
heroism at the chosen reservoir.
I was permitted to go along with mother
and she held my hand as we stood at the
end of a sun drenched parade ground and
waited for the ceremony to end when the
last drum beat sounded and the standard
bearers had retired. The colors.
My father's strode from the field on
which he had just been honored and knelt
briefly to let me view the
object of the mornings.
Pageantry a gold star in
lieu of his fifth navy cross,
the most ever earned by any one marine
and our country sank second highest award
for valor now joined the
panoply of ribbons that
covered most of his left chest.
The moment of that frozen instant more
than three decades ago is this fresh and
firmly fixed in my mind today as
any of my most vivid boy had boyhood
recollections.
Okay.
At Camp Pendleton,
father commanded the third marine brigade
and was charged with training fresh
troops for the denouncement being played
out along the 38th parallel in Korea.
On several occasions,
he and his dream driver,
Sergeant Orville Jones took me with
them to observe war games and field
exercises in Pendleton Scrub,
dotted boondocks.
I was naturally fascinated
by the maneuvers of khaki
clad marines and the smoke
and funder of mock warfare.
So
it's,
it's a beautiful picture.
It's a beautiful picture
and he's home from war.
Luckily they must have had their kids
pretty late because he's young and you
know, chestie's I think 45 at
this point or something like that.
45 or 46 so had the kid had at
least Lou Louis Junior when he was,
I don't know, 40 or something
like that. And this is like a,
every kids you know would be
stoked on this dad. And you know,
I know when my,
when my son was like this age,
I would bring him sometimes to
our training sites and he would,
yeah,
shoot machine guns and
grenades and stuff like that.
And he'd watch all the maneuvers.
Sorry, these, let me tell you.
Six year old boys, they like that kind
of thing. I promise you. All right.
Back to the book. In August, 1953 when
the crew with the Korean War ended,
father was promoted to major general and
the sign in front in our front yard was
repainted to reflect as new rank.
We had to mute our celebration because
the general who lived across the street
was not selected for promotion, but all
in all times were good in our lives.
We're happy father had
sufficiently decompressed from
his Korean War experience
that he was no longer making the kinds
of inflammatory statements about the
conduct of the war that had gotten him
just him into so much trouble in the past,
including one that haunted him for years
to the effect that whiskey and beer
would make troops fight better
than ice cream and soft training.
The promotion to major general was proof
that he was on track toward at least a
possible shot at becoming commandant
of the Marine Corps and fulfilling a
lifelong ambition.
So the commandant of the Marine Corps
is the senior ranking marine and
that's,
I guess
obviously his goal or was his goal.
All right.
He was ordered by the
commandant. Now, you know,
I covered some of this
and in the first book,
but he was ordered by the commandant of
the Marine Corps to report to Bethesda,
Maryland, Maryland naval
hospital for further evaluation.
After two weeks in the hospital,
he was found unfit for duty and
scheduled to go before retirement board.
In early August.
He returned home angry and bitter,
and perhaps because he couldn't
discuss the perceived unfairness of his
situation with his fellow marines,
he vented his frustrations on mother.
He had felt from the time of his illness
that a quartiere of senior officers in
the Marine Corps was jealous of a
celebrity and would use the stroke as a
pretext to end his career. And that's
what is not mentioned in the first book,
is that it was a,
it was a minor stroke that he had had.
He viewed his summons to Bethesda
after a board had already passed on his
fitness report as part of a conspiracy
to do him in and was even critical of the
commandant of the Marine Corps.
I was never told what words passed between
my father and the commandant while he
was away from us in Bethesda,
but given his father,
but given father's outspokenness and his
sense of injustice being done to him,
I'm certain that they
were less than cordial,
general Lemieux Mule Sea Shepherd.
The commandant had also been my
godfather and prior to father's stroke,
he regularly sent me birthday presence
after father came back from Bethesda.
I never received another
gift or communication from
my godfather and for years I
did not understand if or
why he had abandoned me.
So I'm sure chesty I'm sure Jesse let
let the common dot know what was up and
what he thought about what's going on.
So as we know from the first book marine,
the life of chesty puller,
that after he was retired
from the marine corps,
they went to
two chestie's wife's hometown.
Here we go back to the book,
the Sleepy Little Virginia town of Saluda.
Although straddling a major north
south thoroughfare was no more than a
crossroads with a dozen or so small
businesses and 50 or 60 houses.
Had it not been my mother's birthplace,
it would've seemed strange.
It would have seemed to same strange
setting for a man famous as my father to
have picked to spend his retirement years.
There was so little industry and so few
business opportunities that most of the
young men and women moved away as soon
as they finish school and the inhabitants
who remained were either old or
unenthusiastic about moving on.
Without a support staff,
our lives become,
became much less pampered and for the
first time Martha and I were faced with
household chores prior
to father's retirement.
I never made my own bed or shine my own
shoes and now it was expected to help
maintain a home.
There were times early on as I struggled
beneath a load of firewood or rake
leaves into a pile for burning when
I thought what a downward turn of our
fortunes had taken. Gradually, however,
I began to take pride in
my responsibilities and as
the house and grounds began
responding to our nurturing,
I felt real accomplishment.
We never talked about father's
stroke after we moved to Saluda,
but there was an unstated premise that
he was unable to do any strenuous work
around the house and I
tried to step into the void.
I puffed with pride to think that I
was in a sense becoming the man of the
house.
So little boys stepping it up.
Now
as as in the first book we talked about
the trial that took place in the end
where the recruits were killed in and
drowned and chesty puller was called to
the witness stand from retirement to
talk about Marine Corps training and this
is when he comes back from
that back to the book.
We met him at the airport in Richmond
when he returned home and I knew by the
way, he constantly strode
through the crowd of cameras,
photographers and newsmen on his way
to the car that he was pleased with his
performance at Parris Island.
Apparently most Americans agreed for
in the weeks and months that followed,
he received hundreds of phone calls,
telegrams and letters praising him for
coming to the defense of the Marine Corps.
I realized then that bitter as he was
for the way he saved himself to have been
treated by the higher ups in
the Marine Corps headquarters.
He was incapable of sitting idly by
while his beloved core was under attack.
His testimony also reinforced
the perception that he
was a marine's marine who
cared far more about the enlisted men
than he did about high ranking officers.
We also hunted together as we had five
years earlier in the hills of Camp
Pendleton. By now having moved up
from a 22 to a 12 gauge shotgun,
I could easily keep up with my father
as we stocked through the woodlands and
open fields around Saluda looking for
rabbits and squirrels in California.
I had been amazed that my father could
walk so fast and so far while I seem to
always be out of breath or trying to
ignore the woodiness in my legs now.
However, as he neared 60 years of age
and I was moving into adolescence,
the roles were reversed and he was the
one who needed frequent stops renew his
strength.
He still had a good eye and quick enough
reflex is to be able to bring down a
flushed quail are moving rabbit,
but I was beginning to understand that
when he paused to listen for game or
check his bearings,
he was really buying time against his
encroaching against the encroachments of
old age.
So that's the way it is.
That's the way of works.
Yeah.
Good manners were an element
in our upbringing that
mother and father considered
important.
I was taught early to stand when adult
entered adults entered the room and help
ladies out with their chairs
or with car doors. We weren't,
we never interrupted grownups and
conversations and when addressing them we
always ended our responses
with sir or ma'am.
Father taught me to squeeze a man's hand
firmly when I shook hands and to look
people straight in the
eye when we were talking,
he valued personal appearances and good
grooming and until I left for college,
I never went more than a
few weeks without a haircut.
When I was in seventh grade,
he taught me how to tie a neck tie
and from then on I was expected to be
properly dressed in a coat
and tie for special occasions.
Okay.
I was equally aware of how I
looked to others. In seventh grade,
I was fitted for braces by an orthodontist
in Richmond and on the way home in
the car,
my teeth hurt and I was depressed.
I had gotten eyeglasses only a few months
earlier to correct my near sightedness
and the braces were coming so quickly
after the glasses were more than my
fragile psyche could handle.
Father noticed my despondency and
suggested that we stop on the outskirts of
Richmond for cheeseburgers and ice cream.
With my sore teeth,
I could manage neither.
So while mother and father were finishing
their meal and the drug store where we
just stopped, I wandered over to the
magazine stand and began browsing.
Before I had gotten two
pages into the magazine,
I had selected a burly white collar.
Druggist appeared at my side,
snatched the magazine from my hand,
then began brow beating me for reading
the magazine without paying for it.
I was totally bewildered by his attitude,
but before I could retreat or apologize,
I saw it at the corner of my eye that my
father had risen from his booth and was
advancing towards the druggist.
His teeth were tightly clenched,
as were his fists,
and there was fire in his eyes
as he came to rest with his face,
not six inches from the drug lists.
Before he spoke,
I looked at my mother, who with
her eyes closed in the vinyl booth,
appeared to be praying and then I looked
at the druggist who is at least 50
pounds heavier in 30 years younger
than my father. Leave the boy alone,
my father growled, growled,
and a voice gone hard,
or you and I can go outside
and settle this for a moment.
That drug has said nothing has his face
blanched until it was the color of his
color.
Excuse sir,
he finally stammered and then retreated
to the safety of his cash register.
Okay.
Mother had reacted as if she had seen
my father behaves similarly on other
occasions
at Christchurch, so this is where
he went to school at Christ church.
I threw myself into studies
partly to compensate for
not being a capable athlete.
I did well academically and quickly
gained a reputation as one of the bright
boys.
So in the book he talks about how you
know he's just not not a great athlete and
his sister is a better athlete than him
and she kind of, it's his twin sister.
She kind of does better and things,
so he focuses on his academics.
As I grew older,
I began to sometime the sometimes
painful process by which a son distances
himself from his father and preparation
for striking out on his own.
I began to realize that my father,
the man and my father, the legend,
we're not always one and the same.
The legend was all powerful,
fearless in the face of any challenge or
adversity and incapable of mistakes in
judgment or unfairness in
dealings with lesser mortals.
The man,
like most men approaching their twilight
years was not as strong as he had once
been. Occasionally showed signs of self
doubt and made his share of errors when
interacting with other people
from the time I was a little boy,
he had delighted in balling up his fists
and playing and playfully going several
rounds with me. He continued the
game after I started high school,
but by the time I was 15 or 16,
my reflexes had become sharper than his
and I became uncomfortable exchanging
mock punches with him.
Okay.
The, the, it's, it's interesting
and I watched a few interviews with,
with uh,
Lou polar junior and he's not,
it might sound my keys,
um,
being disparaging by saying there was the
legend and then there was the real man,
but he, it, he comes clear in the book.
He's not being disparaging at all.
He's, and he definitely, in some of
the interviews I watched with them,
he's explaining like, no,
it's not a negative thing,
it's just that everyone fought.
Chesty Puller was this legendary thing,
but it was the man that he knew as his
dad and that man was more important in a
better human being and all that.
So he's not being disparaging by saying
that there was a difference between the
two. He's just be stating that
there was a difference. Yeah.
Okay.
But as you know, as loopholes going
through this rebellious stage,
back to the book,
I also began to be bothered by my fathers,
by the waste of my father's considerable
talent and an inordinate amount of time
he spent on trivial undertakings.
Okay.
My father spent hours sitting at the
dining room table playing solitaire or
rereading books that he
had owned for many years.
Mother was busy running the House
and raising Virginia, Martha and me.
While there were days during which my
father did nothing more than make an
occasional trip to the corner
store fetcher fetch the mail.
He was easy to have around the house and
was almost totally undemanding of his
children.
But it seemed to me that
this living legend should
have more important things to
do than serve as an air board.
Aaron boy. For my mother.
I did not realize that the Marine Corps
had been his whole life and that in
committing himself so
totally to its mission,
he had never had the time for
hobbies or other outside interests.
I also did not see until I was much
older that my father's stroke had taken a
physical toll on him that
he would never acknowledge.
In the middle of my junior
year in high school,
my father awaken one night in intense
pain and they took him to Portsmouth Naval
Hospital.
And on the way there,
my father held tightly to my hand for
most of the trip and I could tell that he
was in agony.
Although the only complaint was that
he was not allowed to smoke in the
ambulance.
Okay.
And when he returned home
a loophole or finally realized
that he wanted to talk,
and so now they're kind of,
they kind of connect here for
perhaps seven or eight days.
In that winter of 1962 I was able to
communicate with my father as I never had
before.
He told me that he was fearful about aging
and the inevitable declining state of
his health and about how he never
wanted to be a burden to his family.
I listened as best I could to an old
man reveal feelings that he had never
expressed before.
He also told me that he was counting on
me to carry on when he was gone and how
proud he was to have a son
to continue the polar name.
Okay.
We did not talk about the military or my
attempting to follow in his footsteps,
but even then,
there was some unstated assumptions
about the course my life would take.
Several years earlier,
shortly after his retirement,
we had gone to the William
w gone to Williamsburg for
an outing and he had taken
me to see a short film about the
American Revolution called the story of a
Patriot,
which was shown continuously to tourists
visiting the new information center.
At the conclusion of the film,
the main character watches a group of
young men who have just enlisted to go
fight the British and he swells with pride
when he sees his son among the ranks.
Of the newly enlisted,
my father's enchantment.
With that scene registered
powerfully on my young psyche.
And without ever saying another word,
I knew that someday I would be
enlisting in some as yet undetermined.
Cause now five or six years later,
I shared the dining table of
our home with the man I loved,
like no other in the world.
I wanted desperately to be
what he expected me to be.
It took me years to realize that I could
never hope to emulate the legend that
was chesty puller.
Okay.
But I knew even then that I love
the man far more than the legend.
Okay.
Oh sorry. Yeah, it's reality. It's life.
And as I mentioned in the
beginning of this whole thing,
this a story about life.
If you carry it through all
stories about life and death,
and you can see some
deterioration starting to occur.
Back to the book in the autumn of 1967
with the lengthening shadow of the
Vietnam War,
spreading a chill across America.
I moved on from the carefree pursuits
of undergraduate life at the College of
William and Mary and join the
Marine Corps like my father,
who had enlisted 50 years earlier
during the war to end all wars.
I traveled from Rural Virginia to the
Marine Corps recruiting station in nearby
Richmond in search of
something larger than myself.
I had drifted through previous four years
drinking beer and chasing girls with a
singleness of purpose that belied
my lack of meaningful direction.
And now on the threshold of
manhood and with war is a backdrop.
I realized the time had come
to put my frivolity aside.
So obviously he goes to college,
he gets done with college,
and he says,
I'm going in the Marine Corps.
William and Mary in the months prior
to my departure was still the sleepy
southern campus who's quaintness
at attracted me four years earlier.
The carnage taking place in Southeast
Asia had remained a distant and
nonintrusive reality for all,
but the most perceptive of us insulated
as we were by youth and inexperience.
So even with the Vietnam war going on,
like they weren't even
paying attention to it.
Even even even loophole and
wasn't paying attention to it.
Yeah.
There were,
however signs of a more ominous nature.
The networks had begun reporting the
rising casualty tolls on the nightly news.
I viewed the graduation that ended my
student draft deferment and qualified me
for the Marine Corps officer candidate
program as an opportunity rather than a
burden.
As I entered the recruiter's office,
I was acutely aware of the impact that
my name would have on the sergeant whose
duty would be to convince me of the
golden opportunities that a hitch in the
Marine Corps could provide.
Okay.
The marine corps builds men.
The decal sat on his office divider and I,
in my youthful exuberance,
never pause to consider that
the core might do the opposite.
When he realized who I was,
the sergeant dispensed with his usual
sales pitch and concentrated on the
mechanics of becoming the recruiter
who signed up chesty puller son,
the recruiter,
also telephone to Marine
Corps in Washington DC to
obtain a waiver for my poor
eyesight and the authority on the other
end of the line at first demurred but
then act. We asked when he realized
that if he stood from the core,
would fail to sign up the son of
its most famous marine because of a
technicality.
Okay.
I returned to Saluda to await orders
to Quantico for basic training.
My older sister's husband,
captain build the beat.
Dabney was already serving a tour as
a Marine infantry company commander in
Vietnam and she too was back at home,
sitting out our generation's
initial venture into the war.
Okay?
After a childhood diet of Hemingway
novels and John Wayne Movies,
along with my father's ex Zamvil,
I viewed my own prospects,
if not with eagerness,
at least with equanimity.
Okay?
The comradery of the fraternity.
It talks about how he's in a fraternity
and whatnot. One of these at college,
the Camaraderie of the fraternity now
seemed almost trivial and although I often
drink myself to the point of oblivion,
I could not escape the
feeling that for me,
the carefree celebrations of
youth could not be recaptured.
Of all my acquaintances,
acquaintances at William and Mary,
the only one had been touched by war
for which I was headed. Brian Speer,
the president of a neighboring fraternity,
whose dreams of manhood
I have been privileged to
share and frequent late night
bull sessions had preceded
me into the marine corps
and had been killed within months of his
arrival in Vietnam. The previous June.
His death saddened me and brought home
the intimations of mortality with which
most of my circle were
blessedly unfamiliar
during this.
You Remember Charlie Paul talking about
when they are at the naval academy and
they weren't even talking about
Vietnam. It's crazy, isn't it? Yeah.
Very similar,
but it must've been,
I guess they didn't have the 24 hour
news cycles you have now in the Internet
and the stories and the click bait and
all that stuff going on and those things
can be a little bit more isolated. Yeah,
like you got to choose to follow it. Yeah.
Yeah.
You've got to help the story a little bit.
During this waiting time,
my father had remained characteristically
closed mouth about my future in the
Marine Corps. I, of course,
knew that he was immensely proud of me
for having chosen to follow his example,
but a tacit understanding between
us made words unnecessary.
I felt an urgent and compelling need to
prove myself worthy of his name and key
in the twilight of his military
career that spanned almost 40 years,
wished that he could go in my stead.
Okay.
As I said my goodbyes and
prepared to leave for Quantico,
he kissed me squarely on the lips and
held be tightly and his arms are reported.
Officer candidate school is late
in the day as was acceptable.
I overheard two large sergeants
conversing animatedly about who among this
miserable collection of pukes could
possibly be chesty puller son.
And I wondering if I had taken
on more than I could handle.
So they got a.