There are no bad teams,
only bad leaders.
Do you think there are exceptions to this?
If so,
how do you know you're
apart of the exception?
That is a quote from the book,
extreme ownership written by
myself on my brother Leif Babin.
And it is a quote that I don't
want to say we stole, but we stole.
We appropriated from David
Hackworth who said there's no bad,
I think you said no bad officers,
no bad unit's only bad officers.
And Napoleon who said there is no
bad regimens, only bad kernels.
And we said there's no bad teams,
only bad leaders. And the question is,
is there an exception to this?
And how do you know if you're part of
the exception? Well, actually there is,
there's a big exception to this and the
exception is that there are bad leaders
with good teams. That is
true. That can happen.
Sometimes you get a bad leader that
is running a really, really good team.
So that's an exception.
I guess it's an exception to this rule.
Maybe that's the way I took it.
Uh,
so you get a team that's so good
that they just continue to perform.
Even though they have a horrible leader,
they perform despite their bad leader.
Gotcha.
Now what this doesn't,
this does not prove,
you know, I always say leadership is the
most important thing on the battlefield.
This doesn't disprove that statement.
You'd think maybe it does because oh well
you've got a bad leader and you've got
a good team. Then maybe leadership
hasn't been important. That's wrong.
Actually what it proves is that leadership
can come from any level inside the
organization.
That's what improves.
And it proves that because I've
seen that over and over again.
And when I was running the
training for the seal platoons,
eventually I didn't care where the
leadership in the platoon was because I
realized that it was a real,
it was a real hard thing to hope for
that you had the person that was in the
leadership positions like the platoon
commander or the platoon chief to to
assume or to figure that they were going
to be the leader that you wanted them
to be,
was a big assumption to make.
And so what I realized
after training for awhile,
it was like even though I wanted the
leaders to be those senior guys who were
supposed to be taking leadership,
eventually I realized as I didn't
care where that leadership came from,
as long as there was a
couple of good leaders,
you would end up with a good seal
platoon and a platoon would be on track.
Now maybe the question is what this
person is hinting at the exception being,
is there an exception that
if there is a bad team,
maybe that team is just so filled with
bad people that they can't get the job
done.
That's the kind of accepting you talk
about or failing because the team is so
bad. Even though the leader's
good, even though the leaders good,
but the team is so bad that that's an
exception to the, oh well guess what?
Who's responsible for
the people on the team?
Who's responsible for training the people
on the team so that they can get good
at their job and they can perform with
excellence or who's in charge of getting
rid of the people that are sub par so
that the team steps up their performance.
Well, by answered all those
questions is the leader.
So if you're on a bad team and you're
leading the team, it's your fault.
And there's no exceptions
to that. Yeah, zero. Yeah,
I'm over here trying to think of the
exception, but just what you said is like,
Eh, kind of, yeah. Kind of mitigates
any, hey, this, this, let's take a real,
a real simple example of like
a sports team, right? Oh,
this sports team got dealt a bad hand
and now the people on the team, well,
what are you gonna do? You're going to
train those people who's responsible?
I'm not saying you're going to
press start performing right now,
but you can get on the trajectory will,
you'll be good eventually.
Now if you just blame, hey, I
got a bad team. Well guess what?
Then you don't put an effort. Guess what?
You're going to continue to be a loser.
The exception. Yeah, but my
team, my team is just so bad. You
can't train your people.
I'm not saying you're a miracle worker.
I'm not saying you can.
You can take people that don't have
any skills and instantly through your
leadership turned them into
incredible performers. No,
that's not going to happen.
But guess what?
As a leader,
you go out and you bring people
into your team that are good. Go.
You do train the people that you do have
up to the best of their abilities and
the people that can't perform the way
they need to perform. You get rid of them.
Yeah.
Yeah. That's it. No real
exceptions other than, yeah,
you can have a good team with bad leaders.
Yeah.
If only because there's a good
leader somewhere in there. You know,
the exceptions thing, I think
it's healthy, in my opinion.
None didn't go through this.
And most other things where if,
if I or we start thinking
that we're the exception,
so we don't have to put in like, I
don't know, like the work or whatever,
and not necessarily work with the, you
know, how like, okay, we'll take this on.
No bad teams don't leave
badly. Leaders. Ah, you know,
if I say I might be the exception
to this cause my team is so bad,
it's Kinda like, yeah, aren't you kind of
do a little cop out there kind of thing.
100%
our bottom line is if you don't
take ownership of what's going on,
then you're not going to perform well.
If you just blame your genetics,
then that means,
okay,
well then I'm not going to get in any
kind of shape whatsoever. Then guess what?
Guess what kind of shape you're
being junk, substandard, substandard.