This is Jocko podcast number
22 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
And I would say that it is a good evening.
Sure because we are free,
we are free
and I talk about that
all the time and you hear me
say discipline equals freedom.
You hear me say free your mind
and here in America and in places around
the world that have the ability to be
listening to this podcast,
a lot of times we take freedom for granted
and we all want freedom.
We want the ability,
the capability to move around
and go where we want to go.
But more importantly
we want freedom of the mind
and freedom of the heart.
And those things sound abstract.
They seem like things
that cannot be taken away.
We don't even know what that means to
have them taken away because of the way we
live and how we were raised
to think what you want to think and
believe what you want to believe
to be who you want to be,
to have and to exercise
the freedom to question
and the question,
everything.
That's freedom.
And there are parts of the world
where none of those freedoms exist.
Yeah.
In worse,
there's parts of the world where any
chance of free thought is exterminated.
From childhood,
we'll broken
dreams,
extinguished,
faults controlled.
So
let's go to a place where that
is the reality, and again,
I'm going to point this out.
This is not a dystopian movie
or some post apocalyptic novel.
This is real,
real life
with real people.
Cool.
Red is reserved for the lettering
of the propaganda signs.
The Korean language uses a unique
alphabet made up of circles and lines.
The red letters leap out of the
gray landscape with urgency.
They march across the fields,
preside over the granite
cliffs of the mountains,
punctuate the main roads like mileage,
markers and dance on top of railroad
stations and other public buildings.
They say things like this,
we have nothing to envy in the world.
If the party decides we do
long live, Kim, Il Sung,
let's live our own way.
We will do as the party tells us,
we will do as the party tells us.
And like I said,
this isn't a book.
This is real.
This is North Korea.
This is a story of horror,
end of slavery and of brain washing.
And it's also a story of choices,
story of freedom.
And it's also a story of the
strength of the human will.
This is a book that is
called nothing to envy,
ordinary lives in North Korea.
It's by Barbara Dimmick
or DEMEC.
Yeah,
it Teresa's a bunch of
people that defected,
who Barbara Dematic was able to interview,
who wants,
they left North Korea,
but it traces their lives and
what their lives were like.
And one of the characters, and
again, I want to call it a character,
one of the people that's
in the book is named me,
ran and going to the book here,
me,
his father was a pow,
and it talks about that me,
his father never talked about being a pow,
but there's a nother fellow
pow who wrote a memoir,
and in his memoir,
and I'm going to the book here,
he said that men were housed in squalid
camps where they were not permitted to
bathe or brush their teeth.
Their hair became infested with lice.
Untreated wounds swarmed with maggots.
They were fed one meal of
rice and salt water a day
under the name construction unit of the
Interior Department knew pow camps had
been built near the mines.
Coal Mining in North Korea was not only
dirty but exceedingly dangerous since
the mines frequently
collapsed or caught fire
and that same former pow wrote,
the life of a pow was
worth less than a fly.
Every day we walked into the mines,
I shuttered with fear like a cow
walking to the slaughter house.
I never knew if I were to emerge alive.
So if you don't know
anything about anything,
the leader in North Korea at
this time post war is Kim Il Sung
and you still hear his.
His grandson now is in
charge of North Korea,
but at this time, I'm going
to the book. After the war,
Kim Il Sung made it his first order of
business to weed out fo from friend.
He started at the top with
potential rivals for leadership.
He disposed of many of his comrades
in arms who had led the struggle from
Manchuria to unseat the
Japanese Japanese occupiers.
He ordered the arrest of the founding
members of the Communist Party in South
Korea.
They had been invaluable during the war.
Now that they'd served their purpose.
They could be discarded throughout the
1950s many more were purged in what was
increasingly coming to resemble
an ancient Chinese empire.
With Kim Il Sung the
unchallenged master of the realm.
Kim Il Sung then turns his
attention to ordinary people.
In 1958 he ordered up an elaborate
project to classify all North Koreans by
their political reliability,
ambitiously seeking to reorganize
an entire human population.
The North Koreans were
methodical to a fault.
Each person was put through
eight background checks.
Your Song Bun,
as the rating was called,
took into account the backgrounds
of your parents, grandparents,
and even second cousins.
The loyalty surveys were carried out
in various phases with inspiring names.
Intensive guidance by the central
party was the first announced phase.
The classifications became more refined
in subsequent phases such as the
understanding people project
between 1972 and 1974
so those things to me,
they all sound like just bad movie
plots,
right?
The in in intensive guidance
by the central party.
Okay,
that's something you
don't want to mess with
and here's how they would be.
Here's what life was like.
A little bit of life. People would be
closely watched by their neighbors.
North Koreans are organized into
what are called in men bond,
literally people's groups,
cooperatives of 20 or so families whose
job it is to keep tabs on one another
and run the neighborhood.
The Inman bond have an elected leader,
usually a middle aged woman who reports
anything suspicious to higher ranking
authorities.
It was almost impossible for North
Korean of low rank to improve his status.
Okay,
now we talked about
this character or sorry,
the person Miron that's being talked
about and she talks about her father
and here's what she says about her.
Father.
Me Round often found her
father's passivity maddening.
Only later did she understand
this was a survival mechanism.
It was as though he had hammered down his
own personality to avoid drawing undue
attention to himself among the thousands
of former South Korean soldiers who
tried to assimilate into North
Korean society. Many slipped up me,
Ron's mother.
Later later told her that four of
her father's buddies in the mines,
fellow South Koreans had been
executed for minor infractions.
Their bodies dumped in mass graves.
Being a member of the hostel class meant
you would never get the benefit of a
doubt.
I'll sarcastic inflection when referring
to Kim Il Sung or nostalgic remark
about South Korea could
get you in serious trouble.
It was especially taboo to talk about
the Korean War and who started it in the
official histories and there was nothing
but official history in North Korea.
It was the South Korean army that invaded
acting on orders from the Americans,
not the North Korean army
storming across the 38th parallel.
Anybody who remembered what
really happened on June 25th,
1950 new,
it was wise to keep one's mouth shut.
So even history,
even facts that you learned that
the country learned or just lies
me ran, didn't have any particular
artistic or athletic talent,
but like her older sisters did. But she
was a good student and she was beautiful.
When she was 15 years old,
her school was visited by a team of
serious looking men and women in somber
suits.
These were aqua members of the fifth
division of the Central Workers' Party
recruiter recruiters who
scoured the country looking
for young women to serve on
the personal staff of Kim
Il Sung and Kim Jong Il.
If selected,
the girls would be sent off to military
style training camp before being
assigned to one of the leadership's.
Many residences around the country.
North Korean girls her age
didn't know what a concubine was.
Only that whatever you might do to serve
the leadership would be a tremendous
honor.
Only the smartest and prettiest
girls would be selected.
I think we can all imagine what that
looks like.
Twisted men in seats of power,
preying on the entire
nations for young girls.
Disturbing.
Now another character in the book,
and I'm getting,
I keep using that term character.
You hear that even me,
I'm sitting here trying to tell everyone,
hey,
remember these are people but
I'm calling them characters.
These are characters in a book.
These are people
and this person was named
Mrs Song and Mrs Song.
What's interesting about Mrs
Song is she's a true believer.
She's a true believer,
and you're going to hear some of this,
but these folks that are raised in
North Korea, they just believe that,
that they believe the propaganda.
They believe that North Korea is the best
place on earth and it everywhere else
is suffering and that because
of their great leader,
their lives are better than anyone else
in the world and she truly believes that.
And here's kind of what her attitude,
here's what her life was like.
And her attitude was like,
Mrs Song usually went to work with one
baby strapped to her back in one or two
daughters dragging along behind her.
Her children basically grew
up at the daycare center.
She was supposed to work eight hours with
a lunch break and a nap in the middle
of her shift after work.
She had to spend several more hours in
ideological training in the factories
auditorium.
One day the lecture might be about
the struggle against us imperialism.
On other time.
It might be about Kim Il songs exploits
actual or exaggerating fighting the
Japanese.
During World War II.
She had to write essays on the latest
pronouncements of the Worker's Party.
By the time she got home,
it would be 10:30 PM she would
do her housework and cooking.
Then get up before dawn to prepare
herself and her family for the day ahead
before leaving home around 7:00 AM
she seldom slept more than five hours.
Some days were harder than others.
On Wednesday mornings,
she had to report to work
early for mandatory meetings
of the Socialist Women's
Federation. Friday night she stayed
especially late for self criticism.
In these sessions,
members of her work unit,
the department to which she was assigned
would stand up and reveal to the group
anything they had done wrong.
Mrs Song would usually
say in all sincerity,
sincerity that she feared she
wasn't working hard enough.
Mrs Song believed what she said.
All those years of sleep deprivation,
all those lectures and self criticisms,
the very same tools used in brainwashing
or interrogations had wiped out any
possibility of resistance.
She had been molded into cumulus songs,
improved human beings.
Kim Il Sung,
his goal wasn't merely
to build a new country.
He wanted to build better
people to reshape human nature.
Once in power,
Kim Il Sung retooled.
The ideas developed during his time as
an anti Japanese guerilla fighter as
instruments into instruments
of social control.
He instructed North Koreans that
their power as human beings came from
subsuming. Their individual
will to that of the collective.
The collective couldn't go off Willy
Nilly doing whatever the people chose to
some democratic process.
The people had to follow an absolute
supreme leader without question.
That leader of course was Kim.
Il Sung himself.
So they're being told
through multiple channels,
through every instrument available,
newspapers,
radio, television, all
controlled by the state.
And through all these they're being
told that they have to submit their
individual will
and perform at the will of the collective.
And you know, you, you
will hear me refer to,
for me
the most important piece of humanity
is the individual individual freedom
[inaudible]
and obviously this attitude is the
opposite of individual freedom.
And also you got to remember
from a leadership perspective,
the way you maximize a team's effort isn't
through a supreme authority trying to
control everything.
It doesn't work.
That's why we have a little something
called decentralized command.
I want my front line leaders to think I
want my front line troops to understand
what they're trying to make happen and
use their free will to make it happen.
Use their own brain to make it happen.
So if you're in a leadership position
and you realize that you're trying to
control everything yourself,
you're not getting the most
effective performance from your team.
Hmm.
And we're going to see this on
a grand scale. And you know,
we do see it on a grand scale when
governments try to control humans.
It doesn't work.
Now, it might seem crazy that you
would buy into this propaganda.
And here's a, here's a paragraph
in a statement about that.
Back to the book.
We laugh at the excesses of propaganda
and the gullibility of the people,
but consider that their indoctrination
began in their infancy during 14 hour day
spent in factory daycare centers
that for the subsequent 50 years,
every song film,
newspaper,
Article and billboard was helped,
was designed to deify Kim Il Sung,
that the country was hermetically seal
to keep out anything that Mike might cast
doubt on Kim Il Sung his divinity
who could possibly resist or you're not
just being told that this guy is the
leader you being told he's God.
Mm hmm.
In 1972 on the occasion
of his 60th birthday,
a milestone in Korean culture,
the Workers' Party began distributing
lapel pins of Kim Il Sung before long.
The entire population was required to
wear them on the left breast over the
heart and Mrs Songs
home as in every other,
a framed portrait of Kim Il Sung
hung on an otherwise bare wall.
People were not permitted to
put anything else on that wall,
not even pictures of
their blood relatives.
The children were never to forget that
they owed everything to the national
leadership.
North Korean children.
They didn't celebrate their own birthdays,
but those of Kim Il Sung on April
15th and Kim Jong Il on February 16th
when the time came,
the children lined up in front of the
portraits to express their gratitude in
unison. They would bend from the
waist, bowing deeply with feeling.
Thank you, dear Father Kim. Il Sung,
the children repeated has their
mother looked on with satisfaction,
televisions and radios and North Korea
are preset so they can receive only
official government channels.
Still the programming was relatively
entertaining besides the usual speeches of
Kim Il Sung on a typical weeknight,
you might have sports concerts,
television dramas and
movies produced by Kim Il,
Kim Jong Ils film studio.
On weekends you might get a
Russian movie as a special treat.
The newspapers would occasionally run
feature stories about heroic children who
ratted out their parents to
be denounced by a neighbor.
For bowed mapping the regime
was nothing extra ordinary.
Starting to get a little feeling
for what we've got going on here.
Now,
what happens when the government tries
to control everything and you take the
the freedom of the people away?
Communism,
obviously,
and
things are not as
productive as they could be.
That's what happens when there's
no individual drive to succeed.
Because if you're a farmer,
once you plant your food,
it's just going to get taken away
by the government and redistributed.
So what's your, what's your drive to grow
the right amount of food or more food?
There is none because it's all just
going to be taken away anyways.
They avoid punishment. So
they do the minimum. Yes.
Rather than the opposite.
When they strive for the maximum,
that means they're focused on what can
be, you know? Yes. Avoiding what can be.
Yes.
And so now this is again,
I'm breezing through chunks of this
book to get to some of the highlights.
So now we're into the 80s and
we're starting to run out of food.
Kim Jong Il,
who by the 1980s was increasingly,
it's assuming his father's duties
offered on the spot guidance to,
to address the country's woes.
Father and son were experts
in absolutely everything.
Be at geology or farming.
Kim Jong Il onsite
instructions and is warm.
Benevolence are bringing out the,
bringing about a great advancing goat
breeding and output of dairy products.
The Korean Central News Agency opined
after Kim Jong Il visited a goat farm near
Chung Gyn. So that's the kind of, that's
the kind of headlines in the news.
Okay.
One day he would decree that the country's
had switched from rice to potatoes
for staple food.
The next you would decide that raising
ostriches was the cure for North Korea is
food certed shortage,
the country lurched from one
harebrained scheme to another.
So w the fact of the matter is that
even if this guy was a brilliant or is a
brilliant farmer,
he's not taking into account the various
terrain and the different climates that
are in the area and who can get what done.
Whereas if you let the free market decide
what can be grown and let individuals
decide and let freedom
and guide people things, work things,
find a way,
the control does not work.
Okay?
And you'll see that here.
Back to the book soon the country was
sucked into a vicious death spiral without
cheap fuel,
oil and raw material.
It couldn't keep the factories running,
which meant it had nothing
to export with no exports.
There was no hard currency
and without hard currency,
fuel imports fell even further
and the electricity stopped.
The coal mines couldn't operate without
electricity because they required
electric pumps to safe and water.
The shortage of coal worsened
the electricity shortage,
the electricity shortage further
lowered agricultural output.
Even the collective farms couldn't
operate properly without electricity.
It had never been easy to eek out enough
harvest from North Korea's hardscrabble
terrain for a population of 23 million
and the agricultural techniques developed
to boost the outport,
relied on electrically powered artificial
irrigation and on chemical fertilizers
and pesticides produced it.
Factories that were now closed for
lack of fuel and raw materials.
North Korea started running out
of food and as people went hungry,
they didn't have the energy to
work and so output plunged further.
The economy was in a free fall.
North Korea was the last place on place
on earth where virtually all staples are
grown on collective farms.
The state confiscates the entire harvest
and then gives a portion back to the
farmer.
But as harvest withered in the early
1990s the farmers themselves were going
hungry and began stashing
some of the harvest away.
There were stories from the countryside
of roofs that collapsed under the weight
of grain hidden away in the eaves.
The farmers also neglected the collective
fields for their private kitchen
gardens next to their
houses or small steep plots.
The carved out of the side of uncultivated
mountain slopes driving through the
countryside.
You could see clearly the contrast
between private gardens bursting with
vegetables being pulled,
soaring skyward,
vines drooping with Pumpkin's next to the
collective fields with they're stunted
stunted haphazard rows of corn that had
been planted by so called volunteers
doing their patriotic duty.
Case in point.
Koreans like to think to themselves
as tough. And so they are.
The propaganda machine launched a new
campaign playing up Korean pride by
recalling a fable from 1938 to 1939 in
which Kim Il Sung commanded a small band
of Anti-japanese gorillas fighting
against thousands of enemies in 20 degrees
below zero breathing through a
heavy snowfall and starvation.
The red flag fluttering
in front of the rank,
the arduous march,
as they called it,
would later become a
metaphor for the famine.
And here's a,
one of the statements that they would
make no force on Earth can borrow the
Korean people from making an onward
march for victory and the revolutionary
spirit of the arduous march
and the d p d p r a k will
always remain a powerful nation.
Democratic People's Republic of Korea.
So people are starving
and the government is saying, yeah, we're
going to drive on. It's a tough road,
but we're going to make it
enduring. Hungary became part,
one's patriotic duty.
Billboards went up in Pyongyang,
touting the new slogan,
let's eat two meals a day.
North Korean television ran a documentary
about a man who stomach burst.
It was claimed from eating too much rice.
In any case, the food shortage
was temporary. Agriculture.
Agricultural officials quoted in the
newspapers reported that bumper crops of
rice were expected in the next harvest.
When the foreign press reported on food
shortages in north in the north in 1992
the North Korean news service
was indignant and here's
what the new North Korean
new service had to say.
The state supplies the people with food
at a cheap price so that the people do
not know how much rice costs.
This is the reality of the
northern half of Korea.
All people live a happy life
without any worries about food.
In our land,
people are starving in
the government is lying.
If North Koreans pause to contemplate
the obvious inconsistencies and lies in
what they were told, they would find
themselves in a dangerous place.
They didn't have a choice.
They couldn't flee their country,
depose of their leadership,
speak out or protest.
In order to fit in.
The average citizen had to discipline
himself not to think too much.
Then there was the natural human survival
instinct to be optimistic like German
Jews in the early 1930s who told
themselves that couldn't get any worse.
The North Koreans deceive themselves.
They thought it was temporary.
Things would get better.
A hungry stomach shouldn't believe a lie,
but somehow it did.
Along with the new propaganda campaign,
the regime stepped up its extensive
network of domestic surveillance.
The more there was to complain about,
the more important it was
to ensure that nobody did.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now at this point,
further in the book,
Miran has gone off to college to
become a teacher and she shows up there
and this is what she deals with.
The food in the cafeteria was even worse.
North Korea was starting.
It's let's eat two meals a day campaign,
but the school took it a step
further and offered only one meal.
A fin soup made of salt water
and dried turnip leaves.
The cafeteria would,
would sometimes add a spoon of rice and
that had been cooked for hours to plump
up the grains.
The girls in college began getting sick.
One of me,
Rand's roommates was so malnourished that
the skin was flaking off of her face.
She dropped out of school
and others followed.
Now,
during the,
during the middle of this,
Kim Il Sung dies and you know,
it's, um, it's crazy to
hear how the people reacted.
And so I'm going to start off with
this announcement that was made
and I, this is long, a little
bit of a long announcement,
but just to get the tone of
it is worth it. Here we go.
The central committee of
the Worker's Party of Korea,
the Central Military Commission of the
Party, the National Defense Commission,
the Central People's Committee and the
Administration Council of the Democratic
People's Republic of Korea report to
the entire people of the country with
deepest grief that the great leader,
Comrade Kim Il Sung general secretary
of the Central Committee of the Worker's
Party
of Korea and president of the
Democratic People's Republic of Korea,
passed away from a sudden attack of
illness at 2:00 AM are respected fatherly
leader who has devoted his whole
life to the popular masses because of
independence and engaged himself in
tireless an energetic activities for the
prosperity of the motherland and
the happiness of the people for the
reunification of the country
and independence of the
world till the last moments
of his life departed from
us to our greatest sorrow.
Very disturbing.
And what's crazy is you hear
all these bureaucratic names.
That's what's crazy about it.
All of these government organizations
picking away at the people.
And here's some of the reactions.
The morning that went through
and and people like Mrs Song,
who is a true believer, this is
how they felt the old women wailed.
How could you leave us?
So suddenly the men's screamed.
Those waiting in line would jump up and
down pound their heads collapsed into
theatrical swoons, rip their clothes
and pound their fists at the air.
In few tile rage,
the men wept copiously as the women.
The histrionics of grief took on a
competitive quality who could weep the
loudest,
who was most distraught?
The mourners were Egged on by the TV news,
which broadcast hours and hours of people
wailing grown men with tears rolling
down their cheeks,
banging their heads on trees,
sailors banging their heads
against the massive, there's ships,
pilots weeping in the cockpit and so on.
These scenes were interspersed with
footage of lightning and pouring rain.
It looked like Armageddon.
Our country is envelops in the deepest
sorrow in the 5,000 year history of the
Korean nation.
Intoned in an announcer on television
and they had these little miss that they
throw out there like this one. Here's a,
here's an official release.
When the Great Marshall died,
thousands of cranes descended
from heaven [inaudible] fetch him.
The birds couldn't take him because
they saw that North Koreans cried and
screamed and pummeled their chests,
pulled their hair and pounded the ground.
They couldn't let him go,
but nonetheless,
despite the heroic efforts
of the Grand Marshal,
okay,
the famine continued
and here we go to another
person in the book
whose name is Dr. Kim,
a woman doctor in North
Korea in the pediatric ward.
Dr. Kim noticed that her patients
were exhibiting peculiar symptoms.
The children she treated born in
the late 1980s and early 1990s were
surprisingly smaller,
even smaller than she'd been
as the tiniest kid in her
elementary school class.
Now their upper arms were so skinny,
she couldn't circle them with
her thumb and forefingers.
Their muscle tone was a week.
It was a syndrome known as wasting where
the starved body eats away at its own
muscle tissue.
Children came in for
constipation that was so acute.
They were doubled over in pain,
screaming.
The problem was with the food housewives.
It started to pick weeds and wild grasses
to add to their soups to create an
illusion of vegetables.
Corn was increasingly the
staple again instead of,
but people were adding leaves,
husks stems and carbs
to make it go further.
That was okay for adults, but it
couldn't be digested by the tenders.
Stomachs of children,
the babies were in the worst shapes.
Their mothers themselves under nourished
didn't produce enough breast milk for
them.
Baby formula was nonexistent
and milk was rare
in the past.
Mothers who couldn't produce enough
breast milk would feed their babies a
watered down Kong he made
have made from cooked rice,
but now most of them
couldn't afford rice either.
And here's Dr. Kim talking
about the toddlers.
They would look at me with accusing eyes.
Even four year olds knew they were dying
and that I wasn't doing anything to
help them.
Dr. Kim told me years later,
all I was capable of doing was to cry
with their mothers and their bodies
afterwards.
Dr. Kim hadn't been a Dr.
Long enough to have a record,
the protective wall that would insulate
her from the suffering around her.
The children's pain was her pain
years later when I asked
her if she remembered any
of the children who had died
on her watch,
she answered sharply.
I remember all of them
now, me ran, has graduated from college
and she's an actual school teacher.
Dan Actually requirement of school
teachers was that they knew would need to
know how to play the accordion,
which is like a transportable instruments.
So therefore was considered to be a good
thing because you could carry it on a
march. So all school teachers had
to play the accordion. Today's,
they sang songs like this
and they would sing it with the class.
Our Father,
we have nothing to envy in the world.
Our houses within the embrace
of the Worker's Party,
we are all brothers and sisters.
Even if a sea of fire comes towards us,
sweet children do not need to be afraid.
Our Father is here.
We have nothing to envy in this world.
Another one of the songs that they'd sing.
Where have we gone?
We've gone to the forest. Where are
we going? We're going over the hills.
What are we going to do?
We are going to kill Japanese soldiers.
And another classic that was taught in
the music classes called shoot the Yankee
bastards.
Our enemies are the American bastards
who are trying to take over our beautiful
fatherland with guns that
I make with my own hands.
I will shoot them, Bang, Bang, Bang.
That idea of nothing to envy
in the world and, and again,
you know,
as you read through this book,
you hear the people saying that
they believed whole heartedly,
that they had nothing
to envy in the world,
that this dismal life of starvation or
near starvation was as good as it gets.
Then here's what the hunger would look
like in school. According to me ran,
each child was supposed to bring from
home a bundle of firewood for the furnace
in the school basement,
but many had trouble carrying it
there. Big heads load on top of scrawny
necks. They're delicate rib cages,
protruded over their waste so small that
she could encircle them with our hands.
Some of them were starting
to swell in the stomach.
It was all becoming clear to her.
Miran remember seeing a photograph
of a famine victim in Somalia with a
protruding stomach, although she
didn't know the medical terminology.
She remembered from our teachers,
teachers college course on nutrition
that it was caused by severe protein
deficiency.
Me Ran also noticed that the children's
black hair was getting lighter,
more copper toned.
It was always the same progression.
First,
the family wouldn't be able
to send the quote of firewood.
Then the lunch bag would disappear.
Then the child would stop participating
in class and would sleep through recess.
Then without explanation,
the child would stop coming
to school over three years.
Enrollment in the kindergarten
drop from 50 students to 15
what happened to all those children?
Yeah.
Miran didn't pry too deeply for fear.
The answer she didn't want to hear
a decade later when we ran was a mother
herself trying to lose or pros pregnancy
weight through aerobics.
This period of her life waited
like a stone on her conscience.
She often felt sick over what she did
and didn't do to help the young students.
How could she have eaten so well
herself when they were starving
is axiomatic that one death is a tragedy.
1,000 a statistic.
So it was from me ran.
What she didn't realize is that in her
is that her in difference was an acquired
survival skill in order to get through
the 1990s alive one to suppress any
impulse to share food.
Yeah,
to avoid going insane one,
how to learn to stop caring in time.
Miran would learn how to walk around a
dead body on the street without paying
much attention.
She could pass a five year old on the
verge of death without feeling a feeling
obliged to help.
If she wasn't going to share
food with her favorite pupil,
she certainly wasn't going
to help a perfect stranger.
And here's some,
I guess I would say thoughts on
a famine or realities of famine
in a famine.
People don't necessarily starved to death.
Often.
Some other ailment gets them first.
Chronic malnutrition impairs the body's
ability to battle infection and the
Hungary become increasingly susceptible
to tuberculosis, tuberculosis,
and typhoid.
The starved body is too weak to metabolize
antibiotics even if they're available
and normal.
Normally curable.
Does illnesses suddenly become fatal?
Wild fluctuations of body chemistry
can trigger strokes and heart attacks.
People die from eating substitute
foods that their bodies can't digest.
Starvation can be a sneaky killer that
disguises itself under blend statistics
of increased child mortality
or decreased life expectancy.
It leaves behind only circumstantial
evidence of excess morality.
There's excess mortality statistics that
show a higher than normal desk during a
certain period.
Yeah.
Yet another gratuitous cruelty.
The killer famine targets
the most innocent.
The people who would never
steal food, lie, cheat,
break the law or betray a friend.
It was a phenomenon that the
Italian writer, Primo Levi,
identified after emerging from Auschwitz
when he wrote that he and his fellow
survivors never wanted
to see another one again,
one another again after the war because
they had all done something of which
they were ashamed
as Mrs Song would observe a decade later
when she thought back on all the people
she knew who died during those years,
it was the simple and kindhearted people
who did what they were told they were
the first to die.
Yeah,
yeah.
By 1998 an estimated 600,000 to 2 million
North Koreans had died as a result of
the famine.
As much as 10% of the population.
By the end of 1998 the worst
of the famine was over,
not necessarily because
anything had improved,
but as mrs song later surmised,
because there were fewer mouths to feed,
everybody who was going
to die was already dead.
Now.
That's how the famine wrapped up.
But to go a little bit in depth of what
it was like once the famine was raging,
people became homeless,
which was strange because in North
Korea they never had a problem with
homelessness because if you wanted food,
you needed to live in your home because
if the government would allegedly bring
you food, well once they
won't bring in food anymore,
there was no reason to stay at home.
So now you had people going
out trying to survive. Right.
And this talks a little bit about that,
especially for the children.
It was a dangerous life.
The children couldn't sleep
without worrying that somebody,
perhaps another gang member
would steal what little they had.
There were strange stories going around
about adults who preyed on children,
not just for sex but for food.
High ACC was told about people who had
drug children kill them and butcher them
from meat.
Behind the station near the railroad
tracks were vendors who cooked up soup and
noodles over small burners and it was
said that the great chunks of meat
floating in the broth or human flesh.
The stories got more and more horrific.
Supposedly one father went so insane
with hunger that he ate his own baby.
A market woman were said to have been
arrested for selling soup made from human
bones.
From my interviews with the defectors,
it does appear that there were cases in
which people were arrested and executed
for cannibalism.
What did our wonderful,
uh,
leaders do during this?
Here's how they handled the people as
the people who started black markets and
started growing these gardens and
selling what they could to get, you know,
people started to try and survive
through exercising
their personal freedoms.
And here's one of the ways that are,
here's their comments about this.
This is coming from Kim Jong,
Il as well as any of
the world's strong men.
He understood perfectly the cliche that
an absolute just regime needs absolute
power.
Everything good in life was to
be bequeathed by the government.
He couldn't tolerate people going off
to gather their own food or buying rice
with their own money.
Telling people to solve the food problem
on their own only increases the number
of farmers, markets and
peddlers. In addition,
this creates egoism among the people and
the base of the party's class may come
to collapse.
So He's trying to stop people.
Yeah,
from solving the problems themselves,
which they have the capability to do,
and I don't talk about it too deeply near,
but they'd go into the,
the massive black market that was
started and there was people that were
surviving,
were people that were doing that,
that we're figuring out
a way to make money.
And Kim Jong Il retaliated against that
free market excessively to try and stop
it.
It was better that people die of
starvation than they have the freedom
to try and let their get
their family to survive.
And here's an example of what they
did with one man that was trying to
get money so his family could survive.
Back to the book,
the man was accused of climbing electric
poles and cutting copper wire to sell
the theft caused extensive damage to the
nation's property and was done with the
intention to damage our social system.
It was an act of treason that aided
the enemies of the socialist state.
The prosecutor read his voice bellowing
through the scratchy speakers than a man
acting as a sort of lawyer
for the accused spoke.
Although he offered no defense.
I have determined that what
the prosecutor says is true.
The accused is the hereby sentence to
death and the sentence will be carried out
immediately.
Decreed a third man,
the condemned man was bound
to a wooden stake at the eyes,
the chest and the legs.
The firing squad would aim to sever the
ropes in order three bullets in each
location. Nine in total, top to bottom.
First,
the lifeless head would slump over so
that the body would crumble in an orderly
heap at the foot of the steak.
Neat and efficient.
It would look like the condemned
man was bowing in death,
as if to apologize.
A murmur went through the crowd who
thought the execution was excessive
punishment for a minor theft,
the electric lines or
weren't working anyways,
the few meters of copper
wiring the man had stolen,
probably had gotten him no
more than a few bags of rice.
A pity he has a younger sister.
Somebody said,
two sisters set another.
The man's parents must be dead.
Clearly he knew nobody with
influence to intervene on his behalf.
You probably had a poor
class background as well.
Maybe he was the son of a miner.
The shots rang out
head, chest, legs,
the head
burst open like a water balloon,
blood spurted out over the dirt,
almost spilling onto
the feet of the crowd.
Now
what do people do to stop this?
You know,
and you have rebellion in the world.
You have people turn against
the government in the world.
But in North Korea that did not happen.
And here's why.
The level of repression in North Korea
was so great that no organized resistance
could take root.
Any anti regime activity would have,
would have terrible
consequences for the protester,
his immediate family and all other known
relatives under a system that sought to
stamp out tainted blood
for three generations.
The punishment would extend to
parents, grandparents, brothers,
sisters, nieces, nephews and cousins.
A lot of people felt if
you had to give one life,
you would give it to get
rid of this terrible regime.
But here you are not the
only one getting punished.
Your whole family would go through hell.
So with the fact that they're
going to give you protest,
they're going to kill everybody.
So there was no protest.
So now the only thing you
can possibly think of doing
okay
is escaping.
And it goes through the various people
in the book and how they escaped.
But I thought what was interesting,
in fact the most interesting
sort of mental transition
to make was for Mrs Song.
And again she was referred to as the true
believer and her daughter had escaped
and made it actually to South Korea
and her daughter arranged to have Mrs Song
Visit China,
but she visited China sort of against
the rules thinking that she was going to
go back to North Korea.
Yeah,
because she truly believed that
North Korea was the better place.
She believed that South Korea
was the enemy. Indie was evil.
And so she spends,
but she does go to China and she spent
some time in China and when she's in
China,
she staying in the House that you know,
her daughter set up for her to stay in
and they have TV and they have microwave
oven and they have dishwasher
and they have a rice cooker,
which, which like is miraculous to
her. I mean she's talking about it,
she's saying at a certain time the light
would come on and it would make a chirp
and that means the rice was now being
cooked. And by the way, at this time,
they didn't have rice in North Korea.
So there's this thing that
just automatically cooks up
your rice in the morning.
And it was that combination
of things that broker,
because when she first saw that stuff,
she said, oh, this is imperialistic.
You know, this is capitalism. It's evil.
They're trying to buy us and
enslave us with their capitalism.
That's what she'd been
convinced her whole life.
Hmm.
And then she has the realization
bad at Madden would close with this
because after this it goes through the
stories of how they escaped and whatnot.
But this realization,
this moment in time when
our mind becomes free
and here's, here's how it
goes, how much they all,
how much had they all missed herself?
Her daughter's locked away in North
Korea working themselves to death
for what
we will do,
what the party tells us,
we will die for the general,
we have nothing to envy.
She had believed it all
than wasted her life
or maybe not.
Yeah.
Was it really over?
She was 57 years old,
still in good health.
This was her wake up call.
She was ready to go.
So I ask,
yeah,
what is your wake call?
Yeah.
What is in sleeving you?
What is controlling your thoughts?
Okay.
Is it the television set feeding your
mind images of what life should be?
Is it the Internet drawing you
in and controlling your time?
Is it drugs or alcohol numbing your brain
and diminishing your desires?
Or is it weakness,
a lack of discipline that prevents you
from accomplishing what you want to
accomplish?
And I'm not saying that you have to rebel.
I'm not saying that there aren't
things in life that we just have to do.
There are.
But what I am saying is ask questions.
Don't believe everything that you're told
and don't follow the path just because
it's there.
Don't get in line just
because other people are.
Get up
and wake up and be conscious of
what is creeping into your mind.
What's getting in there?
What are you letting in there?
What is forcing itself in there
and what does it want you to do?
You have only one life.
So don't waste it
being controlled
by someone else.
That's one of the things that's um,
it's everywhere.
Like you can easily be controlled
by stuff. Like I'm a big one is,
I hate it. I hate to harp on
parents, but like your parents,
so nobody's perfect,
right?
So all your imperfections or a lot of
your imperfections will be passed onto
your kids just because
you don't know any better.
Like that Mrs Song Lady like she just
believed it. She didn't know any better.
And so you can end up passing these
things down like certain traditions or um,
you know,
just methodologies of raising kids
that you might hear otherwise.
But that's your thing.
You know that you believed it it
in your mind because your parents,
their parents,
you know,
and you don't like how you say ask
questions and you don't ask questions,
you're just like, hey, that's
how I was raised. You pass it on.
Meanwhile you're doing the
wrong thing the whole time.
That's what happens when
you don't ask questions.
That's what happens when you
don't ask questions. You know,
that's what happens when you believe
authority all the time. Yeah.
And Hey, this might come across as
some people are sitting there saying,
wait a second, Jocko worn shoe in the
military for 20 years. You're damn right.
I was,
yeah.
And there was a definitely,
I was a rebellious kid and when I was
in the military I was always questioned
everything that we did and why we did it.
So,
and I think that's one of the things that
helped me get to a leadership position
and become a,
a decent leader was the fact that I didn't
just take everyone's word for it and
say, Oh yeah, that's what we're going to
do. Okay. All right. No, you know what?
We're actually going to
change the strategy. We're
going to change the tactics.
What why was taught isn't working right
now. We're going to do it differently.
Yeah. They did that all the time.
Yeah. But this is a broader scale.
This is a broader scale. This
is life, not just in the book,
but life in general.
Life in general.
Like what are you doing?
Where are you getting your
direction from? Yeah. Who is,
who's got a hold of your
steering wheel. Yeah. Yeah.
And make sure it's you that's got
a hold of your steering wheel.
Yeah.
And that's one of the things where it's
tough because you've got to balance it
as well. You know, so if you're
just rolling around saying, hey,
nothing's true until I figure it
out, it's Kinda like, you know,
you've got to consider the opportunity
cost where some people you got it,
you know,
you got to consider their credibility
and then you got to kind of just go with
it.
And again,
this is just kind of demonstrating
like there's a balance there,
but just like are you're
saying if something,
if it's not working and someone
presents you with some alternative,
don't just be like, Hey, I've
done it this way, so, you know,
leave me alone type of thing. You know,
ask those questions and listen to them.
You know,
chances are you might find
a little improved method
and doing some stuff. Yeah.
Or you might find out that you've
been sucked into a trap, you know,
do you don't want to be in,
no, you got to free your mind.
You got to free your mind. You got to get
out of that box, out of that cage. Yeah.
Think of that. You know,
I meet people now and
it's so bizarre because,
because I've traveled a lot and I've,
and I've walked with a lot of different
kinds of people, you know, oh,
from all different walks of life.
And I meet people sometimes
and I think to myself, man,
this guy is pretty awesome.
He's got all this, you know,
I wonder what this person's goal is.
And sometimes I'll ask like, you know,
what do you want to do? Or
like, what are you, hey,
how meet some kid or what you want to do.
And some people say,
you know, well, I want to do,
you know, I, I think they're,
I think they're going to come
out with this giant dream
and they come out with like a
little mediocre idea.
And I,
and I won it and I,
I haven't done this yet.
I've talked to five people in the last
six months that I thought were going to
tell me about their dream and that I
was going to be like in shock and I was
going to be impressed and say, yeah,
that's what I'm talking about, brother.
Go get it.
And instead I had to bite my tongue
because they were telling me their dream,
but it wasn't big enough. It
wasn't big enough. It wasn't.
It was too realistic. You know, you now,
you meet some people sometimes and
they tell me their dream and I go, man,
you ain't got a chance at that. You
need to, you need to tone that down.
You need to get a grip. Right.
These people that are like,
you can achieve anything you want.
No,
actually you can't
achieve anything you want.
If you could achieve anything you want,
you know,
everyone would be sitting on a yacht
or doing whatever big badass thing that
they want to do. Kind of depends on what
you mean by can't though. But yeah. Yeah,
it's true. I mean can't,
that's what I mean.
These guys, these people that are
like, you can do whatever you want. No,
actually there's limitations to that.
All people are not created equal.
Some people are smarter than other people.
Some people are better athletes
than other people. Hey,
reality.
Now what can you hear the question?
Isn't that the question is
what can you do with your,
with what you've got,
what can you do?
And I'd much rather,
I love to hear people overshooting,
but don't trap yourself in a
box where you're like, well,
I'll be happy if I can do
this. Right. And there's whole,
the other part of this is,
it's sorta like North Korea.
There's people that are trapped in a
paradigm in their head of the world.
They think that the world is,
this is this thing that they live in.
They think that the world is this small,
this small place that the
people that they know, right?
And the,
the atmosphere that they live inside.
And it's really,
really small.
And I think to myself,
man, you gots to get out.
And I'll tell you,
part of this came when I got out of the
military because my whole life, you know,
the only guys I knew were seals.
So I mean that's just who I knew.
And so when I got out and
I started meeting other
people and especially started
working with big businesses,
started meeting really
not just successful in terms of financial
people but people that had really done
something [inaudible] and I started
realizing that there was a whole nother
level that, not a, not a higher level
but there's just another world. Yeah,
like in the seal teams.
Oh well you know a, I did,
I did my seal platoon to silk Tim
commander, you know you do these certain,
I did task unit commander,
you do these things and that's what you
do and it's awesome and that's a whole
world. But there's other worlds.
And I remember telling him,
one of my seal buddies,
we were out surfing and this is after
I'd been out for like two years.
I had this exact conversation
with them. I said, hey man,
like we were taught,
we were out there surfing for an hour and
for 58 minutes we're talking about the
seal teams, the seal teams, the seal
teams, the seal teams in the seal teams.
And then I w I said, hey man,
the seal teams is awesome.
But just so you know,
there's other things in the world and
it's stuff that I'm saying my mind was in
North Korea, my mind was just
seal team, you know, and I,
and I'll tell you what I'm glad it was
because it made my life very simple and I
still, you know, obviously I love
the seal teams more than anything,
but there are other worlds out there and
you can do other things in the world.
And so now when I meet people in different
environments and different jobs and
each little,
each little environment
that I poke my head into,
cause we work in different industries
all over different, you know,
manufacturing and gas,
oil and,
and financial and they're
all their own little worlds.
And sometimes people are trapped in those
worlds. And I just want to say, man,
free your mind, free your mind
and see what else is out there.
Yeah.
Kinda like what you and Tim,
Tim Kennedy were talking
about how you guys,
you guys are an example of
people who have seen the really,
really bad parts of the world and the
really, really good parts of the world.
Cause you guys travel all over and you
live in San Diego, which is, you know,
arguably one of the,
one of the best places to live.
So you have that expanded
view. Meanwhile, some people,
they only go on vacation when they travel,
so they have,
although a real positive
and really nice view,
but it's really narrow or other
people who only lived in bad places,
just like people who grew up
in a real negative household.
When they go out into the world,
just their beginning view
of the world is negative.
Like money's just so hard to come
by because be when they grew up,
their parents are complaining about the
rent and bills are piling up and all
this stuff. So that's their
attitude when they go out and then,
then that's how they kind
of take on the world. Man,
I know this and this kind of a different
thing. Same, same content, same subject,
but, um, I had a friend in,
in high school in this people,
I grew up in quite a
small island in Hawaii,
so some people straight up have their
whole life having been off of choir in no
less than mainland.
The mainland is this fantasy world place
with where Disneyland is and Hollywood
and all this stuff. So I had a
friend, one of my good friends,
he moved to the mainland, but it was
just this small, teeny tiny town,
just as small as coy. So I remember one
time what state was the down in Colorado?
Colorado is he moved to Pueblo,
it's called.
So I remember we were just
having a conversation later
and I was like, Hey, yeah,
let's, let's go to Las Vegas. A lot
of white people go to Las Vegas.
And I was like, let's go to Las Vegas
or whatever. I was like, when do you do,
what do you do you rent a car? He was
like, I would never drive in Las Vegas.
I would never drive in Las Vegas
because it's too crazy. You know,
there's freeways, there's
no freeway on quiet on who
there, there's a highway, but,
and he, a grown adult, so to speak,
um, can't even dry, you know? So that's
like an example of that's how narrow his,
his whole view was world,
his whole world.
And I'm that extended to
his driving skill. You know,
this was just so hectic on a
freeway highway Las Vegas even,
I don't even know how crazy that is.
I mean,
that's not a crazy place to drive really.
You know, compared to like, I don't know,
whatever.
Yeah.
So to La man hit the 405
north on a Thursday afternoon.
Yeah.
There's no doubt.
There's so much out there and if
you stay comfortable in your world,
you can get used to, you can get
comfortable starving in North Korea.
That's what the scary thing is.
That's the point that I think I'm trying
to make is don't be comfortable because
what you think is awesome right now,
there could be so much more.
You know,
if you can envision and pay attention
to what's going on in the rest of the
world and break out of that paradigm
that you're in and see that you can fly,
you can fly around the world,
you can do it.
Yeah. Just don't get trapped
and for your mind. Yeah.
All right,
let's get to some questions
from the interwebs in webs.
Speaking to Inter webs. If you
like supplements, good supplements,
which I think we both recommend,
right?
As far as supplements go get on it.
Supplements and the,
and we are uh,
sponsored as it so happens by on it.
But I would say get on its supplements
anyway cause I was taking them even
before we were sponsored by on it
on it.com/jocko and get 10% off.
Get your Krill oil supplements.
Get Your Alpha brainy.
Yeah.
Krill oil and Krill oil is anything
for your joints is critical.
Cause like when you, even even when
I was young, when you lift hard,
when you get after it working out.
Um,
so okay, so if you gain strength, right,
which of course we all kind
of want to do or whatever, um,
you don't have to put a
whatever on the end of the day.
We just all want to just period
generally best not to speak for everyone,
but I think it's safe to assume that yes,
we're getting straight straight.
But when you have a higher
capacity for strength,
a lot of times your muscles will
just want to fire real heart.
So what that can end up with is
this weird stiffness, you know,
so you're going to end like,
it's like you got to,
it's almost like you've got a warm up
in life. It's almost like that feeling,
you know, so it's like,
yeah, you're strong,
you're about to carry like the whole
bloat of groceries in and you can do that.
It may be,
you know,
you grown a grocery you to come up with
song saying everyday stuff and you can,
you can get after doing that. But
you kind of got a warm up, you know,
it's kind of like eh could have anyway,
groceries, you have a lot man. Hey Man,
get after in the store, out
of the store. So anyway,
so the point being like when you have
stuff like for your joints or you don't
take care of your joints, see I would
have told this totally differently.
I like if you want to Jack big steel,
you want to do Jujitsu,
you want to jump off things,
you want to throw stuff around,
get some krill oil so you stay healthy.
Yeah. Talking about groceries. No,
but I'm saying though it's, it's,
it is, it seems counter productive.
Cause I've experienced, experienced
this where I'm like, yeah,
but then I kinda gotta like
do twists. You know, Dan,
I'm strong, you know, it's kind of cold
out. And then I'd go to live, I'm like,
Dang,
I can lift a lot of weights.
But why on this first set I can't even
lift anything. You just need to Krill oil.
I'm just saying your joints gotta be like,
good to go.
That was a long explanation, right? It's
absolutely true. I'm telling you, if,
if you take it, you take that to
heart. Well you already take Krill oil,
so you're the man anyway.
Yeah on it.com/jocko get 10% off.
You'll be happy you did.
And if you want to support this
podcast before you shop at Amazon,
go to Jocko podcast.com
or a chocolate store.com.
Click on the Amazon link on the top.
And um,
it gives us a percentage and you
know, you don't pay nothing. Um,
people have been a few people
mentioned that like the, the,
the link doesn't work or whatever.
And I found out through one of the,
the true pursuer in the know,
sometimes you have ad blockers on
your browser and they're activated,
which is a good thing by the way.
It's, it's good to, you know,
cause sometimes they can air can get
it back anyway. Yeah. Because it's,
it's an actual code and it
works in, in, in the same ways.
Don't tell those small stuff
to me. Yeah. Anyway, so
deactivate it. If, um, you know,
you want to get past it, there it is.
Or if you want to buy some shirts,
which uncle was hit and or
name on it, go Jocko, store.com
that's it's cool way to represent
anyway. Yep, there it is. Alright,
let's get it first question. Any
questions? Okay. First question,
how do you continue to train
Jujitsu when hurt or injured being?
Same thing with whatever kind of interact.
Got In whatever I'm going to do,
I'm going to do what I can. You know?
Now one thing you do have to do what?
You have to let yourself rest enough
that you can heal because sometimes they
get the sprained ankle and instead of
lasting one month, it lasts 18 months.
No kidding. If you push, if
you just won't let it heal,
that thing is not going to heal.
So you have to let things heels now,
but you can go through
all kinds of positions.
You can work different transitions,
but sometimes you get an injury
and if you're a Jujitsu person,
you know what I'm talking about?
Like you get a weird injury that you can't
do certain movements. Yeah, like guy,
I'll have a hurt back, can't get
on top. I can't be on top, I can't.
So you just practice your guard or
you have a hurt, you know, groin,
muscle. So you can't hold any guard.
You have to work like side control only.
Okay, cool. Let's keep side
control or be inside control.
So you can definitely do those things.
You just figure out what
movements you can do.
You figure out what training partners
aren't going to go psychopathic on you and
dis hurt you even worse. So
that's important. You know,
just being in class and you're learning
some new technique. You know, I find if,
if I cannot roll when I'm in class,
I'll like pay a little bit more attention
to what the instruction is being given
because I know I can't roll.
So I know all I'm going to get out of
this is what I'm going to learn right here
from Jeff,
he Glover or dean list.
And so I will be like paying extra special
attention. Yeah, yeah. That's good.
And uh, then I'll tell you,
this is something like,
I wear knee pads when our role and I
think that they prevent some injuries from
happening.
And I just made a transition in my life
where I used to wear extra large pads,
knee pads, the neoprene,
neoprene, kneepads like neoprene.
There was raised braces though.
Nothing bracing in there,
just like a piece of neoprene.
Yeah. But I recently like uh,
two weeks ago I went,
I used to wear extra large,
then I went to large cause they felt a
little bit snugger and I just got medium
and I got some pretty big legs.
And then I got medium in there,
like really compressing my knees and
keeping it all together and they feel
really good.
So maybe just order that exercise down to
little compression. And the same thing,
like when I've heard elbow,
I'll put an elbow pad on. Uh,
so wrap up whatever you can
and just keep training and
warm up a little bit. Yeah.
You know, I didn't use to,
I do now I'll do a like a five minute
round where I'm not trying to kill the
person. I'm hoping that the person's
not going to try and kill me.
Although you and I had a
little incident the other day,
we get a little excited
in that first round.
Yes. Just to clarify, when you say
knee pads, elbow pads, they're not,
not like the kind soccer,
you know,
they're neoprene through [inaudible]
got wet suit, like a neoprene seat.
Aesics yeah. Gotcha. Yeah. Clif Keane
wrestling kneepads that's what they are.
That's what they're calling. And they're
generally made a neoprene. Gotcha. Yeah.
So a lot of this,
the trading partner thing,
that's a big deal if you choose to
train when you're injured. Because man,
I can't sit here and say train when
you're injured. And I might even say,
don't train, just learn. Like,
how are you saying if you want to show
up because you actually got placed it,
man. Yeah. You know, you
can't just not show up on the
mats and you know the maths,
even if you're not rolling, it's
like it's, that's a good place to be.
Let's face it for most of us.
Um,
and you sit in on a class or,
or just do the instruction
part of it and you know,
and do the movements cause you're not
going full speed, you're not rolling.
Do the movements that you can and
you can pick up a lot man. In fact,
when you especially know how you say you
were learning from Dean Jeff and most
of the instructors here,
they're really good.
Even if you learn one little detail and
even if you know, I know this guard pass,
you know,
he edited that one little detailed Dang,
I've been training for all these years
and I just learned that one dude,
you can always add something. Um, the
aim, I think that that's, that's a,
that's a big deal.
Show up and be there and you will learn.
It's like I was talking to Greg one
time, long time ago, he, he was like,
we were talking about Hazel. If someone
asks you, how long have you been training?
But let's say you treat,
you started training 10 years ago,
but then you train for a year. You
took off a year and then you went back.
But you were only training a little bit,
you know,
so how long have you been training?
Really? How do you count it and all that.
Anyway, so he was like, he did, we didn't
go too deep into it, but he was like,
not man,
if you started 10 years ago,
you've been training for 10 years
because if you start training for a year,
even if you take a year off, when you
see something, you hear something, you,
someone's talking about something,
you're picking all that up because it's,
you have the context, you
know, you know, so your, your,
your brain is already assimilated
into your system in your mind,
even if you're not training. Yep,
exactly. Right. So if you're injured,
just keep that going.
That's a weird thing to do though.
There's a little ego situation
if you're like, well,
I've been trading for 13 years,
meaning I started 13 years ago,
but I took a lot of time off.
Right. So you might catch me, right?
Yes. Browse basically what they're
saying. So just tell people like,
I've been training for 13 years. Yeah.
You cut that kind of got a whore.
You know what? Let's see how good I
am. Yeah. You know, if in fact you,
yeah, cause I think it's calming.
Get it so automatic for the person.
Like, like if you're at, if you ask
me how long have you been training,
it's so automatic for me to try to
justify my skill with my number. Oh,
of how long,
you know,
even though the guy asking typically
is just asking for conversation.
He's not trying to evaluate how good you
are to ask you while I'm size and their
shit.
But you're different.
How long you've been training
for what school. Right.
Everybody, you're different.
You compete.
Well I was talking to Keenan about that.
Like how do you do it? And they're
kind of psycho though. They'll be like,
it's man hours. That's how you say it.
You train for 10,000 hours. You do.
That's how long you've been training.
I don't know if he was serious or not,
but that's the one we're looking at
it. But yeah, moral injury thing. Man,
I don't feel the same way as you though.
I think I definitely training
and I'll tell you what,
like if I've said this before,
if my back is tight. Yeah.
Nothing better for your back. That
Jujitsu. Yeah. Your next little sore.
Jujitsu. Yeah. Shoulders in
that little stretch or it,
no, I'm not saying go out there
and you'd be able to kill it.
You're gonna be able to go like the
superhard crazy rounds. Not going to work.
Yeah. Yeah. Just be careful. I
would say be careful. Yeah. Yeah.
I am not a doctor
in probably if people listened
to me as if I was a doctor,
their health would be deteriorated
quickly. It'd being questioned for sure.
From time to time. Don't sleep,
eat meat, train, injured, go.
That's my attitude. All
right. Next question.
How crucial is knowing
the personality type,
introvert extrovert of your colleagues
in combat business or choosing an mos,
which is occupation. Yeah. Um,
okay.
How crucial is it to know
the personalities of people?
It's really crucial.
Knowing in understanding people is
critical in every aspect of life.
And
that being said,
the most important part of knowing people
is knowing that you really can't know
people,
not 100% and I hear people talk about
like personality types and there's these
tests and these, these categories
and stuff like that. And honestly,
I've never been familiar with that.
Um,
but you know, you can put
people in different categories,
but for me,
when you put person in a
category by themselves, right?
That's only 50% of the situation.
The other 50% is the other people
that they're working with [inaudible].
So I want to know not just what
type of personality they have,
because that's a, that's a, like I
said, that's half of the equation.
The other half is how do they interact
with other people and other people's
personalities?
How do they handle slackers?
How do they handle over achievers?
How do they handle loud mouse?
How do they handle submissive people?
How do they handle aggressive people?
Those are all different
personality traits. I want to know.
I want to see how people are going
to handle other personalities.
And then I want to also know how they're
going to handle certain situations.
Pressure,
conflict,
a responsibility.
I mean,
I want to know not just
what their personalities,
but how they're gonna react because you
can get people that are a really easy
example is people that are
super aggressive but they
fold under pressure and you
can get people that are super passive,
that fold under pressure and vice versa.
You can get someone that's super
quiet and humble and under pressure.
They're just strong.
So that's what I want to know.
I don't care what kind of personality
you have. I mean, I do to an extent,
but I want to know how it
interoperates with the, with the world,
with the people and with the situations
that you're going to face and how do you
do that?
You do that by observing
them while they're dealing
with other people and while
they're dealing with pressure situations
and that's just a reality. Yeah.
And you can't, you can
have an idea, you know?
I won't say that. You won't be able
to predict it, but you get surprised.
Sometimes you get surprised about a person
that you think is all tough and they
fold or PR person that you think
is weak and they're strong.
So you will get fooled sometimes.
A lot of times you're, you know,
you're probably right 60% of the
time, 70% of the time. Yeah. Yeah.
Big One is also how,
how they react when stuff goes bad.
Like when stuff doesn't go their way,
you know, and that's a spectrum too, but,
and some you can meet someone
and or things are going good,
you're hiring new people with growth
or whatever, whatever your situation.
And it's like, Dang this guys,
I'm so glad I hired this guy,
but when something goes wrong they
self destruct or something like that,
then yeah. That's I think a critical
component. And so I get the, you know,
the simple answers that there's,
there's so many different variables,
so many different nuances that what
you want to do is you want to know your
people.
Yeah.
You want to build relationships with
your people so you know them so you
understand them. That's
what you want to do. Yup.
The r word relationships.
Yeah.
That's what you need.
That's how you get to know your people
and that's how you lead them correctly.
Next question.
In regards to subordinate leadership,
how do you begin to change the culture
slash school of thought of an industry or
a company?
You know,
I'm not sure if they mean in regards
to how do you change your subordinate
leaderships or if you are subordinate.
I'm not sure what,
which one of those it is,
but regardless,
it doesn't matter because guess what I'm
going to do? I'm going to lead. You do.
Yeah. That's what I'm going
to do. Whether I'm on,
whether I'm the subordinate guy or the
Superior Guy [inaudible] I'm going to
lead [inaudible]. Oh, we're going to,
I want to change things and
make them a certain way. Cool.
I'm going to do those things.
I'm going to make those things happen.
That's how you do it and if you're doing
the right things for the right reasons,
your message is going to spread.
Yeah.
You know how many bad seal
platoons I was in? How many? Zero.
You know why? Because me and my
buddies, we always had a good attitude.
We always had the right attitude and
that spread to the other people that were
with us.
Hmm.
Now there is a red flag that
you can get for yourself.
Yeah.
And this is frustration when
you start seeing yourself,
which I'm not saying this necessarily,
but this kind of question is coming from
somebody that wants change to happen,
but it's not happening.
So they're getting frustrated and
they're thinking they are not on board.
They don't care if they
aren't professional.
They're not motivated like me.
They don't have a good
attitude too. There's a lot of
blame going on right there.
Yeah.
So this isn't about them though.
It's about you.
And it's about leading from any
level in the chain of command.
If you're leading,
if you're doing the right
things for the right reasons,
that's going to spread.
So when I,
the classic example I talk about at all
time is if you're exercising extreme
ownership, if you're saying, you know
what, I got this, it was a mistake made,
it was my fault. That spreads. Yeah.
If you're humble,
that spreads.
If you have an open mind that spreads,
if you're being aggressive, not, again,
not aggressive towards other people,
but if you're being aggressive in
pursuit of your goal, that spreads,
you know what doesn't spread
is when you're aggressive
at people [inaudible] Oh,
I'll actually, it does spread, but it's
negative. Yeah. You don't want that.
You know,
it doesn't spread.
It doesn't spread when you're trying
to get people to do things because it's
gonna make you look good.
Yeah. That doesn't spread.
You can't get people to behave
better because you want to look good.
It doesn't work. Yeah. People
see right through that, oh,
he wants to look good. You know
what? I'm gonna do sabotage.
Now the other thing
I've been saying lately,
because people are surprised or whatever,
or not surprised,
but they're concerned,
they don't see how it's gonna work
so fast. And I say, you know what?
It's not gonna work fast. It's
gotta be, and here's the word,
it's got to be a cam pain.
It's gotta be a campaign.
It's not like World War II
was not one battle, right.
World War One was not one battle.
It's a campaign to win in Europe.
It's a campaign to win in the Pacific.
He takes battle after battle after battle.
And guess what? You don't win them all.
Yeah. You lose some of them. And so
you're going to, on this campaign,
you're going to win and
you're going to lose.
But you got to have the persistence
and the patience and the to continue
[inaudible]
in another piece of this is
cute.
You are best off if you go
indirect and not be like,
Hey, you need to act like me. No,
people don't like that.
Hmm.
You need to just act how you're acting.
And if you're doing it though,
like I said,
the right things for the right reasons,
people are going to see you
and they're going to follow.
Mm.
So that's how you begin to
change the school of thought.
Yeah.
That genuineness like tends to show
itself or that like if you're not genuine,
it tends to show itself, you know,
just because of the dynamics of Vinny,
nevermind tends to it just
straight shows itself.
So when you're doing it
for the right reasons,
like you can't help but expose that,
you know, that will be exposed. So yeah,
people will sign up the sign right on
and then you end up gaining like how you
say it's a campaign. It's like
you'll gain a little bit of ground.
You might win this guy over
like hey wait, that's, you know,
that's a cool way of doing it.
Or you know,
whatever the group is and you make these
small little steps and you kind of hold
that ground and yet before you know it,
it's kind of like Dang,
the whole culture of this, I don't know,
office or whatever. It's kinda changing.
You know? It just happens.
It's true. I've seen it happen.
Next question.
Yeah.
Jocko Echo.
How do you work with people
who overthink things?
The classic overthinker, what does
that mean? The over the means.
They won't pick up this pen right here
because they look in and say, hmm,
I wonder what the weight of that pen is
and if I should pick it up right now.
Because I'm also thinking about saying
something and what if I dropped the pen
while I'm trying to say something that
makes a noise on the desk that disrupts
from the flow of my sentence. And then
the whole flow of my sentences disrupted,
which means my train of
thought will be disrupted.
Now I can't refinish when I was
going to say that's an overthinker.
So that's personal training.
Now you can just imagine applying that
fought pattern to an actual project that
you're working on, right?
Right. Not a good scenario.
Or you're trying to apply it to a combat
situation that you're in or you're
trying to apply it to a relationship that
you're in. You start overthinking, well,
if I see this, then she might
think bad, right? What they
mean by that, right there,
that little by that. Yes. Yes. Dang. Yeah,
that's true. Okay. That's an overthinker.
So quit thinking so much.
You're overthinking it.
So here's what I do. When someone's
overthinking, I got someone that's like a,
like a chronic overthinker,
I'm going to,
I'm going to funnel them into the right
mindset with questions and I'll give you
some real easy questions to ask that'll
make this happen. Things like, Hey,
what do we mean by that? Or
like, can you explain that again?
And you're getting them to explain it in
a simpler way. Mm. Or you say, you know,
hey, so hold on. So what's the actual
goal? What are we trying to get done here?
Because again,
they're putting layers upon layers of
complexity on top of things that don't
deserve it. So what exactly
are we trying to do? And again,
you're just kind of playing dumb
a little bit and asking questions.
And then if you can't get to them, if
you can't quite get them to simplify it,
then you say, oh, okay.
So we're trying to do this
very simple statement. So,
so that way they start subconsciously
being coached and being taught to simplify
things as much as they can in their head.
And you know,
another thing I've been saying lately
when I'm out working with people is I used
to not really understand why people
are drawn to this complexity,
but I actually think I understand now
and I think it has something to do with
the fact that if I come up with a plan
and it's super complex and super crazy
and you don't understand it, then I must
be smarter than you. Right? Yeah. Right.
I came up with something that's so genius
and so complicated that you don't even
understand it. I understand
it. I understand that. Yeah,
they get you don't get it.
Right. And by the way, you know,
the only way you're going to understand
it if I have is if I break it down for
you because you don't get it.
You know?
So it's an ego trip and it's completely
wrong. Because the fact of the matter is,
if I'm trying to get you to do
something and you don't understand it,
I'm a loser. I'm failing as a leader. So
you,
you got to try and get
people to understand that
simplicity beats complexity
every single time and overthinking things
is a failure in ability to simplify.
So
another thing,
and this is more kind of about planning,
and this is something I used to talk
about in the seal teams and I called it 6%
advantage over the enemy.
And what this was was let's say you have
a target building that you're going off
of or going after.
You're going to go take down a target
building in the middle of wherever,
the middle of the desert,
and you basically come up with
a plan that you're going to use,
your standard operating procedures,
you're all going to get online,
or you're going to at least set up a
base in a maneuver elements. Very simple.
Two elements.
One element is going to hold cover and
the other one's going to move through the
target cover move. It's, I mean it's
as simple as it gets. That's great.
So you come up with a plan,
that's your plan.
And then as you're looking at the
imagery or you're looking at the map,
you notice that there is
an outhouse [inaudible] 150
meters away from the house.
So now what you do is you go,
you know what?
Because there's that outhouse there you
don't want to do is I'm going to take us
another team of our guys.
We're going to break them off
from the main assault force,
going to put them over there,
and that's what they're going to be in
case the guys in the outhouse, blah, blah,
blah. So what you've done is
you've separated your units,
you've increased your
communication problems,
you've sacrificed your fields of fire,
you dis-aggregated your fire power,
you've diminished your unity of command.
You've broke from your
standard operating procedures.
You've given up your real tactical
advantage that you have for the chance.
The chance that this guy at two o'clock
in the morning when you hit the target
is in the outhouse and not in his home.
Is it worth that?
No. So don't overthink it.
We're hitting this target.
You know what? Cool. We'll keep
eyes on that thing. No big deal.
But don't give up your tactical advantage
because you overthought the situation.
Hmm.
Go with what you know.
And
another piece of that is a lot of times
when people get super detailed like that
and planning,
they're actually planning things,
planning on things that
that can't be known.
So why would we make a plan for
something that can't be known?
I got a better idea. Instead of making a
plan for something that can't be known,
make a plan that's adaptable.
[inaudible]
you want your plan to be adaptable
and you know how you have the best
adaptability,
for instance,
on the battlefield that you have the most
control over your guys so that you can
move them, maneuver them
quickly. And how do you do that?
By having good unity of command.
And how do you do that?
By keeping your guys for
the most part together,
the minute you start spreading them out
all over the place and something changes,
something unknown,
that unexpected happens.
Now you've got a real everyone back
in and try and get them to change the
formation of their assault.
It becomes very, very complex.
So if you set up your plan so that
it's adaptable to changing situations,
then you're going to be good to go.
Same thing in business. Do you know
what the market's going to do? No.
We have predictors. Yes.
Do. Do we know them? No.
Do you know what your
competitor is going to do? No.
Do you know what your consumers are
going to do? No. Do we have intelligence?
Of course we do. Do we have metrics? Of
course we do, but we don't know things.
So keep your plans adaptable so you
can make adjustments when you need to
as opposed to overthinking things and
creating specific branch plans for a
possibility of something that might
occur in the future or might not.
Don't overthink it. People, you know,
sometimes people who under
think things [inaudible].
Sometimes they tend to say, hey, why
you overthink things when you're,
when you're just normally thinking about
something like you're thinking about
the whole stem. Yeah. So there's obviously
you have to think about things, right?
Yeah. And yes, you should
be cautioned of someone,
cautious of someone that's
just constantly saying, Mary,
you're overthinking this.
Three minutes planning.
Yeah. Yeah. Watch out for that guy. Yeah.
That's why. Yeah. One, the word
open, one overthinking comes up.
Kinda understand what that means.
But I feel like your example is sound
juggle.
What do you think of Greg Jackson that
[inaudible] famous MMA coach criticizing
Jon Jones on his recent power
lifting and muscle gain?
Yeah, so if you didn't see
this, if you're into MMA at all,
they caught Greg Jackson on the
mic after John Jones recent fight,
say, and you know, basically,
hey, I told you so. He's too big.
He's all that power lifting.
And I've talked about Greg Jackson
before and nothing but respect for Greg
Jackson. Uh, not only is he an
outstanding coach and a great tactician,
he's also just super humble guy who has
built a really cool gym and built a lot
of champions.
So his record speaks for itself.
So I'm not going to second guess.
You know what he's saying about a fighter
that he's worked with since day one.
And I think really it boils down to
this sort of definition of perfection.
If you've ever heard this definition of
the definition of perfection is when you
have nothing more to add and
nothing more to take away.
You've got it where it needs to be.
And they use this with design,
you know,
design of whatever,
furniture of iPhones have anything,
buildings.
When you've,
when you've got everything that needs
to be there and you can't take anything
away, that's the, that's perfection.
They say this about writing too,
and you look at someone
that writes really well,
every sentence you look at that sentence,
you can't take away a word
and you can't add a word.
And that's perfection.
And I think that is what Greg Jackson
is trying to do with Jonny bones.
Jones,
get him in that physical status where
you don't want to add anything and you
don't want to take anything away.
So what they may have done,
according to Greg Jackson,
is they may have added a little too
much muscle because of course you got to
have some muscle because it gives
you strength and explosiveness.
But at the same time,
muscle requires oxygen.
And so you can actually get too big
to where it's affecting your cardio.
So I think that's all Greg
Jackson was talking about.
And I think that's the balance that I,
that's the balance I'm always looking for.
You know, I want to be big and strong
enough, but I want to have endurance.
That's what I'm trying
to do. Yeah. You know,
and I try and find that balance by doing
bolts, strength work and endurance work.
That's, and when I say endurance,
I mean muscular endurance.
I don't mean marathon running
cause I don't run marathons.
METCON metcons baby.
So that's what I think he's talking about.
And you know,
like I said,
respect for Greg Jackson
and I'm sure that he had a,
he's got a good handle
on why he's saying that.
Yeah. Fully. And when you,
I do know a little bit of a
little bit about this where, um,
so if you gain some,
a bunch of muscle fast,
like over short period,
period of time,
you can have a way harder
time dealing with, you know,
the drawbacks of that muscle. And that
is endurance. That's the main thing. Um,
and at the same time,
this doesn't have much to do
with this particular situation,
but if you gain muscle real fast,
you can lose it.
You have the potential to
lose it real fast. But at the
same time, you vice versa,
if you cultivate this, you know,
muscular body build, whatever,
um, over time, like let's say you started
lifting at 15 years old and you're,
you know, 35 years old now and
you've always been muscular,
your body will have an easier time holding
onto that must for if you stop like
lifting for even a year or if you stop
leaking for a long time and then you get
back to lifting, it'll, it'll,
it'll jump right back up as far as
your muscle muscular muscularity.
So in regards to endurance,
no matter what,
bigger muscles require more oxygen, more,
more fuel. So it's harder to get that PR,
um, endurance up when you have
big muscles just in general,
but you're going to have the potential
to gain that endurance way more if you've
had muscle for a long time.
So you do these big jumps in muscle gain.
Man that endurance is going to suffer.
It's going to be really hard to
build up that endurance really hard.
I'm not saying impossible, but it's just
really, we're going to take time. Yeah.
So yeah, that is a dangerous
thing. Not Dangerous, but it's,
it's a risky thing to do when,
you know,
I'm going to jump back into the fighting
situation and I'm huge now. You know,
it's like God, that insurance might stuff
around that one, you know, obviously,
or apparently it, uh, it
did there. I think we, uh,
maybe do one more here. Okay. Jocko,
do you ever feel like Sisyphus pushing
a rock up a hill only to watch it roll
back down again and have to do it again?
How do you overcome that?
Do ever feel
like Sisyphus?
Yeah,
of course I have. Yeah. I mean,
I do and I'll tell you,
I've,
I've thought about this and I've been
waiting for people to start saying like,
oh, you put another picture of the
sweat and have a squat rack. Really?
But
I don't know if they understand.
I've been getting on that squat racking,
grinding it out for 25 years
and I'm not bored with it yet.
Hey,
it might seem
like that's an unwinnable battle,
but really to me
it's not about winning.
It's the battle itself.
It's the struggle.
It's the daily test.
That's what life's about.
Not just physically,
but mentally
getting that rock to
the top of the mountain.
That's not what my goal is.
My goal actually is pushing the rock
because pushing the rock
that pushes me,
that makes me tougher.
That makes me harder
mentally and physically.
He,
he,
it gives me much more than I give it.
I want a struggle how wanna
grind in Claude scratching.
I want to dig in and I want to
push and I don't want it to end.
If I ever got the rock to the top of
the mountain, had it stayed there,
I push it back down myself.
I don't want to rest and I don't want to
coast and I don't want to reach a point
in my life where I say,
[inaudible], that's it.
I've done enough.
I'm not gonna give any more.
I'm not going to push anymore.
No,
no.
That relentless cycle of
day to day challenges,
they are maddening to me.
They don't frustrate me.
They inspire me,
inspire me to drive and push
more and to push harder.
That's what that rock does to me.
So why is c d g n
and get to push it
can I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
So,
so all you troopers out there,
thank you for joining us.
Thanks for inspiring us.
Thanks for listening to us listening to
the podcast or watching the podcast on
youtube. I had somebody hit me up the
other day on Twitter and said, man,
I didn't know you guys were on
youtube. Yeah, we're on youtube.
Got The youtube channel
Jocko podcast.
Sure.
And thanks for giving us feedback
and for spreading the word.
And if you want to connect
with us on the Inter webs
on Twitter, echo is at
echo. Charles on Instagram.
Echo is at echo.
Charles on Facebook,
bookie,
what are you
slash Echo Charles? Yes sir.
And on those three I'm the same.
I am at Jocko Willink and to
everyone out there in uniform,
military, police, firemen, EMS,
thanks for what you all do.
And gratitude for your service.
Thickened that ain't for
keeping us free and safe.
And if you want to support the podcast,
once again, how can you do with Echo
Charles? Um, support the podcast
at the same time. Get supported to buy
on it on a.com/ [inaudible] you get,
they give you 10% off. Boom. Support
your endeavors to get better.
Supplement yourself.
Um,
again on.com/jocko or you can support
the podcast by doing your amazon.com
shopping through Jocko, podcast.com.
Click on that link and then, um, you know,
he can support it that way.
Mind your ad blocker if you have one
that's rare, but if you have one minded,
um,
if you feel like donating that school too,
and thank you guys who
have done that. Um, yeah.
Or if you want some shirts,
get some shirts, man represent,
I think they're cool.
I have made an effort to
get like the quality shirts.
Is that why they're sold out so much?
Yeah.
See in the a big part in that
cleaning about you. Yeah, I know.
And here's the thing,
I can't buy 5,000 shirts because where
am I going to put them right now?
You know, so we uh, it's a
long story, but so yeah, sorry,
I'm getting them. I'm getting them
and I'm going to improve on that too,
by the way. But their quality shirts,
they are there. They're solid.
They're not like the ballpark giveaway.
No, no. Sure. $2 shoes, shirts.
I would wear them if they
didn't have my own head on them
or if they just did victory
mme and fitness on them,
then you live. That's right.
But anyway, yeah, I had@jockostore.com
or you can get a coffee mug.
They're kind of cool, I think. I think
they're kind of cool. And if you want,
if you, if you kind of liked what,
uh, what we're talking about here,
leadership life lessons,
you can check out a little book that
myself and my brother Leif Babin road,
it's called extreme ownership.
You can get it on
hard cover,
you can get it on kindle.
You can get it on audio.
And the audio was read by
myself and by life as well.
So you can check that out.
And thanks for supporting that.
And finally to everybody
out there in the world,
living in freedom,
take advantage of it.
Take advantage of your freedom
and your life by driving hard.
And by pushing that rock up that
hill with everything you've got
man. Also. And of course,
drive hard by getting out there
and getting after it.
Yeah.
And so until next time,
this is Jocko and echo
out.