This is Jocko podcast number
97 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening
to the master stone Mason
in the town of Mansfield.
Greetings and God,
much beloved parents.
If my small letter finds you in good
health, I should be mightily glad.
What concerns me?
I am pretty much in health here in
the white country will have to die.
All of hunger,
all is burnt and the Russian army has
carried off all subjects as they had such
a fear of us and there is no food to be
found because nobody is to be found in
any town.
Whenever a house is found,
it is empty and dark.
Dear parents,
I have to give news of our last battle
as we had already gone hungry for three
days and March day and night
at five in the morning,
we marched into this battle
with the cabbage stump in
our stomach and we were in
in it until the evening
and then we again had nothing
and could not eat for tiredness.
Only cannon fire from morning to evening.
God has helped me out of the third battle.
Also without harm though.
The bullets hailed down pretty well as
if one were to take peas and throw them
at someone,
but none got me.
The whole cavalry is lost.
Now I want to write you about
the Russian town of misery,
Moscow,
which is seven hours walk along and as
wide and the Russians put fire to it for
four hours at burned and then it was
extinguished and we were stationed before
Moscow.
And I don't know whether we
are going forward or back.
I don't know what to write
except that you will shortly see many
cripples without arm and leg and so many
must die pitifully of
hunger and terrible dangers.
Russians appear all the time for
the last battle. Let's end now.
Finally, farewell and stay
healthy until we speak again.
Many greetings to brothers and sisters,
brothers in law and sisters in law to
the Balts ans the Krogans and all good
friends and acquaintances and I am
quite well if only I can live farewell.
I remain your faithful son until death.
Johann Andreas Warner.
So Napoleon
who is often praised by
many in coding myself,
praised as a military genius.
And he was one of the first military
leaders to effectively utilize
psychological warfare.
And this included most famously
his bulletin's de la Grand Army,
which was sort of an update.
It was like a newspaper that was sent out
while the campaigns of France or being
embarked upon.
And that was his media.
So he had control of it and he also
controlled the mail that his troops sent
home and made sure that it
painted a positive picture
of what was happening down
range. And that is where that
opening letter came from,
that it was actually excerpts of a letter,
but it was confiscated by the
military of the Kingdom of Westfalia,
which was a vassal state
under the first French empire,
which was Napoleon's empire
and the Kingdom of West Valeo,
which is a German piece of land.
And it provided hundreds of thousands
of soldiers for the Napoleonic wars.
And when I say provided soldiers,
I should say specifically calm scripts,
which are basically slave soldiers,
you have no choice.
You will go and fight
and overtime Westfalia eventually
conquered by the Russians for a period.
And then some of the
confiscated letters survived.
And ended up as historical documents
that explained what was happening on the
ground.
And that's where that letter came from
through old Russian files where they had,
they had this letter,
and again,
we make a habit of glorifying Napoleon
and I have done it right here on this
podcast,
which is actually pretty substandard
behavior for me since I always try to
listen to the voice and hear the voice
and understand the viewpoint of the foot
soldier, the grunt, the front
line troops on the battlefield.
Because that is where
the fighting takes place.
Those are the men that execute
the plans of the general.
And that is where the
wars are actually want.
And history as a whole has a
tendency to forget about them
because generally it's the admirals and
the generals that right the memoirs.
But in this case we are going to
hear from one of Napoleon's grunts,
a guy by the name of Jacob Walter,
and he is a German conscripts
who was fighting for France.
So this is a guy grew up in Germany,
but when Germany was,
became part of and became a vassal state,
like a subordinate state
of the empire France.
Then he ended up fighting for France,
but even more,
and you're going to find this out quickly.
He was fighting for his own survival.
So let's go to this book.
The book is called the diary of a
Napoleonic foot soldier by Jacob Walter.
And here we go.
In the year 1806 I was drafted with many
of my comrades into military service in
the conscription at that time and was
assigned to the regimen of Romaic in the
fall.
I traveled with the regiment
to Prussia in the campaign,
which Emperor Napoleon with the princes
then his allies was conducting at that
time against pressure.
And this is interesting because I've
talked about on this podcast before,
the battle of Jenna and what happened
at the battle of Jenna and what happened
at the battle of is that the Prussian
army was defeated pretty savagely by
Napoleon's army.
And that made them make some major
adjustments to the way they ran things.
And that was kind of the beginning of
decentralized command from the German
perspective. But this guy, Walter
Jacob Walter was actually there.
Now this is what's interesting, and I, I,
I go take some time to paint this picture
of the way these soldiers operated
back then.
First of all,
they marched just about everywhere
and sometimes they'd ride horses,
but sometimes they are, but most of the
Times they marched and when they marched,
what they would do is just wherever they
were, whatever village they were in,
they would go in and get quarters
in that village. They'd go in, hey,
we're here where we need to stay in
your house and we need to get fed.
And that's what they did. And people
allowed them to do it. I mean,
a bunch of people with guns show up at
your house and say, we want food and beds.
You, you know, these people gave them
what they wanted sometimes willingly,
depending when they were traveling
out of their own country.
So when they were in Germany
there or in their Westfalia,
the locals as they were
leaving, the locals would give
him, Hey, we'll support you.
It's like military guy,
we'll support you.
And then when they got
into enemy territory,
they would be asked to be more forceful.
But here's how it starts
off with him marching.
We were given good quarters everywhere,
which kept me always healthy and cheerful
in spite of the continuous marching.
Furthermore, I was only
19 years old, a fact,
which caused me frequently to
participate in thoughtless and dangerous
enterprises. I think he was getting
after it as a young 19 year old,
and this is another thing
that's interesting. So
this guy, these conscripts,
they weren't,
they weren't permanent soldiers.
They were more like reservists where
they would go and fight and win.
The war was over. They go back home and
continue with whatever their job was.
And so that's what happens to
him. He, you know, gets tasked.
He's only 19 years old. Boom, you're
going to go fight. He says, okay.
He starts going in,
marching back to the book in this city.
It happened in my quarter that a comrade
wanted to force the landlord to sing.
However he refused to do so. Sitting the
whole night on a bench near the stove,
weeping. Since this man could not
sing because of his sorrow, sorrow,
soldier, Hummel wanting to
frighten him, took his rifle,
cock the hammer and shot the bullet passed
by me and another soldier and lodged
in the wall.
I wanted to mention this in order to show
how the soldiers were running wild at
that time. So like I said, when
they were in their own country,
they'd get good support and
everyone would take care of them,
but then the further they got into
other countries, they had to use force.
Hmm.
A spy who was in the village,
a spy who was a village.
Smith was brought before the guard house.
He had letters in orders to tell
Prussians of our strength in manpower.
He was laid on a bench and
whipped by two or three corporals.
Two men had to hold his
feet and to his head,
his leather breaches were stretched
out and water poured on them.
And then he received about 150 blows.
Okay.
At last he could no longer
speak because he was half dead
after this experience, the Smith was
taking to the threshing floor and shot.
Yeah.
Glows with clubs also were heaped upon
many innocent people in this city.
So these guys are
things turn bad real quick.
Things turn bad real quick.
And I can't even imagine these days where
there's a lot less accountability and
you have 19 year old soldiers coming
into towns and just basically doing
whatever they want back
to the book. Finally,
when light fire, now they're getting
into uh, an attack situation. Finally,
when light firing began upon the outpost,
we were commanded to attack by waiting
through the rampart ditches with fancy
jeans,
with fast scenes to tread these in and
to scramble up the outworks by chopping
and shoveling.
When I stood in the ditch,
each first soldier had to pull
up the next one with his rifle.
The ramparts were of sand and everyone
frequently fell back again because of the
attack of the enemy or just
because of the sliding sand.
Yet in that place,
the huge cannon balls flew above us
funding so violently that we would have
believed the earth would burst to pieces
when everyone was almost on top of the
earthwork.
The Prussians were slaughtered with
great vigor and the rest took flight into
the gate.
Then we to wanted to gain possession of
the gateway in order to enter the city,
but at this critical time,
many of these Prussians were shot along
with our men by small and large guns and
the gate was closed since all sorts
of shells and rockets broke out of the
fortress like a cloudburst.
We had to take flight.
Those who meanwhile we're scrambling up.
The outworks had to jump from the
fortress into the mote along with their
prisoners and all the
rest had to do likewise.
During this retreat,
many fell on bay in nets.
Many drowned and many of us were also
brought into the fortress as prisoners and
sent away to Danzig by see.
Now it's interesting,
this guy, the way he writes, it's very
matter of fact as to what happens,
and again, this is a relatively, I'm going
to take you to through three campaigns.
This is the first one.
The last one is the campaign and Russia,
the famous Napoleon's famous march into
Russia to try and take Russia at and
everyone knows how that story ends.
It's not good,
but this first one is, like
I said, against the Prussians
back to the book one morning,
the Prussian surprise,
the Polish camp from the sea with their
ships. As it happened before Easter,
the cannon fire on the polls was so
heavy that they could not withdraw fast
enough.
Their cannon balls also traveled more
than half again as far toward our camp as
all balls date across the water since the
surrounding swamps were frozen and the
balls could roll along on ice so fast
that one ball took off the feet and legs
of 10 or 12 men frequently,
both feet of the same man.
During this blockade,
the Prussians frequently made attacks,
although every time with great losses,
one the nightmare that is you're standing
on frozen swamps and these cannonballs
or.