Jocko hindsight is 2020.
But here's a crazy thought.
North Korean soldiers would have ended
up with a better life like South Korea if
they did not fight as they did in the
50s when should a soldier question his
leaders values?
That is not a crazy question at all.
And the answer is very straightforward.
A soldier should always question their
leaders, not just their leaders values,
but their leaders plans, their leaders
strategies, their leaders vision.
You should question everything
that your leader is telling you.
And if you see something is wrong,
then you should raise
your hand and call it out.
And I would say not only is it
something that you should do,
it's actually your duty.
It's actually your duty is to
raise your hand as a soldier.
And I'll tell you this doesn't
only apply to the military,
it applies to any organization.
And it might sound like I'm encouraging,
um,
mutiny or rebellion.
But actually the opposite is true.
If you have a team that
questions the leader,
the leader doesn't become weaker,
the leader becomes stronger if he's a
good leader, if he's on the right path,
if he's doing the right thing,
he becomes stronger because everyone
starts to understand why things are
happening.
They understand the vision more fully.
If the leader doesn't have a good vision
and he's getting questioned and he
can't answer the questions, yeah,
you might have a mutiny on his hands,
but it's not because the people are
asking questions because he doesn't know
what he's doing.
So the leader can't see everything and
he can't solve every problem or have
every idea. But the collective mind of
an organization can make that happen.
And that's why as a leader,
if I'm in a leadership position,
I want my subordinates to question me.
I want them to question me.
And like I said,
if I don't have a good answer,
I either need to find one
and if I can't find one,
then maybe I'm actually doing something
wrong. That's entirely possible.
And now from a,
if we want to talk about like a moral or
an ethical perspective than absolutely.
Okay.
There was a group of high ranking soldiers
in Nazi Germany that tried to kill
Hitler and unfortunately they failed,
but they did the right thing
and try in trying to kill them.
They did the right thing,
like not only did they questioned him,
they knew he was wrong and they
said, okay, we're going to kill him.
Yeah.
Now do you put yourself at risk
when you ask these questions?
Because I'm sitting here saying, yeah,
I want my subordinates to ask questions.
There's people that don't want
their subordinates to ask questions.
Not good leader, not good leadership.
That's not a good way to lead.
I'm sorry, I'm telling
you the truth. I mean,
and so it's so there's a risk as if
you're a leader doesn't want you to ask
questions and you raise your hands
and ask a question and you do it in an
untactful way and you do it in
a way that offends your leader.
Well then you might end up getting fired.
Or if you try and kill Hitler,
you might get killed yourself because
that's what Hitler did well after his
assassination isn't happy.
You wouldn't killed a bunch of people
including romble his best general.
Okay.
Cause he thought he was involved in it.
So you are definitely taking a risk,
but then you have to ask
yourself what is the alternative?
So in a moral or ethical situation,
what's the alternative?
And I'm not saying there's no alternative
cause sometimes maybe you'd be better
not trying to kill Hitler,
but rise in the ranks and
get to a situation where you
can have more control and
mitigate the damage that he's
doing to the country. Right.
That's a possible consideration to take.
Maybe you say, okay, you know what Hitler,
I'm going to be your guy and I'm going
to, you know, I'm going to do things.
So that way you can rise up in the ranks
and be in a position where you can stop
his bad decisions.
Okay.
As opposed to if you try and kill him
and you fail you, you, you want me to,
obviously once you're dead, you don't
have any influence. Over the organization.
Same thing if you're in a business where
there's something going on and you want
to raise your hand,
and yet if you raise your hand,
you know that there's a risk that you
might either a get fired or you might get
demoted or you might get put out of
your leadership position and now you're
letting down, not when, now you can have
an influence over the scenario anymore.
So that's,
that's something to consider as well.
Takes a significant level of moral
courage to stand up in those situations.
And
you have to be tactful.
I think that's important to say. You
have to be tactful. You have to have,
you don't walk in and just start
questioning your leadership immediately.
You have to build the
relationship force first.
You have to grow your
trust between each other.
And then once you have that,
you can then tactfully bring
up questions and try and get
yeah
to the bottom of why things are
happening and why things are being done a
certain way or another way.
Hmm. Question your leadership.
And if you're a leader, don't get offended
when you get questioned to be happy.
Be Happy.
Even when your kids do it.
Even when your kids do it, especially
when your kids do it. Yeah.
Cause you always want to take that easy
out. Just do what I told you to do. Yeah.
Yeah. Do it. I'm a dad. Yeah. It's, it's
different than, it's not what I said.
Cause you caught yourself. I like that.
Well Dang self policing over there.
Outstanding.
Uh,
what about when they always add the kids?
Wouldn't they always say why?
And then he was thinking, you gotta be
careful of, I'm speaking from experience.
You know how you know though? This is old
school. Like, Oh why? Oh because of this.
Why, why, why?
And then it gets fun to them just to say
why they don't even want to know why it
now. It just becomes the game. Then
what? Just shut it right down one though.
That's when you should keep, oh
it's me against, you know. Oh No,
just go Jujitsu on them. Hmm. You, they
ask why you asked them a question back.
Why do you think it goes that
way? And then they'll say,
well, I don't know. Well,
why?
Why don't you know,
just one sweep sweep,
I'm going to do good one.
Yeah, that's really good.
Actually speaking from experience,
I got four kids.