This is Jocko podcast number
one 45 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
The primary mission of the Marine
Rifle Company and platoon is to locate,
close with and destroy the enemy by fire
and maneuver or to repel his assault by
fire and close combat.
Yeah.
The primary mission of the weapons
platoon of the rifle company is to provide
supporting direct and indirect fires
including clothes in anti tank fires and
demolitions for maneuvering or
defending elements of the rifle company.
Okay.
Boom.
It does not get much more
straight forward than that.
That is taken directly from FM FM
six tack for Marine Rifle Company.
And this is a, this is a solid
manual, a very solid manual.
Very solid field manual.
Huh.
And one of the reasons
that I pulled it out again,
because I wanted to look at the
general principles of war and this has,
so the the U s military,
all branches talk about the principles
of war as the Amir as America sees the
principles of war.
For whatever reason,
the FM FM t six tack for has sort of the
best descriptions of them that I like,
I should say maybe they're not the best.
They're my preferential
once the ones that I prefer.
So the principles of war
pretty straight forward,
but I wanted to talk about them and
this kind of led me down a little rabbit
hole, which I sometimes go into when it
comes to, you know, military strategies,
principals, tactics. Sure. And
I ended up in a place that I,
that I thought was very interesting.
It kind of brought me back to something
that I had uncovered years ago.
One of those early things that started to
Gel. My thought process started
to, started to see little,
little, little connections
in the world. Yeah.
So it started with this.
So the principles of war,
so they talk about just these
broad principles of war. Again,
everyone in the military covers these
prints are ever in the u s military covers
these principles of war.
Here's how the Marine Corp in the Marine
Rifle Company manual discusses them.
Okay.
Principles of war general.
The principles of war are fundamental
truths governing the prosecution of war.
That's so legit. Anyways,
I'm going to read that again.
The principles of war are fundamental
truths governing the prosecution of war.
There you go.
The principles of war are guidelines to
be used by a commander to effectively
apply the combat power of the marine
company or platoon to aid in the
accomplishment of the assigned mission.
The effective application of these
principles is essential to the proper
exercise of command
and the conduct of war.
Although combat leaders
have studied the principles,
it is not enough to name them in sequence,
but rather to know when and how to
relate them to the combat environment.
The principles of war are included here
to provide a review for the commander to
be used when applying doctrine
contained in this manual. Now,
the important parts of remember is,
and you're going to see this,
that these principles do not only
apply to war at all. In fact,
they apply to everything.
Okay?
Principle number one objective.
The objective of a military force is
the goal or aim usually expressed as a
mission for which the
force was constituted.
This principle is overriding,
it's,
it is the apple. It is applicable to
any operation at any level of command.
The objective of a force can be stated
in either broad or precise terms,
depending upon the nature of the goal.
Each element of an infantry
unit contributes to the
attainment of the objective
of the larger unit of which it is a part.
For example,
when the objective of a
battalion has been defined,
all elements of the battalion must be
assigned objectives that facilitate the
attainment of the battalion.
Objective success in combat is measured
by the accomplishment of the mission.
So this is important to remember
from a leadership perspective.
When you come up with a mission and it's
a broad mission for your company or for
your team,
then the smaller teams within your team
have got to redefine that mission as it
applies to them and make sure that what
they come up with for mission is aligned
with and supports the
broader mission of the team.
So when you own a manufacturing plant
and your goal is to manufacturer x amount
of widgets a month,
well then the people on the line,
they have their little portion of that
widget that they manufacturer and they
got to make sure that they can fulfill
their part of mission that allows you to
do this overall success.
Also,
there's like supply people that are
bringing the supplies in for the widget.
Their goal,
their mission is to provide the supplies
needed to make these things and so
that's what it is.
You've got to make sure that the,
the mission of the sub subordinate units
are in support of a nested inside of
the broader mission,
but sometimes we forget as leaders that
the f the front line or the subordinate
people below you and the chain of command,
they might not understand that they
need to do that might not happen,
so you need to do it for him. Sometimes
you need to spell things out. Yeah,
next or offensive
by the offensive,
the commander can impose
his will on the enemy,
set the pace and course of battle,
exploit enemy weaknesses
and meet unexpected.
Develop a developments. Boom, be on the
offensive. What do, what do we call this?
We call this default aggressive, right?
That's the, that's the similar not,
and I will continue to make
the comparisons between
what we talk about w what I
taught,
what I came up with,
the original four laws of combat and
how they are intertwined with these
principals.
Back
to the book.
Even in the defensive,
the commander must be alert to
regain the initiative by offensive,
counteractions aggressiveness,
flexibility of mind,
and the ability to make rapid reasoned
decisions are required to apply fully the
principle of the offensive.
In defense,
the commander can often best accomplish
his mission by office of action.
So even when you're on defense,
you should be,
you should be looking
to go on the offense.
And there's some other definitions that
talk about, and this is very, very clear.
When you're training Jujitsu, have
you ever trained with someone? Well,
I know you have. When you're training
with someone that's constantly attacking,
yes, that's, that's you're
going to go down. I mean,
you're going to, when someone,
that's how someone gets the upper hand.
They're attacking here. They're attacking.
They're,
they're attacking over here.
They're attacking back there again and
you're constantly on the defense, defense,
defense, defense, and eventually they
get the upper hand and crush you. Yeah,
very clear.
In Jujitsu.
[inaudible]
next
simplicity.
Simplicity.
Demands that detailed a simple plans
be adopted in every military operation.
It's interesting dichotomy,
detailed and simple.
It is of course a relative term because
all actions in war are essentially
complex. That's a great point.
And I talk about that too.
I talk about how easy it is to
like how these, how a mission, hey,
so easy to see a seal mission
is not rocket science, right?
It's not brain surgery. You've,
you know where the bad guy is,
you know where you are.
You're going to load in some helicopters
are some vehicles, are some boats.
You're going to go to where they are
and you're going to get them and you're
gonna come back. There's the mission
that's a little over simplified.
To me it'd be,
and it's not that much over simplified,
but you know there's things like fuel,
there's things like load load plans.
There's thing about weight,
how much each vehicle can carry or how
much each helicopter can carry this.
So there's there are and how you're
going to put cover fire down there. A,
there are more detailed things.
So like the statement says,
all actions in war are
essentially complex.
And I will say that all actions in
war are also essentially simple.
Hmm.
Because what are you trying to do?
You're trying to close with and
destroy the enemy. That's it.
I've had that happen with companies
where I go into a company and
they've lost sight of the
simplicity of their mission. Yeah.
The simplicity of the mission is to
make something and they get all wrapped
around all these other things,
but what you're supposed to be doing is
making this thing and everything that
you're doing should be lead to
supporting the making of this thing.
And people go down,
they focus their efforts in other areas.
So it's good to think about. Yes,
there's complexities. It's, it's,
it's a total dichotomy. It's a total
dichotomy in business too, right?
There's a total dichotomy.
It's, it's very complicated,
but at the same time it's
actually very simple. Hmm.
So when you feel things
getting too complicated,
that's when you take a step
back and go, okay, what is we,
what are we actually trying to do here?
That's the question.
Back to the book.
Simplicity will be especially important
on the new Keeler battlefield.
Yeah.
Where the full use of available
means will require close control and
coordination and where plans must be
simple, as simple as the situation will,
will permit detailed simple plans
lead to coordinated timely execution.
So what's interesting at the
copy that I'm using of this,
and it's going to lead to the rest
of this whole podcast, which award,
which is when we're going to start talking
about the Soviets and which goes back
to the eighties I think
the date on this book,
on this particular version is
the eighties which is cold war,
prepare for nuclear combat.
That and when are we getting to the
Soviets and what they're thinking you're
gonna see nuclear combat was absolutely
part of it was part of their planning.
Yeah.
And so same thing here.
I don't even know that I have a comment
about keeping your nuclear war simple.
I don't know if I have a comment on that.
Hey,
we're going to drop bombs
and everyone is going to die.
I don't know how we simplify that anymore.
And clearly laws a combat simplicity,
simple.
That's one of the primary laws.
That's actually law number two in my
laws of combat that we put an extreme
ownership.
And why is that?
Because I would see over and over and
over again what would jam up to use your
term, what would jam up? A seal
platoon is a complicated plan.
You would do it every single time
so you have to keep it simple.
That's one of those ones.
Before I really started diving into sort
of the broad canon of military theory,
I, I had told everyone, hey,
you got to keep it simple.
You gotta keep it. And Anna,
I'd been told, you know, the Vietnam
guys would say keep it simple, stupid,
you know, Kiss. But I,
I was a little nervous that I was
maybe overboard with that. And,
and as soon as you start looking at it,
keeping things simple is a broad military
principle that's been around forever.
And there's a reason because it's true.
Next up,
unity of command,
unity of command is the
establishment of a single authority.
This is the best means of
ensuring unity of effort,
which implies a singleness of purpose
and cooperation by all elements of the
command.
That one seems obvious.
I'll tell you what prevents this from
happening. Most of the time it's ego.
Most of the time in the business
world, it's, no one wants to say, hey,
you know what?
We're putting this other guy in charge.
Give them the support that he needs most
of the time in the business world. Why?
Like, you know, we don't want to make
Billy feel bad. So you know what?
You run this part of it and then you
run the other part of it and then,
and then Jennifer over here,
she can run the, so it's all,
it's actually all three of you are
going to coordinate together to, uh,
to make this happen. Well, who's
in charge? You're all in charge.
How's that workout?
Not Good.
The only way it works out good as if one
of those people or or two of the three
people are exquisite leaders with no
egos and can prop up the other person
that's an egomaniac and make
them feel good and let it happen.
Otherwise it's going to be problematic.
You'd see this.
So in the military what they do is they
designate someone as the main effort.
So one,
one company or one battalion
will be designated, okay,
you're the main effort.
We're all here to support you.
That's it. That's something you
definitely have to be careful of.
And I'll tell you, I'll give you
a little hint, a little help.
The best way to do this is just to do it.
The best way to do it is be like, Hey,
you know what? I need one person running
this. So Billy, you got this one,
Jennifer, I'll probably give you the
next one, but Billy, you, you need to,
you need to take command of this one.
I know you know this terrain a little
bit better. You run this one. Jennifer,
if we go over to your your market
area next time you'll be running it.
So do what you can to support Billy right
now cause you he'll be supporting you
in the future. Boom. Done
what we what people do.
They want to have the harder conversation.
They don't want to just tell Jennifer
that she needs to take the back seat on
this one.
That hurts too much.
So they put everyone in charge and
now you've got no one in charge.
Now you've got a disaster on your
hand. Unity of command. Yeah,
next mass
mass depends or sorry.
Mass demands that superiority of combat
power be attained at the critical time
and place for decisive purpose.
This superiority is both
qualitative and quantitative.
Combat power is primarily a
combination of firepower and maneuver,
which is applied at the right time,
at the right place for decisive purpose.
So what does this mean?
Focus your efforts. This means prioritize.
Next, execute. This is the same thing.
This is the same idea as
prioritize and execute,
which is pick where pick what the
biggest problem is and that's what you're
going to attack.
Focus your resources on it.
Back to the book.
The use of nuclear weapons by enemy
forces will require greater dispersion for
passive defense.
Therefore,
a greater stress must be placed on the
application of mass from the point of
view of time rather than space.
Violation of this principle exposes the
command to the risk of piecemeal defeat.
Even buy an inferior your enemy.
Let's hope we don't have nuclear war.
Next economy of force economy.
Oh,
before we get there mass.
Another.
Another way that this relates to Jujitsu
is that when you get an arm lock,
what are you doing?
You're focusing all your strength
on the one weak point of the enemy.
When you get to choke,
what are you doing?
You're focusing all your force on that
one weak point of the enemy, their neck,
you know, next number six,
economy of force.
Economy of force requires that sufficient
force be applied at other than the
decisive time and place to permit mass
to be applied at the point of decision.
These two principles,
economy of force and mass are so closely
related that they cannot be considered
singly application of the two principals
requires a sound estimate of what is
sufficient elsewhere to permit the
attainment of decisive superiority at the
decisive time and place.
Sufficient is the key.
It connotes the application
of force necessary to
accomplish the purpose and not
the application of as little force as
possible. So economy of forced, this is,
we heard a lot about this
in judo, right? When we,
when we talked about judo in depth,
it's all about economy of force.
That's sort of the
underlying principle of judo,
which therefore makes it one of the
underlying principles of Jujitsu depending
on what kind of game you got. That's
what it's going to say. I mean,
that's cool in theory,
but you know, again,
on the mat it's not going to be like
that all the time. I mean, yeah,
if you can perfect it.
Good. So that's what,
there's some people that have the kind
of game where they're going to use an
economy of force to their advantage
because they're going to wear the other
personnel.
Yeah,
I would say I actually do that.
I do that. I don't, I will,
I will allow people to move around and
get tired and that's sort of a good thing
for me to do. I don't do it all the time
and I can't do it to everyone. You know?
I can't, it's right now, I can't
really tie around Andy. He's, he's,
he's not getting tired right
now. And the, yeah, the um,
that's the general principle,
you know,
like it's just generally
that's what you're doing,
whether you're perfecting
it or not. Generally that's
what you're doing. So like,
you know, when you're a white
belt and someone mounts you,
or even if you mount somebody,
you're like going for stuff and you're
trying to get out immediately and all
this stuff. Even though, Bro,
that's not the best time to get up and
you can kind of use timing. Actually,
I understand your point where they said,
okay,
the best time to get out is right
when they get through it. By the way,
that's the best time. That's the best
time to disrupt any situation. Yeah.
Like if you've got a situation
like a self defense situation,
you just disrupted immediately
as soon as it starts. Right.
And you just poke some, you know, stick
a pen in their eye and run away. Right?
You don't wait for them to grab you
and how you do. You don't do that.
An active shooter situation.
No, you don't think,
oh well I'm going to see
where this is going. No,
you immediately disrupted get out of there
as fast as you can wait around so you
don't let the enemy
settle in their position.
Because once they settle in
their position, they're there.
Now they can now focus on what's happening
because they're no longer having to
focus on settling. Right. They've,
they've established position. When you,
when you were fighting against
an established position,
it's problematic for the,
and I guess, you know, maybe
it's little bit different,
but technically it's in the
transition space, isn't it? Transits.
The Dean does a really good
job of teaching where as
the person gets into their
final movement to get in position,
he teaches where the gaps are because
there are definite gaps there.
And in the middle of a term transition,
for example, that's, that's a huge gap.
But in a way,
since they don't necessarily have
whatever the position they're going for,
like the amount, for example in
the transition to the mountain,
they don't really have them out.
So that's a huge gap.
But it's not technically escaping them
out technically because they don't have
it.
When you go to the other side of that,
that transition still in the
transition though, maybe the site,
we'll call it the second
half of the transition.
It's be way before they settle for sure.
Yeah.
That's where it's going to be 100%
but when you're a white belt though,
let's say they, they settle in and you
don't want, someone gets like, okay,
we're gonna use the mountain as the
example. The guys mounted right.
Hooks it or feed established and wait to
establish holy mountain, the mountain,
God established whatever. If you're
in a tournament, oh, and the early,
the earlier on you and you're just,
you're going to be trying to get out of
there. He immediately getting guns. Yeah.
And that's not economy of force right
there because it's like person is fully
established. Yeah. In fact I'll
go ahead and tell you you're,
you're wasting energy. Exactly.
That person is fully established,
very lost your opportunity when,
during that transitional period. Right.
So the point there though is
indeed you too. The more you learn,
the more you kind of learn about Jujitsu,
the more you, you realize that yeah,
this, this, that's a general purpose.
Like your hold you get to game is
economy of force, right? Your whole game,
you're not going to perfect it every
single split second of the year you get to
know sometimes you'll even step outside
of the rule to make something specific
happen or when it's arts dean will
be like, oh that was a spazz defense.
Like I'll just could get nuts for a
few seconds because you, you know,
in hopes that a opening opens up and
oftentimes it does when you're stronger
than that guy for a second or whatever.
I condoning or encouraging the spazz
as the premier escape situation.
Cause it's not,
cause there's plenty of times,
especially against an unskilled
opponent, they can spousal, they want,
they're not going anywhere. Yes,
correct. Yeah, exactly. Right.
And now I got something,
you know, I talked to, uh,
I was talking to Dave Burke
about this good deal team
and from a leadership perspective,
there is also something very similar that
happens from a leadership perspective
as a leader, let's say, okay,
when you're a black belt or a brown belt,
you have someone that's
a white belt right there.
You're mounted on them and they're
grabbing whatever they're grabbing.
They're grabbing it with full,
like craziness.
They're grabbing your belt or they're,
or they're grabbing your sleeve like
as hard as they possibly can or they're
grabbing your neck. It
is no factor, right?
I mean it's literally no factor to you
if you make it a factor that me just
means you're not experienced enough.
That means you, if you're only,
if you're only an a blue belt and you're
going against a lower blue belt and you
might start getting concerned about this,
but when you're a black belt,
you're like, oh, this doesn't matter.
From a leadership perspective,
there's things that are
going on with your team,
with individuals on your team.
And if you don't know what you're doing,
you're concerned about them and they
freak you out and they make you react.
And yet if you're a black belt,
these things happen and you just,
you just realize what they are.
It's just wasted energy for them and
it's going to have no impact on longterm
deal that you're, you know,
where you're going. So it's a,
it's a clear indicator to me when I'm
working with a leader and they're spun up
about little things, I, for some reason,
I always think of like they're spun
up that the person's grabbing their,
their belt, right? You're mounted on
them and they're grabbing your belt,
like they're gonna do something with it.
They can't do anything.
That happens all the time. From a
leadership perspective, someone, you know,
some of your subordinates or scope
doing something crazy, it's like, okay,
does it really matter?
Most of the time it doesn't even matter.
Occasionally you've got to address
it. Like if a guy, if your guys,
if you're mounted on a guy
and starts to lift your knee,
you reached down and address it.
No big deal. You don't panic.
You don't give up the mount. Yeah,
you just address it and then you,
you take it back to normal. So as a,
and what this has to do with really is,
has to do with detachment because you,
if you're detached,
you'll see that whatever the situation
is is not that big of a deal.
But when you're all up in the fight and
they're grabbing your belt or grabbing
your sleeve and you're freaking out,
you're not doing a good job of
detachment at all. Feels like, right?
I don't know what it is. I don't feel
right about it. I see it all the time.
And by the way, here's another important
piece. If they're doing something,
if they're grabbing your sleeve and
now you expend energy to stop that,
well, you're expending energy. You're not
following the idea of economy of force.
And what you're also doing is
you're giving up leadership
capital because you're
wasting time trying to stop them from
doing something that doesn't even matter.
So why are you worried about that? Let
that thing go. Just let that thing go.
Focus on the wrong thing. Yes, yes. Yeah.
In one when I was a bouncer, they,
this was part of the training,
but they did call it minimum. The
minimum minimum of course. Yeah.
Which kind of when you're training
could kind of, it's kind of like,
especially if you've been in like
breaking up like a significant fights
situation, you start telling me I
gotta use minimum, it just sounds off.
I know what they mean and this is what
they mean right here is sufficient.
They made sufficient. They basically do,
they don't want you over doing it. Yeah,
they do mean they do mean minimum,
but they also mean
sufficient cause the minimum,
well if you use the minimum
force required and it works,
then that was sufficient. Yeah. Yeah. And
I, and I understood it when they said it.
Of course like it's a one, one we're
not in the situation and like, yeah,
that's true.
We'll use it.
Just I like how they use sufficient
though because it one one you hear like
especially if you're talking about
warfare or in my case bouncing when you're
breaking up guys fighting with you know,
bottles or whatever and they're saying,
hey, use the minimum. You're like,
no man, we're going in there.
We get it done as quick as we can.
But the thing is it's like no Bruh.
Like you're not to use maximum.
Yeah, you're not going in
there swinging punches,
you're breaking it up,
you know kind of thing.
And it makes sense because guys will
do that. They'll be like, well you're,
you know,
kind of thing.
And then they'll like injure somebody
or something like that when they don't
have to. Yeah. Not Good. And
then efficient. Sufficient,
sufficient force check. Alright. Next
maneuver.
Maneuver requires that all military
resources be brought to bear in the
accomplishment of the objective.
Correct.
Application of the principle of maneuver
requires not only the full use of
combat power at the
decisive time and place,
but includes the movements
of elements of combat power,
including combat service support
to the area of operations.
That's pretty straight forward.
You have to move your people
in the right positions,
including the support people that need
to get there to keep the logistics lines
open, to keep the intelligence flowing,
to keep the radio is working on all that
application of this principle is a
function of command at all levels.
At the highest level,
it usually means the movement of men means
and supplies to an area of operations
and at the lowest level it means the
positioning of troop units and fires to
destroy the enemy
straightforward.
That's what that one is
next.
Surprise. Surprised connotes
striking the enemy when,
where or in such a manner that he
is unable to counter effectively.
The achievement of surprise is not
necessarily dependent upon misleading the
enemy as to intentions such as,
for example,
concealing from him an
intention of attacking.
He may know from the situation
that he will be attacked.
Yet the attacker may achieve surprise
by the time place, direction,
size or composition of
forces or tactics employed.
Yeah, that one's pretty straightforward.
That one's pretty straight forward.
That's the, that's the difference
really. That's the difference.
That's one of the differences between
like a white belt and a blue belt.
I mean it's actually, it's,
it's not even two blue belt yet.
You've got to be able
to surprise the person.
They can't know what's coming in Jiu
Jitsu if they know what's coming and they
know any Jujitsu that are
going to defend that thing.
So surprise comes when you are baiting
him with one thing and you hit him with
something else. And when for I've
told them, I told you that story.
Like when the first,
when I was like a white belt,
I'd probably been trained
in for like four weeks.
And this seal buddy of mine who had been
training for a while but kind of off
and on and,
and he was a friend of mine and as
soon as I was training for like a week,
I was like, hey, let's train incident.
So I was kind of roughing him up. Right.
Cause he, he's training off and
on and, but he's a good dude.
He's a great dude. And I said to him, so
after like three weeks, I said to him,
you don't, here's the thing in
Jujitsu, you can't just do one move.
You gotta like set it up with something
else. And the next time we were old,
he was going for a choke hard
on me. And I was like, dude,
this guy's man, I don't want to talk
to this guy. I can't let them. Boom,
here are mocked me. And
I was like, whoa. Yeah,
yeah. And I, that was the
last time that happened.
You didn't like that was
awesome. Was, he took just,
he took just my words of
what I told him and this,
this guy's a frigging awesome seal.
He took just my words of what I told them
and apply them to what he already knew
physically about how to do a
choke and how to do normac. Yeah.
And he'd are mocked me. Yeah. Yes.
Surprise,
surprise.
You go through these just kind of
naturally too, because they're like,
since they're grappling movements,
like unless you're one of these
super duper quick guys, you know,
like everything's going to
be more or less telegraph.
Do you know if like if
I say, Hey Jocko, um,
if I know you love the arm lock
and you don't go for arm locks,
I know that's coming. Yes
and no. I, I agree with you.
There's sometimes when I submit people,
when they'd completely know that
it's coming and they can't stop it,
Dean does that to me where it's like
he's getting an arm lock and I can't stop
him. He couldn't say like, here it comes.
And I'm like, oh, I know it's coming.
I can feel it coming. I can feel
it and I can't stop it. Yeah,
but here's the thing about that
technique too. That's like their will.
There's two elements that go on in
here. One, there's like, Okay Dean,
cause we talked about this before. Well
Dean, he's going to say, Okay Dean,
I'm a thing that the surprise
came earlier. Yes. Position.
We're not either he was ahead of you
now or he's in a position where all your
defenses that he knows have to
comfort for you to stop him.
He knows the defense and all that.
He put himself early on into a position
where he can shut down those differences
before to the point of this,
he did through surprise,
there's some little movement and all
of a sudden he's mounted with my arm
exposed and now I know how to
get our unlocked. I kick it,
kick it out of exactly right.
But
sometimes so,
but so sometimes you do submit people
like that where they know it's coming,
but you're right.
You got to get that surprise movement
to get insufficient in position.
And they're also, the
second part is, uh, Mike,
like little for lack of better term
Mike Crow surprises. So it's like,
you know how it's like,
Hey,
I'm going to go for this arm lock
and I know your arm luck is coming.
But just even for like a
half a second split second,
I'm going to like tip you off balance and
just for that split second you're like,
oh, your mind goes okay, are you just
your body reaction? Like your reaction.
Oh I gotta put my, you know, you know that
it's like our early movie learn and um,
Akbar used to do this all the time where,
you know,
the setup sweep from the card sit up
suite for the guard and when you base you
go straight,
you go back to the triangle.
That's what cause two to
basically put your arm down.
You can get your leg over like that.
For example,
like if someone likes to do triangle,
Jill tutor used to do that stuff to me
all the time because he liked to triangle
and yet he do these little things that
you got to put your arm down just real
quick. Even if you're like,
yeah, just real quick,
I'll just put it down real quick to base
or whatever and I'll put it right back
into the defensive position. Like
Bra. That's a little micro surprise.
Even though you weren't dressed in the
dark the whole time and where did that
triangle come from?
It's not that,
it was just for that little little
split second he split second surprise.
It's a surprise that works.
Hey, back to this, um,
maneuver like I feel like that's like,
and I learned this from you,
where put simply you say,
hey,
build the relationship with
people. Like you're like, Hey,
my boss won't listen to my input
or my coworker won't, you know,
listen to my, my strategy, which is
awesome. And all this stuff. You're like,
hey cause you're just going
to straight. You got to, you
got to create a relationship. You've
got to get into the position. You know,
I just got this question today, I was
getting interviewed and the guy's like,
you know, that guy's like, well, I mean,
what happens when I even see it's already,
it's like, it's like when someone says,
well, you know, it's like in Jiu
Jitsu when someone says, well,
you know what it was the guy does this and
say, well, yeah, so the guy says, well,
you know what happens if you get told to
do something by your boss and you don't
agree with it? And he just
says, do it my way anyways.
Right. And I'm like, well, I don't
get in situations like that. Why?
Because I've spent the last six months,
eight months,
one year building a relationship up with
my boss where my boss tells me to do
something that I don't believe
it. And I say, Hey boss,
I don't know if this is a good idea.
How about we do this a different way?
My boss says, oh, thank you John.
Thank you for not allowing me to tell you
to do something. It doesn't make sense.
Yeah. So you're right, it's a preemptive,
a preemptive maneuver to be in the right
position so that you will not get told
to do something.
Now,
does that mean I haven't done a bunch of
things that I didn't want to do leading
up to that point? Yes, absolutely. That's
called building leadership capital.
I'm going to make my boss when
over and over and over again.
No one wants to hear that.
I just got to when when Lafe and I were
out in Staten Island guys like, you know,
what can I do to lead people that
are that debt don't want to do,
you know, do what I want
him to do. Tech man,
you got to build relationships with those
guys. You can't bark orders at them.
It's not going to help. It'll help for a
minute. Like they'll load that truck up,
but they're looking for another job.
You know what I mean?
You've got to build relationships with
these people up and down the chain of
command and you know what that is? That's
maneuvering. You are correct. Yeah. Yeah.
I thought that was critical or critical.
Yeah.
But really helpful because again, that's
one of those things where you gotta do,
you got to detach, you've got to, you got
to kind of step outside and be like, hey,
cause that okay to build a relationship
with your boss, no one thinks like that.
That's the solution to the problem because
directly it's kind of not even though
a huge, huge, yeah. Why would
you say it directly? It's not,
cause it's straight up is, well it
doesn't seem like it put it that way.
Well if you just think kind of, I don't
know, for lack of a better term, linearly,
like if I'm like, Hey, I want
Jocko to loosen to my input, right.
A direct approach to would be like,
hey Joe, go take your headphones off.
Listen to my input. That's like a
direct, so if I go indirect, right,
that's more like, hey, I got to build
a relationship first, then I can,
it's basically adding another step.
But that step is like this
straight up requirement and, and,
and the thing is this,
it's not a step,
it's a broad underlying fundamental
situation that you set up for success.
Yeah.
And,
and then there's this whole thought that,
cause I,
and I've said this on here many
times to say it all the time,
I built relationships with bosses
that I didn't like. Right. And People,
oh well Jockos at an ass kisser.
Yeah.
And Jack was a brown noser cause he just
tried to build a relationship with his
boss. And I always say, no,
I'm not a brown noser a known on an ass
kisser. I'm winning. I'm here to win.
That's what I'm here to do.
If you know what I'm here to do,
take care of my platoon and make sure
that they can have what they need to
accomplish our mission to the
best of our ability. If my,
if I have an antagonistic
relationship with my boss,
can I truly support my platoon?
The answer is no. All Day long.
He's not going to give me the gear
that we need because he's unlike me.
He's not going to give me the training
that I need because he doesn't like me.
So why is he going to give me what I need?
He's not.
But if I have a good relationship
with them that I built,
then guess what he's gonna do.
He's gonna let give me what I need to
accomplish my mission and he's going to
give me what I need to be the most
effective platoon we can have.
Now where does it cross the
line? Where does, where does,
where does Jocko become a
brown noser and an ass kisser.
Cause we know these people exist and
I'll tell you exactly where the line gets
crossed.
The line gets crossed where I'm kissing
my boss his ass so that I can get
promoted or I can get taken care of her.
I can take care of myself if
that's what game you're in. Yes,
you're an ass kisser. I don't like
you because you're doing it for you.
It's like the difference between
manipulation and leadership, right?
If you're doing,
if you're,
if you're influencing people so that
they do something that's gonna help the
team and help the mission and help them,
that's influence.
If you're doing something, if you're
influencing or that's leadership,
if you're influencing people so that you
can help yourself and benefit yourself.
That's, and it doesn't help the team and
it doesn't help to mention that's the
manipulation leash.
Yeah. Yeah. Fully. Yeah.
And when you go outside of the scope
of like the broad goal, you know,
and I can see it by the way everyone,
everyone can see it.
Everyone can see it.
Yeah. Everyone can see it.
And what's really jacked up or,
and it's not even jacked up.
What's kind of cool is if you're looking
out for the boys and you're looking out
for the mission and you're
doing everything for their,
for their, for the best,
for their best, that
shows through to, yeah.
And when that shows through,
guess what your people,
your boss wants to take care of you. Cause
you're trying to win for him, you know,
not for you. So yeah,
but the way you say it,
I mean obviously you're, you're, you're
not new to this concept, but you know,
and you're not new to the concept of one
year in the situation if you don't like
the person.
And now Jocko wants me to build a good
relationship with this person that I
don't like or whatever. But I'm not
keeping it real. That's what it's like,
what it be like this to face guy.
You think I'm going to be give
him my respect, my valued,
coveted respect and man,
that's, I'm, I keep it real.
I keep it to reel to reel for that.
I'm not gay.
I'm not bowing down to that guy can do
it. Cool, so you're going loose. Yeah.
So you'd rather lose. Yeah. See, but when
you put it into perspective again, that
perspective that you put it in, which is,
which I did, what's, what's,
what's interesting just to,
just to take that to one more level.
If you're the guy that's like, Hey,
I've got too much pride to do that,
I'm not doing that.
I'm not bowing down to him.
Okay, so you're going to
lose. Because to me, I look,
I don't just look at it like one hit.
That's the end of the game.
The game doesn't end there. The game
ends when I'm on top with the big win.
And you know what?
My Ego,
my ego won't allow me to let
my ego interfere with the
fact that I want to win a
big game. The long game, I
play the long game in this one.
In all of them maneuver. Yeah.
A little bit of maneuver.
Maneuver. Yeah. If he can get into
a habit like you kind of nuts.
You surprised straight up surprises
me because I forgot by the way,
cause it's not as,
doesn't come as natural with one of your
answers at roll call when you were like,
hey, build a relationship. Oh like you're,
you know this person is when you know,
you remember the situation and the person
didn't like you didn't follow through
as much as he should have.
And because he's so good you can't
tell him anything kind of thing.
And then it's like, no, you gotta
you can't like harp on this guy.
You got to build a relationship with him.
I was like Aww Dang.
Cause that's a lot.
Most of the time that's the answer.
If you ever have a problem with
somebody like not doing it, you know,
like just like I said,
most of the time,
most of the time what
people think they should do.
How should I confront this person? Should
I care them to do what I wanted to do?
How can I confront them? Should
I fire them? Which it's like, oh,
you know what you should do?
Build a relationship with
them. Make them understand.
Make you understand where
they're coming from.
Can you lead someone that
you don't understand? Not
really. Here's another one.
You get someone if, if you're, oh, oh,
this person that works for me, thanks.
It's all about him. What should I do?
You should make them think it's that
everything's about him. Yeah. That's the,
that's the black belt. The black belt
movies like, yeah, you're damn right.
This is all about you and here's how
you're going to win. And by the way,
the whole team's going to be
winning because you're winning,
but we don't worry about
that. We're worried about if
your perception is that, oh,
echo, echo thinks this is
all about him, guess what?
I'm going to make echo think he's writes
and he's going to be busting his ass
cause it's all about him and the team
is going to echo is going to win,
which means the team's going to win,
which means I'm going to win. Yeah,
it's a no brainer. All you gotta do is
step back six to eight inches from the,
from the, from the front line to take
a look around and see that pretty far,
six to eight inches. When you need
to know this is the other thing.
No one wants to hear those answers. No,
no they don't. I shouldn't say no one,
but most people don't want
to hear those answers. Yeah,
because the fact of the matter is is it's
your fault. Yeah, it does. When your,
when your person is not doing what they're
supposed to be doing, it's your fault.
Hey,
do you get the person that just has a
totally negative attitude that shouldn't
be on the team? Yes,
they exist. I get that.
Whose responsibility is it to get rid of
them? You get two years here, the boss,
if they're not that person,
whose responsibility
is it to get everything you can out of
them? It's you. You're the boss. Yeah.
People don't like to hear that answer.
No.
It's a hard answer because you
want to throw whatever you know,
all the millennials, the big
one, right? The millennials are,
oh,
well,
maybe if maybe if maybe if
you were a better leader,
the millennials would be on board.
It's a hard thing to face,
but if David Hackworth and Jim Mooky Yama
can get draftees in Vietnam to go and
risk their lives and fight the enemy and
possibly get wounded or killed in a war,
they don't believe in. If they can
do that through good leadership,
I think you can get a millennial to
get get after it, and by the way,
there's millennials getting after it
everywhere. I meet him all the time. Yeah.
They're not like, Hey, I did.
Hey, it's good to meet you.
I'm glad you're putting out word about
how to be lazy. No. They're like,
I am going to crush the world.
They're out there. Yeah.
It takes a little bit. Yeah. What
it takes, it takes leadership.
That's what it takes. I'm sorry.
Leadership is not easy to people do.
The millennials don't want to listen.
Who wants to listen?
I was more rebellious than
any millennial off Matt.
Hmm.
Let's see. Anyways, so
next
security security provides readiness for
action or counteraction and is enhanced
greatly by flexibility.
Flexibility in mind,
organization and means
contributes to security.
It's attainment embraces all measures
designed to avoid being surprised or
interfered with seriously.
And the retention of freedom of action.
Security is not imply.
Undo caution and avoidance of all risks.
Important security does
not imply undo caution.
So there's a dichotomy here.
It doesn't imply the avoidance of all
risks for bold action is essential to
success in war. And what does bold
action requires? Requires risks.
Otherwise it wouldn't be bold
when security is provided.
Unexpected developments will not seriously
interfere with the attainment of the
mission check.
So I've got to maintain security.
That makes sense.
So those are the nine principles.
This is the nine principles of
war. That's as they existed. Now
they also talk about,
and there's a debate right
now going around of weather,
weather flexibility should
be the 10th principle.
Some people think it should,
some people think it shouldn't.
And then in 2011 they added
some principles to joint
operations and here are
those principles.
Number one is restraint to limit,
correct collateral damage and
prevent unnecessary use of force.
So now we're getting into
the minimum force, right?
Restraint requires careful and disciplined
balancing of the need for security,
the conduct of military operations
and the national strategic end state.
Make sense?
That's where they came up with us.
You have to put that minimum force. That's
what that is. That's the same thing.
Right.
And I think the key to that,
they put on the end, the
national strategic end state.
So what does that mean?
Sometimes if you use too much violence,
if you as a bouncer use too much violence,
you're,
your goal of your mission is a
bouncers to keep the place safe. Yeah.
If you use too much violence,
people don't want to go there cause the
bouncers are, are, are assholes, right?
They're beating everyone
up. That's a problem. Yeah.
So what's our strategic end state
is that we keep this place safe.
So that's why they,
they're talking about that same situation.
They actually changed our name from
bouncers to, uh, fursuits host.
Wait, Whoa, whoa. They call it there.
You're not bounces your hosts and then
with the change it to a door host. No, no,
no. Okay. They went, bounces the
to know you're a doormat. No,
you're just adore the
dormant and they're like,
no door hosts fits like the
personification of this place.
You know, like you're just,
yeah, that was a good trial.
It's interesting. Yeah.
It's interesting though,
because that's a little leadership
maneuver that they're doing.
They're trying to, they didn't do a
good job because you're joking about it.
Right. You thought it was a joke. He
liked us and ridiculous. The thing is,
I actually wasn't men and it ultimately,
I was like that.
That totally makes sense because when you
think bouncer, you think dive bar guys,
beating up guy, you know, bouncing
these guys out the on off the wall.
I'd roadhouse talks about
minimum force though, right?
And boy. Yeah. Dalton. Well,
what does he say? He said be nice.
Oh, that's like the rule, right?
He nice and he's like, uh, ask him to
walk, but be nice if he doesn't walk,
walk him. But be nice if
he, if he still won't walk,
get another guy to help you walk
him and you will both be nice.
And he said you be nice until
it's time to not be nice. Oh,
that's super bad ass. Right. Good.
Hold it back. You're good. All their
back. Right. That's like the, the,
the to hold it back.
That smile like the Bio,
what do you call it? Not The Bible,
but the movie version of the,
you know how you have like what do,
what's the navy seal movie?
But when you got to, you know, for,
for pilots it's top gun. You know,
if there's a seal on the one
with Charlie Sheen. Yeah.
But I don't even know if that's
the iconic, not as iconic
as roadhouse. If you're a bouncer and
you watch in front of, that's your thing.
Yeah, for sure. No, it's the
iconic belter I don't even,
is there even another bouncer movie?
I don't know.
Shouldn't be as it doesn't even
exist. Nope. Exactly right.
Check.
All
right. Next. This is one of the new
ones. One of the new principals.
Perseverance.
To ensure the commitment necessary to
retain the national strategic end state.
The underlying causes of
the crisis may be elusive,
making it difficult to
achieve decisive resolution.
The patient resolute and persistent
pursuit of national goals and objectives
often is essential to success.
What I don't like about that one
is it it, it, it kind of,
it kind of says it's, it's
saying like, well, what's the
number one rule objective?
Like you've got to know what your
mission is. You got to have an objective,
and this one is saying,
look,
the underlying causes can be elusive.
It can be difficult to achieve
decisive resolution. So
I guess the theory or the principle
of perseverance means we're going to
continue to do this.
My problem with that is that is how do
you end up then or do you end up then
with a Vietnam,
we're continuing to fight
even though we're not quite
sure what our end state is,
what our objective is and it's so
elusive that we're not sure where to go.
That one makes me a little bit hesitant.
Do I believe in perseverance?
Absolutely. You keep going,
but as I've talked about before,
don't quit.
Doesn't mean never give up on the the
plan that you came up with and just keep
going until you freaking either
die or you achieve your goal. Yeah.
Next legitimacy to maintain legal
and moral authority in the conduct of
operations legitimacy,
which can be a decisive factor in
operations is based on the actual and
perceived legality,
morality and rightness of the actions
from the various perspectives of
perspectives of interested
audiences together.
These 12 concepts form
principles of joint operations.
Now I'll tell you what's
interesting about legitimacy.
Obviously you have to have it.
You have to have, you know,
moral and legal authority.
The Prom I,
the problem I have with that
is who gets to judge that?
Because the per the people
that you're fighting,
they don't agree with what you're doing.
You're not legitimate in their eyes.
So how were we coming up with
that? I think, I think we can,
but I think we have to do
that decisively and say,
look, this is what we're
trying to achieve. This is why.
And if there's a bunch of
people debating about it, okay,
well we're going to hold off then
until someone says, oh, you know what?
This needs to be stopped.
Or the situation situation needs to end
because you do need legitimacy and if
you don't have legitimacy,
you're going to have problems really,
truly accomplishing the mission. Yeah.
Yeah. And I mean kind of in a way, I mean,
I'm sure there's obviously,
but in a way there's always going
to be like some deep date. You know,
how like, they'll be like, hey, you know,
I'm going to make a generic example,
but like you,
you know,
if they some turmoil in this country
because of the way these people are
treating these other people
in this country, right? Boom,
US steps in and all this
stuff. Some, there's going
to be somebody debating, hey,
like that's their country.
That's how they roll. You know?
It's like who are we to step
in and call them, you know,
immoral or whatever when that's how
they'd been living for thousands of years.
Yeah. That's my point. So yeah. Who
gets to make his decision? Yeah.
Well it's a tough one.
Yeah. Like almost like a,
like a global standard needs
to be established, you know?
And I think that's kind of the end.
And I think you,
I think it is actually possible
to do that. I think so too.
I think it is actually
possible to do that.
And I think the fact that we
sometimes decide that, hey,
it's not our place to make that decision.
Like I'll give you an example.
Isis,
hey,
if you're systematically
raping eight year old,
nine year old,
10 year old girls and boys,
you don't get to do that. Right?
We will come and stop you. Yeah.
That's the way it's going
to be. Yeah. And you need,
if you need a documented argument
for why that is, I think,
I don't think that'd be
a problem to produce.
I think if you need a
documented argument for that,
you just made the list as well.
We're coming after you.
I think I agree with you sir.
So yeah,
Nazis,
guess what?
You don't get to do that same dealio
imperial Japanese army rolling into China.
Rape of Nan King. Nope. You don't
get to do that. That doesn't work.
We're not okay with that.
You just made the list.
We seem to have a harder time doing that.
We seem to think these days that evil
doesn't exist. Yeah, and that's wrong.
It's wrong.
Next,
next it talks about the application
of the principles application,
the principles of war. So that's, that's
the, well, it's now the 12 principles,
but now I'm going from the new principals
that were added on back to the 1984
Marine Corps Field Manual
Fmfm six TAC for rifle company
application.
The principles of war act as a checklist
for the commander in order to apply
combat power effectively and
reduce his units of vulnerability.
A review of military history will
demonstrate that those commanders who have
adhered to those principles have most
often enjoyed success on the battlefield.
There you go.
I like the fact that they're taking these
principles and broadly applying them
to the past and saying,
look, when this happened,
historically you will have victory.
Most of the time
there have been, of course,
exceptions to the rule. However,
these exceptions prove the rule that
any attempt to rigidly apply all the
principles to all battlefield
environments may lead to defeat.
We got to, we got a little chapter
in the dichotomy of leadership.
It's called disciplined,
not rigid. Yeah. Why?
Because of what that just said.
The commander should recognize the need
to apply the principles as flexibility
as all other tactical
principles, oh, sorry.
As flexibly as all other tactical
principles based on the circumstances with
which he is confronted,
flexibility in the application
of principles is as
important as flexibility in
the application of combat
power on the battlefield.
Isn't it cool to come up with
principles and then just say, yeah,
you got to apply. I'm like, as needed.
It's interesting. There's a, there's a,
there's a, it shows how much you
have to think as a leader. Yeah.
You have to look at things all the time
and sometimes your principals getting
ready to back off though.
And that's Kinda what we
did in the dichotomy of
leadership because can you make
things too simple? Yes. You can cover
and move the number one principle.
Can you cover and move too much?
Yes. You can prioritize. Next. Cute.
Can you prioritize and execute too much?
Yes you can. What does that look like?
It looks like target fixation. What is,
what does cover move too much look like?
It looks like you're stepping
on the toes of other elements.
What is too simple? Look like? You
haven't covered all the contingencies.
What is too much decentralized
command look like?
It looks like your people don't even
know where you're supposed to be going
because you've haven't made it clear.
You've let them go too far
back to the book.
No commander can rigidly
follow the examples provided
by doctrinal resources but
must modify them according to his mission,
the situation and the terrain
over which he is fighting.
So there you go.
Now what was interesting is I
found this in an air force manual.
So that's, that's what I covered
from that Fmfm six tech for,
which is just really good broad
principles of combat principles of war.
Now it was interesting,
I was looking at an air force to
kind of get their perspective,
similar perspective,
not as detailed,
but one thing that they did that was
interesting was they put the other
countries principles of war and
compare them to our principles of war.
And a lot of them are very,
very close.
But one of them that stood out
was the former Soviet Union. And,
and this is where we get into,
you know,
I was talking specifically
about the USSR back in the day,
back in the eighties
back in the 70s you know,
this is the other superpower in the world.
And they have some interesting theories.
And, and again, there's a little chart
that I found it kind of laid out,
you know.
So in America we have objective
in Great Britain and Australia, they
say selection, maintenance of aim,
right?
So understand what your aim is.
We have on offense offensive
in Great Britain, Australia,
they have offensive action.
We have mass meaning we're going
to use our concentration of force.
What does Great Britain and Australia
call it? Concentration of force.
We both have economy of force. We call
it maneuver. They call it flexibility.
We call it unity of command. They call
it cooperation, which is interesting.
Cooperation is very similar
to cover and move. Yeah.
We both have security. We both
have surprise. We have simplicity.
They don't have simplicity,
but they have another one called
the maintenance of morale,
which is an interesting,
important thing that maybe we left out.
Why do we leave that out?
It's an important one.
France,
they have three concentration of effort.
That's the same as mass surprise. That's
another one and then their last one,
liberty of action, which is interesting.
That's decentralized command, right? Hey,
you've got to go out and make
things happen. Yeah. China,
they have some similar ones.
Objective,
they call it selection and
maintenance of the offense.
They call it offensive action mass.
They call a concentration
of force maneuver.
This is an interesting one.
Maneuver.
They call it initiative and flexibility.
Again,
a little bit of decentralized command
sprinkled on that unity of command.
They have coordination,
they have security,
they have surprise and their
last one is morale, mobility,
political mobilization
and freedom of action.
Interesting dynamic from
China and then they,
they listed out the Soviet,
the former Soviet once because this
is one of the largest armies that ever
existed. This former Soviet Armand
Army. And as I was reading that little,
this little,
this little chart about what the Soviets
had masking and correlation of forces
economy and sufficiency of force
initiative, Surprise Mobility Temple.
I was, I was going to, there's,
I remembered reading an old assessment
of the Soviet style of warfare broken the
dude and I remembered it
had some interesting takes
and I was able to find this
field manual from the 80s I
want to say again, this is,
these are like from the same time period
as the FM that I just read from the
Marine Corps, the FM, there's updated
ones which we can cover as well.
But these are the old school ones.
And again,
it's in the 80s I mean you wouldn't assess
the Soviet Union the same now as you
would then. So this, we had a manual,
America had a manual FM 102 tack one the
Soviet Army and I thought it was kind
of worth reviewing some of what,
what they talk about principles
of war because again,
this was like one of the largest
standing standing armies in history.
It was our major foe.
It was well experienced from World War II.
So figure with all that,
you know,
we probably could learn something
from them. So here we go.
Getting into the Soviet Army a little bit
and some of their principles, how they,
how they rolled
the introduces it by saying
the Soviet ground forces.
This field male describes the operations
and tactics of Soviet general purpose
ground forces.
The content is based on information in
Soviet writings and other open source
literature.
Most available information is focused
on potential battle in central Europe.
This is when this was the reality.
Folks, this is in the 80s.
The Soviets believe that any future war
could involve the use of nuclear weapons
and that the initial stage of the
war will be decisive. This is crazy.
Tactical nuclear,
tactical,
nuclear weapons have been assigned
at all levels from division up.
That's crazy. Wait, so what does
that mean? Everybody has new,
well, at the division level, so yes,
a lot of people have, a lot
of people have nukes. Uh,
the Soviets have the largest and most
effective array of chemical weapons and
equipment in the world.
They are capable of employing chemical
agents from battalion level upward.
That's crazy.
So a battalion is like the lowest
fighting unit that we have.
It's, it's, it's, I don't know, 500,
600 maybe 700 guys generally.
And imagine 700 guys with a,
with an o five. This is a probably a
35, 40 year old guy in charge of it.
They got chemical weapons
on the battlefield ready
to employ. And by the way,
two levels above them. At the division
level. That's what we're talking about.
Nuclear Weapons.
Not exactly what I love.
Okay. The Soviet front,
I had to put this in here.
The font is the largest
field formation in wartime.
It is an operational administrative unit
and its size and composition can vary
widely depending on the
mission and situation.
Roughly equivalent to a US
or NATO army group of front.
It could be composed of three to
five armies with organic artillery,
missile layer defense engineer. The
reason I found that funny little layer,
there's,
I often refer to Ashkelon front
simply as the front,
but what what is also interesting,
I looked up front to see if
that was a commonly used,
if to see if that definition and it did.
They didn't have it listed. They didn't
have a, this is a, this is a group,
an army group. They didn't list it
that way. So That's interesting.
Learn something new. All right. Um,
at this time they're saying that the
Soviet ground forces were like 1.8 to 2
million people and 191 maneuver divisions.
So to answer your question,
191 divisions and each one
of those hundred and 91
divisions had tactical nukes.
Get some
man,
and now we get into, so just that just
kind of lays out how this came together.
Okay.
The Soviet concept of war to the Soviet's
war is a manifestation of the class
struggle.
It is an expression of the
conflict between progressive
forces of socialism and
the reactionary forces of
imperialistic capitalism,
which they feel will ultimately raise B,
which w which they feel will be
ultimately resolved in favor of socialism.
The Soviet concept of war represents,
represents a continuation of politics.
Same thing that we have. We, you
know, we think of war is when,
when politics don't work, that's
when war happens, unfortunately.
But yeah,
reactionary forces of imperialistic
capitalists. You know what that is?
That's America boy.
Uh,
that's how the, that's how
parts of the world view America.
All right. The Soviet military
doctrine is officially accepted.
The Soviet military doctrine is the
officially accepted set of concepts that
delineate the ways and means to achieve
military objectives in the interest of
politics.
The formulation of Soviet
military doctrine is a
continuous evolutionary process
based on number one communist ideology.
Number two,
Soviet foreign policy.
Number three,
economic and military strength
of adversaries. Number four,
Soviet resources in geography.
Number five, history. Number six,
science and technology.
Soviet military doctrine is based on an
elaborate integrated system of thought
and then it breaks it
down a little bit more.
And I kind of had to build that in there
cause it talks about military doctrine
and then it talks about military
science is the study and analysis of the
diverse psychological and material
phenomena relevant to armed combat for
developing practical recommendations
for the achievement of victory in war.
Pretty straight forward.
But the reason I had to say or talk about
military sciences because I wanted to
get to this point,
which is military art and a lot of times
we don't think of the Soviets. Right?
What do you think of the Soviets? What do
you think of? I, I know what you think.
What do you think of when you
think of the Soviets? Come on.
When you think of the Ussr,
what do you think of? You're
going to let me down, Bro.
What? What do you think of when you
think of like the, the Russians,
what do you think of these? They're
strong wrestlers. Okay. As a whole.
When you think of the Russians,
what do you think of,
if you had to characterize the
Russians in one individual,
who would you think of? Stalin? Ah, close.
I thought you were going to say
Drago. Okay. Ivan [inaudible].
Ivan Drago the machine, right? Sure. This
is what this is. That's what I think of.
You know, I think of that. That's what the
Soviet Union is. It's like the, you know,
no emotions, no religion.
It's just raw machine.
Cold. Right? Actually
fairly accurate. Yeah,
but they go here.
Military art is the most important and
primary field within military science and
is the basis for strategy,
operational art and tactics is the
theory and practice of conducting armed
conflict.
So they put this high hide.
Yeah.
Respect to the art. Art.
Probably interesting.
Possibly higher than we do.
Maybe you know it is possible.
All right, so now we get into it.
And
principles of military art.
Soviet military theorists consider
the following points to be the general
principles of military art.
So that's what,
that's where I'm going with all this
guys to get their principles. Gotcha.
They do not represent any
special revelation of truth
or radical departure from
traditional male military thought.
However,
by their emphasis on
these particular points,
Soviet military leaders
reveal their character,
the character of their military thinking
and predict the basic characteristics
of future Soviet military operations.
According to the Soviets,
they're armed forces must,
and here's the list before we
prepared to accomplish the mission,
regardless of conditions under which
war begins or must be conducted.
Yeah,
next, achieve surprise whenever
possible. It sounds familiar.
Military operations must be
characterized by decisive descent,
aggressiveness forces must strive
continuously to seize and to hold the
initiative. That's good information. Next,
make full use of all available military
assets and capabilities to achieve
victory. Next, ensure that
major formations and units,
all of all services,
branches and arms effect through
thorough and continuous coordination.
Got To work together. Cover, move,
select the principal enemy objective
to be seized and the best routes for
attacking it.
Make a decisive concentration of combat
power at the correct time, right?
Same thing. Next, maintain continuous
and reliable command and control.
Interesting.
The reason that's interesting is that's
like a little bit leaning towards
centralized control, right? Centralized
Command as opposed to less committed,
but they're going to reverse
that later. Next, be determined,
decisive in achieving the
assigned mission. Next,
maintained complete security of combat
operations. Security, right? Same thing.
Next,
reconstitute reserves and restore combat
effectiveness as quickly as possible.
Makes Sense. Next. Well
now it continues on.
These are general principles that apply
to all three levels of military art,
strategy,
operations,
and tactics at each of these levels that
are more specific detailed principles.
Soviet military fought,
subscribes to certain laws of war at
the strategic level and principals of
operational art and tactics which
apply to the actual conduct of combat.
So here are the laws of war
first law,
the course and outcome of war waged with
unlimited to employment of all means of
conflict depends primarily on the
correlation of available strictly military
combatants at the beginning of the war.
Second law,
the course and outcome of
the war depending on the
correlation of the military
potentials of the combatants.
Third Law,
the course and outcome of war depend
on its political content. Fourth, law,
the course and outcome of war
depend on the correlation of moral,
political and psychological capabilities
of the peoples and the armies of the
combatants.
Now,
I didn't break those down because they
actually do it for you in the manual.
Here's what in simpler terms,
what these things mean. First law,
be prepared,
prepare in peacetime for the next war.
Forces in being are the decisive factors.
The side with the most and best troops
and equipment at the start of the war
will win the war.
That makes sense.
Barring any major strategic blunders,
second law,
the side which can best sustain a
protracted war will win the war.
Makes Sense.
Third Law,
the higher the political stakes of a war,
the longer and more violent it will be.
That's a good one.
And you got to think about that one.
From a leadership perspective,
when you start getting involved
in things that have higher stakes,
this is when people start
stabbing each other in the back.
So people get ruthless.
So when there's more at stake,
there's going to be more violence,
Huh?
Yeah.
We don't recognize that sometimes,
hey, this guy's always been cool to me,
but all of a sudden the stakes go up.
All of a sudden we're getting stabbed
toward the dirts coming out.
Right. The claws come out.
It's always interesting. You get to
see people's real true colors, right.
When things are at stake, when more at
stake, people's true colors come out,
the violence occurs.
Yeah. Yeah. Can I like when the, you know,
the detective shows up at your door,
hey, let got some questions for you.
Ah, I don't have time. Whatever.
All, we could do it here,
or we could go back to the station.
All right. All right. You know?
Then they start revealing little
bit more. Then they're like, hey,
they don't want to cooperate that much.
They say this thing. They say, yeah,
I was there, but I don't remember all
this stuff. And they said, well, hey,
if you don't tell us the truth, you
could be going to jail. All your freedom.
Now the stakes go up off. They start
talking more. See what I'm saying?
Then they say, hey, your friend,
was he involved in what I'm saying?
And you're like, oh no, no, no,
you're right. Hey, if you're lying,
not only do you go to jail, then you know,
and they raise the stakes a little bit.
Odd.
They ran on their friends.
No mm clinic where the stakes go up. Go
Up. Yeah, man, the violence increases.
Next fourth law war aims must be seen as
just modern war cannot be waged without
public support. Very important.
Yeah, very important.
So Viet Planning and preparation for war
reflected dominant feeling that war is
inevitable.
This is not to say that
the USSR wants war,
but that is preparing for it continuously.
The Soviet state is autocratic,
militarized, and centralized.
It's political and economic systems
give priority to military requirements.
The state allocates resources and
directs production for preparation and
maintenance of a war footing.
The Soviet Union is prepared to exert
itself at great expense to achieve its
goal.
It is a nation which through civil war,
collectivization attendant famine and
purges inflicted more than 20 million
deaths on its own citizens
from the Russian revolution
to the start of World War
II.
It is a nation that endured the loss of
20 million people during World War II.
It's tolerance for sacrifice is high.
Yeah.
That's a little something to think about.
Now what's interesting is
what's stronger that or the core
desire and mandate for
freedom that we have here,
and actually I can answer that question
because history has answered that
question.
Freedom will win.
Yeah.
Next,
as the laws of war dominate
strategic planning for war,
so do principals of operational art and
tactics govern the conduct of warfare
within a given theater of operations.
The popular Western version of these
Soviet and tactical principles is very
brief. Objective offense,
surprise, maneuver, and mass.
This list is not fairly characterize the
basis on which Soviet military leaders
plan and conduct operations and tactics.
Just as they add new equipment to
their forces without abandoning older
equipment.
The Soviets have modernized operational
and tactical principles without fully
abandoned,
abandoning their earlier ones.
A good place to begin is with
those classical principles
that were taught by the
czarist at general staff.
So these are the classic
Russian military principles.
Here they go.
First,
extreme exertion of force at
the very beginning of the war.
Okay,
next simultaneity of actions.
Next economy of forces. Next
concentration. Next chief objective,
the enemy's army. Next
surprise. Next unity of action.
Preparation,
energetic pursuit,
security initiative and dominance over
the enemy's will strength where the enemy
is weak and that's the list.
That's the old classic list and
it breaks it down a little bit.
The most significant
points of this list are
okay.
First,
he who gets to the initial
battle with the most wins.
That's sun sued.
By the way,
the enemy must be confronted with
more than one situation to deal with.
Oh, that's, that's how I got
are locked all those years ago.
I was dealing with that choke
and there came me arm lock.
Next one should not be diverted
by geographical objectives,
but should concentrate on the destruction
of the enemies. Military forces.
Next,
detailed,
exacting preparation must precede and
attack design actions to preempt your
opponent and keep him reacting
to situations that you control.
Concentrate on the enemy's weak
points rather than his strengths.
Contemporary military,
contemporary Soviet military theory just
hold that nuclear weapon tree and other
means of modern warfare have
modified these basic principles.
By the early 1970s the
following principles dominated
Soviet operational art and
tactics.
So they literally made these
adjustments for nuclear war
first mobility and high rates
of combat operations. Next,
concentration of main efforts and the
creation of superiority and forces and
means over the enemy at decisive
place and at the decisive time.
Next surprise and security. Next
combat activeness. That's a good one.
Combat activeness.
Next,
preservation of the combat
effectiveness of friendly forces.
Next conformity to the conformity
of the goal to the actual situation.
That's a good one.
Conformity of the goal
to the actual situation.
Know what that means is your goal can
change and it can change based on the
situation you're in. Yeah,
that is important. And the
last one is coordination,
which is basically covered move.
Now it goes on a melding of contemporary
writings and those of the recent pass
plus an influence of significant classical
Russian principles results in the
following specific Soviet principals
of operational art and tactics.
And we'd go into a long list.
The offensive is the basic form of combat
action only by a resolute on offense
conducted at a high tempo and to great
depth is total destruction of the enemy
achieved. So we need to go
hard. We need to go fast.
Next combat maneuver units must be
mobile and capable of rapid movement.
Next fire support,
command and control and logistics
must be as mobile as maneuver units.
That makes sense.
Conduct or conduct thorough
and continuous reconnaissance.
Find the enemy's weak points.
Yes.
Okay.
Perform a thorough estimate of the
situation and make timely analytical
decisions.
Be Realistic.
Consider the mission enemy,
your own combat power, terrain,
weather and light conditions and time.
So yeah,
you got to look at this situation.
You've got to look at it.
Best thing about that and you don't
hear this very often. Be Realistic.
How good advices that it's damn
good advice. Yeah, be realistic.
You don't hear that often enough.
Next plan and prepare
extensively and in detail.
That's a good idea. As we know though,
you can go to the extreme with that.
You can overdo it.
The planning and conduct of an operation
must involve the full coordination and
cooperation of all commanders involved.
That's important.
If you're coming up with an operation,
you got to involve the commanders that
people that are going to be in the
operation with you.
You can't just send them an email
of how you want it to go down.
That's not going to work.
There must be unity of command,
a signal commander for every operation.
Boom.
We already talked about that.
Fully orchestrate all of the all
available combat means in coordinated,
cooperative, combined
arms effort. Makes Sense.
Next to deceive the enemy.
Attack from an unexpected direction
at an unexpected time. Check.
Use terrain and weather to your advantage.
Check strike early with great force check.
Okay.
Constantly strive to preempt
and dominate the enemy. Again,
I was thinking when I hear that,
I always think of Jujitsu when someone's
getting the upper hand on you and you
can't dig your way out of it,
attack the enemy violently and
simultaneously throughout his depth.
Carry the battle to the enemy rear with
swift penetrations by maneuver units,
fire aviation,
airborne and Hella born assaults.
And by unconventional warfare
means be bold and decisive,
seize and hold the initiative.
Isn't it amazing that just
being aggressive goes so far?
If you are just get the upper hand.
I mean if you get the upper hand you just
have it and you just need to maintain
it.
How do you maintain it?
It's by be continuing to be aggressive
and not sitting back on your haunches
when you got the upper hand. I do
that and you just do some time. What?
Sit back on your haunches or yeah,
get a little bit of a advantage.
Relax too much. Let
let a little, you know,
let a little time give that person to,
you know when you see it as an MMA,
when somebody gets dazed, right.
And the person lets them recover,
takes him a minute,
takes them a minute and 30 seconds.
They don't get on that
person. Yeah. Got To do that.
Prosecute and operation relentlessly
without pause under all conditions of
visibility or NBC contamination.
That's nuclear,
biological and chemical contamination.
Doesn't matter. Keep going.
The Russians,
this is good.
Keep the enemy under constant
pressure and off balance.
Do not allow them to react effectively.
Obviously Jujitsu,
fully exploit the effects of nuclear or
chemical strikes with deep attacks by
all available forces.
I wonder what these guys were thinking.
They're thinking about how they're going
to follow up the nuclear assault bro.
Whenever possible achieve
mass by concentrated mask
nuclear or non-nuclear fires
rather than by massing maneuver forces.
What that is actually saying is
instead of using your troops,
use nukes instead to get the upper hand.
Good Lord man,
how did he get to this?
I mean we, we can look back
on it now. I hope. I mean,
cause there's obviously new
cars everywhere still, but man,
I hope people aren't sitting around
plotting right now coming up with the
tactics. I mean obviously we have to. You
have to, you have to game it out. Yeah,
it makes sense.
But man,
I hope we got some other avenues of
approach before jumping into the wall.
New quantia's
next.
If maneuver forces must be mass,
do so rapidly,
disperse them as soon as possible
after the task has been achieved.
Maneuver first with firepower.
Firepower is maneuver and move gets
some maneuver forces should attack the
weakest points in the enemy
defenses. Yes. Sun Tzu. Thank you.
We agree if necessary,
create weak points are holes with
nuclear or non nuclear fires.
Bypass enemy's strong points of strike
and is, yeah. Hey, you know what?
We were going to create a wake
weak point with nukes. Get some,
it's funny to hear that.
How like nukes is just sort of one of the,
I'm just throwing it out there,
just throwing it out there.
We're not talking like, hey, is
anyone going, hey by the way,
that's the end of the world. Hey,
hey kernel. Hey Kernel I got,
I just want to bring something up. You
realize that we all die when this happens,
right? Like this isn't, this isn't like
a good plan. You're planning socks. Yeah.
Like hey we get it.
Hey there's a little,
we had to create a weak point like right
over there. Hey we should send like,
like you know like maybe
12 guys or something maybe
over it or we could just use
this new cause it's here or maybe I'm
going to send this document to a Jordan
Peterson cause cause you know,
you know how we use all paranoid about
new nuclear war when he was in college
and that's kind of what sent him down
this path of how could we get to this
situation
is going to really disturbing.
It's like hey boss, look, check this
out. When you guys were playing. Yes.
How we're going to create a little
weakness where the nucleus Newcomb man,
scary.
It's very scary.
Avoid frontal attacks wherever possible.
Strike the enemy in the flanks of the
rear. Obviously we're all about flanking.
Maintain security rule and flanks.
Maintain sufficient follow on,
forced to assure achievement of
the mission and to end to deal with
contingencies,
maintain a uninterrupted combat support,
maintain effective continuous command
and control and communications.
That's getting a little bit,
you know, that's important,
but sometimes I think that they were very
centralized and you can see that from
when they fought in Afghanistan that
they definitely had some centralized
command going on and the
units that perform well with
a few that would have the
most decentralized,
which was generally their special
operations units maintain redundant
communications at higher levels,
rely rely on audio and visual signals
and well-rehearsed battle drills at lower
levels.
Staffs at every level must have equipment
and skills necessary to collect and
analyze information quickly employ radio,
electronic combat to deprive the enemy
of effective command and control of his
combat forces.
That means they're going to use
jammers and whatnot at here.
Now this is where it's interesting,
so as much as I talk
about centralized command,
adhered to the spirit and letter
of a plan, if the plan fails,
use initiative to accomplish the mission
check, that's decentralized command.
You can only do that if you actually
know what the mission is. Next,
to be prepared to react effectively to
a rapidly changing battlefield. Check,
develop procedures to deal with
numerous contingencies, check,
think quickly and be decisive and
resourceful in accomplishing the mission.
Check,
conserve fighting strength through the
use of combat vehicles with collective
NBC protection. Again, that's nuclear,
biological and chemical protection.
Disbursable forces minimum combat
power necessary to accomplish the task.
The use of captured the enemy
equipment and effective logistics
and then that's the end of the list.
Obviously it's a pretty broad list,
but very interesting.
You can see the parallels.
You can see how the same themes come up
over and over again and it says this,
these principles are idealistic. They
are what the Soviets strive to achieve.
They show what the
Soviets would like to do,
but not in all cases what they
may be capable of doing. However,
the principles serve as a basis from
which any examination of Soviet operations
and tactics must start
and it can't. It's just crazy to read
about this nuclear warfare implications.
The advent of nuclear weapons
caused Soviet planners to
go through a long period
of rethinking and revising their
combined arms doctrine. Modern,
totally mechanized armed forces supported
and threatened by weapons that can
change the face of the battlefield
in a matter of minutes,
gave a whole new meaning
to the high speed combined.
Our operations in depth,
uh,
when we talk about can die combined
operations are combined arms in,
in the military. We talk about, you know,
we're going to use mortars or
we're going to use artillery.
We're going to use your air
sport. Where do you use, you know,
heavy machine gun fire. We're going to
use all those together in coordination to,
to catch our enemy in the combined arms
dilemma where there's no way to get out
of it. It's like checkmate, right?
Yeah. I never ever thought about,
hey, let's get him in the ultimate
checkmate over here on this one. Bring in,
bring in the tactical nukes again,
just just to point out that,
okay,
under nuclear threatened conditions,
the Soviet offensive concept
would have the following features,
avoid concentrating, forces, concentrate
fires, but not firing weapons.
Attack across broader
frontage is on multiple axis.
Avoid enemy's strong points,
probe for enemy, weak points,
penetrate where possible,
commit,
follow on forces when and where
they can best contribute to success,
drive rapidly and deeply into the enemy
rear to destroy nuclear weapons and
enemy forces.
Okay,
and just to wrap this up because
I thought this was an interesting,
we're not covered a bunch of this book,
just like we barely covered any of the
marine corps rifle. Uh, manual. Yeah.
Norms,
initiative and flexibility as Soviet
military doctrine includes a system of
performance standards expressed
in numerical forms called norms.
Norms defined the ideal performance in
a multitude of tasks and conditions.
I've talked about task conditions
and standards on here before.
They are used to determine
such things as intervals.
Rates of March frontage
is logistics requirements,
fire support and training drills.
Norms provide a mathematical
prescription for proper action.
So this is where we get to,
you know,
I started thinking of that
Soviet stereotypical like,
hey, we're just going to,
here's the numbers, plug them in
and that's what we're going to do.
They are formulated by historical
analysis, training exercises,
requirements and gaming
models based on norms.
A given situation has
an approved response.
The correctness of commanders action or
his troops response is often measured by
their adherence to the established
norms for that situation.
The advantage of this system is that
it provides a high degree of combat
readiness, at least in the initial
stages, drills at the sub unit level,
battalion or lower our well-rehearsed,
the tactical level commander is aware in
advance of how well his troops can cope
with time and space factors. The and so
there's, there's what's good about it.
You have everything like laid out like
this is what we do in these situations.
Back to the book of the
obvious disadvantage to
strict adherence to norms is
less provision for the unexpected.
If a situation arises for which there
was no established normative response,
a lower level commander
might find themselves in
peril, which I totally agree.
That's why I made the training super
hard and crazy for the guys that I put
through training so that they were
ready for non normative situations.
The topic of initiative receives much
attention and Soviet military writings.
When a plan fails,
commanders are strongly urge
to use initiative as a cure.
All the Soviet perception of initiative
involves finding a correct solution,
following normative patterns.
If the commander adheres to norms
and a successful he is praised.
If he violates normative patterns
and fails, he's condemned.
So what, what kind of a decentralized
command do you end up there?
No one wants to take any risks.
Success, however, is most important.
If commander solves a problem by his own
devices, he is lauded. So that's cool.
But if you're afraid that if you make a
call and it doesn't go right and you're
going to get in trouble for that,
you know what you're gonna do,
you're not gonna make a call. And
that's what crushes your decentralized.
Yeah.
Isn't that like a good
tactic or whatever for like kids were,
you know,
like if they make an honest mistake,
you don't just hammer him, you know,
you can correct them or
whatever. Um, otherwise, yeah,
they're not going to want to like venture
out and do things, you know? Yeah,
totally.
And, and this, yeah, you have to, you
have to allow your kids to make some say.
I I've been saying lately,
you've got to allow your kids to brush
up against the guard rails of failure
without smashing them. Yeah. The bumps
and bruises or when a good are what are,
what go is going to make
them formidable in life.
If they never got a bump or a bruise,
life's going to hit them hard.
They won't be conditioned for it.
And this thing wraps up just saying
these concepts are not descriptive of a
rigid or offensive doctrine,
but one that is both mobile and flexible.
So there's a little something from the,
from the Soviet army in, and obviously,
like I said, the principles of warfare,
while they're nuanced and their
stated differently, they're the same.
I mean you see the same patterns over
and over again and they apply to war and
they apply to life.
And so I think it's important to see him
from different angles so that you can
understand them.
Because if you understand them broadly,
well then you can see him in all things.
And if you see him in all things and you
can actually apply him in all things,
which is important,
cause that's what's gonna make you better,
it's gonna make your Jujitsu better.
It's gonna make your business better,
it's gonna make your team better,
it's gonna make you a better leader,
it's going to make you better and it's
going to make your life better. And he's,
these principles have been
around for a long, long time.
So that's the,
okay,
that's the Soviet
maneuver warfare doctrine.
And you know,
I also recently had to do
some maneuvering myself.
Sure. A little bit of maneuvering
and I, I wanted to, uh,
bring it up because it's an interesting
little bit of aggression. Yeah.
A little bit of maneuver warfare.
So I wrote another book and the book
is called Mikey and the dragons. Right.
It's another kid's book.
It's for younger kids,
maybe a tad younger than the warrior kid
crowd. Right. So we're talking like four,
five, six, seven, eight
ish, something like that.
However,
okay.
Like the warrior kid books,
there's lessons for everyone in there.
Yes, there is. Yeah. And
so what's interesting, so I
wrote this book, I had to,
I had like a vision. Does that sound
too much? Oh yeah, when you say it,
but you know, I dig it. Okay.
I had the vision of this book,
what the story was. Right. And I
wrote it. I wrote the first half,
the original idea just like hit
me and I just wrote it. Yeah.
Like the first half of the book and
then a couple of weeks went by because I
wasn't quite sure about the ending.
Exactly.
And then one night I woke up
before three 30 in the morning,
I had the whole thing,
the rest of it.
And I sat down and I just
wrote the rest of it.
It was like overflowing from
my brain and I just literally,
I just woke up and I wrote the,
they took like two hours to finish
overflowing from your brain and your heart
and your soul.
Yeah.
I don't know about all Monroe wake
up three 30 in the morning, come on.
And that's like a,
what do you call it?
Like an inspired creative genius types.
I don't know about all that. Come
on, come on, come on, come on.
But when I got done I was, I
could, I really like, I liked it.
Like I realized it was something new.
It wasn't nothing.
And as soon as my wife and kid,
my wife and my youngest daughter
woke up that day and I was like, Hey,
let me read this to you.
And I read it to him and I could tell
because as soon as I got done reading it,
my daughter was like,
read it again,
but was even funnier was my wife was
looking at me and the look on her face
was basically a look of like, I can't
believe that you actually wrote that.
She looked real suspect
and I was like,
you know, I was waiting for it. It's like,
Oh, where'd you find that? Right. That,
and so it was like, no, I
actually did write and I, and I,
I read it to one of my seal buddies
who's got like really monotone voice,
but he's got young kids and
I'm awesome friends with them.
And I got done with it and I was like
looking at it as I was looking, I'm,
as I'm reading, I'm not looking
at him, I'm looking at it right.
And I get done and he's got this like
classic monotone voice and he's like,
how did you even do that?
And I was like, okay.
So that's kind of, you know, he was stoked
on it. And then I read it to you. Yes.
And well, you heard it, Mikey and the
dragons. And when I first read it to you,
cool.
You read me one, it wasn't even done yet.
Oh. And it was like, I was like, Dang,
I was in first,
I kind of want a superficial level.
I was impressed with your ability to
like actually rhyme stole. That's right,
cause it runs. Yeah. Cause
you don't have some, you know,
one time like I dunno me how I'm going
to bust out some rhyme I made up.
It's gonna be so far fetched.
Fred just do better with that.
But yours is like, it
all fits. It's like yeah,
I understand how your friend was like,
like how did you do that or whatever.
You know, cause it's just not, you can't
just throw words together that rhyme.
But um, yeah. So here the
first version without the big,
without the ending kind of thing. I read
that in the beginning and you were like,
hey there's more and there's an ending
or whatever that I didn't quite know.
I was like Dang, that's good. That is real
good actually because, and you, you up.
Cause you always have this little
message that's like real deep. You know,
that kind of applies to like a huge
message and it like it applies to kids
directly and then it applies to adults
directly though. That's the thing.
So you know how like, okay, so I read
kids book, I got kids, we all know that.
And there's kids book, but the messages
is real simple mess. I don't know.
There's like a, I don't know,
whatever the little kid message,
but it's like as an adult,
I'm not going to read that and be,
I learned that a long time ago. I learned
that when I was a kid. But these ones,
even all the worrier, kid
books or whatever, the bread,
these are adult messages for kids.
So that's what,
that's another thing I was like, Dang,
I was thinking that too bad. How do you,
how do you do that? You know? And then
I'm thinking, you know what happened?
You were like scared of something like
bugs or something when you were living as
this what I was thinking in
my head, I don't know, maybe
we're maybe your, anyway,
so
yeah, so the finished one, I
think I told you this year,
when you read the finished one,
I was like, holy cow. That is,
that is gold on so many levels. So what
I did was I stole the story, borrowed it,
I borrowed, this is what you do, but it
works. So I borrowed the story. Obviously,
I can't remember eyes,
the rhyming parts of it,
but I understand the story and story.
Yeah.
I told the story to my daughter has a
bedtime story and like she's like, oh,
she's like, oh are they show
all these questions. You know,
cause she thinks it's real. But
man, the lesson is so good. So good.
Well from your reaction from act actually
read to them all of my older kids as
well.
And the same thing.
Super just like stoked on
it and a little bit of like,
did you actually write them, you know,
back kind of attitude. And when I,
when I, when everyone kind of had
the same reaction, I was like, okay,
I need to get this into kids' hands as
quickly as possible because you know,
it's the arc, typical story of
a, of a kid that, as you said,
needs to overcome some fears.
And it's also a story within a story.
Right?
So basically the fundamental
thing is there's a, there's a boy,
his name is Mikey. He's scared of
everything. That's his basic situation.
And here's how he gets
introduced in the book.
It goes like this.
There once was a little boy named Mike
and there were many things in the world
that he didn't like.
He was scared of spiders and beetles and
bugs and always thought they hit under
the rugs. They were creepy
and crawly and nasty and mean.
And he ran from every bug he'd ever seen.
But it wasn't only insects
that gave Mikey a scare.
There were many other things
for which Mike didn't care.
And that's sort of the opening. So you
learn a little bit about Mikey scared,
scared of some stuff,
and eventually after you learn about all
the things that Mikey scared of and how
he kind of is
sad that he's scared of so many things,
you can do anything.
And he kind of wonders why is
he so scared of everything?
And eventually he stumbles upon this
book and the book is that there's a book
that Mikey calls the Dragon Book.
Yeah.
Even though the book itself
is called the Dragon Prince,
but he flips us book open for a second
and he sees pictures of dragons and the
dragons are all crazy.
And so he's a little bit scared,
but there's also pictures of like a young
boy in there that kind of looks like
he knows what's up. And so Mike,
he decides that he's gonna read it.
And so this is where you get the story
within the story because then you,
you turn the page and you see the cover
to this other book, Different Font,
different voice,
different situation.
The pictures look a little bit
different. That's cool. Cause I saw,
I only saw some,
I need to see the completed just some
of the pictures and you know Zach,
you know, he knows what he's
doing in there. And anyways,
the story that's in within the story is
it turns out that there's this little
prince that loves nick, where the king,
who was the prince's dad has died.
And of course everyone's all sad because
of that. But even more than being sad,
they're actually scared because it
was the king that always protected the
kingdom from the dragons who lived
over the hill in the dragon cave.
And with the king gone,
there's no one to protect the kingdom.
The knights are scared.
The guards were scared.
The only one that everyone is looking
to to protect the kingdom is this young
prince. And here's how you get
introduced to that, to that. But now
that the king had died in,
was gone,
there was only one person to fight and
carry on and that person wasn't big or
mighty. You are strong. In fact,
he hadn't been alive that long.
Now the person who had dragons to chase
was just a little boy with a smiling
face.
Yes.
The person that now must stand up and
be bold was just a little prince who was
only seven years old.
So the boy eventually realizes he's gonna
have to stand up and face the dragons.
He goes to his father's
war chest and opens it up.
And of course the shields super
heavy in the store is massive.
We can barely pick them up
and now he's even more scared.
But then he sees at the bottom of
the war chest, he sees a little note,
little note from his dad,
the king, the mighty king,
and the mighty king explains to the
son what he has to do to stand up.
And face the dragons
and the notes pretty
powerful in my opinion.
And the prince goes forth into the fray
and through those lessons from his dad
and he faces the dragons and
we get a result from that.
And then the original character and story,
right
Mikey,
he learns also how to face his fears.
So that's the basic fundamental story.
And the way it came
together was pretty cool.
Other than the reactions from everyone
was pretty cool. So like I said,
I wanted to get it into people's
hands as quickly as possible possible.
So I talked to my publisher about this
and I told him about it and I was in the
middle of negotiating
some other books with them
and they of course were like,
Hey,
we've already got these books that
we're looking at. So you know,
we'll put this one on the back burner and
maybe we'll put it out in a year and a
half. It was actually wasn't going
to 14 months. You didn't let me down.
I didn't like that. I didn't like that. So
I said, no, you know, hey, it's all cool,
but I really want to get this one out
very quickly. I want to get this one out.
This was in the summertime. I said,
I want to get this one out by,
I want to get this one out by let's get
the gift, get it to kids by Christmas,
right? This is an important
lesson for kids to learn.
Let's get it to them by Christmas.
Get Out November.
Kids can get it for Christmas and learn.
And they're like,
no. And, and if I go back and forth,
and finally the message I get is I get
message from my children's publisher
because they're focused on other things.
It's the way it is.
They come back and say,
look, there's no scenario,
no scenario where this
book comes out in November.
There's no scenario where that
happens. And I said, Roger, that.
And then I immediately formed
my own publishing company
called Jocko publishing.
I talked to John Bozak who did
the art for the warrior kid books.
And he was like, okay, we're
going, this is due now.
And he went into hyper creation mode.
And did the,
the images are a lot different
than warrior kid because
of their full color and
their take up full pages and their
dragons and Crispin awesome this.
And he laid out the entire book and did
the art and colored it in about a month
and a half. And now the book is
in fact coming out in November.
So in the past when I would talk
about preordering book with, you know,
so you get the first edition whatnot.
And I would always say the publisher
doesn't know it needs to know how many
books to print, which is true.
Now the person, the publisher,
the person that needs to know how
many books to print is actually me.
So if you want to get some,
you need to order it. Uh,
people might think that this is dumb
on my part, which is fun to do this.
This is, it's like a lot of
taking on a lot of extra work.
Probably won't make as much money,
should've done it on the normal polishing
release cycle so you can get more.
Like they have a whole cycle. The way
they average. There's a whole thing.
There's a whole thing to make the book
more popular in all of this stuff. Right.
And I just had to look about it.
The bottom line is,
is I don't really care about
that and I'll tell you what,
after doing book signings and you see
what the warrior kid book does for kids,
I don't care about anything but trying
to get this book into as many kids hands
as possible. If I make
less money, whatever,
if it doesn't make the New York
Times best seller list, whatever,
because this isn't about making money
or it isn't about making the list or
whatever it's,
it's about these kids.
It's about teaching kids a core lesson
at a young age so that they can have a
better life.
Pretty Sturdy,
pretty straightforward aim
goal. Mission. Yes sir.
So if you've got a kid or you know a
kid or you just want to get after it and
support the cause over here of
discipline and justice and strengthen of
overcoming fears because
that's what the book is about,
then jump on Amazon or this book,
it's called Mikey. And the dragons
and I appreciate that cause it'll help
a lot of kids out and that is no matter
what a good thing to do in this world,
no matter what kind of
judgment you want to put,
if you can help out of five year old,
a seven year old,
a four year old little kid,
man,
that's worthwhile to me.
So Mike in the dragons,
do you get get some
now obviously we're going to help some
kids get on the path with that one.
Um,
maybe echo you could recommend
some ways to get the, you know,
basically the masses a little
bit tighter on the path. Yeah.
Can you tell me and keep us on the
path really when it comes down to it,
I liked it. Yeah. So yes.
So obviously well it is obvious.
Like I said last time when we talk
about origin, you know, why? Cause what,
when you think of path we're thinking what
fitness or how should I say capability.
I don't want to see fitness or whatever.
Not just fitness. Yeah. It's like it's
like capability. That's what it is.
Capability and Jujitsu,
which is essentially it under
the umbrella of capability.
Somebody asked me today another interview,
I'm sure,
how do you recommend men?
It was like one of those
men centric interviews.
How do you recommend men
increase their confidence? Yes,
and I thought about it for a second and
I, I was at first I was
kind of like, um, you know,
I don't know that I need
to answer this question.
This is kind of one of those things.
And then I just thought to myself, okay,
realistically,
how do you increase someone's confidence?
Cause it's kind of a throwaway
question in a way, right? Isn't it?
A little bit of a throwaway
question. It's like, Hey,
what magic pill do you
have to increase revenue?
That's the answer that I think
was, was being hoped for. Yeah.
Let's hear Jockos version of it.
How do you increase your confidence?
And let's put that as a, as a damn
bullet point on the Click Bait, right?
Navy seal tells you how to increase
your confidence. Right? Right.
It's a click bait all day long.
So I don't like those kinds of things.
But I thought about it for a
second. I thought to myself, okay,
where does confidence come from?
And then I rattled off. I was like,
well,
first of all,
if you want to be confident,
then you should do things like
exercise and be physically fit.
If you're physically fit, your confidence
will increase. You. Tell me Echo, Charles,
is that factual or or wrong?
That is factual. Okay,
so if you increase your
physical capability,
you'll be more confident.
If you learn how to fight,
if you learn Jujitsu, Muay Thai boxing,
you will become more confident. A,
does that sound like I'm a
meathead? Maybe? Guess what?
It's actually true. Yeah,
it's actually 100% true.
If you're physically capable
and you actually know what
to do with your physical
capability in a confrontational situation,
you will become more confident. Okay,
so there's next. What else? Okay.
How about we learned to articulate
ourselves well. Go. Okay.
Yes.
Will you be more confident?
If you can speak clearly and concisely
and people can understand it? Yes,
you will become more confident. How do
you do that? You practice, you rehearse,
you carry on conversations,
you read a lot so that you have a better
vocabulary once you're done with that.
What comes next?
Well
do we lack confidence if we are
in the unknown? The answer is yes.
How do you get more knowledge?
You study, you read you, you,
you do your best to learn as much as
you can possibly learn and that will
increase your confidence because you'll
be more comfortable and more different
situations cause you have more knowledge.
Yeah.
And the final thing is if you,
one way of getting this as like
a self licking ice cream cone,
what I'm about to say,
but if you have the confidence to say,
I don't know,
your confidence will increase so I can
go and get interviewed by anybody because
worst case scenario I'll say, you
know, I don't know about that. I'm not,
I'm not, I don't actually
don't know anything about that.
I'm going to have to pass on
that question cause I'm not sure.
Am I s is everyone in the world's supposed
to think that Jocko knows everything
in the world or am I,
can I keep,
can I get in my humble enough
to admit that, you know what,
if you quiz me about every subject
in the world, I may not know it.
Is that okay?
It's fine.
No one expects me to be an expert in
anything in definitely not everything.
Like I'm pretty good at a couple things,
but not an expert in anything.
And so if you do those things,
you will become more confident.
Yeah. I thought that was pretty
straightforward. I think so too.
I think that's very, uh,
uh, she's an informative,
they kind of get that kind of makes it
less impactful if I say informative,
but yet, yeah, no. Yeah.
There's also another aspect,
and I guess this is
covered by the other ones,
but like just stepping up
and leading sometimes. Yeah.
We'll get you better at it.
Right. Stepping up and talking in a group
of people, you'll get better at it. Yeah.
So when you say like basically
like practice, rehearse,
rehearse. Absolutely. So the, the
talking to people, that's a big one.
Like you know how someone will,
you'll have like, I don't know,
social anxiety and there's this,
it's a spectrum.
Some people have massive social anxiety,
some people just prefer not a lot of
people be there, you know, kind of thing.
And it's a spectrum. Um, and, and
obviously real comment, right?
So yeah, if you want to increase
confidence, you say, okay,
in regards to the talking part, right? In
articulation practice, talking to people,
like if you go to the store, this is kind
of a little mental exercise. They do.
Do you get a lot done in the grocery
store? Let's hear the mental one.
There's a few things I actually do.
How do we increase confidence as a
drill in the grocery store? Okay. So,
and I kinda got it from like being in
like Oregon and sometimes in Hawaii where,
so in Oregon, right. Okay. So we'll
compare the two scenarios right. In,
in San Diego compared to Oregon in
San Diego. If I go in in the, I dunno,
frozen foods and someone else,
they're kind of in front of the peas,
whatever I'm getting and I'm going to,
I'm going to politely,
hopefully politely wait for
them to finish and leave.
But put bluntly,
that's like,
I'm going to wait for them to get out
of my way and so I can do what I have to
do. And then I'm going to, you know,
in Oregon you go to the frozen food
section and someone else's there,
they're going to look into, hey, it's
almost like an attitude like, hey, here,
here to shoot.
What do you get?
You're getting piece to
write on like kind of like,
it's like they acknowledge
for lack of a better term,
celebrate the fact that you're
sharing space. You know,
like almost at the grocery store,
you don't kind of just put it,
this is my interpretation or the field.
Right.
So I kinda got that lesson
and I'm quite like that too.
But it's more because everyone kind of
knows each other, you know, or you know,
you seen the guy, your AA
and they say hi, that's the,
so what I did was kind
of try to bring that, um,
I really liked it by the way,
the loss, the law spirit.
Um, so now you go in the store and you're
just kind of sharing the same space.
So I'm not saying every single person
you pass, you're bothering them in, hey,
how's your, you know, that
stuff. I'm not saying,
I'm saying if you're sharing their space,
say something to them,
acknowledge them politely.
Right.
Where were you have to
actively expend energy to say
something? Yes, but it's not,
there's this straight from
Dalton what I'm saying,
like actively like engage in their
world right there, you know, so,
and that goes for like kind of everyone
who's sharing space with you and you
know how like you're standing there in
line and you guys are just sort of avoid
eye contact because you're just on your,
your thing and they're on their thing
and we're going to stay out of each
other's way.
It's not like don't play it like that.
Play it like hey like you make eye contact
say is say hi, you know, kind of thing.
It didn't try to do as genuine as possible
obviously cause you don't want them
to think you're going to
catch them outside and sell
them something or something
like that. And then same thing
goes for like the cashier.
Especially if you see him all the time
you use, you don't say the generic, hey,
how are you? Like that kind of yeah,
I dunno. Like make it for real.
Like you care about like, hey,
so how was it today? You know,
cause you know when you're a
cashier you see people after people.
If it gets crowded, that's something.
If it's real debt, that's something.
So you can say, hey, how was
it tonight? Wasn't a crowd.
I do that more than just a random people.
I don't,
I usually leave people alone
because I want to be left alone
in the store. Don't, don't, don't mess
with you. Yes daddy your way, Bro.
Stay out here with no about the cash
register, the, you know, the waitress,
the person behind the whatever
coffee thing or you know,
like I always try and just be nice to
them because I know that they're probably
having a not nice day because when you're
the cash register people are mad at
you already just cause there was a line
and you couldn't find the chocolate chip
discounted coupon thing. And so, you know,
I like to give them a
little acknowledgement that
all good and that there's
actually humans out here that
are in the world and yeah,
well it's the same concept and
I'm just in the, my point is that,
that's just where it Kinda came from.
So the whole point of this is just to
increase your confidence in communicating
with other humans. So when,
when you, when you do that,
the more and more you do that, the
more just, I would say comfortable.
You get just talking to random
people, you know, like just people.
It doesn't have to be your best friend.
And to start opening up a little bit.
Obviously not everything,
but just, just a little bit.
So now you go into a
public place it Brian,
you're no stranger to talking
to strangers anymore, you know,
in the morning where you do it. So yeah,
you get more confident kind of like, Oh,
if this guy what rolls up to me? Yeah.
I have no problem talking to this guy.
I don't have social
anxiety. Yeah. What up, bro?
You want to know how my day's going?
But I'll tell you. How's that? You know?
So it's that feeling and it
helped me while I'm over here.
Why are you looking at me all I my way?
No respite.
The low spirit. Oh cool, cool.
And speaking of Aloha Spirit,
what were we talking about Jujitsu?
Well,
we weren't our confidence because in
order to increase your confidence,
one absolute 100% way to increase
your confidence is to train Jujitsu.
Yes. All Ages. All genders.
Let's just say to say safe for age four
and up age four and up. Yes, correct.
Age for now. Below that is like, there's
exceptions from below. It's play time.
Yeah. Yes. Which just part of what you
just said too, by the way, as a kid. Yeah,
for sure. It should be fun, right?
Think about this as you do this right,
you'll be able to relate to this.
So you know,
like with your friends when you're
young, right? A kid, I don't know,
maybe eight nine,
10 1112 when you 1819 2023 whatever you
do when you're drunk at a party with
your friends,
it's all the same deal.
You guys get in little friendly
arguments and it's go time.
You wrestle in the yard
or in the living room.
Then you went to in a seal platoon, so
you want to, it's on. Exactly right.
And your parents say, hey,
take it outside. It's all
this thing he gets from fight.
I'll sit in the grass or
the dirt, whatever. And you
know who big fights usually.
Sometimes. Yeah, usually the
bigger brother or you know
your friend who's bigger,
usually he's going to get you right.
But it's fun. That's how it always,
it's all fun and maybe you lose
your temper, maybe fight whatever,
all the little brother that can't take
care of the kids and he tries to like
kick you in the nuts, like, you know
what I mean? And you know what I mean?
That kid, I didn't know. It gets
all red in the face, bad temper,
got to look out for himself,
wants to project the power,
even though he's smaller than
everyone else because younger, sure.
That happens occasionally and which
actually fits into what I'm about to say.
So what Jujitsu is, it's basically
that, but the skill that,
that that's required to
win it, that, you know,
so we still have that need
like me and you right now,
your whole point is to say that just
do fun. Yes. Yeah. Agreed. Okay.
So now you've got to unpack
it because it's like,
you can see there's a lot
of things that are fun.
The thing is, but they didn't
know what kind of fun, you
know. So if I say, hey, um,
you know, actually it's more fun
than that. Well, here's the fun.
It's fun in a whole different level.
Right.
Well hear this though because it's fun
because you're connecting things together
that are part of a like grand,
right? It's like being a musician.
It's like, Hey, here's the ref. Well,
yes there's that 100% but I think
just as a fundamental kind of,
I don't want to say need
but want is like bro,
like see how you're even
looking at me right now,
like where I kind of want
to fight you right now.
I don't want to like fight you like,
but I kind of want to fight you
as a friend. Like do you want to take it
on the match right now? Kind of thing.
Like if we're like 10 years
old, he'd be like, what?
You want to take it outside
and throw you as friends?
But that's all did you get to really is
that's really what it is. It's like, yeah,
let's go on the mat and let's basically
fight in a way that we don't burn our
each other's bridges and not be friends
anymore. And then, but on top of that,
it's like they teach you the skill to do
that. That can literally save your life.
Oh yeah. Literally at a minimum it will
increase your confidence as a human,
as a human being. Yes sir. Sometimes it
gives you too much cost. Too much. Yes.
Especially early on,
especially if you're 13, 15,
21,
20 [inaudible] you start thinking you
could just smash everybody nonetheless.
So if you're training Jujitsu when you
change it, well if you're on the path,
that might be good too.
If you need you to gear,
which you do need some Jujitsu gear,
you need it what's called a [inaudible].
If you need to g you can get a
[inaudible] from our company,
which is based here in America.
And we make gies all American from the
ground up from the dirt through it's
called origin main, best [inaudible]
ever in the world to ever,
ever in the history.
And if you need rash guards,
which you can use for Jujitsu,
you can also use them for weightlifting.
You can use them for running
and cycling, cycling, surfing,
uh, guitar playing. It might not
have, might not be necessary.
I do not wear rash guard
when I play guitar.
Maybe I should maybe and those are also
made here in America along with what
else?
Just regular clothes too,
like shirts and you know some athletic
wear but the shorts that I wear,
I only wear, well I have one pair of like
random, I'm old shorts. Oh by the way,
I'm going to get you some,
we got some new shorts coming and you're
going to be very excited about these
shorts. Well I already am because
every sin, even the error,
the mistake shorts that they made when
they were my favorite shirts literally
ever. And then they came out with
deliberate that they can actually
sell. Not No, those are my
favorite shorts. So yeah you
say it or because he know,
I bet Pete he cares.
You don't care about the fashion
stuff but they fashion subtleties.
Nothing to do with fit, fit style.
But it's subtle though. Anyway,
they got a bunch of stuff on there,
a clothing wise as well,
like joggers and and you like the
joggers and then they got supplements.
We got supplements. Sure. We got
supplements. We've got joint warfare.
We got do you want word for is good. If
you're working out, if you're on the path,
your joints are going to take a beating.
Joint Warfare will protect
them and heal them.
A krill oil. Another good
one. Discipline. Good.
Pre-Operational get some,
get your mind right real quick.
Get your body right. And then of course
we have a little something called Malke.
Yes sir. We do. What is milk? Really
simple. It's smoke. Smoke. Yeah.
So you know, um, you
know, coa. The kid, yeah.
Happens to be my cousin.
He's on the path. Oh,
the beginnings of the path
taking the first step.
Trustingly got on the multi train as
the first step. That's an interesting,
interesting.
But here's why though,
when you're not really technically on
the path and you just drink Mulkey just
think you're drinking a milkshake.
See what I'm saying it for the taste.
And that's a point.
Which is good though because it will
keep you on the path in regards to that
additional protein that
you're going to get.
The original flavor was mint chocolate.
My favorite.
We went to peanut butter from there
available then vanilla gorilla.
I don't like plain vanilla. I don't,
I just don't like, I don't want to,
I don't want to eat vanilla
anything like you unless,
unless I'm meeting with
some damn chocolate cake.
I'm not going to order
vanilla ice cream ever.
The other day when you
had a cake situation,
cake scenario in some ice cream and ice
cream, it was vanilla. There you go.
And that whole scenario, just on
the folded wrong, it really did.
I just rationalized the whole
thing. Lied to myself. Just again,
just got after it. But what?
Well here's what bummed me out.
As soon as I was done I was like,
well I was on the road, no milk.
So when you don't have dessert,
sometimes you get that little, oh,
I'd like a little something that
tastes good too to wash down the stake.
That's a good state. And then, and then
there's no milk cause I'm on the road.
I got to figure that out.
People give me good suggestions. I know
I can put a little baggy in the thing.
And just grab some milk
somewhere, mix it up, no factor.
So I need to start doing that. Uh,
nonetheless. You don't like vanilla,
so no vanilla is not my favorite flavor.
The Vanilla tastes good.
I was not the judge on the vanilla.
You know,
Pete and Brian were like
a, the is awesome. I said
I'll try it. It tastes fine.
I'm not the judge cause I don't want
to judge something that I don't fully
comprehend. I'm not deserving
of being a vanilla judge.
So therefore I didn't do it. And,
but the darkness, which is chocolate,
the darkness that is
also freaking delicious.
And when you're getting this stuff,
you'll be getting it from origin main.
You got to Cindy up there. You met Cindy.
Of course she's fired up.
So when you're getting your stuff packed,
it's not just being,
it's not just being randomly
placed in a box by a robot.
No, Cindy's up there. She's getting after
it. And I'm going to say one more thing.
Little announced announcement.
Little announcement. So you,
you remember when you were a little kid?
Yes.
And you loved chocolate milk?
And he loves strawberry milk
being loved it so much, whatever,
whatever little brand name that you got.
And there was a couple of them that were
prominent and they tasted delicious and
it was like desert. And for some reason
you didn't really understand why,
but your parents would actually
allow you to drink it all the time
because your parents thought,
well you know,
it's kind of milking it so
it's gotta be good to go.
It'll make their bones strong and
just a little protein in there,
so we'll just let them drink it.
What they didn't realize is that little
chocolate and strawberry milk that you
were drinking as a kid is completely
filled with sugar and high fructose corn
syrup and a bunch of other chemicals
that they couldn't even pronounce.
And so the milk that your parents,
my parents were allowing me to drink was
actually a freaking net loss overall to
my health because it was
filled with poison, but it
tasted good and you loved it.
It was like a dessert you
could have all the time,
but it was filled with poison.
So you know, we did, we fixed it.
We fixed it and we now have
available at this time warrior kid.
Yes, Warrior kid milk. We made
chocolate and we made strawberry.
Just like you remember when you were a
kid only instead of having a bunch of
garbage in it, it's got protein,
extra protein, 12 grams.
It's got vitamins that you need.
It's got probiotics because kids
are getting told all the time they,
their parents are getting told they need
to take probiotics and here take this
pill and that pill,
no take warrior kid moke
and there's no sugar in it
and it tastes freaking amazing.
So
it's better than any other
of these flavored whatever
chocolate milk you grew up
on,
this taste better.
So now your or your kid out
there can get on the milk train.
It's awesome.
And again,
for me to see kids and be able to
help out kids that are four years old,
six years old, eight years old, to
give them something that's healthy,
that tastes good, that's going to
make them stronger and healthier.
I mean this is what it's all about.
So
order up some warrior kid milk
for your children available.
Now my kid's going straight on the mock
trial. Yeah, for sure. One way ticket.
Does that apply when we
take it on? Yeah. Yeah.
You understand what it was
to totally fully the Vanessa.
Speaking of which my son, two years old,
by the way, I liked the vanilla as more.
I didn't know.
I'm like,
should I give my son that
much additional protein?
You know,
you even questioned that.
I just don't know a lot of things, you
know as far in regards to either way, so,
okay. Yes. Kids on milk train on
the path. Kids are on the path. Yes.
Straight and want to be at that book
signing there. There wasn't many.
There weren't many kids. They're the
ones that I did on the east coast.
Lots of kids in, tons of kids. All of
them on the path fired up, man. It was,
it was amazing. Every kid there
last night at was not in the path.
Huge time.
One kid literally tried to challenge
me to a Jujitsu match on more than one
occasion and I'm not even joking like for
real attitude, which I dug by the way.
I mean I couldn't engage
them cause you know,
I mean you're getting all
this challenge me double
get away. Okay. Kids on the
vessel, which brings me to our uh,
store Jocko has a store, it's
called Jocko store. Right.
Pretty straight forward. Anyway, there is,
there are where your kid rash
guards for when they joined Jujitsu.
No Geek part of it.
Rash guards on there.
There's obviously where he could shirts
if they're in the geek part of it.
That's cool. You got to origin
main.com and you get him,
you get him the warrior [inaudible] get
some boom and also new edition for where
are your kids patches on there right
now if you went literally right now you
live eye patches for
your g for your backpack,
obviously, wherever you
want to put it. But yeah,
the little round one and long kind of
Jujitsu and made kind of four digits you,
but you can put it wherever want anyway.
Yeah.
It's on [inaudible] dot com also on
Jocko store.com is where you can get your
shirts,
disciplining freedom.
This is one of the thing about
shirts is everyone wears shirts. Yes.
Even if you don't want to wear one, which
I don't like wearing a shirt. Hell no,
but I you sometimes you got to wear
a shirt. Everyone needs a shirt.
Might as well be you. Kind of a cool
one. Might as little reminders. Yeah,
big time and truckers hats.
Chuck has hands on them.
Just completely stoked on my discipline
equals freedom hat or the def core hats
out yet the difficult cats are should
be done. Are they live? I don't know.
Okay.
I got there was,
there was a technical thing where
like the logo and get, you know,
cause hats have panels, a certain
amount of panels and you know the logo.
Does it fit on this dis,
does it go on the scene or do we need
a different panel hat now anyway,
it's very tactical. Well, but
nonetheless the DEF core hat is out soon.
That's deep representing right there.
What about the deaf court shirt? Is there
a pure def course shirt? Black cops. Ah,
yes.
And then
I was thinking a one called def core
declassified. It's just white on white,
whatever. Black out. You see what
I'm saying? Anyway? Well, you know.
Yeah. You know, I'm going
to have to ask that.
We all kind of just kinda
checked back on that one.
Maybe it's like maybe
it's not none the less.
If you go there and you
want to represent hardcore,
that's where you can get your shirt or
Hoodie new hoodie on the way, by the way.
Oh yeah. Duty heavy duty,
heavy duty techniques.
This better be good.
That's the thing.
Anyway, hoodies on there. A
lot of cool stuff on there.
Oh, and I did the research.
Who, what? What's better? What do people
literally, what do people like better?
Flex fit hat. Oh, trucker
hat. Even even Steven. Okay,
cool.
Actually there's like,
I think two more people historically
speaking like the snap back,
so technically you're
right. Yes. Nonetheless.
We've got some rash guards in there
as well. Also, we got on the podcast,
subscribe to it wherever. No, don't
forget the warrior kid podcast.
A lot of people don't know about that yet.
So spread the word on the warrior kid
podcast will questions from uncle Jake for
Uncle Jake and little stories from Uncle
Jake about how he developed his sort of
values in the world.
That's the warrior kid bond cast,
the warrior kids soap from Irish
oaks ranch.com at young Aden,
the warrior kid milking goats,
making soap,
getting after it,
order some of that so you can stay clean.
Also youtube checkout echos,
legit enhanced videos,
which some people like
some people like them.
Most people I'd say like you don't get a
lot of thumbs down on your videos. Yeah,
the annual, what I like is when
someone funds down your video, there's,
there's multiple people in the
comments that'll be like, Ooh,
well down this aisle communist.
So that's good.
We've got some plans for the youtube
going to step it up a little bit. Yeah,
a little bit more I should say, cause
he was stepped it up a little bit. Yeah,
we're gonna step it up a little bit more.
Yeah.
I think videos just in general are
like fun to watch and it could be just
speaking for myself,
but I would tend to agree with you and
also psychological warfare working on
album number two, psychological warfare.
We're aiming for a Christmas release.
If you have any suggestions, hit
me up on Twitter. In the meantime,
you got the psychological
warfare one album,
which can help you get through
whatever little moments of weakness.
I wish I had it the other day for that
cake and my brain with ice cream to watch
out for that.
It was good about that. You
learn, it seemed like anyway,
according to your post and you that you
learned a little lesson and you're open
about it too. Yeah. That's good. Yeah.
It can't be like hiding your
failures in an actor like no,
cause I'm saying because I'm human. Yeah.
Yeah. Anyone that thinks I'm not human,
you're wrong.
I'm all too human.
I get tapped out in
Jujitsu I get and what?
You know what I mean?
I mean it's like, yeah,
hey and you pound huge pieces of the cake.
We every once in awhile
cake with ice cream.
So disappointed in myself any way.
Stay on the path is what I'm saying.
I'm also,
if you're,
if you're incorporating kettle bell
workouts in various ring workouts,
I'll tell you where you can get them.
Get them from on it on
it.com/jocko by the way,
I incorporate rings every single day.
Every single day.
You're all on the ring for ads and core
power. It's good and I can't quite,
I can almost do pull ups again.
Oh look my bicep or whatever.
But muscle ups coming to
Muslims coming in action.
Know that honestly my shoulders
getting back up to speed. Yeah.
Cause it went through a
little down period. Then it
got, then it got the healed.
Now that I tweaked it again
doing something stupid.
You know what I did? Yeah.
I eat ice cream. That's good.
You know I didn't do that.
I edit a massive numbers of weighted
dips super deep and in a mess up you
shoulder messed up my
shoulder. Oh okay. That was,
that was like six months ago or something.
And he was a long time ago dealing with
it. But finally it's coming back around.
Yeah. And shoulders pain
in the ass, man. Yeah.
You've got to make do the maintenance
man and you've got to do the maintenance
and I don't do enough of it. Need to do
more of it. Yeah, yeah, yeah. But yeah,
go there.
That's the,
you can get some cool workout stuff and
actually good travel workout stuff too.
Like those written, well you
already said this. I know,
but I'm slowly come to
the realization that you,
when you travel with rings but opens
up your whole travel game changer.
Game Changer.
You know if you're working out too,
when you're working on that dead lift,
one thing you can do is if you probably,
if you're stuck at like a 4,000 pound dead
lift plateau, no, we can't accept that.
Get Jocko white tea and
it comes with a guarantee.
I don't know what kind of guarantee.
So you can deadlift 8,000
pounds immediately. Probably
take you like four sips.
Yeah.
If you can't define,
if you can't deadlift 8,000 pounds
after drinking Jocko white tea,
either the ones in a can
or the ones in a teabag,
uh,
that you can get them on Amazon.
If you can't think your deadlift
isn't 8,000 pounds after that,
just drink more and you'll get
there. Yes. Also got some books.
Obviously the way the warrior kid books
that the first one way of the warrior
kid. The second one is Mark's mission,
which is the best book. And I'm going,
if I'm going to say it,
I'm going to say it's a bold statement
and in fact I was debating whether or not
to actually say it out loud.
That's the best book in the world.
Straight up March mission mission.
The second one.
You okay. So I'm reading it to buy,
we've just finished it a week ago.
Oh is this your first time finishing it?
Finishing it yet. Okay. Well we could.
Interesting. Interesting. So, um,
well cause we jumped around to
another book and it's a long story,
but nonetheless. Yeah.
So finished it. Right.
So you know why though now
that I'm searching my feelings,
it starts to address a little bit more
sophisticated issues that you can go
through. You know, even though when you
think you got it figured out, you know,
you're taking Jujitsu now and you can do
pull ups and all this stuff or what are
you sort of address those a
little bit more advanced issues.
Sophisticated but like the depth of which
like these issues go and the way you
got to solve them or like the way it's
simplified in broken down to kids or to
whoever's reading it because quite frankly
it's broken down to me in this case,
um, is like, it's pretty, we'll
just say it's pretty interesting,
but at the same time it, you glorify
things like hard work, right?
In a way that it actually makes
the kid want to work hard.
You know what I'm saying? So
it's like, yeah, getting a job,
like go mow lawns and pull weeds
by the way, which if we, you know,
we all know that when you did that
as a kid, you're like, no bro,
we don't want to do that. Is
a form of punishment. Yeah.
And my house exactly right. This
time after reading that part, um,
my daughter, by the way, she
wants to pull weeds. She's,
she's salty cause she doesn't have a job
mowing lawns and pulling weeds. Yeah.
And he makes work for, he's like,
he's like $40. I made $40. Right.
Like exclamation point. She's like, oh my
gosh, you made $40. I want to make $40.
You know, just the way it's laid out,
how simple. But you know, I'm really,
I'm getting into it and it, I see
it affecting it, um, my daughter.
So then it moves onto the Jujitsu part
and this part affected me. You know,
it's like,
well let's face it.
That's why when you get nervous in
Jujitsu with tournaments or whatever,
like there was a,
I remember when I was competing and
strangely I was competing a lot too.
Like maybe two, three weeks.
There was a tournament back then.
Wasn't as often as no, but,
um, and I would be competing,
but every single one seems
like we're driving there.
And if like my wife who was, I
think my girlfriend at the time, um,
and my brother, whoever was driving it
was, if they're talking about other stuff,
I'm like getting mad at him cause
I'm like told, you realize man,
it's like that idea, you know? And
I'm like, I don't behave that way.
But that's what's been
on my mind and tangible.
Small but tangible part of my mind is
like hoping that like the Jim Burke down
when we got there, like I just don't want
to, you know, it's like that, it's weird.
But then the way like you lay out
because mark didn't want to compete in a
tournament. Right. And the way
you lay out and you really,
it's a call out is what it is. It's like
you're calling out. He's like, I'm afraid.
But it's like you're not afraid of
Jujitsu. You do Jiu Jitsu every day,
full speed by the way. And you're not
afraid of juice. You're afraid of losing.
And guess what? Those things,
okay. It really hit me anyways.
And then from there to me
from then on it was like,
and how it culminate has good man. It's
straight out the best book in the world.
I'll give it to you. Don't want
to, but nevermind. Cormac McCarthy,
nevermind about where the warrior king,
they also got the discipline
equals freedom field manual.
How to get after it for adults.
And actually a lot of kids read this book.
That's where they graduate.
They graduate from Warrior Kid. I talked
to a lot of parents and they're like,
oh yeah,
once you know,
now he's 14 he just read discipline
equals freedom field manual.
So that's the,
that's the graduate.
Can Imagine if you had that book when
you were 14 game changer, game changer.
Right. Anyone, and I'll tell you
right now the warrior, that one,
yeah, yeah. No, the feedback
that I get from it, but the,
it's the same kind of
feedback I get from the kids,
from the field manual of
people that are like, hey,
I read this every day.
I read two pages this every day so I
can keep my mind right. Yeah. That,
and that's how that works.
Like that's the one you refer it back to
everyday or every other day or whatever.
That's their guy.
Hit me up on Twitter.
Remember that story I told about being
a Yosemite and the dude was in the river
and he's like, I was like, oh.
He recognized me and I was getting
all fired up with him and he was like,
I'm here to get my mind right.
I was like, year. Anyways, guys,
friend hit me up on Twitter and that
dude's name is meth. That's his name.
His name is math. Math, math. I. M.
E. T. H. Like the dried up. Yeah.
Got It. Well, he was not a meth user.
It just happens to be his
name. Gotcha. Uh, okay.
Then also extreme ownership.
Obviously that's the first book wrote
with my brother Leif Babin and we followed
that book up very recently with a book
called the dichotomy of leadership.
There's a million interviews on it
we talked about on this podcast.
That book is going to really help leaders
finish out strong and then of course
coming out November,
order it now,
Mikey and the dragons echelon front.
That's my leadership consultancy. We solve
problems through leadership. It's me,
it's life. Babin. It's JP Denelle.
It's Dave Berg. It's Flint Cochran,
Mike's Rally and Mike Bama.
Don't call a speaking agency.
If you want us to come and
talk to you or your company,
email us info@echelonfront.com muster
zero zero six in San Francisco,
October 17th and 18th,
uh, sold out. Sorry,
last thing we've got f Overwatch,
which is connecting Spec ops,
veterans and companies that need
experienced the leaders ready to go.
If you're a company that needs leadership,
leadership that understands and operates
when within the principles of extreme
ownership,
go to e f overwatch.com if you're a
SPEC ops that if you're a former combat
aviator,
go to e f overwatch.com and we
will connect you two together
and if anyone out there has
questions or answers or for us,
you can find us out
there on the interwebs.
Twitter on Instagram and on dad based e
Echo is an echo.
Charles and I am at jockowillink
and thanks to all military police,
law enforcement, correctional
officers, firefighters, border patrol,
paramedics, all first
responders. It was great meeting.
So many of you at roll call.
It was,
it was just awesome to meet you all and
did a bunch of the other events I've
done in the past couple of weeks
that book signings and whatnot,
knowing that you all are out there
holding the line and watching our six in
protecting our flanks is awesome.
And it'll tell you what I
do not take it for granted.
I do not take it for granted that
you're there and no one should.
So thanks to you all for doing what you
do and for everyone else that is out
there.
Remember the way and remember that you
can use it everywhere in everything that
you do.
So find the enemies weak points,
attack the enemy violently.
Be Bold and decisive,
seize and hold the initiative.
Keep the enemy under constant
pressure and off balance,
and be fully prepared to accomplish the
mission regardless of the conditions
under which the war begins.
And of course you do all those
things by stepping out into the fray
and getting after it.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jocko.