This is Jocko podcast number
53 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
At what point
do you quit?
did you give in?
At what point do you surrender and
what is it that makes you surrender?
The enemy
fatigue, hunger, thirst,
bitter cold.
Who are these men
that decide
that they will not
surrender no matter what?
What will,
what humans will do?
They have,
yeah,
that they decide they are going to
fight on no matter what they face.
Well,
I will tell you these men,
amen.
They're human beings like you like me,
human beings that decide they're going
to fight on despite being surrounded by
the enemy.
Despite the hunger and the danger
and the thirst and the bitter cold,
they decide they will not surrender.
Yeah,
and we can find examples of
these men throughout history.
But one of the four most examples
comes from the Korean War
in late November and into mid December
of 1950 when 30,000 UN troops,
mostly American,
we're surrounded by 120,000
communist Chinese forces
in these Americans were attacked, attacked
by the enemy, and attacked by the,
the bitter, freezing cold and
attacked by hunger and fear.
And yet they would not and
they did not surrender.
Or tonight we're going to hear from a
lieutenant in the United States Marine
Corps, Joseph R, O,
n who served as a mortar section
commander for Baker Company,
First Seventh Marine Regiment,
First Marine Division.
Okay.
In his book,
which is called colder than hell.
And the book starts off with one of the
best short overviews of the Korean War
I've ever read, likely because it's
written by a man who was there,
a man named General Raymond
Davis. Ray Davis, who,
first of all,
he was a battalion commander in World
War II at the battle of Pellalou awarded
the Navy Cross there for leading his
men against overwhelming Japanese fire.
And in Korea he was
awarded the Medal of honor
as well as two silver stars,
a Legion of Merit,
and a bronze star
as the commander of the first
battalion seventh marines.
Okay.
And beyond that,
he also served as the third
marine division commander
in Vietnam in 1969 where
he was awarded the Navy Distinguished
Service Medal and three republic of
Vietnam Gallantry Crosses.
So when he speaks,
I think maybe we should listen.
Yeah.
And I'm going to start with that
forward by General Davis in the book,
Colder Than Hell.
My Joe,
twice in 1950 during the first
months of the Korean War,
the United States faced
military catastrophe.
Both situations occurred because of
American errors of diplomacy and faulty
intelligence.
And because our military was not prepared
to meet a determined enemy on the
battlefield,
North Korea and China where the
enemies that exploited our failings
on two occasions that year,
they caught us by surprise,
launching massive attacks first
against our allies, South Korea,
and that against our
own inadequate forces.
Yeah.
Both times the consequences
were devastating.
There were tragic numbers of casualties
in the ranks of our soldiers.
And Marines and American prestige
worldwide was severely impaired.
The surprise invasion of South Korea by
North Korea with a supportive communist
China and the Soviet Union was a virtually
invited by the United States in the
South Koreans.
South Korea was vulnerable.
It's soldiers were ill-equipped,
poorly trained and improperly deployed.
The American forces at that time,
victims of Washington politics and
false economies were nearly as bad off
following the end of world
war two drown draw down.
They were in skeletonized formation.
Sad be undertrained and
inadequately equipped.
So there's a little warning for us today.
You need somebody.
Somebody asked me that question,
what's your foreign policy?
Can you say it in 140 characters?
Somebody asked me that on Twitter.
I answered it in one word. My
foreign policy, his strength.
This is why.
Okay,
back to the book.
Moreover,
our secretary of State had proclaimed to
the world that the Korean Peninsula was
outside the area of American
vital interests. North Korea,
China and the Soviet Union read that
message to mean that the United States
would not defend South Korea
against outside aggression.
South Korea would be
theirs for the taking.
We now know of messages exchanged between
Joseph Stalin and the North Korean
President Kim Il Sung that explored our
weakness and concluded that South Korea
could be captured in five days.
Subsequently,
the North Koreans launched a sudden and
massive invasion solve the North Korean
capital.
It's quickly taken and soon all that
country was overrun except for one small
pocket around the port of Pusan.
That pocket was formed by American troops
on ready as they were that President
Harry Truman hurried into Korea in
response to the crisis at great sacrifice.
These American soldiers with a follow
on brigade of marines held the Pusan
perimeter long enough to allow forces
to assemble for an amphibious assault on
Incheon behind the North Korean lines.
We recaptured soul and the North
Koreans were put on the run.
Okay.
Fearing entrapment,
they fled back across their border to
the North American and South Korean
troops.
We're joined by soldiers from other
United Nations countries and pursued the
aggressors deep into North Korea.
Our mission was to fold,
to punish the North Koreans and to block
the Chinese People's Liberation Army.
If it threatened to enter the war?
Yeah.
Because of a failure of intelligence.
However,
we were far too late to deter the Chinese.
They had already positioned vast numbers
of their well trained soldiers in the
mountains of North Korea.
We were sued under heavy attack,
fighting a numerically superior enemy
in unfavorable terrain and blue brutally
cold weather.
The UN forces predominantly American
were chased out of North Korea.
Okay.
At the chosen, whereas of war where
we were outnumbered 10 to one,
the Chinese generals prematurely boasted
of the destruction of the First Marine
Division.
Yet the opposite happened there.
Although the marines
were forced to withdraw,
we destroyed several Chinese divisions
as we fought our way to the sea and to
escape.
Our withdrawal was a successful one,
but we paid a terrible price.
Casualties reduced the division
to nearly half its strength.
The three rifle companies at first
battalion seventh Marine Regiment,
which I was privileged to command and
dirt losses of even greater proportions.
My battalion had been hastily activated
in response to President Truman's urgent
call to action.
It was a thrown together rifle company,
a collection of regulars gathered from
marine corps posts and stations all over
the world and reservists mostly untrained
who were suddenly called from their
homes, jobs, schools with
only a few days of training.
Okay.
They were embarked aboard a ship heading
across the Pacific and thrown into
combat.
They had to learn to
fight while under fire.
They're saving grace was that they were
led by disciplined officers and NCOC who
showed them by upfront example
how to fight like marines,
although they suffered casualties that
proper preparation would have avoided.
They learned well and they
hardened and define rifle company.
No North Korean or Chinese force ever
stopped them from taking it objective or
overcame their position.
Let us do all we can to assure that no
future generation of young Americans need
to go to war unprepared
as were those heroes who
went to Korea in 1950
and again,
that is the foreword of the book,
which was written by General Raymond
Davis, Medal of honor winner.
And like I said,
the book is written by
Joe Oh and Joseph Owen,
who was marine corps officer.
And
let's continue on.
And now we start hearing from
Joe and they're at Camp Lejeune,
North Carolina. Nobody at Camp
Lajune had expected a shooting war.
We nor we were ready for one.
So they're, they're, they're,
they're just kind of peace time,
peace, time, marines, you know,
kind of doing their
thing and all of a sudden
the North Koreans attack and here we go.
They're all sitting around listening
to the radio, a bunch of marines.
The announcer continued
more than 2000 Americans,
military advisers and civilian workers
and their families are said to be in the
path of North Koreans.
Surprise, aggression.
Their fate is unknown at this time.
American involvement in the
new war is not clear war.
Yeah.
The possibility of American marines
in a combat role. Excited us.
So these guys are young, not all of them.
There's, there's, there's definitely,
we're gonna run into many World War
II veterans, but the young kids,
they don't know. They want to get
after it there. They're fired up.
They're so fired up back to the book.
One story alleged that a commando force
of volunteers was forming up for an
immediate commitment to battle.
Yeah.
That one tied up phone lines on the base.
As we tried to track down the commando
headquarters in order to volunteer.
They're all ready to rock and roll
now. Then they start seeing what,
what's beginning to occur.
They see that we're surrounded.
They see that we're kind of getting
the North Koreans are getting the best,
if not routing back to the book.
Americans at home were stunned
by reports that their army,
the conqueror of the mighty Germany
and Japan only five years before was
outnumbered,
outgunned and out fought by
the upstart North Koreans.
Yeah.
General Macarthur called for a full
division of Marines to help him turn back
the North Koreans.
The Marine Corps welcomed the call,
but we did not have a full division to
put in the field like all the services.
The core had been stripped of men and
weapons in order to reduce itself to the
level of the 1930s
both the first and second marine
divisions were less than half strength.
The core would need to draw men from
guard detachments to ships companies and
posts and stations throughout the world,
but it still wouldn't find
enough troops to fill a division.
President Truman thus authorize the
commandant of the Marine Corps to call up
the reserves,
so it was,
again, this is a warning
as a nation and as a,
as an individual cumin,
don't let down your guard.
Peacetime will not last
and the weaker you look,
the sooner the peacetime we'll end.
Now they get the orders
standby to ship out
on the Saturday evening before we left
Camp Lejune Dorothy, so that's Joe's wife.
Dorothy hired a babysitter and we
went to the officer's Club for dinner.
There were candles out at our table
which was covered in white linen and set
with heavy silverware.
The food was delicious and plentiful and
I would think about it often in Korea
when my men and I were hungry and cold
that night,
Dorothy's hair glistened like gold and
the candle light and her eyes smiled
bright and blue and warm.
We danced and laughed with the
other lieutenants and their wives.
Yeah.
For some of the couples
are closest friends.
There was the last night they
would ever have together.
So they depart lagoon and they
show up at Camp Pendleton,
California and they get
to Camp Pendleton and he,
they will,
we'll talk more about this,
but camp Pendleton is a,
believe it or not,
it's on the coast of California and there
some pretty aggressive hills in Calif
in Camp Pendleton,
which I've spent many nights on
cause we would work up there and uh,
they,
they can,
they can turn some soft men into some
hard men pretty quickly or break men if
they're too weak.
So back to the book,
our ranks were filled by 215 men and
seven officers who had never before served
together. Half of our enlisted men
were infantry trained regulars.
The other half were reservists,
most of whom were youngsters who knew,
knew little of marine infantry
and its method methods.
Five weeks after we first
formed up at Camp Pendleton,
we went into the attack against North
Korean soldiers who were dug into a hill
north of Seoul.
And we had spent half of that time
on board ship on the way to war.
So let me break that down to you.
They have five weeks,
so five weeks from when they form up,
five weeks later they're attacking
North Korean troops. So just Fyi,
for a seal platoon that's going to Iraq,
we used to work up for a full year.
This is after we went through seal
training and after we went through seal
qualification training,
and after all the guys show up the team
and go to special schools and then you
get formed up into a platoon, you have
an unbelievable workup to prepare. And,
and the Marine Corps does this too. I
mean the army, everyone does this now.
That's the amount of preparation
that it takes to prepare for combat.
And here are these guys five
weeks of which, what was it?
Half that time is spent on a ship
just sailing over there. Hmm.
Unbelievable. Back to the book, The Sun,
scorched hills of Camp Pendleton had over
the years tough in the legs and tested
the spirits of thousands of
America's best fighting men.
One of those towering hills loomed
across the road from our training site,
so again,
you want to get tough,
get on some hills with a rucksack on your
back that that will do it to you and I
guess I kind of included those little
sections about Camp Pendleton hills for my
pleasure and thinking about those hills.
Awesome.
Back to the book.
They're going through,
they're going through this training
and they're getting ready to deploy and
we'll go back to the book now.
Dorothy took $75 of our scant resources
and bought an airline ticket from
Syracuse to San Diego each night
after we had dismissed the troops,
bill and I,
this is Bill Graybar,
he's another one of the officer's
bill and I caught a ride to the hotel
restaurants in the little village of
San Clemente. We're closed that late,
but Dorothy would have a
cold supper waiting for me.
Then we would stroll to the beach and
listen to the waves crash across the sand.
During those walks we talked about the
babies and we made plans for my return
from Korea.
My next assignment.
I assured her would give us at least
two years at a good duty station.
Maybe I would be senior enough for us
to rate decent quarters in the mornings
early.
It's still dark bill Graybar and I would
grab a ride back to camp with the other
officers.
Everyone except the driver's slept all
the way crowded against each other and
the tight seats of the car.
We were very tired but we were young
men and we did dearly love our beautiful
wives
and you're going to see throughout this
book that even though his wife was not
with him,
she was with him the whole time.
I like many spouses are when guys are
deployed overseas and now they are on
board the ship.
The ship is getting ready to
pull out of the San Diego Bay.
Back to the book. The wives remained on
the dock long after we had gone aboard.
The sqirl of bagpipes
sounded as we wave to them.
Pfc Timmy Killeen Able Company stood on
the fan tail of the oak can outgun and
his bagpipes filled the feeding
afternoon with the marines.
Hymn handkerchiefs flooded from the
dock and the ship's horn blasted.
We were underway.
There were tears,
but marines and marine wives aren't
ashamed of tears when they're him plays.
Okay.
So now they're heading over to Korea.
They're in cramped quarters.
I've done a couple deployments
on board ships and there's,
and fibia ships is what they're called.
And these ships were meant to
take people overseas, don't.
The ones that I deployed on were,
were what drove us,
what drove soldiers to Vietnam. We used
to deploy on those ships for six months,
but it's just really cramped.
You know, their basic,
you're basically like a cattle car,
a giant cattle car ship,
and they just pack everyone on there.
It's really tight and uh,
there's not much to do on there, but
you know, you take a bunch of marines,
you put them on a ship and they figure
something out. Back to the book.
Staff Sergeant Richard revealed
himself to be an all purpose NCO and an
acquisition specialist.
One day he produced a set of boxing
gloves and the men of Baker one seven
immediately became avid pugilists
okay.
For three exuberant rounds to
the delight of the company,
the little bull by folk and the little
gorilla Lupa cine engaged in mutual
annihilation.
When Sergeant Richard claimed his
mess gear to end the Bra, the troops,
and much of the ship's crew
or an a cheering frenzy,
it had been a grand fight.
Both men were covered in
blood at bruisers bruises,
and at the final clang they wrapped
arms and leaned against each other.
Exhausted my mortar men
swarmed into the square,
pummeling by folk with
congratulations Perkins,
who had been holding by forks,
glasses,
placed them carefully
over his swollen eyes.
I saw Burris then gently guide
by fork out of the ring. Gino,
Brian Lupa,
Chinese platoon sergeant followed with
his man and Baker one seven we're still
whistling and cheering when
the two fighters and their
handlers went through the
hatch and down the ladder to sick bay.
Joe Casaba stood next to me,
so go joke,
or is one of the platoon
commanders stood next to me.
This outfit is coming together.
He said Joe rarely smiled,
but there was a big grin on his
face after that fight. So there's
you. You notice that in these
stories about combat wrestling,
fighting, boxing, there
is something to it.
There is something to it
that bonds men together.
Fact,
back to the book when we
weren't on deck with the troops,
the officer spent the waking
hours around the wardroom table,
so the wardroom ownership is where
the officer's eat. Captain Wilcox now,
this is the introduction,
introduction to Captain Wilcox.
He's the company commander and
he's a a vet from EOL Jima,
Captain Wilcox,
lettuce.
In review of the principles and
lessons of the of rifle company combat,
he and Joker Saba use their
own battle experience.
As experiences has illustration,
they focused on the chaos of combat
and how the best laid plans always
disintegrated under enemy fire.
That's why we got to
keep our plants simple.
Hmm.
War is hell.
Captain Wilcox who had much
experience at it would tell us,
but you never know what particular
kind of hell it is going to be.
We studied the after actions report
that had come from the fifth marines.
The North Koreans they had faced
were tough skilled fighters.
Every bit is tenacious in battle as the
Japanese had been in the bitter Pacific
island fighting of the last war,
the red soldiers,
fifth marines called them gluecks.
We're well trained in the Russian
style of combat with effective use of
supporting armor,
mortars and artillery.
They were men who also were
adept at night fighting.
Fighting at night was a combat
skill we had yet to learn.
We would do so under fire
and at a terrible cost.
So Joe Owen is actually,
he's not a platoon commander,
he is a,
he's the mortar section commander.
So in a company of, yeah,
call it 200 200 marines,
there's multiple rifle platoons,
maybe 40 guys,
50 guys in each one of
those rifle platoons.
And then there's a little
section of mortar guys.
And mortars aren't indirect fire weapons.
So for those of you that
don't know anything about
mortars, mortars, shoot rounds,
they're there. You see him
in movies, there's a tube,
they're basically a tube and they're
at a really high angle and the,
and you drop rounds into it and they fire
at a very high altitude and high angle.
And then they dropped down from
straight above and hit targets. And so,
so Joe and in this company is
in charge of the mortar section.
Back to the book, when Baker one
seven was still on the way to war,
the first and fifth marines forced the
landing across the tidal flats at Inchon
harbor.
The radio and the ship's wardroom was
tuned to the tactical net and we listened
to commanders on the beach
as they reported the action
to their senior echelons
and made call for air and artillery
support and ammunition resupply
over the static and crackling
transmission. We could
hear shells exploding,
small arms, fire, battlefield curses,
and the screams of wounded men.
The transmissions were piped out
onto the deck with the troops.
Also listened to the grim sounds.
I left the wardroom and went
out to be with my mortar men.
They sat in a tight cluster
staring intently at a
loudspeaker as they heard the
war that was about to swallow us.
That's a real introduction right there.
You're, you know, you're going to award.
You get to listen to guys on the ground
and a fierce firefight and hear the
shouts and screams of the wounded.
That's a reality.
That's a reality check right there
for those guys. So at this point,
um, Owen, he,
he kind of wants to pick up a platoon
instead of being the mortar section,
he kind of feels like mortar section,
you know, they're a little bit in the,
in the rear and he wants to
be a rifle platoon. If you,
if you remember what Mac Alan said that
the last book we did about the Korean
War and you know, rifle platoon
commander, rifle platoon commander, right.
For two commander. That's what if you're
gung Ho, that's what you want to do.
And so Joe, when he feels kind of
like, you know, I wish I was a platoon.
I wish I was a rifle platoon commander.
That's what I want to do.
But he's a mortar section
commander. Okay, that's fine. Well,
he tries to get that
job and he says he is,
he's kind of pressing to get
that job up the chain of command.
I should have backed off.
I plowed on Sir.
The word is that the first and fifth
marines are running short on lieutenants.
I like to request transfer as replacement.
The captain turned to Caney first
sergeant, if you will excuse us.
I'd like award alone with Lieutenant Owen.
Okay.
Yes sir. Responded Caney. So he kind
of gets rid of the senior enlisted guy.
He knew I was about to get reamed any
smirked at me as he disappeared behind the
pile of crates. Captain Wilcox
gave me that glare. Once again,
you want to transfer out of Baker
one seven sir. It's the, Oh,
it's only that I want to put my training
of some use before the fighting ends
and to hell with your men. To hell with
the company. Is that right, lieutenant?
No Sir. Captain, it's just that. It's
just that you want to jump ship on us.
The skippers face glistened with press
perspiration and he turned into a
steaming red. He had been angry with
me before, but never like this, sir.
I, okay lieutenant, here's what you do.
You put your request for transfer in
writing and I'll forward it approved.
No sense holding back a gung Ho hot
shot. The second lieutenant, sir.
It's not that I want to leave the outfit,
it's just that I thought that
put your request in writing.
That's all lieutenant
dismissed, sir. I dismissed.
So this is your typical typical meat
ball that thinks he's gonna. You know,
he's just been gung Ho was trying
to make something happen. Yeah,
it's not a not a good way to be.
And you can see that.
So that's another thing you've got to
think about other people's perspective,
right? You gotta think about
your boss's perspective.
Your boss is sitting here trying to get
this company together and then one of
his section leaders go lower. Go some
world, right? Right. Kind of for him.
So what does meatball meatball, oh,
sorry. That's just an expression for,
it's an expression for a new
guy in the seal teams. Oh,
meatball or a meat stick or Fng.
Any one of those can be utilized.
So I guess I threw it on on the, the new
guy here. It kind of slipped out. Yeah.
Oh good.
Now they get on shore and
back to the book,
we passed a company of third battalion
that had been pulled off the line.
It's men were sprawled along the road.
Unshaven and ragged wearied
by days of fighting.
So there's another,
another little wake up call
seeing the guys that are coming off
the line now they get into a position.
This is Baker six move forward out.
Captain Wilcox ordered.
We all reported ready as we
started across the bean field,
we were greeted by a fuselage of fracking.
Sounds North Korean bullets tearing
through the bean plants, frack, frack,
frack all around us. I kept an
eye on my men. They crouched low,
but they stayed together and moved ahead.
Then the Cri Korman God,
I'm hit a few feet from me.
A marine from Kaiser's
platoon rived on the ground,
his hands clutching his belly,
grayish red intestines,
pushed through his fingers and blood
stained the ground as he thrashed about
screaming in his pain and
terror for the first time.
I felt the shivers of dread,
the awful fear that comes with combat.
I froze a second.
How many seconds until I once again became
aware of the flacking sounds and the
bean plants and I yelled at the men,
move it you people keep moving.
They bent lower to the ground.
As we went forward,
the North Korean mortars came,
spouts of earth and black smoke leap the
about us laced with flame and screaming
shrapnel.
The leaves from being plants spawned
in flurries and the ground shook.
I was suddenly in the midst of a
frenzied storm of noise. Mortars,
whistled and crashed.
Bullets, wind and leaves.
Flacked men shouted
prayers and blasphemies.
The far end of the bean field
was the dyke of a rice patty.
We headed for its cover.
A string of mortar shells exploded
around us and a man threw himself to the
ground kicking and screaming, can't
take this. I can't take this screech.
The fear stricken marine tiny
curled up himself into a fetal ball.
I ran to him and prodded him with a
bottom. My car being on your feet,
his head was buried in his arms.
Can't take this.
He wailed get up or I'll shoot you the
sound of the words coming from my mouth
was unreal to me.
Jesus don't shoot me.
The man whined tiers cut Pale streaks
through the dust on his cheeks.
As he stared in horror at my car been,
which was inches from his face,
I grabbed the man by his collar and
pulled him up to his feet, move. I yelled,
Sargent Dale from the first platoon
ran toward us. I got him lieutenant,
he's from my platoon.
Dale said,
so there's fear.
Then you can see Joe in his feeling
fear and he's dealing with it.
And this other young marine is feeling
fear and he's not dealing with it.
Okay.
And they, they finally get to that dike
across the field. Back to the book,
I crawled up the dyke to peer over
the top smoke obscured my view,
but far ahead and across the road,
I detected some movement.
The enemy positions were
difficult to locate.
No flash came from their
weapons when they fired.
I raised my binoculars before I
could focus on the target. However,
a flurry of bullets pelted the dike and
spurts of pebbles and dirt stuck my face.
I jerked my head down
and to cover beside me.
A rifleman tumbled away from the dyke.
He made a choking sound and his
helmet bounce to the ground.
Blood gushed from his head,
which suddenly became a wet crimson pulp.
Another wave of fear shuttered threw
me a massive paralyzing force again.
I froze, aware only of that
blood drenched face and head.
Okay.
Captain Wilcox voiced cracking
crackled out of my walkie talkie.
Baker five this is six. Come in the
voice. Snap me from my paralysis.
Baker six this is five comment six
I was scrambling back up the dike.
I knew the skipper wanted the
sixties the sixties are his mortar.
60 millimeter mortars to bear on the
North Koreans who had us under fire.
Get those guns cranked up.
Five over Roger that six I said to the
radio on the double sergeant wing gun was
a few yards away behind the dike and
I crawled over to get in front of it.
Stand by for a chief fire mission.
I called the wing it number one gun
standing by a chief fire mission,
the staunch wing, it called back
with all the will I could muster.
I forced my head above the
dyke binoculars at the ready.
The terror of having my head blown off
to a pulp was diminished by fear of
losing the respect of my men.
So there's a couple of things there.
You've heard me say you
trained how you fight.
What they go back to is the fundamentals
that they practiced and trained.
And we didn't dive too much in
the training. But if you ever,
if you've ever seen marines in the
field with a 60 millimeter mortar,
I haven't seen army guys.
I'm sure they're outstanding too.
But when you see the marines setting
up a mortar for a fire mission,
it's beautiful. It's a beautiful thing.
And this is exactly what it's like.
Even in, even in the 90s
you know, 40 years after,
after the Korean War,
when I would watch the,
the mortar men set up a mortar to shoot.
It was just like that.
They'd be stand by for fire mission.
And then you know,
one of the sergeant would call out
number one guns standing by a chief fire
mission.
You go back to your training and those
fundamental basics that you learn,
the simple commands, that's what you
go back to. That's why you train.
That's why you use repetition.
So when that fear comes up,
you go back to what you know your
instinct becomes. Instead of cowering,
your instinct becomes to do
what you've trained how to do.
Okay,
back to the book.
All along the dikes are marines
were sprawled heads below the edge.
The corpsman had moved their wounded
alongside the road waiting for the
ambulance, jeeps, the
meat wagons to come up.
There were two bodies
face covered by ponchos.
They were Baker one sevens first
killed in action. The KIAA.
So Baker's is the company that they're in
that you could,
that's why they keep referring to Baker
one seven first battalion Baker company
back to the book someone said
won't be nothing left up there by
the time the are artillery gets it.
So what's going on here is they call
in some, some big guns, some big,
so 60 millimeter mortar small.
And then when you start calling in how
it serves a big giant bombs are coming
from the sky. Uh, that's what
they call some of those in.
And do you know,
you're sitting there sitting there
watching the mountain where these,
where these North Koreans aren't,
they're seeing massive explosions.
And so now back to the book, someone said,
won't be nothing left of them up there.
By the time that artillery lets up,
Staff Sergeant Richard,
the company armor was crouched near
us, don't fool yourself. He said,
artillery never wipes out. The geeks
softens them up and keeps their head down,
but they'll be there waiting
when the guns led up.
This is another lesson we learned
a lot about. You know, you think,
you think that no one could survive
something and they do survive it.
It we, we used to, when we were
running training, we had the,
the Humvees would be shooting blanks.
It's training.
So the Humvees would be big 50 caliber
machine guns and they shoot blanks into a
building.
And then the guys in the building would
come and shoot back at them and the guys
and just going through the training,
the seals, all, you know, we,
we shot a bunch of 50 cal in there. Those
guys wouldn't be alive. And you know,
I would say no,
actually they will be alive.
They will be alive because I've seen it.
And those 50 cows,
they're on awesome weapon. But there's a
guy, two rooms deep inside that building,
you can shoot all those rounds in there.
He's going to be okay.
And as soon as you let up, he's going
to be there shooting back at you.
And it's the same thing with obviously
with a big artillery and the North
Koreans are dug in.
I scrambled to my feet,
keep moving.
The men were all up and they ran after me,
bent under the weight of their guns
and Ammo. Get us the hell out of here.
Someone cried. And so what do they do?
They attack. So when you're pinned down,
it's just another example when
you're pinned down attack,
and here's what it looks like.
Back to the book to have Kaiser squads
moved up in short bounce while a third
laid a base of fire.
Okay,
cover move.
You're going to be covering move all
throughout this book and every time we
bring it up,
I'm going to mention it because I want to
make sure everyone that's listening go.
Those folks that are in the military,
you hear it every single time.
This is the first one of many to have.
Kaiser squad moved up in short bounds
while third laid a base of fire,
the first 50 yards when easily.
Then the North Koreans popped out
of cover and took us under fire.
Suddenly the ground before us with skate,
with torrents of bullets,
mortar shells whistled in and exploded
the long car. Kaiser's line corpsman,
corpsman, so if you don't know a
corpsman has as a medic in the,
in the army,
it's a medic in the navy it's called a
corpsman and navy corpsman are the ones
that go and deploy with
the Marine Corps as medics.
So that's when you hear those,
those Corman calls.
That's what it Korman Korman
came a despairing whale,
add top alert stuff from prone position
and ran toward the wounded man as enemy
bullets.
Spurted around him beside me.
Another man went down with
a grunt and did not move.
Fear slammed my gut once more
and I was flat on the deck.
Nichols was down there with me.
What do you want to do?
Lieutenant Nickels,
plump young fee,
face street with dirt and sweat showed
the same fear that had me in its terrible
grip.
Jesus the boy depends on me.
I forced my head up.
That's a classic.
What do you want to do lieutenant?
I was,
I think I might have talked about this,
but I was in when I was in Sri Lanka
and I was a young kid and there was all
those guys that were hardcore combat
veterans and one of the captains,
army captains,
again Sri Lankan army captain,
who had been in tons of combat.
And I was talking to almost trying to
like be garner information about war cause
I hadn't been in any
and he'd been in a ton.
He was wounded and shrapnel in his face.
And I'm talking to him, you know
about it. And he said, you know,
when you're in a war,
he goes,
it's pretty easy to take care of
yourself and take care of yourself.
Like he said, if I was in a war,
if I, when we were in a firefight,
if I just had to take care of myself,
I'd be okay.
But when you're in charge of everyone
is totally different than now.
All of a sudden you got people saying,
what do you want us to do,
lieutenant?
And that's the pressure,
which I will never forget
him telling me that story.
And that's a great example of it right
there. Sure. He's scared. He's scared,
but he's got a mortar section
waiting for them to tell,
waiting for him to tell him
what to do to save them.
Now we get introduced to a
guy named Lieutenant Lee,
who's a Chinese American guy,
very by the book and very hardcore.
You're going to hear plenty about
Lieutenant Lee year. We tend to lead,
came upon Baldwins gun. Sir, I
think we should move this gun.
Baldwin said to his lieutenant,
it's kicking up dust.
You have a good position here.
Baldwin responded. Lieutenant Lee,
I'll show you how to
handle the dust problem.
Lee opened up as canteen and walked
around the machine gun sprinkling precious
water as he went.
Now fire off a burst orderly and
machine gun fired but raised no dust.
Lieutenant Lee walked on
up the hill ignoring enemy
bullets that hit around him.
Moving forward a little bit. Hey
Lee called by folk. Get down.
We're getting shot at by full cad.
Lieutenant Lee's attention.
The lieutenant dashed where by
folk was hugging the ground.
You address me as Lee.
He asked,
standing over the astonished young
marine, Jesus, yeah, get down,
you're drawing fire.
You on your feet.
Demanded Lee Bullets Zip through the
year punctuating the bizarre scene of a
lieutenant bracing a PFC to attention
in the midst of a firefight.
You call me Lieutenant Lee or Sir,
you understand that marine?
Yes, yes, yes sir.
Stammered by folk wishing that he were
in a very deep foxhole and you never
forget that. Understand now
carry on. Set the lieutenant.
And he proceeded to walk
further up the hill,
seemingly oblivious to the enemy fire.
What the hell thought by folk.
And he got up to walk behind Lee,
the rest of the mortar squad or
rose and followed. So like I said,
Lee is by the book.
And that's an extreme example.
I don't think I necessarily
agree with that example either,
but Lee's going to hold the line
and maybe there was much danger as a,
as he thought.
But instilling that discipline,
he's given no slack
back to the book while the
mortars obscured the enemy's view.
Van Winkle moved his people up.
So you've got the mortars dropping fire
and that allows vanwinkle to move his
people. That's called cover and move. By
the way, nearing the top of the ravine,
Hank Kaiser positioned his assault squad
to follow a barrage of grenades into
the enemy positions.
As soon as the mortars lifted.
So you've got three situations
you got the mortars are going in.
That's the first cover.
Then once the mortars left,
they're going to throw grenades.
That's your second cover.
The ammo carriers for the marines machine
guns filled in with riflemen on the
line of assault, ready to charge
up the last few yards of ground.
Lee was with them bayonet fixed to
the top of his car being the mortars.
Fired,
fired a final barrage there.
Explosions were followed by the sharper
impact of grenades thrown at enemy holes.
Shouts and war cries swelled
from charging marines who leaped.
Bayonets pointed into the enemy positions
that were dug in along the face of the
rich. Some of the North Korean stood
to fight their bayonets also fixed,
but they were cut down.
Others scurried over the hill.
Many were shot from behind
is they tried to escape.
We all knew had been a
far from perfect exercise.
Some of the men had been
slow to respond to direction.
Not all of our orders were clear
enough for quick and effective fire and
movement.
We were fortunate that the enemy had not
chosen a fight to the death defense of
this hill as they would have advanced
as they would would we advanced further
north.
So think about this point.
Not all of our orders were clear enough
for quick and effective fire movement.
He's not even blaming the guys.
He knows that the mistake was that
they weren't being simple, clear,
concise with their waters
and that makes everything lag
back to the book.
And we had nearly reached the top captain
Wilcox pushed weavers platoon through
Kaiser's for the final assault platoon.
Sergeant King led the charge
and we could hear is piercing.
Rebel yells all over the hill.
Once again,
it was a ragged performance orders
confused in the hellish noise.
Men who bunched close together and some
who hesitated to risk the move against
enemy fire.
However clumsy we were though,
we had the fundamentals right. The NCO
is directed, their sectors of fire,
the fire teams went forward in bounds
covering each other as they protect
progressed and our machine gun and mortar
fire stayed ahead of the events and
kept the enemy heads down.
That's the, that's what,
that's what small unit tactics are. It's
cover and move, cover, move, cover, move.
Now they're digging in some some night
defenses and because there are these
peaks, I mean this huge
mountainous terrain, steep cliffs,
they end up dis aggregated across
the battlefield. So they're not,
they're not right next to each other
cause there's valleys between them.
Hmm.
Back to the book we had,
we had to set our own isolated perimeters
and we couldn't tie our flanks to the
other companies for mutual support.
The same held true for attack.
Almost always the battalion was channel.
It channeled into attacking some
with one company, one hill at a time.
This sort of isolated fighting made it
difficult to communicate with battalion
and other companies.
That problem was not solved much of the
time we company level officers were on
our own initiative, decentralized
command, just decentralized command.
So imagine this,
you can't talk to battalion.
There was a hill that cuts your
radio signal. You have to beat,
you have to know what the
intent is of the operation,
and you have to be out there ready to
ready to execute on your own to the best
of your ability underneath
the commander's intent.
Hmm.
Back to the book,
I learned how to deflect the fear
after the first jolt of it,
which came with the initial
shock of coming under fire,
I would force myself upright and
attempt to read the situation before the
skippers. Boys came crackling
out of the walkie talkie.
Once I had rammed myself into action,
the fear subsided.
It never completely went away though.
So people ask this all the time,
how are we going to overcome fear?
And what did he do to overcome fear?
He forced himself into action,
didn't weight you. Start feeling
that fear. Go, go, get up.
Take a look at that situation.
Try and analyze it in his own clock.
What he made for himself. The timer
that he made for himself was I'm to,
I'm going to assess the situation
before the boss calls me.
So that's the time we put on himself
that that forced him into action.
Yeah.
So we say this over and over again.
You're afraid of something. Step into it.
Take action.
Don't wait
back to the book. There was no
deflecting the confusion. That's it.
Came with every firefight,
but we'll during patterns of noise and
grotesque scenes exploded all around.
Men screamed it.
Rage and pain and fear.
Swarms of bullets.
Wind and splattered close by the mortars
blasted her old flames and slices of
steel and raised clouds
of greasy black smoke.
The sparing voices yelled corpsman
and someone would surely call,
what do we do, lieutenant? In the turmoil,
the officers and sergeants made
themselves visible and we shouted, orders,
watch your sector or move up or
bear on me or CUC machine gun,
10 o'clock,
300 yards.
We subdued the fear and showed
the men that we were in command,
and I've talked about this one before
too. I talk all the time about, oh,
you got to explain to everybody why you
got explained to why we want everyone to
be happy.
You want people to form the plan with
you and you want it to be their plan.
Do you want them to take ownership?
And then I also say that when
you have a critical situation,
you have to lead and that's what
he's talking about right here.
You have to lead and that's what they do.
They would give these to orders, simple,
clear,
direct orders of what to do
in this situation and show
the men that they were in
command
back to the book.
We could have alleviated some of the
confusion if our walkie talkies had worked
at that as advertised.
The handheld two way radios were supposed
to transmit and receive up to a mile
in distance.
We found that they rarely
functioned over a hundred yards,
never over on even terrain. We carried
them because they were all we had,
but we had little faith in them.
Instead,
just like frontline military
leadership throughout history,
we relied on line of sight communications,
arm and hand signals,
and we sent runners back and forth
in those first five days of combat.
I learned to stay visible and I
learned the value of a good runner.
The North Koreans use to whistles and
bugles for bag battlefield command more
effective by far than our walkie talkies.
And I'm a huge proponent of
verbal commands and you know,
I think life's told this story a bunch of
times where I've told me you don't use,
he's, he's trying to tell these guys
what to do over the radio. And I said,
hey leaf, give him verbal commands and
cause when guys are, when, when you're,
when you're working,
there's this weird,
there's everyone's talking on the radio
and it turns into white noise and so
they're not responding.
But when you give a verbal command
in the seal teams in the military,
you get trained that if I tell echo peel,
right,
you're going to, when you hear that
your instinct and your training,
it tells you to repeat that command. So
you're gonna repeat it. The next person.
When they hear it,
they're going to repeat it.
So everyone repeats the verbal command.
So when you say verbal command,
that's like the radio. It's like, yes,
it's yelling and yelling and talking,
but in all actuality it's a
yelling. It's yelling. And so the,
the radio's just sometimes,
you know, and our,
our radios are infinitely better than
these radios and even while I was in the
radio is made vast improvements in
by the yet. By the time I retired,
the radios were pretty damn good.
But there are times if
the radio is not working,
you've got to go with the verbal commands
and you, that's why you got to train.
You've got to train for the verbal
train without radio's a bunch.
I always tell guys,
yeah, take the rails off,
make sure you can do it
without the radios. It,
how's it going to go with their
communication? Net goes down.
You got to have that backup
communication plan all the time.
Hmm.
Now here we are in another,
another firefight does is basically a
massive book of firefights back to the
book.
The North Koreans disappeared into the
deep ditch that ran along the other side
of the road. They were moving in
our direction and we dove for the,
our own ditch. Grenades flew
toward us, but landed wide.
There was a machine gun up ahead.
However,
I couldn't locate it and it started
and it started to fire down on us.
I tossed two grenades in the ditch where
the North Koreans were concealed and
told burrows to have his men crawl up,
call, crawl over a clump of boulders,
20 paces away.
When the squad and its mortar we're in.
I told Nicholas to go for it.
We were crouched together,
but nickel,
but as Nichols turned to crawl away,
a bullet speared his chest and through
him backward against him, against me,
his blood spattered,
my dungarees.
The boy made a terrible rattling sound
and then was still his teenage face.
Expressionless Burris watched horrified
and I waved him back when he began to
crawl towards us.
Then I took a deep breath,
pressed myself flat to the ground and
crept rapidly away from the ditch.
I left Nichols behind
me where he had died.
Harsh firefights and they,
they,
they wrap up this,
they keep taking their objectives,
their taken a lot of casualties.
And this section here is after the
fight is over, back to the book,
we grew silent thinking of our families.
I took the snapshots from the webbing
inside my helmet and remembered their
images one by one.
Then I thought about the days,
next mission and reviewed the
fighting we had done that day.
I tried to blank out the blood,
screams men killing each other
and dying the ground. Exploding.
Burst of flame and stabbing tracers,
hot smell of weapons at full automatic.
The stench of guts and feces
oozing from a dead marine
and the shuttering.
Fear.
Okay.
And they continue pushing.
They're pushing north and they're on
one of these patrols heading north.
And we'll go back to the book.
Through my binoculars,
I saw bearded old Korean emerged
from one of the huts. Papasan.
We called these GRANDPA's who wore
traditional garb of high black top hat and
flowing white robes.
The old fellow stood before
his doorway watching,
but wilderness has weapons laden.
Marines passed through his village,
crack went brain x car.
Been only a few inches from me,
and the old man fell to the ground.
The tall black hat fell beside him.
Got The bastard exclaimed [inaudible]
his car bean was still up searching for
another target. God Damn Fool. I yelled,
astonished at the murderous act.
Yeah,
without fought. I slammed the butt of my
own car. Been in the brain. It's ribs,
brain IHC, scream with pain and
went down to the ground writhing.
I stood over him, poised to deliver
another, but stroke got damn full.
I screamed again. As right came from
behind me and held my arms wing.
It was with right and pulled my car
being away. Hold it, lieutenant,
right shouted in my ear. Hold it. What
the hell happened? You see what he did?
I screamed.
I'll kill the deer.
Torsky the corpsman was already
kneeling beside Branick.
He snapped a Syrette of
morphine and Jab brandix arm.
I endeavored to control myself.
Deep breaths. Okay, Sergeant.
I said,
and right released is hold.
The men were circling looking for
me to break. They were silent.
Goddammit.
He shot that old man for nothing.
I yelled through the pain brain at grown.
I thought he was a Goddamn goop.
I thought he had a weapon.
Any,
have you seen what happened when
could ask the men? No one responded.
No witnesses, right? Said softly to me.
Whatever happened, nobody saw anything.
The realization hit me.
No one except me.
He had witnessed brain
IX shooting that old man.
But if someone had seen me hit Branick,
I could be subject to a court
martial for striking enlisted man.
No witnesses, right? Said
again. No one saw anything.
This stays in the mortars.
I heard someone say meaning,
we're just going to keep this amongst
ourselves. Yeah, someone else responded.
This stays with us.
There was a murmur of a cent.
Shall I moved them out? Lieutenant,
right? Asked. Yeah, sergeant.
I answered numbly moved them out.
The morphine had not yet
taken as his effect on break.
He ground his teeth together to hold
back cries of pain and he was scared.
I bent over him and said, you
know, you and I know what happened.
Break and you're going
to have to live with it.
Break nodded his head.
He said nothing but blinked his tear
filled eyes and nodded his head,
take care of him doc. Then I went
to catch up with the mortar men.
When I walked past the old man's hut,
a circle of women and children
surrounded the body crying,
their sorrow and old woman caught my eye.
I'm sorry. I said, although she
wouldn't understand my words.
We're all very sorry.
Okay.
It's madness and again,
you young military leaders out there,
you've got to watch your people and you
got to give them good commander's intent.
They got to understand,
they got to understand what's right and
what's wrong and that's going to come
from you.
Now at this point in the book,
and again,
obviously I'm not reading the entire book,
but you all should see, you can
capture everything that's in between,
but I'm jumping forward a little bit here.
They get relieved by the army.
They moved to the rear and they start
getting word on what they're going to be
doing. Back to the book under
the glare of the lantern.
Captain Wilcox spread a map on the
hood and we jostled for a view maps.
To this part of the world were scarce.
This is the first one we had seen
of the country beyond Hamhung.
It was a topographic chart made by the
Japanese during their occupation of Korea,
the characters and language on the map
where Japanese place names and legends
had no meaning for us,
but we could read the physical
features and the contour lines.
That terrain they showed
was a military nightmare,
roadblock and ambush territory.
It was a country of high steep hills,
deep valleys and sharp ridge lines.
The lower elevations
were largely forested.
Settlements were sparse than the few
roads twisted snake like through tight
passes and along river beds
at the northern extremity.
The map at the end of 70 miles of a
narrow corkscrew roadway was a meandering
blue dot.
That was the chosen reservoir.
The Chinese have committed themselves
to this war began captain Wilcox.
They are in force.
They are slicing through the Republic
of North Korea army up north,
like a hot knife through butter
up here.
He used his band ed as a pointer to
indicate the Chinese advance there people
will,
we will fight are the hundred and 24th
division of the regular Chinese army.
Definite and confirmed no matter
what Tokyo wants to believe.
So the military command was in Japan.
They weren't Korea,
the military was the military command.
The generals were over in Tokyo.
So he's saying no matter what,
Tokyo wants to believe this is who
we're fighting back to the book.
They're tough.
Well trained soldiers,
10,000 of them in all of their officers
or combat experienced their very best.
Okay.
After the briefing,
I requested a word alone with Captain
Wilcox to ask him if we could leave
sergeant. Right. So sergeant right, you've
heard his name mentioned a few times.
He was the senior enlisted guy working
directly for captain up for a Lieutenant
Owen and it's, it's actually
time for him to go home.
I request a word alone with Captain Wilcox
to ask him if we could leave sergeant
right behind with the Co
when the company moved out.
Sergeant White has done a good job for us,
but he's a short timer.
Just waiting for paperwork
I offered. Furthermore, sir,
it's not good for the troops to
see him with his morale down.
I like to replace him with sergeant wing
yet before we hit anything serious up
ahead. Good idea. The captain
said, except it's too late.
Battalion says we mount out as we are.
I'm not about to snarl up with them
on a transfer detail right now.
You tell sergeant right that, I'm sorry
we can't do anything for him. I, I sir.
So that was a little opportunity for
sergeant right to get out of there,
but it didn't work out.
And now just talking about kind of the
morale of the troops back to the book,
there was a great energy in the ranks,
strong,
healthy young men on the way to adventure.
We cleaned and recleaned weapons and
earnestly sharpened our bay and nets and
fighting knives.
The old salts retold stories of Japanese
ferocity on the Pacific islands. Oh,
there's remembered pitch battle with
the Chinese bandits along with the
pleasures of the north China occupation.
The newly blooded veterans of last
month's fight boasted to the replacements
about their triumphs over
the stubborn North Koreans.
All hand speculated about whether the
quality of the Chinese army would be equal
to that of the North Koreans
we had beaten down south.
The fear that settles in the gut before
combat had not yet surfaced on that
Christmas morning with
our clean shaven faces,
clean dungarees squared
away gear full canteens,
full bellies and full issue of ammunition.
The marines have Baker
one seven feared no one.
They start heading up north
and one of the colonels is out.
Colonel Litson Berg was there.
He stood beside the road as we pass,
nodding and smiling at his fighters.
You're looking good marine.
He kept saying and all the men
waved and smiled back at him.
The veterans from down South
recognized all recognized old homer.
They had seen him frequently up
on the line, good hunting. Owen,
good hunting young man.
He called to me as I passed by
now.
He has that opportunity now
to maybe figure out a way out for right
who had the opportunity to go away.
While the men were loading up on
Ammo. I talked to sergeant, right.
No sense for you to go up.
I told him your orders could
come down from battalion anytime.
Now stay here with the gunny.
I appreciate that lieutenant
responded sergeant. Right,
but I do want to stay with the
mortars if it's okay with you.
That's what I'll do. I nodded.
It's okay with me, sergeant.
I just don't want you wasting time getting
back to your kids. He said, stiffly,
I'll stay with the section, sir.
He didn't like my favoring him.
He went back to the mortar men and
told them to get ready to move out.
Okay.
I'm telling you there's up,
there's a certain bond.
There's a certain bond and obviously
in this case it's a bond that's even
stronger than the bond he has with his
kids is the bond that he knows is his
brothers and arms are going into harm's
way and he's going with them no matter
what.
So now we get a Baker one seven there.
They're dug into some positions,
they've moved and now they're
dug into some positions.
Back to the book in the brush below.
Kaiser's platoon Chinese assault squads
weighted in silence for the rockets and
bugles that would signal them to attack.
They're quilted uniforms kept them
from shivering in the chill night.
They already knew in detail how Kaiser's
defenses were set up and the location
of each forward hole and our weapons.
During the late afternoon there,
officers had watched Baker one seven dig
in and they knew our line as well as we
did under cover of darkness,
the assault teams had crept soundlessly
into their jump off positions within
grenade range of the marine line.
These soldiers were honored that they
would be the first Chinese to attack
American marines.
So these guys are staged
and ready and here we go.
The sound of a rocket ripping
through the year close above us,
jolted awake and brought me upright
in our whole. Kelly was with me.
A streak of fluorescent
green crossed our line,
followed by a red rocket
from the other direction.
Bugles blared and whistle shrilled
down the suit. Dong Valley.
The luminous hands of my watch says
zero zero three zero Baker one seven was
under attack. A sudden clamor erupted
from Hank Kaiser side of the hill,
the Erie chant Molleen die,
Marlene die issuing from a
chorus of Chinese voices.
Then the crash of mortars,
the boom who concussion of grenades
and the sharp sputter of Burp guns.
Seconds later there was the deeper sound
of answering marine rifles and bars
joined by the pounding of our machine
guns and the explosion of marine grenades.
The screams of wounded men soon
added to the Malosh of sounds,
along with profanities of
rage in both languages.
Fast forward a little bit,
Chinese grenades exploded into
the line and they're burp.
Guns blazed the first wave of enemy
soldiers rushed in and forward.
Holes were buried in
mounds of quilted uniforms,
clubbing and stabbing. The Chinese
searched up the third platoons.
Hill behind them were left dead marines
and wounded men who cried for the help
of their Korman.
And one of the things that they talk
about in here is one of the tactics that
the Chinese used is not everyone would
even carry a weapon when they would
attack. And if you were a guy that wasn't
carrying a weapon, you would go attack.
And as soon as someone got shot,
you would take their weapon and carry on.
So that's how, that's how many
people they had. Number one,
they also didn't have, you
know, a weapon for every guy.
Obviously they would have given them,
but they also do, you know what,
here's the plan. But then think
about how now light you are,
you're not even carrying a weapon. It
even carrying any ammunition or anything,
you're just, you're just
able to travel. And it's,
it's hard for people that were
never have never put on gear.
It burdens you down so much, it just
makes you slower and you get used to it.
Sure. But when you, you can get as used
to it as you want when you take it off,
you feel like superman. Yeah. So
these, these Koreans are f the, sorry.
The Chinese are feeling like
superman sneaking up into
these positions all quiet.
They also had real legit winter gear,
at least this group,
we're going to run into some
groups that didn't have it,
but they got these nice quilted,
uh, uniforms and jackets.
So that's they, they're just
bringing it. They're bringing it.
Okay.
Back to the book.
Van Winkle ready the marines near
him for the next Chinese attack,
putting his people into
recaptured fighting holes.
The men stacked Chinese bodies in front
of their holes for greater protection.
Somebody yelled to van Winkle that
his own shoulder was bleeding.
The big sergeant felt his arm and found
a Chinese had indeed passed through his
shoulder.
He didn't care.
Nobody near sorry. Nearby a man
on the ground sobbing and shaking.
My Buddy,
my buddy Guccis shot his head clean off
the orange glare of a Chinese grenade,
illuminated the sobbing marine van
Winkle crawled over to the man,
grasp his arm saying, come on kid,
come with me, you'll be all right.
He rose from the ground and
pulled the kid up with them.
Leadership
going forward a little bit.
Archie van Winkle now found himself on
the lower fringes of the Chinese attack.
He ignored his wounded shoulder
and fired his car, been one handed.
He called for nearby remains marines to
follow and launched his own attack into
the flank of the Chinese who
were moving up towards Kaiser.
So you got a guys wounded just picking
up young marines to getting them back in
the game, firing his rifle with
one hand and leading it up,
leading an attack on the flank of the
Chinese that are attacking his buddy
higher up the hill.
Gunny foster brought Sherman Richter's
two machine guns from first platoon and
they commenced to pounding
down Kaiser slope,
withering fire and exploding grenades.
Now from both flanks and above
stymied the Chinese attack.
There was a series of whistle
signals and the attackers fell back.
They crawled over their dead but pulled
their wounded with them as they backed
down to the bottom of the
hill and into the woods.
They were supported by well directed,
covering fire and they held
good order as they withdrew.
When the Chinese were
fighting the off the hill,
the marine cease their fire
and both marines went silent.
So the Chinese are also doing cover
and move as they, even as they leave,
as they withdraw,
they,
they're,
they're in another little firefight and
oh, when's trying to quickly get
his mortar up and they drop up,
they drop a mortar round.
The way a mortar works,
you crop the mortar into the round,
into the tube and it fires.
If there's a misfire, it's really,
it's a scary situation because, so if,
if you drop the mortar into the tube and
it doesn't come out, it doesn't shoot.
Well now you've got a live round.
Yeah, inside the mortar tube.
So you have to literally pick up the
tube and let gravity pull, like let the,
let the mortar round slide out and you
put your hands there to catch it. Yeah.
Wait, why does it explode? It's
not like a timer or nothing and no,
it's like it's got a little
detonator. Yeah, makes it shoe.
And you've got little propellant,
um,
around the fin that makes
no different ranges.
But essentially you drop this thing in
there and it's supposed to shoot out and
it,
when it doesn't,
it's a scary because now you've got a
live round inside your mortar tube and in
order to get it out you,
you,
you just lift the mortar
tube up when you've kind of
pour it out into your hands.
So they get a dud round and there's a
bunch of things that can call it cause a
Doug round. Some of it can be, you
know, a bad batch of ammunition,
but that's what's going on here. They get
a dud round, dud round, try another one.
I told [inaudible] again, they're
trying to get some mortars down range.
So they're all in a panic situation and
they're getting shot at, by the way,
to dud round.
Try another one.
I told wing yet Kelly yelled
for us to hurry up wing.
It asked me to wait while he
checked the tube for an obstruction.
He grabbed a long stick,
which he shoved into the tube.
He pulled out a cleaning rag.
The cause of our misfire, it was,
it was careless that we had not checked
the tube for an obstruction before we
fired wing. It said, I won't tell
anybody about this if you don't.
And he says, shut up. Damn it.
I yelled at him and this is the reason
I highlighted this cause he said,
my fear showed itself in anger.
And I think that's an important
thing to think about. We all know,
we all know when someone's
getting mad that,
that they're probably afraid, right?
They're afraid of something that's,
so we all see that.
So if you're in a leadership position
and you start losing your temper, it's,
it's very visible to everybody
that you're just scared.
You might be also frustrated,
but it's showing you what it's showing
is that you're losing control of your
emotions. And that's why we can't
do that in leadership positions.
Or you can't do that. That's why it's so
much, infinitely better to remain calm.
Yeah. When, uh,
flip frustration,
like all the,
so if you go into a situation
where you're scared, you know,
so a lot of times,
especially if you're like an Alpha
type person or a powerful person,
you go and you feel that fear.
It's basically the fear kind of
is this feeling of, of weakness.
So a natural tendency, this goes for
pretty much everybody over natural. Yeah.
It's the bounce back. So, so you,
your natural way to invoke power is a car,
like this anger,
aggression type attitude.
So when you know leaders or whatever,
when they feel that fear,
it's like, oh my powerless.
It's like a subconscious thing.
I'm powerless right now.
So I gotta I gotta fight back. So
comes angry in this point. And,
and the thing is,
you just said, we all cumins
know that instinctively. Yeah.
So when you see a leader
start to act like that,
it becomes very clear
that there's some emotion.
There are some fear or some frustration,
some anxiety, and that's going to spread.
By the way,
if I start panicking and start getting
crazy jaqual you got to get this done.
You know I'm scared. So now you're
saying, wait, if chocolates scared,
I'm scared too.
And now we started having issues.
So try and remain calm is the,
is the basic principle.
So
they get done with that
particular firefight and we
got a little debrief here on
it. Back to the book. Baker one
seven lost more men that night.
Then we had in the first five days of
our campaign against the North Koreans,
Captain Wilcox raised a hell when he
heard Sergeant Dale and his men had been
killed in their sleeping bags. I didn't
cover this section, but one of the,
one of the small elements,
they were in their sleeping bag,
she got overrunning killed.
So Captain Wilcox raised hell when he
heard that Sargent Dale and his men had
been killed in their sleeping bags.
He made it standard operating procedure
that the company stayed out of sleeping
bags at night.
And when we were on the line,
tell your people that they can put their
feet in the bags and loosened their
boondockers. That's as far as
they'd go. He told us from then on,
no matter how cold it became,
we slept outside of our bags and our
boots only came off to change socks.
Okay.
Now I didn't cover this
part where this happens,
but one of these guys, Sergeant
Lany, he, he had, he had,
he had taken a patrol to another area
in one of the mortars and when he went,
they got lost. And then when
they got lost, they got overrun.
And instead of fighting or doing anything,
they'll just all ran.
They just all ran in different directions.
Now actually, all of them lift miracle,
all of them lived.
I shouldn't say they got overrun,
but fighting broke out and instead
of doing something organized,
they just all took off.
And so sergeant [inaudible],
he's, they come back and they say,
what? You know, oh, and says, hey,
what happened out there? And they
said, Sergeant Loney just, you know,
basically said every man for himself
and so he's about to get
relieved of his command,
which means you got fired in the military.
Okay, back to the book. Sergeant Lany.
I'm relieving you of your squad.
He looked straight ahead,
but his eyes moistened you let your
men down last night you abandoned your
responsibilities. It's only good
luck that the squad wasn't wiped out.
They could all be dead or taken prisoner.
Lenny's voice trembled lieutenant. It
was pitch black down there. We were lost.
I use my best judgment. I can
understand getting lost. I said,
but you said no security.
When the Chinese came through,
you forgot to take you forgot
your men to take care of yourself.
Lieutenant. I panicked. I admit that,
but if you give me another chance,
tears streamed down his cheeks
and he looked to the ground.
I can't give you another chance.
Your men don't respect you.
You report to the CP, they'll
give you orders. From there,
his head bowed. Sergeant Lonnie
said, I'm sorry sir, I'm very sorry.
I'm sorry to sergeant dismissed.
Sergeant [inaudible] walked
back to the section perimeter,
gathered his gear than
charged up hill to the CP.
No one's said goodbye to him.
I felt sorry for the man and I couldn't
forget the Times that fear had taken me
close to the edge of panic too.
That's why I included that because,
oh,
when who was going through all
kinds of fearful situations,
he knows that he's been close to that
edge, but he doesn't cross the line.
He holds the line and
that's the difference.
Okay,
now they're pressing forward. Again.
This entire book is them either pressing
forward or you're going to see quickly
that it becomes them trying to leave.
Once they're surrounded back to the book.
Baker one seven took point and marched
for more than an hour without any sign of
the Chinese,
a single file of each of
us on the side of the road.
The men moving easily, so they're
pushing forward and nothing's happening.
All of a sudden
don't like this one damn bit.
Lieutenant Owen O'brian said to me,
he was a reservist,
combat experienced from the Pacific war.
It is unnatural for the Guccis
to let us move up this easy.
We're walking into their trap.
All I know is that Macarthur says the
First Marine Division is going to go for
the Yay Lou Yalu River.
I said,
the Yalu River was North Korea's
border with China, so they're good.
They have been ordered. Hey,
you're going to the Yalu River,
and pretty much they're
all saying at this point,
they all kind of feel like it's a
trap there, but they're walking.
They're not getting any resistance.
Back to the book,
the troops were in good humor.
They joked and laughed as we marched and
made obscene comments about the things
that were central to their lives.
The Chow, the terrain, the enemy,
the lack of women.
Second thing I'm going to do when I
see my wife again is take off my pack.
Said one of the married reservists in
the column. Oh yeah. Came the answer.
By the time you see her again,
you'll forget what the first thing was.
Hell, it'll be so long
before we get backstage side.
You'll be too old for that stuff.
Someone else joke to the married
man who is nearly 30 years old.
Yeah.
I'm telling you guys keep up the
good spirits and that is, that is,
it's impossible.
You know I got include this because
I always had fun on deployments.
I was saying this the other day,
we laughed out loud
like once a day in Iraq,
laughed out loud hysterically at something
so that for those of you
that are civilians or have
any comprehension of this
kind of thing, guys that are in the
military, they have a good time.
Even in the worst situations
they're having. We have fun.
You have to and you know you can
apply that to your job, to your job.
When things get stressful, when
things start getting hard as a leader,
if you're just bearing more stress
on everybody, it's not going to help.
One of the best ways to alleviate
stressors, to have some fun,
and that's exactly what's going on
here. The guys were on patrol. Okay,
we're not getting shot at.
So guess what?
Let's bust this guy's ass
about missing his wife.
No problem at alleviates
some of that stress.
You don't need to just bear down and
create more stress on your people.
I've been asked that. A couple people
have asked me that on social media.
Can you talk to, can you
tell us about, you know,
humor in as a leader?
When do you use humor and
like, yeah, absolutely.
We always have fun and you know,
there's obviously a time to be serious,
but there's plenty of time when you're
going to joke around and have fun and
poke fun at each other all the time.
Yeah.
Do you ever run into like situations where
you know,
some people they just joke more than
other funeral and then there's the,
you know,
the opposite guys joke class.
You ever run into a situation where
you are serious and then someone's like
trying to make jokes, you know, and, and
it does get annoying or in the way of,
I don't know that people when,
when I'm serious,
I don't get a lot of jokesters
and the gate. I, I've, I've just,
I'm saying most of the time when
I'm, when I mean, and I think,
I think there's a pretty, I mean
maybe that happens in, in, you know,
in a school setting, you know, or,
or I guess in a business setting it
could happen, but if you've got to,
if you've got a good team that works a lot
together, people, no, it's not, you know,
and I,
and once you tell a joke or you crack a
wisecrack and nobody laughs and you just
get a look from people going,
hey man, shut up. That's
it. You know? So maybe I've,
maybe that's happened to me a dozen
times in my career where somebody said
something, it's, you know, everyone just
said, okay, well you know, enough at area,
everybody feels it.
Yeah.
I would imagine to working that close
with important tasks like that important
people are pretty going to be pretty
much in tune with the comedy at dynamic.
Exactly.
Now,
I had a guy that I worked with when
I was the admiral's aid and he,
he and I, he was older than me.
He was actually retired captain.
He's one of my favorite guys, but I was
the admiral's aid. So I was a young,
you know,
young lieutenant,
and he was a retired captain and we
would go back and forth all day long,
regardless of what the situation was.
We would never say a serious thing to
each other the entire day for months on
end, nothing. Everything was a sarcastic
kind of comment through each other.
And it made a pretty, a pretty
miserable job of being the animals.
Ate is not a fun job. It made it like we
just had a good time. So, so once again,
we're even in a situation
where, hey, I'm in a uniform,
an office all day from six o'clock in
the morning until seven o'clock at night,
every day, day on day, you know, in
the military and in the civilian world,
when you come back from a trip from
somewhere, they're like, oh, you, oh,
you were on a trip. Hey, you know, don't
come in tomorrow morning. You know,
you can come in a little bit late
because you got back at midnight.
You heard of your animals. I had no,
you're coming. You're coming in at six.
That's the way it is.
There's no, there's no, Oh,
you haven't seen your family in two weeks,
so that's cool.
Could we will see you at six
o'clock in the morning tomorrow. Oh,
you want to take your daughter to school?
No, not happening. So it's like that.
And yet I had this one guy that
I work with who we, we just,
we just never said anything series to
each other and always kept it light and
fond and that's, that was pretty awesome.
Was that D, I mean, thinking back,
do you think that that was on purpose
or did it just kind of shake itself out?
Like it just, you could sell out,
you know, we just said phony. Uh,
the way our relationship was was we were
just two guys that like to give each
other a hard time about stuff and set
each other up for stuff and just, just,
yeah, we both knew. I mean, he was under a
stressful job as well, you know, he's got,
he's got a lot of pressure on him
and so what are we going to do?
Sit there and be miserable
all day. No. You know what,
we're going to have a good
time. Even in this, you know,
fairly miserable administrative scenario
that we're living in a good time with
it because some people do it on
purpose where it's like, oh Dang,
things are getting real tents
here for work or whatever.
And then they'll throw in jokes. They're
going to be on that fine line between,
okay, you're right now things are
tense. Why'd you say that joke?
That's inappropriate. And the other
side, which is like it, it helps,
you know saying like
in like this guy and I,
we would be even in the really stressful
situation where no one else was joking.
I might like,
you know,
shoot him a look across the room
and roll my eyes at him bugging.
You didn't see this coming digit tough
guy and we would just be laughing.
So even in they're really stressful
stuff we would, we would lighten it up.
But that's because, you know, that's
the first time was that we had, yeah.
All right. Speaking of not no
joke whatsoever. Back to the book,
major tie.
The operations officer told us that there
were increasing reports of heavy enemy
concentrations on all sides
of the battalion. However,
General Macarthur himself was expressing
inpatients with a slow pace made by the
first marine division and its
progress toward the Chinese border.
The army was trying to light a fire under
General Smith, the division commander.
So you got the marines are saying,
hey look,
it looks like we're starting
to get surrounded here and
talks a little bit about
this in the book. The marines were
kind of slow rolling. They weren't,
they weren't making any great effort to
go as fast as they could because they
felt like they were going to be trapped.
So they weren't trying to
move as fast as they could.
And Macarthur's general Carthy in Tokyo
by the way, saying, hey, hurry up.
Come on Marines. You know, army
is pushing up there real quick.
What's wrong with you guys?
But they're starting to get Intel
reports that they're being surrounded.
And Oh by the way, uh, Lieutenant
Lee, who I talked about earlier,
the real by the book guy,
he,
he actually got wounded and when he got
wounded taking the hospital, he went on,
he went on. He would
absent without leave. Awol.
You went AWOL from the hospital to
get back to the line. Oh Dad. Yeah.
He's, oh no, I'm fine. My arm can't
move it. Send a slang. Doesn't matter.
I'm going to fight.
And speaking of Lee,
talking about Lees, Lees platoon
here, when they weren't on patrol,
Lee put as men through a rigorous
training program of small unit tactics.
They maneuvered all over the nearby hills
and they bitched at some extra work.
Yeah.
Lee paid little heed to the grumbling.
Soon we will meet the enemy.
He predicted to his men, we will be
ready. So Lee's a hard ass and his guys,
everyone else is doing it.
You know, they're, they're,
they're moving up north and
it was an easy day patrol.
Cause remember the Chinese aren't
pushing hard against them right now.
So what does he do at night? Oh
guys, we're going to go do some work.
We're going to do some tactical drills.
Hmm.
Back to the book.
He was an article of faith with Lee that
combat leadership came from the front.
In the attack.
He positioned himself with the most
advanced squad just behind the point.
He wore a bright fluorescent pink vest
fashion of cloth panels that he obtained
from the tactical air team.
The intended purpose of the brilliantly
colored panels was to mark the Ford
extent of our lines for supporting
aircraft. Lee wore his vessel.
That is men could locate him
quickly during a firefight.
He still had a sling on his wounded
right arm and he carried his car being in
his left hand.
He fired from the hip using it to
shoot tracers that marked sectors.
Okay,
so Lee is just,
I mean a whole nother level,
whole nother level.
Chu [inaudible],
that's his full name to [inaudible].
Now we get into a situation the
Chinese were dug in above Lee.
They had a machine gun
and a line of rifles,
more formal than their
usual defensive formations.
They were expertly deployed below the
crest and their automatic weapons fire,
short discipline bursts,
tracers, street and bullets.
And shrapnel swept down the stroke slope.
It took me some time to locate the machine
gun that was giving the most trouble.
When he found that he fired one
handed to put a tracer on it,
his squads moved into skirmish lines and
the NCO sent their own tracers to mark
for their sectors.
The bar and grill and Michelle and
rifles followed sending a great volume of
fire up the slope with the Chinese.
We waved to me to let me
know the mortar was ready.
I aim to trace her toward the machine
gun and pump my arm four times the signal
for 400 yards.
I saw around leave the tube and following
its path that disappeared over the
ridge line wing.
It realized that he was too long
and without need for my correction.
He came up a turn,
so he's adjusting the where their where
their mortar rounds hitting his own.
His second round was close and
I waved him to fire. For effect,
we seldom wasted ammo bracketing a target.
AMMO carried up the hills was too
valuable to be wasted on the niceties.
The enemy guns slackened as
WIC as wing it pounded them.
Lee's squad moved upward responding to
the NCO signals with short bounds fire
team by fire team,
five 10 yards at a dash,
then to ground bearing their enemy on
the bearing fire on the enemy as the next
fire team winning closer cover move.
It's happening again.
The mortars are covering for them and
then each individual a fire team is
covering for each other.
It was the classic marine rifle tactic
that Lee had drilled into his platoon.
During this extra training,
sessions on marine went down and
ride on the ground. The platoons,
Corman Bill Davis dashed low across the
slope and crashed at the wounded man
side.
Another marine fell and didn't move again.
His buddy stabbed the dead man's
rifle into the earth by its bay.
A Net then continued forward.
The Chinese found it difficult to defend
against Lee's energetic tactics are
coordinated. Mortar and machine gun
fire kept them pinned to the ground.
They were no longer able to apply aimed
fire and their effectiveness Dovid
diminished as our riflemen
pushed closer in on them.
Cover move it.
By the way.
There's a reason why when I wrote
down the the four laws of combat,
the number one rule is covering move.
This is why.
Okay,
lease sent a squad quality crawling
forward into grenade lane range.
I signaled to wing it to cease fire and
the mortar stopped exploding along the
Ford crest of the hill.
The Chinese soldiers heave the barrage
of their potato masher concussion
grenades down the slope.
The Marines through or responding
volley are grenades were more powerful.
Filling the air with bits of hot flying
steel. Both sides, dove for holds.
Another volume was thrown.
Lee Ran forward waiving the car,
being over his head and calling
for his marines to follow.
They search for the top screaming.
They're gung Ho and rebel yells.
The Chinese withdrew.
They pulled their wounded away,
but left their dead on the slope.
Lee pushed his men over the ridge line
where they prepared to defend against a
counter attack.
Lou Puccini stood beside Lee,
his bar at the ready Lupa
cine had appointed himself.
Lee's body guard sergeant bond around
the platoon guide rifled through the
pockets of the dead Chinese gathering
material. For our intelligence people.
I sent Kelly for a detail of the
ammo carriers to bear the casualties.
Bill Davis had two wounded men doped
up with morphine and out of pain,
and there was one marine dead already
covered by his Poncho when he was certain
that the Chinese would not counter attack.
Lee ordered us off the hill and if
patrol on the return march to the company
perimeter, no one complained
about lieutenant Lee's
excessive training methods.
He walked along the column and
thank the men for their good work.
Okay.
I wondered to myself how many firefights
Lee would survive standing at the front
of his troops clad in
that brilliant pink vest.
Okay,
so the excessive trading,
everyone's complaining when they're
training and then you get into a firefight
and everyone's thankful that they
had good discipline leadership.
No.
Hmm. A little bit more if we
now this point again, there's,
they're continuing to get pressed
by the Chinese back to the book.
More Chinese fired,
broken out far too are right in front
of Lee's in front of Lee's line.
They fired from a sharp short
hill that rose from the meadow.
We wheeled one of his rifles,
squads to face the rise and
maneuvered them forward. Burris,
his gun was with we and he traversed the
face of the hill with a cheese before
the squad moved up.
So cheese is high,
explosive mortars and Burns is is one
of the mortar man and he's covering for
the movement of Lee as they're
pushing up. The Chinese ceased, fired,
withdrew quickly.
A familiar tactic.
We stayed with the main body of his
platoon and sent a fire team up to
reconnoiter the top.
When they reached the top of the rise,
the four men walked along the ridge and
search of the vanished enemy looking up.
Lisa has men silhouetted against the
skyline and yelled for them to get down.
There were perfectly outlined targets.
The Chinese saw them too and already
had the ridge line registered for their
mortars, their first rounds,
blue a marine to pieces.
The next barrage claim two more.
The fourth man dough from
the Ridge and leaped,
rolled and stumbled down the hill.
He came to a halt at the
feet of Lieutenant Lee Lee.
It seen three of his men needlessly
killed and he stood in silent fury.
It's good hand grip. This car been so
tight that his knuckles and went white,
stupid. He has through his
clenched teeth, stupid,
stupid over and over again,
stupid.
He turned to gene O'Brien,
his platoon sergeant.
See to it that this never happens again.
Sergeant, you tell the men, if you,
if I see another marine on the skyline,
I will shoot him myself.
We tend at least strode off to be by
himself until his fury and frustration
subsided.
So
you got guys making big mistakes and
for those either don't understand what
happened. When you stand up on a
ridge line, you're completely obvious.
It's very clear and Lee's watching this
happen and sees that as guys were a ripe
target.
Okay?
He's yelling at him,
but it's too late and the mortars hit.
Hmm.
Now we get the company
here a little bit for now.
The company is actually pinned down.
The company's pinned down
back to the book. When the skipper had
artillery fire control on the radio,
he called in the coordinates,
coordinates for a registration round.
The battery of 105 millimeter howitzers
that supported was dug in a mile and a
half away.
So in a mile and a half away you got these
hundred and five millimeter howitzers
big giant cannons.
Hmm.
Less than a minute later.
And,
and you got the company commander that's
calling in calling in to to tell them
where to shoot.
These cause a mild,
obviously you can't see there's no
satellite back then you can't see.
So you're just going off of bearing
and distance back to the book.
Less than a minute later we heard the
heavy ripping sound or the first round
cutting the air over our heads.
It landed a hundred yards of
fronted in front of where Lee,
the captain and I stood,
stabs of flame flame like
lightening from a black cloud,
leaped off the ground and we felt
the earth tremble from the explosion.
Close God to close. Shout at the
skipper, then into the Mikey said,
add three zero zero
repeat ad three zero zero.
So he's telling them that means add,
it means shoot 300 meters further.
The next round landed further away
and we barely saw the stabs of flame.
It was where the skipper wanted it.
The enemy machine gun fire, it stopped.
The Chinese knew what would be
coming at them. Repeat Range,
give me concentration.
Fire three volleys on my command.
The concentration fire would saturate the
area where the Chinese were concealed.
The captain waited to give the order to
fire until sergeant king had positioned
the covering squad in front of us.
Fire 20 seconds later,
the first rounds of the barrage
landed less than 50 yards away.
Short rounds, meaning that the rounds
didn't go as far as they were supposed to.
We go for the deck.
All of us evenly.
The following rounds dropped
among the front of the squad.
That first book tune had
position to cover the company.
Withdrawal screams from our own men.
Mud and flame and crashing funder.
The skipper yelled into the radio,
cease fire, cease fire, short rounds,
short rounds,
friendly fire.
The worst thing that can happen in
combat are dismal day turned to horror,
cries and moons and agonized screams.
Pierce,
the black smoke that drifted
over the broken ground.
Doc Mickens and Joe King.
We're already working among the
wounded and mangled and dead marines.
Bill Davis and ed topple
the other platoon.
Korman sprinted across the
field to help Captain Wilcox.
He yelled into the radio as the next line
of shelled has exploded now away from
us farther to our front.
They'd been in the air before the gunners
could comply with the order to cease
fire. They did us no further damage, but
there noise added to the hellish scene.
I arose,
shaken and not sure what to do.
I saw sergeant right at the edge of the
field and called for him to bring the
ammo carriers forward. We would use
them to carry the casualties away.
Joker Saba had already brought the
company headquarters people to lend a hand
with the grizzly work.
We had four more dead and three wounded.
Casaba went to the skipper and said that
we should get the company out of this
place and back down the road.
Captain shook his head a few times to
clear it at thought about Joe's suggestion
for several seconds.
Then he got Kaiser Lee on the walkie
talkies and told them to prepare their
platoons to move back.
He told me to walk a screen of hs 200
yards out to discourage any Chinese from
following us.
When I reported to him that the mortars
were ready for the fire mission,
I thought I saw tears
coming down his face.
Although it could have
been the drizzling rain,
eight dead marines for the day,
more wounded and nothing accomplished.
The rain and sleet turned to snow wet,
sticky stuff that coded the
ponchos covering the dead men.
The troop struggled down a wet,
slippery trail to the road
burying the dead and wounded.
They were soaked through and spoke
no words except to blast FIM.
The God damn fools who sent
us into this miserable, wet,
cold country
friendly fire blue on blue.
Okay,
think about it.
Try and keep it in the front of your head.
When you're in combat situations,
try and keep it in the front of your head.
Try and keep it as a real possibility.
It's not impossible to have it happen
in the end.
It's to kind of like in fighting. When
they say it's the, it's the, it's the,
it's the punch that you didn't see that
that's the one that's going to knock you
out. It's the same thing in, in,
in this situation, if you could see that
a blue on blue is going to take place,
you would stop it. Yeah.
You can't see it. It's not,
it's something that's going to be
unexpected. That's why it happens.
It happens because it's
unexpected and this one you,
there's a lot of things that can happen
when she started bringing a artillery in.
There's a bunch of variables there
that are really hard to control,
but it is obviously, it's
a nightmare. It's, it's,
it's a nightmare in,
I was having this conversation with
one of my seal buddies the other day.
That's why you train hard.
That's why you prepare for it.
That's why you create chaos in confusion
inside of your training so that you
actually force blue on blue
force blue on blue is to happen.
You forced these fratricide situations
to happen so that they happen in training
so that they don't happen
on the battlefield.
Hmm.
It, it it, it's, you know, same
thing with the police department.
Police Department sometimes has,
has blue on blue train hard set up the
crazy scenarios make people do unexpected
things.
Okay.
All right.
They come down from that scenario
and they get a day arrest.
You might think, hey,
you know, you took eight,
eight killed and multiple more wounded.
I will give you some time off.
They got time off one day,
one day arrest,
and then they're back on
the march back to the book,
the column March North in a cold swirling
wind that swept the road clear of
snow. We put it on the ponchos
again to help ward off the wind.
They soon fro stiff at
crackled as we walked in.
If you notice as they
left that other situation,
the rain turned to sleep in the snow.
So that's like in one hour.
Winter was here and so
now you're going to eat.
Now you're going to start
hearing about the cold big time.
The men weren't a foul temper.
What kind of stupid bastards we got
running this goddamn war came from the
column. Don't worry about them
guys running this goddamn war.
They're sitting by a stove someplace
sticking pins in their maps.
Yeah, and they'll get their pick of
cold weather gear before they send us,
send it up to us.
Poor suckers guy in the battalion mess
line said them rear echelon bastards are
already wearing big fur coats
and winter issue. Boat boots.
That's okay. We'll get the
stuff next spring. Sure.
What's left of it by
the time it gets to us,
we'll be needing jungle gear because
these guys are just letting out their
frustration and anger.
The worst suffering that
day came from our feet.
We only had thin cotton
socks under the boondockers.
A little protection from the cold,
especially as they were still
damp under our leggings.
We stomped the way the freezing toes,
the pain of the freezing toes
and kept the blood circulating.
There were complaints of numbness.
Some meant felt as if they
had tables in their socks.
We didn't know about frostbite.
Yeah.
If you don't know what
boondockers are there,
your basic like the most
basic form of a boot, leather,
rubber soul. That's it. That's what I,
that's what boondockers
or they got cotton socks.
Now they get some new gear and then one
of the pieces that they get is called
shoe packs.
Go into the book.
Shoe packs would change the way we walked
and bring us the crippling scourge of
frostbite.
They were big and cumbersome twice
the weight of our boondockers,
they had thick molded rubber
bottoms with heavily cleated souls.
The tops from the ankle up to the shin.
We're made of stiff leather.
That lace tightly shoe packs
were clumsy for climbing,
climbing and slippery on the ice.
The worst thing about them, however,
was that they were laced
when they were laced up.
No air could circulate on a
steep climb or an a long march.
Our feet would sweat,
no matter how cold it was when we stopped
moving and the cold said in the sweat
soaked felt inserts
and socks would freeze.
Long stretches of wet frozen
feet spelled frostbite.
I Dunno if you remember this
from the last one we did, but,
and I didn't include it,
but one of the videos that they
showed later to the co two, the, uh,
soldiers and marines that were going over
to Korea was to warn them of frostbite.
And it was the doctors with
the frostbitten feet and
they weren't surgically
removing the toes. They were just
like, break them off like Eh,
cause they were just frozen dead
toes and they would just break it.
That's the video they showed
them. Hey, keep your feet dry.
But it was these poorly designed shoes
was one of the problems that they try or
we make these guys, these super warm
boots doesn't, it's not that easy.
It's not that easy. You make,
I'm so warm and so waterproof.
No air escapes from him.
Now you've got sweaty feet.
Now your feet are going to freeze.
Now we get this.
Uh,
one of the replacements that comes
in is a guy named woody Taylor.
You're going to hear it a little bit
about him and there's a little fire fight
that takes place. And Captain Wilcox,
who's the company commander maneuvers.
Some of woody Taylor's guys. He says, Hey,
you guys go check that out over there.
Mm, woody Taylor doesn't like it.
Those are my men. Says Woody Taylor,
so here we go. Captain Wilcox Taylor
called loudly, loudly to the skipper.
If you don't I,
I've used the word skipper a bunch.
I should have explained what it is.
Skipper means the commanding
officer of the company, just just,
just like the skipper of a ship.
Captain Wilcox Taylor called
loudly to the skipper.
He was red faced and out of
breath from the run up the column.
That's a squad from my platoon. You sent
over there on the flank. Yeah, Lieutenant.
I saw a few bandits over there.
Captain, those are my men.
Taylor interrupted my
platoon moves on my orders.
Captain Wilcox glared
at Lieutenant Taylor.
I'd seen that cold book many times
before when it had been leveled on me.
I figured that woody Taylor would not
be long with Baker one seven our new
lieutenant and the captain stared at each
other. Would he calm down a notch, sir?
He said, I'd much appreciate it if
you put any orders to my men threw me.
Colonel Davis sent me up here to run
this platoon. That's what I reckon to do.
Tailoring the skipper war
eyeball to eyeball and the
skipper realize that he had
indeed violated the chain
of command. Yup. Lieutenant.
He said,
you're right.
That's your platoon and I
guess we understand each other.
I guess we do. Captain said Woody
Taylor. All right. Then carry on.
The skipper dismissed
his new platoon leader.
We figured woody Taylor was going to have,
what's going to be one hell of a fighter.
He was the last replacement officer to
come to Baker one sever seven and he was
with us to stay so little stand off,
but there's a lot of little things
that go on there. Right? Number one,
Taylor was too aggressive out of the gate,
you know, hey, those are my guys. Yeah.
That was too aggressive. He was able
to catch himself from back off and say,
hey sir,
I really appreciate it.
If he could come with that attitude
from the beginning, he would have,
he would have had a better chance of
making what he wanted to have happen with
no risk.
Cause there was a risk here.
There was a risk here that
Captain Wilson costumes, you say,
shut up might be your platoon.
It's my, it's my company.
Don't talk to me about this again.
He could've said that,
but also he's a good leader that
when got pressed on this, he said,
well let me, let me, let me
detach. Instead of getting
mad, he was getting mad.
He detached. He said, okay, wait
a second. What's going on here?
This young lieutenant that's
in charge of the tune,
I just ordered this guys around without
telling him. Now he's mad about it.
Does that make sense? Yes it does.
He's calmed down. He's, he's,
he's talking to me in a better tone now.
He's just asking me.
He that he's appreciated. I can accept
that. I was a little outlined. Cool. Yup.
You got it.
And they were able to solve that problem.
So just a little little dynamics,
some dynamics out on the
battlefield going on.
More firefights happen,
more madness going on.
They get through the next situation
and now we have Colonel Davis.
Again, this is the medal of honor
winner. Who's who's in charge here?
Back to the book,
Colonel Davis came up to Baker one seven
to inform us that we were moving out
again tomorrow morning.
We would advance up the west
side of the chosen reservoir.
Our objective was the town of you,
dom knee,
14 miles away.
This was not a patrol.
Our battalion commander told us it
was an attack and we should expect the
fighting to get serious. Right. So they
haven't had any serious fighting, right?
Oh No, wait. Yes they have, but
expected to get more serious.
When he finished briefing the officer's
Colonel Davis asked me to bring sergeant
right to him.
The hardship transfer order had finally
come through and our colonel wanted to
say goodbye personally
to a good marine NCO.
It was a great moment for sergeant.
Right.
All the company officers were there and
the colonel expressed his appreciation
and best wishes to my departing sergeant,
Captain Wilcox and lieutenants
added their own well dones.
Sergeant [inaudible] had done a good
job of whipping the mortar section into
shape and keeping them squared away.
The mortars had a for farewell party
for their sergeant who had been up with
them since the first
day at Camp Pendleton.
The rifle platoon Corman came by Mickens
and Davis and topple each bringing a
canteen of sick bay alcohol.
The skipper and joker Saba joined us in
for a few tastes toast when he was ready
to leave weapon and gear all
squared away like a proud,
like a parade ground marine
sergeant right approached me.
His eyes glistened probably mine did too,
sir.
I think we did some
good with these people.
I want to thank you for giving me
a chance to serve in your outfit.
Thank you surgeon, right?
You're a four five marine NCO.
God bless you and your family sergeant,
right.
Snap the saluted me and strode off.
I would never see him again and I
would miss him very much to sergeant.
Sergeant right headed home,
our guests.
It was his time and he'd pushed on when,
when he could have gone
home a lot earlier,
but he pushed on and now they're getting
ready to make this next move and it,
and he has his orders now in hand
in a orders or orders. So we hit up
back to the book.
The weather turned ugly again as we
formed up to reserve resume the attack to
the north, a bitter cold wind
greeted us, filled with a stinging,
gritty snow.
It was my birthday.
After the troops were squared away,
I crouched in the ditch alongside the
road and took some time to go through my
snapshots.
I thought a Dorothy teaching the happy
birthday song to the babies and how they
would try and sing it.
I saw their little pink cheeks and
blue eyes and Dorothy's golden hair,
rough way for him to spend his birthday.
And as you sit here today,
wherever you're listening to this,
know that somewhere in the world there's
an American servicemen that's out there
celebrating their birthday
in a similar manner.
I guarantee it away from his
family and his loved ones.
What else does he get out for his
birthday? He gets some enemy activity.
Back to the book.
The enemy fire became heavy,
about 50 Chinese were dug in against us
and they were serious about defending
this place. Lee took his platoon off
the road to extend our firing line.
Captain Wilcox came forward with Garcia
and the big radio and set up in the
ditch just behind I marvel.
That is easy.
Ambling gait during firefights,
he always stood up straight.
It's like JP,
the static of the SCR 300 radio out at
added to the pounding of our own machine.
Guns and bars.
Rifles cracked Johnson's
mortar thumped out.
Eight gs and enemy bullets zing through
the year and spun off chips of boulders.
Soon came the urgent cries.
Korman Oh God.
Corpsman and the fear came as it did
to me on the onset of every fight.
The corpsman cries the booming
explosions and the wine of bullets.
Blood trenched Parker's dear God,
not this time please.
Platoon sergeant king from Taylor's
platoon crouched among some large boulders
above me.
He shouted down that there was a machine
gun near the spike of rocks that mark
the Chinese main position.
I willed myself to climb
up and get a better look.
The fears submerged and
the cold was forgotten.
Overcome that fear.
Take action.
Okay,
now they continue in this little fire
fight and then finally we get enough
talked about them before we get some
air support's marine corps support.
We've got some marines on
the ground that are pilots.
What we now call Anglico.
The marines are on the ground.
These are fighter pilots that go out
and do infantry work and call for fire.
And so here we go.
Back to the book,
Bob Wilson brought in the course errors
that were on station to cover our
advance.
I called down to burst to laid down
around of white phosphorous to mark the
Chinese guns and the flyers came
in on the column of white smoke.
They flew in low, barely above, above us.
They're great racketing noise overpowered
all other sounds as they flashed by on
the first pass, as they fired
the machine guns and cannons.
These had a little effect. The
Chinese were dug in to, well,
they followed with a napalm run,
a spectacular,
a spectacle of awesome
and terrible beauty.
The pod slid from the plains,
tumbled across the ground that exploded.
Black smoke,
billowed and red flame leaped against
the white snow and seconds later we felt
the blast of heat that consume
the ground 200 yards away.
Chinese soldiers were a flame
running about and frenzied circles.
They threw themselves flailing into
the snow. There was sudden silence.
The Chinese ceased fire and
our own weapons were quiet.
We were stoned by the power of
that close end flaming strike.
Okay,
200 yards away. That's not a big distance.
That might seem like a big distance.
That is not a big distance when you're
in an airplane and you're coming down to
drop napalm and kill a bunch of people.
So that's a tiny distance.
Marine Corps pilots just getting after it.
It's called danger close by the way.
So if you're going to call in an
airstrike that's close to your positions,
you have to say on the radio, you
say danger close, meaning look,
I know it's close by and you
got to do it right, right
go. And so they, they, they sniffle
out that one. But guess what? The,
the Chinese are far from
done back to the book.
The Chinese showed that they would not
hibernate from the war because of the
cold weather. The farther we advanced,
the stiffer was there resistance.
The hills continued to grow steeper and
each climb we made encumbered with the
heavy clothing became its own or deal.
Most of our fights were platoon sized
Kaiser or Lee or tailor maneuvering up a
Slippy slippery snow covered slope to
dislodge a force of Chinese who fired at
us down the road.
So as they're moving down this road,
they're just having to go into the high
ground all the time and take out the
Chinese.
Here's a,
here's a cool little anecdotal story.
They get pinned down and Colonel Davis
is there and they're trying to figure out
what to do.
I'm going to the book.
Colonel Davis was at the head of
our column with Captain Wilcox.
When the Chinese opened up from
across the Chaz. I'm 300 yards away.
The skipper called me upfront.
Can you knock out those
guns? Captain Wilcox asked,
he in the kernel crouched
their acknowledgement of
machine gun slugs that torn
to the slope above our heads.
Yes sir.
I answered crouching
alongside my two commanders.
So there's a machine gun up on the hill
and they can't get it with their guns,
but they want him to get his,
his mortar tubes up there and
then drop mortar rounds on the,
on the machine gun position. So he yells
out to his runner. So he's runners,
just the guy that spreads word.
He runs out to his,
his runner Kelly bring up Johnson's gone.
I commanded Hugo was with,
uh, Kaiser's platoon
leading the column that day.
They were just behind the bent.
I Sir snapped my runner in a
way to impress the colonel.
Colonel Davis and Captain Wilcox
continued to scan the opposite slope.
11 o'clock said the kernel indicating
slight movement and an outcropping of bowl
of boulders. Yes, sir. I have it.
I told my carnal as I located the enemy
machine gun through my own binoculars
and another one at 10 o'clock,
50 yards higher, sir. Good eyes.
Lieutenant said Colonel Davis,
there was a sudden commotion behind us,
the sound of marine singing as
they doubled timed up the road,
Kelly was leading the mortar men forward
and he had them sounding cadence with
his parody of an army marching song,
song, marching songs sound off.
How can a mortar man survive following
a man who's six foot five sound off puts
your rifles and machine guns away. The
60 mortars are all in the way. Sound off,
sound off?
So they're in a firefight,
they're pin down and these guys come
running up the road singing cadence.
And by the way, I forgot to mention
this, that Owen is six foot five. So he,
that's who they're talking about.
There was no ditch.
So Hugo could not take cover from
enemy fire while setting up his gun.
He and Dean Westburg spread the bi-pod
on the rear of the rear edge of the flat
open road surface. I stood behind
the gun as they work quickly,
the volume of bullets increased.
11 o'clock you go. I said,
give me three five zero.
I fired a tracer from my shoulder.
Westburg had a mortar round ready?
You go with his sharp shooters.
I spotted the target and said
three five Oh, plus a hair.
He laid the tube in the direction of
the machine gun and cranked is elevation
fire. He said to Westburg, the round
thumped out and we followed its arc,
ignoring the Chinese bullets that were
bouncing off the frozen surface of the
road and the slope behind us.
The first round was a direct hit.
God bless you. You Go.
Johnson, captain will.
Wilcox called out for the
platoon to continue the march.
Colonel Davis approached the gun.
He had a big smile.
You tell your men they're
shooting is right on lieutenant.
He said he glanced at our choir director,
Kelly and added,
but tell them that they're
singing is way off key.
Like I said, even having a good
time in madness of firefights.
The cold is getting brutal.
Back to the book we seldom removed are
knitted gloves that we wore under the
canvas. Mittens. Bare fingers we found
froze to metal. They froze to weapons.
Bayonets buckles, whatever
we touched. The cold,
forced a corpsman to change
their way of doing business.
With the first sounds of a firefight,
they would take several Seretse of
morphine and put them into their mouths.
This kept the morphine liquid until the
Seretse word jabbed into the wounded
mans flesh to relieve his pain.
The corpsman were the only ones who
worked with bare hands in the severe cold
and they found a way to keep their
fingers nimble while attending two wounded
man,
the heat of the man's blood did the trick
or his guts as they were stuffed back
into his belly
freezing cold
back to the book. Despite our efforts
to keep the men and clean dry socks,
we were losing the fight
against frostbite, which
resulted from damp, cold feet.
Med would complain of pains or numbness
in their feet and when they limped badly,
we sent them to battalion aid station.
Many never return.
Some waited too long to turn themselves
in and by the time the doctor saw them,
their toes had become purplish black.
It had to be amputated
because the ground was
frozen hard digging,
good fighting halls was nearly impossible.
Digging in became a matter of chipping a
shallow in the unyielding earth beneath
the snow than barricading it
with rocks or tree bridges.
Okay.
If any dead Chinese
were found on the hill,
we added they're stiff
corpses to the barricades.
Yeah,
to make level places for their guns.
The mortar men took turns at the concrete
like dirt within trenching tools and
combat knives
and
they're continuing in this freezing cold.
They get to a point where there
in sort of an open area,
and we'll go to the book that Chinese
maneuvered down from the ridge lines all
around us.
They ran across the snow in squad columns.
Then foreign firing lines among
the boulders or prone in the snow.
Chinese mortars began
to fall on us in the CP,
which was 50 yards or oss and the CPU,
which was 50 yards behind us,
around, exploded close by
and lifted me off the ground.
I was dazed for a while and
went full awareness returned.
Kelly had me by the arm leading me toward
the CP. Where are we going to Kelly?
I didn't understand why we were
heading away from the line.
Get a corpsman to look at you.
I thought you were gone or back there.
He pointed to my park of flapping around
my knees. It adds shrapnel holes in it.
They don't get closer than
that to tearing your balls off.
It's a good thing you
got me around lieutenant.
The corpsman at the CP was far too busy
with the seriously wounded to tend to my
mild concussion, the casualties
laying blanket covered rose,
doc, Torsky, Davis and topple. Those are
the corpsman went from one to the other.
They jabbed morphine, slowed bleeding,
cleaned out holes, blasted in Flash,
patched them and wrap
them as best they could.
The corpsman had their mouth filled with
mouth filled with Seretse of morphine
and their bare hands were bloody.
When they worked with the WWE,
they worked with enemy mortars,
exploding bullets,
stabbing the air two feet above them.
Weak,
frightened voices called for their help.
Doc Mickens from first
platoon took some shrapnel,
then a 25 that a slug in the leg where
he was patching the wounded in action on
woody Taylor's line.
This stretcher bearers,
drag Mickens to the CP and laid him
in the line of casualties next to him
damning the Chinese and his Arkansas
drawl was sergeant king who had been
blasted by grenades and hit by a burp gun.
Paul Renden on machine gunner with the
platoon lay there to a leg shot up the
first platoons rapid. The first
platoon was being rapidly depleted,
depleted and was having a hell of a
fight holding their end of the perimeter.
So these guys were, you had
a perimeter, like I said,
sort of an open area in the Chinese,
just calm down in there, you know,
full on attack on them,
full on back to the book.
The afternoon light faded and we worried
about whether the AMA would run out.
The Chinese said fully encircled us.
Their volume of fire was just
enough to keep us pin down.
They would wait for dark
than swarm over our lines.
They had plenty of people to do the job.
Our band nets were fixed
and our grenades ready.
Every man had a target sector and we
kept fire discipline to conserve ammo.
We began to settle in and wait for dark.
Okay.
As bullet zinged grenades exploded
and marines cried for help.
Someone yelled out that cop,
Captain Wilcox had been hit.
He taken a bullet to the face and a
piece of shrapnel and shattered his arm.
Joker Saba took over as our skipper.
Okay.
As soon as we heard about the captain,
we ran to the CP. We found him there.
His head wrapped in a big
white ball of a bandage,
unable to speak his blood soaked
sleeve dangled beside him.
He kept struggling to get on his feet.
When the docs put him down
on his spread out Poncho.
After awhile the morphine kicked in and
the skipper nodded off groaning softly
before they stabilize the line
around us. The Chinese, of course,
the first platoon back almost to the CP.
So you got the platoons.
The CP is the, is the kind of
like the brains of the unit,
right?
They got the different platoons are out
in the perimeter in 360 degrees and in
in the center of that, you've
got the command post, the CP,
and you have the radio men in there.
You have the people that are
going to do fire support,
maybe the mortar sections in there,
and then you have the
leadership is in that CP.
But now we start to see that the,
the platoons are getting
pushed back towards the CP.
They're losing their perimeter.
Just as Joe Casaba came in to
take over command of the company.
What he tailors stormed in demanding
that we get the hell Outta here.
The geeks have all the high ground.
They got us surrounded, he boomed.
They're going to pick
us to pieces tonight.
Joker Saba answered him quietly.
We need air support to
run interference for us.
Then we might be able to
make a break for the road.
The better get to work mighty fast.
Said woody,
we only have a few
minutes of daylight left,
so there's joker Sabas keeping it
cool again. World War II vet now,
just out here getting after it.
Yeah.
And
that's what they need.
So what they need is they need
the course errors to come in,
which if you don't know what a Coursera
course, there's an awesome aircraft,
World War II vintage and you can tell
them cause they have very distinctive
wings that have a distinctive
bend in them. And they're very uh,
very distinctive looking aircraft and
obviously very good at at close air
support. Back to book all
afternoon, Joe Hedrick,
the air controller had attempted to get
a piece of the air support dedicated to
the fifth marine.
So there was aircraft working on another
group of Marines working for another
group of Marines.
Now in the remaining minutes of daylight,
he caught a flight of four course
errors in search of action.
Then he calls those things in, gets,
gets them on the horn, calls him in.
And here we go.
The four Coursera street in Lowell above
us pointing themselves at the Chinese
position less than a hundred yards away.
They dropped their big earth shaking
bombs and they SCADE the long deep valley
with rockets and heavy caliber slugs.
The Chinese took cover and we moved out.
So that's covered. Move. Once again,
all they needed to do to get
out of this situation with,
they needed someone to
cover for their movement.
That's what they needed and they couldn't
supply it themselves because they're
shooting uphill,
didn't have the firepower income,
the corsairs to get after it and give
them cover to move back to the book I lost
ground in that day.
The Lad who,
who had tried hard to
be a good combat marine,
he was running toward me carrying
a helmet filled with grenades,
taken from the wounded when a
bullet tore through his throat.
The shot didn't knock him down at first,
just threw his head back and I saw a
fountain, a blood spurt from his neck.
He staggered a few steps,
then fell face forward and the snow,
which quickly turned red.
When I got to him,
he was already dead.
It took hours more for Baker one seven
to make its way the mile down the road.
Colonel Davis brought elements of
Charlie company out to meet us.
We loaded our dead and wounded on
waiting trucks and sent them back to you.
Dom knee. The Chinese had caught
off the MSR. That's a myth.
That's a main supply route
between you domini and Haga.
Rury the colonel informed us,
so now they are truly trapped on
the march back into the U. Dot.
Omni perimeter past midnight,
the men were silent,
spent from this cold,
brutal day and Captain Wilcox had been
a good skipper and when they get there,
Lee was waiting for us. When we
staggered into you dumb knee perimeter,
many of the men limped with the first
stages of frostbite and there were some
walking wounded who had elected
this stay with the company.
Undisguised tears ran down Lee's face
when he saw the column make its way in.
And that was the reason that Lee wasn't
with them was because he literally got
ordered 10 that he couldn't go because
his arm was becoming infected and he,
he was, he could not,
they would not let him go.
And so he's there an undisguised tears
down his face as he saw the column make
its way in.
Joker sobber formed us up at first light
while the core stairs were blazing at
enemy hills. He told us that
we were going to aid Charlie,
going to the aid of Charlie company,
which had been posted on Turkey hill
to guard the MSR last night after we
marched away from that area that
Chinese had poured out of the hills and
surrounded Charlie.
Charlie was fighting for its life when
we went to pull them out. So there's a,
there's a small company of Marines,
Charlie Company,
and they are surrounded.
They go up and one of the, one of the
abl companies, so you've got able,
Baker and Charlie able company sets up
on the flank and then Baker also patrols
up and kind of sets up to to come
to their aid. Back to the book,
through my binoculars,
I had a good view of Charlie's
perimeter for 100 yards away.
They were in a tight circle,
not more than 75 yards across
halfway up the slope of Turkey hill,
Chinese machine guns and rifles infested
the halo around them firing at any
marine who moved Charlie's people
were thoroughly pinned down.
So picture this a little circle,
see all your, your whole company.
Maybe there's a hundred maybe there
could be 150 but I think they've taken a
bunch of wounded,
but at this point,
but they've got a hundred guys in a little
75 meter circle and you're all pinned
down and no matter what, every time you
move, every time his head gets stuck up,
you're getting shot at.
Back to the book lead,
put his machine guns on the Chinese who
were firing into Charlie's perimeter
from lower slope.
My three mortars had the same target
ables machine guns and mortars raped the
hill above the perimeter.
Soon our tracers line the sky and puffs
of black smoke from the mortars dotted
the rocky hill.
Then the big shells from artillery and
the battalion's 81 started to fall and
the hail rocked with their explosions.
Chinese soldiers scurried for cover.
My classmate pay attention to this.
My classmate gin Stemple led ables
assault down the ridge line and into the
Chinese.
The enemy soldiers had their heads down
from the heavy covering fire. Once again,
covering fire and Stempel's platoon
tore into them through the binoculars.
I observed one squad of temple's Marines,
led by a giant of a man in a flapping
Parker who swung a huge double headed ax.
The Chinese soldiers seeing this
great maniacal devil charge it.
Then branding brandishing a bloody ax,
abandoned their positions in terror.
So there you have it. I've never, I never,
I don't even know where you get a
battleax in the midst of the Korean War,
but this marine right here attacks
the Chinese not with grenades,
not with a bar, not with a machine gun.
He attacks with a freaking battle ax.
Okay.
Back to the book.
That Chinese quickly lifted their seeds
of Charlie Company and made a rapid
retreat from Turkey hill. As they
fled able companies downhill assault,
they had to cross Baker's line of fire.
Woody Taylor's platoon had come up to
extend our line in every weapon we had was
trained on the Chinese says they ran to
the protecting slopes on the other side
of the valley. Turkey shoot at
Turkey hill are people called it.
We were at rapid fire with the mortars
and machine gun and machine guns,
the bars and there, and the rifles.
Even call Vars, rocket launcher.
Few Chinese made it all the way across
the gauntlet of exploding flaming steel.
They dropped and heaps even before the
Australian planes came down on them.
We hadn't worked with the Australians
before and they were out to prove that
there was gung Ho is our
own Marine Corps pilots.
They came roaring low along the valley
from behind us and when they passed above
Lee's glowing pink vest,
they dropped even closer to the ground.
They're, they're low enough to cut off
the chinks. Pigtails, Kelly quipped,
the planes had their blood there,
guns blazing and the Chinese
went down and bunches.
The Australians made two passes at the
end of their second low level of salt.
There were no Chinese
soldiers left to shoot that.
It took almost every able bodied man
that Charlie company had to bring down
their dead and wounded there overnight.
Defense of Turkey hill had costs dearly
and they got one more rescue
mission basically to do.
There was a uh,
Fox company is now in another situation,
you know,
horrible scenario and first Baker one
seven needs to get to them and it is a
treacherous, treacherous
movement. And they decide,
you remember early in the book you said,
you know,
we weren't used to night fighting. They'd
be mostly work during the day. Well,
they decide that they need to do this
at night so they go on this patrol at
night. Going back to the book
under the heavy Parker's,
our body sweated with the strain, but
our hands and feet were frozen, numb.
The wind borne cold
attacked with terrible fury.
When we stopped for bearings,
we stood silent and motionless
because we needed to maintain Silas.
We could not slap our hands against our
sides or stomp our feet for circulation.
The cold gnawed at our toes and
fingers and ate into our bodies.
The sweat we generated,
wall climbing froze against our skin.
We shivered violently. Men muttered
through their clenched teeth. Some of our,
we're freezing to death here
and they push on.
I returned to, decided to call them.
Many men had collapsed in the snow,
curled into balls like Eskimo dogs and
CEO's moved along the fallen prodding and
kicking,
urging them to their feet.
I collided with another marine
churning forward through the snow.
Both of us fell and as
we weirdly recovered,
I realized that I had knocked down
Colonel Davis. What's the holdup?
Lieutenant was all my
battalion commander said.
Then he continued breaking through
the snow to the head of the call.
Time had no meaning.
We labored through infinite darkness and
ghostly clouds of snow over an icy path
that rose and fell,
but seem to lead nowhere.
We saw only the back of a man's head,
a hunched figure in a long
shapeless Parker who's every
tortured step was an act
of will.
We carried on with the only
strength that was left to us.
Marine core discipline.
Yeah.
They finally get within range after this
brutal freezing march and here we go.
The night exploded with the
flash and sound of the fight.
The marines had the advantage
of surprise and momentum.
They fought with fierce energy. Now
released from hours of cold and misery.
The Chinese could do little
more than try to escape.
Many of them were on armed
and most ran off to the south,
so the the the Chinese run,
there's some firing,
there's some shooting,
but it's pretty much our route because
they had gone at night and they had
pushed harder. They had that
surprise and violence of action.
Back to the book.
Dawn arrived gray and cold and we
jumped off the second phase of the
breakthrough.
Able and Baker attacked online,
headed out for Fox hill
a thousand yards away.
Minutes after we moved out.
Kaiser's platoon on the left walked into
heavy small arms machine gun fire from
a ridge on his flank.
The sixties responded with h e on the
ridge and Kaiser's people broke through
the deep snow to melt the hill.
When they neared the ridge line,
we lifted mortar fire and the platoon
drove through the enemy position on its
own firepower cover and move added again.
We were astonished by our
first view of Fox Hill.
The snow field that led up
to the embattled company's
position was covered with
hundreds of dead Chinese soldiers.
Many of them seem to sleep
under blankets of drifted snow,
but their bodies were
frozen in spasms of pain.
There would jumbles of corpses
in padded green uniforms.
A white clad column had fallen in the
formation that it attracted the attention
of Fox company's machine gunners.
Craters of dirt and snow made by the big
guns were rimmed with bodies and parts
of men,
thick bands of dead Chinese lay at
the base of Fox company's perimeter.
We stood in wonder men
bowed their heads in prayer.
Some fell to their knees or their
brief quiet ost oats of disbelief.
Tears came to the eyes of raggedy marines
who had endured bitter cold and savage
battle to reach this place
of suffering and courage.
Someone let loose a wild cheer and we
broke forward in a jubilant run across the
snow covered at corpse field battlefield.
The Marines of Fox company waved
brightly colored banners. The blue,
yellow and red remnants
of the parachute drops it.
It sustained them for nearly a week
around their perimeter.
Fox company had constructed barricades
of frozen Chinese bodies from behind
these walls of of the d from
behind these walls of dead.
The marines had mounted their weapons
and maintain a fight against an enemy
who's number's never ceased.
Now,
the men of Fox company arose from behind
these groups and piles to join us arms,
slings and blood.
SOCOM presses were common among them.
Med hobbled about with makeshift
leg splints. All hands,
we're haggard at dirty as we're we.
We exchanged profane greetings that did
not conceal the love that we marines
felt for each other.
The Sun came out and marines appeared
along the skyline's to the north.
Then we saw marines marching
down the MSR towards us.
There were columns of riflemen at first
followed by a long trail of vehicle and
the vehicles and artillery pieces
are Corsair, swooped in close.
They're crooked,
wings wagging and salute.
The fifth and Seventh Marines
had broken out of you. Dumb knee.
Now they broke out.
They have a path,
but they still have to go 14
miles to get out of there.
Back to the book.
All the platoon sergeants had been hit,
as were most of the squad leaders.
We had corporals and privates
stepping into leadership billets,
but they were combat experienced
marines and they knew the work.
The Marine column that came
out of the besieged, do you?
Dom knee had hundreds of jeeps,
ambulances and trucks as well as the
big guns of the artillery regiment.
Many of the trucks were filled with
wounded men and some were stacked with the
corpses of our own killed in action,
the walking wounded.
So now you've got to picture this column
like almost like a mad looking column.
The walking wounded who could carry a
weapon work turned to as riflemen to
protect the column.
Every man who could walk,
hobble or limp was ordered off the trucks.
The only riders were those serious cases,
the gut wounds and blinded men along
with severe leg wounds and men with
frostbite so bad that they
would need amputation.
Okay?
Many of the wounded died in the trucks,
some froze to death and some
were shot by the infiltrators.
The 14 mile ride was three days
and nights of grim survival.
The rifle companies of the
fifth and seventh marine
stayed in the hills guarding
the MSR is the column pulled in to Haggar.
Rury.
The garrison town came out to meet the
bedraggled Marines who had run the 14
mile gauntlet of fire and ice.
As the walking wounded came
with inside of the town,
someone commanded them to fall into ranks.
Maybe it was the limping sergeant who
gave the command the old salt who had set
the defenses along Bob
Fisher's stretch of the column.
It could have been father Griffin.
We're sergeant wing it.
We're corporate Burris
or Corporal Johnson,
the wounded men and some who are unharmed,
but who staggered from exhaustion
formed up into three files,
shouldered their weapons
and marched and ragged step
slowly the tread of their thick rubber
soled Pat Schou packs on the icy road
became a steady sure cadence and the
haggard and hurt marines put their heads
high.
Captain Wilcox,
who couldn't carry a weapon
was in the Ford ranks.
His arm was in a huge cast and splinted
so it was horizontal to the deck.
His head and face were a cocoon of
bandages, but holding himself erect.
He picked up the cadence in March,
standing straight into Haga Rury,
a battalion sergeant at battalion surgeon
took time away from the hundreds of
wounded men. He tended in the aid
station to witness the columns,
arrival,
those bastards,
those magnificent bastards were the words
the doctor used to describe the worn
and torn marines from you dumb knee.
And I want you to,
I want you to picture that image,
okay?
That image of these hundreds
of men just battered, wounded,
barely even able to walk frostbitten and
they're meandering into camp and when
they get close, someone
says, Hey, fall in.
And they fall into ranks
and they begin to march
will.
That's human will and it's human
will under the power of leadership.
And he doesn't even know who gave that
order. Somebody said, fall in the ranks.
It's the right thing to do.
And they do it.
They find more,
they find,
they dig deeper to fallen to ranks and
hold their heads high as they walk back
into town.
Back to the book,
except for the road we had
opened Haga Rury was under siege,
surrounded by many thousands
of Chinese soldiers.
They had been held off by a battalion
of the first marines and a hundreds of
rear echelon people who had reverted
to rifleman for three days and nights.
The cooks and bakers truck
drivers and artillery men office,
pinkies and technicians dug
in alongside infantry marines.
They threw back every thrust the Chinese
made against the Hagia Rury perimeter.
American soldiers were there to army
technical support people who picked up
rifles and bars and went up the
hills and filled in the marine lines.
Wherever there were gaps.
The artillery through an massive
bombardments during daylight hours,
the coursers flew in low with bombs,
rockets and napalm to help
hold the attackers at bay.
The three divisions of Chinese who
tried to isolate the fifth and seventh
marines,
plus those who had been at Fox hill
followed us south and now they added their
numbers to the Incircl Mint of Hagia Rury,
the single road,
the MSR to kowtow re and our only
way out was caught off the hills.
That flank that road were high and steep
and there were as many Chinese embedded
in them as their head
been at you dumb knee.
So there's still completely surrounded,
but all this stuff is happening.
There's still surrounded
the engineers with their heavy earth
moving equipment had dynamited the frozen
ground and leveled and airfield large
enough for cargo planes to fly in and out
of Hagia Rury air force pilots flew
in the big clumsy planes loaded with
replacements,
rations and ammunition
for the return trip.
They filled the plains with
the most seriously wounded.
When they landed and took off,
they had to fly low between
the hills that line the valley,
the planes became slow moving targets
for the Chinese guns in the hills and
every one that left Haga Rury
was perforated with bullet holes.
The men on the ground marveled at the
courage of the air force pilots who kept
flying in and out of there.
So you've got just cargo pilots
flying in to this place in sanity
now?
Yeah,
they're in a position on a perimeter
because just because they survived all
that, they still gotta to go
back out and hold perimeter.
They get out to hold
perimeter and here we go.
Back to the book through my glasses,
I saw column of 15 rifleman marching
toward us out of Hagia Rury.
There were two files and then moving
at a brisk pace alongside the road,
but alongside both sides of the road.
They weren't crisp,
White Parker's and swung their arms
smartly because they were clean shaven and
an energetic, we assumed they were fresh
replacements flown in from the airstrip.
We found out later that these clean
and jumped he troops were royal British
Marines who had fought their way
into Haga Rury from the south.
They too had found the MSR blocked and
they had punched through the Chinese
forces,
far superior to them a number.
They were the 41st commando,
a unit that roughly compared in size to
one of our own rifle companies like us.
These marines had
suffered heavy casualties.
The Royal Marine column halted in spread
into ditches along the road near our CP.
A freshly groomed young officer's strode
toward Kelly topple and me with the
young officer was a grizzled sergeant
whose proper military bearing could have
come straight from the pages of Kipling.
The sergeant had a meticulously trimmed
broad mustache that would've stirred
gunny Buckley's envy,
like the lieutenant or the sergeant
was dazzling, clean, and squared away,
right binoculars hung around my neck,
which is how the lieutenant
distinguished me as an officer.
Certainly there was little
other difference among
Kelly and topple and me are
Parker's were all stained with blood food,
gun oil,
dirt are filthy.
Faces were matted with bristly beards
that bore icicles of mucus and spittle.
The lieutenant concealed his
disdain for our appearance,
braced himself and delivered a
broad hand salute. I say, sir,
we've ordered to extend our
patrol beyond your lines, um,
to get up the covering machine guns
and I would be most grateful for your
suggestions.
I appreciated the British lieutenants,
Kurtz courtesy,
and if I possessed a ranger,
I would have shaved on the spot to
make myself more presentable. Says,
one of the reasons I included this,
because people always ask me, you know,
you ever work with any other militaries?
And I've worked with the British and
people say, you know, how are they? Well,
this is how the British are.
The British are outstanding,
the are so professional.
It's, it's, it's great.
It's so impressive. They're
like impeccable. Just the
way they're described her.
That's the way the British art,
that's the way the British military,
as their outstanding
back to the book,
the Royal Marine Lieutenant and his
sergeant followed me to our machine gun
positions and they checked out the
fields of fire for their own mission.
As we walked the line together,
we exchanged observations
about fighting the Chinese.
The British lieutenant knew
what he was talking about.
Okay.
Cock a little bit about the army units.
The army outfits that went east to the
reservoir were her be patched together
and poorly equipped for their mission.
The artillery and tanks that
were to support their advantage.
We're not organized in time to accompany
them when they move north of how out of
Hagia rowry the heavy weapons that
aided the marine breakout west of the
reservoir.
We're not there for the army and many of
the soldiers in that fight had not yet
received cold weather gear
scores of them froze to death.
It was the army's bad fortune to that.
A large number of its officers and
experienced NCO is had been knocked out of
the battle out at the onset,
the two senior commanders occur,
a colonel and the lieutenant colonel
was killed at the front of their troops.
Most of the company commanders and
platoon leaders went down in a short time.
The casualties of all ranks outnumbered
the able bodied and some of the wounded
had to be left behind,
but tunes and squads dwindled to a few
men and coalesced into small bands that
fought until their ammunition was gone.
Those who could walk or crawl then
made their way back across the frozen
reservoir to the marine lines
at [inaudible] for the soldiers.
It was a disastrous fight,
but it had one good effect.
The Chinese division that mold them
was aimed at the attack on Haga Rury.
The fight the soldiers put up on the east
side of the reservoir had slowed their
advance and that bought valuable time
for the marines and the army survivors
made their way into hogger Rury.
Those who could still carry on were
reequipped and formed into a provisional
battalion. That became part
of the First Marine Division,
a fall along side us for the
remainder of the campaign.
Now,
well, like I said, at this point,
there's still surrounded and they need
to now break out to get south to a town
called Hung Naum where there's a port
where they're going to be extracted during
be pulled out.
Back to the book,
one seven Arba and two seven where to
lead the breakout from Cotto re one seven
was to take the high ground east of the
road to seven the west four miles on the
MSR. The Chinese had blown out
a bridge over a deep chasms.
The battalion first marines coming from
the south would take the ground that
commanded the other side of that gap.
Then the engineer's were putting in a
new bridge beyond that was a full army
division.
The third waiting to give us cover.
After we crossed the bridge,
the army would take over the fighting.
All we needed to do was
get a few more divisions,
get through a few more
divisions of Chinese soldiers.
So even on the division level,
10,000 we're talking,
covering move even on the division level.
So it's an individual thing.
It's a squad thing.
It's a platoon thing.
It goes all the way up to the division
level because they need to have the cover
of the army to get out of there.
Here we go.
April company went out in front.
The Chinese, the weighting,
Chinese immediately put down a sheet
of fire, mortars, machine guns,
burp guns, rifles. April's
casualty. Soon started to return.
We huddled against the blowing
clouds of snow and prayed to God.
That able wouldn't get so badly malt
that we would have to take their place.
Our prayers were not answered.
Battalion ordered us to pass through
Abel and continue the attack.
Although it was daylight,
we could barely see where we were going.
The Chinese did not need to see us.
There was only one way for us to get
it damaged straight along the road.
They had our approach well marked
and covered with their weapons.
As soon as we went past able,
the Chinese mortars began to drop
and their machine guns opened.
The tracers where weird streaks of orange
that flew out of the blinding snow.
Clouds are new.
Korman was quickly put to work.
The Chinese were shooting down from a
hill that flanked woody as well as from
straight ahead.
Joe didn't want to send anyone up that
hill fearing he would lose them in the
heavy snow. I keep, you're
just getting shot at the,
there's clouds up there at altitude and
so you're just getting shot from snow.
It's like a cloud. That shooting machine
gun fire at you. It's a nightmare.
Back to the book.
We were getting nowhere joke or Saba
was standing alongside the road behind
Lee's platoon.
He called me over to him.
Bullet zinged in shrapnel wind around us,
but Joe stood straight
and I stood with him.
He decided to risk and move
up the hill on the left flank.
Move Your platoon up there, Joe.
Oh, by the way, at this point,
Joe had taken over a platoon. He was no
longer just in charge of mortars. Now,
one of the sergeants was
in charge of the mortars,
so he's now in charge of a rifle
platoon. Move Your platoon up there, Joe.
He instructed me, see if you can
take those guns out there killing us.
He spread out his mat and trace the route,
spread out his map.
They trace the route that I was to follow.
He fell silent.
A Chinese bullet had found its target
just below the rim of his helmet in the
center of his forehead.
A small black hole appeared there.
Joke or Saab is dead.
Eyes stared at me for several seconds
before he slumped slowly to the ground.
I caught him in my arms as he
fell and held him for a moment.
Then I lowered him gently into
this snow. Jesus. God joke,
her Saba, my friend Joe, who had
helped me so much show me so much,
who had gone to bat for me with Captain
Wilcox, who had been my big brother,
joker Saba,
whom I loved
taking the mat from his mitten hands.
I went forward to give it to Lee and
inform him that he was the new company
commander.
Okay.
On the way over,
I got on my walkie talkie to tell
battalion that Casaba was Kiaa.
Their CP was close behind in the walkie
talkie, worked through the Merck.
I spotted Lee's vest.
He was walking the line behind his men
who were prone in the snow covering 50
yards upfront.
Looper cine with the bar was with him.
I felt alone without Kelly.
The Chinese fire was passing overhead
high. The enemy couldn't see us either.
Casabas dead.
I told Lee caught one in the head.
Dam was all Lee said in response,
you're the new skipper.
I added giving him the map.
Joe told me to go up the
hill on Woody's flank.
See if I can get around
those guns and take them out.
You still want me to do that?
We must do something.
Lisa said they're killing us up from
up there. That's what Joe said. Yes.
See what you can do. Is Your
radio working? Yeah, I just
talked to battalion on it.
Okay. Let me know the situation when you
make it and when you're ready to attack.
If we can get artillery. I don't want
you to want run into friendly fire.
I skipper.
I said First Lieutenant Lee gave
me an ironic little smile at that,
so they're going to go up this hill and
try and take out that machine gun and as
they're going up the hill,
he starts hearing something.
Someone called from behind us,
sir. Lieutenant owned Owen.
It was woody Taylor's runner.
He was breathing hard from the effort
he had made to catch up with us. Sir,
Lieutenant Taylor wants you
back down with the company.
Lieutenant Lee's been hit and Lieutenant
Taylor wants you on the double. He says,
damn it to hell.
I might've been able to roll the Chinese
from the flank and take out the guns
that were holding back the company.
I tried to get woody on my walkie talkie.
I got more static.
I waived for Morrison to rejoin us and
the tiny platoons slipped and slid back
down the hill as they came behind me.
The men,
Kirsten complain about the second
lieutenants making up their mind.
What he tailored,
waited for us at the base of the slope.
He was senior to me in rank and with lead
down. He was our new company commander.
He said that battalion had sent up a
pair of tanks and their firepower would
cover a frontal assault up the hill.
So here we go.
Finally we get tanks in. Anyone that
doesn't know I am a huge fan of tanks.
I love tanks and all
you tankers out there,
thank you for being out there
for these ground pounders.
So he couldn't, the old school tanks, they
had a little phone on the back of the,
on the back of the tank to talk to
the guys that were inside the tank.
He picks up that tank as they get
prepared to do this assault and he says,
put your thirties up below the ridge.
Goop,
wishing going to 10 o'clock then on
my command, hit them with the cannons.
We'll jump off on that.
A tinny voice came from within the tank.
Hear you loud and clear.
The 30 caliber twin machine
guns of both tanks began there.
Jack Hammer pounding.
I watched red tracers stabbing up the
snow covered hill toward the Doug and
Chinese gun that we could now see dimly
now the under that fire power, they start
to attack our line. Moved up the hill,
25 yards above me to Chinese soldiers
appeared from behind a large boulder one
had a rifle, the other burp gun. As
I swung my car being toward them,
I heard a grunt from Lupa cine.
He fired his bar straight into the
air and he fell forward in the snow.
He did not move and I knew he was dead.
The best bar man we had,
God dammit,
you've lost Lupa cine.
I couldn't get my weapon on the
two Chinese above me fast enough.
The one with the rifle put around in my
left shoulder that spun me around its
impact,
generated a shock,
like a powerful jolt of electricity
that went through my entire body.
Damn. How can I be hit after all
of this? How could I get hit?
I saw the burp gun trigger a burst at me.
The snout of his weapon flashed and I
could not lift my feet above my need of
above the knee deep snow to get
out of the path of his bullets.
Two slugs tore into my right arm to more
of the electric jolts and my car being
flung itself away from my grasp.
I saw it rise into the air.
As I fell into the snow,
this cannot be happening.
I tried to raise my head and reach to
retrieve my car being get the bastards.
My arms wouldn't move.
I could not raise myself.
Joe's down. Someone shouted, Bill
Flux Voice, get the bastards.
I heard myself yelling,
get the bastards.
I screamed in pain and overwhelming anger
and my marines rushed past me and up
the hill leaving Lupa cine and me
and the snow. Get the bastards.
I yelled again and again.
It was all I could think to do.
The young corpsman who had been assigned
to us for the day's battle cry for the
day's battle. Heard my screams. Although
the enemy fire steel flayed the hill,
he ran clubs lead through
the snow to reach my side.
I was flat on my back and he
crouched beside me. Okay, Lieutenant,
he gasped for air with the exertion of
the run laden with his aid kit and cold
weather gear. His breath made puffs
of white steam and is smooth shaven.
Face was red with 25 below
zero cold with bullets.
Zinging all around of the new corner.
Cutaway my Parker,
the bullet through the shoulder,
it nicked my lung and blood was gushed
and blood gushed from my mouth and down
the front of my parka covering his
bare hands. Give me some morphine.
I told the kid the pain was
terrible. I can't sir, I'm sorry.
He shook with the cold and with his own
fear bullets stung the air and raise
little fountains of snow a few feet away.
Gimme some goddamn morphine. I yelled,
spraying my blood on him,
sir. The morphine is frozen.
I can't give it to you.
What the Hell is wrong with you?
Carry the goddamn stuff in your
mouth, don't you boots snow. Yes sir.
I'm sorry sir.
He put the surette in his mouth and
continued to cut away at my clothing.
Just just try and be still, sir.
Even with the pain and the rage,
I realized that no one had told the new
doc how to take care of casualties in
below zero weather.
I gritted my teeth and tried to shut up.
I didn't feel the jab when he shoved
the syringe surette into my flesh,
but I soon felt a wave
of warmth come over me.
The pain float away and the noise
of the fighting above us receded.
You're a good lad. I told the corpsman
I felt his hands doing something.
You'll be a good marine.
Yes sir.
He sounded far away before I drifted off.
I remembered the photos in my helmet.
Those are the photos of his wife and
his two kids. My pictures. I said,
that's my wife and kids. Don't
let the geeks get them. I won't,
sir,
said the corpsman who had risked his
life to save mine and who's name I never
knew.
Woody Taylor was the only law
officer left with the company.
He let the troops, the crest of the
hill fighting as a rifle man himself.
The Chinese were on the run and battalion
ordered Bacon one seven to keep after
them.
The troops were frozen and exhausted,
but wardee pushed them on.
Okay.
Late in the day they reached their
objective with their small number.
They set a tight perimeter on the high
ground overlooking the gap in the road
that engineers would bridge the next day.
So they get that targets cure.
They get that hilltop and now they're
overlooking the gap where the engineers
are going to build that bridge and
they sat in to a security perimeter.
Woody Taylor put the weary company on
50% watch against the enemy assault he
knew would come in the dark.
It was the coldest night that the men
had yet endured a reported 30 degrees
below zero. The wind howled
at them and every direction,
all through the unbearably cold hours
until dawn Taylor and Sergeant Richard
move from man to man to assure
that no one froze to death.
A detail of Korean soldiers who had been
attached to the army arrived to bolster
the perimeter. But most of them
filtered away during the night.
Yeah.
Several Times. Marines hurt the enemy
moving around their lines in the darkness,
but no attack came would he put out
patrols early in the morning before light.
Okay.
Within a hundred yards of a wine,
they found frozen dozens of frozen
Chinese soldiers whose feet and hands were
frozen to ice.
The extreme cold had been on our
side holding back the attack.
Yeah.
And the next day would he,
Taylor brought the remnants of
the company down from the hills,
marched them across the bridge and into
the shelter of the Chow town of Chin,
Hong knee,
their battle and did there
sergeant Richard took roll call,
his final count.
Where's 27 men?
Okay.
27 minutes.
And that is,
that's out of the original
200 plus men of the company.
And then on top of that,
another hundred replacements that
filled their ranks in this battle.
So that's 300 men and only 27 remained
now
few of us will ever
face those kind of odds
in few of us are ever going
to face those hellish demands.
You of us will ever stare
at Hale like these men did.
But
I want you to think about something.
I want you to imagine.
Imagine what we can accomplish if we
applied even a fraction of the will that
these men displayed,
the iron will
oh will that is stronger than their
bodies a will that is stronger than their
minds
because clearly let's face it,
their bodies,
yeah,
their bodies were broken
and their minds in many cases or broken
and they didn't want to go on,
but there will,
there will prevailed.
Okay
will
we'll conquers all
and our will is delivered
through discipline
and as Joe Owen stated
many times in the book,
sometimes the only thing that
press them on was disciplined
discipline,
the discipline to push
yourself and you know, we
are all capable of more
I and capable of more.
You are capable of more,
you can overcome the obstacles
and the challenges and the enemy,
and you can overcome your own weaknesses.
Thank you.
Can overcome your own desire to quit.
Let let bees men
that these men be our examples
of how to fight
in,
how to use your will and how to drive on
and let these men B are examples of how
to live
or don't.
Don't let these men down.
And I think that's all
I've got for tonight. Echo.
If you,
uh,
want to give me a second here to recover
and talk about some stuff over there,
I'd be much obliged. Yeah, man,
this could be one of the
rougher of transitions. Yeah.
You know, it's, you gotta remind yourself,
this is a book. This
happened, this happened,
this happened,
this happened
in the fact that these guys
could endure this and fight on.
If that doesn't give you the inspiration
that you need to step pass whatever
pathetic little challenges in
front of you, you're wrong.
Don't listen to this podcast anymore.
Go somewhere else.
Yeah.
It's easy to forget it because of
the kind of the contrast of your,
like your problem or whatever you want
to call it, your challenge, your task,
right issue that you're
trying to overcome.
And then contrast with basically the
luxury that you live in and that luxury is
kind of put on you this kind of
way of feeling on a habitual level.
So
now you're faced with
this task comparatively.
Habitual comfort is what we experienced.
Yes. Habitual Comfort. Exactly right.
So then one night I woke up
early in the morning. Yeah.
Okay.
You know what I mean? Hey, I worked
out real hard and sweated a lot. Okay.
Well really is that all I got? I need
to step it up man. I need to step it up.
Yeah. And you know, I woke up
early in the morning or you know,
I didn't get that much sleep.
So my real hardcore yeah,
your foot's not freezing off of your body.
Yeah. You know what I mean? Yeah. And,
and what's, what's incredible, this is
every single time you go, damn, you know,
I'm glad they made it out of that didn't
make it out anything that they're still
just, just surrounded. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, what's is when you do remind
yourself of this kind of stuff, like,
like right now, if you knew one
feels the way I do, I feel like, oh,
I feel pretty much rejuvenating.
And when I kind of flashed back to my
life for a second, yeah. I'm like, Oh man,
I'm kind of stoked. Yeah. I can
go, you know, if I got to work out,
I'm going to crush that workup
because I got all my limbs right now.
They didn't freeze off all this stuff.
So the point there is,
when you re are reminded
of real adversity,
whether you remind yourself or the, or a
book or something you see or hear about,
um, like it, it gives you
that, like that added will to,
to overcome.
Maybe you,
you actually can take some
of their wheels. You can
learn it, you can learn it.
You can say, Oh, you know what? Oh, I'm
cold right now. You're not cold, you're,
you're in. You are not cold. You
are not, you're tired right now. No,
you are not tired. You're afraid
right now. No. You are not afraid.
Learn. Yeah. Yeah. Learn,
increase your will through knowledge.
It's a real thing. Yup. It's true.
And when you do,
with my point being,
when you do remind yourself of
this kind of stuff and it helps,
it'll help you do whatever it is or,
or overcome the faculty.
Yeah.
Because you realize that you,
that human beings are capable of
more way more than once, you know,
you know more than I know I'm
capable of more than what I've done.
I'm going to do more. I'm going to
get after it harder. That's the,
that's what I take away from this.
These kind of books obviously besides,
there's incredible tactical lessons in
there. There's incredible leadership.
There's incredible, but that
the, the testament of cumin will,
is income is unbelievable.
Unbelievable Testament.
Yeah.
So now I feel like,
or it seems like you knew that when
we're faced or when I'm faced with like,
oh, this is too hard, or, Dang, I got all
this ahead of me to, I got to do all this,
all really,
all that is now looking at it.
It seems like all it is is a
deviation from my habitual comfort.
That's all it is.
And I'll tell you what was awesome.
The way that he reinforced it reinforced
several times because people talk about
fear. I've talked about fear
on this podcast before, but
you know, I kind of say,
Hey, take action. If you're
afraid, you've got to step into it.
And she said that over and over again.
He actually had a methodology. Okay,
if I'm afraid I'm gonna, I'm gonna
get my, I'm going to stand up.
I'm going to get a record. I'm gonna find
out what's going on and I'm gonna get,
I'm going to,
I'm going to find out.
I'm going to assess the situation
before my boss calls me.
That's my timeline that I'm working on.
And that forces them to take action.
You know, so many, so many
great lessons learned in there.
Well yeah, I feel like, yeah, we can
transition over to used to support.
We'll, yeah, if we want, if people,
if people do want to support
the podcast out there,
I guess you could if you're in the
mood of how to do that. Uh, yeah.
So the first way, and this is kind
of a two way street, you know,
um, okay on its supplements, right?
Supplements, all kinds of cool stuff.
In fact, my friend from quiet Cameron,
he hit me up and was like, Hey,
what's on it has this,
it's a new uh,
preworkout you know,
but it's non stimulant.
Usually preworkouts crush up a bunch
of Phaedra and these feed it to you.
They don't actually do that,
but it seems like they do,
I'm not saying that's all a bad thing,
but it's not like healthy, you know?
So anyway, this one is like a healthy
one is like nonstimulant who's check? Oh,
I got, I just got it.
Haven't tried it yet,
but I'm going to get a report
back to us once you've tried it.
But if you're into like,
you know,
sometimes you go on the website and you
get like caught up reading all the cool
stuff and all this stuff like that.
It's on there so you can look at it and
see how good you actually mentioned that
a lot. How you go to the
Onnit website and you know,
I maybe I just don't do as thorough
research as you when it comes to checking
out where my krill oil comes from.
But sure,
I know what I'm looking
for it and I go do it.
But if you're more like echo and you
want to spend time on the website reading
and researching,
it's a good place to do is on [inaudible]
dot com throw a slash Jocko on there.
If you want to get a little buddy saved.
Yeah,
if you want to send save 10% 10% off
slash Jockos it's on it.com/jocko anyway,
they've got some good stuff. You can
pretty much rest and not pretty much.
You can rest assured
that it's all good stuff.
It's not a bunch of federal crushed
in two powder form, you know,
and they're selling it as a,
I dunno,
it's Krill vasodilator
or something like this.
It's not that big words echo
I read. No. So anyway. Yeah,
10% off on it's on it.com/jocko
shroom tech is dope to Alpha brain.
These are all part of the,
what do you call the EDC?
Everyday carry every day. Every everyday
consumption. Everyday consumption.
I like that. Right Buddy? See Yeah.
Krill oil took that today already out
for brain. That's like every other day.
It depends on PODC.
Yeah.
Get on Alpha brain every day.
Some people take it every day.
Some people take shroom tech every day.
Yeah. I take from tech when needed. Yeah.
When anticipated needed Krill oil
everyday. Krill oil every day for sure.
Without question. Strong
bone everyday. Yeah.
I got this peanut butter
or your bar when needed.
I've been having one every two every day
for the past four days because it's so
easy.
Oh,
I want to eat something healthy and
that tastes good and then we'll kind of
hungry and I want to get it really
quickly without having to do anything but
peel open a rapper, boom,
warrior bars in the house,
no guarantee.
But yeah,
there's some cool stuff and I got
this peanut butter peanut butter,
cashew almond and I don't know
something else, but it's real good.
It's real core to MCT oil.
It's all up in there anyway.
Good stuff. Trying to of
MCT oil too, by the way.
I take the coconut MCT oil from on it
and I mixed it with heavy whipping cream.
I don't, yeah, I don't do
that until it's whipped cream.
I just pour it in a little bit in there.
I stirred up and I drink heavy
whipping cream, which is just all fat,
which is awesome with MCT, which is more
fat and I didn't drink all that. Yeah,
and it's a good fat. It's good
fat, but it also, it's, it's very,
very fulfilling. Very, very notes.
But I'm not, I'm talking, I almost,
it's a little bit big when I have little
glasses that I mix it in there bigger
than a shot glass,
but they're smaller than a cocktail glass.
It's called the rocks glass
perhaps in the bar industry.
You know more about that stuff.
Yeah, it's bigger than MCT.
I mean not to go into all the fats and
good feathers, but it's more fulfilling.
Fat has nine calories per gram.
Carbohydrates and protein
have for alcohol. Seven
little trivia. I was not aware of that.
Yeah, it's all good. Alcohol is not,
I don't think they still icon on
it, so you're all good there. Um,
but that's a good way.
I feel like I'm repeating
it on it.com/jocko but if
you do want the 10% off,
you got to add the slash Jocko if
you want to put, pay the full price,
which is cool too by the way.
Just go on and.com anyway,
another way to support, if you're in
the mood to support the Amazon link,
click through. It's Christmas.
Chris coming. Christmas is
coming up. What is today?
Whatever the date is today,
Christmas coming up. We then
within what, three weeks,
two weeks, whatever. Anyway, and when you
do your shopping, if you're like, Hey,
I'm going to shop for Christmas for
my friends, family, whatever, and
it's in your mind that you want to
support podcast, just go to our website,
[inaudible] dot com or Jocko Jocko,
podcast.com a lot of people ask me,
hey, where are your favorite
books that you've read?
Can you send us a list of
those? And I said, yeah,
go to www.jockopodcast.com all the books
that we've talked about on the podcast,
the book that I read today, go and buy
it. Yeah. Going by it colder than hell.
A Marine Rifle Company at chosen
reservoir by Joseph are Owen. Buy It.
Read it. I could've, I could've
just read the entire book on Air.
Obviously I'm not going to do that,
but take a long time.
It would take a long time,
but there's so much stuff that I,
that I absolutely had to skip and say,
you know,
I was like struggling with myself going,
I used up most of a highlighter
and a half highlighting this book,
so you order this book,
you will have it on the website.
It's page. All of them are on there.
Yeah, on the pit you go top menu,
you know books from the podcast,
I think it's called.
You Click on it and there's links
directly to Amazon. Yeah, play out. Boom.
There's another way to support, but
it's all Amazon. You Click through a,
if you guys just doing regular shopping,
there's a banner on the
kind of the right side.
You Click through there
and do your shopping and it
supports the podcasts to two
birds, one kind of thing. Anyway,
also you can subscribe
to the podcast on iTunes.
We Jocko, we'll probably well know
you already mentioned this. Oh,
we got on the top podcasts of 2016 list.
I too. Big Deal. Anyway, so it's
great to their youtube, not youtube,
iTunes.
We were on the top podcasts of 2016
list from iTunes is your statement,
correct? Yep. Yeah, that just popped
in my head because when you subscribe,
you subscribe on Itunes, leave
a review. If you're in the mood,
actually leave a review
and make sure it's awesome.
Not Awesome in terms of good, but just
make sure that it's fun for me to read.
That will invoke more,
uh,
the will to read or if it's not fun to
read some good points that you like or
don't like. And yeah, I like
reading those reviews. I do,
I read every single review,
so I'm reading them.
It's good to check. Yeah, yeah.
And make sure we're delivering. Yeah,
you've got to deliver I guess. Um,
subscribe to the Youtube Channel.
So we've been slowly putting more videos
on there, you know, excerpts and whatnot.
Jocko mcnuggets where you can say or
share with your friends or whatever.
Quickly. I'm put more input more
today even. Um, and then, yeah,
some good at x or play,
think subscribe to that
steam formed video wise.
Also, we have a store, Jocko is a
store, it's called Jocko store.com.
So if everyone, we all wear clothes tee
shirts, right. Why not make it a jacket?
The shirt, that's kind of the,
the thing, you know, it's,
it's a thing, you know, how's this? So
Chris, I don't know if I showed you this.
So Chris Rue is our
friend fellow black belt.
He's that I want to see a art,
I don't even know the whole story.
I was trying to call him. He
was like, oh, but there's no,
I totally know this story. Yeah. So yeah,
he's the one of the,
one of the cadets at West Point.
Yeah. So, um,
he's, I don't know how, do you know
how he saw how he saw him or whatever,
but a cadet at west
point and I don't have,
I don't have his name right now in
uniform. Yeah. Yeah. He's in uniform.
But the uniform that they wear,
it's cold up there.
So then basically it's like a giant Cape.
And underneath the Cape he had a, uh, a
Jocko podcast shirt on. He had actually,
he actually had the straight up
Jocko face on that thing and it was,
he said he posted an awesome
picture on social media of him,
of him pulling up his
cape and he had that that
okay.
That tee shirt on. Yeah. Chuck Lewis face.
Maybe that was the secret weapon that
led the army to the first victory,
I think 14 years over navy and football.
Tom, Neil, Tom the, Oh yes, he's the,
he was the cadet doing it.
Yeah. Sending in the wild
in the wild. Doubling the oil. Yeah. Well
that's, he gave y'all in the wild. That's,
I mean I don't know what
the regulations are,
but I'm fairly certain that the t shirt,
the Jocko podcast tee shirt is not part
of army regulations something unless it
is now. I'm just saying, I never
know perhaps. But yeah, he's been,
he's been actually in touch
before he went to west point. He
was, when he was getting ready to go,
he was like reaching out and he was
getting after it. Right. And go crush it.
Doing this point. So good for him to some
Gnocchis Jujitsu as well. True, true.
Chris [inaudible] dot com. That's
where you can get like cool shirts, uh,
discipline equals freedom,
you know, all these things.
And also women's stuff on there.
Some hoodies on there,
some rash guards on there for,
for some activity.
You know what I'm talking about?
And some patches on there,
the regulation one within the
velcro that's um, that's on there.
Some other stuff. So yeah, go on there,
look at it. You don't have to buy nothing.
Just look at it. If you like
something, go ahead. Get it.
Good way to support and
boom, you got a shirt. Um,
also, okay, so here's the thing.
And this started a while ago. Okay.
So I'll tell this story,
I'll keep it short, but,
so I was like, I don't have echo
went rogue again, basically. Yeah.
So, and it started with kind
of nothing, so, you know, okay,
we're talking about luxury and like,
okay, fine, I only got six hours sleep.
I'm usually used to eight and a half
or something like that. Right. So,
but I know I can do a workout and I
know you don't get that much sleep or if
you're tired or not tired of what a,
you still push through the workout.
But I'm thinking, yeah, yeah, your hard,
your money, whatever. But you got to,
there has to be times where you got to
basically talk yourself into it basically.
So I'm like, all right, like
what do you say? You got to,
you know, be honest. Like,
what do you say? You know, to
yourself. And I figured it would have,
you know, like a lot of the stuff that
you can always say like, you know,
we have this luxury and all this
stuff. I'm like, all right, but let me,
so I asked you and what you told
me. I was like, okay, that, um,
that was good. It was legit right
there. So, and, and it worked.
It totally worked. Um,
so what I did, you know,
one thing led to another kind of in
my head, so I was like, all right,
you know what we're going to do?
We're going to record that.
You're going to say that I'm going
to record it. And on top of that,
not just the working out and usually like
with food and stuff like donuts and I
joke around that I eat like whole
things of Oreos because they, how I,
that's just a joke. Like sometimes I do,
but you do. Yeah, but I have willpower.
Like that's not a problem with, but
um, some people don't. So I'm like,
yeah,
the,
if that workout thing that you just
said could apply to like all these other
things, we're going to record that too.
Then you start thinking and you know,
a lot of people have been saying,
hey, what about like a ringtone?
You should ever ringtones w you know,
for my alarm and all this stuff.
So I'm like, all right, well basically
one thing led to another, we recorded them
and I put them on iTunes,
called it psychological warfare.
Good move. I think on my, it's on
iTunes. Yes, on iTunes. It's like,
yeah. So we're trying to, here's the,
so this kind of ties it back to how
you can support the podcast look.
So we hit about eight to 10
birds with one stone with this,
it's 99 cents for a track or you can buy
like the whole fancy and was like 1314
tracks on there for nine bucks.
I think that's kind of standard and but
so that's how much I put it or I listed
it as um, and you just download
it. You put it as your ring.
There's one for waking up. Actually
there's two for waking up. Right.
So you scan your foot reefer
waking up maybe. Yeah. But
there's a few, in my mind,
I pictured people like, Oh, you want to
wake up? Cool. We can come down on that.
I go through that every day
waking up. So yeah, we'll do that.
It's of like a song that you could buy.
It's like a song that you could
buy on iTunes. Howard album. Yes.
Same process. You just,
yeah, you just don't know.
You can buy one track d tracks or
the whole thing wouldn't handle it.
I mean it's 99 cents. So it's
not like you're supporting
the podcast. Yes, exactly.
Right. Here's, here's a little
tip. I was thinking about though.
So you need your wake up. There's
like a few wakeup ones, right?
I mentioned that if you put that as your
alarm cleared with your wife or whoever
you're sleeping with,
I'll tell you right now if that thing,
but if she don't know about it and
that comes on, it'll freak her out man.
So do that. That's a little pro tip
right there if he's in it, but I will,
I will almost,
I'll say it's 100% guarantee if you're,
if you felt like how I felt with workouts,
like I'm really not in the mood to go
do a workout and you listened to the
workout one, I will say with 100%
certainty you will not skip the work.
I'll say that right now as a legit anyway,
psychological warfare.
Who's the agonist?
I think it's just a willing,
okay.
I think cause that's how they list them
by artists, right? Yeah, I think so.
Did I just that just become
an artist. That's scary.
Let's call it something else.
You kind of got,
can I use you something else?
You kind of got and pushed into
it though. So you know, artists,
author,
a podcaster technically.
Is that a thing at the happy I heard it.
You know what?
I can give you the heads up. Three,
I'm over here being an artist.
What happened? Okay, but it's all
you know wrong. Not going to happen.
It's offered good cause though I'm
telling you because if anyone's like I am,
which I'm, I'm straight up. It's
more than an assumption. I'm,
I am of the belief that some people are
like me in that way where you just don't
feel like it. I know we just read
this and now we all feel like it.
I understand that. But you don't
have that feeling every single day.
I'm telling you right
now. This helps. This helps you get
after it helped me for sure. Anyway,
psychological warfare,
you know, all right.
Also Hae on iTunes or sorry,
not an iTunes bought on Amazon.
You can get some white tea.
It's like I said,
we're working through
the supply chain issues,
but it's been popping up every couple
of days. They refill. You can order it.
It tastes good.
And it makes you feel good and it will
increase your dead lift capabilities to a
minimum of 7,000 pounds.
Many are getting up to 8,000 pounds,
headless from drinking
chocolate white tea.
You can get up and get after it
Mug by the way too. So those are,
they're bigger than normal. I'll say
that they're bigger than a normal mug.
A normal mug is not as big as it
get after it mug with every sip,
like you're acting, you're doing
bicep curls, you're getting, actually,
that's not my joke. I could steal
that from Twitter. So that's that. Uh,
also on Amazon, you can pick up colder
than hell. The book I read today do it.
Put it in your collection of Badass books.
You can pick up another book
that's called extreme ownership.
That's written by me and
my brother Leif Babin.
It is also a book that's about combat,
but it's more of a book about leadership.
And if you want to give some work,
speaking of the holiday season,
if you want to give someone
a gift that's gonna,
you know some gifts that you get,
they go in the drawer that
doesn't get opened anymore, right?
And then it takes you a couple of
years and you're finally throw it away.
Don't give that gift the gift
that someone's going to say,
you gave me that book, it's legit. I
read it. Oh, I implemented this. Hey,
what'd you think about the good?
Give them a gift that's gonna have
long term value, longterm value.
Give him a little book called
extreme ownership. You can
get it on amazon.com uh,
hey.
Speaking of extreme ownership also we got
the muster number two zero zero to May
4th and fifth at the Marriott
Marquis in New York City.
Now the last one that we had,
we had people from 42 different states.
We had people from five foreign countries
and we had leaders at every level of
the chain of command in every size
business that you could imagine.
So it was a super diverse group of
people that are all together with,
they had one similarity in that is
they want to get better and crush it in
leadership,
in their business and in their life.
So that's what we do at the mustard
leaf and I who are there obviously when,
when I say we're there,
I don't mean where their meaning we're
in the same building but were hiding
somewhere. No, no, no, no. Where
there we are actually with you.
We are sitting down with
you. We are talking. We are,
we're not hiding behind the curtain.
We don't even have a backstage.
They said well where do you want
your backstage or we don't need one.
We're not going backstage. Yeah.
People want to come and talk and learn.
We want to learn from them.
So come and get it.
I've said this every time
this is going to sell out,
it's going to sell out and
then you won't be able to go.
And also the prices are going up.
So as you get close to the event,
the prices go up.
The reason we do that is so we incentivize
you to buy the tickets now so that we
can plan better, right? We like to be
planned, we planned and we prepare things.
If all of you sign up,
you know,
April 22nd we got some logistics prompts.
I don't want to be in the same boat
I'm in with Jocko white tea where I've
failed logistically and it takes
me a while to get it back on track.
So sign up early,
save yourself some money and let
us be better prepared for that.
If you got questions,
you can email muster@echelonfront.com
or you can check out the website,
www.extremeownership.com and we will
see you there and we will and you'll see
me,
you'll see Lafe,
you'll see echo Charles and
you'll see everybody else.
We'll all be there getting after it while
you're waiting to hang out with us at
the muster. If you want to kind
of hang out with us virtually.
Well Echo and I are both kind of
cruising the cruising the interwebs.
Yeah. Twitter. Yup. We're there.
Instagram were there
and you even go on Ics,
you even going to see us on that
Facebook you bought echo is an echo.
Charles and I am at Jocko Willink.
And finally we appreciate you listening
and supporting the podcast and of course
spreading the word,
but don't just listen,
do
execute.
Take a look at your life and see where
you can apply the kinder human will we
heard about tonight.
They're kind of human will that
overcomes challenges and obstacles.
Whether you're fighting a war or you're
fighting a fire or you're fighting
crime,
or you're building a bridge,
or you're building a piece of software,
or whether you're doing
HVAC work or retail work,
or whether you're healing
kids or you're teaching kids,
no matter what you are doing,
what can you do to do it better?
What can you do to make you better?
Ask yourself that question.
Apply that will
and get after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.