Jocko, I've just finished about
face the book. Amazing book,
interested how you modeled your style
on Hackworth though hack was a renegade
and always bending the rules to
break into the breaking point.
But in extreme ownership,
you talk about, for example,
not pushing back on higher command when
it came to Iraqi troops have listened to
podcasts too, but was hoping
you could go into it a bit more.
Yeah. So I guess that's
a good question. Hack.
He was kind of considered a renegade,
but, but also he was also a total company.
Man. You gotta realize that there's that
dichotomy there. There's a guy that hack,
loved the army,
he loved the army.
He wanted his uniform would
look super squared away.
He followed all the rules
and regulations that,
and he supported the leadership all
the time when the leadership was right.
And that's what makes him a good renegade,
in my opinion.
And I was very much the same way.
I was all about the navy.
You know, I was all about the
games as a matter of fact, tone.
You know what Tony used to
say? Uh, it was a little thing.
We got going into you
bruiser that spread around.
But of course it came from Tony First,
which was all navy all the time.
We'd just be joking
about, you know, I think,
I don't know what originally caused it,
but like guys would make fun of me because
I would wear like jungle boots or Dan
or boots out too on liberty with
a clear of like old jeans. Yeah.
Cause when you're, when you're like that
kind of old just raised in the teams,
you don't even know any
different and you're like,
oh well I'm going out and I need to wear
shoes. Cool. Where's my jungle boots?
That's what you end up like and
you're into it. You're not like,
you think it's good. You think it's
normal. Like this is the way things are.
And so I supported the teams and
hacks supported the army of course.
But this is the thing,
if the leadership was wrong or there
was something being passed down that was
wrong and it was a big wrong,
like if it was a little,
I wouldn't be like, Oh man, this is crap.
They're making us wear different parish
shorts now. Cause like that would happen,
like some new commanding officer would
come in and change some thing. Right.
And some we go to do that where it's like,
dude, be quiet, you know, just be quiet.
Do you know they're giving you new
shorts where the new shorts, you know,
oh they're telling us we can't wear
baseball hats anymore. Cool. Don't worry.
Baseball hats. And some guys
would go up there. It's who cares?
It's like they don't care what
I'm wearing on my head. You know,
like oh you want to issue a different
ball caps are find whatever.
But then if it was a larger issue then
or obviously if it was something that was
like actually wrong,
like criminally wrong or morally wrong
or something like that, then yeah,
I'd be like, no, we can't do that.
So the reason that I didn't push back
on Iraqi troops in working with Iraqi
troops when we got to Ramadi
was because as I looked at it,
I realized that it was the
right thing to do. And yes,
it was going to be more dangerous.
And yes,
a definitely took us
out of our comfort zone.
But as I explained in extreme ownership,
if we didn't train those people up,
if we didn't train the Iraqi soldiers
and take them out and get them fighting
and get them squared
away on the battlefield,
then Americans would have
been doing it forever.
So it was the correct call was to do that.
Now I've, I've talked
about the same, same thing.
When they told us our ratio,
they gave us a ratio of how many Iraqis
we had to have for every one Iraqi we
had to have, I don't know what their,
I forget what the number was, seven or,
or for every one seal we had
to have seven Iraqi soldiers.
They said that something like that.
I forget what the numbers were and I said,
no,
that doesn't make sense to us because
sometimes we only have 10 guys to go out
and there's no way I'm sending only one
seal with 10 Iraqi soldiers not doing it.
Need a corpsman,
need to radiomen need machine
gunner need a leader like that.
That's what I need.
So,
and when I pushed back because I didn't
push back against ball caps and because
I didn't push back against
some stupid uniform change,
they were like, oh yeah, well
that actually makes sense Jocko.
We don't want you to go on
the field with only one seal.
So I would clearly push back if it
was something that didn't make sense.
Same thing with like the martial arts
training that they had us doing in the,
in the late nineties and early
two thousands. It was not good.
And I was told everyone, hey, this
is not smart. This is not good.
This training is dumb. We need to do
other training that's better. Uh, and,
and same thing, you know, things go, oh,
like here's another like stupid example,
they wouldn't want to issue a platoon.
The radio was you were going to take on
deployment because they didn't want you
to break them or whatever.
And so the issue,
not enough radios for everyone.
And so now everyone doesn't know how to
operate the radios and you're basically
operationally testing the radios while
you're going through your workup.
So I said, hey, this is garbage issue,
everyone radios, if that's how we operate,
that's how we need to train.
Gotcha.
So in the training they
wouldn't issue the radios. Yeah,
there was a time period where
we low on radio and they said,
we're going to keep these radios for
deployment. It's, that doesn't make sense.
I got a good idea by more
radios. Uh, so, you know,
those were things I pushed back on it.
And you are always pushing back on the
type of training that was going to happen
and who was going to be, how you're
going to run the training. So, um,
when something,
when it made sense to push back,
I pushed back just like Hackworth did.
Now Hackworth did it on a massive scale
because he eventually pushed back on the
way the war in Vietnam was being run.
And had I been smart enough and the war
didn't take the shift that it took and
we didn't move towards counter insurgency
and we didn't make those adjustments
that the, that Colonel Mcfarland
implemented in Ramadi. Maybe.
Maybe. I doubt it. Maybe I would
have been smarter to say, Hey,
we're not running this war,
right.
We need to do something different
and run up the chain of command. But,
but at the time, you know, Colonel
Mcfarland made great decisions. He led,
he had a great plan, a great strategy,
so I was a hundred percent onboard. Um,
but if you don't Hackworth,
that didn't happen.
They were not fighting correctly
against the Vietnamese and,
and they were taking massive casualties
for a hill that two days later they'd
give back. And so he was saying, what
are you doing? And, and the other thing,
you know,
when he took over the hardcore battalion,
they were fighting for
months and they had,
they literally killed almost no editing.
I think it was zero.
I think it was actually zero enemy.
And yet they had taken all kinds of
casualties themselves. And so he's saying,
this is wrong, this is
wrong. So I think that's,
that's what being a leader is. You support
the stuff, you support the command.
Yes,
of course you support the command when
it makes sense and as long as it makes
sense. And normally it's gonna
make sense. You know what I mean?
Normally it's to make sense,
not like the,
the admirals and the generals are
saying, hey, how can we lose this war?
Let's come up with a stupid strategy.
No, they're doing the best they can.
So it's not like it's a regular
occurrence. I mean, like I said,
when I was working for Carter,
Colonel Mcfarland, he was a smart guy.
He was a brilliant guy that had a great
strategy of I'm like, okay, awesome.
I'm here to support. Um, and, and
I'll tell you when I did, and this is,
I think this is important,
is that even though I was kind of a
renegade and hours more rebellious when I
was a kid, obviously I was, uh, I was
young when I got the seal teams then. So,
you know, we would push the, all those
things that I said, oh, we gotta do this.
That was me when I was at e four
in the seal teams. You know,
where do we go do that? We should
just be able to do whatever we want.
We were just stupid.
But as I got older,
I realized that you need to,
you know,
come across as a renegade quote unquote,
to come across as a big rebel.
That doesn't, well, immediately when
you go and push back on something,
everyone just dismisses you. Oh yeah,
Jocko. He's just a loud mouth. He just,
he just pushed back against
everything he doesn't want.
He's wanting to do everything his
way. No. You want them to say, Oh wow,
hold on a second. If Jocko is
pushing back against this, then this,
this must be something wrong here because
he doesn't push back against stuff.
He tells the line all the time,
so we should listen to them.
That's what you want to build.
That's what I did my best to build and
that's how I think it would be comparable
to the way Hackworth led
and the way that I try to,
obviously I know Hackworth,
but I stole as much as I could from him.
And the weird thing is, I'll tell you
this, I always say I stole from him,
but it wasn't like I was sitting
there reading the book and go,
I'm going to do what he did here.
I think it was just absorbed.
And even even the naming of task
unit bruiser like when I did it,
I wasn't thinking this
is what Hackworth did,
but it was real obvious that
that's where I got it from.
Like I didn't think I'm going to rename
this and you were going to turn this
thing around based order
would not turn it around,
but we're gonna build this based
on no, I was like, you know what,
we're not going to be Task Unit
Bravo cause that sounds lame.
Or It'd be tasking bruiser because
that sounds awesome. You and,
and then later, you know, as I look
back I'm like, Oh God, that's what,
that's exactly what Hackworth did.
I obviously stole it from him. Yeah.
So appreciate it hack.
But that's what I'd say be a renegade.
But that's should be,
that should be in the background.
That should be in the back of your mind,
in the front of your mind. Should be, hey,
I'm a, I'm a supporter of
what's happening. Yeah.
Kind of like the willingness to be a rent
or any gate if you have to. Yeah. Yeah.
If you have to,
and believe me,
I've known all kinds of good
seals that were to renegade. Yeah.
Just like I'm rns. Yeah. They're just
straight up, hey, I'm a renegade. And,
and you know that just, it the only
guys that could get away with that.
Well guys that were so ultimately
operationally squared away. Yeah.
That people go, yeah, you know, he's
kind of a maniac, but dude, he's really,
really good and really tactically
sound and all that. And they could,
they make that happen.
Now as you get more and more senior,
the homie don't play like that
before or after a certain point,
it's done and you got to get,
you've got to play the game.
That's what you gotta do. As you get
more senior, you gotta play the game.
And from like your subordinates viewpoint,
if if they looked at me and go,
oh, jock was just playing the game.
He's just doing, yes, I am. Yes I am.
Because this way it gives me more ability
to control everything that's going to
impact you. People that
work for me. So yes,
I'm going to play the game so you
don't have to. You're welcome.