Pomegranate, what does it, pomegranate,
Chai tea. White tea. Yep. That's what I,
and so when you're deep,
deep. So action. Action.
All right.
This right here is the
first Jocko podcast.
Here we go.
I guess to start off,
how did we end up here?
How did this happen?
I guess I have to thank Tim Ferris four
initially having me on to his podcast
and that was via
a couple people that helped me
out. Get on there. Kirk Parsley,
Peter Attia,
and they made some introductions
and introduced me to Tim Ferris.
Tim had me on,
got a lot of good feedback on that,
on that show.
And that led to me going on to Joe Rogan.
So thanks to Joe Rogan
for having me on as well.
And once those two things happened and I
actually got online and started getting
communicating with other human
beings online and they were asking,
you know,
you should,
you should do a podcast because it was
interesting and both Joe and Tim told me
to have a podcast because
it was interesting. So as
I got all that feedback,
which was awesome, um,
I kind of realized I should do a podcast.
So I'm sitting here,
my name is Jocko Jocko Willink. I was
uh, if you don't know anything about me,
I served 20 years in the military,
retired
in 2010 myself and one of my buddies,
guy by the name of Leif Babin,
we started a company where we
do leadership and management
consulting for businesses.
Doing all that work eventually got us to
a situation where we had some knowledge
and kind of aggregated some knowledge
and so we put that into a book.
The book came out and
been doing pretty well.
It's called extreme ownership.
So that's who I am now.
I kind of
sometimes find it a little
strange just to be talking.
And so as we decided to
put this podcast together,
at one point I had done some follow up
videos for Tim Ferris for him to put
online and I did those with a buddy
of mine who sit in here with me now,
guy by the name of Echo Charles,
who is a longtime Jujitsu
training partner of mine.
And he does video production.
He's got a company called flex point TV.
Uh,
and whenever I got to do
something video related,
he's my go to guy.
And so when this came,
this opportunity came about when we were
filming the videos for Tim Ferriss and
we had questions from the Internet and
we were sitting there and he's filming
and we were basically doing a podcast
cause we were talking and we were having
conversations about leadership and about
Jujitsu and about problems and about
everything.
And that kind of rolled
into when we started talking
about doing a podcast and I
said, Hey, do you have audio equipment?
Do you have a recorder?
Do you have,
do you have time to sit down and
hang out with me and, and do this?
And I do. He said, I do.
I do have all that stuff and
here we are. So then, uh,
what we did was we,
we took a bunch of
questions that I got from online.
People hit me with all kinds of
different questions, which is awesome.
Thanks to everybody for giving me that
feedback and listening and talking and
communicating with me.
That's awesome.
It's kind of weird because I've never
been like the most social person in the
world and
not that I feel like lonely
cause I never do. I'm,
I don't care if I'm alone or not.
It's no big deal usually.
You mean like online social? Definitely,
definitely not online social.
I mean I had zero online presence prior
to being on the Tim Ferriss podcast and
mmm.
But, but even socially, I mean, I
don't like hanging around with people.
You know that every night.
I told you that like the last time
I was over here I said, hey, yeah,
I just don't do that a lot.
So it's kind of interesting to me being
online and communicating with really
thousands of people and they all,
and it's cool because I'm not used to
having people that are kind of interested
in the same thing I'm interested in,
you know?
Did you get to the working
out the wanting to do better.
They'll want to get better. The
want to learn more. That's what I'm,
that's what I want to do.
And it's cool to be able to communicate
with a bunch of people that want to do
the same thing. And you know, I
think that's what this podcast,
which I know is going to evolve
into all kinds of different things.
But I think the,
the underlying theme
will be lessons learned.
You know, lessons learned. I want to
learn from people. I want people to,
I want to pass on what I've learned.
I don't want people to make
the same mistakes I made.
I want to learn other mistakes that
people have made so I don't make them.
And I think that's going to kind
of be the underlying theme here
with this. Yeah. What about you?
I mean,
is there any thing and your background
that you would consider to be important
for people to know
above and beyond what you
just said? No, I think that's,
those are the relevant points for sure.
That's, that's, that's as
we talked about doing this,
that's one of the things that
struck me as you're a director,
you know, for Your
Business, right? You're,
you're a film director and you
don't get in front of the camera.
That's not your thing.
Right.
And so that's why I think this
interaction is good because you're,
you're drawing things out of
people. That's what a director
does. Yeah. You're not,
I believe that's where you're
going to be doing here. Yeah. Yes.
Especially when I did a lot of the
metamorris stuff, that was essentially my,
I was like maybe a third of the
whole job if she gets stuff. How to,
so the Jujitsu players out there,
if you follow metamorris at all the
videos that the, what do they call it?
Lead up videos, like promo promo
videos for the matches. Yeah.
Those were Downes Downes that's right.
Those were,
those were Echo Charles
material right there. Yeah.
So you'd occasionally hear his voice in
the background with a question. Yeah.
So speaking to questions. Yeah. We
got some questions from the, uh,
from the interwebs when we got
for the first one. Here we go.
First question is,
why do you wake up early in the morning?
Actually, this is, I kind of have the
same question because I wake up late.