This is Jocko podcast number
one 15 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
Okay.
War is different for
everyone who experiences it.
Okay.
On one end of the spectrum,
there are some people who deployed to a
safe area and protected by concrete and
steel and Barb wire and their job,
which is definitely an
important part of the machine,
but it just doesn't require them
to be put into direct combat.
And then with a little luck
because of that situation,
they can easily complete
a wartime deployment with
little or no contact with the
enemy whatsoever.
But they did their part and
we are thankful for that.
On the other end of the spectrum,
there are some people that end
up in anything but a safe area.
They end up in the belly of the beast.
They are called on to do more than is
required and much more than could be
expected.
And that situation also
creates a spectrum.
Okay.
Some men find it to be too much.
Yeah.
And instincts of self
preservation takeover and they
go into survival mode and
they cower and they hide and
they'd give up and they wait.
Yeah.
For the inevitable.
But others do what they can.
They try to do their duty.
They put one foot in front of the other
and they reload their weapon and they
try to keep firing.
That's the middle of the spectrum.
And then at the far end of the spectrum,
there are those men that
step up and go forward
across the threshold,
really across the threshold of life.
And they go into the fire and into the
flame and toward the unknown and toward
death.
Not to save themselves.
Yeah.
But they disregard their own safety and
their own life to save they're friends.
Yeah.
They're brothers.
Okay.
And their comrades in arms.
And then beyond even that,
okay,
almost off the spectrum.
Okay.
There are those men that take that step
across the threshold of life and death
over and over and over again.
Not because they were ordered to,
not for a metal, not because of
some manufactured set of ideals,
but simply because that is who
okay
they are.
And I'm honored to have one of
those men here with me today.
A son,
a father,
and American. Oh, United States marine,
a man by the name of Mr Dakota Meyer.
Dakota, welcome to the podcast
and thank you for coming on.
No, thank you so much for having me. I'm
telling you, I'm honored. I'm honored.
All right.
As we normally do,
let's start from where you started.
Tell us a little bit about,
about Columbia, Kentucky. Yeah.
You know, it's, um, it's a small town. You
know, I grew up in Columbia, Kentucky. Um,
you know, I grew up in that first half
of my life with my mother and, uh,
ended up going and living with my
father and um, you know, I didn't,
didn't come from money. You didn't
come from anything nice. You know,
I ended up losing my father.
I'm adopted on my father's side and a,
you grow up on a farm, um,
you know, it's just, just, uh,
just, um, you know, I'm, I'm, I'm,
I'm a simple guy. It's a simple,
it's a simple way of life, you
know what I mean? And that's,
that's just how we grew up.
We, you know, my dad, you know,
he always instilled in me and me and my,
I have to give so much credit to my father
and my grandfather. I mean, I might,
you know,
I mean,
they just stay instilled so much in
me of what's right and what mattered,
you know, you know, uh,
okay,
we're talking a lot of your childhood
was an, and I wrote down these notes,
farm work, football and
females. Yeah, yeah.
I mean that's a, that I
told you I'm simple. Yeah,
that's it. You know, there's not much
else. Ain't Columbia, Kentucky though.
And uh, you know, you
wrote, you wrote a book,
the book is called into the fire and
that's where I'm getting some of my
information for, from an a, and I would
say that in the early descriptions,
the way you described yourself,
not exactly Mr sensitive is,
is what we were dealing with back then.
No, not at all. Um, you know, I was,
no, I wasn't sensitive. I was, um,
I was just a hard kid, you know,
um, set in my ways. I, I, you know,
my dad just instilled in me, my
dad is still, I mean, you know,
my dad is a man who doesn't, he doesn't
care the social status. He's not, uh,
you know, he, you know, and
I watch it from him and he's
just a hard, hard, hard guy,
you know what I mean? And so there's
not living in a house of two men. Right.
You know me, it was just my dad, you
know, there's not very many feeling,
it wasn't a real nourishment to
your sensitive side. There was a,
there was not much nourishment.
Yeah.
There's one part of their talking about
you're in a football game and you jack
up your elbow real bad. And so the coach
got you in the locker room or whatever.
Yeah. Yeah. So I was, uh, I was sitting
in the locker room and I mean, I,
I had carried the ball probably 18,
19 times the first half,
and I'd go in there and my
elbows are like, just jacked.
Right? I mean, you know,
just, we were just
getting pounded. And, um,
I remember sitting in there and the coach
like, Hey, don't come out next half.
Right. You know, you just look, you know,
cause it was a Jv game and he's like,
you know, don't come out in the next
half and I'm gonna tell you something.
My dad seeing that I didn't come off
when we were warming up for a second half
and I mean he came in there and that
was not, that was not acceptable.
But one thing my dad taught me is you
start it, you finish it, check, check.
Now
what happened to that football
career? What'd you get? You get,
you did get some like legitimate injury,
right? Yeah, yeah. I
know. I got, I, you know,
I banged my knee up real bad on my
sophomore year between my sophomore and
junior year. Never really recovered
from it, you know. Um, and so,
I mean, I could've went
and played somewhere. Like,
I'm not going to still come nuggets here
and tell you I'd had full scholarships
or anything, but I could've, I
could've walked on somewhere, you know,
probably played outside linebacker or
you know, a strong safety. But, um,
you know, I just, I was going to go
play football and I had planned on that.
I had been through the clearinghouse.
I mean,
I'd done everything I needed
to do to go in and, you know,
my senior year and I just, and I ended
up going in the Marine Corps route. Okay.
Now I,
I've,
I've talked a few times down here about
the effectiveness of the Marine Corps
recruiting program, which they have
like the best recruiting numbers,
but they spend the least on recruiting of,
of any of the military service branches.
And it sounds like you've
got rolled right into that.
I did. They got me, they got me. Let me
tell you something. They, uh, they got me,
you know, but, but I think, look, I, you
know, the products, the product with them,
right? Like, you know, you,
you know, you're either,
you're either going to be a marine or
you're not going to be a marine, right?
Like you're, you either have it in here,
you don't like, it's not, you know,
they just, they just know how
to talk to their own. Right.
And I think that's what
they're so good at is,
is that they know how they know
what would have fired them up.
And so they say the same thing
that would have fired them up.
And if you buy it on it, then you're,
the type of person needs to be a marine.
And if you don't, they don't want
you anyway. You know what I mean?
Yeah, yeah. That's a
perfect way to put it.
And this is 2006 2006 2006 and again,
this is not my,
I always have to remind myself and I'll
remind everyone else while I'm at it, is,
you know,
when I joined the
eve in 1990 there was no war going on,
right? There was no war going on.
It was just, you know, peacetime.
And you're joining in 2006 where we're
award to different countries and 2006
things are not going well. They're a
little quiet in Afghanistan at that time.
But Iraq is full bore. I mean, that's
when I was in Ramadi and it was,
it was a real hard fighting was taking
place and on all on Bart province,
the rest of Iraq was pretty bad.
So, you know, for you, you know,
you're going and you know you're going
to go to combat. I mean, that's just like
kind of a given. Yeah, I mean I, um,
I don't know that I ever really
understood that though, until I was in,
you know what I mean? I think that, I
don't think it ever really hit me. Um,
I never really,
I didn't really join.
I can't sit here and give you some Modo
story that I joined to go, you know,
the advantage night 11 or you want
to hear something that's jacked up.
I joined in 1990 and I had the opposite
viewpoint, which is, I mean, you know,
there was no war going on, although
I'm not so sure I was going to war.
I was like,
oh,
it's all Sheila's got to be doing things
all over and doing stuff we don't even
hear about.
That's what my attitude is.
And here you were staring at
Duke War in two different,
two different zones and you're like,
I don't know if it will really happen.
I mean, honestly, I did. I know it sounds
dumb, but I mean like, I, you know,
by that time we're five years past it
and people had already got used to it.
Right. It was no longer
like, oh shit, you know, in,
in like the population, you know, in the,
you know, the average civilian. Right.
It wasn't, you know, cause
it, they've been doing it for
what, five years? Yeah. And,
um, so, you know, I didn't really think
about it and I, you know, I honestly,
you know, I joined a, I, you
know, I wanted to go infantry.
I wanted to fight. Um,
but I didn't really,
I don't think it ever really hit me
until I got into boot camp, you know?
And then I really started
understanding what,
and when you were going boot
through boot camp at that time,
basically every drill instructor must have
been coming back from the battlefield.
All of them. I mean, I'm telling
you, everybody, especially, uh,
especially in a school of infantry,
everyone of them had been, they were
shoes you. Yeah. I mean everyone,
I've been in the shit. Yeah.
You know, even my recruiter,
my recruiter had just got back
from Fallujah. Dang. Yeah.
And He'd been in the shit.
Dang.
Yeah. So with that, I'm going to take it
to the book right now because you know,
I think I was never in the Marine Corps.
I'm pretty sad about that sometimes.
But I have like read so much about the
Marine Corps over my life and be hung
around with so many marines
and work with bringing so much.
So whenever I get to Marine Corps
boot camp, it's like strikes.
A romantic side of me just wants
to at least get a little taste and,
and you did it really fast, which
is great. But here, here it isn't.
It's just like exactly what
we're going to the book again,
this book is into the fire by
Dakota Meyer and here we go.
So it began close haircuts to strip away
your old identity exercises to prove
you're not half as strong as you figured,
simple tasks to show you
that you're mentally weak.
Drill instructors who mock your attempts
to look. It's right out of the movies,
but it never stops. And there
you go. You know what's coming.
How many times did you watch full metal
jacket before he went in a time? Yeah,
I mean I timed, you know exactly what's
going to happen. Does that even help? Uh,
no. It's just still, you
could, I mean you, you know,
like during bootcamp it was the
hardest thing I'd ever been through.
But when I look at everything I did in
the Marine Corps, it was the easiest.
That's the same thing with buds.
So first of all,
when I went through buds and I
didn't know anything about buds,
no one knew anything about buds in
1990 when I joined the Navy didn't know
anything about it. And, and so I always
think that the guys are coming in now.
You can basically watch the entire bud.
You can watch the whole thing.
You know what, they, they,
the students eventually captured the
schedules and so they actually know what's
coming and you know, you know how many
people it keeps from quitting. None.
It's still the same attrition to,
okay,
so it's going to suck really
bad and now you know it,
you didn't know it before you
even know when it's going to end.
You know what I mean?
Alright. Uh, back to the book.
The second month is the turnaround
when they build you back up.
Sergeant Brady made me a squad leader,
meaning he yelled at me for the
mistakes and the other 10 recruits,
that was all right. He had his job.
I had mine. You bust it through,
you get to graduation day, which was
obviously awesome. And then it's,
I spent the next two months
at Soi School of Infantry.
Only 15% of the marine corps and
the army are in the infantry.
In today's military there are more
combat pilots and infantry squad leaders.
Dang. Yeah. Ah, man, that's crazy.
15% of the marine corps and the army
are infantry troops for the ground.
That's,
that's an interesting figure in Vietnam.
And I was talking about this with life
and with actually the whole echelon front
team the other day, I had heard this
somewhere, I heard it from Hackworth,
that in Vietnam,
the height of the Vietnam War,
there was a little over 500,000 troops
on the ground and it was only 10% of
those troops that were,
you know,
infantry units that were on the
ground in combat. Yeah. You,
you know what I find so interesting about
that fact and that stat when I looked
at it, you know, like I didn't understand
it obviously when I was in, but you know,
what I look at it is to understand
like how much it truly, you know, as,
as the war fighter,
you know,
I think we take for granted so many times
of what it really takes for us to be
able to do our job effectively. I mean,
you take it, I mean, it takes, you know,
85% of the organization just to
support that 15% to put you yes.
Face to face with the enemy.
There's gotta be another. Yeah.
I mean you look at it 10 to one 15 to
one or something like that. It's crazy.
Tend to one that's got to
put you up there. Yeah,
but that's what works and that's,
well here we go. Breaking down,
breaking down a little bit of
what the Marine Corps like.
A Marine squad is comprised of three,
four man fire teams.
Everything you do as a rifleman
revolves around that four man team.
A one man carries a weapon more
powerful than those of the others,
but that's a minor point in the field.
You don't do anything without those
other guys. You don't shit sleep,
eat or move without the other
three knowing about it. Yeah.
A Marine squad with those three fire
teams is like a boxer with three arms,
one arm jabs with bursts of fire to
keep the opponent off balance while the
other arm loops around a left hook with
a third arm ready to follow up wherever
there's an opening. If one arm is
wounded, the other two can keep fighting.
Fire to pin down the enemy maneuver
to finish them off fire and maneuver,
fire maneuver, fire maneuver. And
I always have to point this out.
Extreme ownership, you
know, this is covering move.
This is what I was talking about.
The fundamental,
that's the fundamental gun fighting
tactic. Yes. Fire maneuver.
I was called a cover and move.
So you get done with Soi and
you head out to the Third
Marine regiment in Hawaii. Yeah.
That,
so how was that when you're checking in?
Oh yeah. Well we pulled in and as
soon as we pulled the bus in, the,
uh, seniors, uh, you know, they're all,
they had all just got back from a
hadith of the triad and I had a hard
deployment. They got, they got the
shit kicked out of him. And uh,
and uh, so we pull in in a, you
know, there's no empathy there.
And so we pull in and they're throwing
beer bottles off the deck and they are
all hammered. It's in the middle
of the night. And um, you know,
so it's like welcome, you know,
but it was awesome. You know,
I was honored to be out there.
And then how long did it take for the
sniper bill it to open up and for you to
get that? Yeah, so it was a, I think
it was like around February. Uh,
so I got there in
October. So September. No,
so I got there in October,
November. So November timeframe,
I think I got to why October,
November timeframe and then
I, it opened in January,
February timeframe. Hard to get a snack.
Isn't it hard to get a sniper built?
Did you get lucky at need a new
guy get us Naperville. So I did.
So I was actually the youngest sniper
in the Marine Corps in 2007. Um,
so what happened was,
is I had Brandon the Indoc,
so you have to run an Indoc
to be part of the platoon.
So you come in and then like
you, you, you're on probation,
so you run a huge Indoc, you come in and
you go on probation and then you start,
um,
you know,
usually you were go on deployment and
then after deployment you go to school.
Well,
they had a couple of schools so I had to
open up and a score and they basically
gave me the option of you can either
go home on predeployment leave cause we
were heading that rack.
You can either go and predeployment
leave or you can go to sniper school.
I was a 18 how many milliseconds did it
take you to make that decision? I said,
I said I've been with my family
for 18 years. I'm, I'm all good.
Oh man, that's awesome. And then
Marine Corps sniper school, uh,
that's a, that's a hardcore school
and 50% attrition rate. Yeah.
And seals in it with this. Yeah. And
then you know, our early seal snipers,
you know,
and I don't know the full,
I'll bring a sniper on here someday
that knows the whole history of the seal
sniper program. But it's deeply rooted
in the Marine Corps sniper program.
Deeply rooted.
Just like all of our training is
rooted in the Marine Corps and Raiders.
There's a lot
of crossover in those early days. But
Marine, the Marine Corps sniper program,
now everyone's going to think that's
a civilian's going to think like, oh,
you're sitting on a gun shooting. But,
but that's not really the hardest part.
Is it 5% of the job? Like it's
like the, it's, I would say, yeah,
I would say it's less than that,
you know, you know, I mean,
you gotta I mean the communication piece
of it, the mission planning, the, I mean,
there's so much, I mean, you, you
literally, you literally are the, uh,
you know, the commanders, the
battalion commander's trigger finger.
You guys do heavy stocking.
Right? That's just a gut check.
And how much did you weigh
at this point? Uh, probably
about 180. Okay. 85. And it's,
um, where do you guys do your
stocks? Uh, so we were in Hawaii,
so I went to Hawaii sniper school.
Okay. Um, and we do a mountain,
the cuckoo's out and just dripping
sweat. Oh, lane in, they're crawling.
Walking is terrible.
Scrawling for four hours
and going 35 meters. Yeah,
I mean, just like, you know, you know, you
start off, you got thousand meter lane,
you know,
and they're,
they put an observer up and they're
using the best glass there is.
And they're sitting on this truck and
a, you have to, you have to move up.
And, um, you got to
get within a, you know,
at a certain distance and whatever they
tell you. And then you get, you know,
you have to veg up and whatever you take
shot, you can do whatever you, you know,
you take a shot with a blank.
Okay.
And then they come over and so the,
the bigger walker on a walker on you
and then they try to walk, you know,
back and forth, they try to find you. If
they see you or anything, then you know,
you lose. Um, and then you got to take
a second shot. Wild. They're, you know,
cause that Walker gets within
the vicinity of you and like,
it's like 10 or 20 meters and then
you take a second shot and if they see
anything, then you know, you, you,
you, you failed too. So it's, you know,
yeah. And it's a walker. So basically
they bring a guy out who is like,
who you know has like a stick or something
and they can see them and then they
tried to say it so they go,
okay, I think I see him here.
So I need you to take left three
steps and then back four steps.
They tried to walk him on you.
Gotcha.
This will be interesting
when they get to you,
do they say sniper at your
feet to the guy? Huh? So yeah,
you have to say it sniper at your feet.
That's the same thing that they
say in the seal sniper school.
That's what they said to get
there. And they go, okay,
sniper your feet though. Yep.
Your boss. Did you fail?
Three, three steps left. Two
steps up. Sniper at your feet.
Yup. They'll say, nope. You know
what I mean? And so there's,
there's the crossover that
shows you that that's,
that stuff has rooted together and there's
a guy by the name of skin to who was
one of your instructors. You
were born your instructors,
right? Yeah. And here's a,
here's a,
going back to the book skin to told us
about a sniper team in an Overwatch and a
half constructed building in
Ramadi in 2004. It was a warm,
dull day and after several hours,
they dozed off and never awakened in.
Surgeon sneaked up and shot
all four marines in the head.
They left behind a high powered EMM 48
83 and it's excellent Schmidt and bender
scope.
Over
the course of the next year,
they allegedly killed two more Americans
before marine sniper took them out and
recovered the rifle.
Skint hammered home his message,
no every aspect of your job and never,
never let down your guard.
If you slack off or you take
things for granted, you die.
He, um, I, I had a lot. Look,
I was fortunate to have a lot of people
around me that influenced me. I mean, I'm,
I'm nothing special.
I'm the product of my environment and my,
I'm direct reflection on my leadership.
I'm so fortunate,
but I'll tell you right now that when I
did that day was because of him was it
was because of the mentality that he
instilled in me. Um, knowing your job,
knowing it and obsessing with it and
knowing every aspect of it and no one
everybody else's job around you.
And then when you know your job and
you know what's right you, you do that,
you don't worry about
what everybody else says.
Yeah. The, the, the noncommissioned
officers that, again,
they're same guys that raised me in
the seal teams have such a huge impact.
And what,
what I also found interesting about
this was this story about the snipers.
When I got to Ramadi in 2006, we heard
this exact story and you know, it,
it was another thing that made us more
paranoid and made my guys more paranoid
being out there. And we
actually had thought, I didn't,
this has 2004 we thought it happened
a little bit later and closer to our
deployment. But um, yeah, man,
just a, just a nightmare. Yeah.
Yeah.
Another little commentary from you here
back to the book shooting another human
being was a math problem.
You are either right or wrong with no
subjective in between decided by someone
else.
I liked problems that were black and white
life or death before taking a shot at
a target 1000 meters away,
you had to calculate the effects
of the light air at altitude, wind,
humidity, angle of fire,
cartridge velocity and gravity.
You had to align the target, the
background of the terrain, the weather,
the noise and the weapon.
You had to work in concert with others.
At the same time, the target enemy
was figuring out how to kill you.
Combat was a zero sum making
played for the highest stakes,
live or die.
And the 31 people started the course
and 13 people graduated so that,
that should tell everyone why that sniper
designation is so damn hard to get it
cause it's no joke. And there's usually
at any point in time there's not.
There's usually around 300 school trained
snipers in the Marine Corps to anytime
really? Dang. Oh, that's in my task unit,
which is about 40 seals. We had
13 snipers. It was so awesome.
Yellows killers got lucky. You know,
I got lucky that the stars aligned.
Okay, so now you're trained up
and then in 2007, you deploy,
you deployed to Iraq? I did
first deployment. How pumped
palm you. I was pumped.
I have and I just, I just got out
of school trained man, you know, I'm
ready to go. I'm ready to go
turn the heat up. Right. And um,
and where we were going was actually a
bad spot. I mean we were in Karma. Yup.
And uh, it, it had, it had been bad,
but it was like we were part of that
search and uh, when we got there,
we took some contact once and
I just like to waterfalls.
It turned off, you go from streets
that you're fighting down to.
Next thing you know, I mean, you
could walk out with no gear. It's,
what were you guys doing? Just doing
patrols? We were doing a lot of dwell ops,
which is what we'd go out
basically what they were, the,
the theory on this was we would go out
off the farm and stay like four or five
days in a house and you know, um, you
know, we would get hit by indirect fire,
uh, you know, some, but I mean,
but I was only there for like 45 days
and then you got hit in the hand would go
what I got,
I got bid on the right hand,
my right hand by a spider and a
actually suffered severe nerve damage.
Lost the movement in my last three
fingers and a big chasm act you for this?
Yeah. Or medivaced you
back to Germany. Yeah.
So they send me to Al-assad and tried
to fix it there. I did. I, they,
they rushed me and I had two surgeries
and can't flew gia. And then, um, they,
they moved me to outside and they sent
me back to Germany and I was there for
like 25 days in the hospital in
Germany to save your hand basically.
And then they sent me home and then I
was having to do occupational therapy to
get, you know, to get my fingers
back. They wouldn't move, you know?
When were you back in Kentucky?
No, I was back at Hawaii.
Hawaii in my unit.
And,
but you did have a little bit of Kentucky
with you there in the form of Bourbon?
Yeah. Yeah. A lot of it. I was drinking.
How's the drinking started getting
after it a little bit. I did.
And even a little bit too much. Yeah.
Too much. You know, I started, you know,
it was hard.
It was hard coming home and knowing my
teammates were still over there and no
one that, my unit was still there
and I wasn't part of it, you know?
And then did you go,
did you have to go back or you came back
to states like on leave? Uh, no. No.
After you were, after your hand
was hurt. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So I came back to Kentucky Grata.
And you hung out there for awhile and
actually lost a couple friends at that
time. I did it. I did cause she was
tragical tragic situations. Yeah,
it was terrible. You know, I had a guy,
the guy, you know, actually his, you know,
his name is on my chest and um,
he,
we played football together and uh,
he had called me,
I was leaving the hospital and I was
coming home that weekend and he had called
me, he had called me right before I was
on the way to the hospital and said, hey,
you, hey man, we're going to go
to this football game. You know,
we're going to watch my little
brother play, you know, all of that.
And I got a call as soon as I was
leaving the hospital and he had, um,
he'd had a wreck and got killed. Yeah.
Close, close friend. Then I lost a,
um, another friend she got, she
got killed in December. Um, not,
not exactly what you want to go home or
leave for, man. That's harsh. No, no, no.
But you know, it's, it's just the way,
the way it goes. You know, they're in,
and then you say you spend that time at
home, you go back, you rejoin your return.
And this is when you find out that
they want volunteers to go help out in
Afghanistan. Yeah. So we built up weed. I
was back probably a year, year and a half,
went to mountain sniper
school. And, um, you know,
I became in charge of my own team, um,
but got married til he actually promoted.
Um, I was, you know, I
was a lance corporal lead,
a five man team with a sergeant on
it, you know, and uh, you know, I, uh,
ended up taking, like I had the worst,
like I got like the newest guys,
they gave me the newest guys and uh,
we ended up being the
general support team.
So we moved all the way up to the
platoon and ended up being, you know,
one of the best, one of the best
teams. And I'm stern and um, yeah,
so we're out at 29 palms doing her
final train up to go back to Iraq.
And this was when nothing
was going on in 2009. I mean,
they weren't letting you leave the
wire. Right. And, uh, we had no mission,
so it kind of sucked. Right. And, uh, they
came and said, we need five volunteers,
go to Afghanistan. And I said, what's
the mission? I said, we don't know,
but we just need five bodies. And
I raised my hand, said, yeah, I'm,
I'm ready to go again.
Like how many milliseconds?
Zero. That decision. And so that
what you were volunteering for,
you find out later is, is, uh, embedded
training team and advisory teams.
Know what that's all about. So an embedded
training team is where they take a,
you know,
they take different ranks and different
skillsets of marines and they put them
or you know, whatever, you know,
military unit and they put them together
and they embed them with a, you know,
a, an Afghan unit. So we were embedded
with the Ade Afghan's a whole, not a,
it was a company. And so
that's, that's, we just lived,
we did everything with them.
We did everything from, you
know, teach them weapons,
tactics and, and uh, you know,
um, shooting, shooting. We,
I did the change over for
the NATO weapons, right?
So we took them from cause
Soviet to the natal weapons.
And that's another key factor that we
need to bring up to talk about and that
gunfight. Um, so we were teaching them
on that call and them all and that,
you know, everything from
everything. I mean, we,
we did everything with these guys cause,
and then could you,
did you do any kind of work
up before you went over? Yeah.
So we that was it with that team.
Yeah.
Your actual team that you were
gonna deploy with. Yeah. So we did,
we did a workup with them.
Actually, no, I just left 29 palms.
I go back and we trained for
like a month or two in Okinawa,
Japan with this new team.
And then we head back to 29 palms and
then we go from, well we went back,
so he went to Bridgeport and
then we came down 29 palms.
We did all our mountain stuff
at Bridgeport, um, all our
mules and all that stuff,
you know, pack. And then, uh,
we came down and did it ended in
29 palms and then we headed over.
And that was with that four man team?
Yeah. With a Lieutenant Johnson,
gunny Kenefick,
um,
and doc late and myself and we'll talk
about those guys a little bit here in the
book. We've done it, Mike
Johnson's Forman team at Monte.
This is where you end
up place called Monte,
which is 10 miles worth north
of another fob called Joyce,
Lieutenant Johnson Sani and smiling
with an easy laugh but completely
professional with the highest standards.
I'd climbed mountains with
him in California of course,
and I knew he was a strong
physically as he was
mentally.
Staff Sergeant Aaron Kenefick was a
personnel specialist with eight years
expertise in administration.
So his job was to bring some order to
the Afghan personnel procedures and pre
pay records.
Doc Leighton are corpsman,
would provide some basic medical
care to the Afghans and the villages,
but it's primary job was to be ready
in case any advisors or Afghan soldiers
were wounded.
I had a job to lieutenant Johnson put
me in charge of tactics operations in
weapons training before each patrol I
approved of the Afghan scheme of maneuver,
inspected the radios and guns,
coordinated fire support and
planned and emergency escape route.
This was far easier than planning the
sniper missions I had been trained for.
So you,
you were,
you were kind of the most tactically
savvy guy in the group Vena sniper already
deployed to Iraq.
Yeah, no, I was, and you don't want,
and what will prepare me was my training
that I deal with my team. Um, you know,
my sniper team. I mean, look, I, I,
you know, people thought I was crazy.
They thought I was crazy the way that
I was training in my platoon before.
You're like, we're going to Iraq,
we're not gonna do anything. I'm like,
I don't give a shit. Right?
Like, I'm, I was still learning,
tack sat and I was still learning,
you know,
Satcom and I was still learning and HF
and I was still learning how to low crypt.
I mean, I wanted to know every
aspect of every part of the job.
I was learning every, I was going over
to the, to the Bas and learning, uh,
you know, all the medical stuff
that I could, and I was, you know,
I mean everything I could do,
like if I could get just a little nugget
in knowledge and better myself in every
aspect that was doing
it. And, um, so yeah.
So when I got over to this
team, I mean, you know, I,
I was the only tactical guy in there,
you know,
and, uh, yeah. And it was, you know, they,
they were, when it came to the tactics,
when it came to making sure
that the weapons were ready,
that the vehicles are ready,
that, that the, that the,
you know, that, uh, the jammers,
we're working that, you know,
if anything that mattered in the
patrol, it was on me, on you. Yeah.
That trucks were loaded.
And the reason that the Marine Corps put
the teams together like this is because,
well, that they're trying to develop the
whole Afghan army, every aspect of it,
not just the tactical side,
but they want like the administration.
So that the people can start getting
paid on time and the organization,
so they got the lieutenant in there and
at the same time they want to help the
villagers. So they put a corpsman
in there. So do medical work.
So that's kind of just a name.
If everyone's thinking,
why the hell would you put
together a team like that?
It's because the people that are
supposed to do the fighting are actually
supposed to be the Afghans.
Right? Yes. And, and,
and the team is there to support them,
help them train them, and get them ready.
Yeah. And that's, that's the
mind. That's the theory, right?
The theory is that you train,
you train them and they do the fighting
and you're just there to advise them.
Right. Um, but it never was works
that way. It does. It didn't
work that way in Iraq. And,
and one of the things that I pointed
out many times was, you know,
what kind of your you want to develop a
relationship with, with a group, right?
And, and now you say, okay,
we're going to train you,
but when it come time to do something
dangerous, you guys go by yourselves.
That's not, you're not building
a relationship. You're,
you're in fact you're going backwards.
No. Yeah, it's the same way. Oh,
so you get there and you start doing,
you're just kinda going on patrols
to going on patrols with the,
with the Afghan army company.
It was kind of interesting,
you know,
cause I was kind of the high
strung one on the team. You know,
like I was like the one that always was,
you know, we need to be ready to fight.
You know, I don't know how many arguments
I got into with some of the, the,
the leadership in teams, you know,
cause we, we were 21 man team,
but we were broken into four main
elements and spread out, you know, in,
in this area.
And I don't know how many times I got into
arguments with people and the team of,
you know, hey, this is how we need to do
it. We need to stay up. I mean, I was,
I was trying to train them, I
was doing stuff of, you know,
trying to train them to do ivs at
night with nods. And they're like,
why the hell are we doing this?
You know what I mean?
Like in a lot of people look down
on it and, uh, and, and I said,
I'm going to prepare to fight. And they
said, you know, we're not, you know,
they saw many times leadership got on me.
We're not going over there to fight.
We're going to advise.
And that was the mindset of a lot of this,
and I'm not gonna say my team,
but a lot of the team and uh,
and it showed, yeah, yeah. You know,
for everyone out there, that's it.
Wearing a uniform right now,
man.
Be ready for the worst case scenario
all the time. You're not ready for it.
You know what I tell him he is?
I said, you know, Lieutenant
Johnson was, uh, was a,
a calm guy,
satellite guy,
doc late and was a blue side Korman
and gunny Kenefick was an s one guy,
you know, and I always wonder, do you
think that they ever thought they'd be,
and one of the deadliest
battles in Afghanistan,
do you think they ever
thought they didn't?
You know, you don't know
where you're going to be at,
but one day you're going to be
tested. Yeah, you better be ready.
So you guys are rolling
out on these patrols.
Here's a good kind of aspect of
what you see on those patrols.
And you called the army.
The Afghan army soldiers ask ours.
Am I saying that other call? NASCARS
nascars all right, here we go.
Back to the book.
When we walked into some hamlets,
you could feel something was wrong.
When kids threw rocks at you,
you knew what the parents
were telling them.
Sometimes the ass cars grabbed the
kids soccer balls and slice them apart.
This didn't win any hearts and minds,
but it did stop the rocks.
Whenever the elders hurried through the
ceremonial tea though I'd watch the ass
cars when any soldier senses danger.
He crouches down a few inches to make
himself less of a target when the ass cars
did that. I went on full alert
Hafez ms saying that right? Yeah.
So his name is [inaudible] so I had
named him Hafez in that to protect him.
Got It. He's how he's here in
America now. Okay. We're good.
Hafez was our lead interpreter and we
quickly learned our best warning system at
a 37 year old sergeant major
retired from the Afghan army.
Hafez had served in Kuhner for
three years with advisor teams.
The Afghan soldiers distrusted him
because he refused to support their never
ending schemes to skim off the Americans.
So he's your, your most trusted advisor.
Interesting that you point out how when,
when soldiers sense danger.
And I was telling you about JP,
my lead sniper and one of my
two platoons and t you bruiser.
And when he came on the podcast, I'd
described him walking through the streets.
And you and I, because
like I told you, man,
I don't think JP was going to live
because JP was too brave for his own damn
good. But when I'd, you know,
I'd, I'd be watching, I'd be like,
like holding security and watching
patrol go and you'd see, you know,
I'd see guys moving with that little
crouch cause everyone's expecting that the
shooting's going to start.
And I'd see JP man walking with
his head up and his chest out,
like ready to get something.
It's nice to be 23 years old.
I'm not that you could die.
So that's my brother Jake.
And the other thing that, you know,
when you're in these foreign countries,
when we were in Iraq and Afghanistan,
the locals,
we can't tell the difference between it.
We really can't tell a difference
between a good buy in a bag.
I now you learned some sense
of it where you go, okay,
that guy looks shady and you're,
you're probably pretty accurate.
But the a guy let cuff Hafez, you get
to know, you can get to know instantly.
He was the unofficial fifth member
of our team inside of Hamlet.
If he shook his head at us, we knew it
was time to forget the tea and get out.
So w how much good,
how much,
how often would you go into a handle it
and the people were cool and all good
and drinking tea and you know, most
of the time, I mean most of them look,
I mean look, I, you know, the
people there want it to be better.
I mean they live in the shift. Yeah. They
live there. They want it to be better.
You know, they're just caught in a
bad situation. It's not a, it's not a,
it's not a simple equation.
You know,
there's nothing simple about
the life that they have to live.
You made some friends going back to the
book in the hills along the Pakistani
border. No Afghan military or
civilian had much of anything.
I think practically every American
soldier marine tried to help in some way.
We purchase candy and trinkets
in the markets to give the kids,
I assume had two little buddies boys
about 10 or 11 they'd hang around the main
gate. Jaelyn my e. Dot. A. Dot.
Trying to say your name
when they saw me at first,
I buy him cokes and then started sharing
my care packages from home soap, candy,
peanuts,
gone gum maybe a decade from now.
Some kids remember that some Americans
were kind to them even when they're older
brothers were shooting at them.
Maybe not.
You don't help out because you expect
something in return. So you're,
you're a human being man. Trying to try
to take care of some kids a lot there.
Um,
I think this is getting into
your first sort of legit,
we'll call it combat and a,
you're taking some small arms fire.
I'm going to the book here.
Staff sergeant can affect was standing
outside a bunker about 100 feet from me.
Meyer, we're under attack. He yelled
technically, yes, but the shepherd,
there's some shepherd out there,
but the shepherd was shooting
without poking his head up to aim.
He had one chance in a thousand of hitting
us, a second harmless, harmless burst,
followed the bullets cracking more than
10 feet above our head call for already.
Now staff sergeant can
affect yelled holding.
The radio had a headset out towards me.
Oh Nice staff sergeant.
Soon to be Gunnery Sergeant Kaktovik
needed the lowly corporals help.
I trotted towards him.
Stopped, assumed parade.
Rest postures aren't locked
behind my back chest.
Push forward in the wide open and pasted
to respectful expression on my face.
What does the staff sergeant
wish the corporal to do?
Another burst from the Aka.
This is no time to be a smart ass Meyer.
A few more rounds. Still way too high.
I'm locked at parade rest.
I staff sergeant,
he balanced the headset considering
whether to throw it at me. Meyer hurry up.
He had started calling in the artillery
mission and when I got to him he was
asking me,
what do I say now?
Left 100 drop 200 I said he
repeated it on the radio. What now?
He asked fire for effect. I said, should
be dead on. Okay. Fire for effect.
He repeated over the radio
and that's it.
You hit the guy. But
uh, it's funny that you,
even in that situation,
um,
you were talking about being kind
of a wise ass when you're a kid,
you're still a wise ass.
Yeah. You know the thing
about Ken, if Duke was,
me and him were butting heads
real hard at that time, you know,
we were butting heads. Um, you know how
some people would just take over. Like he,
he, he took over and tried to
make up for his lack of, you know,
nothing against him. And he wasn't
a combat. I mean it wasn't his job,
but what he tried to make up for in the
lack of his combat knowledge was his
authority. Right. And so, you know, he,
he had kind of pissed me off pretty bad
about, you know, asking me to do you,
can you stand at parade rest?
Like he was all big on it. Right.
And it's like we're on, we're on a
cop. Like, you know, we, you know,
you still need it, but you know,
customs and courtesies, right? Yeah.
And so I used that, that situation
to make a point, you know,
he just kind of pushed me over the
edge and then, but after that we,
yeah, that's kind of broad. You broke
us all, you know. That's awesome. Great.
You had some good Afghan
soldiers and under,
you were talking to me about them early.
One guy by the name of dawn Ali.
Here you go. He was fun to talk
to, open, friendly and fearless.
We'd sit around talking and
asking questions of each other.
Like kids in middle school learning
as much as we could about each other.
He proudly cleaned his soft five times
a day and absorbed every tip I gave him
about shooting. He was the most
disciplined ask are on base.
That's why we gave him the
salt in the first place.
She had good relationship with that.
Yeah, I mean I had a good relationship
with all my Afghans. I mean I,
I I at least two meals a
day with them. Um, you know,
usually I didn't eat breakfast with
them. I would eat it over at the, uh,
over at the, uh, you know, the Chow
Hall. But I used, you know, that was my,
that was my policy. I mean, every
night I ate dinner with them,
every single night I would eat dinner
with my Afghan soldiers because I was no
better than them.
You know, sometimes I hear,
I hear people, you know,
people that don't understand all what
was going on in Iraq or Afghanistan,
they'll, you know, you,
you, we were occupied.
America was occupiers
and how could you do it?
And it's like I always remind them like
we were fighting alongside the Iraqi
soldiers fighting alongside the Afghan
soldiers. I mean, spilling blood. Yeah.
I mean, we weren't, I mean, just
cause it was Iraq and Afghanistan war.
We weren't fighting Iraq and Afghanistan.
We were fighting with them.
We weren't fighting against
Iraq or Afghanistan. We
were fighting next to them.
You know, we were helping them
against the same enemy. You know,
so many people miss that
point, man. And his feeds up.
It's an important point to be
missed. It's a big, it's a big fat
man. I hear that. And it just
turns my stomach man. Um,
now I kind of joked about that,
that first situation being your first
combat and now you had legit your first
kind of trial by fire.
You're at combat because you're at the
outpost at Cop Monte and you're under
attack. You actually got some wounded,
some ass cars are wounded and you're here.
We're going back to book.
Where's dad? Where's staff
sergeant can affect? I yelled,
doc late and pointed toward
the North East Tower.
Get over there and stay with him.
I yelled,
suicide bombers sometimes rush the wire
trying to take an take an infidel with
them as they evaporated in a red flash
without hesitating doc late and ran down
the stairs across the open space and into
the tower with Staff Sergeant Kenefick.
Two or three seconds later or
rocket slammed into their bunker,
exploding into pieces and Afghan
worker huddled there behind beside the
sandbags, smoke rolled out
of the tower. They're gone.
I yelled to Johnson not believing what
I had just seen. I resumed firing.
It's all you can do. The best first
aid at that point was to return fire.
Johnson worked the radio,
Fox three one fox. We won.
This is Fox three staff sergeant can
affect doc late and come on answer up.
We kept firing, but it seemed
unworldly. Now we were on automatic.
Lieutenant Johnson got on the radio again.
Three one fox three one. This is Fox.
Three staffs aren't in. Can
Effect Dot Leighton. Come on, man.
Answer up then finally. Yeah. Yeah.
This is three one we're good. 10 minutes
later or attack helicopters began.
Strafing runs low rumbling
burrs like a giant burping,
incredible fire power. Those lovely
birds and to me, fire ceased.
Attack over Johnson and
I ran over to the bunker.
A Staff Sergeant Kenefick and
doc late and stumbled out.
The four of us sat on the bloody sandbags
and the growing dust talking about it.
Their eyes were slightly glazed and wide,
wide open.
Lieutenant John Johnson,
staff sergeant can affect doc and
doc Leighton weren't infantry.
They had considered that by coming
to Afghanistan they might die,
but it hadn't kicked in until now.
Now they had heard the screams and
seeing the blood. Everybody suit covered.
Understood. Now that if we went home
together, it might not be alive.
The ass cars were cleaning
up the bloody mess,
not six feet from us taking away the rip,
the body of their friend.
We mumbled some stuff.
All of us
were too embarrassed to
talk about our feelings,
but we knew what we were all thinking
this shit was for real and there were only
four of us will be there for
each other doc late and said,
the surfer dude surprised me.
He had said the one thing
that made any sense.
Yeah, that was, um,
yeah,
that was the Sunday before.
Uh,
so ganja gold was on a,
on a Tuesday.
That was September 6th of
2009 is a huge rocket attack.
I mean, they were dialed
in. It was terrible.
Like I can remember it as if I was there.
It was terrible.
How many rocks they fire. Oh, I
think we had nine that hit that one.
Oh seventh did hit dead on like in not
just nine. That hit just inside of,
of, not the whole base,
but just my Afghan base.
It's probably this,
you know,
where we're at right now is probably
bigger than that. He was terrible.
And that was a wake up call. Oh,
it was for all of us. I mean,
it was for all of us and it was for them.
And I, you know, I'll never forget, um,
yeah.
You know, I'll never forget talk. I mean,
we finally sat down and talked about
what do we do if we lose one of it,
you know, what do we want?
And, um, gosh, it was so real.
And you know, I'll never forget
Kenefick I had, um, I had met a,
backed out a guy, oh, the
wounded soldier that day. Um,
and he was putting me in for a bronze
star and I'll never forget he was walking
through in the, um, in the
little hooch and he said, uh,
and where we lived at.
And he was just, you know,
kind of joking a little bit later on that
day. He's like, hell Meyer, you know,
the way shit's going for you. And
it's unlucky as you are. He goes,
you'll probably be in for a medal of
honor before this deployments over with.
Huh. And, uh,
it's his crazy.
Yeah.
So that's two days before you
guys head down to Ganja Gall.
We'd actually got the call that night
that we were supposed to go to Ganja Gall
and the seventh and uh, they ended
up pushing it right to the eighth.
So we left the next day. We talk a lot
about it a little bit here. Ganja Gall,
late two miles north of joy. So we
drove right by the mouth of the valley.
Ganja gall sounded like the name of an
Irish town full of smiling faces and
friendly pubs.
I could see a few of the larger
compounds far back on a hillside,
nestled against steep ridge lines,
bad place,
half as muttered bad people. So
you're getting right away. Get,
I mean, we were told instantly. I mean, we
were told like, I mean we, I mean, yeah,
there was no doubt.
Now one thing that I think
made you feel more calm,
a little bit more comfortable.
You talk about in the book,
historically the Taliban had not
sprung ambushes from inside villages.
So that wasn't discussed at the briefing.
Plus we were going in
with 90 Afghans and 15 advisors with a
platoon from one three to deployed behind
us in a quick reaction force.
This shows us,
this show belongs to the, to
our Afghan counterparts. Fabio.
Am I saying that right? Yeah, Fabio.
Fabio said we advisers will stand off
to the side and let them talk with the
elders were not in the lead. We're
assisting. That made no sense.
I thought considering who is doing
the briefing and who is hearing yet.
We were in the tactical lead
even if we claimed otherwise.
That's what a little point.
But that's a political thing.
Um, yeah, I mean I, I think
it's an ignorance thing. Well,
I think it's an ignorant thing too,
but the reason it happened. No, no, no,
of course.
I mean technically we fail under,
so I mean technically
the way that this works,
it's crazy as this sounds I was working
for like my commander was Afghan
commander, whatever the Afghan commander
told me was what I was supposed to do.
Right. I mean, I'm saying
that's a political thing for
us to say politically, look,
the Afghans are running this operation.
Yes, yes, yes. I mean that, you know,
but that, um, if you remember what I said
a little bit earlier about, you know, hey,
we're not going to do the
fighting. I mean, you know, that,
that's the mentality of the
leadership of team. Yeah.
Yeah. Not Good. Then
as you just said here,
that made no sense, I thought, and you
were a corporal 20. How old were you?
I would say 2121 years old. And
you're looking at this going, hey man,
this doesn't make any sense. We're the
ones that are sitting here briefing it.
Yeah. We know where the ones that know
how to call for fire. Yeah. I mean,
and I brought it, well, I
mean, first off, first off,
the Afghans can't even talk to anybody
that calls for fire or the helicopters.
I mean,
they don't even have any comms with them.
Their own h f you know what
I mean? Yeah, yeah. I mean,
I,
so the,
the three main factors that I brought
up in the brief and I brought up that,
look, we're only, everybody's going in,
we have over 12 different moving elements
between the ops and different teams
inside this patrol. Yep.
All on one frequency.
I brought that up. I brought
up the fact that, um,
we didn't have direct air support is
on 15 minutes strip alert and that's in
Jalalabad so all,
and you know,
so they were taking it as if the birds
would be there within 15 minutes. I said,
that's not what, 15 minutes
Tripler meetings. They're up.
That means off the ground in 15 minutes.
And then they still got night are probably
60 minutes to get from Jalala bad to
us.
And so that was another factor.
And then the other thing
that I brought up was, um,
why would we put our snipers 2000 meters
away from the village outside of their
effective range of their weapons? There
you go. But here's what I was told.
I'm an e four in the
United States Marine Corps.
What do I know about mission planning?
And that's why I was taken
out of the team check. So, um,
yeah,
when you say, when you talk about
getting taken out of the team,
explain how that went down a little bit.
So you've got your four man team. Yeah.
Team Monte. Yeah. It's your
money. And so what they did was,
is, you know, they had, there's like
they would put the teams, you know,
you would go with your Afghans
in here to do their part. Um,
so our team was supposed to
go to the back of the village,
cover the back side of it,
and then we were going to search couple
house up there for a machine gun. And, um,
while the meeting went on and they took
me out of the team because I brought up
those concerns and, um, you know,
they kind of took it as me going against
the orders, questioning their authority,
and they replaced me at the gunny,
gunny Johnson.
So I'm just, I just have to say this right
now, so I talk about this all the time.
And, um, if you're in a leadership
position, you don't want, yes, ma'am.
You don't want, yes men. You want
the the corporal that says, Hey boss,
I don't understand why
you do that right now.
And if your answer to your
subordinate is because I said so,
or it's you're already for be
quiet or you're an e five be quiet.
If that's what your answer is,
that means you don't have a real answer.
That means that what you're
doing is probably wrong.
So surround yourself,
the best people you can have on your
team or the people that are going to
question what what it is that your,
your plan is.
And if they question it and you can't,
don't have a good logical answer and your
plan doesn't stand on its own two feet.
Well think about it and reassess it and
take some advice from down the chain of
command on how what we could
do to change this planet.
Yeah, I mean it was,
look, they're complacent.
You know,
that's,
that's the type of mentality that you
have when you don't expect to go get your
ass handed to you.
That's why you need to expect to get your
ass handed to you every day and train
like it.
Yeah. You know, I, I, I used
to, when I was running Turner,
we trained for worst case scenario all
the time. It was like worse than me.
You know what? And it was, it
was insane. Like we had great,
we had great financing for our training.
So the training was awesome.
We had mayhem going on,
we had paint balls and we had laser,
this multi multimillion dollar laser
tag system and we had roleplayers and it
was awesome.
And I wanted may him and we had,
we would put guys down and you'd
have to carry them out. And it was a,
it'd be like we'd be mayhem
and sometimes guys, cool,
this is coming to and realistic and
what are the chances this is really
happening? And I'd be like, look,
if this doesn't happen, great.
You don't ever have to worry about it
happen for real. But if it happens,
you'll be ready for it.
At least as ready as you can be.
Yeah.
So you get pulled off the team.
I got to pull it off the team and my
job was going to be to stay with the
vehicle. So like basically we were going
to drive vehicles in park the vehicles.
Now. That was the other thing I
said. I said, this is dumb. Why,
why would we leave our up armored
guns a couple of miles away?
And they said, you mean you ready for
the response here? You're ready. Oh,
well Dakota, uh, because we want to
go into the village clendette Stein,
you have a 90 man patrol. Yeah.
Yeah. That's not going happen.
Just to paint
a picture for everyone.
Basically there's a deep ravine walls
on either side at the top of the ravine.
It kind of splits into two other ravines
and there's kind of villages on both
sides of that.
Yeah. It splits into, it splits into two.
Like it's Kinda like two valleys
inside of a big valley. Right.
And on the right hand side
was another bad valley,
but we were going in the left hand
side. Now is ganja call. And um,
I mean this, this terrain was built
to fight. It was built to fight.
I mean they had trenches in it,
there were trenches in it that they
use to fight out of. It is not,
and obviously you're
walking up the valley,
which means automatically
you're in the low ground,
which is not where we want to be ever.
All right.
Now you the one of the guys you
are going to be working with.
MMM.
In the Hummers was staff
sergeant Juan Rodriguez Chavez.
Here we go.
Back to the book I sought out Staff
Sergeant Juan Rodriguez Chavez are motor
transport chief.
I known him for five months.
He didn't stand on rank and we traded
stories about growing up on farms.
He had grown up on a ranch in Mexico
having a similar approach to life.
Rob and I had become friends.
He was in the eighth grade when his
family moved to Texas where he learned
English, played football, earned
good grades and rope cows and Rodeos.
Our team called him hot rod.
He laughed a lot,
bragged about how smart his two daughters
were and kept all our vehicles in top
condition. Rob, this mission is fucked
up if the shit hits the fan. I said,
we're going in my teams walking
point and they'll get caught off.
We have to go in and get them out.
And he looked back at you devil dog.
Rod said,
say the word and I'll do the driving.
Yeah, that's legit. He's
the man. He is the man.
And uh,
continuing on, you say having
some sort of contingency plan.
Now I walked back to the adviser
headquarters and brief Lieutenant Johnson.
By the way, Lieutenant Johnson didn't
want you out of the team either. Right?
He wanted you to stay with Canon.
Fake were pissed.
He knew that you should be with the team
if things get hairy.
I said I'm coming in,
rod will drive radio your coordinates
and get down to the wash fucking climate
and we'll haul ass back to the main body
cause they were going to be exposed on
the far end of that.
Right.
Wow. Yeah. So I,
so everything that I did was
planned out the night before check.
Everything that I did was planned out
the night before and it was all in our
team. I mean, I told him, I mean,
I told him, I said, you know,
you say the word and I'll head in there.
I don't care.
I know I'm coming to get you. And um, I
mean that w we had this all planned out.
Like all they had to do was get
to the road and I would be there
continuing on back to
the book and the talk,
a report about Ganja Gall had
come in via brigade internet.
A special forces team reported that
32 fighters, we're moving Pakistan to
reinforce God. Your
Gall, half an hour later,
the video feed from an unmanned aerial
vehicle showed a man with a mortar tube
on his back entering unknown, safehouse
two kilometers north of conjugal village.
10 minutes later for more men entered
the same house. So, so you're,
you're watching this. So here's
the crazy part. Nobody told us.
Oh, so you didn't even get
that report. Nobody told us.
Check. Um, and I got to
point out to everyone, I'm,
I'm obviously skipping giant chunks of
this book and there's an awesome amount
of detail that,
that Dakota goes into in,
in how this is going down.
And I'm kind of hitting the wave tops
to get to get the story there. But,
uh, okay. You don't even get that Intel,
but doesn't matter because the next
day I guess where you're going into the
valley, um, you got a guy
with you named Swenson,
he's in charge of some border police,
some Afghan border police. Is that right?
Yeah.
So Swenson's border police turned
to Hafez when the lights went out.
Dutchman. He said, am I saying that
right? Dutchman Dishman Douche man,
which is another term for
enemy for enemy douche man.
They said we must turn back. So they're
already freaking out. Yeah. Yeah. So they,
I think I, uh, I think
that they, they were, uh,
why some of the police had already
knew they had lead tipped it off. Yep.
They had had information one way or the
other when we were coming in and they
leaked the plan. Yeah. So I think that
that's why they were trying to bail out,
in my opinion, it was because they knew
what was already there. Yeah. Got It.
And um,
just before five in the morning,
rod and I heard gravel contract
crunching on the trust.
So now you're actually in position, you
dropped off the guys and now, uh, the,
the Afghan team with some of the advisors
including team Monte are heading up
the valley and you're waiting
at the bottom end of the valley.
I'm sitting back at the back of the
trucks and they're going, you know,
they're going into the valley and um,
yeah,
at this point now everybody's leaving
the valley. Yeah. This, this part,
just before five in the morning, rod and
I heard gravel crunching on the trail.
Men, women, children,
sheep and goats suddenly hurried by
our trucks heading out of the valley.
Okay.
Predawn always brought the first sing
song called a prayer followed by per
people scurrying about. And, and this
is just, you knew right then, right? Oh,
a hundred percent no, 110%
yeah. I mean, no doubt. So this,
do you know, just for anyone
that's listening that is important?
Two and two together here,
there's a village with a
bunch of civilians in it
and the civilians all leave
and they take their animals with them.
They take all their,
they take everything that's worth,
worth anything with him so they
know that there's, it's on.
Going back to the book as Lieutenant
Johnson Approach, the first row of houses,
he radioed back to Garza
that he and lieutenant ruler,
we're heading toward the house of
an e mom, one of the village elders.
Seconds later, an RPG street in from
the east followed by a of PKM, a Russian
made machine gun that shoots a
hefty 7.62 millimeter cartridge.
It started tearing up the ground and the
Adobe walls as the men took cover among
the terrorist walls.
More PKM fire came in from the northeast,
joined by a k's at a closer range.
Enemy fighters were crouched inside
the houses and below the windows of the
schoolhouse on the southern Ridge.
They were hiding in the alleyways and dug
in behind the stone terrorist walls to
the east.
They had a dozen fixed positions and we're
shooting downhill with the sun behind
them. Yeah. They know what
they're doing. Yeah. This is, um,
again,
um,
do any kind of anybody with any kind
of military knowledge whatsoever.
When you read that paragraph or that,
that does two paragraphs right there,
you see that you are not in a horrible,
horrible scenario.
Multiple enemy machine
gun positions in elevated
coordinated attack. Yeah. Horrible.
And here's your thoughts back to the book.
I waited for the firing to die down,
but it didn't.
The chaos of the RPG explosions,
PKM machine guns [inaudible]
and [inaudible] increased.
I heard the report of a recoil less rifle,
basically a hundred pounds shoulder or
tripod mounted cannon and a sure sign of
a plan.
Damn Bush as a Douche.
Men Don't lug that over
the hills for an exercise.
Then I heard the crump crump
of their mortar shells.
There was a wide babble of voices on the
command radio advisers yelling at each
other to clear the net. No one was taking
charge. There was no central command.
I was pacing around,
frustrated,
being out of the fight and
not being able to help.
So yeah,
seen enough of like little firefights
that we'd be able to burst of fire and
then people are going to run it by me
know, like they're going to just see,
they blow their load like right in
the beginning and then you know,
they don't have enough.
Like they're not able to like us resupply,
they don't sustain anything.
This was endless.
And then yeah,
you mentioned this earlier and again
just to kind of point out to people,
so they, so they understand what you
were talking about. You said Hey,
there's going to be 14 different
maneuver elements. A 12 yeah.
12 different maneuver elements
and they're all on the same net.
Now what that means is they're
all in the same radio frequency.
So picture this you,
you're trying to have a conversation
on the phone but so or 12 other people,
11 other people all trying
to have a conversation on
the phone at the same time.
Yeah. With their, with their nerves,
with their nerves while
they're chaos is happening.
Yeah.
And
so this is what you end up
doing is actually on a phone
you have a better chance
because a phone, we'll kind of kind
of let some of that traffic through,
but when you start stepping
on each other on the radio,
it just cut each other off
and you can't hear anything.
That's exactly what happened.
And the other piece of it was it's not
just that it was all that one frequency,
everything had to be relayed
through those snipers to get there.
The elevated high ground
to get back to the,
could you,
did you have direct coms with the
guys on the ground? Yes I did.
But I'm saying like to get to the
command like you know in the big thing I
brought up was was you know what happens
if you're calling it a med evac and
you're calling in call
for fire. Yeah, that's,
that's like trying to call the fire
department and the ambulance and,
and you're trying to call
him at the same time.
Like you gotta you gotta separate them?
Yes. Actually that's not a good example.
It's trying to call the
ambulance and it active shooter.
And trying to maneuver all that
stuff happening at the same time.
Yeah.
Back to the book soon.
Both Ridge lines were sparkling with fire
as the ass cars and Douche Min engaged
each other with rocket propelled grenades.
Smoking shrapnel filled the air.
MMM Swenson
ease.
He's on.
This is Highlander six he yelled over
the Din Ford Ford Line of troops pinned
down at x Ray Delta and
heavy enemy fire request.
Immediate cert suppression
fire Kilo Echo will adjust.
So he's trying to call fire
your back and you and rod says,
what do you think rod said if the
Dishman caught around the rear,
I said and close the back door.
They'll catch our people in a fire sac.
This is deep shit.
They got to get out of there.
The way to break up an ambush
is to hammer it with heavy fire.
The Humvee gave us armor
mobility and a heavy gun.
We would roll in and bring team Monte
back to the location of the command group.
I grabbed the radio and called Fox
Fox three Lieutenant Fabio, no reply.
I tried Fox six Williams and then
Fox nine first Sergeant Garza.
No one replied.
I was calling for permission to enter
the valley asking for it from anyone who
would answer.
Finally,
Fox seven Valdez up on the
northern Ridge answered on the net.
Fox three three your request
to enter the valley are denied.
Fox Nine says you are to stay
at your present location.
Okay,
and again, I'm throwing out a
bunch of different names here.
These are all the different leaders
that are out there on these different 12
elements and when you read the book for
yourself, you can kind of catch and,
and understand exactly what was
happening there. But the, the,
the, basically what was going on was your
calling to whoever would answer to get
permission to drive up the
valley and go give a hand. Yeah.
Shine and get permission.
I put down the hand set and sat there
listening as the does as a dozen advisors
try to talk over a single radio channel.
It was sheer bedlam. This is bullshit.
Rod. I recheck the ammo belt and the
Mark 19 rod sat in the driver's seat.
You Ready, rod? Give it a few more
minutes. Meyer, you'll fry for this.
He said he was right, I'd get sent
home for disobeying a direct order.
There was no question
in my mind about that.
I was already on thin ice with Garza,
Fabio and Williams.
So I sat there frustrated
listening to the shooting,
flexing my hands on the grips of
the mark 19 and breathing hard.
I tried to calm down,
maybe the battle sounded worse on the
radio than it really son of a bitch inside
the tactical operations center at joy.
So Joyce is a couple miles away and the
TAC or operation center is where they're
running this. There were
supposed to have, um,
kind of situational awareness of
everything that's happening and they're
supposed to be able to supply supply,
fire support.
So that's why when we're talking about
the tactical operations center at Joyce,
that's what it is.
Captain Aaron Harding was the senior
officer on duty from midnight to eight in
the morning.
The battle captain.
He had been in Afghanistan for eight
months but had rarely controlled fires and
certainly not in certainly not unlike
this as artillery stood by at Joyce a few
miles away.
Ended up [inaudible] a few miles away.
Harding asked for more and
more information from the
men on the long table who
was requesting the fire missions?
Was it shadow for Highlander five or Fox
three what did they heard from Fox six
who is presently in charge?
The marine advisors or the Afghan army.
Did the ground commander know
where all his troops were?
Had they double check
the grids of the k ease.
Okay.
He asked question after question.
At Joyce,
120 millimeter millimeter mortars were
fired for fired 15 minutes after Fabio
requested. The first shell though struck
within 50 meters of the enemy position.
The next flurry of shells was on target.
That would be the only effective fire
mission of the entire day and this is one
of the things that you're
going to get more into.
We actually recently talked about the,
the battle in the,
I drank valley and those guys would
absolutely 100% have been overrun.
And what saved their ass over and over
again was artillery and fire support.
Yeah. That's the biggest advantage that
we have on the battlefield as Americans.
100% and your co and your
team is calling for it.
The advisors are calling for
it and they're not getting it.
Yeah. We're not getting it. I mean,
they shut it down and, and, and, and to,
to try to give the benefit of the doubt
here. Right. A of why they shut it down.
I totally understand it, but it goes back
to the one thing I said, right? I mean,
they couldn't probably couldn't figure
out who the hell was calling what and
where, what was where. I mean,
I don't know that I could've
confidently fired around and,
but part of it was because of the
layout of everybody on one frequency,
you know, it goes back to
the initial problem. Like,
I don't know if I could have
fire round now I am. I am.
I pissed that they didn't fire
around. Absolutely. Like it was wrong.
It was wrong for what the reasons
they did it. But you know, I, I,
the confusion was so chaotic
in the beginning especially.
Um, but I can tell you this,
that if they had got the rounds,
it broke the enemy
and you don't again to,
to advance your point of giving
the benefit of the doubt.
If they have no idea where friendlies are,
they could've fired rounds
on friendly forces as well.
Exactly. And then, you know,
they'd have been accountable for
that. And I'll tell you, that's, um,
that's a hard to make to,
to possibly, you know,
fratricide blue on blue is,
is in my opinion,
that's the worst thing
that happened in war.
And so what these guys are being
asked to possibly do is, is,
is risk a fratricide yes.
Which in their minds and most
probably a lot of military minds,
I think mine included. Well, it's
hard to say what's better, you know,
risk fratricide or risk,
uh, getting overrun.
Now if we know for a fact people are
getting overrun, then you're like, okay,
we'll risk fratricide. And that's why
that happens sometimes where people say,
dropped that bomb no matter what,
but to say,
I'm not 100% sure people
are going to over run,
but I'm still going to take the
risk of fratricide at this point.
That's probably why they're holding
off it is in the beginning. Yeah. Yeah,
and they get to a point where they call
the danger close rounds and try and take
responsibility and we'll, we'll
get there. Back to the book.
The enemy above the neb above work
their way around the edges of the valley
shooting downhill.
The Taliban machine gunners tracting on
one ass car then another than another.
It was a killing ground.
They're all over the place.
Swenson was thinking to himself,
I may not make it out of here.
Okay.
If you hunker down and don't shoot back,
you will surely die.
The other side gains confidence and
rushes forward in the frenzy of combat
soldiers act like sharks.
They sense weakness and circle in picking
off the wounded and the defenseless.
Slowly the Douche men we're closing
in from both sides of the wash,
so they were ready.
Oh the, let me tell you something.
They were good. They were good.
They were trained that year. You know,
they had, they had plate carriers.
They are taking the uniforms off
or a dead guys. Um, you know,
they put Kev Lars on shit.
They're good.
Still trying to get fire support here.
Swenson.
It identified enemy position
to four grid positions.
There are two basic ways
of calling in artillery.
You can give the grid coordinates of
the target or the Kilo Echo number for a
grid and adjust after the initial round
or you can give your own location and a
compass bearing to and
distance to the target.
The second technique is
called a polar mission.
Provides the guns with the locations
of both the friendly observer and the
target. Tell the talk. I'll send
it. Polar Swenson. Radio de Kaplan.
It's on me. Give them my initials.
I'm making the decision, not them.
Assuming accurate fire. The U s
mortars were less than two miles away.
The only target endangered by the
polar plot was the enemy by sending his
initial Swenson was taking full
responsibility. If anything went wrong.
If a friendly soldier
or civilian were hit,
the burden rested squarely on sweats
and not with the talk in the rear.
The talk responded to the polar request
by asking again for information that was
impossible to provide.
Where were all the friendly troops?
What was the forward line of
trace of the friendly units?
Was everyone accounted for?
Were any civilians?
Yeah.
Kaplan told shadow the relay team above
the him tell the talk. That's that.
It's critical. I repeat critical.
We have advisers pin down the talk.
Denied shadows,
fire mission,
Furious Sergeant Summers at shadow
for pressed back against the talk.
The main element is being hit
from the north, east and south.
All elements are engaged. I repeat.
All elements are heavily engaged.
We need fire missions.
Now.
The NCO is inside the talk.
We're doing their job and the artillery
and mortar cruise wanted to oblige.
Yet it seemed to sergeant summers that
every time he relayed a fire mission to
talk,
ask him 20 questions.
A second string was running
the show here and not well.
Okay.
In firefights.
It's not unusual for 200 to 2000 artillery
shells to be fired over the course of
the first hour of the ballot.
Ganja gall when men lay trapped and dying.
The talk at Joyce allowed only
21 artillery shells to be fired.
Yeah.
Since World War II forward observers
had received artillery fire.
Under the rule of silence is consent
when it observer called for fire.
The mission went by radio to the
operation center and to the guns.
Silence by the ops center constituted
consent for the guns to fire
and the 21st century with computers
making instant firing calculations within
two minutes shells could
be hitting the target,
but beginning about 2006 sergeants
and lieutenants on the front lines,
we're trusted less.
The high command believed the grunts
were too quick to call and fires that
endangered civilians resulting in an
embittered population that supported the
insurgency. The solution was
to apply a strict new rule.
Two months before gone. De Gaulle,
general Stanley McChrystal,
the senior commander in Afghanistan
issued a directive that forbade the use of
artillery against or near any structure
likely to contain civilians unless the
higher,
the next higher headquarters commander
had approved that ended silence is
consent.
The high command had shifted decision
making from the battlefield to the staff.
Swenson was not trusted to
make the hard decisions.
Instead officer's in the talk with a
confused idea of the battlefield had to
decide whether to honor
his requests for fire.
Yeah, I know it. So that's where my
problem comes in, right. Is, you know,
if the doctrine is that you, I give my
initials, I take the responsibility,
we'll then follow the doctrine.
Yeah. You know, that's, there's,
there's where they went
wrong. And I'll, I'll tell you
something else that, you know,
you talked about how confusing it was
over the net and clearly it was obviously
very confusing.
How long would it take to verbally
explain the layout of this whole,
Oh,
it would take a very long time.
It would take an extremely eloquent
person who had the time to kind of compose
himself and,
and sit there and try and explain it.
That's why you make Kate Key low echoes.
That's why you have these preplanned
fire positions so that you don't have to
think anymore.
We can direct fires and,
and what instead of having to communicate
what the situation on the ground is,
what you communicate is this is what we
need and this is where you need to put
it. I mean, that's 100% in
it. I mean, that's 100%.
It is, you know, um, you
could never first off you,
you could never relay all the
information there and guess what,
at the end of the day, it was irrelevant
to what they were needing to do it.
And also by the time you, if you could
relay it by the time you related,
it would be different because what are
you going to tell everyone to sit still
for a minute while I explain where you
are, that doesn't work. That's why,
that's why decentralized command
is so important on the battlefield.
This is the exact reason why decentralized
command is so important on the
battlefield.
When you centralized command people and
the people that actually are there that
need to be able to make decisions,
make things happen, can't do it. Yup.
Okay.
Um, and by the way, how do you
overcome a situation like this?
How do you overcome a situation
where, okay, you're my subordinate,
you work for me and I don't,
I don't want you to be able to have
the ability to fire because I'm afraid
you're gonna hurt civilians.
How do I solve that?
The way to solve it is not to say no,
I don't get that.
You got Authority the way I solve
it, as they say, okay, Dakota,
let me explain some things to you.
We need to protect the civilian populace.
We need to make sure we don't damage
any infrastructure to the best of our
ability. I want you to understand
how strategically important that is.
Do you understand?
Let me put you through some scenarios.
What if you were here in this happened?
What would you do?
What if you're hearing this happened?
I train you and I build trust so
that I can decentralize the command.
That's how you overcome it.
You don't overcome it.
It's a shortcut to try and centralize and
it ends up getting people killed. 100%
all right.
Going back to the book,
Fox three one Lieutenant Johnson
finally came up on the radio,
were pinned down in a house receiving
accurate fire from the next house.
We have to get out of here.
He was caught off by others
pushing to use the same frequency.
Three or four advisors. We're trying
to talk, stepping on each other.
I could hear the strain in their voices.
The lack of Chris borders,
the frantic yelling of men who were
pinned down after a few minutes,
Fox three to staff sergeant can affect,
tried to pass his location on the
grid to Fabio. I can't shoot back.
Aaron said, because I'm pinned down
there shooting at me from the house.
It's so close. Grid three two.
This is three three radio staff
sergeant can affect, repeat your grid,
repeat your grid or you. You radioed
to Kenefick. Repeat your grid.
Repeat your grid.
So he faded as he was trying to tell you
is grid nothing after that but static
in garbled voices that broke it for
me. I had promised my team I would
be there as far as I was concerned.
My command element wasn't in command
twice. I had heard shadow say that
air would be on station in 15 minutes.
Nothing happened.
How long do you do nothing while your
friends are fighting for their lives?
Fox seven this is three. Three sitting
here is stupid. We're going in.
Rod and I were on the net with Valdez.
There was no dispute among us.
It was about zero 600 time to move.
I was the vehicle commander so the
fault lay with me for disobeying orders.
If I arrived in the valley and discovered
that the command group had had the
situation under control,
I knew there was a good chance I'd be
sent back to the states and disgrace.
When I shouted the ask ours to follow us.
They look confused up
on the north outpost.
Valdez grabbed a senior Afghan sergeant,
the sergeant radio to the Afghan
drivers clustered around our truck,
urging them and past due to follow me,
mortar shells were falling a
football field away to our west.
The enemy knew our trucks
were somewhere on the path,
but uncertain just where the explosions
made my made the askers jumpy,
just the same.
Some of them jumped into two Humvees
and roared in a position behind us. Rod,
let's go.
I said he put it in gear.
Now.
By that time you start actually going
into the valley and as you're going in,
by that time several NASCAR's,
we're stumbling out of the battlefield.
Some bleeding, a few without the rifles,
all exhausted where Americani I yell,
dose dose, the ass cars pointed
up toward the village. So,
so as you're driving in your scene,
guys fleeing the battlefield,
I mean it was like, it was
terrible. Like is we go in and you,
you're just seeing these guys come out
and it's in Ramadan so they won't eat or
they won't drink any water and they're
coming out of this battle and they're
just like,
you're not even close to the valley yet,
and they're coming out as battle.
They don't have any weapons on them.
They're just broken. Their
bloodied there, there been shot.
They've just, I mean, you're carrying
each other and you're just like,
okay,
what are we going into?
Somewhere behind us
was a u s army platoon.
It seemed to me to be a time
for them to make a move.
They were the quick reaction force.
Our Insurance Policy Valdez was on the
radio argument with dog three six the
quick reaction.
Army platoon commander dog-free six this
is Fox seven Valdez radio radioed you
need to get in there man.
Fox,
three threes to your front in a Humvee
drive east until you link up with him.
Fox seven this is dark
three six at the lieutenant.
Our vehicles are too big for the mission.
Okay.
We were driving on a footpath.
I was barely wide enough for our home.
The Valdez came up with an alternative
dog-free six. This is Fox seven.
I understand. Drive forward until
you reach the Afghan vehicles.
Use them to get into the fight.
There are people out there dying.
The platoon leader said he had to wait
for clearance from the talk at Joyce.
Yeah.
What kind of vehicles did the
QRF after an MRI. APPS. Okay.
No
God, I mean me excuse. Yeah. How
awesome would it be to have an m wrap?
Roland did this situation with and I
don't think they could have the road.
Wouldn't tell it to small. Yeah. Cause
they ended up coming in and one of those,
uh,
it looks like a tank but it's on wheels
and it ended up flipping over often off
the bank. But they look at the end of
the day, we had a ton of Humvees, women,
we just brought in 90
people sitting right there.
They could have jumped
in the Humvees and came.
Yeah.
The helicopter ops center called back
saying the re tasking of the birds had
been canceled because lance had not
called his own brigade headquarters to ask
permission.
And because another mission north of
Ganja Gall was of higher priority.
So one of the guys in the, in the ops
center had actually said, you know what?
Screw it, I'm calling for
calling for kilos. And he,
but he hadn't called the brigade and run
through the proper chain of command and
they,
they shut him down.
Yeah.
So here we go. More than an hour into
the fight, the situation was as follows,
team Monte was trapped in a house in the
u s and Afghan commanders were pinned
down by shooters closing in
on them from three sides.
Yeah.
The North and south observation
posts were under fire.
The ass cars were caught in
the open with nowhere to hide.
Rod and I hadn't reached
the wash. The one, three,
two quick reaction platoon
was not quick reacting.
The talk at Joyce was paralyzed,
preventing artillery support and the
helicopter gunships had not arrived.
It was a perfect storm.
Damn.
That's just, um, there's
absolutely nothing else.
Go wrong right now. It's a perfect
storm is the absolute perfect storm.
Okay?
Swenson wanted a massive artillery
barrage because the Douche man didn't have
overhead cover. Artillery. Air
Bursts would send millions of lance.
It's raining down toward them.
Hundreds of shells had to shake the
mountains and roll funder down the valley.
The douche, man, we're zealots,
but they weren't crazy.
Once artillery began exploding overhead,
gunman with eight K's wouldn't get
up and run forward in the open.
Yet the talk refused to fire it gone.
Juggalo me a few miles from Camp Joyce
on leasing a barrage in your own backyard
wouldn't win any applause
at higher headquarters.
The directive from the
high command was so clear.
Do not employ air to ground or
indirect fires against compounds
to as any structure or building
known or likely to contain civilians.
Unless the ground force commander has
verified that no civilians are present.
Sarah and I mean, you
know, and there's that.
You know that rule right there
is Britain so impossible.
You know what do you do? [inaudible]
mean the village you're getting shot at.
So you run through there, you
civilian. Are you shooting me?
Okay.
You know,
um,
I'd have to look do like a full
review of the Rois or this Pacific der
Directive. But you know, normally the
self defense thing trumps everything.
Well, usually, and that's what I always
say, right. I always talk about Roe is,
and you know, Ryes we'll say, you know,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Within,
at the end of it, it always ends, it says,
or hostile act, hostile
intent. [inaudible]
but it's all by interpretation. I mean,
it goes back to the commanders. I mean,
you know,
I don't blame the Rov that Stanley
McChrystal put in place for what happened
that day.
I blame the people,
the leadership who was
incompetent to make a decision.
You know what I mean? Like, like,
it's like nobody wants to just own
it and take accountability and take
responsibility and say,
you know what,
I'm doing this because it's the right
thing to do. They want to be able to say,
well, I didn't do it because, well,
this is the order. Come on, come on.
You know, if you're in a
leadership position to take,
take responsibility.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
You got to do the right thing.
That's the bottom line.
And that's what makes leadership hard.
And sometimes the right
thing is to break rules.
Sometimes the right thing
is to not follow orders.
Sometimes orders are wrong
and you shouldn't follow him.
And Napoleon said,
if you,
if you're in charge and you get tasked
with something that's wrong and you
execute it, you're culpable. It doesn't
matter if you get ordered or not.
Okay.
Sometimes you break the rules going right
back to the yes man. Thick, right? Yeah.
And I guarantee,
I guarantee the intent of Stan McChrystal
putting this roe in place wasn't to
deny guys that were pinned
down by enemy fire. But
again, how are we communicating
it and are we putting,
so we put in the para priorities in
place correctly so that everybody knows.
Yeah. I mean, you know, um, when it's
put out in an email, it's kind of like,
it's as dangerous as you
interpreting me a text.
I mean, everybody looks at different. Yup.
Okay.
And you know what, that's why things
like commander's intent are so important.
If I know what it is, like your
eye, if I what it is that you want
done and my job is to get it done and
you give me parameters to do it within.
I'll stay within those parameters
and I'll get the job done.
Okay.
And I'll come back to you
and say, Hey boss, I had to,
I had to bend the rules a little bit here,
but I got the mission done.
Or I might call you back and say,
Hey,
I'm getting ready to break the
rules to get the mission done.
Do you want me to break them or not?
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
Back to the book.
Shadow the army outpost on the southern
Ridge replied that the talk at Joyce
said the fire mission was too close to
the village, too close to the village.
Lieutenant Johnson said, if you
don't give me these rounds right now,
I'm gonna die.
Yeah,
try your best
shadow replied knowing
the talk wouldn't fire.
Try your best.
Okay.
From the tone of shadows voice, I knew
he was on the verge of complete rage.
He wanted to strangle the officer's in
the talk at Joyce. I felt the same way.
This couldn't be happening.
We were on the same side.
We weren't marines or soldiers,
we weren't Americans or ask ours.
We were one lone group fighting
desperately to stay alive.
The villages villagers
weren't our friends.
This was a war and my team
was on the verge of dying.
Who side was the talk on
radio call after radio call?
Swinson kept requesting smoke.
Finally around zero six 30 the talk at
joy's permitted for white phosphorus,
white phosphorus rounds to be fired into
the southeast backside of the village
too far away to conceal my team.
Yeah.
Those were the last rounds
fired during the battle
that about zero six 40 the talk at Joyce
for obeyed any more artillery support,
citing garbled communications in complete
calls for fire procedures and a lack
of situational awareness on the
part of those trapped in the valley.
Yeah.
So there's the, there's the
reasons from their perspective.
MMM.
Okay.
Garbled communications in complete
calls for fire procedures and a lack of
situational awareness on the part
of those trapped in the valley.
Okay.
Meanwhile, during this time you've been
moving up, grabbing bodies, coming back.
Yep.
And here we go again as we move forward
for a third time to talk and find the
ordered the army platoon dog
three to to move forward.
They pulled in behind us with the platoon
leader in a Humvee with an anti tank
tow missile on the roof.
The toe made no sense to me,
but the truck was equipped with a to
40 machine gun behind them were 20 us
soldiers and for heavily, heavily
armored vehicles. You Rolling with me,
lieutenant?
I was confirming what I took for granted.
I'll scout the route first
before I bring my platoon in.
The terrain may be too tough.
He refused to put his soldiers into the
Afghan vehicles. I could understand that.
Okay. I go first. I said, you cover our
six, the Afghans, we'll be behind you
as we bounced forward. I heard teen
Monte again come up on the radio.
We were under fire.
Lieutenant Johnson said we're surrounded.
So now you're heading back in.
Yeah.
Yeah. And I, um,
and my whole goal was just to get them,
you know, was to get them to the road
and uh, yeah, I mean that was their goal.
Can you get to the road?
They can get into the vehicles are good.
It's always trying to push. I thought
that they had took over a house. Right?
Like I thought they had pushed into
the village and took over a house and
pointed a house and that's what I
thought they had done. And I lost,
I lost communications with them.
So I thought they'd done, you know,
when a Kenefick was
trying to give that grid,
I was trying to write it down cause
I knew if I could get that grid,
I'd know where they were at a plot and
I could be there and go get him. And um,
you know,
the,
the one part I don't talk about it and
there is probably the hardest parts of
the whole deal is,
is that the first trip that I made in,
okay.
I was probably 70,
60 to 70 meters from him.
They're still alive.
So you're out in the valley now
you're with a group of guys are going
back to the bulkier up bullet had entered
a Westbrook's neck near the shoulder
blade and ricocheted downward.
A Dang a dangerous but not fatal.
Wound Swenson applied quick clot powder
and a bandage to seal off the bleeding.
The fight had been raging for over
90 minutes and the chain of command
throughout Kunar province was on alert
procedures for releasing helicopters had
been on snarled and two oh h 58 Kai was,
we're in route to the valley at zero
seven 15 ne contacted Swenson Highlander.
This is Pale horse. The PC pilot
command radioed, what do you need?
Pale horse.
Swanson replied,
I'm under heavy fire from the village
and the hills to the east and on both
sides.
Request immediate suppression of while
we pulled back the Kai Kai was squadron,
had been in Coonara for 10 months.
The pilot's knew the terrain
and the enemy habits.
They intended to swoop
in low and crisscrossing.
Strafing room runs deliberately
swerving and cutting back at odd.
They didn't care whether
they hit the Douche man,
they wanted to force them to
crouch down and cease firing.
The aerial tactics would allow the command
group to pull back westward to draw
down under under reduced enemy pressure.
As Swenson moved, he called for a
medivac shadow. Radioed back to that.
The talk wanted questions
answered before calling for one.
Is he army or marine shadow said
Swinson cursed major Williams was more
diplomatic. This is Fox w six Williams
radioed it doesn't matter his service,
he's us.
There was a pause then shadow.
Reluctantly radioed repeat talk
needs to know if he's army or marine.
It's in the regulations.
Yeah,
it was um,
guy calling for medivac and
you're getting asked, hey,
is the person that needs,
is the casualty army or Marine Corps?
Yeah.
And it really didn't matter to him.
It really did matter to them.
You're saying it mattered.
I'm saying it to who was asking.
They really,
their decisions were
based off of who it was.
All right.
Um,
at this point you're,
you're,
I think you're, you're going back
and forth, going back to the valley,
getting bodies, helping
wounded. Coming back out.
You're under fire the whole time
rod is getting after it with you.
Sometimes you have some us people with
you, sometimes you don't. And again,
these are things you have to buy this
book and it to get these details out of it
and read it so you understand the full
magnitude of what we're talking about
here.
Yeah.
Going back to the book,
Hafez left the command group to sort
itself out helping a wounded NASCAR was
headed back west to the operational
release point when I had stopped him.
I need you to come back in with me.
I can't find them without you.
I said Hafez was married recently.
He was wounded and exhausted.
He could now go home and have a life.
Yeah.
If today is my time to die,
then I die.
So He's rolling with you?
He did.
He wrote with me the whole time
again to all those people out there that,
well I guess I should just say for the
people out there that have a hard time
understanding of what's going
on overseas, um, you know,
here's an Afghan soldier that is now
going to risk his life to help an American
marine go and find his friends.
Yeah.
Cause we were brothers.
Going back to the book shortly after
we had it again down the valley,
we bumped into another group
of rent wounded, ask scars.
Rod recognize the first sergeant who was
dripping blood down the right side of
his trousers. He was waving his arms,
be begging us to stop for askers,
hobbled over and threw
themselves into the backseat,
splashing blood all over the place. We
drove them back to the collection point.
The first sergeant was blubbering beg,
begging us not to go back in.
I was a little rough shoving
him out of the truck.
I was running out of time and patients,
once we drop them off,
we'd gunned it back down the track.
Okay.
We were getting to a place
where we couldn't turn
around and couldn't dodge and
weave the art as the RPG
smoke trails came at us.
We could get pretty stuck in here.
Rod yelled the truck,
had very little traction and absolutely
no cover then I guess we'll die with
them. I yelled back, what else could
I say that we weren't going back.
Rod shifted into low gear
and we bounced forward.
You,
I noticed this throughout the book,
you have a hard time.
Like anytime you saw wounded
guys who were like, all right,
well we gotta make another trip
now we've got to make another trip.
Even with those wounded Afghan guys,
like you want to go help your guys.
But at the same time you see these guys
here like are getting the truck and
we'll take these guys back. Oh, you've
got a big heart, bro. Got a big heart.
I mean look, you know,
I didn't just lose, um,
I didn't just lose a four guys that day.
I lost 10 guys cause I lost six Afghans.
I lost 10 brothers.
You know what I mean? I mean, those
guys were just as close to me.
My Afghans were just as close to me
as any marines I ever served with,
and that's why they're joining
you to go back in there and fight
the ethics and that's why I'm alive today.
I mean that's,
that's the relationship that I had with
them and the Brotherhood that I had for
them with them is why I'm alive today.
I mean they,
they are incredible human beings.
So you're driving around in here.
Back to the book.
Only rod scale at the wheel was preventing
me from being hit again and again.
Bullets make different
sounds when they pass by you.
The cracks of bullets breaking the
sound barrier mean they're high,
maybe five or 10 feet over your head.
The bullets at snap close by
your ears are the real killers.
A few losing power and slowing
down made a low buzzing sound.
Strange though it may seem I wasn't
scared or angry. I was beyond that.
I didn't think I was going to die.
I knew I was dead.
There wasn't anything I could do about it.
I wasn't a thinking human being.
I had gone,
I wasn't firing the machine gun,
I was the machine gun.
Rod wasn't driving the truck.
Rod was the truck.
I had melded with my weapon.
I was no more human than a five
foot machine gun. I was embracing,
we were locked together, metal
and flesh. Without that 50 gal,
I would have quivered like the ha ha,
scars helpless in the storm.
But with that weapon,
I felt transported.
I had something to do
until the blackness came.
Yeah. He just kept, I kept like the
bullets were hitting inside the tourists.
They had elevation on us and still
they were hidden inside the turret.
And um,
man,
you could hear him coming by and I just,
I remember sitting there,
you know, cause if you get down, I
mean, you know, you, you know, your,
your instinct is to duck down the turret,
but you do that delve around you.
I mean, they were running
at the truck, so yup.
You ducked down there full sprint and
you're never going to come back up.
You know what I mean? And, um, I
just kept waiting for a bullet.
I just knew it was who's
going to hit me in the face.
I just kept waiting for a bullet to
hit me lights out like I just, I just,
there was no doubt in my mind that
I was going to die zero c road out,
but I was going to make this
son of a bitches, aren't it?
Yeah.
They had it to do
Jack.
I wasn't paying attention
to the Afghan soldiers.
Rod and I plan to keep driving
east until we obliterated,
until we were obliterated or we found
my team suddenly with no warning,
five or six ass cars who were lying in
a terrorist about off a hundred meters
away,
leapt up and race towards our truck
when wish one was shot back and pitched
forward. Wham. A second man went
down screaming, Wham, a third,
then a fourth and a fifth.
I'd never seen anything like it.
Five men down in five seconds.
There was so much screeching
and shooting that I could,
couldn't pick out the location of a
weapon that had shot them to deliver such
lethal grazing fire.
The machine gunner must been hidden only
a few hundred meters away with a clear
line of sight and his
bi-pod firmly anchored.
Yet whoever shot those men didn't
raise his gun sights and stitch me.
I knew he was looking at
me, but I couldn't see him.
There was nothing I could do.
He let me live, not one of his rounds
even struck our truck. I can't explain it.
W W we used to call the truck's
bullet magnets. They are,
I mean it's like the ripest target
and a free gear. The Turret gunner.
You're like the, the, the icing
on the cake. You're the chocolate.
The Cherry on the icing on the cake.
Yeah. Cause that truck gets over.
If they take the gun out, that truck
doesn't come out of their own silver ran.
Oh hell yeah. Yeah. But you
know, even though it's a bullet
magnet, I mean, you know,
just like right there,
I think that kind of paints the picture.
I mean it's the, it's the only chance you
have, right? I mean you're, you're out.
I mean, that's how doubting
they are. It's, it's
literally watching guys see people
throw the term miracle around. Yeah,
all the time. Like the fact that you
right here, there's five guys within,
you know,
spitting distance from you and they all
go down and you're the most prime target
and you and you don't get job in
helpless.
The most helpless feeling
you got is watching guys
trying to get to you and just
getting mowed down.
I mean,
you want to talk about helpless and you
don't even know where it's coming from.
I mean,
you want to talk about
helpless is watching another
human being run directly at
you
to get help and you're
just watching them just
go down one after the
other after the other.
Can you imagine it dude? Yeah.
It's just the, you know, I'd say
they were good that day.
You get this call from Valdez,
they're coming at you. I can see them
closing from both sides. They're swarming,
you know,
in front of our truck,
I saw few guys sprinting across the
washed from left to right, heads low.
I don't think they saw us coming up
behind them or if they heard the truck
engine over the din of the gunfire.
They scurry too quickly for me to get
off a burst. Glancing to my right,
I'd looked smack into the eyes of
five or six men in dirty man dresses,
crouched alongside a drainage ditch,
not 10 meters away. When I gave them,
they ducked down like they
were playing hide and seek.
It took me a few seconds to realize that
they were spreading out to seal off the
open end of the Horseshoe Valley Zip
locking the frozen as scars inside a fire
sac.
Rod and I had blundered into their rear,
so they were about to,
they're about to surround everybody.
That's what they were doing. There
was a trench and they were closing it.
They're closing the
gate and we that truck,
you happened to be there to be in it.
Fire Sac is a,
is a doctrinal term actually,
which means you're surrounded and they're
going to shoot into the sack and kill
everyone.
Yeah.
We are bouncing over the rocks
no faster than a man can run.
When a bearded Douche man clutching an
AK leapt out of a ditch and sprinted
after us like a man trying
to catch is a catch a bus.
My gun almost wouldn't swivel
low enough to shoot him.
The barrel was tilted down
as far as it could go.
I fired into his chest and he went
down like you'd hit a glass wall.
The bullet doesn't blow a
man back like in the movies.
Either he stumbles or on or he falls
dead. This man fall, fell dead.
Rod was yelling at me. Maybe I was
hypnotized for a second. By the death,
there was a guy trying
to open the right door.
I couldn't depress the 50 cal bat
low. I can't get him. I yelled,
the gun won't go down low enough.
It takes the brain 12 thousands
of a second to react to danger.
My mind was a complete blank.
I had fired so many thousands of rounds
that I didn't think what I was doing.
Once you've practiced emotion long enough,
it becomes second nature.
Some reachers researchers call
it expertise induced amnesia.
Athletes Call it being in the zone.
I call it self preservation.
I grabbed my m four leaned out and
shot the guy four or five times in the
shoulder and neck.
It was like shooting a Zombie.
There was no shock power and the little
five five six millimeter bullets.
He felt the ground. I pivoted back
to the 50 Callen, grabbed the spade,
handle the weapon,
my hands and my eyes were working as a
trained unit independent on my brain, man.
Sight, picture, shoot,
man. Sight picture shoot.
You don't really look at the target.
The enemy remains out of focus.
You concentrate on the sight
picture, man. Sight picture shoot.
I hit one or two guys next to the truck
and the other's duck back into the ditch.
Valdez came back on the Radio Rod,
watch your front.
Rod was focused on keeping traction in
the loose gravel. If the truck got stuck,
even for a moment,
we'd be toast.
He looked ahead to see a bearded hatless
man in his mid thirties dressed in a
brick red man,
jams with a green chest rig full of ammo
running toward the truck and firing an
eight k at us from the hip.
Hold on, homie. Rod Yelled,
he hit the accelerator, the truck
at the man squarely in the chest.
There was a bump and then
another bump under the tires.
Holy Shit, Rod rod yelled.
I just ran over a guy
back up and do it again.
I had been shot in the elbow,
a bleeder that did no real damage.
The bone was fine in a fight. Adrenaline
deadens the pain. I did a little rapping.
It got back to shooting.
The more fucked up things got the
more rod and I started laughing.
He was steering away from RPG streaming
at us and laughing and I was shooting
the big gun and laughing.
Definitely crazy,
but your emotions have to go somewhere.
Okay.
The enemy fire slack and on us.
As the Chi was darted around,
they were like a steel umbrella over us.
A few minutes later,
Pale horse came back on my net.
Three three were Winchester.
We'll be back in 15 Mike's
Winchester meant they'd
expended all their ammunition.
They were too light to carry much and
they'd been shooting at targets wherever
they looked. The firing picked
up. We were again, the pin, Yada.
I climbed down from the Turret
and talk to talk to Rod and Hafez.
We had started with six ammo cans.
We are now down to one.
I had fired more than 2000
rounds. Guys, we need a new gun.
I said it was three steps forward,
two steps back. As we turned,
I saw and ask our free crawling
feebly toward the road.
We stopped and I hopped out a PKM machine.
Gun was tilling the ground around me,
so I dodged back and
forth until I reached him.
One Kiowa out of ammo hovered
above me and distracted the enemy.
Ignoring the RPG shells
exploding in the air.
I turned the asker onto his back,
hit by three rounds in
his upper chest and neck.
He was gurgling and drowning in his
own blood. I rolled him onto his side
and he died before I could pick them up.
Okay.
Yeah.
Like
you can see I kind of circle things
that I'm going to read. Yeah.
And I just was like circling
giant chunks. Yeah, too.
So people can understand what I mean.
I,
I know that people aren't
going to understand really the,
the kind of chronological evolution
and maybe the mechanics of what was
happening,
but I want people at least understand
until they read this book themselves to
freaking situation that you were in,
which was beyond mayhem.
Yeah. You know, you talk about training
and life to the worst case scenario.
I always had done the same thing.
And this was worst than any worst
case scenario that I could have ever,
ever dreamed up of.
I've ever been in.
There was the worst of any situation
I could have never sit here.
And you said, gimme the worst
thing you could just come up with.
And I could have never done it. I could've
never, I could have never done it,
uh, of just, I mean, you
just, I mean it's just like,
I mean, I just felt like
everybody was dying. Like,
I mean it was just,
I mean,
there were like literally there
were bodies everywhere, Eh, Eh,
I mean you couldn't turn around and
look and are not be a body somewhere.
Okay.
And you just pretty much figured you were
going to be joining them soon enough.
No, I did. I mean, there was no
doubt. There was no doubt in my mind.
I wasn't making it out of there.
And you know,
I walked in that day and this
just shows you how ignorant I was.
Like when you talk about, oh, your buddy
who was kind of like, puff the chest up,
right. I had that with me. I literally,
I'm a, I'm going to tell you,
I'm going to just tell you how ignorant
I was. I walked in that day and I, I, I,
there was not a situation that I was
ever going to see that I couldn't get us
out of. There wasn't
one, there wasn't one.
And it was like,
you know,
it was like God showing
me just how small it was.
No, you got to take, I mean,
these, these Afghan soldiers,
I mean they're my buddies,
you know, and part of the problem,
what was the long and the deployment,
was this supposed to been nine months
and how long this, when did this happen?
We got there in July.
August. September. Yeah.
So this is like two months or three
months into deployment. Yeah. And I'm,
part of the problem was we'd just done the
NATO transition and they were using
weapons systems that they weren't used to
that shoot a smaller
round. Yeah. Yeah. A lot.
But they weren't used to these weapons.
They weren't even used him for us. I mean,
I knew him for us are so much more fickle.
M 16th and six [inaudible] six things
are even more so than an m four m six
things are so much more fickle than an
hey k they must've been cursing them.
Damn. May 16th they were,
I mean, they were, oh yeah.
I mean they,
you know,
that they would have something go wrong
and they would just drop the magazine.
I mean,
I mean they were just,
yeah,
so there is,
so like I'm telling you if you say
everything like we had just so we just hit
Ramadan, so none of them
were drinking water. None of
them were eaten. We had just,
I mean,
you look at every factor to this.
It was the perfect storm and
we had just transitioned.
This is the first mission at first or
second mission that we had ever went on
with all NATO weapons. I mean, you
look at all these factors and it was,
it was perfect.
Had you ever worked with the QRF before?
Not that one. I was used to the ones,
you know, up near where we were at.
Do you hadn't had done no interoperability
with those guys before? No. And uh,
they got shut down. So after the
talk, learn that it was marines,
they got shut down,
all support stopped.
All sports stopped.
Cool.
Okay.
All right.
Um,
Tom Toms, I got nothing to
say and that's one of them.
I can't even comprehend that.
Yeah.
All right.
We're going back to the book.
We turned left out of the
wash onto the narrow track.
Back to the casualty collection point.
I looked around for major Williams.
He was sitting off to one side,
wounded in in shock.
There were four or five vehicles and
at least 20 ass cars milling around.
These were our Afghans.
We'd come down from Monte together.
I glanced hopefully from the group,
from group to group.
Hafez was asking if they'd
seen Lieutenant Johnson.
They say lieutenant is back in Ganja Golf.
How fast said the team didn't make it out.
Shit.
Somewhere farther up the wash.
My team was fighting to stay alive.
I'd promise to get them and rod and I
had the only gun truck willing to enable
to go in.
I climbed down from the Turret
and ran over to the asker.
He'd taken a bullet in the fight
and he was slowly bleeding out.
I kept a stack of tourniquets in
my med and knew how to apply them.
I wrapped a tourniquet around
his thigh and my frustration.
I twisted it extra tight and he screamed.
How tell him to up.
I said hurting is better than dying.
If you're a grunt,
you'll come face to face
with horrendous Gore.
You have to steel yourself to seeing
mangled bodies and smelling blood.
Doctors and nurses cope with
screaming and suffering every day.
I had dressed out dozens of deer.
You learn to disassociate from the task
when you're pulling out warm guts are
cutting off slabs of dripping, meet
with the blood, sticking to your hands.
He went through something
like 15 tourniquets.
Yeah.
At least quite a few vowels and morphine.
MMM.
A couple of neat needle decompressions.
NPA is quite a few NPH nasal.
Okay.
The quiet.
The Chi was at rearmed and come back
on station directing us toward another
wounded. Like it or not, we had been
pressed into ambulance business.
The Kiowa commanded by chief
warrant officer. Yes. Syrian Salono,
a good name for guide.
A crazy war had been a marine grunt
before becoming an army pilot.
His bird was easy to talk to and he
directed me where to go sometimes hovering
so low I could just about
reach up and touch his skids.
He was covering my rear area.
When I got out of the truck,
the pilots were fearless
knowing my team was lost.
They were running search patterns 20 feet
off the ground so they could identify
each body.
Damn. Yeah. I mean, and he did that like,
you know, they were so his commander,
he was having problems with his commander
and the guy who was leading those
birds, you know, cause they fly
in two birds and a fill the,
but when I told him that
it was marines missing,
he dropped down and covered me the
whole time. You ever meet him? Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. He's incredible.
I just seen him, um,
I seen him like around thanksgiving.
Yeah. He is an incredible human being.
Just so everyone knows like just cause
you're in a helicopter does not make you
safe at all.
Especially a Kiowa.
Like maybe you're a little bit safer
and Apache cause you got some armor.
I don't know how much, how much
orders in a Kiowa. Zero. Right.
They look like little
and I don't know how many he is. Bird
was shot to shit. No kidding. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. It was shot to pieces.
Okay.
I climbed up a terrorist wall
and followed the contours,
the field around a corner to find a body
lying face down on the man's hands were
green gloves with the fingers cut.
I knew before I even rolled
him over that it was Daud Ali,
my closest Afghan friend.
He was due to take leave in a few weeks.
He had left on bad terms with his
mother who was sure he would be killed.
Finally,
after two years,
she had relented and invited him
back to the farm for a visit.
He'd been hit in the face.
When looked at his dole lies.
I lost my concentration and knelt
there for a moment, oblivious.
He was a little guy too
small for his body armor.
He and I had rigged up two tourniquets
to hold the body armor in place close to
his chest.
I knelt down to untie the tourniquets.
I needed them for other guys and I needed
to get the heavy armor off him so I
could carry him to the truck.
I felt a tap as something hit my left
shoulder. It didn't register at first.
It was like I'd been
hit with a Lightstone.
I glanced up to see a tough looking
Afghan with a long black beard.
Glatt glaring down at me. He was wearing
a dirty gray man dress, a flak jacket,
and an Afghan Hornby helmet.
He was pointing an AK at my head,
gesturing for me to stand
up in broken English.
He was telling me to drop
my rifle, come. He said,
waving the barrel of
his eight K in my face.
I couldn't believe that
I'd screwed up so badly.
All I could think of was that my head
would be sawed off and held up on TV.
No Way.
I die right where I was right now. I
had been dead for a few hours. Anyways,
the borrowed time was up.
That's all my rifle was resting on my
left thigh, pointing in his direction.
The stubby grenade launcher was
attached to the underside of the barrel.
I raised one arm like I was going to
surrender and pulled the trigger of the
launcher with my free thumb.
The 40 millimeter grenades shot
forward two feet to his armored vest.
It didn't explode. Instead it knocked
him back, stunned him with the,
with the breath slammed out of him.
He staggered back and fell on
his side for a few seconds.
I thought the blow had killed him.
No such luck.
I pushed myself erect as I pushed myself
a he June, a big breath and stirred.
I kicked out his face, losing my
balance and falling on top of him.
We were both on the ground wrestling.
Afghan tribesman have legs like steal
from climbing mountains all day all their
lives. So I had to keep his legs off
me. I pinned his elbows and blocked.
His reach for is eight K.
I was pushing my helmeted head into his
chest so he couldn't gouge my eyes any
second.
I figured that grenade would explode
and both of us could stop worrying about
any of this.
I called the ground with my right hand
and found a rock the size of a baseball.
I clutched it and swung
by blindly at his face.
The blow stunned him before he could
recover. I Pour, pushed off of his chest,
lifted the rock high and my right fist
and smashed it down like a hammer,
breaking his front teeth. He looked me in
the eyes, the fight knocked out of him,
his head not moving.
We both knew it was over.
I drew back my arm and drove the stone
down, crushing his left cheekbone.
He went limp. I pushed up on my
knees and I hit him with more force.
The blow caved in the left side of his
forehead. I smashed his face again.
And again,
driven by pure animal rage.
That's close combat obviously when
you're killing another human being with a
rock.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's real. Um,
you know, I just, I just remember
his face, you know, and uh,
I mean, look, God, let me just
state this up front. First off,
I feel no remorse at all.
Um,
but I think it was at, it was at that,
at that point to where it humanized it.
Does that make sense? Like, it humanized
the fact of taking another person's life,
like out.
Remember the look in his eyes
when he knew he was gonna die.
And at that point, like, you know, I
obviously I didn't think of it then,
but you know, when I still see that
face, I still think about, you know,
he was a father.
There was somebody at home that wanted
him to come home just as bad as somebody
wanted me to come home. Um,
you know, whether you agree
with his beliefs are not,
people don't agree with their beliefs
and you know, but at the end of the day,
he believed in his beliefs just as much
as I did. Um, we're both human beings.
We're both fighting for a
cause that neither one of
us can see that we both just
believe in. Um, and it had to be one of us
in my guesses, and you
can, maybe I'm wrong,
but my guess is the reason he didn't just
straight kill you is because you had,
you had the drop on you. Yeah. And, and,
and having you as a trophy in an orange
jumpsuit would've have been much more
impactful for him and their costs.
Yeah. I mean, he could have easily,
um, it would have took him no
time to get me across the border.
We were right on the border.
That's what he would've done.
He would've took me across the
board. He just told me, um,
and he would have been a hero.
He'd probably been promoted
and whatever, you know,
network he was in. I mean, he
would have been the man and, um,
I was worth a lot more to him alive
than I was dead. And I, you know, but,
but then on the backside, I
mean, I've questioned it so
many times, like, you know,
it was it that or was it the maybe
maybe he was trying to bluff me,
didn't have bullets to me. I don't know.
I don't, I don't know. Like, and you know,
there's so many times in this whole
battle that I just wonder like,
like, why, why, why not me,
you know, uh, I mean, war and I gets,
you could apply this to all life,
but it becomes very clear at war, it's
like inches, millimeters. You know what,
what? Sure. You could
say he got missed by,
by around by a foot a couple of inches.
But when you take that
back to a person's weapon,
you got missed by a millimeter a of aim.
That's what it is.
You could have got,
you could have got missed by a
gust of wind and [inaudible].
Literally you could have, you could
have been missed by the wind picking up.
So while all that's going on.
Okay,
back to the book. Highlander was the
radio call sign for Captain Swenson.
He was trying to gather reinforcements.
He pulled aside the lieutenant in
charge of the Quick Reaction Platoon,
mount up Swenson's and told him,
you're no help back here.
We need your fire power.
I can't.
Lieutenant said the tox says
we're to cover the vehicles.
Swenson grabbed the lieutenant's
50 watt radio and called the Joyce.
The talk told the platoon to
move into the valley, Swenson,
Fabio,
rod and how Fez then hopped into an
undamaged Tom the to drive back in,
but the platoon did not follow.
Instead,
the platoon leader again called back to
Joyce and somehow received permission to
remain in the rear.
Out of the fight.
Yeah. It was frustrating. It was
frustrating. It was frustrating that,
you know, and I, I, I met
that guy a few years ago.
We ran into,
we were in the same meeting.
MMM.
It was frustrating. Every bit of it
was frustrating. It was so, I mean,
every single bit of it was unnecessary,
unnecessary and frustrating.
Back to the book, I started the day with
14 or 16 tourniquets. I use them all.
I put four on one guy who'd lost his
left arm and his left leg below the knee.
He survived.
One ask are shot in the neck.
Sounded like he was
slurping through a straw.
There was nothing I could do except
listen to him. Strangled to death.
Yeah. At 1.2 FTE f fifteens
roared low through the valley,
opening their afterburners to
create a hell of a lion's roar.
The pilot's wouldn't drop any bombs.
Yeah. I mean, and you know, usually,
but at this point, you know,
the only show of force
ever works is, is, I mean,
they had so much momentum at this time.
I mean, it was like momentum. Right.
So it started out as fighters, like his
fighters that came across the border.
And then what it turned into was when
they seen that we weren't getting the
support and when they seen that we weren't
getting control of the situation and
fires weren't coming,
they escalated and they gained momentum.
What everybody else joined in,
you take the,
so you had the guys that showed up to
fight and then you have the opportunist of
the villagers that turn into fighters
instantly because they have the upper hand
and so they start gaining momentum of
more people fighting you every minute.
Cause I was,
I got to do is pick up the gun off
the dead person. You know what I mean?
Literally. I mean there were
literally women run in through uh,
the village with the like these
bowls and you know, you look at them,
you know, well, you know,
she's just a woman with a
ball running rocket comes in,
she drops the ball and it's
full of grenades and ammunition.
The women were running up and re
re supplying all of these guys.
The Kai is Kai was, we're still
supporting you back to the book.
Inside the villages,
the army pilots ran astonishing risks
to find my team or co a Kiowa would
swooped down toward the compound flare
back at rooftop level and potter down the
alleyways at 20 miles an hour,
allowing the pilots to peer into
every backyard in, into every window.
Yeah.
As the day grew hotter, we gradually
cleared the valley of casualties.
Over 30 wounded or dead were evacuated.
We watched a Salono.
The lead pilot brought us Chi went down
to a few feet above a trench and Hubbard
there. Highlander. We spotted five bodies.
I'd heard all I needed.
I jumped out the door and sprinting
across the field to the right,
opening some distance
before Swenson yelled at me.
I ignored him knowing he'd be
right behind me. A PKM shifted me,
shifted to me when I was
halfway across the terrorist.
I hopped over a terrace wall and fell
into a deep well constructed trench.
I landed next to Dani
Johnson and my heart stopped.
He was lying on his back with his
arms out, spread his eyes open.
Okay,
but never to see anything
again on this earth.
A few feet further on,
I came across the body of
an Afghan interpreter who
had traveled with our team.
I felt sick to my stomach.
I knew what I would see next.
Lieutenant Johnson lay on his
back with his eyes closed.
Okay.
He looked peaceful despite the
entry wounds in his right shoulder.
Doc Layton and lay on top of him with
medical supplies scattered around.
I rolled him over.
Doc had taken a three round
burst in the right cheek
off to the right staff sergeant
can AFIC was lying face down.
His gps with a busted screen
clenched in his left hand.
His mouth was open and full of dirt.
Okay.
I think he was yelling
out his grid location.
The numbers I heard over the radio four
hours earlier when he was shot in the
back of his head,
the team was wiped out.
Their bodies were stiff and cold.
Most of their gear was gone.
Weapons, helmets, radios.
The two 40 machine gun was missing,
but Lieutenant Johnson's pack
was filled with link Ammo.
No one had fired the gun.
I was supposed to be caring.
I had never believed
it would end like this.
My mind refuse to accept what
I was seeing. Hour after hour,
I'd imagined them holed up inside a
stone house, shielded from RPG blast,
exchanging gunfire with
the Douche men who were,
who knew better than to rush them.
Swenson was standing above the trench.
We were taking random incoming and he was
watching for movement among the houses.
He talked into his radio for a few seconds
and bent down and picked up some of
the teams. Gear. He didn't say a word.
He left me alone with them,
okay?
I always did the staff sergeant
over my roles, right shoulder.
He was heavy and I fell.
Once he landed on top of me,
I got up and carried
him to an Afghan truck,
carefully talking him into the open bed.
Okay?
I stood there for a minute, suddenly
beat as I turned away from the truck,
half has put his hand on my shoulder.
The Asghar say,
you carried out, they're dead.
Now they want to help you.
Five or six of us returned to the trench
while the damn PKM kept shooting at us.
I carried Dani Johnson back the ass cars,
took Lieutenant Johnson and Doc Leighton
Swenson loved back the rest of the
equipment.
Okay.
After six hours it was over and I
felt empty as a balloon without air.
Hafez took me aside. They've
gone to a better place. He said,
don't cry the ass cars.
We'll take it as weakness.
No Way.
I was going to cry,
but at that moment I didn't feel
like killing new anyone either.
I wasn't angry or bitter,
just deflated and exhausted as the wide
run a marathon and couldn't remember why
I wanted to do it.
I was too damn tired to
stand still taking fire.
We left the valley in a
convoy of about four trucks.
Rod stopped near the casualty collection
point where we talked with Captain
Kaplan and Captain Ed,
Corporal Norman,
who had walked down from
their observation posts,
Staff Sergeant Valdez and Miller radio
that they were coming down from their
perch to everyone was accounted for.
We had shuttled in and out of the valley
five, six or seven times that morning,
depending on which one of us you asked.
It was all a fog.
No senior American or pursuit
force had come forward from camp.
Joyce.
Captain Swenson said he would try to
wrap things up half as an I climbed into
the back of an Afghan truck
carrying my dead brother's
I held staff sergeant can affect with my
left hand and Lieutenant Johnson rested
on my right arm.
As we bounced down the track,
we passed.
Villagers returning to God your golf.
Some started to laugh,
pointing out my dead friends.
I reached for my rifle.
Don't half ass said holding my arm,
not worth it.
When we arrived back at Camp Joyce,
I walked into the battalion
aid station to get bodybags.
Major Williams rushed up and clutched it.
My body armor tell me they're
not all dead. Not all of them.
Okay,
they're all dead.
I said removing his hand.
I walked outside where my friend
Sergeant Charles Bogus was waiting.
Boca said,
I'll give you a hand.
We walked back to the bodies.
Okay,
sergeant major Jimmy Carr.
Bellow the top enlisted men at Joyce
hastened up and put his hands firmly on my
shoulders trying to steer me away.
You don't have to do this devil dog.
My guys will make sure it's done right.
That wasn't how to end it.
If I had died,
I'd want Lieutenant Johnson and staff
sergeant can affect to put me in the bag.
I'll finish it.
I said
bogus and I carried the bodies
back next to the freezers.
Take off their battle gear and dig
through their pockets marking items for
shipment to their families.
I take a Chevron from Staff Sergeant
Kenefick and attach it to my dog tags.
Yeah,
40 we had started out not liking
each other a thousand years ago.
We cleaned them up as best we can,
wiping the blood and dirt off their faces,
taking off their field gear,
straightening out their camouflage
uniforms and placing each in a black body
bag.
We mark the name,
got the head draping
American flag over each bag,
bow our heads in prayer
and drive them out to the Hilo.
Pat Gone to gall was one of the
deadliest small arms battles.
Nope.
The Afghanistan
war.
Okay.
We lost five advisors in
addition to team Monte,
army sergeant first class Westbrook,
a died of his wounds.
Eight ask.
Ours were killed in 13.
Seriously wounded by rifle
machine gun and RPG fire.
Okay.
The enemy losses to small arms.
We're probably have a similar number.
There were no ids,
no bombs,
and very few artillery shells.
Bullets caused most of the casualties.
Ganja gall was a mountain
fight from an earlier century.
And
it's a fight from an earlier century.
But uh,
yeah,
but some things don't change.
That's a fact.
Yeah, it was a, Gosh,
you know, I say it and I don't think
people understand it, but do you know,
I might not physically died that day,
but I died
right there next to him.
I mean, you talk about,
you know,
I mean,
it's one thing to lose one person,
but everybody,
I mean, it's uh, Eh,
I mean,
I mean that's the worst case scenario.
You're living it. Do you know
what I mean? You're literally,
you don't even have anybody from your
own team to put your dad on the bird.
Do you know?
And you know,
how old were you at this point?
2121 years old.
2121.
You know, and I, I don't know if it
talks about it in the book, you know,
after I did that with my teammates,
I went straight from
there and I went to um,
so are the Afghan side and I
did it with all their guys too.
And usually what they do with their guys
is they just call the families and they
got so many days to come get
him and I wasn't allowing that.
I went back and I took body bags up
there and we gave them the exact same
respect that we gave my guys and we put
them in the freezers until our families
came and got him.
And you know,
I didn't go,
I didn't go start worrying about my
stuff until we had taken care of all the,
all the guys, you know, and it's just,
it was his long day.
A long day.
Okay.
And
I mean,
you do, you, you're just like, okay.
Yeah.
You still have a job to do. Yeah. So,
I don't know if it talks about
it in there, but that, you know,
they tried to put me on the helicopter
with him to go back to a bog room and
then wanted me to fly home to do the
ramp ceremonies and he wanted me to fly
home with them
and
I actually put them on there and
I told him I would be right back.
And I knew those birds had to take AUC.
Same words,
the PJ's weren't going to sit on
the flight line very long and I,
I just made sure that I knew that they
had took off before I got around anybody
else because I mean,
they were dead. I mean,
I still had guys who still needed me
and they didn't need me
anymore. And so I, you know,
you know, I knew my Afghan soldiers
needed me. They needed to see that,
that they weren't alone. They needed to
see that, that we're in this together,
you know? And that was what, that was
what mattered to me. But what the guys,
I still had left.
How did the Afghan,
your Afghan soldiers respond
to this whole situation?
You know,
sometimes in Iraq there'd be a mass
casualty like this and we'd lose a whole,
there was actually in Ramadi, we lost a
whole battalion. They all, they all left.
Yeah, they quit. Yeah. What were your
guys did? How did it affect them?
Okay.
I mean, they stuck it out.
You know, they stuck it out.
MMM.
They did. I mean, I'm
telling you that your,
they are some of the most incredible
human beings I've ever seen. You know,
we come in and deploy,
we're there for a certain amount of time.
They live at forever. And, uh,
they responded. I mean, they,
you know, they, they got their
shit together. Um, and yeah,
I mean, we were back in the
fight three days later, you know,
and they don't get, they
don't get to risk, but they
don't get the support we do.
You know, they don't get, I mean,
they don't get anything we get,
you know what I mean? [inaudible]
and it's just, you know, but we,
but we stuck together, you
know, they helped me, they
helped me get through it. Um,
and I hope I helped them,
but I think the most incredible
thing was it was that point that,
that they brought me into there.
I was accepted as one of them.
You were one of them.
Yeah.
And that was probably the most rewarding
piece of it to me. You know, was it, I,
I had finally proven myself to
them that, that I was, one of them
in deployment wasn't over yet.
And you know,
there was more fighting to be done.
Going back to the book army,
an army convoy had been
ambushed north of Monte,
lieutenant colonel and Captain Brian,
the company commander were
on their way to assist.
I look to colonel you who nodded
in agreement minutes later.
You Bakis Staff Sergeant Richards and
some of the colonel's guys that came with
him, uh, doesn't ask ours and
I, we're headed out the gate.
Or basically what you run into
is there's a, uh, a huge kind of,
what did somebody hit an IED?
Is that what had happened?
It was all day ambush aside this and they,
what they done,
they blew the Jingo trucks up and
block the road. So that, you know,
they intertwine those Jingo trucks
and between the u s convoy and it's so
stupid. And so the jingle truck is
blown up and it's blocking the road.
So guess what happens?
The rest of them,
they're all sitting and you can't go
around it because it's about a 250 foot
drop off into the Kunar river on the side.
So they're stuck on the side of this.
And I've been listening to it
on the radio for a long time
and I knew they were
going to get slaughtered.
I knew that you weren't just going to
sit there and they had buttoned up.
So that's what you were talking about
earlier. You buttoned up and you wait,
well now they're going to maneuver on.
Yep.
And that's what they were doing fire
though. And that's what they were doing.
So the guys in the Jingo trucks
had jumped out. And, uh, I kept,
I kept asking over the radio,
you know,
cause I could monitor and I kept asking
over the right and I could see the smoke
from where,
how his head and I kept asking over the
radio show is a clip platoon and I cat a
combat logistics patrol.
And I kept asking over the radio,
how many rounds have you fired?
Cause I was afraid they were
gonna get low on Ammo. Zero. Damn.
Okay.
So that's when you rolled out.
Yeah.
You get out there and this is
three days after Ganja Gall Damn
pkms and a case we're hammering down on
this mess with little return fire would
be crazy to drive into that tangle of
vehicles. Is it bogus or Bach is focus.
Focus focus was on the
mark 19 on our truck.
He couldn't shoot because
of the angles of fire.
Richard stayed in the driver's seat wide.
Vance on foot by bounds into
the wreckage our ass cars.
Ron Ran forward with us,
but they're light [inaudible] sixteens
didn't impress the Taliban machine gun
crew. I was quickly pinned behind
us. Disabled truck looking up.
I could see the P cam was shooting from
a thick stone house 200 meters up slope.
I actually needed to have a targets.
I excited to have his target so close.
I fired about five shells from my grenade
launcher before my common sense kicked
in. What am I doing? I thought I'm out
bad outmatched by a machine gun, but he,
there's an army Humvee sitting next to
me with no one in the 50 cal turret.
You run over there, man. You're 50
calla yelled at where logistics came.
The muffled reply.
We don't fight some supply guys
can't wait to get into the action,
but not this gang.
I wasn't worried though.
Wild Man Kerr would soon
have air on station.
Bodies were scattered all over the road.
All civilians lying face down next to
me alongside the army truck was a skinny
teenager and a tee shirt bleeding from
shrapnel in his chest and his left arm.
He was a pathetic sight sprawled on
his back and his filthy brown shorts,
an orange tip needle protruding from
above his heart and a plastic stopper
shoved above his left nostril.
He didn't weigh as much as I ate in a day.
His hands and feet were uglier than the
dirt from his efforts to crawl out of
the line of fire.
He wasn't old enough to grow a beard,
but he had a full shock of black hair.
Not a bad looking kid.
Once he was cleaned up at the aid station
and had some ice cream, he'd be okay.
I felt good. In fact, I was pumped.
I had applied dozens of tourniquets,
but this was the first time I had smelled
death his out and that's cause you
needled him down and I didn't cover that
part yet. A sucking chest wound and you,
you gave mud decompression.
I had saved a human being,
a poor,
scrawny kid eking out a living by driving
a banged up truck pass known ambush
sites.
What do you eve,
what do eventually join the Taliban
and betray and American convoy?
I had no idea. Sure. Some of the villages
at Gone Juggalo had been real pricks,
but why should I hold it against this kid?
I ran back down the road,
hoisting up another wounded truck
driver and carried him back.
Then I stopped to check on the skinny kid.
I wanted a pat him on the shoulder to
make myself feel good for my supposedly
wonderful deed.
Only he was dead.
He had bled to death from
the wound to his left arm.
The crew in the army truck
had let him bleed out,
not five feet away because he was
an Afghan and they were afraid,
dammit.
The Afghan drivers were all huddled
together in a ditch by the river.
The ambush had been sprung
about 90 minutes earlier by now.
They had pissed themselves dry and had
nowhere to go. I banged my rifle on.
I'm being my rifle,
but on an army truck yelling to the
soldiers to open up at least give me some
water for those poor bastards.
I shouted. A sheep is medic,
got out of the truck with several bottles
of water and his med pack and ran over
the ditch.
I knelt there looking at the blood stage
stains from the kid right beside the
truck door. I banged on the steel
door again. It opened a crack.
Fuck you.
I said to the captain inside
as the traffic jam was sorted out,
Cornell,
you and I walked back to
our home v the dead kid,
kid lay on the hood and rather
ride to base with a corpse
between us. We wedged the body in
the trunk. Sometimes you laugh,
sometimes you want to cry
before dropping the
shell down a mortar tube.
The gunner levels the bubbles on his site.
If he loses the bubbles than the
tube is pointed at a crazy ankle
after ganja juggle.
I was losing the bubble.
So investigations take place.
There's actually a, you know,
accusations and excuses. And one of the
terms that that wasn't there, that was it.
There was, it was being said that
there was four battle management. Yeah.
And you're talking to a psychologist
onsite at this time and you know,
that's some of the support you were
talking about that we might have an Afghan
kid and the Afghan army might not have.
And it was a feat.
Was it a female captain,
Katie cop and she was making
some assessments? Yeah,
back to the book. It's true. I
didn't feel connected with others.
The askers were smoking Hash jabbering
on their cell phones and wandering around
and flip flops. The American
soldiers were playing video games,
stuffing themselves at dinner,
laughing too loudly at nothing.
We weren't fighting a war.
We were holding a few acres of dirt
while the war swirled around outside our
barbed wire. There were
Douche mean in every valley.
Drink tea with the villagers.
Pay $40 for a chicken. We were in
Kumar to fight. Let's get it on.
That was my attitude.
The psychologist insisted that I go back
to the states for treatment. No thanks.
As a captain, she had the rank
to make a recommendation stick,
but she wanted my agreement.
So she challenged me.
We would play a game of ping
pong. If I won, I could stay.
I lost by one point.
She was very good and she really was
worried about me and cared about me.
I knew that,
okay.
It was my time to go home
ping pong game.
Was she like a Legit Ping Pong player?
No, I thought I had her. You know,
I was the only, uh, you know,
it was either, you know, I, um,
it was probably best I went home.
Uh,
I would say if it wasn't, if I didn't
go home, I, I would've never came home.
Um,
you know,
I was just getting wound tighter
and tighter. I mean, I was,
you couldn't tell me, you
couldn't tell me. I was not,
I wasn't, I wasn't command like you
couldn't, you couldn't tell me what to do.
You were out of control. I was, I was out
of control. Yeah. Uh, I mean, you know,
I wasn't doing anything,
nothing, you know, a morally
unethical, right. Like nothing.
I was doing my job,
but as far as like commanding
me, you couldn't, you, you were going
to do what you were going to do.
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, I was, you know,
I was at the point to where I had no,
I had no, uh, I didn't trust my
command. I didn't trust anybody.
I didn't trust anybody who's gonna. I
mean, it was, uh, I was the one, you know,
not a one man. I was a three man
operation. Right. I mean I was,
but I was a one man. I was a one man
wrecking crew. Right. Like I was,
I mean I was going to do, you aren't going
to tell me anything. I mean there was,
it was, it was pretty bad. I mean,
I was fighting and how, you know,
the fist fighting.
Okay.
Uh, you know, how much the last guy,
how much longer was it that you actually
lost the ping pong match and got sent
home?
I lost it. Right. Um, a couple of
days before thanksgiving. Okay.
So it was like you were, you were there
for another, what's Thanksgiving meal and,
and, yes, and we fought her ass
off the whole time. The whole time.
It was,
it was,
we fought our asses off almost every
single day and sometimes three and four
times a day. Well, that momentum
that you talked about in the valley,
they built it. It keeps coming. Right.
It keeps coming cause right after that
they overrun Keating right after. I mean,
it's all of that, all of it, you know,
they just built so much momentum
and they were hammering us.
I mean hammering us every day and um,
you don't hate it was,
it was pretty bad.
So you get sent home here. We go back to
the book. When I got home in December,
I felt like I landed on the moon.
Okay.
Everyone around me was excited
about football, Christmas
and other normal things.
I was looking at the clapboard
houses and the cars thinking, man,
that's so flimsy. They wouldn't give
cover worth shit in a firefight.
It was an exposed feeling and
where where my machine guns,
I found my old pistol and kept
her around like a rabbit's foot,
but I missed my two forties
and my 50 cows something awful.
It seems weird, I'm sure. But I
really just wasn't buying that.
There wasn't some enemy about to come
over the green hills and I felt so
unprepared.
I wouldn't be any good to protect anybody.
I was soon sent off to Fort Thomas,
Kentucky for Ptsd therapy.
Maybe that would settle me down and let
me get some sleep and stop feeling so
depressed and angry at every little thing.
Some guys really go nuts when they come
back and I wasn't in danger of that,
but I could feel the kind of crazy
things that maybe got the better of them.
You're over there long enough and under
such constant battle stress that it
resets all your settings the way,
way into the red and they're
very hard to set back.
The main thing knowing was that I didn't
get my friends out as I had promised.
I had spent a good part of my 21 years
being pretty critical of other people who
failed at their responsibilities and now
it was all coming back on me and a dump
truck.
Everyday.
The psychologist urged us to step back
and identify why we were experiencing
negative emotions.
In other words,
take a minute to really be conscious of
the emotion instead of just letting it
seep in.
Don't let your mind stay in neutral.
Watch your thoughts and by the way,
I'm hitting this stuff pretty hard because
a lot of people that listen to this
podcast, yeah are, are, are
thinking these things right here.
I think that's an important part.
Don't let your mind stay in neutral.
Watch your thoughts.
Refusing to get out of bed or go to work
or smile at others are all decisions.
Find the reasons,
those decisions and turn negative
feelings into positive actions.
It's not enough to identify
why you're feeling bad.
It's about having the character to do
something positive, to take up that space.
Don't wallow in your misery, which is
just selfish, childish shelf absorption.
It was all good stuff.
All I ever need is a good operating
manual through you're getting some good
instructions.
Yeah. Not with, you know,
I can't say that the end of
the PTSD center helped me,
but what it did is it educated me,
it educated me on why I was feeling
the way I was and what it was,
and then therefore that helped
me deal with it. Right. Um,
it Kinda like, you know, uh,
you know, you, you, you know,
Kinda like how you know your diet
that works for you. Hmm. You know,
like you can look in the mirror, are you,
how you feel after you eat it. Right?
Yeah.
It's kind of the same thing.
Like it educate you on why your body's
doing this or why you're having this
reaction, you know, and, and that
it's normal and it's just, you know,
and this is why it's doing it and this
is how you help counter it. Right.
And that was kind of, that was kind
of what it did for me. It didn't,
I don't think it really, it
didn't, it didn't fix anything.
It just educated me on
what the problem was.
So you could start to identify
the problem. Yes. So I
could identify the problem,
I could identify why I was feeling
this way, and then, you know,
I could make decisions based of,
of how I
was that when you look at the
root of that problem, yeah.
What was it that feeling of like, hey,
the, the promise that you made was,
I'll get you guys out.
No, I mean, no, I mean the facts of
the facts are like, here, here's,
I get so frustrated with people who want
to, like, I'm, I'm a factual guy. Like,
you know what I mean? I, I'm, everything
to me is black and white and, and I'm,
I'm in fact base. Like I, I went in
that day to go get my teammates out.
I failed, I failed. There's
no, you can't jump around it.
You can't, you can't ignore the
facts of what happened. I failed.
I failed miserably.
And so, you know, you, if you tell you,
if I tell myself I didn't fell,
I lie, I'm lying to myself. So
for me, you know, um,
I failed,
I was tested and I failed
and
now I have to figure out what to do
with that. And that's part of it,
you know, and, and that, and that's where
I get so upset about like, you know,
the counselors or whatever. Right. It's
not, well you didn't fail. No, no, no.
Like as soon as they say that to me,
hi, Yay, I'm done. I'm done. Cause no,
that's, I'm not going to lie to myself.
I failed and now I need to deal with it.
I need to deal with it.
You know, I can't lie.
And, and that's, and I
mean look, I mean it's,
I always say the equivalent to try to
make people understand like how to,
how I feel about it in this
situation is it would be like
you inside of a house and your family's
there and the house catches on fire
and you end up getting out
thinking that maybe they're all out
and you can't get back in there
and they all burned to death.
Okay.
That's kind of the equivalent of it.
And you know,
so I just have to deal with it and,
and you know,
I deal with it the best I can every day.
I learned from it.
I try to turn it into something good,
but at the end of the day I still failed.
And
you know, that's, that's the way it goes.
Going back to the book,
ma'am,
after my two months at the clinic,
Mike,
my enlistment term was
in fact coming to an end.
It didn't take a genius to see it. I'd
be be, and I'd end up behind a desk.
So I chose not to reenlist.
I love the core. So it hurt.
Before joining the corps, I had
three concussions, mononucleosis,
and an operation on my right knee.
When I mustered out four years later,
I'd added two operations on my right
hand or right road or rotator cuff
operation, a fourth concussion
from an RPG, a dislocated shoulder,
and two herniated discs from
clumsily lifting the dead
and wounded one vertebrae.
Given Wayne Ganja gold.
When I picked up an ask aren't
slipped in the bloody mud under him.
I have no idea when the second
vertebrae went out during the battle,
I had that nick and my arm
from a bullet or shrapnel,
but that hadn't been anything.
I was in deep in decent shape
for construction work. I figured.
Yeah.
After the Ptsd Clinic,
I returned to Kentucky.
It was the winter of 2010 and they warm
myself up by slipping back into hard
drinking each night.
I hadn't seen an active duty grunt months.
Fabio and Rodriguez Chavez were due to
receive the Navy Navy crosses at the
Marine Corps base in Quantico,
but I couldn't get enough time off
to fly back east where you work in
construction at this point? Yeah. And
your boys are getting Navy crosses.
You can't get time off from work.
Swanson and I had been recommended for
the medal of honor. We knew that. No,
we knew though that the award was
usually downgraded. Upon review.
When I drank, which was too much,
I'd laugh at the insert absurdity.
I had screwed up big time.
My achievement
was losing my brothers.
The Marine Corps would come to its senses
and I'd never hear another word from
another devil dog. I had no idea what
was in front of me and I didn't care.
I couldn't take a walk,
turn on the TV or read a
book to distract my mind.
The emptiness of my life was the dark
all around me with nothing to see you in
any direction.
Four years ago,
I'd left the form for an
adventure and a new beginning.
The chord shape meaning and I had
arrived in Afghanistan. Confident.
I do well in combat.
Sure enough,
up at Monte I had emerged
as the young gun every day,
brought fun danger against the
backdrop of spectacular mountains.
It was fun stuff.
Shooting thousands of rounds,
not losing many people and seeing
the damage. You inflict it.
There was no weapon I couldn't handle
and my team trusted me to get them out of
any hotspot my cockiness put us in,
but when it counted most,
I wasn't with them.
They weren't trained to do my job.
Gunny Johnson didn't spend
every day behind a to 40
yeah.
Staff, staff. Sergeant Kenefick wasn't
comfortable with weapons or ankles.
A fire doc late and wasn't a fighter and
Lieutenant Johnson didn't adjust fire
missions.
We aren't worried.
We know you'll get us out
if anything goes bad. Meyer,
well, I didn't lieutenant. That
was a load of worthless shit.
Not there when you needed me.
Yeah.
Around three in the morning,
I pulled my truck into the driveway of
a shop owned by my high school friend
Derek Yates had cut the engine.
I turned on the cab light
and fished out by cell phone.
It wasn't right to burn my dad,
but I wanted to connect
one last time with someone.
Yeah.
I picked out a text message
to my friends and then Toby,
they had known me since I was a toddler,
but they didn't know me that well.
Did they?
Okay.
Here I was back where I had
started with an aluminum bracelet.
Okay.
With two names on each
arrest.
That's what I had done with my life.
Lost Four brothers.
Okay.
I can't do it any more.
I typed,
I reached into the glove
compartment where I kept my glock.
I always kept a full magazine with
a round chambered in the pistol.
A Glock doesn't have a safety.
You pulled the trigger
and the weapon fires.
I stuck the gun to my head
and squeeze the trigger.
Click
nothing.
Nada.
No round in the chamber.
As you can imagine.
I sat there quite sobered
up and didn't double shock
suicide is terminal self revulsion.
I was mixed up but I knew my
team would be disappointed in me.
Okay.
Staff Sergeant can effect
would give me hell,
which is where I would be bad ending.
That was not going to happen.
Okay,
but who downloaded my pistol
right on the spot?
I knew who had done it. Have I ever
talked to that person about it?
No.
I put away the pistol and drove home
that night.
I experienced no sudden change
of direction in my life.
I didn't know where I was headed
in the future, but I knew,
I knew quitting wasn't right.
Not that night.
Not ever.
I had never told.
MMM.
I never told anybody about that night
until it was published in the book.
And,
uh,
I just,
you know,
I just felt like it was important to the
story because I didn't want people to
read the story and then just think
that it was all okay when I came home.
I didn't want to give
them that perspective.
And there are so many guys out there
that write these books of the crazy shit
that they do,
but they never talk about what,
what that crazy shit does to them.
Yeah. They never talk about
that. And so what happens is, is
people read that and they're like,
Holy Shit, that's, that's crazy.
I could never do that because I deal
with problems. And it's like, yeah,
we all do. And you know,
I had to put it into,
I wanted people to know that I'm just
a human. I'm no different now. And I,
I felt like that I couldn't put in the,
the,
if you want to call it good stuff
and not put in the bad stuff,
it's,
I'm sure there's some psychologists that
could figure something out about this.
But you got to the point,
right,
and you made the decision clearly.
Yeah.
And you came out the other side by the
grace of God and whoever knew you well
enough to,
to figure out that they needed to make
sure you didn't have a loaded gun.
But that's a message for anybody that
feels like they're in the same situation
that you felt like you were in, which is
that there's not going to get any better
is like, okay, come out
the other side, man,
come out the other side. And it
was like, I mean, like you said,
it's not a sudden change in
direction, but you, but you knew
hi. Uh, you couldn't quit. I
always like to say that, you know,
sometimes you find yourself in the middle
of nowhere and sometimes in the middle
of nowhere you find
yourself. And, uh, you know,
I, uh, I mean I had no idea what my life
was going. I made a deal with myself.
You know, I had sat there and, uh,
I had said, if I'm going to keep
living this life, this way, the rack,
rack it back and get it over with,
but I said,
if I ever put the car in drive, I'll
never look back. And I sit there,
I'm not going to lie to you. I probably
sit there for five, 10 minutes.
And I had done it at,
at my buddy shot because I knew he'd be
there eight o'clock in the morning and
he could just find me. And, uh,
I put it in drive and I just, I never
looked back. You know, I, you know,
and it's, I'm lucky. I'm fortunate.
Did the gun didn't go off right. Um, but,
um, you know, I think that, you know,
you always got to hit that rock bottom,
you know, I think that in
that was for me, that was it.
That was the rock bottom.
And you know, it changed it.
I mean, again, I just want to stress this
as much as I can because I believe me,
I hear from people,
especially from veterans that are,
that are walking this line,
man, they're walking this line.
And if you're walking that line,
hold it.
Yeah. Listen, it's not
worth it. I mean, it's,
it's not like, you know,
I had to change, honestly,
I had to change the way
that I looked at life.
The only problem there was
was me, you know, instead of
just facing it and saying,
Hey, look, I want to fix this problem.
I was blaming everybody
else for my problems.
And what I had to do was I
had to say, you know, okay,
if you know,
if the things that I seen were so bad,
I've seen what freedom cost firsthand.
That's what's got me there.
So if anything,
I have more reason than anybody else in
the face of this planet to go out and
make the most of my life because I've
seen it firsthand of what it costs.
So instead of walking around
and Phyllis, I, you know,
I'm not feeling sorry for my teammates
because they're in a better place,
they don't feel anymore.
I'm really just feeling sorry for myself.
And then by doing that,
I'm sick.
I'm wasting the sacrifices that they
made on my behalf and I had to change the
way I looked at it.
Instead of using it as my excuse,
I had to use it as my fuel.
And that's a choice.
That is a conscious choice.
You wake up every day and you decide
how you look at the situation.
You decide what you do with the,
you decide whether you use it as your
excuse to hold you back or you use it as
your easy a,
you know,
valve of hiding who you are or you use
it as your fuel to go out and be the best
that you can be. You decide that nobody
does. Nobody else does. You do every day
and it is a conscious choice.
I mean, I still deal with it,
but I still make the choice.
That's awesome. That's awesome.
And anybody that's listening,
like I said, anybody that's listening and
that's, that's walking that line. Yeah.
There you go. Make the right choice.
Make the right choice, make the choice,
make the right choice. And you
know what the right choices. Yeah.
And I mean you're talking about
how much and, and I feel this too,
like every day,
how much am I letting down my friends
that didn't come home if I'm not doing
everything I can to take advantage
of the gift they gave me,
if to be sitting here right now.
Right.
I mean, I mean any day that I don't
want to go on and push on for myself,
I can look down and I bet you anything,
I got four reasons right here.
They would switch me one day.
They would switch me my worst
day to have one more day.
Yeah.
Do you know? And, and, and I just,
yeah.
You know, I'm not okay with letting
their sacrifice. It'd be wasted.
I'm not okay with watching
anybody else waste them.
So why would I be okay with
letting myself waste them?
Well,
and other thing I want to say,
he is like walking that line.
I want to say this and get it out
there. It's normal. It's normal.
It doesn't mean you're weak. It doesn't.
I want to get that, that stigma out there.
Uh, you know, I want to get that off
the books is, it's, it is a normal,
like I don't understand why,
why it's okay in our society or in
the military. A guy breaks his leg.
Okay, do you go make
him Ryan Tomorrow? Yeah.
He puts a cast on it.
He, he, he rehabs it.
It's the same thing with the mind. It's
the same thing. It's the same thing.
You go in and you watch it.
The people you have to worry about
are the ones that go watch their close
friends and they watch human beings and
they watch this evil and people die and
suffer and don't have a reaction.
Those are the ones you
have to worry about.
It is a normal reaction
to a not normal situation.
And it's okay. It's okay. It is 110%.
Okay.
Absolutely man.
Absolutely.
As you, we mentioned quickly, you know,
there was some buzz possibly about,
about you getting a medal of honor. Yeah.
And, but you know how it goes. Like it
was all, I didn't believe it. I never,
I never had any idea. Uh, you know,
you hear talk about it at
Silver Star, medal of honor,
navy, cross, whatever. Right.
I didn't care. I didn't, I,
I promised the last thing that I
ever thought about. What's an award?
An award.
That's the last thing.
Yeah.
Well,
it gets approved.
And going back to the book, when the
president hung that medal around my neck,
I felt glum.
I couldn't smile and I said nothing.
I gave no remarks and avoided the press.
As a marine,
you either bring your team
home alive or you die. Trying,
my country was recognizing me for being
a failure and for the worst day of my
life,
the marine commandant,
General Jim Amos at General Joe
Joseph attended the ceremony.
Throughout the years after gone to golf,
the Marine Corps leadership has provided
con consistent support, not just to me,
but to all who fought there.
The top enlisted man in the Marine Corps,
Sergeant Major Mike Barrett twice came
to our farm to meet my dad and Granddad
and to encourage me.
There is no such thing as a former marine.
Yeah.
50 years after they have left active duty.
Marines still sign emails to each
other with SF, semper Fidelis,
always faithful.
Of course we have among us
those who failed themselves,
their family and society.
The fact remains though that the core
expects every marine to live by a set of
core values. In turn, the core
keeps its side of the bargain.
Yeah.
You can not ask anything more
of an organization than that.
The metal of honor given in the name
of the Congress of the United States of
America, symbolizes the courage and
determination of our entire country
and
speaking of the country you were in
New York?
I was in New York City.
Yeah,
at the twin tower site.
Ground Zero with gunny Joshua Peterson.
Someone I knew from my
first days in the core,
we were greeted by hundreds of
police, firemen, construction workers,
Wall Street guys and suits, city
officials, and the families of the fallen
Meyer. I can't believe this
scene, gunny. Peterson said,
make sure your ribbons are squared away.
We stood side by side.
Yeah,
two grants and sharply iron Khakis
waving like we had won an election.
I thought of my sad fumbling meetings
with the family of team Monte,
the families of team Monte when
I couldn't think of much to say.
I was alive and their loved ones were not.
Yeah.
Now here I was standing before
a monument for 3000 dead.
Yeah.
I saw some big iron workers in
hardhats standing off to one side.
When the ceremony ended,
they sneaked me in onto a work elevator
up. We went to the top of the ride where
we then climbed wooden ladders until we
couldn't go any further.
Okay.
Then the [inaudible] guard rails.
I stood there looking out at the
most beautiful country in the world,
trying to make sense of my feelings.
This was where it all started.
So many good people lost the people who
had been working here and the people I
had known who had not gone blindly
into uniform, they had reasoned why
Americans do that.
But they had gone ahead to do and to die.
An iron worker handed me a silver marker.
Then I wrote on a girder.
Yeah.
For those who gave
all
for those who gave all,
and that wraps up the book,
Em,
you know,
you're talking about the awards and what
you hear and what happens and all that.
And I wanted to say this as well,
on the battlefield,
on that battlefield,
and on every battle,
there are acts of extreme valor
that no one will ever know about.
I'm talking about an infinite number,
okay.
No one's ever going to know about them.
And it's important to know this,
that our military men and women don't
do what they do for metals or ribbons.
They do what they do because they love
freedom because they love America because
they loved their comrades in arms,
and that right there is why
our country thrives in battle,
not because of technological advances,
not because of superior weapon tree,
not even the size of our military.
It's because of the bond that is shared
between warriors that is our real
strength
and Dakota, that something
that you represent in space.
They don't. I want to thank
you for coming on the podcast
and sharing this incredible story and an,
I know it's not only a story of you,
but it's a story of all the men,
American and Afghan as well,
that rode into battle with you that day
and showed a once again what it is that
makes America a place of,
of hope and a freedom.
It's because of,
it's because of man.
It's because of individual men that
in their heart and even in the face of
death,
actually live actually live the
ideals of this great nation.
Not only in their words,
but in their actions,
in the way that they live and in the way
that they died.
God bless.
All right.
They're incredible.
You know, I, I mean, you're
exactly right. Like, I mean,
there's so many stories that
are, I mean, people have done
so many stories of people doing
such incredible stuff and you know,
it's, it's, it's literally out of
the love of another human being.
It's literally, I the love of making
the world a better place. That's really,
that's really all we do. It's
all we do. I mean, we join,
nobody joins it. Okay. To go
with just shoot people or fight.
They literally joined to,
to try to make the world
around them a better place.
Whether it's passing out a,
whether it's rendering aid
to a civilian or to, uh,
uh, you know, I,
fellow American or whether it's taken
out the bully that's inflicting fear in
that place.
Every thing that we do
is to try to make the world
just a little bit better.
That's it.
Yeah. As I was reading about when,
when you got back to your team,
you could see, I mean just from
the way the guys were laid out,
you know,
staff sergeant was trying to get comms
and trying to pass grids and doc was
working on the boss.
I mean everyone was trying to make
things happen and who knows what those
moments were like, you know,
but there's moments of there's,
there's heroism there that
we're never going to know about.
No, I mean, I mean 100%. I mean
doc late and was rendering aid,
you know what stopped him was
cause pause l was with them.
What stopped him of getting to the
road was Lieutenant Johnson got hit
and a gunny Kenefick in gunny
Johnson were on either side,
provide security while doc
late and worked on him.
And that was the med evac we
heard called in from gunny.
Kenefick was trying to call that medivac
in for Lieutenant Johnson right here.
And um,
you know,
but they weren't going to,
they weren't going to leave him behind
even more,
even more of not leaving them behind.
They weren't going to
just throw him over his
shoulder and get him out.
They were going to try to fix him.
I mean, what'd he say?
What'd he say? I mean,
you know that right there. I mean that
right there is everything. I mean,
you take that, you take, I mean,
there's so many actions. I mean,
I've watched people do
such incredible things,
such incredible things that just
make what I do. I mean, Nah,
you know, Nah, makes me look like a,
you know, I've done nothing. I've,
I've seen it, you know,
people are incredible.
Well, I'm again, man.
I can't thank you enough for coming on.
No thank you on the
podcast and hanging out and
being out there and kicking ass and
talking smack to people. I like that too.
Uh, did I miss anything?
Anything else? No.
Thank you. Thank you.
Covered it all. I uh,
I think you covered it, you know, Echo,
you got any questions for
the man over there? Nah,
usually I come up with some
lighthearted question, but man,
I'm out of words, to be honest with
you. We took that little, a break.
An Echo was like, man, he's that
guy. Just keep the SEC. I, I,
I'm sitting there thinking to myself, this
really happened man. And I'm like, yeah,
I told, I gave, I gave echo heads up
sometimes, you know, I say, hey man,
it's going to be heavy one or whatever.
And I was like, told him this afternoon,
I'm like, Amen. It's going to be heavy
one, you know, stand by. And you know,
we're downstairs when we were taking
that break and he's like, man,
all this really happened. I said,
yeah, and you know who it happened to?
The guy we're sitting in a room with when
his friends, like that's what happened.
So, uh, no, I it, early on
when I started this podcast,
I'd be reading a book from
Knight, from World War One. Yeah.
Or I'd be reading the book from World
War II or Vietnam or whatever, and I'd,
I'd like after bite,
I don't know how many podcasts,
but like seven or eight
podcasts, I was like, Hey,
I just want to stop for a second and
remind everybody that the characters that
I'm talking about in these books,
these characters,
they're not characters in a movie.
They're, they're people, they're humans.
And this stuff that we're talking
about really happened to these people.
So again,
it's obviously avenue sitting here.
And I was talking to you about when,
when Colonel William Reader was
in here and you know, you're like,
you're reading stuff that happened to him.
He was tortured,
he was mock executions. He had, he had,
he was locked in a Bam,
a two foot tall bamboo cage in the
jungles and Vietnam and got his legs
in shackles and the,
he's trying to sleep and he's getting
woken up by the rats that are eating the
wounds in his leg.
And it's like, that's
just inconceivable. Yeah.
I mean, edit happened.
Yeah. I mean that's,
you know, I hear stories like that and
just, you know, that's real people.
Yeah.
These are real people dislike us.
Yeah. In, in, in, in honestly, man. I
mean, I'm sure you saw me like sometimes,
you know, um, yeah, I'm getting, I
get emotional when I read your story,
but why do I get raw emotional
when I read your stories?
Cause I'm thinking of everything I've
been through. I'm thinking of my,
my friends and I'm just like,
it's
man, you know, it's a,
okay,
it's real. And, and for those of you
people that are listening to this,
and I talked to,
I dressed like the veterans out there
a bunch today. Um, but you
know, to those of you that
didn't have the opportunity to
serve for whatever reason, you know,
if I could relate something to you,
it's like, yeah, these, these people,
these lieutenants, these
sergeants, these staff sergeants,
man, there are people, man. There
are people. Yeah. They're just,
they're just people. They're
just people. I mean, that's,
they're just people.
They're just,
uh, you know, and I think that that's
kind of what makes it hard for society of,
yeah.
Is it,
they see so many of these movies and
they read these books and you know,
they read it, but what they don't
understand is that somebody lived it,
you know?
And I think that that's a perspective
that you always have to remind yourself of
is that yeah, you're reading
it and, but somebody lived at,
do, you know? Yeah. Then you kind of see,
you know,
on the news like, Oh yeah. Then the
medal of honor ceremony and the pictures,
you know,
of you getting there and you know,
you see the president putting it on
and it's like, wow, that's so great.
Or whatever in you,
what you don't,
what we don't see, you know,
people who haven't served, oh,
is like what really happened to talk
to arrive at that one quote unquote
glorious moment where you get
the metal. Oh my gosh, thank you.
Let's go party or so, I don't
know. Something, you know,
it's like, Dang, Bro did.
Yeah. People think it's just
so great, you know? And, uh,
okay.
I despise everything that metal
stands for for me. You know, me,
not anybody else,
but I,
you know,
when I put that medal around my neck,
okay.
To me, it's literally here's the
stamp to show the world how bad I
failed.
Here's the,
you know, um, that's why
I don't, I don't wear it.
I don't, I don't wear it because, you
know, it's the worst day of my life.
And,
uh,
I lost everything that day.
I lost not just my team.
I lost my career in the Marine Corps.
I mean, everything that I wanted to be
was gone within one day and,
you know,
and then I get recognized for it,
you know?
So not only do you have to live with it,
but now you have to live with
it in the face as a nation.
Well,
from that perspective, from, from
my perspective, looking at that.
Okay.
For one thing,
the metal,
okay.
Yeah.
I mean it was put around your neck,
but I believe that metal represents
everyone that was with your team and you
might have gotten the, the, the
metal put around your neck, but it's,
it represents that story's going to be
told over and over again in your name.
Might be at the top of the list, but
every name is going to be on that list.
Everyone's going to know, and I mean,
obviously I can't imagine the burden
that comes with that metal that you live
with,
but at the same time
being able to have that you
have your brothers remembered.
I think that it makes it worthwhile
and, and you know, in that, and that's
the piece of it. You're right. I mean,
so on the selfish, you know, when I,
what I just said was on the selfish side
of it, right? That, that, that is for me,
um, that that is the only reason I
did it except a metal was because
I want my teammates to live on forever.
I want people to know who they were
because the day that I stopped speaking,
their name is the day they truly die.
And I have an obligation that
as long as I can still breathe,
that their names are still
need to be told. And um,
so that's what that metal allows me to
do and it is our metal. I mean it's,
it's for them. Um, but yeah, I mean,
you know,
you don't,
it's just, it goes against, you know,
and I think the one thing you know,
that is so hard for us to wrap around
is how many times in your training
did you,
how many times did you say it?
Like when you were training
guys and this and that,
how many times did you ever set them up
for when they did everything that they
could,
they failed
eight to be honest with you, when I was
running training I that all the time.
Yeah. I'm not kidding. I mean you can talk
to anybody that went through training.
When I ran it. It was, it was just
mayhem and it was, you were going to,
you know, you are going to carry out
bodies. You had 16 guys in the platoon,
you are going to be carried six bodies
out and you're going to be carrying him
for four kilometers to
a helicopter extract,
which wasn't going to show up and you're
going to have to go on another six.
It W it was brutal and there was times,
there was times where I'd kill
every single, you know, training.
I'd kill every single seal because they
were not doing what they're supposed to
do, where they were making mistakes
or the leadership wasn't stepping up.
I did that all the time.
I did it all the time.
I mean,
I can't,
I came back from Ramadi were when my guys
were in some really bad situations and
I wanted everyone to be ready
for that man. And like that was,
it was, I mean, I was not, I mean I,
I came back from Pullman and got put
in charge of training. It was awesome.
It was the best thing that I ever
could have done for me. And, and I,
I've thought it was the best thing I
could do for my teammates was to be like,
okay, we're going to make this
training hard, really hard. And,
and so probably not.
You probably thought I was gonna say
never book man when I was running training
and then that's, that's awesome.
And I had gotten, I mean,
I had many guys that came back from Iraq
and Afghanistan and, and would say like,
yeah,
Amen.
We got,
we got hammered hard in this
situation and we were ready.
Nothing is bad as your situation,
but yeah, but the mentality of it is,
you know, there are some
situations you're not going to win.
There are some situations where you
show up and you're not going to win.
And that's against everything that we
believe in. Everything that we're taught.
You know what I mean?
That,
that if we do our job and we
do it right and you still lose,
it doesn't make sense.
Well let's,
that's something I've told
many guises meant you,
you can do everything right.
You can make no mistakes,
then you can still get killed. You
could still lose. You can still thinks,
you know, there's decisions that you make
on the battlefield. You say if you say,
okay,
go left,
you can go left and everyone can be
great and it's the best decision ever.
And you could say go left and everyone
could die and it's the worst decision
ever. There's, there's things that
you can control inside of combat.
So you prepare and train
as hard as you can and,
and the other thing you do is you
get the leadership in the situ,
in a mentality that they're
not going to put themselves.
This is like if my guys planned something
that was stupid, I let a Mexican,
this is in training.
They came up with a dumb plan.
They were going to execute that plan.
I wasn't going to stop them and
they were going to get slaughtered.
So they'd learned some lessons.
But Oh,
that's why that training is so important
and it's important in everything now.
A hundred percent a hundred percent
I appreciate you having me on.
Yeah, man. Thanks for coming
brother. No, thanks so
much, man. It's awesome man. Yeah, right.
I do not accept that from you.
If you are the man. All right.
Echo. Yes. Talk about
something good. Sure.
Chill cruise. Little bit.
Good. What do you mean? Okay,
so we'll shift gears.
Kind of a rough transition.
I'll let him know that we're like three
hours plus right now so you can tell it
quickly if you want.
If I want,
please see how they kind of recommend
that. I feel like me and Dakota,
we have some catching up to do.
You guys have been talking so you know
I might drag this out a little bit. No.
Okay. So origin mean, this is
where you get Jocko supplements.
Krill oil joint warfare's for your
joints. It's free joints. Yes.
Important supplement. Yes.
Important supplement. Yeah.
Also he has one called disciplines,
the cognitive and physical
enhancement supplement.
Preworkout pre mission. It's what
it's called. It's a good one.
Also at origin may its origin,
main.com Maine. The state,
not like the main one.
Yeah. That's good. Um,
you got geese on there for Jujitsu.
You trained, you jittery? I do. Yeah.
So if you get the origin g,
those are all made in America.
Everything in orange is the,
we'll get you an origin
Giesen and American.
You got to represent some of them.
Yup. From threats from the cotton. By
the way. We grow the cotton in America,
not the guy.
And they import the fabric and we
assemble them in everything from seat.
What is it? From seeds to seat from
dirt to shirt. The shirt or tee shirt.
The shirt. I'm pretty good, right?
Yeah, it was good. I liked it.
Oh they got some rash
guards on their spats. Yeah.
You know what spats are? No. Yeah, we
didn't really either. We had to kind of,
we had to research it arrived at spath.
Here's the bottom line.
They're spandex, their tights basically.
Compression gear. Where do you train?
Do you train a 10th planet?
Do you do to some you seen dudes down
there was playing or was always talking
about it in its 10th planet.
It's all about them. Bats.
They're all about the
spouse was worried about,
I was worried about using the
word spats cause I didn't,
I w it sounded like maybe
it was some kind of like,
let's just say sounded kind of girlish
like some girl, like a girl would be like,
oh I'm going to wear spanx. What
are those? It sounds like spanx.
I don't know what some girls wear.
Rice banks are real tight. Like the,
it's Kinda like, it's essentially
compression. Compression.
Like I would compress,
compress,
they should be illegal.
I figured out somebody who should be
illegal because it's like selling,
oh it's false.
I was on,
we were on like some kind of live
broadcasts and someone would,
spats is comes from what soldiers?
Cavalry soldiers in World War war,
like leggings.
And they were called spats and I was like,
okay, it's cool. Well let's say it now.
Yeah, they weren't really even leg you.
They're just, it's like this lower,
have that lower part that covers the boom
that was straight up. That is
not spats. That's something else.
What are those things called?
Did you have to do honor guard?
You had to wear those things? No, I think
they were actually called leggings. Wait,
the,
so we're unclear.
I know what spats are very unclear
because in football you tape your shoe and
your ankle, that spat. So it
just, you know, I like it.
It works. It does. Right.
See those nonetheless,
origin has some spats, some
compression gear, rash guard,
and so it just all made American good
stuff. Or did you mean.com go on there,
check out all their stuff. You'd
be like something, get something.
Also for the kettle bells that I have
Trina on it planet. Yeah. On
it. You know the kettlebells?
Probably more bells. Yeah.
Got The whole set. Yeah.
He's very proud of that.
Whatever you see this semester feels
like a summit. You Know Primus Walter?
No. Oh yeah. What's that?
Primal, wet swells. Swole
soldier. You gotta check 'em out.
He works out down at on it like
he's a big kettle bell guy. Boom. Ba
boom. Yeah. So anyway, on it.com/chocolate
that's where you get the kettle bells.
You want to get the whole set like me
or you know,
or other stuff. Like I said, if
you actually, I said this before,
you want to vary up your workout
and make it more interesting.
Chocolate lakes boring workouts.
That's cool too.
But if you want to make more interesting,
get the Mace, get some more, uh,
what do you call it? Like more creative.
Yeah, the maze fitness equipment
on it. Dotcom slash Jocko
was a good spot. Also,
when you buy the book into the fire,
the quota, Meyer, don't worry,
I've got it listed on our website,
Jocko podcast.com by episode,
by the way,
along with all the books that we
go over on this podcast. Boom.
Just click through there,
take you to Amazon shop,
continue doing shopping if you want.
Good way to support.
Also
subscribe to the podcast. If
you haven't already, stitcher,
iTunes,
Google play,
Spotify.
I just know I just learned
what Spotify with me too.
I'm not even sure I know what it is.
Some kind of Mbk feed thing,
but we're on it. Yeah. I don't want Alexa.
You do you have Alexa and never heard
of her? Okay, well see Amazon go,
oh, well you can ask it to
play Jocko podcasts. No Way.
I'm going to buy one just for that.
Just be like Alexa,
play Jocko podcast and then
it says playing the latest
episode of Jocko podcasts.
Yeah,
and you always see it.
Do you have Alexa?
That's like saying, Hey,
do you have or you should go buy a Siri.
You can't buy Siri.
Siri comes with your phone.
No, no, no. You can buy Alexa.
No, you cannot buy an Alexa.
Buy An Amazon Echo. No one calls it
that though. No one talks about that.
Maybe they should because
that's the correct date.
We don't want to confuse people know
the only one that's cute. No, no, no.
You do want to come to these
people talking about Alexa.
I know that I'm trying to edge all right.
If you're going to dig in on this thing,
you had to go Amazon Echo. Believe me.
I know. It's a tube. An intelligent too.
They have to be all about you
and that's what it comes down.
[inaudible] that's what it is.
Look how happy Jocko
get that Amazon Echo.
And then you ask Alexa.
So essentially Alexa in the Amazon Echos
get, what? If I wanted to ask echo,
it won't. It won't respond. You can
call me up whenever I'll respond.
Amazon Echo will not respond to the name.
Alexa lives in Amazon Echo.
Just like Siri
in your iPhone. There's nothing living
in my iPhone. It's a machine. It's,
it's artificial life diligence.
Nonetheless.
Subscribe if you haven't already.
Also.
So Christ subscribe to Youtube where
we'll have the video version of this
podcast and excerpts on there as well,
and enhanced excerpts as well. If
you're into that. Subscribe Youtube.
Youtube also Jocko is a store.
It's called Jocko store.
It's like, it's called Jocko podcasts.
Jocko store. Cause it's a store.
I like. His reading is called Jocko. Yeah.
If I had a bad ass name, like Jocko,
if your name is Dakota, come on man.
I know everybody thinks it's like a girl
though. Oh really? Is that girl's name?
Dakota. Dakota fanning. And I like,
I pick up the phone and they're like,
uh ma'am. And I'm like, uh, no.
I didn't even know there was a girl's
name. Dakota. Well, yeah, sorry man.
You like a girl named sue.
Is that why you turned out so bad as
that is awesome by Johnny Cash?
I kind of feel like when it came down to
Jocko to name his own store and stuff,
he was all cool.
But when Amazon names their thing echo,
it's like you know me a little bit.
See she messed up. I was on your team.
No, no. You kind of called
me out. Remember at that
moment nonetheless. Hey Man,
I dig it either way. Jocko, store.com
this is where he can get shirts,
discipline equals freedom,
good shirt. The good shirt.
And when I say the good shirt,
it's a shirt with jock was hit on.
It says good backwards. So when you look
in the mirror, he's telling you good.
You know, I like that. It's pretty good.
When I get one I'm going to get one. Yeah,
I got you. I got you. And to you
too. Nice. I got you too. Alexa
will take care of you
extensively. Jewelry. Nonetheless,
there's some rash guards on there.
So I'm hoodies, some hats, patches.
I got to restock. The patches
are, we stopped everything
on there. Got The patches.
Yeah. Hey look, I'm trying over here. Um,
women now the restock automatically,
am I correct? Well, okay.
I'm not correct. Okay. Forget it depends
on what you mean by automatically.
I just mean things will
be in stock from now on.
That's what we'll just say
more often, bro. Just say
you had one job.
You know what?
Forget it when I say he's got two jobs,
make videos and keep the store stock.
How's he doing to you? Like
chocolate store.com. That's,
that's, that's the website anyway.
I'm not saying single buy something.
I'm saying, look, check it out.
If you want something, get something good
way to support. Also good way to sports,
psychological warfare,
support yourself and your campaign.
We call it a campaign against weakness.
It makes sense. Yeah, I like it. Yeah.
We liked it too. So it
was suggested to us. Um,
you know those days where you
kind of don't feel like it. Right.
And who better to ask for a little
assist on those days then Jocko,
right. In theory, right?
I mean I agree. So boom,
now we have this album with tracks,
chocolate tracks telling you to get how
to get past moments of weakness that may
come up. Waking up early,
skipping workouts, you know,
diet stuff on it works pretty good.
That's bad ass 10 for 10 results.
You'll never skip a workout for me.
So I made this echo is like ask me,
ask me a question one time
like why do you not stip it?
How do you not skip workouts? And I
was like, well I'll just mobile boom.
Yeah Tony, you don't feel like, and
he's like, dude, I need to record that.
And then he just asked me a bunch of
random questions and then we made a new
recording and we put
it on iTunes for sale.
It was the number one spoken
word on iTunes for I think,
I think until you're both 11
months finally got knocked
out of number one spoken
word by when I released this book,
discipline equals freedom field manual
on iTunes as a spoken word album.
So I'm just saying it's like, so Randy
effective. Yeah. And it's not him.
So Rah Rah. Just talk like I'm not a
killer. You don't seem like a young,
you don't have to know. You
don't have to tell the guys, Hey,
I mean obviously you've got to yell on
the battlefield and you gotta yell people
like you so they can hear you.
That's one thing. But yeah,
I mean I was used to tell guys,
if you have to yell at someone and
you've really screwed something up as a
leader, if I got to yell at you
or if I got to be like, yeah.
Nonetheless, it's a, yeah, very
effect. Like if you, he'll be like,
oh, there's this one called sugarcoated
lies. Right. And it's about like,
you know how like when you're at work,
you were talking about the good
video. Yeah. Right. So this is the same
thing, but it's like a track you can get,
you can get,
actually this is the discipline equals
freedom field manual album has good on.
There's a track just to
track. Boom. There you go.
So you can put it in your whatever you
can say. So because I had people calling,
you should make an alarm clock,
you should make alarm clock.
So when we did the album with tracks
and when you could use that thing as an
alarm clock. So when people ask me for a
long talking, I'm like go get the albums.
There's three albums now by the way.
Three albums,
psychological warfare and this
one was in two different albums.
You really only need the first album of
discipline equals freedom field manual
frivolously for the audio. Yeah,
you can get, well there's, there's,
well if you want the knowledge parts,
that's the second video. The second,
the second album, you didn't know
I was over here. So this is where,
this is where echo started. Hammer Hammer
me because you know when they list you,
they list like psychological warfare and
then they have to list who made it and
it was artist Jocko Willink. No, no, no,
no. I'm not an artist. I just, well, I'm
just speaking. I'm just saying it works.
That's not art. No, it's heck no,
no, no. You're an artist. You know,
so he didn't know that man.
I never,
I never looked at you and said, well,
I don't come across with the artist,
some artist, artsy guy. Nonetheless,
very effective. Very effective.
Good way to support too,
by the way,
also on Amazon through Alexa,
if you want, you can order Jocko white
tea, Amazon Afghan. And by the way,
I don't know if I'll give
you some Jocko white tea.
And the reason I'll give it to you isn't,
I don't care if you like to,
you might not. You might hate tea. But
what this t does is it is a guaranteed,
it's guaranteed to give you
an 8,000 pound dead lift.
It's scientifically proven over and
over again. Double Blind, double blind,
placebo tested right there. Jocko
white tea, 8,000 pound deadlifts. Um,
yeah. So you got that also
her books, the books. Um, yes.
Get into the fire by Dakota Meyer and
being west. Get it through our website.
It's, it's an awesome read matter. We, we,
I covered less than 10% of the book today.
You only understand 10% of what the
whole situation was by listening to this
podcast. Get the book to support
the podcast at Support Dakota.
Learn about what these brave
Americans and Afghans went through
way the warrior kid.
There's a book I wrote for kids. Why?
Because who's, what kind of kids?
What kind of books were kids reading?
I know, cause I've got four kids.
My kids were reading books about lame
people that were being encouraged to be
weak. Yeah. Instead of
like, Hey, you know what?
It's okay to actually get after it
and try and be smarter and try and be
stronger.
So if you want your kid to be smarter
and stronger and eat healthier and work
harder, if that's what you want, you'd
get the kid where the warrior kid,
if you want to make your child
a week and on disciplined,
that's cool. You can buy any other
book for a kid and that's what you get.
And that book did good with
people and I wrote another one.
It's called way of the warrior kid too.
It's called Mark's mission and it's got
a whole new genre of issues that mark
has to face with his uncle Jake.
Uncle Jake comes to help out young mark.
Would you call them more advanced issues?
They are slightly more advanced.
Let me tell you which one of them.
One of the,
one of the issues that young marks or
marks in sixth grade now in book too,
he loses his temper sometimes and he
gets in trouble at school for Hawking a
paper machine,
Pumpkin at another kid's head
and it deflects off his head,
hits the teacher in the
face. Oh man, he gets,
he gets sent home from school
last day of school. Anyways,
he has to learn to control his
temper just like all kids do.
And I know this cause I got kids and
I know this cause I was a kid and you
remember when you were a little kid and
you lose your temper and your dumb stuff
evil. And when I say little
kid, I'm talking like 23
years old. I was like sure.
I was like, yeah, I do. You
know what I'm talking about?
They were, I got to go get you a
copy. Uh, his uncle and the book is,
is a seal.
It was a seal and he comes to stay
with them for the summer and helps them
squared away these little problems. Yeah.
Yeah. So that's what that one's about.
He also learns about working hard.
He gets a job, starts a business.
He's 11 years old, has his own business,
mowing lawns and pulling weeds.
That's way the warrior kid and where
the warrior kid to Mark's mission.
Uh,
you can also get,
speaking of which warrior
kids from Irish oaks ranch,
there's a young warrior kid,
12 years old business owner.
He makes soap from goat's milk right
here in California on his farm.
Yeah. That's cool. Wow. Yeah. Well,
it seems like, well, how are you?
How does you even,
why are you talking about this?
He got in touch with me and said,
I want to make good soap doco
soap, and I was like, well,
who are you? He's like, I'm a 12 year
old kid named Aiden. I live on a farm.
I'm starting a business. I figure you
might want it on the action Jocko.
And I was like, hey dude, how man,
let's do this. Maybe some soap.
You might want it on the AG.
I is. He offered me a piece
of the action. I was like,
Oh God, yes. Amen, man. Warrior
kid getting after it. And so yeah,
you can order that soap
at Irish oaks ranch.
He's dot com you know, no
big deal. Soap Empire, right?
What is like Johnson and Johnson probably
started off making soap. Ivory soap.
You think ivory soap doesn't
have some good profitability.
Only differences. This kid starting
at 12 you're guaranteed Johnson.
Johnson didn't start at 12 sorry,
12 get on there.
You just order some of,
he'll have kinks worked out before
he can even drive. Yeah. Yeah. He's
all over it. I mean, I'm telling you,
he's a manufacturing soap. You think
about when you were, um, I mean,
let's just, let's just get
all of our own, our own,
lose herself out on the table here. What
were you doing when you were 12? Right.
I was like smearing boogers on my sister's
daughter. You know what I'm saying?
We're just talking loser. I was
eating dirt. I didn't know it so poor.
I was still eating dirt.
Yeah. I, I made up the
slogan to simple slogan,
simple slogan. And it's, it's actually
a great slogan. You know what it is?
Jocko stope state clean.
You got it.
You got to admit it.
I gotta tell you a God who would have
been as good, sloping the good stuff.
Good stuff. I don't know. I don't
know how you came up with that.
I'm telling you, Jocko
soap stay clean. Right?
With Jocko store.
Yeah. Chuck clothes store. Real
unreal. Creative when it comes to them.
Them names. Uh, also, hey, another book,
discipline equals freedom field manual.
If you need to get on the path,
stay on the path and be on the path,
move further down the path. If you're
having trouble getting after it in life,
get the book discipline equals freedom
field manual and then don't just get the
book and read it. You have to
actually do something that's in it,
but it's pretty clear.
It's a field manual.
Echo claims to know all about field
manuals and my favorite kind of manual you
actually know about field manuals go into
field manual that tells you how to get
after it so you can do that.
The audio version of that is not on
audible. You can't find it there.
Why? Because you couldn't cut it up into
tracks, which is what you all asked for.
It is on Amazon music.
Google play iTunes as an MP three.
Also extreme ownership.
The book that Leif Babin and I wrote,
it's about combat leadership.
Some of them actually,
every topic that we talked about
today when it came to leadership and
organizational issues,
it's all,
it's all things that are inside
extreme ownership. Get that.
And it's not just about war, but
it's about life. It's about business.
And on top of that, we have a leadership
and management consulting company.
It's called echelon front.
We solve problems through leadership.
Every problem that any organization has
can be solved through one thing and one
thing only leadership. That's
it. So if you've got problems,
call us Ashkelon front me,
Leif Babin, JP Denelle,
Dave Burke,
echelon front.com.
Of course also we have the muster,
it's a leadership gathering
to leadership gathering,
seminar,
conference gathering.
And that's what we do. We,
we get together, we have
all kinds of leaders come,
we present,
we talk about issues,
we give pragmatic actual tactics and
techniques on how to lead people.
If you want to like come to a conference
and get all happy and clappy and make
hugging promises to the guy
that's sitting next to you,
don't come to this conference.
That's not what this conference is.
We're not singing and dancing
at all. No. We talk about,
we talk about how to lead. That's what it
is. So if you want to learn how to lead,
come to the,
to the monster.
There's only two of them in 2018
only two of them. One of them,
Washington DC, May 17th and
18th. One of them. San Francisco.
October 17th 18th. That's
it. We're not going to,
what's the name of your
hometown? Columbia. Kentucky.
We're not going to Columbia,
Kentucky for the monster. We couldn't
find it. We couldn't, we couldn't,
your barn wasn't big enough to hold
it in. If we can we expand it? Yeah,
I'll, I'll work on it for next year. Work
on it. Uh, we actually did one in Austin.
If I'd known you at the time, you
would have been there. Awesome.
And let me know if you want to
come to one of these. We're,
but we're not doing it in Columbia,
Kentucky. Uh, we're not doing it in,
what's another random place?
Oh, mile call I Hawaii.
We're not doing it in Hawaii.
If you want to come,
you gotta come to one of those to register
a, by the way, they've all sold out.
We've done four of them.
They've all sold out.
This one's going to sell out to
register extreme ownership.com and we,
okay, we raised the prices once we
hit a certain date. Why do we do that?
Why do we raise the prices once we hit
a certain date to make my money? No,
I'm just kidding.
No,
we actually don't want people to do that
because what were the would reason we
do is we,
we want to incentivize people to register
early so that we can block enough
room, order enough food
plan, plan correctly,
get the venue set up the right way.
So we were trying to make people come
early. So we, it's actually a pen.
We're penalizing you for being slow
and prefer procrastinating. Yes.
Procrastination. You're going
to pay. That's right. Oh,
it's a procrastination penalty. I like
where you're coming from. If you wait,
you pay, I'll take credit for that.
We like people that get after.
Don't put that as one a Jockos.
Okay.
You'll get credit or get credit.
I think you get a percentage because
you were running off my lead and I got a
little cut. All right, so that is that.
And until the roster,
if you have questions or feedback for us.
We are, we are ready to receive
on the interwebs on Twitter,
on Instagram and on Dash Facebook.
He Blah,
echo is an echo.
Charles and I am at Jockowillink and
Dakota is on the interwebs in a big way,
in a big way on Twitter at
Dakota underscore Meyer.
That's how we linked
up by the way via Twitter.
That is, that was like,
I can't believe you responded to me.
It's so cool.
And I'm like I can't believe
you said something to me.
A couple of little kids on Instagram.
Dakota Meyer.
Oh three 17 sniper.
No just o three 17 Dakota Meyer.
That's, that's Instagram on Facebook.
Sergeant Dakota Meyer.
You can just look to go to Meyer and it
pops right up cause you're kind of the
man. You have a podcast,
you have your own podcast.
It's called owning it,
owning it with Dakota Meyer.
Now you kind of took that from my
book. Extreme ownership, no big deal.
I did take a little slice of that.
That's cool.
You Have Dakota meyer.com is
another place. So, like I said,
that's why I said you're all over the
interwebs cause clearly you are all over
the interwebs. You got a youtube channel.
Yeah, I've got a youtube channel cycle.
Uh, it's, it's just Dakota Meyer.
So I've got the youtube channel,
just Dakota Meyer where my podcast goes
up. It's on, on the dash on the dash.
What does that mean? Uh, so, you know,
own the dash comes from a point when to
Ellis had wrote called the Dash. And, uh,
you know,
I,
I felt like I felt like people in America
just needed something to hold onto.
And uh,
you know,
so I always look at what is success
and how do I want to be remembered.
And that's kind of like a
big thing for me. And I, uh,
so Linda Ellis wrote an
appointment, talked about how
like at a funeral, you know,
what man, so to speak, and you
referred to the dates, you know,
on the tombstone from the beginning
or you know, with the, the date he,
the person was born the day he died.
And really those are the two only two
days in your life that you don't make any
decisions or have any control of
and everything else.
What matters that dash in between.
And so how are you going to own your dash?
What is your dash going to look like?
Because you can control that.
You can control what that dash looks like,
how you know how fulfilling it is,
how selfish it is, how
giving it is. I mean,
you control it by your
decisions every single day.
And what do you want your dash to look
like? How do you want to be remembered?
Because it doesn't matter
how much money you have,
it doesn't matter how whatever you did,
the empires you built,
what matters is how you change people's
lives and that's how you're remembered.
And where your true success in
my mind is you'll be defined,
will be what people say
about you at your funeral.
And so that's where it comes
to me is his own the dash.
It's where the idea of it came
from. So own your dash, you know,
and you do public speaking as
well. I do. I do. Public speaking,
I go around and do get in there and talk
to businesses and teams. Yeah. You know,
I come in and talk to businesses,
teams, give my leadership principles of,
you know, what I believe to make success.
You know, listen, I'm simple though. Um,
but you know what, what I
feel like, you know, my life,
I talk about my story and
kind of what happened, me.
And then I come around and I,
what does that mean to me? Right.
What does that mean? Like, you know,
every story without,
uh,
every story or experience that you go
through that doesn't have a meaning
afterwards is a wasted experience. And,
uh, so I talk about that and I just,
you know, did a lot, did a lot
of public speaking, trying to,
I just wanna inspire people.
I'm like, I just, you know, I
just want to, honestly, I just want
to change the world. No big deal.
Just want to change the world. That's
it. No, I just want to change the world.
Awesome man. Awesome. And he did. I, did I
miss anything else? No, I don't think so.
I think that's, I think that's
everything. Yeah. Anything,
any other projects or anything else
everybody needs to know about? No,
no. Listen, I can't, I can't tell you
how much I appreciate you having me on.
We're having some honor to have you
on echo. You got anything else? No,
thank you very much for coming on.
Thank you. Closing thoughts, Dakota. Hi.
You know, listen to this. Uh, I
got a lot out of this podcast.
I got a lot of, uh, you know,
and just hearing your perspective
and you know, uh, I just,
I just want people out there to know that,
you know,
I'm no different than anybody else.
The only difference is opportunities.
It's been put in front of me and um,
you know, I appreciate you having me on.
Well, Maris, it's obviously
an honor to have you on.
Thank you for your thank
you for your service,
both in the Marine Corps and what you
continue to do now to try and help people
and, and just change the world, which
is what you're trying to do now,
which is awesome.
And
it's been a true honor to have you on,
again,
to be sitting across the table from you
and knowing what you've been through and
to see where you are now
is, is awesome. And it's,
it's my honor to be sitting here
and of course,
to all the service men and women on
the battlefields around the world,
doing what must be done to protect us,
thanks to all of you.
And finally,
okay.
To those service members that
made the ultimate sacrifice,
who gave the last full measure for us.
Thank you.
May you rest and peace
and no without question
that we will never forget.
And until next time,
this is Dakota Meyer and deco and Jocko
out.