This is Jocko podcast number
one 85 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
You get one shot
and that's it.
And in the end you're
going into the ground.
Okay.
Regardless of what you believe the
afterlife consists of or what it doesn't
consist of as far as what you
get to hold on to once you leave.
Here is nothing.
And I implore people all the time,
okay.
To make it count.
Cause this is it. This is the finals.
There are no re dues.
You can't hit the rewind
button. And even worse,
you can't even hit the pause button.
There's no way you can stop
the clock from ticking.
Okay?
No possible way the countdown is on
and the days are finite.
Do you only get so many?
Okay.
And then it's over.
So until them make them count,
make all of them count.
And on the podcast today, I
have a guest, a fellow frogman,
whom to the best of my knowledge is
doing his best to make his days count.
His name is Mitch Aggie, R
and we just met each other.
But like I said, he's a frogman. He
likes Jujitsu. He likes to get after it.
So my guess is we should have some
things to talk about. So Mitch,
welcome to the podcast. Thanks for
having me. Good. Good to meet you. Yeah.
Good to meet you as well. 10 minutes
ago. Yup. Picked you up at the airport.
I think we are linked up some
way on social media. Correct.
And you are in the EO doing some
training and so here you are. Cool.
Where'd you grow up?
I grew up in Virginia Beach and then uh,
was there till about 11,
then moved to Maryland
and uh, live with my dad.
Was there till about 16 and
drew up in Virginia Beach.
Parents in the military. Yup. My
Mom and dad were both in the navy,
both in the Noun. That's
right. Shaq. And uh,
my mom was an o s and my dad was a
combat camera man with a Dev group.
Okay. Right on. And, and so then you
were there until you said you were 11?
Yeah, it was in no Virginia
Beach till I was 11.
They were divorced and my dad had gotten
out of the navy and was living up in
Maryland working at the
Aberdeen proving ground. Okay.
And doing high speed photography
there and, uh, you know,
filming tank rounds and all kinds of
cool explosives and stuff like that.
And he had like a wicked cool job he had
before. It was cool. Wicked cool. Jack.
And, uh, so I went up there and lived
with him for awhile and then, uh,
around 16, um, moved
up to Ohio. My mom had,
uh, moved up to Ohio. My stepdad
was also in the navy and, um,
he had gotten out and they'd started a
business up in Ohio and I went and lived
with her up there and, uh,
finished out high school in Ohio.
Um, 10th or, yeah, 10, 11,
12th grade and then joined the
navy from there. What, what uh,
what was high school like? What sports
were you playing? I was playing football,
basketball, Lacrosse, and
uh, yeah, that was it.
Were you good? Were you
a good athlete? I was a,
a good athlete and I was
also into, uh, some, uh,
sports that weren't at
our school. I was on, uh,
arm wrestling team or run
on Dad Dodge ball team,
like a traveling dodgeball team,
traveling dodge ball team. It was,
it was by far my favorite. Wow. Like how,
how many games would you play
in dodgeball in a day? No,
in like a season. What's the season?
The dodge ball season? Well, you know,
there's practice obviously and
uh, if you'd take it serious,
like we did a, we, we practice like
three times a week and then we, we would,
uh, travel on the weekends for
tournaments. What balls do you use?
Uh, we would some, some
leagues are different. Um,
but mainly it's those kick balls
and you see red rubber ones.
Yeah. How many people are on the
team, each side? Um, there was,
it was like six or seven
people per team or,
and then we had like a
couple substitutes, you know,
in case there was injuries, injuries,
you know, just like any other sport, man,
you had your first string
starters and then you,
but you didn't wrestle. I
did not wrestle. I didn't,
you didn't restaurant that light it
into run cross country. I didn't swim.
I didn't do anything in
high school that would, uh,
be useful in my ongoing
adventures. Well, football,
basketball, I mean, you're
becoming an athlete.
You're coordinating your treasure. Like
just in general, I would say, well,
I would say that competition
mindset, you know, um,
that and just, yeah, being
an athlete overall, uh,
that was always something that was
just ingrained in me. You know,
my, both my mom and dad,
they were really competitive,
like always had us in sports growing
up, my brother and I, and um,
you know, I always loved the competition
side of things, you know, and I,
I actually like hate working out
still to this day. Like, I just,
I don't really enjoy it,
but if there's some sort of comp
competition involved in it or you know,
competitiveness, that's, that's
what I really like. True work.
So you get done with high school year
and you, what makes you join the navy?
Um, honestly I was, I was just bored. Uh,
I was living in Ohio and it
sucked there and, uh, the,
I there was just nothing
there that I wanted.
How long after you graduated high school
did you join the navy? A couple months.
Did you,
did you go in the dye fair program to be
in the teams or did you just want to be
in just in the navy?
No, I originally, um, I mean, it, it,
it wasn't planned out at all. Uh, I
was, I was working three different jobs.
Uh, I was a, uh, um, a Roofer,
which I really, really loved.
That was, that was a great
job. And, um, I worked at my,
my parents, like they owned a deli
slash convenience store kind of thing.
I worked there and I was, um,
a lifeguard at Kalahari and I,
and I was a surf instructor.
And you said Kalahari. It's an India.
It's the world's largest indoor water
park. And they have waves there. Yeah.
They have a flow rider, like a
couple flow rider machines. Oh,
the thing that you've seen
[inaudible] plastic. Yeah, yeah, Yup.
Creates an artificial
wave. So I would, uh,
I was on the competition team and I
would like give people lessons on how to
right that thing.
So between that and dodge ball,
we were kind of dialed in first.
First of action. That's a
good setup. So you recommend,
if someone wants to get a
career special operations,
they focus on dodge ball and
arm wrestling and surfing.
Awesome formula for success.
Formula for success. And so you're,
you're, you're doing
these jobs and you're,
you're not having a good
time with yeah, I ever,
oh, I was, you know, I'm not
a very good, uh, uh, studious,
uh, student in high school. Um, you know,
high school is more of like
a socialization for me. Like,
I really enjoyed going there to
socialize. I really enjoyed, you know,
making friends and I liked sports and, uh,
and I was always, I always loved
working and making money, you know,
like school is just kind of a, in
the way I had kind of, you know,
at the time I just had zero interest
in any sort of classwork whatsoever.
And, um, I don't even understand how I,
somehow I had graduated and, um, then,
you know, I was like, yeah, I'm
definitely gonna do something in life.
I don't know what I'm, I'm assuming
it'll be good though, you know,
I just don't know what it is. And, and
my teachers were kind of in that same,
uh, mindset. They're, you know, half
of them were just like, man, they're,
you're hopeless. Like there's, you're
just going to work at Burger King,
whatever. And then the other
half were just like, yeah,
you're going to do something great. It's
definitely not going to be in school,
you know, who knows what it is. And
I was just kind of in that, you know,
glass half full. Uh, I was
thinking the same thing. And, uh,
I didn't know what it was.
Honestly, like I said,
I was roofing and I
really loved, uh, roofing,
but you know, I was making
minimal money and, um,
I knew that that wasn't going
to be it. So I was in the area.
I knew that nothing around the
area interested me, you know,
there was nothing that I wanted to
pursue around there. I was young,
I was 18, you know, my,
my mom and dad were both and my
stepdad where we're all in the navy at,
at points in their life. And you know,
had talked about the
benefits of the military.
My Dad was always trying to get me to
go in the military and I just wasn't
interested at all. And um, yeah,
that was never really even a
consideration until quite literally,
like I was just bored.
And the recruiter happened to walk
in and catch me and it was like, Hey,
you want to join the navy? And I was
like, sure, why not? And uh, and uh,
I was, at first I was going to
do, um, mastered arms. Like,
I was like, Oh, you know, I've always,
I've always had like a kind
of respect for police. Um,
my grandfather was a police officer,
my uncle's still a police officer and
that was something that I felt like,
you know, it was a courageous
job and, and uh, a helpful,
useful one or whatever, you
know? And I figured that I could,
I've always been real protective as well,
so like I figured that job would
kind of maybe be fitting for me.
Um, so he, he had asked me, you know,
hey, yeah, you want to join the navy?
And I was like, okay. Then I thought
I'll, I'll go that route. And a,
he was like, well, you look like
you're in good shape, do you want to,
you want to be a seal? And I was
like, ah, this, there's a sneaky guys.
You know, the, the, the only
thing I knew about seals was, uh,
from that, where the,
where the there on the
beach or it's a scene on,
it's on the beach and the clouds
roll over the moon and then they,
they pass and there's footprints. Yeah.
And so that's all I knew about
navy seals and, and I was like, oh,
this guy's [inaudible] this was 2007.
So you're watching the wars are
going on all through high school.
You're seeing all that stuff take place.
Nine 11 happened when I
was in seventh grade. Yeah.
You were probably boots on ground or
something on there. Well, I mean I was,
I was um,
yeah I had been in for like 11 years at
that point because I joined in 90 so I
was born in 89. Yeah. So I'm,
I'm a little bit older
than you are apparently.
Yeah. So did you not,
did you realize like, um,
so this was your first kind of connection
because for me, when I was growing up,
like every time some kind
of war event happened,
I was all bummed out that I wasn't there
cause I was too young and that's just
the way I was. I was always thinking about
that. I was always into the military.
But you were kind of like not,
I was the total opposite. Like I wanted
nothing to do with, with the military.
I wanted nothing to do with like
I'd never even thought about it. Um,
my dad was just, you know,
he was in and he was a combat cameraman
with Dev groups. Obviously he was,
you know, really involved
with, with it. And uh,
anytime he would try and talk to me about,
I'm just like, I'm not interested in,
I'm not gonna join the fucking
military. What flipped the switch?
She was mega boredom. Yeah.
Just, I just, you know,
I was like, well worst case
scenario, I know. I don't know.
I'm in for, in the navy for four years.
I'll go see the world a little bit.
I'll, you know,
gain some life experience and worst case
I get out and I'm fucking 22 like who
cares? I'm not going to college. I
know that, you know, high school was,
I barely made it through that and just
not, cause I'm stupid just cause I just,
man wasn't your seeing Oh my God,
I'd rather do hell week 10 times in
a row than write an essay, you know?
So you get in the navy
and do you prepare at all?
Like four?
I had never run like further than
a mile and like I all my sprint,
all my sports stuff was all sprinting.
I mean those dodge balls are only,
you know, dodge ball courts are small.
Yeah, they're cool. They're short.
So it was just, I was always
a really fast sprinter and uh,
that was kind of all I really cared
about. I, I didn't even, I was also,
I also like now looking back how stupid
I was and just how dumb you are at 18
like you think you really like know
when you're 18 you really like,
you're like man, you know, you look back
at when you're 10 and are like, man,
I know so much now.
I just compared to my seven year old self
compared to compared to my eight year
old self. Like I didn't even know what
I was doing. Now I'm a, I'm a man,
you know, I know what life's
about. But at that point,
obviously now I'm 30 looking back at
that, I'm just like, man, you're so dumb.
But I really was and I'm just really
inexperienced with life. I had never,
like I said, run really
further than a mile. Um,
I didn't even understand like that
people did that I had heard about like
marathons and stuff.
But, um, I remember when,
you know, when,
when I had heard that I had to run
like a mile and a half for the pst,
I was like, what in the
fuck? Like why Wa and then,
and then like I told my dad
that I signed up for the,
the seal teams and I was like, yeah, I'm
going to be a seal. And he's just like,
you have no idea what
you just signed up for.
I didn't even know I had to
go to buds. And then, uh,
so he, he, I was just like,
yeah, I'm going to be a seal.
What's wrong with that? And He, uh,
he bought me the, the two, three,
four documentary and we
sat down and watched that.
And I remember like, just watching the,
the four mile timed run. And
I was just thinking like,
is that even possible? Like,
do people really do that?
And I was just thinking like,
Jesus Christ, like this is,
I'm going to have to do all
of this shit. Oh my God,
I better start running. I'm
about to start training.
So did you start running and training?
Yeah, I mean I went out and uh,
you know, actually back up before
I even saw that the first, um,
the first introduction I had to buds was,
or navy seals in general once I signed
the, like a signed up and I was like,
all right, I'm going to be a navy
seal. I better do some research.
So went out and got navy seals with
Charlie Sheen and I watched that and that
was my very first introduction
to what navy seals were.
And I was just like, man, it looks
pretty intense. Pretty cool though.
And uh, you know, in the
scene, the scene in that movie,
they say it's buds,
but it's obviously not cause it's
like in the woods and they're like,
there's like grenades
going off and they're like,
they're like a army crawling under
barbed wire. And he's like, this is buds.
You know, like it was just like
this crazy scene or whatever.
And I was just thinking like,
damn, I gotta go through all that.
All right and better.
So I went out and bought some fucking
Cammo pants and bought some boots,
like just leather boots and
I'm there and I went for a run,
uh, down my street. And I remember it
was like a mile or I did, I was like,
I have to run a mile and a half, so
I'm going to see how this goes. And I,
and I went and got those
pants and got suited up
and I was just thinking like, Oh
man, this is going to be hard. But,
and then, then, then my dad got the,
uh, the two, three, four documentary in,
and then that was just like, oh, okay.
I really just have no fucking
idea when I just signed up for.
And I was just thinking like,
damn, that looks really hard.
But I already told everyone
that I was going to do this.
And I was just kind of that, you know,
that's one good thing about being 18
and you're just young and dumb and
stubborn. And you know,
luckily I used the, the,
the good of that to get through I guess.
So you get, I was gonna say, you know,
my, my, my, my, a dive motivator
was Mike Nos. Do you know him?
Yes, I know who it is. I
don't know personally. Um,
well he's an old Vietnam
frogman a plank owner at,
at a damn neck. And he,
he came in and he's a tall guy and
he walks with like a kind of a,
a big limp cause he had like a hip
replacement. He's still swims like a fish.
And uh,
he actually taught me how to do the
sidestroke the day before my pst.
So it was like pretty steep learning.
Yeah, that's, that is,
I always tell people I'm not to make
decisions when they're super emotional and
so I'm going to start adding, don't make
decisions when you're super just bored.
Yeah. You might end up at
buds. So you show up there,
you show up the buds and you must've,
you know, obviously you made it through.
Was there any, what was your,
what was tough for you in buds?
Running? Running was definitely, uh,
I mean obviously that's like
what you do the most of. And, um,
man, it was just,
I went from no running
ever to running my ass off,
just everywhere. And, uh,
and those timed runs, man,
I was just fucking having a
lot of conversations with,
with Jesus and those
runs and just, you know,
giving it everything I fucking had
just to make the cutoff on those,
on those runs. And then,
and then I eventually,
I became like a pretty good runner
just from doing it. And, uh,
um, but yeah, I was, I was for sure
captain of the Goon Squad and, uh,
but luckily all those fucking dodgeball
sprints were paying off and the goon
squad, so it was, it was
nice, uh, in the goon squad,
I felt comfortable. Did you get rolled
for anything? Yeah, I got rolled. Um, uh,
for, uh, some I had real bad shin
splints from, from loading from the,
the lack of running previous and
uh, but other, you know, got rolled,
dealt with that. And like I said,
I picked up like from running,
so I just got good at
it and I was like young,
so adapted well I guess.
Yeah, it's, it pays to be
young in buds in my opinion.
Yeah. Well I'm a physical
perspective. Physical, yeah, for sure.
With like dealing with the
overuse injuries. I mean,
cause you're definitely gonna just,
they're obviously just gonna fucking
ream your ass and then you have to get up
and go.
Yeah, I was talking to, uh,
one of the medical guys there who
came from like a sports environment,
like the, I think the NFL. Who's
he? The, I think it was the NFL.
And do you remember the, uh, I think
it's Patella for moral syndrome.
Did you ever know anyone
that got that there? Anyways,
there's a bunch of people that get this,
this, this patellofemoral syndrome,
you know, there. And he said, yeah,
at Buds I would see 10 cases a
week of Patella memorial syndrome.
It's where your Patella like rubs
against your, your femur or something.
And he said in the NFL you'd see
like one of these every year,
maybe one a year.
And so these guys that would
come to buds for from a physical,
what was the athletic trainer perspective
would learn so much because they're
just getting these mat.
These bodies are just going
through abuse like no other bodies.
And so they see all those,
all these common injuries
that you get to your knees,
your uh, your shoulders, your
back like that. You go to buds.
As an athletic trainer, you learn.
And as a doctor you learn so much about
how to deal with these things because
you see 10 times more than you would
or more than you would anywhere else.
I believe that. But I've also
talked to people who say like,
I was young to going through buds 18.
And so you get the, um, you get the,
you get the mind of, Hey, I've just do
whatever they tell me to do, you know,
but there's some people that say they
have told me they didn't think they were
mature enough at 18 or
19 to go through buds.
Um, I for sure was not,
I don't want to say I wasn't mature enough
to go through because obviously I did
and I made it through
however you say like what,
or ask like what my biggest struggle at
Bud's was, was definitely my maturity.
I mean physically, like physically
it was running, like, just, uh,
I was never a long distance
runner, obviously. Um, sprinting,
I was fast as fuck sprinting and I was
really strong on the log and like the
boats, the boats on heads was
extremely surprising to me. I like,
I remember seeing it on the
videos and thinking like, okay,
that's kind of weird. Like why are they
running around boats on their heads?
Like, and then, uh, I didn't think it
was going to be painful because they're,
they're like inflatable, the
rubber boats or whatever.
And when they put the thing on your
head, I was just like, Jesus Christ,
this thing is smashing my fucking neck.
Did the instructors jump around in the
boats when you went because they stopped
doing it at some point? Yeah,
they would. Uh, like some of the
little guys would like jump in,
hang on the handles and, and shit like
that when, when you're riding. But yeah,
he definitely knew when they were on the
boats cause they got a lot heavier. But
um, what they would do and I went
through and they stopped doing this,
which is a good thing they would,
they would be like the boats would be
lined up and we'd have them in head.
Carey and the instructors would be in
like boat one and then they would just
jumped into boat two and
then jump into boat three.
And I remember hearing when they would
did that to me a couple of the times that
they did it to me. I heard
like this deep kind of
[inaudible] inside my neck.
And I remember thinking this
is probably not good. And they,
they stopped doing it thankfully.
Cause that's not healthy.
So you actually used to be like
six to, I dunno if I got shorter,
but I definitely took some, took some
damage, took some damage for sure.
Yeah, that was that.
The boats on heads was probably the most
surprising thing to me of how like I
just wasn't expecting it to be that
bad. And uh, but like the log PT,
you know, I was always,
I actually really enjoyed the log PT
I think probably because from roofing,
you know,
I was always carrying those 80 pound
bundles of shingles up the ladder.
And then like I was the
young guy on the crew,
so I was a shingle bitch or three
years and you know, everyone,
everyone on my crew is in their
forties. So they, you know,
I was the 15 year old when I came
on the crew and just a young,
strong kid. They,
they took full advantage of it and just
wherever they needed shingles on the
roof, that's where I hauled them up.
And, uh, so I was used to carrying,
you know, that the heavy load and stuff
I didn't, like I said, I feel strong.
I felt really good on that
stuff and mentally I was like,
um,
I just was super competitive and that's
what really got me through Bud's was,
was just that sheer competitiveness.
The maturity level. Where
could that have tripped you up?
Were you like doing dumb stuff
on the weekends where you
no, not really. Um,
cause I mean I wasn't even old enough to
go drink or anything like that, so, uh,
it was more just kind of not understanding
well one like I was different.
I was different than most people
there because like you said,
you wanted to be in the military your
whole life and like you wanted to be a CLM
assuming. Did you?
Yeah. I mean as soon as I kind of figured
out what the seal teams were. Yeah.
Yeah. So like, like that
and like just how you are,
you're very disciplined,
you're very, you know,
you're very militant I would
say. And I would concur.
I was like more of like a wild,
like free spirit kind of,
you know, kid growing up.
And uh, and I,
I was not military at all and so, and,
and I also like getting through bootcamp
was difficult for me because of that as
well, you know, just like,
I'm like, why, why my,
my question was like, why do
we have to [inaudible] we're,
we're literally spent all day
undoing our bed and, and remaking it.
I was like, I, what the fuck
is the point of this? Like,
it's such a waste of time and you know,
obviously it's all for a
reason than design, but I just,
I couldn't wrap my head around it so that
just lack of military bearing and um,
lack of maturity and understanding,
like why things are the
way they are. And you know,
the whole military structure just, you
just do it and you don't questions,
stuff like that. You know,
that was probably my biggest
hang up, you know, just,
I was different than everyone. I
was young, I was, I don't know,
I didn't want to be a seal
my whole life. You know,
some of these people like this is like
their dream and they've been training for
it for whatever.
And I'm just Kinda here showing up and
guys are quitting and, and I'm not.
And you know,
and like physically I was doing like
a lot better than some guys who,
like I said, it was kind of just like,
man, I'm just here, whatever, doing this.
And other guys, it's like,
this is everything to me and you know,
so it's like I track,
so you get done with buds and you
show up and where'd you go? Team 10,
team 10 know, right on. And then how
was that checking into team 10? Um,
it was, it was cool, but by that
point, you know, I'd kind of like, uh,
obviously I was like, all right, I'm
a seal now. And I had been in the,
in the pipeline for a while and kind
of getting in the flow of things in the
military and, and stuff
like that. But, uh, yeah,
I was super excited to
check into team 10. Um,
and I originally I was going
to go to team five and then my,
I told my family, you know,
that I got orders to five and they were
all kind of bummed out cause they want
it, they're all on the east coast. And,
um, they were like, Oh man, you know,
we were hoping you'd come to the
east coast. And I was like, Eh, okay,
I'll go to the east coast.
And I thought it was like,
kind of cool too because it felt like, uh,
like a new, like a new chapter
because like, you know,
the seal team one, three and five are,
and seven are right by the buds
compound. So it was like, you know,
I'd been there and been in the scene for
the last two years or whatever it was.
And it was, it was cool.
It felt cool to like go across the
country and like check into a team and,
you know, I just felt like, like,
this is it, this is a real deal.
So that was super cool.
I felt, felt good. Um,
my trip was awesome.
And, uh, what was your,
what was your job in your first
platoon? I was a heavy gunner for sure.
A Dub. A knuckle dragger yeah,
that's a classic new guy. Strong new guy.
Guess what gives him a pig?
Your big strong new guy got
something for you. And I loved it.
I embraced it. I didn't think it
was like a bad thing, you know?
What year is this now? 2009.
Okay, so you yeah, you went straight
to the, to the mark. 48. No,
end the 60 for you.
[inaudible] that's, that's, that's
nice. Yeah. We shot sixties and stuff,
but now like act fam, shoot
with sixties or something. Yeah.
And there was sixties on like, uh,
humvees and stuff like that and
going through a vehicle stuff.
So there were still a little
bit of transition taking place.
So you're a pig gunner, your first
platoon. How was your first workup?
It was awesome. Uh, it's
definitely a good time. Uh, Gotcha.
What surprised you about like going
through workup, being in a seal platoon,
what were, what was different
than what you thought it was?
What was different from how
it was for Charlie Sheen.
Okay.
You know, it was, it was
a lot like the movie.
I'm just kidding. It was, it
was, it was great, man. I, I,
I thought it was a lot of fun.
Um, we got to travel, travel,
travel the country. That was the cool
thing too about the east coast. Um,
the training sites were kind of all
over all over versus the west coast.
It was kind of like the same song
and dance like Nyland and, and uh,
let's the other one. Um, you know
what I'm saying? Like in the training,
the trainings, like all the same sites.
And uh, so going into the east coast,
I got to see a bunch of new
places and that was cool to me,
just kind of seeing
the world. Um, and the,
the Brotherhood of like
being in the troops and,
and stuff and you're, you're rolling
around as a team. I thought that,
that was really cool. Um,
was there anything that was more
challenging? Like, you know,
cause I'm new guys, they have a hard time
and their first platoon with whatever,
with land warfare, they
have a hard time with CQC.
They'll have a hard time
with, you know, whatever.
Sometimes it's like not
easy sometimes. You know,
you get a guy that can't
dive very well and whatever.
Was there anything that was any skill
set that was hard for you or did you
pretty much, which is,
I would say most guys coming out of
buds and SQT like most of them are fine.
Like most of them get, get they, they
can, they pick things up pretty quick.
You know, they made it
through all that crap.
They made it through SQT where you're
getting screened. Right. Again.
So most of the time, but still, you'd
still get guys showing up a platoon that,
you know,
they wouldn't be comfortable with this
or they wouldn't be great at that.
Was there anything that was tough for you?
Uh, I would say like
everything was, was tough. I,
I wasn't, I wasn't a master at
anything other than my pig, you know,
and, uh, so everything was, was,
was somewhat challenging for me,
but I also didn't really
struggle with anything too,
too much other than like my
maturity, like that, you know, I was,
I had checked into a seal team before
I could even go into a bar, you know,
and I didn't go to college or
anything like that, so I was,
I was a 20 year old at a
seal team, you know. Um,
so yes, I had been through a lot of,
as far as like buds and Sgt. And you know,
that kind of forces you to grow up, um,
to an extent, but seals
like to party too. And, uh,
and I kind of,
that was probably my biggest challenge
was just my maturity and just kinda
learning when to, to lock on and,
and you know, when it was
time to like chill out.
Did you ever get caught? Did you ever
get in trouble? Did he ever get arrested?
Uh, I did get arrested and not in my new
guy platoon. I got arrested in my, uh,
and when I was in my second platoon, uh,
got into a bar fight,
um, this, these guys,
it was actually three, three dudes, uh,
had just started mouth and off
to one of my platoon members,
wife. It was him and I, and uh,
my girlfriend at the time and his
girlfriend at the time now or wife and uh,
we are coming out of the bar and they
just had had a couple of drinks and they
had come over and said some disrespectful
shit to them and you know, and I,
I just was feeling froggy
a little bit and, and uh,
didn't let it slide and ended up whooping
their ass and beat up three people
outside of a bar and got arrested. But,
but your first platoon, you,
you manage to keep your nose clean or
at least as far as the actual law go,
the actual law enforcement goes
tremble. And then where was that?
So you did your workup.
Where did you guys go on deployment
to your first deployment? Afghanistan.
And when you were going to
Afghanistan, where you going?
Did you go as a whole
troop to Afghanistan?
Uh, Yep. Yeah, I'll, I'll, three of
our a platoons went. Yeah, it was a,
it was kind of an interesting,
um, thing because, uh,
it was in 2011 and, uh, I dunno if you,
you said you got out in
2010. Well, yeah, there was,
I'm sure you'd heard about they, uh,
they wanted us to somehow get
on the army schedule and uh,
so it was us and team
seven [inaudible] and um,
we ended up basically doing
two deployments back to
back and got sinked up with
the army or something like that. I don't
know. I don't know all the, all the,
yeah.
You know, Mumbo jumbo that actually took
place, but or why, why we did it. But,
uh, they told us kind of right before,
it was like two months before we left,
they were like, Hey, I'm just kidding.
You guys are going to go to Afghanistan
and we're going to need you to stay
there for basically a year. And
we're like, oh shit. Okay. So, uh,
we went there and, uh, it was,
it was an interesting deployment
for sure because my platoon,
um,
we were the furthest outposts from
any major base in Afghanistan.
And, uh, you know,
we're basically rough in it the whole
time we were out there.
Did you guys take over at
outpost somewhere or did
you guys establish one? Uh,
we took one over that had just been this
established like literally a couple
months ago, you know, so there was,
there was nothing there. We were sleeping
in tents still, um, no running water,
no, no, nothing like that. And then, um,
I think around month seven
or eight of our deployment,
we packed up and went 15
miles north and set up a new,
uh, sites.
So it was literally just fucking
rough in it the whole time.
Uh, you know, airdrop
and our food in and um,
no running water the whole time.
And what, what type of ops were you doing?
Um, we were, we were doing
all kinds of stuff. Uh,
and I was lucky enough to kind of, we
got to, they shifted our guys around too.
So like we got to all it
kind of experience different
things cause we all had a
different kind of mission
set and different,
we're on all three of our platoons were
in different areas of Afghanistan. So,
um, I got to kind of
do a lot of everything.
So where are you guys going
out on patrol from your,
from your Ford Operating Base. Was
that, yeah. And yeah, pretty much daily.
And you were, uh, interacting with the
local populous type thing. Yep. Yep.
Try to establish relationships.
Yeah. I only did that for a little
while. That was a really dumb,
you don't because you didn't
feel like you made any progress,
didn't make any connections.
Yeah, I mean, in my opinion, I
just thought it was like kind of a,
a waste of time. And um, I just,
I just felt like we could have been doing
a lot more stuff or better stuff with
our time and training and all that.
And it was just like a super
dangerous area to be in.
You know, it was in a Hellman and
we basically just lived in a fucking
minefield, you know? And it was just
[inaudible] everywhere, just as
a constant threat. So, you know,
and we were going on these long
patrols every day and, and uh,
and all these,
all these ops we were doing and hitting
these villages that were just riddled
with idds everywhere and
you know, getting contacted,
you know, on your basically just stick
out like a sore thumb there, you know.
So, uh, I mean, you know
how it is overseas. I,
I didn't feel real
comfortable with that. Like,
and it sucked. Uh, being in a
minefield, like just every step,
just please don't blow up. Please
don't blow up. Please don't blow up.
Please don't blow up, you know,
for a year. Yeah. Did you guys,
did you guys hit any
ids? Uh, yeah. Yeah, we,
we encountered a couple ideas and um,
so shitty. Yeah. And that the enemy,
did you have a feel for
who was bad and who was
good when you'd go out?
No, definitely not. Um, there was, I mean,
cause like literally there was,
there was a times where, you know,
we'd be in the village fucking
shaking hands with people and then,
you know, on the way out, get contacted,
getting a firefight and then
fucking go back and look and, oh,
it's the same guys that we were just
shaking hands with it or fucking dead.
Yeah. Um, so it was,
it was hard to,
okay,
it,
it was really weird to like get rev
ramped up and everything as he's like,
you get in this mindset, this
warrior mindset, you know,
that you're going to war and you're going
to this fucking land where everyone,
everyone is, you know, your enemy and
blah, blah, blah. And then it's like, oh,
just kidding. Let's, let's try to help
some of these people or whatever and,
and the, you know, the good and
use like, okay, yeah, I want to,
I want to help people and, and stuff
like that and, and do what I can, um,
to help these people out.
And then if they're getting
like bullied essentially by the,
by the Taliban or whatever,
like that's not cool. But
I just felt like it was,
it was really weird too to be there and
go there with that mindset and then have
to fucking like try to help people.
And then when you tried to help people,
they don't want your help and you know,
and they fucking shoot at you and,
and shit like that. So it's like,
and then you're expected to like go out
and try and help these people again and
it's, I dunno, it was just
like a weird, weird dynamic.
And would you go,
when you said you would move and
positions where you going from,
like would you like switch platoons and
go to a different operating base? Yeah.
And then you'd spend some time there with
them and then do operations with them
and then after a little while and
go to a different one as well. Yeah.
Yeah. We, we rotated our guy, all of
our guys just to, so we can all get,
you know, experience doing other things,
like working with the commandos or,
you know, uh, training,
the fit, training fit and,
um, or doing the VSO stuff.
And yeah, it was cool. I,
I enjoyed that just cause it broke
up the monotony of every day,
you know, going on patrols,
doing the same things,
seeing the same places or whatever
and dealing with the same threats. Uh,
it just, it keeps you kind of from
getting complacent, I felt like,
so for the 11 month or, yeah. So I,
I was definitely happy to move and,
and do new things and work
in like, and it was cool too,
because on the base that
we were at in Afghanistan,
it was literally like a hundred
yards by a hundred yards.
That was your, that was like our camp.
It was like being in prison, you know,
but worse like, cause
we're getting shot at too.
And like if you,
when you go outside to go get your
fucking food that they airdrop in,
you know, you're, you're
worried about stepping on ids.
Like we found IUD is literally right
outside of our compound, you know.
So it was a constant
threat always. And uh,
and like I said, like going to get our
air dry. It was just a lot of work to,
because not only it was like
we were sealed bees, you know,
we had to like filled our,
we had to like build our camp and also
like all the stuff that came with that,
like going and getting
our, our, uh, supplies,
I would airdrop in and, and
being out there, you know,
you only get ring routes and, and stuff.
You only get airdrops every
once in awhile. And uh, so when,
when shit would come in, it was
like all hands go work on this.
And then also you got to prep
your shit and get ready for the,
the op tonight or tomorrow
or whatever. And um,
and I remember just,
I remember I have a video of one of
our big airdrops coming in and uh,
you just see like three or four
pallets just burn in, just explode.
And you know,
it's like always like all the
water bottle pallets are fine,
but it's that one with like the
goodies, you know, it's like, Oh man,
you know,
that's the one that burned in and it
just fucking hits the ground explodes.
And you see like all the
repeats or something, you know,
something that people were looking forward
to just exploding. You're just like,
fuck, I dunno, I just accepted
that this was my life,
so whatever. I wasn't, I wasn't
thinking about the time too much.
And then, um, I just, you
get into a rhythm, you know,
and we got to, we got to go home for
rnr. That was cool. Took a little break,
but it was like bittersweet, you know,
go home for fucking two weeks and like,
oh,
I've just been playing in this minefield
where everyone's trying to kill me for
the last six months and come home
for two weeks and like to normalcy.
And you're just like, you know,
literally just fly straight from there,
no decompression or anything.
And then now you're back in normal
society with your family and,
and by the way, you're
leaving in 11 days to go back.
Yeah. And then don't get comfortable
because we're going right back over there.
So that was like, kind of like,
it was bittersweet and, uh,
got back over there. But that was cool
too, cause it was like, all right,
I'm fucking halfway through.
Like it's downhill now, you know,
so that it kind of definitely
fired me up to, to finish out.
But then, uh, towards the end and
we were there for all four seasons,
so we saw literally all
four seasons is interesting.
And um, by the end of it,
by the end of it, uh,
I remember when the ring route
came to pick me up to go out.
Uh, I remember flying away from,
from the base that we were at and just
thinking like, I, I felt kind of sad,
like,
like almost like when you move away from
somewhere and like I've moved my whole
life, I've moved around a
lot, so I was like, damn,
like this has been my home for the last
year. You know, I'm kind of bummed to,
to leave, but fuck this place.
I can't wait to go home.
Yeah, I got, I got kind of lucky because
I had been in the navy for awhile when,
when I deployed to Iraq and especially
my second deployment to Iraq where I was
in Ramadi. And, and like I, I, you know,
sometimes people will say,
oh, I look back and I,
I wish I would have
appreciated it more. You know,
people say that about certain parts of
their life. I don't have that at all.
Like I 100% appreciated every single
day I was there. I was like, this is,
this is the best part of
my whole life is right,
is what's happening today
right now. You know?
So I got kind of lucky in
the fact that, you know,
even talking to the guys that were new
guys on, on a, that deployment to Ramadi,
they, they just kind of, they were like,
from then on they'd be saying, damn,
you know, I thought that's what every
deployment was going to be like.
And it was, and it was, they just
didn't have that same perspective of,
hey man, this is like this target
rich environment where we're getting,
do what everyone's dreamed of doing their
whole life and you're going to do it
all the time. That
doesn't happen. You know,
it doesn't happen like that
usually, you know, it's hard.
And so I was pretty lucky in the fact
that I, I was, I could appreciate it.
Yeah. I know as far as the work,
like I was as far as like,
like being a seal and working there
like that, that was awesome, you know,
and I was, uh, you know,
one of the biggest,
like I say, concerns I had or, or not,
or even not concern was just like
a question to myself was, you know,
what would, how am I actually
going to react and combat,
you know what I mean? Cause everyone,
everyone likes to think that
they're ideally, you know, in a,
in a situation of shit popped off, you
know, I'll be, I'll be the guy who will,
you know, hold them, have my shit
together and be that, you know,
the rock or whatever, you know what
I mean? And, uh, some people crumble,
you know,
and I saw that as a seal like that,
that was kind of my, I was always
a realist, you know, it was like,
I've never been shot at, I've never
been in a gunfight or whatever. So,
um, I definitely, you know, I, I,
I feel like I'm not a coward and I
feel like I would step up and do,
do what I gotta do and perform. I feel
like that, but I don't know it for sure.
You know what I mean?
And, um, so that was,
that was definitely when it happened
in a, in a, you know, an I did, I,
I stepped up and, and
felt very pleased with,
with how that all went down and all the
combat and everything that I had been
involved with. Like
that was definitely, um,
rewarding to me, you know, like
as a seal and, and as a man just,
and as a warrior, just like,
okay, like I felt legit, you know,
I felt like fulfilled in
that sense. Um, so the work,
the work was really good,
but just as far as being
in that environment, like,
uh, the [inaudible] was really
like the IUD in the fucking, like,
invisible enemy was kind
of, um, discouraging,
you know, it was like,
it felt like we just had so much risk,
you know, for not a whole
lot of reward. And, uh, like,
which is different. Like I would say, oh,
I feel like in like Ramadi
was like a different way,
different environment. Um, but yeah,
yeah, no, that's, that's the, that's the
way in surgeons are supposed to fight,
right? You're not supposed to see them.
They're just supposed to pick away
at you the death of a thousand cuts,
you know, indirect fire ids and snipers.
And they don't want you to ever see
him. And, and that's what they want.
And just to slowly pick away because
they don't care about human life.
They don't value human life.
And here we are, you know,
every time we lose someone,
it's a, it's a tragedy.
And they don't care if they lose guys
or not. They don't, they don't care.
They don't care if the civilians get
killed, don't care about any of that.
And so that's why they have,
that's why they have an
advantage in those situations.
A psychological advantages. Hey,
we, we don't care if you kill us.
And by the way,
we know you care about your people and
so we're going to pick away and you're,
hopefully you're never going
to see us and we don't care.
We're going to blow you
up and we don't care.
Yeah. That was, I mean, that
was pretty apparent. I mean, uh,
cause a lot of the IED set
went off where, you know,
local villagers stepping on them
triggered by civilian, you know, and, uh,
and that, that just happened all
the, all the damn time. And, uh,
and we would, we would help
them, you know, we would,
we would aid the wounded and stuff like
that and they would like get pissed at
us and we're like, we didn't plant that
shit, you know, like get mad at them,
not us.
Yeah. There's that, that
insurgencies thing is,
but yeah. And like, you
know, do worth, it was,
it was just super
frustrating to me. Like, uh,
okay.
It was super frustrating to me.
Okay.
Dealing with like the politics
involved with war and um,
you know,
I felt like we absolutely could have
done things to give us more of an
advantage,
but it seemed like they were more
concerned with the politics and shit like
that, you know, as more than,
more than like the safety of us.
And I just felt like we could,
you know,
there's no reason why the we should
be going out in the daylight period.
You know, we, we train like
why not fight like we train and
oh, because you guys got locked down
from doing stuff at night. Right.
Is that right?
Dude, night shit. But we also did
a lot of day shit and I, you know,
to me it was just like, why
the fuck are we doing this?
Like we have night vision. Why
are we going out during the,
do you have Afghan forces
with you sometimes.
A lot of times we did. Well, yeah,
we, we had to work a lot in Ramadi,
in the daytime. Um, and the main,
the main reason why we look worked well,
there's a couple of big reasons why
we worked in the daytime in Ramadi,
which as you, as you just pointed out,
as a huge tactical disadvantage compared
to being out at night where we can
literally see and the enemy cants I
mean it's, but in reminded, you know,
we had to work with Iraqi soldiers
who didn't have night vision,
so they didn't even have flashlights.
They would have like one flashlight for
every four people and we'd eventually
got them flashlights and
stuff. But anyways, it was,
it was a problem because to go
out at night with them, it was,
they were blind. And so now you're,
you're like at a, you're at the same,
the same disadvantage
because you're trying,
you've got people that can't see mixed
with people that can see and they're not
getting anything out of it. They're
not improving their skills at all, all.
And they're just horrible. Yeah. And
they were, they were not, not good,
not good.
And so that was one reason was to take
them out in the daytime to get them to
operate. We had to go out
with them in the daytime.
And the other big one was the
enemy knew that we owned the night.
And so the enemy in Ramadi,
they didn't come out at night.
They came out in the daytime.
So if you wanted to kill them,
you had to go out when they
were, when they were moving.
And so that's where we are now. And
you know, we, we did both. I mean,
we did a ton at the night
as well. And also, you know,
we'd take advantage of the
night to get in good positions.
We know when and then during the daytime
they would come out to fight and you
know, they'd get it.
Yeah, we had, we had, uh, art we had,
we were working with the commandos
and they had night vision. Um,
but like I said, they were
just terrible. And, uh,
like one of them almost
shot me, um, on and up. Uh,
we were actually in a helicopter
flying to target and, uh,
it was one of their heavy
gunners. And, um, he,
uh,
it was around midnight and we
were flying in a Chinook to,
to the target. And, uh, I was
just kinda not enough, just,
you know, just, just
trying to con, you know,
catch a little nap on the ride to the
op and it's pitch black and the in the
Hilo obviously. And uh, all of a
sudden it's just crack, you know,
like four or five rounds
crack off. And the guy neck,
it was the guy next to me and thank
God he had his barrel down and,
uh, like literally just shot
like four or five rounds,
like less than six inches from my feet
and there's just holes in the bottom of
the bird and shot the comms
out of the Hilo and everything.
And at that point I was just
like, you know, I was there,
just kinda used to shit being shitty and
just reached over and took the rounds
out of his gun and just that was it.
Yeah. And just like come over to comms,
like, yeah, the fucking
commandos 80, you know,
now everyone's just like, whatever.
But, uh, so then we changed like,
alright, no more commandos, Roland
hot in the birds and you know,
on the way to target a target. And
uh, so we, we, we had changed that.
So then the next one we did,
we fucking got to, we uh, got to our,
our uh, target burdened landed,
get out and do our formation
and all of a sudden,
and it's like a total brownout, you know,
cause Afghanistan is super dusty
and everything there. And uh, the,
the Hilo lands were all getting out,
we're in our formation and total brown
out and then all of a sudden we hear
fucking rounds going off.
Correct. Remember, cause they,
the dudes loading their pigs like all of
a sudden had a runaway gun or whatever.
We don't know if we're getting contacted
like you can hear it's outgoing,
but like why, why is there outgoing
fire when we're infilling, you know,
are we getting in contact
or what's going on?
And it's just these guys are
fucking stupid with their weapons.
And Yeah. So that was
always, always something fun.
Always good.
So you wrap up that deployment and come
back to come back and roll into your
next, next platoon.
Yup. Come back. And, uh, Roland, so
the next platoon and um, I always to,
how was that? How was that coming
home now you're now you're home.
You did the two weeks in the middle. How
was the transition when you got home?
It was a, it was, it was rough. Um,
I was definitely dealing
with some PTSD I would say.
And uh, I was, I was
definitely kind of angry.
Um,
okay.
I was, I was angry.
Yeah.
It was a weird, weird,
weird emotions. Um, cause I,
I kind of was kind of
pissed off at like, uh,
America, like, like
not America as a whole,
but like I felt like a,
the, the politics, you know,
like I said earlier, I
felt like they really, um,
cared more about, or they just didn't
really give a shit about our safety.
I felt like, uh, you
know, it's one thing like,
obviously we're doing a
dangerous job, but why,
why on earth are we not giving ourselves
every advantage that we are capable of?
You know, like, like the night
vision and stuff like that. And,
and a lot of times we
would capture people, um,
who we knew were bad, you know,
talking to our Intel guys
and they're like, 100%. Like,
this dude is a fucking
terrorist. Like, he's a bad dude.
Like everyone in his phone, you know,
they rip apart their shit. And like every,
every one of his contacts
are bad, you know, like,
this guy is definitely an IED
maker, you know, whatever.
And so we've got these guys captured,
but then we have to turn him
into the Afghan government,
which we also know is corrupt.
And then all of a sudden these dudes are
out on the streets again in a couple of
months time and making ids that, you know,
me or my brothers can step on
and fucking, that's a wrap. And
you know, uh,
Caleb Nelson was a seal that died on our
deployment from our team and it's kind
of, you know,
life and death and war just
puts things into perspective.
And, uh, it really made me angry that,
okay,
you know, like Caleb couldn't come
home because of an IED and like,
we're letting these people go.
And I just felt like we weren't being
okay
utilize fully and uh, and
like, like it was costing us.
And so I was like really
angry about that. And um,
and then also just kind of being in
that environment for a long time,
just it's different, you know,
different mentality and then
coming home to America and like,
people just don't understand
how good it is here.
And it's like a fucking fairy
tale, you know? And, and trying to,
and listening to people talk and complain
about about Shit here and I'm just
like, you don't even
have to, you don't even,
you just walk down that sidewalk and
didn't even give a fuck where you stepped.
Like, you don't even care cause
you're not worried about anything.
You're not worried if there's an IUD
there, like you have running water,
you took a shower today, you
fucking, I had to burn my own shit,
you know? Um,
so I was just like a lot of anger dealing
with that and I was drinking a lot,
like, uh, and I also felt like,
I felt like seals were the only ones
that kind of understood and got it.
And then also being over
there in Afghanistan, I saw,
yeah,
you know, Kandahar, the main base.
And Kandahar was like a fucking,
it was like a little town, you know,
and there's like flag football leagues
and shopping and TGI Friday's people
having birthday parties and shit like
that. And you know, that's where,
that's where like Tim McGraw flies in to
do the concert for the troops and shit
like that, you know? And it's like,
oh, is this where we're staying?
They eating like kings in? And
they're like, no, no, no, no,
you're going out there. So
then, you know, that's where I,
that's where I was and that's where,
where me and my boys were, you know,
living in the sock live in doing
some serious fucking shitty living,
you know, and, and,
and working a job that was
dangerous as fuck every day.
And then just seeing that
kind of shit. And like,
I don't know, I just, I felt like,
yeah,
before I had gone over
overseas, I was like real,
like thank you for your service
to everyone I saw, you know, and,
and afterwards I was just
kind of the opposite and uh,
I was like, fuck all motherfuckers, man.
So I was just disgruntled and whatever.
And M and P, you know,
I'd hear people talk about PTSD
or this or that. And I'm like,
what the fuck are you, what
are you afraid of? You know,
you were on a main base that like,
wasn't, it's not even a thing,
like you didn't experience war,
but that was like just kind of
immaturity at the time. And, and like,
like I said, me being just
kind of disgruntled and um,
dealing with that and I was
drinking like heavily, uh,
and
okay.
I was just a super aggressive
person and it wasn't like a good,
it wasn't good for my friends and family,
like people I cared about or whatever.
And like I said, I,
I felt like seals were kind of
the only ones that understood.
And then even amongst seals,
I felt like only the ones who,
who had to live so shitty, like we
did, like our platoon, you know,
no running water for a year. And like,
like just living in that environment was
super rough and I felt like they were
the only ones who
understood. But then again,
it's like I just spent a year with
these assholes in a hundred by a hundred
foot, you know, place. I
don't want to see them. And,
uh, so just kind of felt alone
a little bit, you know, and uh,
whatever dealt with that
got got through that I'm
doing better now. And,
and I was like, kind of
okay,
disgruntled towards people claiming
PTSD and all this kind of shit for years
after that. And then
actually some random, um,
uh, this random, at a
dinner I was at, she was,
uh, in the army or
something like that. And,
and she had t she was talking about
PTSD and I was just thinking like,
Jesus Christ, what the fuck are
you? What, what is it? You know?
And I kind of said my viewpoints on
it and she was like, well, you know,
fear is relative and you know,
like you are,
you were seriously trained
and stuff for war and,
and to be in that
environment and you know,
some people weren't and like
fears relative like this,
like being in a gunfight to you, you know,
and versus like just being in that country
like could be the same amount of fear
or more for that person. And I was
just kinda like, you know, hmm.
I never really thought about it
that way. Okay. I'll change my mind.
War is different for everybody. And I
remember my first deployment to Iraq, we,
we, we travel
a lot and we went to a lot of different
places and so we'd go from like the
incredible palaces that had been taken
over that had subways and Starbucks.
And then we, you know,
the next day we'd be out at
some outstations somewhere
there'd be an ODA team
just living in, you know, the
most horrible living conditions.
And then the next day you'd be with some
random Marine Corp company out in some
other forward operating base into, and
again, they're just living like in hell.
And then you come back to another,
another like main farb and it's all
luxurious and nice. And I mean it just,
it Kinda is what it is, you know,
it just Kinda is what it is.
And that actually makes sense what
that female said about, you know, hey,
it's different. People are there, they're
there for different reasons. You know,
like we joined the seal teams because
what we want to do is go out and go on
patrol with a machine gun. That's like
100% of why you're doing the seal teams,
someone that goes through, you're
hoping for, you're praying,
you're praying for a war.
Yeah. And I remember, I remember
like being out there, man,
I remember my very first
up, um, when I, we,
we flew in to this, to, to this village.
And I remember being like super
nervous and like, Holy Shit,
I'm fucking navy seal. And I'm actually
going on my first mission. Like,
Holy Shit. And I'm just thinking
like, uh, when we land, we,
we landed at like 3:00 AM or something
and that we offset like way far away.
But I was thinking like
that's going to be guns blaze.
And as soon as this Hilo Lance
that jump out the he load,
I'm just like full blown ready for more
like what are bringing on, let's go,
where's it been logged? And
it was just pitch black,
quiet and sat there for
fucking hours. And you know,
till the sun came up, nothing
happened. I was like, God damn it.
I was so disappointed. You know,
I was looking for to like war and
then, you know, obviously we got,
we got plenty. But uh, I, yeah,
I remember just being real antsy
to, to get in a firefight in,
you know, to,
to do what I've been trained to do and
put my training to the test, you know?
And yeah, it's different for other
people who are not experiences may vary.
There was no doubt about that.
So when you went to a bar,
when you got home and you
got put into a new platoon,
did you guys keep a core
group of guys from your,
from your previous platoon
together or was it like brand new?
Oh yeah, no, we, we had guys that
stayed and, and some went, you know,
to trade at and some screen
and standard standard shit.
Few, few core guys stayed
together. Four or five or whatever.
And then you guys got a new
chief and a new OIC. Yeah.
New Assistant to commander. Yup.
Yeah, that was man, God, thank God I am.
So I still do not miss
having fucking 20 bosses,
you know, in the, and
then every, you know,
at the drop of a hat it can change and
then all of a sudden it's like, nope,
new flavor. We're, we're, uh, now
we're, you know, it's like, oh,
Jockos now our fucking commanders.
So we're all waking up four 30 and you
go on a p t it's like, what the fuck?
When did this happen?
This is bullshit, Jack.
And as you do another workup.
Yup. Yeah. And, uh, I, uh,
I'd always wanted to be a
dog handler and yeah. And I,
I tried to volunteer to be a dog handler
as a new guy and, and they said, no,
cause you know, they want you to have
your gun. Yeah. They want you to,
here's your dog names, 48 and uh,
make it bark. So yeah, now I got to, um,
to do the dog handling
thing and, um, the super,
super excited about that. And, uh, it was,
it was honestly such a great time. Um,
I had a bad ass dog and I
was as first handler and uh,
yeah, it was, it was super cool because,
you know, one I was, I
was on one platoon wonder,
so I'd already kind of
gotten that Afghanistan,
gotten some combat under
my belt. And, um, you know,
I was the classic worst. The,
the worst guy in the teams is
a one platoon wonder and a,
so I was full blown, just one. Cruz
wonder, you knew everything 100%.
And uh, and I got a
fucking dog. So watch out.
Stellan no, uh, my dog
was super cool. And, um,
they like a, there the,
there was six of us that went over to
work with the dogs and we all got along
really well. And uh,
and that was super cool because
now you're not a new guy finally,
you know, and I mean, even on
our deployment in Afghanistan,
we were still fucking doing new guy. Yeah,
you're here a new guy years fucking
N***a. I couldn't fucking believe it.
I'm like, we literally,
they made us shovel rocks
one time, like a hole,
like a dumpster or a dump truck
full of rocks. And they just,
we just moved it from one pile
and just tent over like 10,
15 feet to the right. And we just
moved the pile of rocks to this,
make a new pile, 15 feet to the right.
And it was, it was a disciplinary thing.
It wasn't, you know,
all the new guys, your,
your attitude's not good and we're
just like, are you fucking serious?
Like, we're just in a firefight with
you. Like, you know, we're not like,
we're expecting to like be boys now
and they're like, shut up new guys.
Your attitude sucks. Go shovel
rocks and you're just like, God,
you know, we were like literally
having to burn shit. You know,
our own shit. Uh, we had, we had, uh,
barrels that we had wrapped up debt
coordinator around and cut in half and,
um, filled with diesel fuel. Um, those
were our, those were our shitters,
but they needed burned. So when,
uh, when the, when the new guys,
you know, when, when we didn't, uh,
have the best attitudes or our
attitudes weren't up to par,
we shoveled rocks and burned shit.
So I was definitely happy to not be
a new guy anymore. Um, but anyway,
yeah. So as one between
wonder had a dog and uh,
got to go through another workup
with the dog. So that was super cool.
And,
and got to go through dog training
school and learn about the dogs and,
and um, yeah, unfortunately like right,
right before it was,
we were on like predeployment leave
and they had told us like, Hey,
change of plans. We're going now
we're going to Yukon. So, uh,
we don't need the dog anymore.
And I was like, fuck man,
this isn't like a piece
of equipment. I mean,
that's essentially how the navy looks
at them. They are, they are equipment,
but you know, obviously
it's a dog and you,
you form this like super strong bond and
attachment with them just like they're
your pet. And, uh,
my dog was super awesome and I'd
worked with them so much, you know,
it was like a robot. It was
like a, it was so cool and, um,
I was fucking so pissed off when
they just dropped that on us.
And it's just like, yeah, man, hand
the Aleisha over to someone else.
And Yeah. So did that. And uh,
then went to Yukon and, and you know,
a lot of guys were fucking
super pissed off though. We,
we're going to YouCam and you know,
I was definitely looking
forward to using my dog and,
and you know, doing that in
Afghanistan, but, you know,
it is what it is. You, you know, I, I
definitely knew that there wasn't, I,
I didn't see any value in just
bitching about it. And, uh,
it seemed like that was like, the
common thing was just, it was,
it seemed almost like if you
weren't bitching about it,
then you were looked at as a
turd. And like, if, you know,
if you weren't bitching louder than the
guy next to you, then you're, you're,
you know, Oh man, I'm so disappointed
we're not going to Afghanistan. Yeah,
me too. I'm super disappointed. Like,
yeah, well I can't even sleep at night.
Well, I don't even want to
fucking go, you know, like,
yeah, I just realized just to
shed some light on to everyone.
So when you deploy in a seal
platoon or a seal troop,
you can deploy different
parts of the world.
Sometimes you deploy to places
like Iraq and Afghanistan,
which as we just kind of discussed,
that's what everybody wants to go. Well,
95%. Well,
you never know what the real number is
because there's somebody that don't want
go. But there's, there's the attitude,
most guys want to go and
they want to go fight,
but there's also you have to deploy to
other parts of the world where there's no
war going on. You might just deploy
to the Pacific or you might deploy,
in this case you calm
is for European Command.
So that's going over to Germany and doing,
doing things out of Germany in different
parts of Europe and it's definitely not
a high threat environment. And so
yeah, and that's the way it goes.
Sometimes there's a mission that has
to be done and it's a different kind of
mission.
You're going to build relationships
with other countries and you do these
exercises and do training events,
but it's not generally what guys
are excited to do in the seal teams.
So there's always, there's
always, uh, you know,
I always get asked that question when
I, when I go and talk to seals is, hey,
my guys are going here. How do I keep
them on, you know, how do I keep them,
hey,
how do I keep them engaged when no one
wants to do it or they don't care about
it? It's like, yeah, you've got to
work through that. It's definitely,
it's definitely
because, you know, I would
imagine, especially if you know,
like that you're going to Yukon and then
starting that workup because you still
have to go through the workup
and train as if you know,
your fucking life depends on it and you're
going to war and you know that you're
the elite, you know, Warrior and, and
you have to be ready for anything.
So you like, obviously
our training is, um,
developed around that, but then
having to keep up that motivation,
like it's, it's one thing
when you're like, fuck,
do this training sucks and it's,
I'm tired, it's hot. Um, you know,
like fucking covered in shit or whatever
and I've got to hike 12 miles carrying
this thing. And it's like, well,
you gotta do it though because we're
going to fucking war like this. Serious,
you know? But then it's
like, oh, don't you come in?
Why the fuck are we even training
today? You know what I mean? But, uh,
I don't know. So I didn't really
have that, that attitude though.
I was kind of excited to,
you know, I had just gotten,
we had just done that that year deployment
to Afghanistan and it was, you know,
in my platoon was the one that was
really, really shitty, shitty living.
The other two platoons were in
Nice spaces that they were like,
had an awesome Jim's like good
food and, and stuff like that.
And uh, you know, so I, I wasn't,
I wasn't too terribly
upset about it. Obviously.
Like everyone wants to go work and
kill bad guys like a champion, but,
uh, you know, when you, when you
got to do that, it is what it is.
You might as well fucking enjoy it.
And that's why I feel I might
as well make the most of it.
At what point did you
start Jujitsu? I started,
I started Jujitsu
actually, um, in buds. Uh,
that was my introduction, um, to buds.
One of our buds instructors was, he,
he was interested in Jujitsu and
liked it or whatever. And uh,
so as a punishment, one day we
had to do wet and Sandy Jujitsu,
like introduction to Jujitsu.
And like a lot of guys were,
were not enjoying it because one,
if you've never done Jujitsu,
you're 100% going to get fucked
up by anyone who has done it.
And we were wet and Sandy,
so it was like just cold and
wet and miserable and sandpaper,
like grinding on each other, you know.
But I actually really enjoyed it.
I was like, Holy Shit, this is
pretty cool. And uh, one of the guys,
there was two guys in our
class that were both, uh,
really high level wrestlers
like in high school and, um,
and they were probably like on
a blue belt level, you know,
they were probably like 130 545 pounds.
And at the time I was
around 180 590 pounds.
I had done never done Jujitsu ever or
wrestled or anything like that. And,
uh, I always punched, you know,
I knew I punched hard cause
I've been in a lot of fights,
like street fights and shit and bar
fights. But, um, art at that point,
sorry, I wasn't bar fights. It
was like high school fights. Um,
dodge ball fights, right? I did get in
a dodge ball fight once, no bullshit.
And, uh, so anyway, these,
these little guys just tied me in a
fucking knot and I was just so impressed
like, because looking at these
dudes, I would be like, 100%,
I'll fuck this guy up in a fight. And
we, you know, they were like, all right,
no striking, you know, no punching, but
we're going to grapple. And I'm like,
okay, and we're grappling and they're
just completely fucking me up.
And I was like thinking, oh my God,
if these little itty bitty men can tie
me in and not like this and just make me
helpless, like, imagine what
I could do if I learned this.
So I started rolling with one of my
friends who was like six to 240 pounds at
the time and just super
aggressive. And, uh,
he was probably around a
blue belt level of knowledge.
Um, maybe not quite a blue belt, you know,
but he knew definitely more
than I did and we, you know,
he was really aggressive too. And, and,
and he was like all about rolling. Um,
so we would roll No-gi and he
would just constantly were,
this is in bugs or in buds and then
buds in the nest gt. Um, you know,
buds was the introduction to it. And
I was like, Whoa, I, I fucking loved,
this is cool.
And then I started talking to one of my
classmates who is also into it and you
know, he had done, he had done some
training before the navy and like I said,
he was around a blue belt level.
So when you got to team 10,
did you start training immediately
or one of the academies?
I didn't start training, um, at one of
the academy's until after Afghanistan.
I came back and, uh, cause one of the
guys, one of my, like my see data, he was,
uh, he was a purple belt at the time.
And um, we would roll
on occasion, you know,
in, and he would be like, and he would
tell me like, man, you have like great,
you know, aggression and an
ability and all this shit, but you,
you got to go to an academy.
And learn, you know,
and I'd only learned just from that guy,
that dude beat my ass over and over
and he would literally like just,
just fucking get on top pressure
grind, arm triangle, you know?
And he'd be like, all right man, you know,
I got on top of you and I fucking
arm trying to squeeze like that.
Don't let me do that again. I'm like,
all right, got it. You know, try harder,
try harder, you know, you know,
you got to do something. No,
you're not doing anything. You know what
I mean? So it was one of those. So, uh,
I had gotten pretty good at just getting
my ass kicked and dealing with a big,
large human or whatever.
So then when I actually
showed up to an academy, um,
I had been doing that for a
couple of years, you know,
with him and never put on a gear or
anything like that. But then afterwards,
yeah, he was like, you got to
join gym. So I joined a gym,
put on the g and then really
like, that's when my Jujitsu, I,
I'd say really started my journey.
And that was in 2012 did you have
someone to train with on your Yukon
deployment? Um, yeah, uh,
trained with my, see Daddy,
he was there and uh,
I trained and you come like we were
obviously going to different countries,
so I would go and hit up different gyms
and the different countries and then all
the other, uh, the other countries, seal
teams, you know, that we worked with.
There's always someone who's
into combatives, you know,
so I would basically just find
out who that guy was. Yeah.
Who wants to get some. And then we'd
roll the mats out and fucking train and,
and I was trying to get guys into
Jujitsu back then and I was telling them,
you know,
it's a great workout and people are just
looking at me like that's not a fucking
workout. And you know, you're not
lifting weights, you're not running,
you're not. I'm like, dude,
it is a workout for sure.
And it's, you know, one that,
that I thought the reason I liked Jujitsu
specifically was because it was like a
deadly martial art. You know,
I could fucking choke you.
And like your, you're tapping your, you're
asking me like please don't kill me.
You know? And that's what I thought
was fucking cool about it. And,
uh, definitely one of the cool things
about it, you know, like there's,
there's times where, I
dunno, yeah. Like we're,
we're gunfighters I get
it, but your first line is,
should be you like my, my body,
what can I do with my fucking vessel that
I was brought into this universe with?
Like versus you if I don't have
a weapon, if I don't, you know,
it's just me and you.
Yeah. One-On-One. Like,
yeah, I mean I got to see
like over and over again,
just guys that didn't know how
to, I didn't know anything.
And they'd get in a simple prisoner
handling situation and wouldn't be able to
handle someone.
And the only thing that they would know
to do was like bludgeoned them in the
head, which is cool.
That's fine, I get it.
But when you bring that person into the
detainment facility and they're freaking
all jacked up,
and then it turns out that they're
not the person you were looking for or
whatever. And, and that just doesn't,
that's just not, that's just not cool.
And it's not,
it's not tactically the best thing to
do because you don't have the control.
I mean, you can't count on punching
someone or hitting him in the head.
You can't count on that solving the
problem. Whereas Jujitsu, it's like, yeah,
no, I have this human under
control. Whereas you can, you know,
you've punched people before that you've
nailed them and they shook it off like
it didn't even happen. Uh, you know, the
whole thing with like muscle strikes.
I've see, I've had guys, I mean,
I've muzzle struck plenty of people,
but I've had guys that
I've seen put the craziest,
most aggressive muscle strike on a
dude and have the dude bleeding. Yeah.
But like still fighting
and you think, yeah.
And so, so yeah, from the people
are in fear for their life. Oh yeah,
definitely.
And they hate you and they hate
your society and they're a jihadist.
It's like, yeah, they're that Mazel
strike if it doesn't knock them out,
which ensure that it is possible.
But the idea that that was just going
to stop someone in their tracks 100% of
the time was completely
ludicrous. Now with Jujitsu,
at least you're going to have
some control, more control.
And even that's not 100%, you
know, cause you could, you know,
you've got someone that's really small,
get someone that's really big and
depending on your skill level,
there could be issues there. But um, yeah.
So you finally started training at a
school 2012 and then you just dove in all
the way.
Yeah, I started a,
I started training at a
school in 2012 and um,
started competing and Jujitsu.
Uh, you know, I really, once I,
once I joined a school,
I learned more in six months than
I did in four years. Of course,
No-gi rolling with my
buddies, you know what I mean?
That is just the blind leading
the blind essentially. Like,
who knows the most today and it's
like, you guys are all fucking wrong.
We're all teaching each other
wrong shit. You know what I mean?
So I learned more in six months
than I did that whole time.
And so I'm at that point,
I'd really like fallen in
love with Jujitsu and, uh,
I started competing all the time
and was really well because I was a,
I was competing as a
white belt and, you know,
but I had already had a shitload
of grappling experience, you know,
with fucking big, strong dudes who
are just fucking me up then. Now,
like now I'm the big strong guy
and I know a little bit and I,
I've been in like hard situations
on the mat, you know what I mean?
And then obviously just the
team guy just will to fight,
you know, that's always
a different level. Uh,
you can tell when you roll
with a, a team that even,
even when a team guy's brand
new at Jujitsu, there's,
they're still going to be there.
You can just tell that they're different
because their will to fight is,
is generally higher. Um, so anyway,
I started competing a lot and doing really
well and then started fighting and j
doing really well and that
as well. And, um, you know,
that led me to what I'm doing now.
And then you actually took over when you
came home from your Yukon deployment,
he took over the combatives
program. Yeah. Yup. I, uh,
I took over the combatives program.
That was something that, you know,
I felt like,
uh,
kind of lacked in, in
the seal teams. You know,
I was very shocked at that. I was
surprised at that, you know, uh,
obviously we're, we're, the
seals are the best in the world,
you know, at what we do and,
you know, were gunfighters and,
and all that shit. But I would,
I imagined that are hand
to hand combat. You know,
like everyone thinks
like, oh, fucking seal.
He must tap me on the shoulder
and I'll, and I'll die. You know?
And it's true just for everyone who's
listening. That's definitely true.
But, uh, I hadn't gone to that school yet,
so I was like confused as to why
that wasn't a school or whatever.
So anyway, I, I felt like
with, at this point I was,
I was, uh, competing
quite a bit and having,
having some pretty good
success in the, uh, fight MMA,
Jujitsu world. And I'd also had,
you know, real world experience,
you know,
a lot of real world experience dealing
with prisoner handling and stuff like
that. And, um,
and I just felt like I
felt like I could bring,
um,
I felt like I could do a good job
at leading the combative. So, um,
I took that on board and, and
they gave me a shot. And, um,
I rewrote the curriculum for combatives
that we used on the, on the east coast.
And, um, it was, it was
really good, you know, and I,
and I went into with the
operationally focused mindset,
you know, not if you're doing it, I'm
all about Jujitsu. I love Jujitsu.
However, if you're doing a
triangle choke on target,
something's probably gone terribly
wrong. Way Wrong, you know?
But it's definitely not a
bad thing to know Jujitsu,
you know what I mean?
Especially as, as an operator,
you're dealing with human beings
and you're not just, you know,
you're not just going to go in and
fucking kill everyone on target, you know,
there could that happen. Yeah,
absolutely. But is that going to happen?
Probably not. And you're going to have
to deal with human beings and you know,
anything from just marshaling them
to a full on fight for your life is
combatives related. You know?
So I covered all of that in my,
um, program and, and I
really focused on, um,
basic,
simple things that you could
remember during a time of stress.
You know,
like you're not gonna remember 12 steps
to an arm bar or something like that
when you're in a situation and
you need it. You know what I mean?
Especially in a combative
situation overseas. Like that's,
your adrenaline is going to be going
like crazy. It's going to be fast.
You need something simple, effective
and that, you know, that you can,
uh, remember easily. And it's also, you
know, how it is like in a, in a workup,
you're, you're, you're getting fed
through a fire hose essentially.
And there's so much shit you're,
you're learning and you're expected to
be proficient and like perfect that I'll,
I'll it all of it before
you go out the door.
So our combatives we didn't get
a whole lot of time, you know,
it was like a two week thing.
And so I really focused on developing
techniques and things that,
you know, uh, and would also be, uh,
effective, effective, uh,
towards your enemy or your,
your person that you're dealing with,
but also mitigate risk to
the operator. You know,
like muzzle strikes are great because
you can muzzle strike a hundred people in
a row and your hands feel fine, you know,
and you're not worried about breaking
your weapons and control. So, you know,
that was kind of my focus
was operationally focused
mindset and um, you know,
and, and on the west
coast I felt like, uh,
from what I had seen going out
there and working with those guys,
it was a lot of, uh, I felt like more
guys were interested in combatives,
but there, it was more of
like a sporty kind of thing.
Like they were up in the fight room
doing Jujitsu and stuff like that.
And which, which I thought was
great. Like I said, it's better.
It's definitely better
to, to, you know, have it,
not need it than need
it not have it. And uh,
so I think that it was good
that guys were doing that,
but I didn't think that it was
operationally focused enough. You know,
like I don't think that you should be
training combatives and PT gear. You know,
like I had my,
I like the program that I up was all
scenario driven and it was all like train
like you fight and you know,
so in your, in your cammies,
in your boots with your gear, you know,
cause handling someone in PT gear
versus handling someone and you know,
full kit is totally different as well.
Yeah. Yeah. Well there's,
it's um, you know, I was the,
the discussion that used to happen a lot
with all this stuff because believe me,
I was in this discussion
for a long, long, long time.
You, you reach a, or you get a ton of
fucking pushback. People are super busy.
People are super emotional about, um,
about combatives and you
know, I would always like,
I wasn't, I wasn't as emotional as
I, I wasn't very emotional about it,
but for me it was just like, hey guys,
need to know how to do this. This is,
this isn't about emotion. This is about
just the facts of being ready to be,
be prepared, being prepared on the
battlefield. That's what you need to be.
And you know, one of the things
that people would say was, you know,
um, the, like the speed shooting contests,
you shouldn't do that because it
will take away from your operational
capability. Okay, I get it. However,
who does better on the range?
The guy that's like a, uh,
a hobby shooter too, and then
goes out to whatever CQC,
he's drilling nails all day long. It,
same thing with parachuting, like, Oh,
okay. So I sky dive, whatever. I'm a,
I'm a skydiver on the weekends and I
like to go down and have a ton of jumps.
I have, you know, 2000
jumps with my slick rig.
How do I do when I put a combat
equipment on? I do awesome.
I'm way better than like a guy like
me cause I wasn't like a recreational
skydiver when I've, I put equipment on
it was like, it was, it was a, yeah,
I had to pay attention.
Whereas the guys that were good skydivers
in the civilian side, they were good.
Same thing with like, Oh, who's
going to do better? Um, in a,
in a grappling match,
a guy that wrestled in high school
with his gear on or a guy that didn't,
you know, has his gear on.
It's like it doesn't matter.
You get certain skill level and you're
going to do great and that's just the way
it is. Now. What you can't do is just say,
oh well we're never going to train
with gear on because there are certain,
you know, it's like saying, hey, we'll
never get to train with the g if you,
if someone never trained with the g
before and they go against some of the g,
it depends on how long that person
has been training with the g four,
because hey, no, g and g have
all kinds of similarities.
They have all kinds of similarities.
They also have some differences and
depending on how much you do of each is
where you're going to kind of shake
out which one you're better at.
But there are, there's so much
crossover between g and Nogi,
between skydiving on the weekends and
skydiving in the teams and shooting on the
weekends and shooting at a teams. The
way I was looked at, it was train more,
train, train all the time with
everything, you know, as much as you can.
And that's, that's how you get
better at things. But yeah,
that combative thing was, um,
it still is. It still is. It's,
it's, it's hard. It's hard
to change. It's a shift, that
taboo thing for some reason. And,
and it totally depends
on who's who's at the,
the head of the table. You know,
what, what their flavor is,
what their take is on it. And if the
guy, you know, is like you or me,
then it's like, hey, we're all going
to fucking, we all need to know this.
We all need to do that. And then other
guys come in and they're like, ah,
that shit stupid. We don't need that.
Yeah. And I was, I was,
when someone would say,
guy should be working on shooting,
I'd say, I totally agree. Absolutely.
You know, give us a range, you know,
in the building and we'll do that in
the building because that's without
question our primary weapons
system and you know, no doubt I,
you want to be a great
shot for sure. Guess what?
How many hours are you going
to shoot a day? I mean,
are you going to shoot 22 hours a day
because you're going to have some time.
At some point we go, you know what,
let's get some other skills in here.
You know, we might as well know. And
like you said earlier, you can't just go,
you don't just go on target
and shoot everyone. There's a,
there's a female, you know Dave Burke,
who's one of the guys at echelon front.
Yeah. He, he has a,
he has a story that he tells about the
first time he came face to face with
looks like Iraqi woman that did not want
him in the house and he's, you know,
whatever 18 year marine at this
point and he didn't know what to do.
Yeah. And it's like, yeah,
you, you, you need to train,
you need to train to
handle those situations.
And, and a lot of people, you know
that people are unpredictable.
They are just totally unpredictable.
And especially in a situation
where they don't know,
like a bunch of people with guns and body
armor just busted up in their fucking
house.
Like you think that person's going to
be like just cool as a cucumber or calm
like, I dunno.
And then when you put hands on people
to people freak the fuck out and,
and you know,
and you don't need to just
muscle strike everyone.
Like you said, like if you do that,
you're gonna get shut down real quick.
You know what I mean? And you
should be, as an elite warrior,
you should be expected,
or at least I expect people
to handle themselves. Like,
and you shouldn't let this fucking Iraqi
woman just walk all over you or fucking
flail around. Cause like, you don't
know what to do. I can't muzzle Stryker.
I can't shoot her. So what, what do
I gotta do? You know what I mean?
And if you've never, and that's
just like a woman, but if let, uh,
now you have like a fighting age
male or something and you know, Oh,
if he resists, I'll just kill. No,
that's not the case always. You know,
it's definitely not like,
and uh, you know, it's,
you definitely don't want the first time
that you're handling a human being like
that to be overseas when it's
real and they can, you know,
very easily get to your shit
on your kit and you know,
it can be a bad day or especially
like I tell people, you know,
just think of like muzzle, muzzle
discipline and awareness. You know,
like when you have your gun,
even at high ready and then you're
marshaling someone and they freak the fuck
out. Now all of a sudden you've got a
hot weapon, like going around the room.
It's just shit that there's so much
things that you, you need to think about.
And uh, the more you do it, the more
comfortable you're going to be with it.
And that was kind of
my mindset towards it.
At what point did you realize
you were going to get out? Um,
well I wasn't,
I wasn't sure I was fighting and stuff
and I was just kind of doing that as,
as for fun as a hobby on the weekends
and competing and stuff like that.
Uh,
and then I had gone out and trained at
Black House with some UFC fighters and,
uh, I had already, I had always
like looked at the UFC, you know,
as I was, I was always a fan. Um,
and I enjoyed fighting and stuff and,
but I'd always looked at those guys like
they were kind of super human or like,
like it was like the
NFL of fighting. Like,
those guys are genetic freaks or
whatever. You know what I mean?
When you think of someone in the
NFL and you're just like, man,
it must be nice to be born like
that, you know, or whatever.
But fighting's kind of a
unique thing where I dunno,
anyone can do it and uh, as long
as you just put in the, the work,
you know what I mean? So, and
being a genetic freak helps too.
But, uh, but I had gotten there,
I had gotten the black house and I had
trained with some of the people in the
UFC and I was just like, Holy Shit.
Like, I'm actually like doing fine.
Like I'm hanging with these guys and,
and um, you know, talking to them and,
and just kinda getting to
know some of these guys.
And it just made it a little more
human, you know? And it's like, well,
what did you do before
you're a fighter? Like, oh,
I fucking worked in a restaurant, you
know, I was a busboy or whatever. I was,
uh, you know, this, that third.
And I was just thinking, you know,
and they're all looking at me like,
dude, you're fucking navy seal like,
and I'm just like, yeah, but
that's all I've ever known,
and that's all I've ever done. I did
right out of high school, you know, and,
uh, and I'm just me, you know,
and I know like, I'm not special,
you know what I mean?
And it just kind of made a ahead of
like a shift or like a realization,
like, these are just
people just like you, and,
and they just fucking stuck with fighting
and practiced it until they were good
enough to beat, you know, the
competition and now they're here.
And I was like, fuck, I, I could do that.
Like, I'm pretty good, you know? And,
um, yeah. And I've been through some shit,
like, I could push myself hard, like,
fuck, I can do this. And at the time,
like I was [inaudible] I'd already
been a seal for awhile and,
and you know,
I got to experience a ton
and life and just in war and,
and just that whole lifestyle
and that whole thing. And, and,
uh, I was just at a crossroads, you know,
and I was like, well, I can stay
in and make a career out of this.
Like I was planning on doing, I was
planning on staying in for 20 years.
Um, and, you know, I can screen and, you
know, try and make it over there and,
or I can get out and, and
kind of pursue this. And,
and at the time I was 29 or, or, yeah,
I was 27 when I was like
making this decision. And, um,
I was like, you know, fighting this
kind of a young man's game and, uh,
like you read earlier in the
beginning of this, like, you can't,
you can't even pause time
waits for no one. And,
uh, I was like, well, if I,
if I just keep down this road,
I don't want to think like, what
if, or like regret, you know?
And I was like, I've already,
I've already been on this path for
a while and it's cool and all that,
but I want to see what
else I can do. So I,
and I was really fucking struggling
with, with that decision for a long time.
It was stressing me out and,
uh, then once I just said,
fuck it and this decided, you know,
which way I was going then the like
all that stress, like relief this,
it was a big reliever and uh,
yeah, cited to get out. And
um, I got out in 2018
how many amateur flights did
you have when you were in a,
like 17 or something. And then, and did
you go pro while you were still in? No,
they wouldn't let me. And that was like,
it was so frustrating to
me because in Virginia,
the amateur rule set is
the exact same as pro.
So it's day before
weigh ins. Um, you know,
all strikes like initial
elbows, no Shim pads, you know,
it's four ounce gloves, no
head gear. It's, it's, it's uh,
it's fucking pro. We're five minute
rounds. Uh, no, there were three,
three, three minute rounds, three
minute rounds. Um, but some,
some of them had five minute rounds,
like I fought in North Carolina. Um,
so yeah, it was no
different, you know, and uh,
trying to explain that to like
my command and shit and I'm like,
there is literally no
difference. And guess what,
like a punch from punch in the face from
an amateur feels the same from a pro.
That's why I'll tell
you what her like those,
that bruise that came from an amateur,
it would have came from a pro too.
I talked to Tim Kennedy about this,
like it's so crazy the army gave that guy
and gives him so much and he's a great
guy and obviously an
incredible fighter. But yeah,
I mean he was just full on just getting
after it red while it is still is. Yeah.
And they support him. He's all,
it's awesome. It's awesome, man.
I ran into total fucking roadblocks
left and right with my fighting and um,
you know, and I used the
argument all the time. Like guys,
you don't even stand same way. Yeah. He
was in the Marine Corps. Yeah. I taught,
I taught the bamboo officer of the Marine
Corps just out there fighting in the
WEC. But the, uh, the fuck go traded
Tim Kennedy, they, they sponsored him,
like ranger up or whatever.
Yeah. We'll rangers up is,
it's actually Tim's Co a company. No,
Tim. But for awhile Tim, Tim was like,
he, I forget the exact story, but he,
he was sponsored by like the army.
Yeah. For awhile they were using it as
like a recruiting tool. And then he said,
listen,
you can either keep paying
me a sponsorship or you can
just let me come back on
active duty. And, and they were like, oh,
that sounds like a good financial
deal for us. So yeah, Tim Tim's, yeah.
And that's, and that's why
I kind of was forced to,
to choose because I was running
into so much fucking bullshit and,
um, you know, like glory,
a glory had come to town and they were
doing a fight at the Hampton Coliseum.
And, um, you know, at this
point I had already had quite a,
quite a few fights under my
belt and had some, a popularity,
I guess as a fighter. And, and
they had heard about me and, um,
they invited me to,
to fight on the show and Mike Tyson was
gonna be there and shit. And I was like,
man, this is going to be a fucking
huge opportunity. It's on Spike TV too.
And I was, you know, I was like,
can I, can I fight on this? And,
and they were like, yeah, you know, we'll,
we'll see what we can do, blah, blah,
blah. And then last, you know,
last minute they told me no, you
know, and I was just like, fuck,
if I would've been your boss,
you would've been fight. I know.
And that's the shitty part is like,
you know, it depends on who's,
who's at this at the table
at the moment. Hey, you know,
now that I think about it,
cause I'm just sitting here thinking
like there's probably a Po. In fact,
I remember seeing some kind of policy
that they put in place at some point.
I forget, even if it was yes or
no, or I forget, but they remember.
But my argument to that was
like, all the time was like,
like just same one with the
skydiving. You know, I'm like,
guys fucking skydive all the time.
There's leapfrogs, you know, why not?
Why don't the navy, why doesn't the
navy use me as a recruiting tool?
You know, like, I, I wouldn't, I
don't want to get out of the teams.
I want to stay in the teams, but I also
want to fight and like, I can do this.
Like I was ranked number one on the east
coast and two weight classes, you know,
and I was like, I'm pretty good
at this shit. Like, you know,
and it,
I don't understand why we
don't utilize this, uh,
utilize me as a recruiting tool,
you know, go to the fights,
set up a fucking pull up bar, handout
tee shirts and try and hand, you know,
or go to the, they had me
go to the national, uh,
high school wrestling contest or a
tournament and they had me do like a
combatives demonstration and, and had me
go out there and wrestle with all the,
the high school students and stuff.
And Yeah, I fucking brought it.
Yeah. I'll tell you what
I mentioned frog baby.
Y'All was up at the California
state championships last year or no,
it was 2019. I was like, hi, a
bunch of hyenas. I mean my, my,
my daughter was competing and, but
you know, we're up there and the boys,
they're just animals. They're animals.
It's, it's awesome to see. Yeah,
it's those dudes, those kids were
fucking taught and they fucking,
they all wanted some shit.
They were like [inaudible] cause I
was there in like Cammie Cammie pants,
you know, and the fucking Blue
UDT seal shirts and, and uh,
we brought the pull up bar
and, and you know, cause the,
I think but buds likes, they try
to get wrestlers because wrestlers,
you know, wrestlers,
I don't even want to say wrestlers have
a good chance of making it through buds
because that's not true.
It's definitely not true.
It was slightly better transit or
normal. Right. However, however,
wrestlers are used to a fucking grind
and that's probably why they're a little
bit more comfortable and used
to the grind factor of buds.
That does not mean they're used to
getting cold and wet and dealing with all
that shit, but they're used to
dealing with the grind, so whatever.
And they're competitive. So, uh, so
we went there and yeah, all those,
all these fucking high school wrestlers
are looking at me like I got something
to prove, you know, or whatever. And,
and I'm out there representing the
fucking seal team, so I'm like, Hey,
I got something to prove to.
Let's go young buck. And, uh,
so we, we didn't know it was a
good time, but I was like, why?
Why don't they fucking, they're cool
with this, but not like fighting,
like what's the difference? Like I dunno.
So I just ran into tons of
frustrating headaches like that,
and that's what really
ultimately decided to, you know,
I was just decided to go go this way
and I'm glad I did. But, um, I, that's,
you know, I gotta say like the seal
teams, I'd never tried to fight pro,
but like the seal teams
was totally support.
Like I would go and train
at places that give me,
well the west coast was a lot different
than the east coast. You guys,
you guys were definitely more
supported on that kind of stuff.
Extra curricular things.
So you get out. And then
when did you go pro?
Uh, right after I got out. So you've
been pro for a year and a half,
two years right now. A year and a half.
How many fights profiles do you have?
I've only done two
profiles so far. Um, I uh,
won my first one by a TKO in
the third round. It was a good,
really good fight. Um, uh, against, uh,
another pro who he was
a pro boxer as well,
and he had called me out and kind of
campaign for the fight or whatever and
cool. So I obliged and uh, and then, uh,
and then I did my, uh, LFA debut.
Um, I fight in a Sunga. I don't know
if you've seen any pictures of videos.
I mean, I have, unfortunately, you
can't unsee it. You're welcome.
No. Uh, so that's actually
my buddy, uh, Jeff gum.
He owns that company. Yeah. So, um,
so obviously like I try to support other
team guys and their ventures and stuff
like that. And you know, uh, um,
it was right up my alley with the, uh,
I thought it was funny if I'll pretty
much do anything if I think it's funny.
And, uh, so I, I fought in the sun go,
which is for those of you don't know,
it's kind of looks like a, a
American flag diaper sort of thing,
but it's, sorry.
Yeah, well it's from Brazil.
In Brazil there's a sun and there's a
Sung Gal and I think the Sunga guys like
the smaller one and the sun
gal is like a little bit,
but their speedos basically speed
up their speedos and dean lister,
because he has so much Brazilian
influence in his brain,
he went through his phase of
training with a Sung Gow and,
and uh, the, those were some of the
worst years of my life to be honest with,
you don't know, know ourself.
We can't do that today. Yeah.
So, uh, I'm, I'm not, I'm
very anti Sanga and some Gal,
but, but you, you know, you go for
it. Hey, it's if, if I wouldn't,
I would make me want to fight you
less if you were wearing that.
So you got that little psychological
edge or it was like confusing to them.
Yeah. I mean, do you remember, were you
watching like UFC when everyone was,
when all the Brazilians were still
wearing them in UFC and they still do
sometimes.
Yeah. Yeah, I've seen some of them. Yeah.
But I thought it was funny. So, uh, I,
so I got a little cut patch sewn
into it, so I go put my cup in it.
And that was my, my new
fighting attire and uh, yeah,
I went out, it couldn't
have, uh, I don't know.
It was awesome. We'll
say that. Uh, I went out,
I fought on LFA on national TV and um,
I w it was during a military
appreciation fight and so we,
they hosted the fight it at a
army base and it was in a hanger,
you know, with helicopters. And
then we've got all these people,
all these active duty army people and
their uniforms and stuff in the crowd.
And, uh, you know, here I am the,
the navy seal and the American flag
speedo and, and come out to fight,
um, and got knocked out 30 seconds.
So it's like good. Could get
really that much worse from here.
So that's cool. But now it was,
it was actually they called it the
craziest 31 seconds in LFA history.
I watched it. It was a lot of
time to watch fights. Yeah,
I had time for one blink.
I think you posted it somewhere. I
posted that I posted the little video.
I mean which some, which so many people
were where so like they were like, wow,
I can't believe you posted this.
And like sat him down first. Right.
Then you sit him down. No, so he had a
14 inch reach on me. He was six, six,
three and I'm fucking big ass dude.
And honestly like I didn't
even know like we were,
we were real cordial with each other
like at Wayans and stuff like that.
So I wasn't sure if like we were going
to touch gloves or not, you know,
cause it's always kind of a, I feel like
they should just like make that a rule.
Like you are, you, you, you either do
or you don't. It's a rule with me now.
But, uh, I,
I wasn't sure if we were gonna touch
gloves or not and like kind of coming out,
dude, he honestly,
he hit me like I didn't even know
he could reach me from where he was.
And it was just like, I think
from that, that, that big weight,
I do a big weight cut and, uh, I
think it just, you know, just fucking,
just put me on Queer street right away.
And, uh, so right out of the gates,
I, I was rocked and,
and was kind of fell down and was just,
he'd swarmed me and I was just getting
punches thrown at me, uh, left and right.
And I'm just kinda like seeing
stars, trying to gain my composure.
And then I finally like got backed
up in and a won against the cage and,
and uh, gained my composure for a
second, landed a one, a clean one too,
and, and dropped him and then a ran over,
like got excited when I dropped him
down, Kinda went over towards him and,
and fucking just,
I think probably my coordination was
just kinda off still from just getting
rocked and,
and I literally just tripped
right over head over him,
over his body. And then
as we're both standing up,
he fucking threw another
punch and that was it. So,
and I was just like, God damn it.
I'm a fucking navy seal on a army base.
Like fighting in an American flag,
speedo on national TV and
just got knocked the fuck out.
[inaudible] you know, whatever.
Know what to tell you that say, man,
you're getting out there. Hey, yeah,
fuck good. You it is. There's,
there's, there's going to be a winner
and a loser. That's right. And if you,
the real losers are the ones that
are actually not getting in the ring.
Hey, I know a lot, a lot more times than
not. I've come out Victoria. So, uh,
it is what it is. I don't,
it didn't slow me down,
doesn't bump me out or
whatever. Just part of it.
And I understand that going into it,
it's a risk. I'm willing to take your,
what's your next fight? Um,
we're setting up one, uh,
looking at August 25th and uh,
Riverside hopefully with the LFA
so hopefully that goes through and,
and I'll be all set to go right now.
I don't care who it is, just I
just want someone, I don't care.
Like I, I never really care who
my opponent is. Honestly, I don't,
I don't look at really their
skill set or I never have really,
I don't care because I've
dealt with people just so
much in like combatives and,
and Jujitsu and fighting.
It's just like people are unpredictable
and that's what I stick with.
Like you may think you have a game plan
figured out and then all of a sudden
they do something different. And I don't
even want to be thinking about, oh,
well I thought he was going to do
this and I had this set up for this.
And you know what I mean? Like
I know what you mean. I will say this,
when you find out who your opponent is,
you got to watch him. You got to watch
some, you got to at least figure out,
because there's people that have things,
they have their game and if
they have that game and you,
and you know about it as, you
know, like if, if you know,
I'm good at whatever, you'll
defend that thing. Right?
And if you don't know it well then
I'll get you in that situation, right?
If you're really, let's like I'm
what we'll anybody, anybody, if you,
everyone's got that thing at their
game that they're good at, right?
And like in Jujitsu, hey, this
guy's got a good guillotine,
this guy's got a good arm lock, this guy's
got flu. Good. He looks, or whatever.
Everyone's got their little
thing. And if they're good at it,
then that's what they'll
kind of steer you towards.
But, um, yeah. So I always, and
I always say, look, I get it.
We don't care who the opponent is, but
when you find out who your opponent is,
take a look, you know, set, send
it to me. Let me look at it.
You know what I mean? Cause like I've
been watching these things forever to say,
Hey, it looks like this guy has got this.
And you also have to watch more than
you're going to watch like three or four
fights and see if they have any grappling
tournaments that are posted on Nagar
whatever on Youtube, you know, and you
find out what kind of game they have.
And if you can do that, then you can learn
from it and you can take it into the,
you can take it into the cage with you.
Yeah, no, I'm definitely not opposed
to doing that at all. I just, uh,
I just don't put all my eggs in
the basket. You know what I mean?
That way I don't, if shit
doesn't go according to plan,
like that's cool cause they're
just fall off too. Yeah.
To evolve. But guess
what, they'll back to,
they'll go back to what they're
good at. You know what I mean?
So that's another thing to think about.
Yeah. Cool. Um, I, uh, so that glory,
that actual story, um,
when I had gotten told no, uh,
that I wasn't able to do that fucking
event and in Hampton roads, so I was,
I was really bummed out. And, uh,
so I ended up actually just
calling the guy already,
like had decided at that point I
was like, you know what? Fuck this.
I'm getting out of the navy.
Like I'm, I don't want,
I don't want to be told what I
can and can't do or whatever.
You know what I mean? Like, and uh,
so I called the guy back and said, well,
when's the next one? And he was like,
oh, we got, we got another, another
one coming up in San Diego. And I said,
put me on that one. And I, so I
just took leave and was like, yeah,
I'm just going to San Diego.
And I ended up fighting in
the Gloria San Diego.
I just took leave and I went out
there and did it anyway and, uh,
ended up knocking the guy
out in the second round.
Right on. Good outcome. Well,
this is a pretty good spot since
we're up to current events. What else?
I know you've got your supplement
company, you got shirts. What else?
How can people support what
you got going on? I would
say the biggest, uh, biggest way
is probably on Instagram. Um,
that's my really my only platform. Uh,
I put out a lot of content on Instagram.
I do a, my live streams from there. I
thought about doing a podcast as well,
but, but, uh,
I think I'm just gonna stick
to my Instagram lives and
just kind of treat them
as podcasts or whatever. Uh, cause
I like talking and interacting with,
with my supporters a
lot. And, uh, you know,
so I figured people would get bored just
talking to me for a long time in a room
like this. I don't know. But,
uh, yeah, I would say, uh,
followed me on Instagram at,
uh, at Mitch Ag Yard. Um,
and yeah, we've got a
supplement company. Um,
our main product is a thing
called the smashing greens.
That's what I gave you
today. And, uh, that,
that actually is a blend of
different organic super foods. Um,
so I watched this documentary
called fat sick and nearly dead.
I don't know if you've seen it or not,
it's on Netflix. And, uh, this guy, he,
he was really overweight and had this
some sort of skin disease and he ended up
getting a juicer and ended up doing
60 days of just vegetable juice.
And, uh, he ended up losing
a ton of weight and, um,
his skin disease cleared up and just like
the doctors were just like blown away
at, at, at how healthy he had
become, you know, just from,
from doing all this and learned about
micronutrients and all this stuff.
So I was like, man, that seems
like a cool, a cool thing.
Like I want to try it, you know, I've
never fasted before or anything like that.
And uh, went out and
bought a juicer and it was,
it was a fucking pain in the ass to
clean that thing like three times a day.
And I was having,
I had to buy like $30 worth of vegetables
every day to make enough juice to,
you know, put into a glass that
would somewhat keep me full.
And I was just like, there's gotta be a
better way than this shit. And so, uh,
ended up going to a vitamin shop and saw
like organic freeze dried wheat grass
and you just add water to it. And I was
like, oh my God, that's so much better.
You know?
So I went and basically picked out a bunch
of ingredients that I did research on
that you know, things
that I wanted and um,
and uh,
put them all into like a Shaker Cup
and added water and drank it and did,
did a fast that way. And uh,
it was obviously much cheaper,
much better, like just more convenient,
way more convenient and
everything like that.
And I just didn't have anything in
post on Instagram one day. And, uh,
and so I just shared it
and I was just like, hey,
this is kind of a concoction that
I came up with and, and I do my,
I do a five day fast like this and uh,
just kind of, it makes me feel good,
helps me lose weight. And
then I started doing that,
like cutting weight for my fights and um,
and then people, it just
fucking caught on like wildfire.
Like everyone was like, what does that,
what does that? And then I was like,
look, I'm not associated with
these companies at all. You know,
like these aren't, I don't get it paid
for this. Like, this is just here,
this is what I do. And like put it,
laid it all out there and I was like,
you can get all these products on Amazon
or your local vitamin shop or whatever,
and just made it as
idiot proof as I could.
And I was just getting bombarded
with questions nonstop, but,
but it was like a lot of people were
having like a ton of success fasting with
that and losing weight. So I was like,
well, that's pretty cool. You know, like,
I'm really, I'm down to
help people, you know,
better themselves and I enjoy like pushing
people and pushing myself and trying
to be better and everything. So, um,
so I stuck with it and just kept,
kept answering all the
questions or whatever.
And then after like a year and
a half or so, I ended up, um,
making my own, you know,
it's just like, well,
I might as well fucking make this my
own products. And so I found a way to,
to kind of make that come to life and, um,
took all those products basically
and just put them into one,
removed all the fillers and all the
bullshit in there and just was like,
you know,
I didn't know anything about the
supplement industry or anything like that.
I just never intended on doing that,
but just Kinda came
about and, uh, you know,
delivered a product that was way more
convenient than everyone was already using
and buying all these
other things. And now,
now it's like my product and
they're able to support me.
And now it's like, I don't, you know,
I don't have an issue answering these
questions now that you're buying my
product. You know what I
mean? So, um, now it's,
it's been super awesome because we've
had just a ton of people lose so much
weight and like my brother lost
110 pounds, you know, using it.
So it really works, which
is cool, you know, and,
and it's really helpful for people and
it's changing their lives and like,
I'm all about that. And now,
like it's supporting me financially
now that I'm not out, you know,
in the navy anymore, cause I didn't,
I didn't get a retirement or anything
like that. I just got out. So, um,
so yeah, that's super cool. And, and, uh,
the supplement in a company like now
that I've been in it for a little while,
like I'm starting to get
more understanding of it and,
and, uh, we're, we're doing
pre-workout protein bcas, all that
stuff, like kinda expanding it and,
and, um, you know, now I'm like
really involved with it and,
and I'm just treating it like
everything else. Like I always tried to,
uh, you know,
under promise and over deliver and like
I always want to make sure that like
people are getting like
something good, you know,
I don't want to ever feel like I gypped
someone or got one over or something
like that. Like when people
come to use my products,
like I want them to be like a
fucking satisfied for certain means,
best policy to have, make the best.
Yeah. Stuff. Just don't skimp. You know,
like my, my, my, my end game
is not to make the most profit.
Like I want an actual good fucking
product like that. My name is behind,
you know, and I'm proud of what's
the, uh, what's the website? Um,
you can either go to smashing frog.com
or massive supplements.com m a s F
supplements.com. Either one, they
go to the same place, but yeah. And,
uh, we got tee shirts
and stuff, but a, I'm,
I'm basically streamlining
my tee shirts, uh,
cause I had massive apparel and I
just made a bunch of tee shirts that,
that I wanted to make, you know,
that were like personal in the me.
Like the mindset is everything.
Attitude is contagious.
Don't be a Polisci be humble, you know,
these are shirts that like I've kind of
made all the shirts that I want to make
and I made them, I was kind of a t
shirt snob, uh, before I had my company.
And then once I made my company and
like got into the apparel industry,
like I just wanted like really
comfortable, nice fitting,
good quality tee shirts and
printed my own shit on them.
And that's all I wear now.
But I'm just streamlining it down
to a couple that I like. And, um,
I'm actually launching a new brand
pretty soon that I'm very excited about.
Cool. Cool. Right on, right? Yeah. So a
few follow me on Instagram. You'll, uh,
you can keep up with all that stuff
I've got going on and, and, uh,
watch my future fights. And
hopefully I don't get knocked out.
Echo you anything.
What happened with that dodge ball
fight you're talking about? Oh Man. Uh,
it was oddly enough, it
was in a church also.
So I got into a dodge ball
church fight, dodge ball church.
Did you win that one? I did. And uh,
knocked the guys tooth out. Um, we,
we were there to, uh,
practice our dodge ball and,
um, we were taking it
very seriously. You know,
cause there was a tournament coming
up that I think had like a $500 prize,
which when you're like
16, $500 is a million.
Yeah, that'll go a long way.
Go a long way. So, you know,
the stakes were high and
uh, we were, we were,
we were there and there was some
local jokers that were just,
you know,
not taking it seriously and like just
fucking with our practice and stuff.
And, and there's one
thing that makes me angry,
legitimately angry is when people are
taking dodge ball service, you know, just,
and it was, there was a
time for joking around,
there was a time for
seriousness and you know,
that wasn't the time
and ended up, you know,
I ended up saying something to this dude
and just you just kind of fucking mouth
off and you know, tempers,
tempers flared and escalated. Yeah.
Things escalated and ended up getting
into like a full on brawl like dodge ball,
dodge gang girl. It was a dodge
brawl dog from dodge ball.
So thank you. That's a good time.
Awesome. Um, Hey, speaking
of fighting, sure.
And smashing things, sir. W I mean Echo.
Yes. We want to be better at fighting.
We want to be better at living.
What do you got? What do you
got for us? I got a few things.
So we'll start with Jujitsu, right?
You're no good. Better. Um,
I'm starting to like Nogi better I would
say just because I feel like it's more
applicable to the cage.
However, um, you know,
like Jocko was saying earlier,
I, I agree wholeheartedly.
I think that everyone who trains Jujitsu
should train in a g as well because,
uh, you know,
there are a lot of similarities and I
feel like if you only train Nogi and then
you go against someone with a,
put a Guiana with any sort
of decent skill level,
you're gonna get fucking choked
for sure. And uh, it just,
the geese everything down
and it's a, it's a totally different
animal. And the thing is like,
you can train in a GE all the time and
take the g off and roll with someone
No-gi and you're, you're going to do
fine. You're, you're still doing Jujitsu.
You know what I mean? It's a different
game, but it's not that much different.
But going from No-gi to g very different.
So that's why I think, I think people
should definitely train an ag still. Yeah,
agree. Yeah, both is best for sure. Yeah.
The g adds these elements
that if you only train No-gi,
you're not used to those elements.
And if someone else is
used to those elements,
all the Nogi l most of the Nogi
elements are in the Geek. You know,
like those elements are there for the
most part of course close, you know,
like using like if you were
getting a street fight,
like you can use clothes like a g. So it
gives you even that many more options.
Yeah, for sure. Yeah, I
agree. Well speaking of g is
what g we're going to get,
everyone's doing Jujitsu. No, I
feel like it's growing essentially.
So what kind of gear are we
getting? Origin G, you know,
why are we getting origin geese?
Because they're made in America and
they are factually the best skis in the
world. Rash guards as well. Okay. So where
do we get, and we get them at origin,
maine.com that's also where we're
getting jeans. Yeah. By the way.
And I got mine by the way,
approval level 100 you know,
always reluctant to sing, you know,
101% approval. But here I'm going to say
it 101% approval because they exceeded,
literally exceeded my expectations.
Your expectations were high worry?
100% I was like, yeah, the way you're
talking, the way they, you know,
PD does a good job in building
these things up. You know,
he's taking close up pictures
of the buttons coming out
of the factory that it's
really good. So I'm like all right,
expectation, expectation level is high.
100% these have to be five star jeans
essentially. They're like five star plus.
Some added things that I
was impressed with. So yes,
a hundred per 101% approval. Yes.
So jeans you can get
them shirts, rash carts,
southern stuff, supplements. Yes. So
what kind of supplements? Joint Warfare,
which I'm happy man.
I've been on the joint where if I think
it's been one year consistent joint
warfare crew oil, so
approved, 100% approved,
actually adding value,
providing value even beyond what
you might think in the beginning,
cause you don't want, you
know, when we're young,
we're all young guys or
whatever, you don't care that,
you know you have muscle
soreness, you have all this stuff.
What are the joint soreness is one of
those things that just kind of creeps up
on you. But if you're on top
of that, that doesn't take it,
it'll take you out of game if you're
not ready. Preventative. Yeah.
And when it comes by, and I, I'd get
like elbow stuff from lifting and stuff.
Uh, but if,
if I was on like joint warfare
glucosomine could join any,
any one of these things that they did
recommend when I started grappling.
By the way, if I was on that, I would've
never got out of the game at any point.
Last point is get your joint warfare,
get your crew in, stay on that.
Get your discipline to
fully get your discipline.
Discipline is like all day now. Yes sir.
That's kind of where it's going. It's,
yeah. It's like, yeah, guess
what? I'm just drinking. Oh,
I'm just going to have some discipline.
Right. It's kind of poured this a,
is this what you're talking about? Yeah.
Yeah. It's just hastiness and goodness.
[inaudible] mission. Is
this a pre-workout? Yeah,
it's, it's not like a super,
um, there's not like a
super caffeinated deal.
Cause I don't drink a lot of caffeine
and I don't want to drink a lot of
caffeine. So yeah, you little cognitive,
a little physical. Okay. And
you just sip this all day?
Yeah, I don't have like some in them.
I won't drink it like after dinner,
you know,
because I d there's a little bit of
caffeine in it and I don't drink a lot of
caffeine. So
not even in the mornings when
you're, when you're waking up?
Nope. Okay. So four 30
says a little bit 15 teeth.
The white tea has some caffeine in it
too. So I guess I do drink caffeine,
but I don't drink high
doses. Like, like a,
like a monster energy drink or
whatever. Yeah, it makes sense.
Speaking of energy drink, we got an
energy trans coming out, but it's,
it's actually good for you, which
is completely, it's like we,
it's hard to call it an energy drink
because energy drink puts it in a,
in a category with things that are
actually horrible for you. Right?
Like the normal energy drinks
that are just horrible for you.
This is something that you
can legitimately just drink
and it's good for you.
Yeah. So that's coming out only you'll
see some cans of that in the near future.
Oh yeah, that's a good one. Also milk,
if you want a dessert,
if you want extra protein in the
form of the dessert, that's it.
Milk all flavors. I like that. Just say
if you want a dessert. Chocolate. Yes.
Big Mint chocolate,
chocolate protein as well. And
I was in my, my protein, our uh,
my supplements took a long
time to come out like way.
I'm sure if you've encountered whenever
you're dealing with any kind of putting
out something,
it never goes according to plan and is
always longer than you're expecting or
whatever. And I had done a mint
chocolate. I that was just,
I've been a huge fan of mint my whole
life. Mint, chocolate, whatever,
deliciousness. And uh,
and I saw that you put out a mint
chocolate and I was like, God damn it.
Everyone is going to think of the coffee.
I don't have the patio with a mint
chocolate or they'll probably think like,
Dang,
I thought I was the only one who loved
mint chocolate better than everything
else. Like, you know,
we all kind of do Jacko and
about seals both like Jujitsu,
but like men chocolate. Yeah. Will, same
thing with Pete. Right? I mean, not,
not the navy seal thing, but wait, was
he into mint chocolate or peanut butter?
Ah, he was in the meant,
but I think peanut butter c the peanut
butter was kind of like the second wall
and started smashing. Well, yeah.
And that makes sense because
in my family, you know,
I'm not disclosed like my favorite
dessert is this or that. I'm not that,
you know. But I will say that when you
came out, it's almost like, you know,
you're, you're going public with your
mint chocolate, uh, love admiration.
I was like, Hey, hey, me too.
But peanut butter chocolate has always
been my close, close second. Yeah.
Easy money.
But the one that really does
strawberry because it's just so,
yeah, good. Oh yeah. But, and
strawberry's a staple anyway. You know,
just like staple everything but
so vanilla, but I'm not over here.
I'm not over here, uh, jumping up and
down about vanilla. Yeah. But some people,
I know, some people are,
I've got a cinnamon toast
crunch for teaming out and
I've got to think of a name
for it because I don't think I can
legally call it the cinnamon toast crunch.
I don't know. I don't know what the
rules are. I thought about thinking of a,
you know, growing up, uh, I always
had, we were kind of not so, uh,
financially gifted when to call
it that living in a trailer.
And um, my mom would always get fruity
dyno bites, you know, there you go.
And Cinnamon Toast squares.
So I used to eat those out of the bag.
That's not what the
other kids eat one size.
Especially once I joined the navy
and started getting, you know,
a good paycheck. I just, I
never, you know, I never, again,
I always appreciated my cereal game.
It was always the good
stuff. Rudy pebbles,
when a real snow fruity dynamites
in this house get out of here.
With that comes in a bag.
Little kids need food. That's where I
got warrior kid milk, strawberry boom,
chocolate. Yup. Let them eat and be
healthy in or God that Jocko White Day.
Yeah. Maintaining. Yeah. Yeah.
My wife gets lit like she hits a point
in the day where she's like, man,
I'm considering just to go to bed right
now or the bus out of Jocko white tea
and just get after it as literally says
that. Yeah. And I know the feeling,
but man, she's really
committed to it though.
You got to take a go to you gotta take
something or may create a supplement of
some kind for a little power nap
because working on it, you know,
I did start a rumor that you take
naps. No, I freely admit that freely.
Yeah. He's very open about
it. I wrote, I wrote about it,
I wrote about it in the district. It was
free and field. I, if I'm really tired,
I elevate my feet above my heart and I
sat in alarm and I'll sleep for eight
minutes and eight minutes. Eight
minutes. Power now. Yup. And if you go,
I mean sometimes I'll go 10
but if you start going 1520,
then you then you're like
legitimately you'll feel groggy.
But you know the deal man from just like
you were talking about sleeping in a
helicopter. Like you wake up from those
things and you're totally on fire,
you know, sleep for 10 minutes,
eight minutes, whatever.
I have no problem with this. I, the
problem with me is a, I don't know,
I tend to nap better than I
sleep. Um, and the like when I,
when I wake up, my brain just
starts going and it just,
once that happens, it's
just, that's it. I'm up.
So when you say a supplement
for power adapted,
like helps you get into like power nap
state, like that guy, I don't know,
we'll look into it. We'll
work in it. It could be your,
your cinnamon toast crunch. A flavored
situation. Yeah. Have you taken hypnosis?
Oh yeah. So origin. So we have, we
have this thing called hypnosis,
which is like a sleep. Yeah.
But that's not for now. In
[inaudible] eight minutes.
It's usually you'd take a rail of
it and you're out for eight minutes.
Just fully recharged. More power
nap. I'm working on it. Well wait,
but technically in, I don't know,
this just seems like this
is true power nap king,
you know you have like what the
five phases, right, of sleep or
actually of insomnia. Yeah.
So yeah, so you can have,
you probably get jammed up somewhere
in one of those stages. Right?
Power nap is stage one, I
think. I'm pretty sure it's
only stage one. Power nap.
I, it depends on how tired you are.
Well then it won't be
considered a power nap.
If you're like super tired and you go
boom all the way. Faith stage five sleep.
But you went to bed. Do you have sleep
apnea or anything? Nope. No. Yeah,
I don't have, I did a sleep study
and I don't have sleep apnea,
but I have insomnia and it's like I wake
up enough not to actually wake me up,
but like, it's like I wake up,
no, don't even know I'm awake. Oh,
you know what I mean? So I
wake up, when I do wake up,
I'm fucking still exhausted. That's great.
Actually. So one of the, I actually
have a CBD line as well. Um,
which I don't know if you get into the
CBD at all. Not really. No, no. Um,
but one of the products
that we're launching is um,
a thing called green dreams
and it's a rapid dissolve.
It's a rapid dissolve tablet and you put
it under your tongue and dissolves in
like 10 seconds and it's um,
25 milligrams of CBD and
10 milligrams of Melatonin.
So, but no one wants that.
That's not for an eight
minute power nap, power nap.
That's the going to bid situation.
That's a go to bed slow ration.
Right on.
Well the opposite of that is Jocko white
tea cause you don't take that before
you go to bed. Maybe after you
wake up in the middle of the day,
like my wife or whatever. Also if you're
into dead lifting, which we all are,
of course it'll increase it to 8,000
pounds proving by the way, double blind,
triple placebo situations. No joke. Also,
we have our own store. Jocko has
a store, it's called Choco store.
We go rash guards doing
shirts. Tee shirts.
You want to represent while on the
path. Oh, there's Rutgers hats. Yeah,
for those of us that like
trocars, which apparently we do.
They're nice. One size fits
all. What about flex fit tech?
I did the flex fit for a while, but you
know I got a small head weight flex.
It has two sizes though. I know.
Yeah. So you're going to get,
you got to get the small medium or the
large XL and I don't know nothing about
the even about that at all.
And get back to it. Hoodies,
hat snob over here. Yeah.
Hoodies. Lightweight.
And do you find youth for
lightweight Hoodie? Definitely.
All the time. Year round? Yes sir. I
agree. Not everyone agreed with that one.
[inaudible] yes, some will. Yes. So the
ones we have, yes, they have zipper.
I'm a fan. I'm a fan of the zipper. The
zipper light Hoodie with the pockets.
Agree. I honestly,
I don't even have any of my own in
my apparel line at the moment, but a,
I'm a fan of those. Yeah. Yeah. Well
Dang. Dang. You know what I mean?
Either dispatcher or heavy hoodie.
That's where it's all
functional and I get it,
but that's like a g zip zipped up,
a non or a zipping lightweight should've
fucking little bit. Yeah, please.
Some warm guard without for sure. And
you know, hopefully it looks good.
Hope you, hopefully you liked the design,
but you will be representing
while you're on the path.
A lot of good stuff on there. Jocko,
store.com some patches on there too.
I reordered some more patches are
coming in. What I did, I made a mistake.
I made a mistake. I don't
want to go too deep into it,
but it resulted in patches not
being available for a little while.
They're going to be available, you know,
you can't buy what's not available.
So yeah. Yeah. That's what they're telling
me too. And I was like, Dang. Okay.
All right. So, you know, you learned
something new everyday and uh, you know,
speaking of which, right on top of
things, I'm trying to be chair to beat.
It'd be anyway smashed
the light button. Oh,
my daughter keeps saying that to me. She,
and she doesn't even know what that means.
I think she halfway knows what that
means. She's like smash the like button.
And I was like bred the video that you're
pretending to make doesn't even have a
like button. You need to just,
I got to cut it on and I got
to stop her from saying that.
That's what I gonna say.
But if you're in the mood to
smash the homework about Dana,
if you want to subscribe to this podcast,
you can still do that if you want one.
Where have you listened to podcasts
talking about the warrior kid podcast,
which there are now three new warrior
kid podcasts live at this time.
Good one. Stories from Uncle Jake.
Yeah. Stories that teach lessons.
An interview with John Bozak,
the warrior kid artists
that drew Mikey the dragons,
talking about how to get better at art,
how to use art as a tool
to better at other things.
How's Goodman those good that
those like do you do any art?
I didn't draw in my books. No, but
I mean, yeah, I can draw. Yeah.
He sent me a man and I'm
going to post this online.
Everybody can seal
paintings. Oh, for real.
Have you been into that for like a long
time or is that like a new situation?
Uh,
did my first painting in
2000 Easter of 2016 yeah.
It's okay. Let new car. Oh yeah. Like,
Oh, when I was three I did my, no, no,
definitely not. Yeah.
Jocko has the original logo where I
have the original logo of echelon front.
Jockos design actually
designed some other stuff too,
so he drew it right.
But so the disconnect was that I drew it.
I didn't draw it on with my
hand. I drew it on the computer.
Like I drew it on power
point. It's so bad. Oh,
it's so funny because when I first, when
he first sent it to me, I'm like I had,
of course you drew it on
PowerPoint then you know,
it's not like you have one of those
pads and stuff, your chocolate,
you don't have that kind stuff. So, but
it's not as obvious when you get it.
You just get the finished product and
it literally looks like my daughter drew
it with her left hand. She's
right handed by the way. And,
but the concept was legitimate.
Do the sound is what the national
and front logo is at this time.
That's what you're pushing and man
received. But the community part of it,
I tried to explain it to
you nine different times
and you kept sending me back
junk. I said, okay, pictures
worth a thousand words.
I don't feel like explaining this a
thousand times. Let's just send him a,
a rudimentary sketch of the concept,
which you then chiseled out
into, you know, glory. Yeah.
Emphasis on rudimentary by the way. But
the comedic part of it is how it looked.
It looked like a child drew it. So now
anytime, like if you ask them, oh yeah,
have you been into art? Boom, that
flashes in my head and he says, yes, boom,
makes it more funny. I'm going to post
it online so we all can have a good laugh
nonetheless. Yes. Work at podcast is out.
That interview with John Bozak is very
good, like especially like cause it is.
He talks about getting like
frustrated with stuff and goes,
I told y'all and his
little kids so it was good.
Don't forget about warrior kids soap from
Irish oaks ranch.com that young Aiden
is making on his farm. You
get soap, you can stay clean.
Of course. Also we have a youtube channel.
If you're interested in the video version
and see when Mitch looks like Hell
Yeah, I'm handsome.
You might be the Buffet's guests
we've ever had, right? I Dunno.
Buffets guests like out of 185 yeah.
We've only had like probably
10 or 15 gap to Kennedy.
Kennedy, Kennedy touched,
you know how many fucking times people
you and Tim Kennedy need to fight.
And I'm like, have you seen Ken
Tim Kennedy's way bigger than me?
First of all, 85. Yeah.
And what do you fight at 71 70 walked
around and I have fun at one 85 as well as
a champion. I want to 85 to um,
I've walked around close to 200.
No, Tim is like to 15 to 20.
He's a big dude. Awesome.
Just in passing. Um, I shook
his hand one time, but yeah,
he's a big dude. And uh, but I was always,
always telling me like that's not w way
of like kind of like similar stories.
Like there's, it wouldn't make
sense for us. Definitely. Yeah.
We just want to see and see
what a psychological warfare
is. An album with tracks. Wait,
wait, no. Back to youtube.
We have a youtube channel. I'm
going to Devin. I'm going to, uh,
what I call explain the value
of Youtube. You just did,
you can see what Mitch looks at.
That's just part of the value.
That's just like the, a big part. I
mean, donuts, don't undersell that.
It's huge. But you know, we have some
excerpts on those. What I was gonna say,
you know, if you don't want
to watch the whole podcast,
there's excerpts on there anyway. Some
of them are enhanced by Echo. Yeah.
So puts his art work onto the video and
they might be slightly better than my
original echelon front.
Maybe low gun and maybe a little bit
better than there's something were over
enhanced. Yes. Some people think, some
people think they're under enhanced. Yes,
I would agree with both guard lists.
Nonetheless, we have a youtube channel.
That's the point. Yeah.
And if you want to,
you can smash the like button. Sure.
Comment, subscribe, whatever the three
things they always say anyways. Yeah.
Psychological warfare
is an album with tracks.
If you're running into
moments of weakness, put in
psychologic warfare, you'll,
it'll solve your problem. No weakness,
weakness, uh, overcome. If the,
if you want the visual version
of that, go to flip side,
canvas.com my brother Dakota Meyer has a
little company where he's making things
that you hang on your
wall, artistic thing.
Some people call them artistic
things and you can uh,
get those if you want him
to make a special one,
you hit him up on Twitter to
some customer if it's like,
if it seems to get some traction. Yeah,
he can put it out. Yeah, he's good.
He's doing good stuff on there. Yeah,
I check them out from time to time.
Flip side, canvas.com also on it.
So you got on it.com/jocko or you
can get a lot of good stuff on there,
including kettlebells, other
workout stuff and bring my routine.
I'm going to Hawaii by the way,
for one month. I know people,
people really don't.
They Undersell Hawaii.
I feel like I feel that the same way when
I went there for the first time I was
blown away. Where'd you go?
I'm Maui and I'm a lot
who I'm gonna cry. Yeah.
One month I heard this beautiful. Yes
sir. It is. So I'm bringing the rings.
Your request, by the way,
that was one of the selling points of
rings is that you can bring them places
too. That wasn't really my request.
There was a statement, yes. Statement,
a recommendation recommendation
should be reluctant recommendation.
You sure did. And it was a really,
it was a legitimate recommendation.
Then the last I'm taking it, I'm
taking them to Hawaii anyway.
Point is the rings. I have it from on it.
You can get those need
kettlebells you can get,
I have this k they have this
mineral electrolyte like mix. Right.
And I think I might've just
enhanced what I called the mega mix.
It's the pre-work. I'll
make a mix. There's two,
there's one for just the one for lifting.
The one for Jujitsu is discipline,
one scuba discipline, little bit of
Gatorade. So it's a half Gatorade,
half water, mixed, optional, Gatorade.
Some people they don't like Gatorade,
some people. And that's cool. You can
put lemon juice in there if you want.
Sure. Um, like I said, the discipline,
the electrolytes from on it.
And then uh, I want to add your
Greens. I'll hook you up. Yeah,
that'll be the mega mega
mix. That's pre Jujitsu.
Is there a certain time where
you gotta take those Greens? No,
just whenever I get them,
make them on all day. Boom.
So that's gonna be the pre Jiujitsu.
The pre lifting is
essentially the same thing,
except you put like the caffeinated pre
workout in it. If you're into it anyway.
Anyway, back to on it.
That's where you get it.
There's a lot of cool stuff
on on there. Quite a large,
large human being yourself, man, looking
good. But I don't sound big though.
Thank you. Perspective. I'm sorry.
Does my voice not match how I live?
You know? I can't say because
you saw me. I saw you seen.
Just started talking. Kind
of ingrained. There you go.
Maybe not though had had you not
spoke, I'd been like Dan. Yeah,
let's dudes probably fucking got a
jacked voice. Yeah, like junk. Yeah,
but it's melodious. It's not
Jacqueline. Sorry. I have a,
I have a high pitched voice. Melodious
very melodious. Yes. Interesting. Anyway,
got some books way to where
your kid three. It's out.
It's called the where there's a will
teaching kids about how to go harder.
That's a little lesson in this book.
Yeah. You got to push harder.
And also teaching them about their
ego and how their ego will get them in
trouble.
Everyone wishes they would've learned
about ego earlier because it makes your
life better. Of course,
there's a way the warrior could want
and where the where could do Mark's
mission. Those books are for
kids to learn to get on the path.
If they're a little bit younger than
that, you can get a Mickey in the dragons.
They can learn about how
to overcome their fear.
There's actual pragmatic protocols
that you can take as a human being to
overcome what you're afraid of. Why not
learn that when you're five years old?
That's my question. Why not?
Because you didn't know about the book
Mike and the dragons and now you know
about it. Your kids are just
out there conquering fears,
which is a positive thing.
[inaudible] yeah, and that's a
good one too because you can like,
you know if you have a bedtime routine
and then you read to your, you know,
four or five year old before they can
read. It's one where you can read it.
Not only can you read the whole thing
if you want to, it's like a 1516 minute,
you know, but they'll want to hear
it again. So it's like a, you know,
so one year while you're
reading it over and over again,
that lesson will be instead, you know,
ingrained and instilled deeper and
deeper than just one of the many books.
Repetition. Exactly. Right.
Then we've got to discipline or freedom
field manual. If you go, Hey Jocko,
can you post your workouts? Yes,
they're in the discipline equals
freedom field manual. Hey Jocko,
what do you think you should do
in a situation like this? Oh,
it's in the discipline equals freedom
field menu. Hey Jocko, will you eat?
It's in the manual. What's your
sleep routine? It's in the manual.
Do you take naps? It's in the
manual. It's all in there,
so they just want it goes freedom field
manual, the guide to getting after it.
If you want the audio version of that.
It's on iTunes and Amazon
music and all the MP3 things.
Then of course we got extreme ownership
and that I got a [inaudible] of
leadership written by me
and my brother Leif Babin.
Those are going to help you become a
better leader in your business with your
family and in your life. Watch it happen.
Of course we have Ashkelon Front,
which is my leadership consultancy and
what we do is solve problems through
leadership because all the problems that
you're having in your life right now in
an organization are leadership problems.
I don't care what they are and if
you want to solve those problems,
you have to fix your leadership and
that's what we do. It's me, Leif Babin,
JP Denelle, Dave Burke deal.
Yes. Flynn Cochran, Mike Cirelli,
Mike [inaudible] and Jason Garner. Go
to Ashkelon, front.com for details.
We also have e f online,
which is online leadership training,
which is something that's
hard to comprehend.
How are you going to take leadership and
teach people leadership from an online
thing on online training
program? Well, you read about it,
you take tests on it and then
you get put in scenarios,
interactive scenarios on the computer
where you have to make decisions.
So that's the f online.
Then we have the muster,
which is a leadership
conference to leadership event.
Something like ring of gathering data
and it's all, it's all in actually.
The muscular is what it is.
Yeah, it's, it's a muster,
but it's the mustard though. Must
Be. So look, the muster leadership,
they've all sold out and
they're all going to sell out.
The next one is September 19th
and 20th in Denver. After that,
December 4th and fifth
in Sydney, Australia,
check out extreme ownership.com
for details. If you want to come,
don't wait to register because then you
won't be able to go and you'll be mad at
me and I, and you'll send me a,
like, let's say you're my friend.
Let's say you're someone I actually
know. Sure. How'd you set it? And, and,
and we're doing a muster
up in San Francisco and you
send me a Texas says, Hey,
sorry for letting you know late. Uh,
you said you're going to hook me
up with some tickets. It's cool.
I can make it and I'm bringing two
friends and I'm like, well, first of all,
no, because it's literally sold out.
It's not like, hey, it's sold out,
but we could still let people in. That's
not sold out. It's sold out. Yeah,
so don't wait. And then of course
we have VF, Overwatch, where we take
proven combat leaders
from special operations,
from combat aviation and put them into
companies in the civilian sector that
need leadership. Leadership is the most
important thing on the battlefield.
Why not get battle tested leaders to
help out you inside your business,
go to e f overwatch.com and if
you want to ask me a question,
us a question, you want to give me an
answer? Did I mess something up today?
Probably. You want to let me know
about that. Please bring it. Mitch,
as he said, he is on Instagram.
Mitch Underscore, AG,
e. R a. G. U. I. A. R.
An Echo and I are, well,
we're on Twitter and Instagram
and on dash fight Boykin.
Cool. Echo is at Echo Charles
and I am at Jocko Willink. Echo.
Anything else? Nothing else. Thank you.
Thank you guys for having me very
much. I really appreciate the uh,
hospitality and opportunity I
had to home. Awesome. Well Mitch,
thanks for coming on.
I appreciate it and thanks for your work
in the teams and I'm sure you're going
to keep putting forth maximum
effort to smash people in the cage.
Look forward to seeing that hey to all
the other vets out there and to those
that are still in uniform. Thank
you for standing. Watch over.
Freedom for our great nation and to
our police and law enforcement and
firefighters and paramedics and EMT and
dispatchers and correctional officers in
border patrol, secret service
and all the first responders.
I travel around the country and I run
into you all the time and I see what
you're doing out there working and
working hard and the reason that we live
safely here in our country is you.
Okay.
So thank you for holding the line here
at home and everyone else out there
remember that you can't
hit the pause button,
get it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter at all.
If you get knocked down or you get tripped
up or you think that something isn't
fair, it doesn't matter.
You still don't get to stop.
So get back up,
bite down on your mouthpiece
and go get after it.
Good. Until next time,
this is Mitch Aggie,
r and Echo and Jocko out.